Just as flowing water has no form, and the breeze is invisible
deductions take all shapes and styles in each and every case to be solved.
At last, the two of us are out on a date.
But an additional dish of trouble is added to our meal.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved with Detective Conan
While exploring a limestone cave
I am shot by a gang of bank robbers
Ran's blood is used for my transfusion... and it saves my life.
I have made up my mind to tell Ran everything, but
Ai points a gun at me...
And then on the day of
Teitan High School's school festival,
while the play was going on in the gymnasium,
a murder takes place in the audience!
And then
from beneath the black knight's mask...
...Who are you...?
It's been a long time hasn't it,
Inspector Megure...
...It's me, Shinchi Kudo...
PERILOUS RETURN-
SHINCHI IS BACK
Yes...
Yes?
Take your finger off that buzzer!
I heard you the first time!
Shinichi,
do you really know today's schedule at school?
No problem, it's the same as last year
all we're going to do is clean up after the school fest anyway, right?
I'll go get ready, wait here
Yawn...
There he is, it's really Shinichi.
I wasn't dreaming! Hehehe...
He's really come back!
Isn't that wonderful, Conan?
Hey?
Yes, this is much better!
This is my real body...
Don't get too comfortable though!
Ha, Haibara?!
Who do you think you are anyway?
The only reason she hasn't found out about you,
is the special antidote I made up
and the capsule & mask voice changer
Doctor Agasa made
so I could disguise myself as you!
You promised that all you would do was talk to her secretly
on the stage for a few minutes.
So why'd you show your face so dramatically?
Sorry!
But when I solved the case,
I just couldn't control myself.
Besides, I never thought the antidote you gave me
would completely restore me back to my old self...
...Do you think I made a mistake...
You should thank that friend of yours from Osaka,
when you collapsed
after I told him what was going on,
he told everyone not to talk about the case...
I don't know how well he convinced everyone though...
I guess I'll have to keep up this act & stay at Ran's place
until things cool down for your sake...
Hey Haibara...
Why are you doing all this for me?
You made the antidote,
don't you want to take it and go back to your old life?
You fool...
I'm only helping you because
if your cover is blown,
I'm going to get caught in the crossfire!
Besides, the antidote you took was a test product...
I don't intend to take it until
I've observed how it affects you...
Uh, by the way, Haibara...
Wh, what is it now!?
Could you stop talking like a girl when you use Conan's voice?
It sort of gives me the creeps...
But why, I think it's rather charming...
Argh...
That's so creepy...
I was so surprised...
who would've thought you were the black knight!
You didn't even have the lines memorized,
you had some nerve doing what you did.
Eh?
If you had kept adlibbing it,
the play would have been ruined
Sonoko, you rat fink...
You got it?
The black knight suddenly grabs the princess
and gives her a big, big kiss!
Don't do any talking until then!
So what did you think?
Eh? You mean the play?
That's a tough question...
Not the play, Princess Heart!
It doesn't matter so much, but I'd like to know...
Oh!
I liked you in that dress!
Eh?
Like they say,
"Fine feathers make fine birds"
you looked nice
Grrr...
What do you mean by that?
Is that supposed to be a compliment?
There's Conan!
Congratulations on being released from the hospital!
Yo! How've you guys been!?
Oh, hello there...
Eh?
Hey, who's that guy?
That's the high school kid who lives next door to Doc Agasa
Oh, from that haunted mansion...
By the way, Ai said she had a cold and wouldn't be coming to school
Oh
Did you catch yesterday's soccer game?
Yeah, I sure did! It was fantastic...
I was one of them until just a few days ago...
it's so unreal... it was like a dream...
Shinichi!
Come on, we've got to hurry
We're going to be late!
Hey, wait for me, Ran...
Huh?
Uh... I, uh...
I was only kidding...
Good grief, stop playing games.
Act your age for goodness sakes!
I told you it was just a joke
Yo, Kudo!
You just got back and already you're walking to school as a couple?
Tweet tweet!
Idiots. We're not like that!
Sure...
Hey, by the way, the new English teacher is one good looker,
she's a foreigner with a great body
Really?
I guess,
You know, you still haven't told me...
Told you what?
You told me you had something important to talk to me about
Oh... that...
Listen...
Eh?
Eh...
You nosey bunch of...
stop eavesdropping!
Oh Mrs. Kudo, help us, your husband's gone mad!
...Tonight at 8
...Beika Center Building...
rooftop restaurant...
Are you sure you can afford this?
This place looks awfully expensive
Don't worry about it.
I've got my father's charge card...
You're a very bad son!
How can you say that,
my parents are worse, they left me all alone & took off on a trip!
Hehehe...
You and Conan are so much alike!
Eh?
His parents are abroad too...
Hmm, really...
You know...
hehe...
I've been thinking about this a long time...
It concerns you being Conan...
Uh... ahaha...
I imagined that you got into some kind of trouble
and had to go into hiding
so you took some kind of medicine or other
that Doctor Agasa made to make you small...
hahaha...
isn't that ridiculous?
Hahaha... you almost 100% right...
It's funny though...
now that you're back, I look at him,
and he looks like a whole different person...
You're crazy, off course he does...
someone else is disguising herself as me...
So?
Eh?
What did you want to talk to me about?
Uh, umm...
it's like this...
Uh huh?
Uh...
I just wanted to say...
Elevator
Eh?
Sir, do you mean you're not going to the party?
Yes, I'm not feeling too good
Give everyone my regards,
Tatsumi Taiji
Game Company President
and ask them to work hard for the company!
Why is this elevator hall so dark?
Sir!
Satoru Oba
I got them to dim the lights for that
surprise you're planning
Oh! Now I remember
Well, say hello to everyone!
Good bye!
Uh...
Excuse me, could you tell me what room the party is in?
Why Miss Sakurako!
The party's at the Italian restaurant back there!
I see...
Why, Mr. Oba!
Excuse me,
I have something to discuss with
Miss Sakurako...
Sure...
but the party's going to start soon so don't be long!
OK...
Honey...
You're late!
You promised to meet me here before 8:30, remember?
Sakurako Tatsumi
I'm sorry! It took me long to get ready!
But never mind that, did you tell dad about us?
Of course I did!
I thought he'd be really mad but he gave his approval right away...
he said he trusted me and knew I'd take good care of you...
Then we can married!
Yes...
Now how about giving me a reward for being so brave?
Let's see...
How about a nice, big kiss...
Hey!
The party's already started
8:30, right on the dot...
Before we go to the party, here!
It's a present for you!
Oh my, for me?
What is it?
It's a pink pearl pendant to go with the earrings you're wearing tonight.
Thank you!
It's the least I could do.
Today's a very important day, it's the day we become formally engaged...
Wow, you figured it out just by something like that?
You're a regular Sherlock Holmes!
You know it!
And?
So what did you want to talk to me about?
Eh?
Uh, about that... er...
Oh good grief...
I know it's not easy to say, but...
If you're a man, then act like one and get it over with...
Eh?
You want to borrow my notes to study for the time you weren't in class, don't you!?
Huh?
Oh dear?
Did I make a mistake?
I thought for sure that's what you wanted,
I made copies for you right here
Oh, uh...
Hahaha, actually, you're right!
I didn't know how to ask!
I knew it!
Silly, that's not what I wanted to say!
Eh?
The reason I asked you out to dinner is... uh...
There's something I wanted to tell you...
It's uh...
It's...
Eeeek!
What's that?
Did someone scream...
Somebody probably just saw a cockroach or something, don't worry about it...
Hey, come quick!
There's a dead body in the elevator!
Did anybody call the police?
OK now, here's what I wanted to say...
A gun, it's a gun!
They said the president of a company has been shot in the head!
It's like this...
You don't have to hold yourself back...
Huh?
I know you're dying to see what it's all about...
No, I...
I'm not like "some" people,
I won't run away or hide,
so go ahead and check it out...
Mr. Detective...
Get going!
I might change my mind if you don't go now!
Ra... Ran...
Thanks...
I'll be right back!
Sure
And? Has the victim been identified?
Yes
The victim is Yasuji Tatsumi, 58 years old
He's the president of a game company...
Those 3 were first on the scene...
they work for the same game company and they were going to take
this elevator to get something they'd forgotten in the office
when they found the body...
What did they forget?
It was a bouquet they were presenting at the company's 20th anniversary party
being held tonight at a restaurant here.
The game company occupies the 24th to the 36th floors of this building
And this is their private elevator...
Mr. Tatsumi said he wasn't feeling well
And he was going to drop by the office then head home...
Hmm, his clothes are rumpled,
the killer must have gone through them looking for money
hmmm
Hey, wasn't there a similar incident here before?
Eh?
You remember,
it was when I just became a detective, a young kid came and butted in...
I was still in elementary school then
Excuse me, I don't think this was a robbery
That's right, it happened just like this...
Eh?
If the killer had a gun and wanted to rob him,
he would have taken him to someplace remote
If he intended to search him for money after killing him,
there was no telling when someone would use the elevator
so staying here would be too risky
Besides, who takes the buttons off the shirt sleeves just to search for money...
Isn't that right,
Inspector Megure...
Ku, Kudo!
Shh, don't mention my name!
What, again?
But why are YOU here?
Ran and I were having dinner
Good grief... high school kids having dinner in a place like this...
Actually, I had a special reason for choosing this place...
Papa!
Papa, papa!
Mr. Tatsumi...
Nooo, who would do this to papa!
When we said goodnight to him here just a while ago, he was just fine...
So you people were the last to see Mr. Tatsumi alive?
The three of us saw him off in this elevator
Miss Sakurako arrived shortly after and...
She and I went over tonight's speech then we went to the party...
Did anyone get into this elevator during that time?
No, no one...
Do you know what time it was?
Let's see...
It was 8:30!
The poppers were going off at the party
and that's the time
I saw showing so I'm sure of it!
But you're not wearing a wristwatch
I saw the time on Mr. Oba's wristwatch!
It was when he touched my earring!
He touched your earring?
When we were here, he gave me a gift!
He said, "It's a pink pearl pendant to go with the earrings you're wearing tonight"
I was so happy...
Miss Tatsumi...
Excuse me
We'll have to return to the party and tell the others what happened...
Miss Tatsumi, we should go too...
Officer Takagi...
Huh?
What we just heard... don't you think their story's strange?
Uh...
Eh?
Yes, well...
I do wonder whether she really saw the dial... though...
How dare you!
I certainly did see it!
I'm sure you're suspicious because when you got here it was quite dark, wasn't it?
But as you can see,
the hands on my watch are luminous
so you can see the time even in the dark
Mr. Tatsumi himself asked me to dim the lights in this hall,
he was planning a surprise...
I still think it's strange though...
Hey, let me in on it too...
Hey, wait a minute...
What strikes you as so strange?
Just watch.
When you touch her earring with that hand, you can't see the dial, can you?
Hahaha... stupid, aren't you... you can see it if you touch her other ear!
Hmmm... why deliberately touch the ear on your right...
Can't you see my looking at her?
That's the side her earring shows!
That's why I...
What about your right hand?
Wouldn't it have been easier to use your right hand?
I suppose though, if your right hand was holding something
you'd have had no other choice...
I wonder what it is...?
I wonder what he wants to tell me that's so important...
What could it be?
You don't think he...
Hey, have you put on some weight since the last time I saw you?
It's possible...
my clothes do feel tight lately...
But he wouldn't invite me to dinner just to tell me that...
I'm sorry to keep you waiting
Could you hold dessert until my friend comes back?
He ran off when he heard that scream just now!
But he's a detective,
I'm sure he'll solve the case and be right back
Tee hee, I understand completely...
Eh? Is something the matter?
Oh, I'm sorry,
it's just that a former sommelier told me about this legendary couple
and you two fit the description perfectly.
That couple sat at this very table too...
It happened about 20 years ago,
The fellow from 20 years ago was a detective too
he returned to the table after solving a case
and shouted it out so you'd better prepare yourself for it too!
Prepare myself for what?
A proposal, he's going to propose!
Eh?!
Well, good luck!
P-P-Propose?
I don't believe it...
he wouldn't...
It's just not possible...
What are you getting at?!
Are you implying
I had a gun in my right hand?!
A gun?
I never mentioned a gun
Did you have one?
Inspector! Who is this kid?!
Well, uh, he's...
I may not look it, but I'm a cop too, fresh out of school!
Isn't that right, Inspector!
Hahaha...
Excuse me, you appear to suspect Mr. Oba, but...
if the three of them saw papa off here,
then Mr. Oba couldn't possibly have done it!
He was with me, after that
Did you leave at any time?
I went to the restroom to put the necklace he gave me on...
While I was there, I retouched my lipstick, it took about 2 or 3 minutes
But we were talking through the walls so it was like being together!
Inspector!
We found a gun with a silencer and empty gun shells!
Where?!
In the building's trash dump!
It appears the killer threw it down the dust chute
Is there a dust chute on this floor?
Yes... near the restroom...
I see,
so you could have it gotten rid of it while carrying on with the conversation...
Oh come on!
It seems you police are dead set on making me out to be the killer, but
tell me how I could have killed
Mr. Tatsumi after he left in the elevator!
I was with her all the time...
and if I shot him...
there should be powder burns on my sleeve, shouldn't there?
Then will you allow us to check you out?
Go right ahead!
Then follow me...
Mr. Oba...
Pardon me... but did you
and he kiss in front of the elevator?
Eh?
W-Were you watching us?
No, it's something my mother told me...
she said a woman will usually reapply lipstick only after a meal or after a kiss!
So tell me, how did he hold you?
How... well, he put his arm around me like this...
Eh?!
At that time, wasn't your back facing the elevator?
Yes... as a matter of fact, it was...
Did you two always meet secretly like this?
Yes... we had arranged to meet here tonight...
Hey, what is this?!
Thank you very much!
You were very helpful!
Oh, I'm sorry but I have one more question...
By chance, were those earrings also a gift from Mr. Oba?
Unfortunately, you guessed wrong!
I bought these these this afternoon on the spur of the moment!
These weren't from him!
Is that so... thank you...
I was right...
he killed Mr. Tatsumi after all... it was Mr. Oba, no doubt about it!
Your fingerprints were on the plastic bag!
Thump!
Of course they would be...
I touched that plastic bag too you know!
What!?
Hey, Kudo, what the...
So, fresh out of school detective, what's next?
Alright then...
let us open the door of truth
PERILOUS RETURN-PLACE
WHERE VOWS ARE MADE