What lies in one's heart is tery to us all.
Star and snow glitter on them .
Ayumi's idea breaks the code,
who is the person full of mystery?
He sees through the one andvonly truth.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult.
No case is left unsolved sth Detective Conan.
Gosho Aoyama / Shogakukan °~ YTV TMS
All Rights Reserved
How big it is!
They're building a bypass.
Are you sure we're heading right direction?
Absolutely!
We've been wandering around for the past 30 minutes...
That hurts on an empty stomach.
I'm starved
I know! Keep on walking!
You're not the only one .
Mr. Hanaoka!
Mr. Mouri .
Hello! I'm here again!
I'm not alone tonight.
Hello
Well, well... welcome to my restaur
Shigeru Hanaoka fEaE EA
Shigeru Hanaoka fEELTE EA
Here, come inside.
Shigeru Hanaoka fEa& EA
Shigeru Hanaoka
{EAE XA
Oh, welcome.
Where have you been?
Just to get cigarettes...
We're having customers now.
Reiko Hanaoka
Em #7 (30)
ERjoOR
welcome, Mr. Mouri.
Reiko Hanaoka
Em IF (30)
(4. [0]
So my I wasn't here. I was changing the water for the flowers
Reiko Hanaoka
Tem IF (30)
Exam
You changed the water just this morning.
The flowers last longer this way.
I'm sorry...
Oh, no, I can't get it off:
please take the table at the middle.
Saki!
Yes, coming!
Rocking Restaurant
Hello... and welcome.
Well! I haven't seen you...
I'm Saki Yoshizawa.
I'm the new waitress here.
Saki Yoshizawa
I'm so sorry...
That's all right.
I'll get a towel right away!
I've got this!
Here, let me do it for you...
Thanks, Ran.
You demand so much attention.
Sorry about that, Mr. Mouri.
I'm sorry about the tremors from the construction next door.
I... the place is really sha
But we've been told that the tremors will stop tomorrow morning.
We have to wait until 10 tonight, it will all be over.
Hey, I'm starved!
We have a big, fat sea bream today. Sonny.
But... I prefer fried prawn.
Okay, coming up!
Mr. Hanaoka...
You're closed tomorrow...
Going fishing for spearfish as usual?
Oh, yes!
I'maiplanning to prepare the tackle
1 baititomight
andlleave the first thing in the morning.
Spearfish fishing in the ocean breeze.
Lenv ou...
Thanks te his hobby,
Im left all alone on holidays.
Alone
I'm no feel...
What do you mean by that?
What is it?
Stop that! Were having customers!
Mr. Hanaoka, look.
Here this picture...
This big fish. Is this spearfish?
Yeah, that's right.
Shing buddy who's also a photographer took that picture.
Mr. Hanaoka,
how long have you been fishing?
Well... I think... for 25 years... maybe.
You know,
I used to live in Hachijo Island.
Look! Is that you?
You're so young!
But this picture looks a little different from others...
Probably it was taken by an amateur.
See?
If you look close enough,
the camera is focused on the chef
1d not the fish
Usually, a photo like this is focused on the fish.
You know a lot about pictures)
Actually, I wanted to become a photographer once.
What's this...
one...
Conan!
Oh#it's you, Saki. Are you off work?
Yeah...
Why, you're here, too!
Oh, hello. Aren't you with your father?
He said he hasn't had enough-yet and went drinking alone
He's a dud of a father!
But, you've still got one.
Found it! "The Last Super Detective"!
D to see this!
This is about a playboy detective, right?
Mr. Mouri must be having a good time surrounded by young-girl fans right now!
You must be kidding...
Freezing!
What luck! The bar closed!
This one's closed, too.
It's Hanaoka alone...
Right .
He must be working on the tackle and bait for tomorrow.
I'd rather not interrupt...
That's... Wada... right?
Yes, Mouri here...
Oh hi, Ito!
What? Mah onc ? Now? Where?
Next to Karantei? What coincidence!
Of course, I'm going. You bet I will!
Oh! I forgot!
What is it?
I need to buy bread for breakfast...
You can go ahead and go home!
Is ate and unsafe now...
Let's go home together.
I'll wait for you here with Conan.
Right. You're safe with her.
He knows karate.
Conan.That's embarrassing!
Okay. I'll be back as soon as I can.
I told you you can go drinking,
but why do you have to drink until morning?
Top yelling at me!
It's ringing in my head!
You only get what you deserve...
I'd really love a hot cup of coffee here.
Something wrong?
What in the...
Sorry to tell you...
He's been dead for quite some time.
Ran, call the police!
Okay!
Mrs Hanaoka, where do you usually put this vase?
On the top of the stairs...
Could it be that the vase fell ith the tremors...
Probably...
By some unfortunate coincidence,
it hit your husbandis head...
By the way, who are you?
My name is Yamamoto,
Mr. Hanaoka's friend.
We were planning to go spearfish fishing off Hachijo Island-today...
Koiti Yamamoto
NADI
I had to wait for a long time for him.
Since I was told he's not home either, ame here with his wife.
Was looking forward to going to Hachijo every year, around this time.
Trace of blood forming straight lines...
Don't touch material evidence!
I was just wondering whether the vase really hit Mr. Hanaoka...
There's blood on the inside of the hat.
At's proof enough that the vase hit his head!
But look... the flowers from the vase that fell...
They're withered compared to others...
I was just about to get to that...
True... the flowers here still look fresh
Uncle, see?
Dad!
See, there's a white fragment something on the floor...
It probably came from the ceiling.
Sq, A
If it's not to salt or sugar,
s highly likely it's white paint from the ceiling!
It has something to do with the cause of Mr. Hanaoka's death
There's a fine scratch on the beam.
The paint must have peeled ff from here.
Oka The other sida!
NIN CA, § 0 IC JAN ICE OINAC.
And the window is open...
I knew it!
The same scratch I found on the beam!
Looks into the construction site...
This may net be an accident...
Mr. Hanaoka may have been killed, set up to look like an accident.
Mrs. Hanaoka.
Mr. Wada, Saki...
A flower vase fell'... and my husband...
What!
And then? What happened to him?
He's been taken te the hospital for autopsy.
Autopsy?
That means...
Excuse me, but who are you two?
I'm Wada. I work here as a cook.
I'm Saki Yoshizawa, a waitress here
Inspector, wasn't it an accident caused by a falling vase?
Yes, Mr. Hanaoka died of wounds a falling vase
However, it appears that the vase was dropped deliberately.
Deliberately...?
Right!
I thought it was so at first...
But, my investigation turned up a lot of things...
The, autopsy showed he died between 11 pm'and 1am today...
However
we found that construction
work ended at 10:30 pm
Iast night due to machine failure...
That means...
Tremors from the construction sight couldn't have caused the vase to falls
I'd like you to see something...
It was found at the construction site.
The line on the fork is used for spearfish fishing
and the line wasted to a'steel frame.
The culprit used this line and he steel frame,
Positioned the vase right above Mr. Hanaoka's head,
and made it fall.
I had Inspector Takagi cheek the freezer in the back of the kitchen
He found the Sea Breem
and found a few petals inside
Which means the culprit...
placed the fork with the fishing line
0 the vase with flowers...
and placed the vase in the freezer.
Later,
the frozen vase was placed instead of the other
right above Mr. Hanaoka's head, as he was preparing his tackle
Moved on the pretense of changing water for the flowers.
And the line running along the beam
was tied to the line to the vase...
Later, the culprit went out...
to go to the construction site and tied the line to the steel frame there
slowly dropping it into the trench.
This way, the frame pulled the vase and moved the vase
right above his head
as the ice melts...
That's what really happened...
Wow! He's done it again and he's awake this time!
By the way,
it's your job to take care of the flowers, isn't it?
Don't tell me
You think I did it?
W-Why do I have to kill my husband!?
This was found inside
Mr. Hanaoka's locker.
What's this?
A report written by a private investigation firm.
This is a report on Mrs. Hanaoka's activities that her husband requested
is a photo of 'her with...
Mr. Wada
Yes,
there is an accomplice in this case.
The one who created the contraption in the construction site must be you.
Mr. Wada?
By coincidence,
I saw Mr. Wada last night coming out of the construction site.
Extramarnital affair.
So that is why you wanted to get rid off your husband.
Is that right?
I'm sorry!
Everything is true!
I did it!
Mr. Mouri! You're splendid as always!
Well... a piece of cake.
Get your foot off that chair!
What's that?
I didn't see that yesterday
Hey. What's with you!?
Uncle, the shape of the scratch on the chair and the vase.
Hello, Megurethere:;Hummm...
Okay
It was from Chiba at the autopsy. &
He says sea bream scales
were found in the collar and around the neck of the victim.
Seabream scales?
Fishing was his hobby...
so maybe they stuck there in an earlier fishing trap
This must be...!
So, that's it... amazing...
Anyway, we need you both to come with us for further questioning.
Wait, Inspector
Mr. Moun?
The two are not the killers.
Who then!?
Certainly, the two built that device...
But, when the vase fell...
Mr. Hanaoka was already dead!
What!?
The real culprit learned of the scheme to kill and took advantage of it.
The trick will not work unless
Mr. Hanaoka sits exactly under the vase.
It was totally unreliable...
That is why the culprit chose the most reliable way...
approaching Mr. Hanaoka from behind...
and with the frozen sea bream...
hitting him on the head.
The simplest and sure-fire solution.
So, that's how the scales got there...
After killing the man, the culprit rushed to return
the sea bream to the freezer and had a problem taking off the glove...
Because this person had to go to a certain location as soon as possible.
To the vi eo shop where Ran and Conan are waiting.
Isn't that right?
Saki!
Conan, show that to the Inspector.
Okay!
Here you are.
Humm.
This is a rubber glove.
This was used in the murder.
I see afaintt ace of Lipstick
Yes, the same color of lipstick
Saki was using yesterday...
No... don't make me a killer just because I wear the same color.
You tried to take off the glove in a hurry
because you had to get to where they were waiting.
But the glove sticks and is hard to take off...
ST, you bit the tip.
To remove it.
There is a bite mark believed to belong to a woman...
You can check and prove whose it is.
Is that true?
He deserved 10 be killed...
21 years ago, he was a fisherman in Hachijo Island...
There was a girl named Aiko Morimura
whom he promised to marry in the future.
But Hanaoka said he wan &d to study cooking
and left the island and Aiko...
Aiko let him go without a complaint
She didn't even tell him she was carrying his baby
Aiko waited.
She had the baby by herself and waiting for him to return,
caring for his child.
She waited and waited
until she lost hope and died this spring...
Then, Aiko's child is...
I could not forgive him... could never forgive him
Saki...
that photo
thatiphoto at the tn
Mr. Hanaoka sat all the time
it most likely was taken by your mother?
What!?
The focus Is Not on the fish but on Mr. Hanaoka...
It looks like a picture taken by somebody who loves him...
Look!
Mr. Hanaoka had the photo placed in the shop
and probably was looking at it all the time
He was thinking of his memories of
Aiko in Hachijo Island.
There is something that looks like the numeral 1 at the corner of the photo.
That probably stands for Aiko...
Aiko Morimura...
So what what's that supposed to mean!?
Are you telling me he should be forgiven
because he kept the photo ed at it?
My mother's already dead!?
Rked hard,
Ied a hard life, and died alone!
If he really did think of her that much, why didnitthe contact her!?
Why didn't he write her even once?
If he did... if he ever did... my mother w. Tld have.
Saki...
I don't know why Mr. Hanaoka never contacted her...
Still, regardless of what he did in the past.
There must have been ways for you to tell him how you feel.
Ways ether than committing something abominable like murder...
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY.
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS.
Michihiko Suwa
. Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS -BY.
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi hioka
SCRIPTS BY
Kanji Kashiwabiri
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRE JOR.
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OFsPHOTQGRAPHY
Takishi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Ogawa
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
Kenji KOdamay
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri elecastine Corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
Gosho Abyamaf-Shoqakukan - YTV - TM
Ail Rights Reserved
Oh! Wow!
It's pulling, pulling hard.
Must be a big one.
Hold on to it tight!
Im ready to sheet!
Ran move back a little.
I can't get the fish.
I can't meve any more
You move back, Dad.
Okay 4
Some more.
A bit more.
Doh. &%
Dad! Are you all right?
You're better off in front of the camera, rather than behind it, mister!
Oh, my!
I-Is that the legendary...
Uncle; look at this!
The armor is gone!