The deduction and suspense that closes
the distance between two people's love and hate
WW is the meaning of the "cross"?
The mysterious case hiding the symbols.
He sees through the one and only truth,
a child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult
no case is left unsolved with Detective Conan.
I think I've seen him before
"know Ive have seen him
But where did I meet
that man in the black knit hat?
And what is this thing I'm feeling?
I feel like something is gonna break if I try to remember what it was.
Yeah at that time...
and that time...!
It's the same bad feeling I felt back then.
Ran!
My gosh
What? Sonoko.
Ahh, it's late.
Hey Ms. Mouri!
Have you been paying attention to my lecture, Ms. Mouri?
Eh? Oh, yeah. Yes!
OK. Ms. Mouri, do you have any idea what that mark on the blackboard means?
Cross-mark
Oh, no, maybe it's the letter.
Ran .
That means
HD. BMT
Ms. Mouri, think about it and give me an answer by next class!
F indYout exactly what?that means.
It pays for a lady like you to Know what the cute mark is!
Y-Yes.
HIDE. HURRY UP AND ABBREVIATE IT
PART 1
Huh?
Is there any special meaning?
Yeah,
Jodie? our teacher, mentioned it at the end of today's class
saying that it was a cute mark.
Ran! No way. Impossible!
You can't get the right answer from this snot nosed kid.
/./ )
But, as you know, Conan sometimes knows about strange things.
Yeah, true.
In algebra,
X represents unknown quantity.
Or, it can mean a problem, something unknown, or unnamed thing
Xzrayy means radiograph
King means no one under 18 is admitted.
X day is a variable day when people think something 1s going to happen
Wait,
if it is the cross...
the X means wrong censored print.
One X can also mean that he or she has been divorced once.
Right, right
She said that it paid would for a woman to know the mark
What?
A woman?
That reminds me.
My mother used to write a series of crosses at the end of the letter
Like, XXX.
But she never told me what it meant even if I asked her.
don't you think that Jodie's way of teaching has changed?
Yeah, yeah!
She used to be too serious and boring before
EHEM
But'now, she teaches us casual English too, and I like it.
Remember this, flattery is not going to get You better grades!
1. Teacher!
Ms. Mouri
Did you figure out what "X" means?
No, not at all...
Right. How about, asking Shinichi about it by e mail?
If you get the right answer,
I'll give you my sweet "X"
Huh?
My Sweet X!
Oh, that's a good I Ral
You think so too, don't you?
What was that?
What the heck does X mean anyway?
o 606 ¢ 0&0 LE BN
But, isn't Jodie heading in the opposite direction from her apartment?
Yes, come to think of it.
I want ask you two something
Will you come with me?
What?
Are you asking if we are being sexually harassed?
You mean us?
There are many girls of our school being sexually harassed on the train and buses.
We've never been harassed, have we?
And even if such a pervert tries to molest me,
then Ran will bust him up with her karate skills!
Oh. You're her bodyguard!
No, no!
But still be careful.
Maybe the guy.
Will follow you all the way home waiting for a chance to .get to you.
He may be a scary sea my satanic stalker
If such a man is creeping around near my home,
the guard will grab and throw him out immediately.
I also haven't seen such a man+¥around my neighborhood.
Right. Conan?
Er? Um, yeah.
OK, then, if you see any suspicious person, please call me at once.
C-Call you?
Yes.
Japanese people still underestimate the stalker
If you call me, I'll give that guy a good scolding, American style.
What?
A Suspicious man is waiting in ambush for you?
Where re you now:
Norihisa Kisug!
Where're you now?
Norihisa Kisugl
ODO Ow
RE TAG
Led LU BAL BD U & ed
BE KBR
At the building where the coffee shop
Norihisa Kisug cre DO Le
RE aX (50)
Beet HERR
At the building where the coffee shop
I said a suspicious man but,
he may well be the man in question who
I have been checking on
KatsunorifChujo wd Lsd OD OD chs BA) (43)
NBA; PRS
When he meets me, he'll probably s
KatsunorisChujo
304d OO OO ch BAI (43)
MAPA PhBR
When he meets me, he'll probably s
I'll pay you double the reward
. ouire [getting so please let me go."
Yeah, listen, let's make a deal.
OK, Ok! I'll pay you triple.
No, quadruple!
So, please come over here now and give me the guy's name and evidence.
It's a deal I'll be right over!
He can't pay me four times, so I guess he'll give it up
Sorry, but that's the story
No offense, Mr. man in question
Hey, hey, I won't change my mind even if you follow me around.
You're finished at any rate.
Cause all the details of your evil deings are contained in.
What's going on...
Is it a black out?
TLY TA.
PWNS
Oh, the lights turned on again.
Oh, what a scare.
It can't be helped. Sonoko,
because you've experienced a blackout in a building before...
Hey, U's right in int of this shop.
Yeah, what's going on?
There's a crowd out there.
Ms. Mouri and Ms. Suzuki, call the police and an ambulance.
Oh, yes.
What?
Something's written on the envelope he's holding.
[ Ircle, Cross: Triangle?
What's this?
Umm.
A thrust with a knife into his Abdomen.
Yes.
The murdered victim is
Mr. Katsunori Chujo, 43 years old.
Judging from a name card he 'carried,
he is the manager of a private detective agency.
A detective
But what I don't understand is this bizarre dying message.
Oh, no, no, no...
Dying MESSAGE.
Huh?
«Cr J»
Oh, you ares
Yeah,
- 7D -
I'm Jodie Saint Emillion.
Nice to see you again,
Mr. INSPECTOR!
Before you correct his English, improve your Japanese:-first.
But you're one person who really gets involved in all sorts of cases, aren't you?
Yes.
But I'm still no match for them.
Huh?
Oh, you're also here, Ran and Sonoko!
When we were in that coffee shop.
The power suddenly went out.
And just after the lights turned on again,
we heard a woman scream.
Then, we came here and saw the man.
Blackout...
The blackout was caused by a mistake by the building maintenance provider,
while checking the electrical system.
And the blackout lasted onlysfifteen seconds or so.
So, the murderer, taking advantage of the black out that happened by accident,
stabbed Mr. Chujo and ran away.
Meanwhile, Mr: Chujo, just=before dying.
I * 7 C,
But, what's this?
This circle, the cross and the triangle.
They are symbols often used for unprintable words.
Is it possible that fO wrote those symbols
because he did not want to give away the person's name to anyonerd
I have a feeling that I've seen those symbols somewhere before. Wl
What?
Where did you see them?
Oh, please
Remember what they are. Jodie.
Lb bY
Oh! The controller
Those symbols are on the Japanes) PC game controller.
Did it help you at all?
Oh, yeah. I remember this teacher is a PC gamer.
Inspector Megure.
The victim's cell phone log shows someone calledhim thirty minutes ago.
Thirty minutés ago. That's about the time when he was killed
So then why don't you return the call?
Huh?
Oh yeah.
You are the one who called
Mr. Chujo thirty minutes ago, right?
Oh no. I just...
Hey!
Huh?
He might be the guy who was calling back then.
I heard this guy talking about something suspicious.
Let's see. He said. "I'll pay four times as much so come here immediately
or something like that.
Can you help me make sense of it?
Ok, ok. I understand.
I'll tell you everything
I'll explain every thing. I promise.
Oh, your company hired a private detect
to conduct its own internal investigation.
That's right
Last month, we discovered an employee has secretly been embezzling money
from our company.
So, an executive ordered me to find out who it was before informing president.
Where is your company?
Our company occupies the 8th to 11th floor of this building.
Fl SQQ.
You got a call from the detective that he tracked down the emtezzler.
So, you tried to avoid meeting him in the office and arranged to meet him here.
As he didn't shew up atjthe appointed time, you called him, right?
Yes.
As the envelope Mr. Nakajo was holding was empty,
I think the embezzler and the murderer are the same person?
Yeah.
It's quite possible that the embezzler killed the private investigator
and then ran inside into one of the offices upstairs.
But, do you have any idea who the embezzler is?
Oh, no. Last week, the investigator gave me an interim report
that included a list of suspicious employees
Here is the list
In-Inspector Megure.
Whoa. Gee, it'll takexa bit of doing to check then) all.
There are fifty-eight suspects.
rs om
res ¢
There are fifty-eight suspects.
ST Er
The only glues so far are the symbols, a circlO, a cross and a triangle.
Hows intriguing
Inspector Megure!
The fingerprints of Mr. Chujo, who was stabbed to death,
were detected on the symbols written with blood
Ohl sée.
As we expected the blood was Mr. Chujo's
and it also hasn't been long since he wrote them,
SO; there's almost no doubt that he wrote the circle, cross and triangle
as av1clue1or=a* dying...
MESSAGE... .as to identity the murderer.
Very good.
Also it seems that Mr. Ghujo was stabbed before:the black out.
Before the blackout?
Yes.
According to a'witness
the lights went out after a man in a coat stabbed Mr. Chujo.
The spot where he was stabbed is around here, just in front of the escalator,
The blackout started while the two scrambled for his envelope,
When the lights came back on,
Mr. Chujo body moved to the escalator
and was crouched there.
The man in the coat approached him,
pulled something like a deecument out of the envelope and ran up the stairs!
So then, Mr. Chujo wrote the circle, cross and triangle,
here around the bottom of the escalator.
Yes.
He probably wrote them during the blackout
You mean, Mr. Chujo tried to hold on tight to the envelope
but the investigation report about the embezzling was robbed,
So, he died in that position and was brought to the top by the escalator.
But why didn't the witness scream right then and there?
The witness thought they were filming a suspense drama
Anyway, it is almost certain that the murderer is the embez/ler.
All we have to do is solve the mystery of the circle, cross and triangle.
And then we can determine the embezzler
from out of the fifty four suspects.
Don't you think-that the X on the envelope represents
And the circle cross, and triangle represent a mathematical formula?
Huh?
But, why does it have to be a circle, cross and triangle?
If the equation is written the culprit could destroy the evidence
so the culprit camouflaged it by using a circle, cross and triangle.
Oh! I see. So, the murderer must be a mathematician.
Is there an employee who excels at mathematics in your company?
We recruit people who people who excel in liberal arts, on the contrary.
It would look like Oden if it were altriangle, circle, and square.
Hey, maybe the cross stands for that "X"?
Huh
You knowf the cute * v-mark that Ms. Jodie mentioned 'in class.
Huh?
No, no.
No, no it's definitely not that X.
Oh, do you mean the mark the girls often put at the end of letters.
Oh, yes.
2) AARAA
Detective Takagi.
Do you know the meaning of that: X?
I see. So, you must often get those kinds of letters.
Well, no only on rare occasions.
So, what is the meaning of the X then?
It has absolutely nothing to do with the circle, cross and triangle in this case.
Mabe it'ys not just a circle, cross and triangle, but another message.
Huh?
Look carefully and closely at the edge of the envelope on the left side of the circle.
There's a blood stain.
Think there was something else besides the circlO, cross and triangle
Oh, we've already noticed it too.
But there was no matching trace of blood left anywhere
Well, did you check the you know where too?
The steps of his escalator.
This escalator isn't running right now
but when the body was found
It was moving
So another character written with) blood must be hidden behind the escalator
That makes sense.
But since the escalator was moving for quite some time,
don't you think the mark might have been completely wiped out by now?
No problem
The blood will emit hight like magic
if a chemical called mineral or something is sprayed on a spot
Right. Detective Takagi?
XY. yeah,
the luminol solution can detect traces of blood.
Also, pleaseytell this to an ID officer
If he victim wrote the message on a step while bending down bleeding,
the step cam be emit light brighter thanyany other steps.
Th-That's right.
And, just one more thing.
Hmm? What is it?
What's the meaning of the X?
You know, Sonoko and you mentioned a little while ago about it.
Think it's a bit too early for a kid like you to understand something like that yet.
ID officer, could you check an W's?
Inspector Megure.
We've found a coat, a hat and a pair of gloves
that are probably the culprit's.
Oh, great.
Those belongingsshad been left in: the
5th floor's bathroom that is rarely used.
But the document that ha I been stolen from the victim weren't found there
Then.'have yourechecked the suspects' alibis?
Yes, Sir.
We split up and checked therm out.
But unfortunately, at the time of the incident
many employees were either taking a nap or out for supper alone.
So, we could confirm the alibis of only twenty seven out of the fifty eight.
Here are the names of the thirty one people without alibis.
hall 4
We're stillssearching
TORE CRS¢ AP OX WERNER,
concentrating heavily on the floors from
8 to 11, but haven't found them yet.
Concentrating heavily on the floors from
OK. then you continue to search for it.
Y ess
We've narrowed the list down to thirty one suspects.
Yet, that-circle, cross and triangle are'the only clues we have.
Unless we find another character from the step of the escalator...
Inspector, we've found another character written with blood.
What character is that?
Inspector. (as a...
Huh? What is this about?
A square?
It also looks like a Kanji character, mouth or ro of Katakana alphabet
But judging from the previous symbols,
IS most likely to be a square.
Well I'm more confused than ever now.
As its shape matches with the trace of blood on the envelope
this was definitely written by Mr. Chujo.
Isn't that square a little bigger than for Ollie, tore ex] ify
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO_AOYAMA
Original Comic Books By.
GOSH NOYAMA
Producers
MIGHIHIKO SUWA
Background Music
KATSUO ONO
Character 02816115 By
MASATOMO SUDOO
Story Editor.
JUNIGHI 11OKA
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KBUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA v ql ll- 0l!
TOSHIKI INOUE
Aninrition Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKI KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
ZR U Vv uy bh », YY, «vd
NATDYUTUIDITT RUDATY/ADIT
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KEN]! KQDAMA
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD in association with yom! RI PEDecasTING
CORPO ATION
DETECIIVE ONAN
NAONHD AQQYANM Ay SHO GARUKANY IVY IMS O
All 813013 Sesariud
Hello Chiba?
Where are you nowe
All right. Just holdson Ill be right up.
Dr. Agasa said, It's OK to abbreviate something sometimes,
I particularly when you're in a hurry.
Hide it, hurry it up and abbreviate it...
got it.