Suspense and deduction closes the gap between the love and hatred between two people.
Could something like this actually be done?
Shift ways of thinking for a quick and sharp solution
He sees through the one and only truth
A'child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult, no case is left unsolved with Detective Conan
Ran, Pops and I were helped by Michiyoshi
Majima, the president of Kiyama Furniture
when we ran out of gas and got stuck on a mountain pass in Izu
And the President, Mr. Majima invited us to stay at his house.
The house had a Rock Garden.
It was so constructed that
water began to flow and fill the ga den at certain times of the day
As it happened to be the day of the opening of the first store of Kiyama Furniture
other guests also gathered there for a dinner party.
O é Te rr. asayu ir as mo oO, »ecre ary assigned to Mr. Majima,
r. Nobuaki Endo, the president of Kiyama-interior,
and Mr: Tomonori Kiyama, freelance writer were the three guests there.
Though the party goes on, Mr. Majima
Ieaves in the middle of the party...
Mr. Kiyama also goes back te his room.
Then, a quarrel begins and the party soon takes on an ugly mood.
After that, Mr. Hashimoto leaves the dining hall, saying that he's going back to his office.
Mr. Endo and Pops who stays, continues drinking
he following morning
Aughhaaa!
Ma President Majima!
P... President!
You! Keep out!
This is a homicide!
Don't enter the garden.
We've got to preserve the crime scene!
Um... Don't you think there's something strange about his corpse?
Huh? Something strange?
What's strange?
Around the body... there are no footsteps at all!
Really...
So, how did the murderer...
carry Mr. Majima up there?
Mystery of the Japanese
Water Flowing Rock Garden " PART II
What? A scrape... It looks
like something was dragged.
Mr. Mouri! Mr; Mouri!
There you are! Mr. Mouri.
Oh, You're Detective Yokomizo.
It's been a while. But it's kinda funny how
I always run into you in a place like this
The renowned detective should be where puzzling cases are...
Huh... Maybe I should just resign myself to my fate,
Hahahaha!
Aha...
Ha... Anyway, this time again we're counting on your cooperation.
Detective Yokomizo: I've got a report from the coroner.
He died of asphyxiation from strangulation.
Aphroximate time of death last night, between 8 pm. 'and 1 am.
His body was moved shortly after his death
Considering that only parts of the dead body, which were touching the ground, were wet,
his body was most likely carried here after 9 p.m. or later... that is
the time of the crime would've been somewhere between 9 pm. and 1 a.m.
I see. I thought so.
Don't tell me that you've already found the murderer!
There's no such word as unsolved in my dictionary!
Ah! Aretyou for real!
Have you found the murderer!
Who? Who killed the president!
Oh, please ease up.
So, let's héar his explanation first
hem. Well, let me get your a
Iibis straight First, Mr. Kiyama,
you got back to your room after the dinner party, at 8 p.m.
and watched the video which you borrowed from Mr. Endo.
You went for a drive with
Ran and Conan at eleven fifteen,
and came back here at one o'clock after midnight.
Mr. Hashimoto, after Mr. Kiyama left, you went out the hall
at about eight ten and went directly back toxyour office.
Hashimoto-Masayuki
8 LEL*RADY IV La mnEtRANE
And this morning, you picked-up my car and came back here. *
HashimotaMasayuku t: IUD
'Ty 4 Te
Y %38. 171
Hashimoto.Masayuki
I-4) N I ~
2 UB Les IV Lo
MARV
That's right.
Hashimoto.Masayuki
& me »
IRE BZ (37)
II nun-ca: 0 La
MB RWRE
Mr. Endo, you stayed and drank with me until about nine thirty
and after that you stayed in your room until this morning.
There's no doubt about that.
Nobuski Endo
RA £25 OF BE
RB (RA AE7 (45)
Xs FIPHR
What is important here is what Ayaka said
Ayaka finished putting things away and got back to the 'staff room at eight forty-five.
She was stationed in the staff room until two o'clock.
During this time. Mr. Kiyama was the only person who went in and out
of the western style house, to go view the night scenery.
Ayaka Honjou
- MNUad Be
IKE HEM!)
& tLe &
Is that right, Ayaka
Ayaka Honjou
AN LEDS BY
IKE ME (24)
BE on
td Ww
Ayaka Honjou
AMNLadS BY DP
HE ME (24)
DINO»
BX iE 0
Looking around the house, there was no sign
that anyone hadfgone
In or out through-windows.
And it's impossible for anyone to go out
of the house without being seen by \ aka
That is, Mr. Endo, Ayaka and
Mr. Kiyama who were with Ran and Conan
have established alibis.
Which means...
That's right!
So I'll tell-you straight that the murderer is Mr: Hashimoto!
Me...
You...
Mr. Majima bitterly urged you to repay your debt, right?
So... that doesn't...
You left the western-style house, saying that you'd be going back to your office.
You then broke into Mr. Majima's room
and killed him there.
Then you carried his body into this room.
Carried his body into this room?
He used the you know what...
What's this?
It's a catching pole for picking up .objects that have fallen into the garden.
Oh, you must be joking!
Mr. Hashimoto carried
Mr. Majima here tied him up
a top the pole like this.
M-Mr. Mouri?
Just watch!
And Mr. Hashimoto carried the body like this...
Look at you...
Just a bit more...
Mr... Mr. Mouri...
No good, after all...
My only clue is .
The trail that looks
like something was dragged.
There seems to be no signs of tricks built into the rocks in the garden
Damn, how did the murderer carry
Mr. Majima up there
XCcCuse me, e ecive, can we go Now.
Huh?
Mr. Kiyama and I are innocent because we were in the western style house
at the time of the killing, you know.
That's true but...
I say. Mr. Mouri...
Shut up! I'm thinking now, just be quiet!
Detective Yokomizo! I found some thing in the trash can in the dinning hall!
This is!
Mr. Mouri!
If you want me to keep about the accounting gimmick
come up to the rooftop of the western style house with this paper at eleven o'clock
What!
Mr. Mouri...
Mr. Majima was killed not in the main house but maybe at the western style house
But...
Ayaka, did you see Mr. Majima coming up to the western style house?
No... er... uh
Don't tell me you killed Mr. Majima...
No, I didn't!
Ayaka! Please tell us the truth.
LO LL Le aru, vin, ov dainiuiiiila 5 tiauguniet
Oh! Tanuma! Are you sure...
you are the daughter of the driver
who died in the accident with the former president...
Yes, the only reason I started working here was because
LL) because I wanted to confirm a rumor
I heard about Majima having rigged
the car to make it look like an accident
Mr. Endo knew about it...
And it was, I think, around ten forty...
Mr. Endo!
And he said... Give me money
If you don't want
Mr. Majima to know who you are...
I see .
At that time, she was looking at he picture of her father...
Is what she said true, Mr. Endo?
So, can you tell me what time Mr. Endo left?
I think it was a little past eleven.
So, you might not have noticed Mr. Majima coming to the western style house
Maybe not...
Hmm. It all sounds too perfect to be real...
I-I didn't kill him, I swear!
It will be clear before long...
Now, let's go to the rooftop.
™~ - on
Mr. Mouri!
Oh, I can see the garden very well from up here!
Aha! I got it! I khowWho the murderer is!
Se, after all, the criminal 1s
The murderer is Mr. Ende. You!
You went over to Ayaka and closed the curtains,
so that Mr. Majima wouldn't be noticed going up to the roof
You then, went to the roof where Mr. Majima was waiting, and strangled him...
You used what you had set up beforehand
then moved Mr. Majima over to the stone garden
I seat
And, just what did he set up?
Archery!
Huh, hey.
You got ready an arrow with a ring on its rear.
You pulled a long rope through the ring.
Then, you left both ends of the rope with you.
You then shot the arrow into the big tree on the other side of the stone garden!
For you, who were a contestant
Nn the National team,
it must've been an easy feat...
You hung Mr. Majima to that rope and slid him over to the stone garden that way.
But Mr. Mouri if so, wouldn't the rope be left in the garden?
Oh, that's easy.
He tied one end of the rope which he kept at hand to the arrow and
shot the arrow into the grove over the rock garden.
Then the rope would be pulled by the arrow and fly off somewhere.
I'm willing to bet-my career as a private detective on it!
The bow and the arrow that is tied to the rope must be somewhere.
I'm not sure if you should've said that...
We found them!
We found the bow in Mr. End0's room
and the arrow in the grove over the rock garden.
I'm proud of you Dad!
That's impossible...
Strange
If Pop is right, how can the dead body be lying in that way?
But, if he is wrong.
Then how can I explain the bow and the arrows with the rope...
[UA q -
LEIS 1
a ticket to Mr. Kiyvama's photograph exhibition
Why is it in a place like thisp
I see . So, that's the story...
If my deduction is correct,
the killer is still supposed to have the stuff hidden somewhere.
Because that stuff's not so easy to get rid of.
I've found it!
Just as I thought...
All that's left now is the evidence...
What's this stain?
See... I've found conclusive evidence!
I was just about to put on a grand show.
I tell you that Conan...
What could be so important?
Ugh!
Hahhh.
I'll take care of things from here, Pops.
I can tell you that!
I didn't kill him!
OK. OK. I'll hear you out at the police station
Detective Yokomizo...
What's up?
Mr. Mouri said he wanted all of us to gather at the rock garden room
At the Rock Garden room?
He seems to have figured out who the criminal is...
W-What!
Mr. Mouri
What's this supposed to mean?
Mr. Endo is the criminal, isn't he? ...Oh?
That pose is!
Detective!
Just as you said, I was going to kill Majima.
What! I knew it!
But he didn't come. Believe me!
Don't lie to us!
I know, Mr. Endo.
Huh ?
The real murderer is someone else
The true criminal is the person who knew in advance
about your murderous feelings towards
Mr. Endoand took advantage of it.
Don't you think it strange?
If Mr. Endo were the murderer, why would he throw away only the subpoena,
in a separate place from his bow?
True.
The murderer took the subpoena from Mr. Map's room
and threw it away on purpose, to publicize Mr. Endo's plan
And if the dead body were carried from the roof,
No matter how you had him hanging by the rope
it would be impossible for him to be found the way he was, on his stomach,
with his hands and feet in place as they were.
Then, in what way was he carried?
Detective, will you please go and get that.
Yes!
Detective Yokomizo, here is...
An air mattress
Now, what might that mean, Mr. Mouri?
Perhaps the time of the grime was about eight thirty.
That's the time whenfwater begins to flow into the garden!
Exactly!
After water filled with the garden, the murderer
tied the string to the air mattress and set it afloat in the water
after putting the dead body of Mr. Majima on it
Before long, the water began to drain away,
the water level went down and just before the air mattress touched the sand,
the murderer held Mr. Majima's body with the top end of the caching pole
and pulled the air mattress out full force!
That was the way the murderer put the dead body in the middle
of the rock garden without leaving no Marks on the sand!
Incidentally, there is a mark on the surface of the stone,
which was placed on the edge of the rock garden.
Which was placed on the edge of the rock garden.
The ticket probably fell out of his pocket into the water at that time.
The ticket. was stuck
In the water drain
According to the forensics,
This scratch was made by the decorative button of his trousers.
Mmm... So, who is the murderer?
Im 'sure the murderer panicked when we decided-suddenly to-spend the night here
If Mr. Endo canceled his plan, everything would go down the drain...
So, the murderer tried to take us outside at the time Mr. Endo called Mr. Majima
Ah! Don't tell me
The murderer is the one who took Ran and the others out and
and made Mr. Endo carry out the murder plan.
It's you, Mr. Kiyama!
After he left the dinning hall Mr. Kiyama didn't, go back-to-his-room-but...
went to the main house and killed Mr. Majima.
As Ayaka was still in the dinnin Thall* he didn't have to worry about being observed
After he put the dead body in the rock garden, Mr- Kiyama patiently waited
for Mr. Endo to close the curtains in the staff room where Ayaka. was.
That is, Mr. Endo tried to hide Mr. Majima from view but,
in fact, in doing so, he helped
Mr. Kiyama carry out the crime...
ee... then the-mattress.
Yes. We've found in Mr. Kiyama's room.
Wait a minute!
This Is a setup!
And the criminal put the air mattress in my room in order to put the blame on me!
Are you sure it doesn't look familiar?
Of course-not! I've never see an air mattress like this!
It sounds odd to me.
Huh?
Mr. Kiyama, could you take a closer look at the mattress again?
Yeah. This is the ink of your father's keepsake fountain pen
that you always carry on you.
Hahaha... I didn't expect that the ink splattered even over the mattress.
I wiped off all the spattered-ink.
But how come?
Majima would've been killed anyway by
Mr. Endo even if you didn't do it...
I just happened to over hear...
the guy proudly telling his story in a very amusing way
Majima rigged the brakes and made my father fall to his death.
While I was away, took the seat as president and took over my father's corporation
When I found out about it, I swore...
I was gonna kill that him someday.
So. Mr. Endo provided a wonderful opportunity for me to kill'him.
You know, it created a perfect opportunity to offer the dead body
as a sacrifice to the rock garden my father loved.
Original Comic Books By.
GOSH AOYAMA
Producers
MIGHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDQ
Story Editor.
JUNIGHI 11OKA
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYACHITA
» 'Y } h >» »,
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Dircctors.
MA ATOMO SUD
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography.
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWACGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KEN]! KODAMA
F y 1 cf 9 y
IN $sotrationpMths
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE XeON AN
(GIST) AY AAT (y S410) AURA ANYIN CIT MS
A Rag hits Reserved
Oh, out of gas again...
C'mon Dad, I've heard enough about your Oh, out of gas!
What're we gonna to do now, on a mountain path like this!
Hey, easy does it.
Perhaps a president may happen to pass us again and invite us to his office
I have a feeling that I'm gonna be able to drink tonight again!
Gah-ha-hahaha...
You never learn...
What? The heroine of a movie?
You mean, me?
Y-You should take it, Ran!
The challenging spirit is what counts!
Al love scene?
Dont do it after all.
«a -Right-you're not cut out for that kind of stuff.