The distance between love and hate is filled as the two solve mysteries together.
Is there such case?
You can't recycle crime!
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult
no case is left unsolved with Detective Conan.
On that day, we set off to Akebonocho in order to arrest a serial thief
Conan, let's catch the thief no matter wat it takes, okay!
Y-Yeah
But.
Doesn't it feel A bit eerie?
To have other people take over and use what can still be used
cherishing what limited resources we have. I'd say it's a splendid arrangement.
Oh, you mean recycling.
But, you don't know who the stuff was being used by previously, you know.
Right, Conan?
No need for worry.
Because there is nobody who rubs snot on everything like you do, Genta.
You really do, Genta?
Y-You rat!
What a thing to say!
< O Tu
Stop it, don't touch 'me!
Oh, there's the bus headed for Akebonocho
On, right!
The Victim Returns
It sure is quiet...
Th 7&'s nobody in sight...
Maybe that's why the thief targets this area
If you see any suspicious
looking people, be careful
Ah gee, what the heck am I doing...
Is it that room!
Wait up. Conan!
What's going on?
Excuse me!
Is it okay conan?
This
The cause of death is cerebral contusion from
being hit in the back of his head with a blunt object.
The estimated time of death is between
2:00 pm to 3-004 yesterday.
He had nothing on him that would help us identify him
Ms. HOsSONO...
willyyou please explain in detail the condition in which you found the corpse.
Yes, sir...
That sofa, is what I bought yesterday at sundown at a recycle shop at Beikacho.
And I had it delivered here at about 10:00 this morning.
By the way, after taking a good look, the sheet was a little out of place
so I attempted to put it back in place...
I found that lady inside the sofa...
I see, and do you have any idea who the victim is?
Not at all...
Where were you yesterday between the hours of 14:00 and 15.007?
A-Are you suspecting me?
No, no, it's just routine procedure to ask
I was at the movies yesterday afternoon!
Was somebody else with you?
I went alone...
I wonder if Inspector
Megure suspects her.
Yeah...
There are two things that-are~thinkable.
Ms. Sanae Hosono killed the victim and
made it look like the corpse was inside the sofa that was delivered.
The other is, a sofa with the corpse inside it is delivered just like she said
But when:we over there she really looked surprised and pale!
It didn't look like she was putting on an act at all!
Right.
Yeah.
It's the job of the police to consider all possibilities.
But .
Inspector, the old lady's ashoes werelalso inside the sofa
I wonder why she washst wearing her shoes?
When she was killed, she was probably not wearing her shoes.
I see! Which means she was killed in the room.
If she is the killer, the site of the crime is in this room
Officer Takagi go and question the neighborhood!
YES'; SM
Inspector...
What, the room next door?
Excuse me, may I ask your name?
1. Tokunaga...
Did something happen?
Well, at your next door neighbor, Ms Hosono's room
a corpse was found in the sofa.
What?
And, Mr. Tokunaga, were, ou in your room
between the hours of 14:001015:00 yesterday?
I-work in the evening...
Around 15:00 did you hear any strange sounds or voices from next door?
Please try to remember.
C-Come to think of it,
I sort of heard somebody arguing
You heard somebody arguing?
Y-Yes...
And, what was the argument about?
Oh, all right, thank you.
I think I'll be asking you about it againilater
Yes, sir.4
I wonder if what he said just now, is true...
It's sort of hard to believe, isn't it?
The thing about her going to the movies seems to be a lie
Inspector...
What is it?
I would like to go ask around the recycle shop.
I got curious on what the children was talking about
Officer Takagi
Okay,
Yeah, please do so then.
Yes, sir!
Oh, that se>fa...
It's an item that we bought from a customer yesterday.
Yesterday?
You mean you bought it and put it out for sale right away?
Yes, we put the items that we purchase out for sale right 3 ay.
That way, we can sell the item for a cheaper price
What about after
Ms. Hosono bought it?
It was here right through till closing time
Then it was loaded on the truck for delivery.
A oN °
S ere any possiianity ra someone from outside can get near the truck?
That's impossible because the truck
IS parked inside the warehouse
And, of course, the warehouse is locked
Oh, is that so.
Which means...
That the old lady was in there already when it was purchased...
Does that mean that the previous owner of that sofa is the killer
The fact is, that sofa is not something that we bought from a customer
What?
But, Mr. Hirose, I thought you said
that you were told to take the sofa, even if it were for free
I'm sorry, yesterday afternoon, on the way back
after I went to purchase items in several places in town,
I think it was around 16:00...
What's the matter Mr. Hirose?
Look at that, what a waste...
It still looks very usable
You can say that again...
You picked it up at a trash dump that youlhappened to pass?
Right
But manager. I felt it so wasteful to be thrown away
like that when it still
looked so usable, so I...
I'm sorry I lied...
Well, I do understand your feelings of wanting to cherish things.
But, if you picked it up from a trash dump
We have no idea who the Killer is.
Right...
But, Officer Takagi.
Yea hr>
It's hard to think that the Killer carried the corpse a long wayYisnt it?
Wait a minute...
Where is the trash dump that you picked that sofa up from?
If I'm not mistaken. I think it was...
Akebonocho 3-chome
Akebonocho!
We're back-where we started...
In other words, that old lady
Yeah, left here about 16:00 yesterday, and via the recycle shop.
Came back to the original place about 10:00 this morning.
I'm sure the killer is living somewhere near here
but howgdo we go about looking for the killer...
Besides, why did the killer put the body into a sofa in the trash dump?
Why else!
Right, the killer didn't think that anyone
would pick up a sofa that was thrown away.
Oh, there you go again Conan with your "buts"
It's a bad habit of yours of not
looking at the situation as is.
Talk for yourself...
Mr. Tokunaga was a little creepy.
I saw him at that family restaurant this morning,
where he was drinking and all smiles.
So he smiles?
He always looks so super square.
So, something really good must've happened?
Tiokunaga...
He's the one that we saw this morning) right.
Ms. Sanae Hosono's next door neighbor.
What're you doing 'here?
Inspector Megure!
What're you doing here, Inspector Megure?
I came to tell Ms. Hosono that her alibi's been backed up.
Wa trad
But, if so...
Voice that Mr. Tokunaga said he heard, must've been a mistake or something
A mistake?
The thing is, while we were tracing the source of where the sofa came from,
we ended back to where we started...
There is no mistake about the fact that the victim was put inside the sofa here.
I'll go look for a witness.
Yeah, do that will you.
I got it!
I figured out who the killer is!
Are you rious. Mitsuhiko?
Yes!
Mr. Tokunaga's testimony about having
heard an argument is probably not a mistake!
But! just a while ago.
Inspector Meglite
So, the killer is Mr. Tokunaga!
What!
He's theakiller?!
It's just as those
Iadies were saying after all!
This morning, that man called Tokunaga seemed to be in a super good mood.
So, my deduction's been backed up.
Mr. Tokunaga must be the suspect!
Conan, when a killer wants to hide the corpse,
The killer doesn't want anyone / to find the corpse, rights?
If the body is found, the victim will be identified.
And the people who are around the victim will be theroughly checked.
The hands of the police will eventually reach the killer...
The corpse is hidden to prevent this.
Exactly.
But if the killer really wants to hide the body,
the body could be buried in the mountains, OF sunk into the sea.
However, why didn't the Killer do so this time?
Yeah, that's the point's that hards to understand...
Right...
There is only one answer.
The killer wanted to go hide the corps in the mountains this time too.
But, the killer had reasons for not being able 6.go.
So, what was the
Killer's reason for not doing $07?
He was saying that.
He works in the evening
That's why he couldn't go far to hide the body!
I see, adults can't ta 3 off from work so
Right, Officer Takagi?
Yeah...
That's why the killer hid the corpse inside the sofa for the time being.
For the time being?
The Killer was goingfto threw it away somewhere after coming back from work!
Yes, the killer was going to throw it away somewhere
after coming, back from work!
Before the killer could get to the sofa
the truck of the recycle shop had already taken the sofa away!
Right!
I'm sure the killer was surprised when he got home from work.
Because the sofa had suddenly disappeared.
And after he was surprised, delight filled his heart
Because after all someone had taken care of the corpse for him
He was spared the trouble of getting rid of the corpse himself
Unable to hold back his joy, he went to celebrate on his own.
However, when he got back to the condo.
He found out the worse had happened
The corpse that had disappeared somewhere
Was found) in the room next 1 his
But the killer who finds that the police suspects Sanae Hosono.
The one who first finds the corpse, remarks...
C-Come to think of it I heard the voices of people arguing
It was no mistake, but rather a lie to frame Sanae up as the killer.
Everything falls right into place, Mitsuhiko!
Wow!
Nah, it's really no big deal
What's the matter, Conan?
Even if the killer had to go to work
why did he have to go out of the way to move the corpse?
If he left it in his room until he got back, nobody would've seem hims right:
Now that you mentioned it
What did we come here to Akebonocho today for in the first place?
To arrest the serial thief that's been raiding the houses in this vicinity, right?
The killer was afraid that the thief would break into his house!
I see! If the thief breaks in and finds the dead old lady,
the police may be contacted!
Exactly!
That's why he couldn't
NO MO He Er) ad Doel
Ieave it in the house!
That won't do after all, Mitsuhiko.
OO SN TX
. omy
Think about it...
The possibility of someone witnessing him hiding the corpse
is higher than the possibility of a thief breaking into his house
don't you think?
Besides, will he really be happy
when he finds out that the sofa where the corpse is hidden disappears?
Think it would be more natural for him to worry
that it may have been discovered by the police, don't you?
Besides, it wouldn't hurt to day a day
O romwor, I Orjus acay.
In other words, deducing Mr. Tokunaga
as being the killer is all an illusion created in your head. Mitsuhiko!
This is homicide~ilet"sithin about it more seriously: okay?
Just who his the one that is overtaken by illusion?
Although you say, normally this and normally that,
I'm sure there a people who get anxious over thieves breaking into their houses.
I'm sure there are people who think themselves
Iucky about the corpse disappearing too, don't you?
If someone who had never taken a day off from work does so,
the people around him may get suspicious
Therefore, he may go to work as usual.
That's possible too, isn't it?
According to the manager of the condo.
It seems that Mr. Tokunaga is running a small pub in the neighboring town.
It seems he's having a tough time,
but he seems to be running the pub without resting even one day
the manager also commented that
Mr. Tokunaga is a square and timid{personality...
It's just a Mitsuhiko had portrayed him
Since he has to make preparations
I before opening the shop.
It seems he always goes out around this time.
15:00...
But, no matter how timid,
I wonder if he would be afraid of a thief that he's not sure will break in or not?
This is the Aekbono Police Stati fh.
Serial break ins have been reported in this area,
so please be sure to
Iock your doors when going out
This is the. Aekbono Police Station.
Hey!
Please stop!
This is Officer Takagi from police headquarters!
Did you patroldthis area yesterday too?
Yes, sir.
But maybe yesterday we patrolled this area about 10 minutes earlier than today.
Officer Takagi!
Yeah, so, that's the story!
Mr. Tokunaga, was probably panicky after killing the victim and heard
the voice from this police car...
This is the Akebono Police Station.
Serial break ins have been reported in this area.
Therefore, you were frightened and hid the corpse
inside the sofa that you found in the trash dump nearby
Isn't that right. Mr. Tokunaga?
Owed that old lady money...
And I asked her to wait just another week for me to pay her back...
Then, she came to my condo and yelled
at me saying that if I didn't pay her back by the date due,
she would take this shop away from me...
That's why I...
That's why I,
Iost my temper and...
1.I'm sorry
Mr. Tokunaga, please come to the station with me
Yes, sir
You?did it. Mitsuhiko!
Gr 'at!
Good deduction work Mitsuhiko, thanks to being free of preconceived opinions.
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
wv (HTH «1-534 WA
Wigan Tas oY Iv PKA
Background Must
KAI " '0 ONO
Charact r Designs By
M SATOMO SUDO
Story Editor:
Scripts By
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
AZUNARI KOUCH
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
CHI HIG
OSHI 1 INOUE
Animation DiFectors
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA yo TET ey
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONQBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chet Director.
KEN}! KODAMA
Produced By.
TMSIENTERTAINMENT,). LTD
I association with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CC NAN
0 AOYAMA HOCGCAKUKAN YTV
All RY WReverved
What?
The thief who had been breaking into house
in Akebonocho was-arrested long time ago?
Yeah [last week a man was arrested h charges of theft,
and when checked for fOrther'crimes, confessed.
Oh boy.
We were all out to get him and then!
What a bummer,
I even 168t out on bus fare!
Which means that Mr.
Tokunaga didn t have tolgo out
of the way to hide the corpse in the sofa at the trash dump?
Yeah, if he left the corpse inside his room,
maybe the case would've never come to light.
He sure is an unluc \ character isn't he?
You can say that again.
Gee, it's a homicide case-and no laughing matter...
Excuse me is Ms. Ujo that Ms. Ujo!
Ms. Ujo the number 1 nicest actress!
That means we get to see Ms. Ujo in person?
It's the real deal!
The Unseen Suspect
Part 1