OP ve Fresns
Loop HTT,
Deduction flows with the rhythm of the wind
Deduction: flows with the rhythm of the wind
Dark stains are rinsed clean and exposed
The seven tiered festival doll set.
And the mystery of the robber who stole it.
He sees through the one and only truth,
A-child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult
no case is left unsolved with Detective Conan.
<S>
(K's;
- < - * - ow (1
SOgc B
8 (»O Yeo
em Dy
Ve om aw§da
Look, look at that hina doll!
How beautiful!
Oh, so Girls' Day Festival is » right around the corner...
I always cat eel!
I really like that Hina doll
But, you've already got a nice one at home, Ayumi
Hey, did you forget?!
Last year you dropped the girl hina doll and its hands and
eck broke off, right?
Oh, that's right!
I'm sorry, Ayumi
But, I guess you can have it repaired.
Of course she did.
But while the craftsman was repairing the
doll he got hurt and blood splattered on the face of the doll.
When the doll was finally repaired,
Peach the dog next: door brought the neck of the doll to Ayumi when she got home
But, the paint that was used to cover the blood on the face was peeled off,
its hair was disheveled and it was wearing a dreadful facial expression
Hey, hey, hey!
Seriously, that doll is cursed!
Yes, ever since then the doll set was securely packed away in a box
By Ayumi's father who was worried a 1e CO SS may bring upon mis or une.
I hear that Wt is still way deep inside the closet...
It's not cursed...
Peach brought the doll to me wanting to show it to me as soon as possible
And, the neck of the doll just happened to fall off then...
<< 7\
Hey, Ayumi!
/11)
Don't cry
ec we
477 )
Just playing
Peach's owner asked an acquaintance of his for me,
so that person is going to give me a set of
Girls' Festival dolls that she
Isn't using anymore!
It has seven rows of dolls and is
Iarger than the one I had!
She says I could have the doll set if I can
Iine them up correctly without
% looking at anything for reference!
But you'd have to line up quite a number
% of dolls if the set has Seven rows to it
Can you handle it alone?
I'll be just fine, because I memorized how the dolls are line up over and over!
And besides, I'm not going to do it alone.
QG-BET),
Girls' Festival Dolls in the Sunset"
Part 1
Oh, hi, Ayumi!
So, did you memorize how the dolls are to be lined up?
You didn't look too confident whenryou came last time so...
Yep, no problem!
Okay, then I guess I'll have you line them up right now
Are these all boxes with dolls in them?
Why do you have to memorize how the dolls are supposed to be lined up, though?
Because she thinks that
Ayumi's going to make a mistake
The fact is, she doesn't want to give it away.
That's not exactly it.
We're just checking to see if she's a girl that will take good care of the dolls
Learning to line the dolls up correctly
will give rise to more affection towards the dolls, no?
After all, they are very precious dolls that were bought for me.
I wish you luck then, little lady!
Okay!
Oh, Genta, that's not right.
The man with the
bow and arrow belongs more to the top!
Yeah, but the more the merrier!
No! You've«got to line them upicorrectly
And, while you're at it, that old man is the
minister of the left andWbelongs on the fourth step to the very right.
0 be 1000?
The young one that looks a loteO
like him is the minister
of the right and belongs on the same step to the very left,
so don't get them wrong!
The left belongs to the right and the right belongs to the left...
You know so much despite being a boy.
I helped Ran a ot when I was a kid,
You used to line them up when you, were a kid too, didn't you?
Oh, didn't I tell you?
I was sent off to the States to study as early as I can remember
so this is the first time I'm even touching these dolls...
It seems my parents got my older sister Girls' Festival dolls but,
my parents died soon after I was born too, so
Besides, my sister never took the dolls
out because they brought back sad memories...
Hey, how did your parents die?
Well, it seems that my sister was told
that they died of an accident during some research they were doing
Come to think of it,
I remembernthat Visco once mentioned that your parents were scientists
Yess although my mother was not all that well known
My father. Atsushi Miyano seems to have been pretty well-know in the field
as a mad scientist who was ousted from academic circles
As a mad scientist?
Hey, what the heck are you talking about?
You developed that drug because you took
over what your parents were doing, didn't you?
Just what kind of drug was it?
A secret drug...
A secret drug that's used to revive the dead...
Will this answer satisfy you?
Then, don't tell me that, the stuff that was written in the diary was...
Just as I thought
The thing you were looking at on the
computer the other day was a clue to those people, wasn't it?
And after you traced the clue, you found out where they stopped by but,
aside from what you expected, while you were waiting for them, you overslept,
I guess the ston went something like this
Yeah, well, sort of...
Well, you don't have to worn
The goal of my research has nothing to
do with making a dream-like drug like that.
Most of the people here on earth would find
no value in the stuff
I'm involved in now
It's like the Girl's Festival dolls that are important
LL ABA va only for the girls of this small country...
Iet's go from thé3top, the Emperor, the Empress
Three Court Ladies, the Five
Musicians, the two guardians
the Minister of the Left and Minister of the Right
O And on the fifth step are the
Three Pages expressing
the human emotions of
Iaughter, worry and anger!
You've passed with flying colors!
Then, are you going to give me this doll-set?
Yes, I'll have it delivered to you by courier right away!
All right!
Make sure you thank grandma later, okay?
Okay!
Shall we start cleaning up, then?
We went out of our way to line them up,
and we're going to, put them-away already?
It can't be helped, because it has to be packed to send out
Oh, wait! Let's all take a picture in front of it first!
I brought daddy's digital camera with me!
Okay, 'here goes
Say cheese!
My. I wonder who it is?
Oh, Mr. Tsumagari of room 503.
Hello.
If it's about that thing, I'm sure my husband already refused.
Yes, but I just can't give it up.
I brought an appraiser with me today, and I thought I'd ask him one more time.
How do you do?
This way, please
This is really something
his is a fine Hina doll set
A famous doll craftsman in
Kyoto seems to have made it.
How much will you sell it to me for?
Are you buying these dolls?
Too late, mister!
They were already given to Ayumi!
No, I don't have a daughter so
I'm not interested in dolls!
What I want her to sell me is the hanging scroll behind all of you.
That's the Thunder God that was drawn by
an artist of the Edo era named Tetsuyama.
I have the Wind God which is the other half of this hanging scroll,
and I really want to make it a complete set.
But, my husband says he has no intention of selling it,
and besides, it doesn't
look to be something so valuable
Don't you know?
How valuable that hanging scroll is!
Do you have any idea how much insurance
your husband's late father placed on it?
Well, no...
20,000,000 yen, 20,000,000 yen!
That much?
I told your husband that I would pay him double that.
Besides, I feel sorry for this hanging scroll.
If kept in this manner, the value of this scroll will go down
I think it'd be wiser to sell it to a
professional collector like
Mr. Tsumagari.
But my husband...
We will not sell it.
No matter how much money you dish out for it.
Mother...
Okay. I'll be back again tonight just about the time your husband comes home
I'm sure he'll agree to sell it.
If I mention the story about him making a great loss in stocks
Let's put away the dolls and hurry on home too, then
How nostalgic, it's already been
10 years since we last decorated them.
The dolls look happy that they were
taken out of the box after such a long time too
Mother...
Ayumi, would it be okay to decorate
these dolls here until Girls' Day Festival this year?
I guess mother wants to say goodbye to them.
Sure!
But, can I stay here a while longer then?
Because I have one more picture I want to take...
Why don't you have mother serve you some sweet sake then!
I thought we were out of the ingredients to make it from scratch?
This is troublesome.
I have to go out soon too
I'll go buy it then!
The supermarket is right there!
Thank you very much!
Ayumi, isn't it about time you tell us?
Just what do you want to take a picture of?
Just what do you want to take a Ricture of?
A picture of all of us having a good time!
We just took one like that a while ago!
Something even better.
Which way was it?
This way.
Okay, just a little while more to go!
Come on, let's go
Oh, okay!
I think it was just around this corner...
Isn't that the appraiser?
I thought you went home?
Well, I forgot my cell phone
I called my cell phone, then the lady
answered and told me that it's in the living room.
She told me I could get it when I go over tonight,
but I may get important phone calls so
I decided toe pick it up now.
But, it seems that no one's home...
You mean grandma isn't home?
Oh, he's right, nobody's home...
NO one is here...
Hey, the door's not locked!
I wonder if grandma went to sleep?
What is this sound?
I think it's the sound of the fax machine.
It's coming from this room...
What the heck is going on!
The room is super messed up!
The fax seems-to be from her husband
Hey everyone.
That doesn't seem to be the only place.
Burglary. A burglar broke in after we left
By the looks of it, maybe the other rooms are messed up as well.
Ayumi!
I'm glad the dolls are fine!
This room looks untouched.
I wonder where grandma is, though?
It seems that grandma's not the only one who disappeared!
Take a look
The hanging scroll of the
Thunder God is gone too.
Let's call the police right now!
Call the police!
G-Grandma?
Oh, so I did miss you, after all.
Where were you grandma?
Well, when I looked I found out that I had also run
out of sugar, so I went to buy some.
By the way, why are you all
looking pale faced about?
W-Well, the thing is.
Setsuko, I thought you went out...
I forgot my wallet so
I came back to get it...
The bedroom's...
Oh, my!
Oh, so we were just about to call the police.
- Iv.
M-Mr. Tsumagari!
What happened?
I heard somebody scream.
Oh, well, the thing is...
A burglar, a burglar broke in .
Let's talk after the police get here.
I see, so from what a gather here,
those children came here to decorate the Hina dolls; and after that,
Mr. Tsumagari who extremely-wanted the hanging scroll thatflwas stolen,
brought appraiser, Mr. Mie with him...
Officer, please don't say it like that.
And after the two men left, you five went out shopping.
Yeah, to buy the ingredients for making sweet sake!
Ingredients for sweet sake?
Mother was going to make sweet sake for everyone,
when I realized that we were out of the necessary ingredients
Since I had to go out,
I asked the children to go get it.
After that you were here alone,
Grandma Yayoi?
Yes, exactly...
Did you notice anything then?
Like strange noise.
It was quiet, until the cell phone that he forgot in the living room rang.
Y-Yeah...
Oh, you forgot your cell phone in the living room?
We were shown into the living room first,
because the children were in the Japanese room
But, we wanted to see the hanging scroll as soon as possible,
so forced our way immediately into the Japanese room.
And, after the phone call you seem to have gone out shopping too, but for what?
I went out to buy sugar.
I realized that we were out of sugar so I rushed out to get some.
Do you know about what time it was?
Well, it was right after I hung up so...
Then, can tell what time it was.
Just before I hung up. I heard the sound of the FAX on the other side of the line,
so if we look at the time the FAX was sent, we can find out what time it was!
Who was the FAX from?
I think it was from my husband...
Then where is that original FAX?
In the living room.
My gosh, they really went all out messing up the room
So this is the FAX you received from your husband
3:218 PM.
What else was stolen besides the hangingrscroll?
Nothing. Only hererand the bedroom were ransacked.
Even the wallet that was on the shelf above the TV was left untouched.
May I have a minute with you, Officer Momose?
It seems that the burglar broke in from the veranda facing this window,
Just as I thought...
Why do you think that this is the way the burglar broke in?
We're on the 6th floor, you know!
It's a common target for burglars who use a rope to get down from the roof
They seem to think that people living on the top floor of condos are rich,
and most times the windows aren't locked anyway
You sure know a lot, don't you Au!
Yes, because ll live with an old man who likes to watch wide shows on TV.
If I'm not mistaken, you're the first ones
who realized that the room was ransacked?
Yeah, when we got back from shopping the front door was unlocked.
And when we heard the sound of the FAX machine and came into the living-room,
It was all messed up! At that time the clock on the FAX was 15:40!
Which means that the burglary took place between
15:30 and 15:40 a period of 10 minutes
I wonder...
The burglar went down on the veranda and came in through thatswindow, rights.
If it were me,
I'd be tooascared to come in.
If you close the window, nothing is in view from the veranda because of the curtain.
F the burglar opens the window wanting to look inside,
the curtain would flutter in the wind, and the lady on the phone would notice.
And, besides the time thezEAX was sent out all show 15728!
Which means that the FAX kept coming
in all-the while we were out shopping until we came back, right?
Do you think a burglar would break
into airoom where noise is constantly coming from?
But, it's just the sound of the FAX...
The more so frightening because it's the FAX!
Because if the FAX completes coming in and the buzzer sounds
somebody in the house may come to take a look at it!
I see...
Beside, it's strange that the burglar didn't notice her wallet and
if the burglar couldn't find what he was after,
wouldn't all the other rooms be ransacked too?
True...
The strangest thing is, why only the hanging scroll was stolen .
But, that hanging scroll is worth 20:000,000 yen!
You fool, only a professional would know if that scroll is really worth that price
Which means that the burglar knew that the scroll was here to begin with.
«> <O »
Yeah, but if the burglar was after the scroll,
\ = 49 . wed Pp
\Q- fl) the other room wouldn't have beenyransacked
Maybe the burglar messed up the other room just to throw people off,
so that he's not suspected.
Which means that the culprit has no definite alibi and on top of that had to face
the police reluctantly after the incident.
Furthermore, that person knows the value of that hanging scroll.
Come to think of it, you were loitering -around
in front of this house, weren't you?
I just told you, didn't I?
That I came to get my cell phone, but nobody was home
But, the door wasn't locked!
Well...
Did you lock the door when you left the house?
Well, I think I did, but I was in a rush so...
By the way, why were you at the front door a while ago, mister?
I came to check things out because
Mr. Mie didn't come back for some time.
Were you all here?
Then, he also knew that you forgot your cell phone, right?
Yes...
Yes, he did, since he was by me until
I started talking to grandma
You mean you left while he was on the phone?
LI just went to buygsome cigarettes!
In other words, just as this child just said, you two do not have an alibi yet.
Hey, hey, will you cut out just suspecting us!
Those two are going to get 20,000,000 yen too if insurance money comes in!
I'm just saying that even you two can carry out something like this!
W-W-What a thing to say!
We sure are in a fix. All four of you have motives, no alibi and
on top of that all of you are capable of carrying out the crime
The key to nailing down the culprit is in the Japanese room!
Original Comic Books By.
Producers.
IIHIKO .
Background Music
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By
MASXTQMO sum)
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HICURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animition Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
TSUSHI AON
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKA HI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chicf-Director.
KEN] KODAMA
Produced By.
TMSSENTERTAINMENT: LTD.
11ssotidtion with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE ( ONAN
COMO AOYAMAY SHOGARURKAN YTV - IMS
All RIEH Reserved
Hey, Conan...
Did you figure out who the culprit as?
Oh, sorry, I'm in the process of thinking now...
But we better hurry or the steps will...
But the steps
Thank Ayumi!
I solved thee mystery!
GirlsFestivalrDollssin thesSunset"
Part?