Deduction flows with the rhythm of the wind
Dark stains are rinsed clean and exposed
The abducting case; ransom money.
What has happened in the tunnel?
He sees through the one and only truth,
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult
no case is left unsolved with Detective Conan.
LI - >
7 -e>2
The Kidnap Car that Disappeared
Part 1
nis 7
GREET),
The Kidnap Car that Disappeared"
Part 1
Yeah, I thought that
Yaiba was going to lose yesterday
What a thing to say!
He missed his Yaiba kick.
Jun!
Hello!
How's it.-Jun! .
How's your broken bone
You don't look too happy.
I They're Jun's classmates...
They always come to visit him
They're Jan's classmates...
Is tht so, thank you so much!
It's rothing. fight?
W-We're friends so...
You two are always like that when you see prettt women
How disgusting!
Don:t you think so?
Hey! Jun, I didn't know you had an older sister.
Did you call me his Older sister?
Oh! Yes!
My. how flattering.
She's Ms. Sachiko Ezaki, a fashion designer.
A-A fashion designer?
Wow!
Did you come to visit Jun?
Yes!
Nic ) meeting you all!
Come over to my place someday!
You're all very welcomed to come!
- . Place?
Jun:s house!
J-Jun's? What do you mean?
- - She-means...
think you'd better go already!
Isn't it time for your fashion show recital to start?
Oh, right.
We'd better get going then
Okay.
See you, Jun
Since Jun. *-'looks bored. please spend as much time as "Ou can with hiff]
Goodbye.
Jun, you'll be discharged tomorrow.
Hang in there just one more day, okay.
< ) << Dp
Is that person called Ezaki
Going to become your new mother?
How nice that such a pretty person's
going to be your mother.
My mother who died was) much prettier!
She's just marrying daddy because
she wants his estate.
Estate?
Right.
Because I heard them
What?
For me?
I'm so happy
Thank you!
How do I look?
They look nice! And, when shall we hav the wedding?
Please wait a little while more.
Until the February show is over.
Are you saying you want to put all your energy into the show?
Yes. I want to succeed this time no matter what...
If I don't make it again this time,
I'm going to give up my career as a fashion designer! My minds made-up
Okay!
I'm sorry.
J It's okay. By the way. about this show, do you have enough cash? If you need some
I'm fine! If I ever need any, I won't
IGSIGG 08$ YOU Of 16p
So. please be prepared!
Keep it within reasonable range now!
Jun! Aren't you
taking everything too negatively?
A pretty person like her could never...
Genta!
I understand how you feel...
Revulsion against your new mother?
G-Game corner
You know the one, where the supermarket in Haidocho is?
From now . a;
Please just once!
I always wanted to go!
But, you're still not fullysrecovered...
I'm just fine, fine.
The cast is just for show. I'm doing just fine See! Watch!
Even if-'you say that.
Are you sure you're okay?
You can go after you're discharged from the hospital tomorrow, right?
No way. impossible
It would never happen
As soon as I'm discharged I'll have to study with my tutor,
Ilalso. have piano and english lessons,
I don't have time for games
sp Fr.
Well, I've always felt sorry fory '1 behind the scenes
So. please!
Today's the only chance I have.
If we can back here in two hot Ts in time for the
12:00 rounds that the doctor makes they'll never & O miss me
H-Hey! What do you think, Conan?
In order to leave the hospital. first, you'd have to go past the nurse station
And, I'm pretty sure that a male nurse will come by and check the room
So. as long as somebody sleeps in bed in place
Hey! Hey! That's absurd...
Come on, we're friends,
Iet's help him.
Yeah, please!
Jun"s pleading with us too...
If we ignore his wish, it'll make a bad name for the
Youth Detective Squad!
Well, Conan?
Youth Detective Squad
Okay...
Thank you
Shall we decide by stone, paper, scissors. then, Conan?!
What? Stone, paper, scissors?
What's 'with him...
Conan is really weak when it comes to stone; paper, scissors...
We don't have time=let'sshurry!
Let's have eels over rice on the way home!
If yourre treating us. Genta!
Yeah!
Well, go enjoy yourselves to your heart's content
Jun?
J:Jun?
Hey! Hey!
Jun's bed is empty, but do you have any idea where he went?
No...
Come to think of it, a bunch of children-came to see him
Shall-l go-look for them?
It's me, Yoshizawa!
I kidnapped the kid named Jun.
It's going just as you planned.
Now, yeah, he's fast asleep.
Where is this?
What happened...
So, you're up, sonny?
Get out!
Hurry it up!
What's with you.
You can't move yet?
Where is this?
WwW. What're you going te do to me?
Hey...
Nothing much. We're just going to ask your dad for ransom.
You mean I was kidnapped?
Well, I guess so.
Good! OK! That's it.
Do the same for tonight's show!
Let's take a-break till then!
Fantastic! No mistake you're going to join the circle of top class designers now
I sure hope so...
Believe in your ability.
Yes, this is Kataoka.
What?
J-Jun's been?
Yes! Okay, I'll head over there right away.
Jun, is something wrong?
It seems he disappeared from the hospital...
What! I.I'll go with you.
No, I'll go to the hospital alone.
You've got an important show to take care of.
But...
I'm sure everything's okay! He probably went out to play some place nearby
There's nothing to worry about!
I'll get in touch with you later!
He hasn't gone home, and I've had the nearby area checked but
Do you have any idea where else he could be?
I wonder, his leg is hurt, so I don't think he can go that far...
S-Sachiko!
Did you out where Jun is?
Sachike, go back to the show site!
Leave Jun to us: What's most important to you now is...
Jun is more important than the show.
I won't go back until I know he's safe!
Officer Sato!
How was it?
I asked the nurses,
It seems that the classmates who came to see him were Conan and the others
Conan and his friends?
All four of them seem to have come" together and gone home together
Oh, which means he didn't go out with them...
T-This is Kataoka...
You kidnaped Jun?
\ If you want your kid back.:get
30.000.000 yen in old bills ready!
H-How's Jun? Is Jun okay?
Yeah, he's fine. I let you hear his voice right now!
Oh no. don't have my voice changer either.
He wants to hear your voice.
What's the matter?
Daddy.
Jun!
"_'- :
Ay 4h
A «O y
Seems the kid's panicked that he's
Iost his voice, get the cash ready quick
PA Please wait a minute!
7 ({ MM
He hung up...
74 NM
Mr. Kataoka, does the voice sound familiar to you?
Ray
This is the first time
I've heard his voice.
Jun"s voice was so weak ll wonder if he's really safe?
I can't say, but please leave the rest up to the police
All right...
Inspector Megure!
Everything's ready
on. thanks!
All we can do now is wait for the kidnapper to get back in touch with us
Inspector Megure!
Please answer the phone
Mr. Kataoka!
Y-Yes...
Hello. this is Kataoka.
Did you get the cash ready?
Yes, it's ready, and, you're going to give
Jun back to us, aren't you?
Bring that money to. the clock tower of the Ogane Park at 12:00!
12:00 to the clock tower of Ogane Park
Ill be there!
Hold it! You're not the one who's bringing the money!
We wantla woman called
Sachiko Ezaki to bring it.
What!
You want her to bring it?
We don't hassle with anybody acting funny!
We feel more secure if a woman brings it.
Don't be late.
Inspector Megure.
I'll go disguised as Ms. Ezaki.
No! Let me
M-Ms. Ezaki?
Il Bot
S-Sachiko!
The kidnapper demanded me to go.
I'm sure he knows how 'l look
But. if the worst should happen.
Please! Nothing. nothing can be greater than Jun"s life!
Let me go! Inspector!
Inspector!
Inspector.
All right. Will you do it for us.
Yes.
Inpsector!
I know!
Ms. Ezaki,
we will be 500 meters behind you so that the kidnapper doesn't realize we're there.
I'll put this tracking device in your bag.
So we'll be able to locate the kidnapper right away,
And, if you need to get in touch with us for anything.
Please use this to contact us.
Sachiko, please donatiill do anything reckless
I promise I'll bring Jun back withime.
Ezaki...
This is your grave!
No use calling for help
Darn! I've got to get out of here fast.
Understand, when the kidnapper comes in contact with Ms. Ezaki
If he has Jun with him, nab him on the spot
If Jun is nowhere in sight,
Let the kidnapper go and get a hold of the whereabouts of Jun.
After confirming whether-he is okay or not, then nab the kidnapper!
This is Sato at Ogane Park!
All the investigators are in, position!
Good! Be very careful.
Takagi, come closer to me!
Oh, no, I'm okay with here.
Don't be silly, if you don't we won't look like lovers!
Oh, okay...
Come on, at least put your arm around me or something
H Here goes, then...
I.Like this?
Get with it, will you!
Inspector!
Ms. Ezaki's car has arrived
A suspicious car is in view
It's a compact truck with the words Honeybee courier written on it
It's a~=compact truck with the!
Words Honeybee courier written on it
Would a kidnapper come in a flashy car like that?
It stopped beside Ms. Ezaki.
Is Jun anywhere in sight?
I can't really confirm whether or not.
Jun, isn't Jun with you?
One of my friends is watching the«id.
I'll give him back to you as-soon as I return with this ransom
Tell the police that if I'm late getting back, the kid's dead.
The kidnapper grabbed the bag from Ms. Ezaki.
And has fled by truck!
ihe number plate on: 'the truck
Is Shinjuku=two letters 44
Mi" for Mikasa 328,
On its orange colored bed
there is a large honeybee mark.
What shall we do, Inspector?
Don't get to close!
Chiba, get the officers in emergency-position on the double.
Yes.
Sato, Takagi, go after him by chopper!
Roger!
A child's life is at stake,
SO be extremely careful
Don't let him get away, no matter what.
Isn't it about time we get going?
It's only a little after 11:00 yet, though.
Then you can still play a lot more!
Next. why don't you challenge the game over there!
Okay!
Genta, are you good at the game?
Nope!
Something. if I can only find something...
Inspector! The truck's headed for Kenbashi Tunnel!
What's the length of the tunnel?
About 1 kilometer, so at this speed...
it'lgo through it-in about a minute!
It'll go through it in about a minute!
Go on ahead and wait at the exit of the tunnel!
Roger!
It,It stopped!
It stopped in the center of the tunnel!
Darn, it won't budge with the strength of a child!
Maybe the kidnapper abandoned the truck...
Po. ou see anybody-suspicious?
No. only other cars are coming out of the tunnel.
No humans, not even a cat for that matter
Why? Why isnat it moving?
Inspector, 10 minutes have gone by.
Okay, let's go inside the tunnel!
Ro er!
Darn! I've got to do something quick!
It was abandoned on the side of the road in the center of the tunnel.
Which means...
The kidnapper threw away the communicator and got away with the cash
But the honeybee courier truck didn't come out of the tunnel...
Are you sure about it?
Yes, the pilot of the chopper as well as
I was watching carefully but
the honeybee courier truck didn't come out of the tunnel.
Maybe he made a
U-turn inside the tunnel?
But if so. he would be driving in
the opposite direction on the freeway and cause a commotion!
Then, are you saying that the kidnapper's car disappeared in the tunnel?
Another thing I don't understands how
the kidnapper found out about this communicater...
Officer Sato, I have. something
I want you to check for me
Yes, Sir.
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers
MITCHIHTKO SUWA
\ -5 a > >a A
Background Music
KalsUO ONO
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
Scripts By.
KANJI"KASHIWABARA
KAZ7UUNARI KOUCHI
«JF MM rr IT «
LICH £1] 5 J
TOWSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors
MA ATOMO SUDO
» * LR Yo. row, \ ha - = AR
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KENJI KODAMA
Produced By
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD.
In=assocaiation with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CONAN t <.<>w':<fi,\<>>AMA; \II()(.AI\UI\AN-)IV-IHS
All RH Fescrved
Strange. Conan's not answering...
I wonder if something's ~appened?
What? What do you mean something?
I called the honeybee courier company
and was told that the whereabouts of all their cars are known!
Could that truck have been stolen?
Does that mean you have no clue where the kidnapper is?
TheiKidnap Car that Disappeared
Part 2