Today's stage is Teitan High.
Just like every high school,
how many strange stories will emerge?
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult.
No case is left unsolved with Detective Conan.
What?!
Night... mare...
What...?
Ghosts are haunting your school?
Recently, our high school has been experiencing a series of supernatural incidents.
It's been giving me the creeps.
Moreover, they say that people always see that apparition early in the morning...
Rumor has it that two years ago,
a student who used to come to school early in the morning died in an accident.
And they say it's the curse of that student.
Two years ago, that's before I enrolled...
So, please, dad!
Come after school today and check,
if it's really the work of a ghost or not.
Let it be, let it be!
It's either someone playing a prank or a natural phenomenon anyway.
Besides, if that ghost appears early in the morning,
it wouldn't appear during class, would it?
Well, no...
As the daughter of renowned detective Kogoro Mouri,
I can't just let an absurd rumor go unchecked.
By the way Ran-neechan, aren't you hall monitoring next week?
Um, yeah...
I see... you're afraid of going to school early in the morning so you want me to check?
I can't help it because I don't like ghosts...
Get rid of them with your karate!
What makes you think that karate is going to have any effect on ghosts?!
Ran...
Do you want me to go with you?
I may come up with a hint to at least solve the mystery!
Teitan High School's Ghost Story
(Part 1)
Conan-kun!
This way, over here!
Sorry to keep you waiting, Ran-neechan!
Hey, Ran!
Don't tell me the guy who's helping us investigate is this kid with the glasses.
But... my dad wouldn't even show up,
a renowned detective can't come to check out such a crazy case...
Well, he may not suffice as an aide...
but he can at least serve as an assistant to I, the deduction queen.
You're the last person I'd want
to hear that comment from...
These are our shoe lockers.
It's a little larger than your elementary school, isn't it?
Y-Yep!
I know...
I went to this school for a little over a year...
I'll put your shoes in my locker, Conan.
Oh, thank you Ran-neechan.
My, what's with that boy, Ran?
Is that the rumored Conan-kun?
That's right! Isn't he cute?
Ugh! Blabber mouths Tashiro and Hidaka.
You can say that again! He looks like a miniature Kudo and sure looks cheeky!
Sonny, don't grow up to be a deduction freak, okay?
None of your business...
Why'd you bring him here?
An assistant for investigation! This glasses kid is pretty sharp, you know...
Investigation, you mean that ghost scare?
No kidding.
Aizawa and Nakamichi of the soccer club!
Don't bother.
You're going to be cursed.
Hey, will you stop saying things like that?
By the way, how'd your re-test go?
Just made it!
Although we were seriously on the brink!
True, very true.
I'm sure that one day you'll run out of bad luck too.
See you then, but take it easy!
If you find out who the ghost is, let me in on it.
O-Okay...
Sure thing!
Is something the matter, Conan?
Oh... nope, it's nothing.
Right... if things were the way they were supposed to be
I would be coming to this school, studying, talking of trivial things with my friends...
And leading a normal high school life...
Gin and Vodka...
If those men in black... didn't force me to drink that strange drug.
And if I hadn't shrunk...
That woman Bellmot one of them, that disguised herself as Dr. Niide.
Got, away from me just as I was about to corner her in order to get
get my body back to normal again and regain my life as Shinichi Kudo!
That woman is probably an assassin who was sent out
to kill Al who had betrayed the organization...
I remember her saying back then, that she would give up on going after Au...
I wonder if I can really believe what she said...
After all she's a witch that has a thousand faces.
,,1
After all she's a witch t hat has a thousand faces...
After all she's a witch t hat has a thousand faces
After all she\s a witch t hat has a thousand faces...
After all she's a witch t hat has a thousand faces...
She's as good as Thief Kid when it comes to disguising herself
qO - 2
She may still be around us disguised as somebody"
and scheming to do something
Va
aati
What the?!
What?!
Oh, Dr. Niide?!
Uh .l heard that since the trial is over
you returned to your hospital in Aomori...
No... I was planning on doing so.
But decided against it. I'm worried about my patients too, so .
And, it:sinot.thatieasyssaying goodbye to you all-either...
Then, you're going to remain being our school doctor?
Yes. I came today to tell the school of my intention...
Ouch, ow- owl!
T-The real doctor?
Hey Hey?! Conan!
Hey: -Hey?!Conan!
Just whatido youithink you're doing?!
Are you all right, doctor?
Oh yes... It's nothing.
The FBI agent called Jodie told me all about what-happened.
Huh?
She told me that a bad person disguised as me tried to do something bad...
She said she was sent back to the States for a while, but it seems that Hikaru
or her grandmother who accompanied her did not take to the States very well...
Then, I heard that the bad person revealed herself and fled.
So Jodie asked to return back here to Beikacho!
But, why are you telling me all this?
I was told to tell only you, because you'd surely be surprised.
That's right?!
Let's have Dr. Niide help us with
the ghost investigation too!
That sounds great!
Huh? Ghost investigation...?
Ha, ha...
First, let's stat, here...
The wailing storeroom of the gym...
One rainy day, a girl student of the gymnastic club who came here early
in the morning to prepare for morning ctice... heard a wailing voice
The wailing leaked out of the storeroom where nobody was supposed to be...
The horrifying sound of someone wailing!
And...
The girl got scared and left,
bringing other people from her club back to the place...
but the wailing had stopped...
and the only thing left was this desk!
It was the desk of a boy student. Hideaki Hosaka,
who died mysteriously at this school 2 years ago!
Huh
Talk about exaggeration.
Yikes!
It so conspicuous that it would scare no one...
He... Ran...
That's no mystery or anything.
He unfortunately tripped on the stairs
and hit the wrong place, that's it!
Don't go spreading strange rumors!
Huh, XY R Kazumi oe...
Huh...? Kazumi...
uri, just what are you doing he
The Karate club is off today, isn't it?
Yeah... A senior and the previous captain of the:Karate club...
I'm investigating the ghost case...
You mean the wailing case?
If it's that everyone's saying tha tit was probably the trick of the wind.
that skylight with the broken lock. It's said the when the wind blows in from there.
The sound of the howling of the wind was taken to be the sound of someone wailing.
It's amazing that you figured out that this desk was the boy student's desk...
I told everyone about it because there was so much fuss over it!
S... his classmate, beside
Is. Is that right?
Why is his desk in a
Iace like this, though...?
It started to rain...
Oh, no... don't have an umbrella...
Neither do I
Then would you like to take's helter from the rain until it stops?
At the cursed library...
I was just about 10 go there myself 100...
S-Shall we go there?
Of course!
What's this... A sign...?
Wow, it'sistarting.to rain cats and dogs!
I wonder if it's going to stop...
I think it will. According to the weather forecast,
this is supposed-to be rain shower...
Dr: Niide, yous sure are a push-over*I
Ike always coming along
to investigate a ghost scare by-request of a student...
W-W-Well
Huh...
Seko!
Where were you? I was looking for you!
I had an upset stomach
Ol cut the afternoon class
and was resting in the infirmary...
Are you all right?
Yeah... Did you want anything? Tsukamoto.
Oh, it's not anything important, s
Ol guess I'll get to it some other time.
Well, I guess I'll rest a while more than, before going home...
Before that worried teacher decides to, lug me off to the hospital...
Was he also a classmate of the boy named Hosaka?
No, he was in 2 different class!
But he seems to
have been childhood, friends with Hosaka...
How unusual! That an athletic person like you would be coming to the library...
How rude, I read books too, you know!
Besides I have the entrance exam of university coming up next year...
Besides... Just like you two,
I'm also investigating the ghost scare!
Oh...
When-you came this morning, the books were left out on the table...?
And all those books were ones that
Hosaka had borrowed before...
Moreover, this happened four consecutive days in a row, you know!
No matter how you think of it, this is none other than the curse of Hosaka
who couldn't read the book as much as he wanted to!
Shhhh!
But, if the books are not put away.
I think that the librarian would notice when locking the library.
It seems that the 4 books were found, one behind the bookshelf,
another under the desk and so on forth...
I think it's somebody whose taking advantage
of the ghost scare and playing pranks, though...
If I ever catch the brat that's doing this,
If I ever catch the brat that's doing this.
I'm going to get him for sure and bust him up.
So when the time comes you help me too, okay, Mouri
O-Okay...
Now... finally for these cursed stairs...
When a student came to these stairs early in the mo ning
the bottom of the stairs was soaked with water, right?
Yep... and it seems that these are the stairs that boy fell from too...
It's probably the curseditears of the boy named Hosaka...
Maybe the window wasn't closed tight, and it rained the day before?
I mean, we're not kids, you know, so the windows would've been closed!
Besides that's not the only thing!
It's rumored that the number of the steps of these stairs
are different each time you count them...
Then, why don't both try counting them?
Huh?
Okay, count we will!
One dees TWO wee
Three... Four... Five...
Six... Seven... Eight.
Nine... Ten
R-Ran, how many did you count?
Twelve...
What?! I counted thirteen!
No kidding... why?!
The correct answer is twelve steps!
You probably counted one extra step when you brought
both ou feet to< ether and made it all the way up the steps!
That's because you keep thinking that this whole thing+ is scary...
Okay! All I gotta do is count it over again right?!
Rather, do you really have the intention of solving
solving the mystery about this ghost scare or what?
Hey, you guys, will you cut out the noise!
I cant concentrate on drawing!
Bm Sorry...
Huh. That student
It seems to have stopped raining...
Well; shall we go home for today?
Il guess so...
After listening, to you Conan,
I'm starting to feel that no such thing exist
and I feel a bit courageous now...
Besides, it's getting kind of dark outside too...
W... What's that...
That desk...
It.It can't be the one we just saw,
could it...
Conan.
There's something on top of the desk?!
My:grudge:, has notiyetvanishéd:.!
Who could've played a prank like this?!
Tthe paper's not wet so it must've been put here after it stopped raining...
If so, something's strange...
The soil is muddy with rain...
Thersoil is muddy with rain... The thing that's supposed to be here is not...
The footprints of the one who yrought the desk here...
J... Just as I thought...
The desk and the chair out there are the ones that
were in the storeroom of the, gym after all!
Yep, there's no doubt that the desk is the-one of the student
called Hideaki Hosaka that died here at this high school!
Then, somebody put it out there to play a prank 7?
Yes, there was a piece of paper on the desk, which wasn't wet.
So It was probably put there after the rain stopped...
But, then it's strange...
The ground of the campus where it was, was muddy with rain, but the only footprints
left were Conan:and mine's that got there when we ran over to the desk...
It's a ghost!
I'm sure the ghost of that student called Hosaka took it there!
It.It's possible...
Because ghosts don't have legs...
I tell you... really, all of you...
Uh, hey...
Tithe desk and chair are gone!
No! H How...
Dr. Nilde and I returned them to the storeroom of the gym.
What...?!
We didn't want to entertain the one who did it by making a big fuss over it.
And besides, something strange was written on the paper on top the desk...
S-Strange?
It seems to have been written with a brush and was quite~sloppy .
My grudge... has not yet vanished...
T-Then why wasn't that paper wet .7?
Because the ghost was wrtine nis « rude e filled
sentence with his body over the desk in the rain...
You guys...
I don't see how you can come up with one idea after the other like that...
Whaaa...
Is.Is anything the matter?
H... He held a grudge against me after all
This ghost scare I ¥his... curse!
By Chance, do you happen to know this student called Hosaka?
Agh... Yeah...
He was 2 member of the art club with me
& Until he fell of f those stairs back then two years ago, that is...
Back then
Don't tell me you were there when this happened. 7
Just as I thought...
Back then when the accident, occurred, this student.
Please leave...
Huh
The teacher was nice enough to I
# et me use this art room all by myself
so that I would be able to complete my piece for the contest...
Go on, quickly"!
I don't want to waste any time!
Oh... okay!
118 ad
Kugh Uuugh...
Uh, should we let Kazumi know that the desk was out on campus too?
O-Okay...
Huh Q0000
Something's shining...
What is it?
Wax...
What's the matter. Conan?
Um...
You said that the bottom of the stairs-was soaked
with water but was it this floor that was leaking?
Right! The entire floor!
The tears of the curse of the student named Hosaka that died here...
Who found that?
I heard that it was someone from the art club
that came here early in the morning
Oh...
Hey, is that for real?!
Jae ay *
Is it true that Hosakanls desk and chair were out on campus?!
Y-Yes...
And on the desk was a paper that said? 2
I'm really pissed!
Thisis going too:fardas a prank!
If you find the one who's doing this, make sure you grab him
and bring him here no matter what!
We'll give him a good licking together!
I thin «\ our spin kick will suffice: though.
Do you know what kind of books were not put away
and borrowed by Hosaka before?
Y... Yes.
Wow...
They're all difficult books that you don't see around too often...
It's not at all surprising...
See, take a look at this library card!
These four hooks seems
0 have been borrowed
virtuallffonly by the studentlcalled Hosaka...
Hosaka wanted to be a comic wirter...
He used to always say that
in order to write an interesting story, it was useful to keep in mind
all kinds of things that people aren't familiar with...
Oh...
You saw his signature on the edge of the desk, didn't your?
That's the signature he told everyone that he was
going to use in the: future when he becomes famous. >
Then, then...
his dream was severed part way too, so he must-ve felt super, attachment to it...
He wet the bottom of the stairs with his tears of curse...
At midnight he re-read the books in the library with his heart full of hate...
He finally brings his desk that is in the storeroom
of the gym out into the campus grounds...
H-Hey, hold it Sonoko!
Huh, Ran...
hat's enough, you...
Right, if we ask the principal, he may know something about it!
After you left the library,
I got up to go to the restroom
and saw a glimpse of him through the window on the 3rd floor!
Like always he was standing In place on campus...
The principal was thinking of what tree to plant there...?
[he principal was thinking of what tree to plant there...?
Yes... hed go out there everyday, trying to decide what to plant...
So, the Principal is still undecided...
I remember that the principal said that he discussed it with you too. Dr. Niide...
Oh...
Yeah, right... that's right...
Wellllit's only natural that he wouldn't know about it.
BecauseiBellmot was the one disguised as Nude as soon as
-_- )) he became the school doctor of Teitan High School...
Come To think of it.
Bellmot disguised as Dr. Niide was also in charge of Teitan Elementary School...
An 18 year-old just like you!
If Ai, who betrayed the organization is really between the age of 18 and 20
and if their looking for her in one of the high schools here.
Looking into high schools and universities should suffice...
If the were thinking that Al had shrunk and become a child like me to begin with
why couldn'tithey find her as soon as
Dr. Nitde became the school doctor...?
There is nothing like a new student who catches the eye...
Damn! It, sure bothers me...!
Thanks for the ghost scare, I've come up with other things that I've got to work on.
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA wlfi
Backoeround Music.
KATSUD ONO
Charaater Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDQ
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
KAN]! KASHVIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCH1
JUNIGHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI_HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Dircctors.
MASATOMO SUDO
WwW HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
4. '4';
1, ¥ - -
I Iter,
TERUMITSU OkSDA
Chief Director.
KENJIgKODAMA
ProdudO By.
DMS ENTE TAINMENT, ATD in association with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
' » ra\
CAT UNRAT II Y
DETECTIVE CON
« COSHO AOYAMA / SHOCAKUKAN -YIV -IMS
All Rights Reserve
Don't tell me that the one who started the ghost scare in school is.
still in the school building somewhere...
Will you all wait in front of the art room?
I've figured out a way to find out who is doing all this.
All you have to do is keep on waiting without saying a word!
WwW. Wait for what?
What else...
but the ghost of the student called Hosaka
come down the stairs while dri» inc with water...
Teitan:High School 'Ghost -Story:_Part.2