besides
The love story of two police detectives.
The Detective Boys plays a part,
And the case takes a surprising turn!
He sees through the one and only truth
With the Body of a kid and the mind of an adult,
His name is: Detective Conan
O-Officer Sato?!...
What is it you want to talk to me about?...
W-What do I do...
Ah, ha
Officer Takagi!
Just get inside!
Oh, okay!
What it is?...
What in the world is it?...
I wonder if I did something wrong again?
Ms. Sato's birthday is in April...
I kept her company at karaoke too...
D-Don't tell me that...
She's going to ask me to break up with her?!
W-Wait.
No way.
Whaat?!
Huh?
Huh?...
I-I got you! You fell for it
Ah, ha...
Huh?...
How'd you like it?
Just great, isn't it?!
Officer Takagi, this toy!
I'm going to try it on Yumi next!
O-Officer Sato.
D-Don't tell me you brought me all the way just to try that on me?!
Exactly!
Oh, anything wrong?!
We're finished work and ready to go home anyway...
C-Come on...
Or are you saying that...
I can't ask you to come with me,
unless I have something important to do?
Police Sergeant Takagi?!
They sure are in love.
No... they're not there yet...
They're probably going to make it soon...
No! Not for some time yet...
There, there.
S-Stop it, will you!,
Officer Sato... Aha, ha...
Love Story at Police Headquarters 6
(Part 1)
Request for dispatch from the Tottori Prefectural Police...
Yeah...
You do know of them, don't you, Megure?!
The band of thieves that raided that area,
and are now stealing nation wide...
Okay... see you...
A joint investigation headquarters was set up in Tottori, and they're asking,
for people from the 1st division investigation section here...
But, Sergeant! Isn't the stealing supposed to be...
taken care of by the 3rd division...
Have you forgotten Megure?
They've a so committed attempted murder in Tokyo too...
Oh, that's right...
Of course, they're sending one person from the 3rd division.
They also need a 1st division-er. Who do we send?...
Well.
Someone who's single, brilliant, and has high stamina,
Able to work in a different prefecture...
If that person is familiar with the area, it's even better.
Huh?! That's right...
Hey! Megure.
Wasn't his home town somewhere in Tottori?
W-Who?
Huh? W-Who's he?
Him... Takagi! Officer Takagi!
T-Takagi...
Oh... no!
Think he's a good candidate, don't you?
Yes... guess so...
Although his appearance doesn't show it, he's pretty sharp.
And I hear he's solved a lot of cases too.
Okay then Sergeant,
I'll notify him tomorrow morning...
Thanks... that'll be a great help...
It's sad to think that he's going to go far away.
Hide's... really going abroad, isn't he?
We still don't know for sure, do we?!
Oh, England is the place where soccer originated, right?
If you do like him, don't you want him to play at the original location?
That's true, but!
Well, as far as I'm concerned.
I feel that it's good idea,
to go abroad and get tough, more so, for the World Cup.
The World Cup...
World Cup...
Huh!
It's stopped raining...
Oh! That's true...
Really!?
Hum?
Huh!
That man was heaving hard and...
he seemed to be having a hard time...
Of course!
That's because he's jogging...
Come on!
We'd better hurry or we'll be late for school!
She's right!
Let's go!
What?!
So I heard... That's the story...
Hey! Are you listening or what?
Miwako?!
Miwako?
Oh... Yeah...
Oh, no! I'm barely going to make it...
Good morning!
What?
U-Uh...
Is there anything on my face...?
Y-Yumi...
Officer Takagi...
Huh...
Yes?
Huh?...
G-Good... bye!
H-Hey!
Just what do you mean?
What!
What?!
I-I'm going to be dispatched to tho joint
Investigation headquarters in Tottori?!
Aha, ha...
M-Maybe you got the wrong person...
Stupid!
You're the only Takagi here!
Don't pretend you don't know!
According to Yumi you should've gotten a call from Inspector Megure...
Huh?! C-Come to think of it.
I did get a call from the inspector this morning...
I was still drowsy, so I didn't really follow what he was saying...
See... It's that phone call.
Huh? W-Well I get to come back after the case is solved anyway so...
You don't understand anything, do you...?
The headquarters is pursuing the robbers that are committing...
the serial robberies nation wide, you know?!
In most cases like these, who knows how many incidents there are...
And besides, if there are several members involved,
who knows, when the case"ll be solved...
Well, things will work out...
With his ability
Three years will be to solve the case...
Three years.
T-Three ears.
Three ears.
1095 days...26280 hours...
The Heavens have not forsaken me...
I'm happy for you!
The air is clean in Totton and you can eat all you want of Matsuba crab!
You can ride camels at the sand dunes of Tottori too!
No! I'm not!
Officer Takagi...
Oh, O-Officer Sate...
Don't forget to send me 20th Century.
Japanese Pears, okay!
They're my favorite!
Aha, ha...
Wow, that's thee WORD!
That's my favorite.
Matsuba Crab is our favorite.
Don't forget the camels while you're at it, okay?
Hey! What's with all this noise!
We got a case!
The scene of the crime
Is on the 23rd floor of...
The skyscraper located on Beika city 4th District!
A man was found stabbed to death.
According to report by investigators,
The one who found the corpse seems to be a woman.
Sato and Takagi, go to the scene of the crime Together!
Yes, sir!
Megure you take care, of giving orders at the scene...
Oh, no, well,
Please have Cho-san take care of things this time Sergeant.
Cho-san!
Okay...
OK...
To the scene immediately!
Yes, sir!
Cho-san!
This is the first tame I'm teaming with you, isn't it. Cho-san...
Yeah, let's get to work...
Officer Takagi.
Yes, sir!
Cho-san is a veteran that's 2 years older than me.
Learn a lot from him, will you!
Yes, sir of course!
And...
Besides, this may be the last time he'll be teaming with you.
What?!
Aaaaagh...!
O-Officer Takagi.
G-Goodbye.
Ah, ha...
Are you serious?!
Hide's press conference will start at noon, right?
What! Oh, no!
We'd better hurry, or we'll miss it!
We'll make it!
Hide's press conference will be on the news of today!
It'll probably be aired several times all day.
Huh!
Somethings seems to have happened...
Yeah!
The name of the man that was stabbed is
Mr. Hirotoshi Nakamoto.
He was 27, an office worker.
The murder weapon is
a knife of 18 centimeters.
The time of the murder is...
Between 07:00 to 07:30 today.
You, his colleague at work came here at 13:00.
And found him dead.
Y-Yes, sir...
I took a day off from work today.
And was supposed to go with him to reserve our wedding hall...
H-How could something like this happen...
And...
Do you know of anyone who may have had a grudge against him?
He was the type to make enemies...
It seems the killer is an acquaintance of his.
Yes, the door was locked.
Then, will you pick out the person...
You think may have had a grudge against him from the album?
I'll go check the person out...
Can you see something?
Ah! It's Officers Takagi and Sato!
So... take care of it, okay?
Yes, ma'am.
Oh!
Did something happen?
I'll bet its a homicide case.
Oh, yeah, well.
Um, didn't it happen...
Around a little after 07:00 this morning?
O-Officer Sato...
H-How do you know?!...
We saw a suspicious person on our way to school!
On the street near this condo!
Come on. Conan!
That man was just jogging and...
Remember!
Just before we passed that man.
It stopped raining, right?
Yes... It was a showers that lasted about 10 minutes...
But, that guy's clothes, was hardly wet at all.
Why was that the case?
Maybe he was taking shelter from the rain somewhere?
Because it started raining while, he was jogging...
And he started running again because it stopped raining.
Fool! If had stopped for 10 minutes.
He wouldn't be heaving like that!
In other words, he wasn't out of breath because he was jogging...
But because he was hyper...
from having stabbed someone in a room near here!
That's what you wanted to say, right?
Uh, is that man here?
What!
T-This man...
Sort of looks like him!
It's Mr. Kato, a colleague of his at work!
If I remember correctly... I heard that,
he was freeloading at his friend's place...
Do you know where that house is?
Oh, yes...
What? A little after 07:00 this morning?
I was here right through...
No! You're the one who stabbed Hirotoshi aren't you?!
What?
Me, commit murder?!
Just what are you talking about?!
Out of nowhere...
What's going on!
Cut out the noise...
I told you to get rid of door-to-door sales, didn't I?!
Oh, well... the thing is...
So, what's the problem?
What?!
Hmm... Oh Huh?!
O-Officer Chiba?!
Yeah...
Oh this is interesting...
What?!
Suspect of a homicide case?!...
You mean Kato?!...
Yes, that's right.
His colleague at work,
Mr. Hirotoshi Nakamoto was murdered.
The murder weapon was a knife, that found on the floor beside the body...
A-And the estimated time of death was?
Between 07:00 to 07:30 this morning...
Then, he couldn't have committed the crime.
Because he woke me up at 07:00.
And we were here together watching TV till 08:00.
Right?
Yeah...
Is it true?!
Yes, we were watching
Nichiuri TV's live morning broadcast.
"Morning Live Seven", a news variety program...
But, Officer Chiba, he woke you up, didn't he?
Then it could be that...
he showed you something that he had video taped some time ago, right...?
N-No way!
I've got proof too...
By the way, why, am I suspected in the first place?
Because you're my ex-boyfriend!
There's an eye-witness.
That says he saw you a little past 07:00 near the condo!
Are you sure that guy wasn't half asleep and mistook me for someone else.
We weren't half asleep!
I saw him clearly! It was him!
He was wearing a gray parka top...
You were running with a black knapsack on your back!
Just as If you were jogging...
Let's have Officer Chiba show us in!
And show us proof that he was watching TV with that man
from 07:00 to 08:00 in the morning.
W-What? What's this?!
What a mess!
I can see why you're always late for work!
I-I'm doing the best I can!
I'm recently not as tardy as
I used to be, right?
Come to think of it, that's true...
How come?
Oh, well, I sort of did something to give me initiative to get up...
What's with these toys here!
Don't tell me, you're some special effects freak or something?
W-Who cares!
I mean after all, it's just a hobby...
Wow, it's Gomeral Gomera!
Kamen Yaiba is here too!
That's a rare object made of tin!
H-Hey!
Don't get rough with them...
I told you to wait in the car with Mr. Kato and Ms. Shimura, didn't I?
And, where is it?
The evidence you mentioned that both of you were watching TV together...
Oh, yes, sir!
It's this video tape.
This is Yoko Okino's 4 minute cooking!
It's February 25th. Friday.
I video tape this corner of the Morning Live Seven each time.
Last night,
I watched rental videos with Kato while drinking and fell asleep here...
I forgot to pre-set the program to record of so I recorded it myself today.
That's why he couldn't have shown me something he recorded beforehand.
Besides, only one video tape deck is used.
But, there's another deck here!
That's one that we only use sometimes for dubbing!
If he used that deck,
the cord would show in front of the TV.
I would notice it no matter how drowsy I may be...
If you think, it's a lie, call the TV station and confirm it!
It's the corner after
Nichiruri TV's Morning Live Seven's...
Weather forecast of today, February 25, Friday...
My, you have many marks
In other places too...
Even the cable TV programs are marked...
There are so man, programs
I want to watch...
I see. That's why you've got
SO many memo pads stuck all over-the TV.
And? After watching the program until 08:00.
I watched videos from 08:00.
What kind?
Oh, well... that's
Chiba, hey! Don't tell me...
Adult?
No! It's this, this here!
Huh?!
It, It's Kamen Yaiba!
This is episode 1 of the first Yaiba!
The mask of the first Yiaiba was, really gross!
And that was one of the good points!
And, how long were you watching this children's program?
I watched one 120 minute tape...
You mean you watched it for 2 hours?
No, it's taped on 3 times the regular speed and the commercials aren't cut so...
S-Six hours?!
Uh, did you video tape all the tapes Officer Chiba?
Kato gave me the ones he taped before.
And, were you with him right through?
No, after watching half the program
I went to take a shower,
for about 30 minutes...
Then, I started watching again.
I watched all the way to episode 12 and stopped the video.
Then professional baseball was being aired so,
You know, the game from 14:00 the Falcons vs: the Jaguars!
It was 2:05 when you, Cho, came while I was watching that game.
I see!
From here to the victim's condo,
It would take at least an hour by car.
If after watching TV for an hour,
they watched the video for approximately 6 hours together.
His alibi is established...
Just to be sure,
Let's look for the gray parka top and
black knapsack the man had on him...
What?!
Is that for real?!
What?! What is it?
Did you find something?!
Nothing really...
God.
If there's nothing, don't shout!
And, how long is the dispatch to Tottori going to be...?
The guys at the 1st division say
It will be about 3 years.
And, what did Officer Sato say?
She wants me to get her
SOME Japanese pears.
That's all?
That's it...
Strange... It's mere natural that she would get more upset...
Although, I'll be dispatched it seems I get to take off once a month.
And I can call her frequently too...
I hope you don't end up like Kato...
Huh?...
He was abroad on a business trip till last month,
But as soon as he got back he called me and asked me to stay here.
While he was away, the woman he was
living with started going with another man.
So he was left without a place to stay, he said.
A-And...
He used to call her everyday, and yet,
he complained he could never understand women...
If you're serious about her,
I think you should let her know, don't you?
About how you feel and what your plans are for the future.
And, you never know what'll happen to you either, right...?
Huh? Me?...
Maybe...
You may end up finding a lover over there!
Huh!
That's right...
If that happens.
You won't be coming home for a while.
It is said that the hearts of people, proportionately pull apart the more time passes.
Although there are rare exceptions.
Hey...
I, will never go with a woman other than her! Never!
"I"?
Just who are we talking about?
W-Who...
Huh?
We were talking about Hide
Because he may be going out abroad...
Oh, Hide...
Oh, it seems that
Hide decided to remain in Japan...
What, really?!
Y-You saw the press conference they had in the afternoon?
No, right after Morning Live Seven started,
There was a flash news report subtitle displayed on the screen.
It said, "Player Hide Akashire of the Tokyo
Spirits have: announced that he will remain!
A press conference will he held at 12:00 noon"
Uh, did the caster mention anything about that news later?
No, not in particular.
Wait a sec...
Maybe...
I see, so that's the story!...
But, it's not possible...
Even if this trick were to be used, there are still...
Some parts I cannot explain.
How was it done?
How was the time rigged...
It doesn't seem to be around...
Not here, anyways.
Why don't you ask Officer Chiba, then...?
Chiba!
I'm asking If you swear...
By this Cherry Blossom crest!
I'll go over there and become a fine police detective!
So, before go...
P-please...
Please...