The Shinkansen...
Our country's pride of the world,
the safest express railway.
Onto this Shinkansen,
someone brought an attaché case containing a bomb.
So then, just where is this bomb?
A canvas stained black with crime.
With brilliant detective skills, its color is changed!
A suspicious rider with a black suitcase!
Time's running out, Detective Boys!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Created by
Gosho Aoyama
"Detective Conan"
Serialized in Shogakukan's
'Weekly Shonen Sunday'
Character Design
Masatomo Sudo
Art Director
Yukihiro Shibutani
Art Design
Hiroyuki Mitsumoto
Director of Photography
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takashi Nomura
Sound Director
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
Music Producer
Hiroki Horio
(PolyGram)
Music
Katsuo Ono
Opening Theme
"Sekai wa anata no iro ni naru"
Performed by
Lyrics
Music
Koshi Inaba
Tak Matsumoto
Editor
Terumitsu Okada
Story Editor
Jun'ichi Iioka
Color Key
Reiko Hirayama
Executive Producer
Satoshi Kojima
Director
Kenji Kodama
Presented by
Nobody shaves in the bullet train
on the way to their best friend's wedding!
It's not my fault!
I overslept 'cuz I was up late last night discussing things with a client!
Oh, please. You got drunk and fell asleep in the doorway.
Hmph!
I brought you along 'cuz you wanted to come, but I dunno why...
But the wedding's in Kyoto!
You really wanted to go there too, didn't you, Conan-kun?
Yeah.
Why did we have to bring him along anyway?!
You know we can't leave him all alone!
Say, are those new shoes?
Yeah! Dr. Agasa gave them to me!
I made you something I'm sure you'll like!
Power Kick Shoes!
Kick a ball with these shoes
and the criminals won't know what hit them!
It uses electricity and magnetic fields
to stimulate your feet muscles,
thereby substantially increasing your kick power!
What about my glasses?
They're ready too.
I added a miniature hidden microphone to them.
I'm certain it'll come in handy!
I hope they actually work when I need them to!
A bullet train!
But why are they with us too?!
What does it matter?
Their tickets have been paid for.
Man, parents these days...
Conan-kun! Let's go exploring!
It looks like it'll be really fun!
Let's go!
Their parents obviously have some issues.
And what about his parents?!
They haven't even called us once!
Uh oh!
I gotta go to the bathroom!
It's not like I'm living with you because I want to!
It's all their fault!
They were the ones who forced me to take that weird pill
and wind up small like this!
It's them!
This is my best chance to steal some of those pills!
Once I turn back into high school detective Shin'ichi Kudo,
I'll expose all of your evil deeds to the world!
Just you wait!
But what in the world could they be doing here?
They're meeting with someone...
Now's my chance to plant
Dr. Agasa's hidden microphone
on one of their seats!
What are you doing, Conan-kun?!
Move!
I wasn't doing anything—
Really?
You're such a troublemaker, Conan-kun!
It's people like you who give kids a bad name!
You should wrap the gum in paper and put it in an ashtray!
There.
I'll hear them just fine if it's in there!
Learn from your friends, Conan-kun!
You're all such good children!
Of course we are!
Let's go!
If I know you, Conan-kun,
that wasn't any ordinary prank!
Was that gum some sort of secret weapon?!
Are those two men spies?! Hit men?!
It would be great if they were,
but I was just being a troublemaker!
For reals?
Aw, man...
What a bore. Let's get back to exploring!
Excuse me for being a bore.
Outta the way, boy.
Huh?
It's not them! They're not the men in black!
I got the wrong people! I feel like such an idiot!
He has a suitcase instead of the attaché case he had before...
Something's not right...
The two suitcases are too different
for someone to accidentally mistake one for the other...
That's it! I'll use the doc's hidden microphone!
He said that if I turn the dial
to match the frequency,
special sound waves will stimulate my eardrums,
allowing me to hear with my glasses on!
I can finally have a smoke.
I can hear them!
This sure turned out to be an easy transaction, boss!
Keep it down!
Don't worry, nobody's listening!
But 100 million just for handing over that case?
What in the world was inside it?
Information about gold.
Information that's worth more than 100 million once it's put to use.
Probably's already sitting back down, smiling with glee
and looking out at the last scenic view that the fool will ever get to see...
Last scenic view?
Included inside the black case we handed over...
...was a bomb that'll detonate in 10 seconds after receiving a large shock!
A bomb?!
So if they accidentally drop the case...
The information is too important.
I doubt that would happen...
And besides, the explosion is set for 3:10.
It's a time bomb?
No. But when the time comes,
they'll unknowingly press the detonation button themselves.
10 seconds later, the entire bullet train gets blasted into pieces.
Into pieces?!
I mean, 8 times 8 equals?
64!
Don't you mean "Happa 64"?
Oh, right!
8 times 8 is 64!
8 times 9...
72!
Stupid kid had me scared there for a second!
Now arriving at Nagoya!
Hurry! We're getting off!
Wait! There's still something I want to ask you!
Wait!
Not so fast!
- Let go! Let go!
- I can't let you out of my sight, Conan-kun.
This is bad! Without them on board—
Wait. The person they made the transaction with is still inside!
Oh, man! 40 minutes until it explodes!
I have to find the person before then!
But how?! There's hundreds of passengers onboard!
Conan-kun!
Where could he have gone...
A bomb?!
Yeah! Someone onboard has a bomb!
We have to stop the train at the next station
and evacuate all the passengers!
This train's gonna be blown to smithereens!
Now, now. Don't be teasing grownups.
Hold on. It isn't nice to disregard him
just because he's a kid.
Wait a second while I call Anpan Man for help!
No good! They don't believe me one bit!
What should I do?!
Conan-kun! Is anything interesting going on?
Let us know if you find another case to solve!
Are these the only guys who'll listen to me?!
There are tons of black briefcases;
checking them all would be impossible!
Damn it! Is my only option to look for the bomb alone?
Find a clue!
Remember back to the beginning of their conversation!
I can finally have a smoke.
What does that mean?
The dining car isn't non-smoking...
Ah! The person they met doesn't like cigarette smoke!
Meaning that person doesn't smoke!
Which means the person's in a non-smoking car!
Let's see, how many non-smoking cars were on this train...
Eight!
Why do you ask?
Are we solving a mystery?!
There have to be more clues!
100 million just for handing over that case?
What in the world was inside it?
Information about gold.
Probably's already sitting back down, smiling with glee
and looking out at the last scenic view that the fool will ever get to see...
Where on this train can you see scenic views from the windows?!
The 2-story Green Cars!
Erm...
There are 3 Green Cars, right?
Which ones are non-smoking?
That would be the second floor of Car 7!
What's there?!
I dunno what's goin' on, but let's go anyway!
No, it's too dangerous for children—
We're the Detective Boys! Let's go!
Who could have the black briefcase with the bomb in it?!
One...
Two...
Three...
Four...
I'll have to check them each one by one!
Stock trading and a gold Rolex!
He's rakin' in the dough all right...
Here goes!
Hey! Can I play that game too?
This is not a toy!
Liar! There's a bunch of circles and rectangles on the screen!
You're disrupting my work! Go away!
Big meanie!
Then let me play this black one!
It's a game too, right?
Owie!
What's the matter, little boy? Are you lost?
Wow!
What a good view this is!
Isn't it? The weather is clear today so you can see Mt. Fuji from there!
Mt. Fuji?!
Do you like Mt. Fuji?
Yeah! I love it!
Damn! It's locked!
Shut up already! What part of
"go away" don't you understand?!
Ugh.
Say, did you go to the dining car?
Eh? Why do you ask?
I just thought you looked like the person who was there
with some men dressed in black.
Oh, you must have the wrong person then.
I haven't been to the dining car.
What about you, Mister?
As if I could go anywhere when I'm this busy!
Sorry!
Hey, did you go to the dining car a little while ago?
I said, did you go to the dining car a little while ago?!
Why yes I did!
No matter how many times I go,
Disneyland is always fun!
This isn't working out. I'll come back to him later!
Gold rims!
Hey! Did you go to the dining car—
What?
I guess it's really none of my business, is it?
That's a napkin from the dining car!
This guy's been there!
Here goes!
Hey, my paper airplane got stuck up there.
You don't mind if I get it, do you?
Okay?
Huh? Where is it? I can't find it!
Don't touch that!
Included inside the black case we handed over...
...was a bomb that'll detonate in 10 seconds after receiving a large shock!
Oh no!
Nice catch, Genta-kun!
Excellent job!
What is this, anyway?
It's a—
Will you knock it off already?!
Underwear?!
You lousy kids!
And stay out!
Conan-kun! The rest of you too! Give it a rest!
14 minutes until it explodes!
But that's one person down! Only three to go!
Who has the bomb?!
Damn those freaks!
It's a time bomb?
No. But when the time comes,
they'll unknowingly press the detonation button themselves.
That's it!
That means the explosion's set off by the person's reaction to something...
The three people have a laptop, a cell phone, and a tape player!
No good! They're all suspect!
I'm still missing something!
No you don't!
Where do you think you're going?
I told you to sit here and behave yourself!
But I need to go to the bathroom—
You just went.
I'm thirsty—
Just put up with it.
Gifts?
You're supposed to buy those on your way back!
A walk?
No!
You sure do like to get into trouble...
Oh no! 7 minutes left!
The only choice now is to explain everything
and have all the passengers evacuate!
But nobody'll believe me because I'm a kid!
There's only one way to make her believe me!
If I tell her that I'm actually Shin'ichi Kudo,
Ran would have to believe me!
Everyone would believe her if she told them!
If the bomb explodes, Ran and I and all the other passengers are...
Say, Ran.
Look, it's not "Ran", it's "Ran-neechan"!
You're supposed to use name suffixes for older people!
Listen to me, Ran.
You did it again!
This is serious!
I'm sorry, Ran.
I've been hiding something from you this whole time.
Hiding?
I'm neither Conan Edogawa
nor a grade school student!
I'm...
I'm actually...
Did we pass the ocean already?!
Yeah, while you were looking away.
But these seats face the mountains!
We wouldn't have seen it anyway!
Facing the mountains?!
What a good view this is!
Isn't it? The weather is clear today so you can see Mt. Fuji from there!
I'm sure those seats faced the ocean!
It would be impossible to see Mt. Fuji!
Then where did she see Mt. Fuji from?
The dining car!
Not good! Only one minute left!
Attention, passengers.
As using cellular phones may disturb other passengers,
we ask that you step onto the outside deck before using your phone.
That's it! The cell phone!
Now what?
Hey! Ran-neechan says she'll buy us any yummy food we want!
Alright! I'll take an eel boxed lunch!
I want sushi!
I'd like a full course of French cuisine!
It's impossible to plan for someone to press a key or button
on a laptop or tape player at exactly 3:10!
But a phone!
It's entirely possible to have a predetermined time or phone number!
Too late!
Hello?
10 seconds later, the entire bullet train gets blasted into pieces.
What was that?
W-Who are you...
Conan Edogawa. A detective!
D-Detective?!
Hey, you! What have you done this time?!
I'm just a grade school student though!
Afterward, the bullet train was stopped
and Inspector Megure and his men began their investigation.
Being late to the wedding was a problem in itself,
but things somehow came to an end
without anyone getting hurt.
It turns out she bought inside information about the trading market
from the two men for 100 million yen.
Apparently she was supposed to call them on a specific phone
at a specific time to find out
how to open the case.
But the two planned from the start to get rid of her after getting the money.
They were caught and arrested by an emergency police inspection line.
I really jumped to conclusions though...
Where did the real men in black who shrunk me go?!
Damn it! I'll never give up!
I'll catch up to you someday!
I swear it!
NEXT TIME... "TURNING POINT ON A DRIVING DATE"
Say, Conan-kun. What were you about to tell me that one time?
Eh? What are you talking about?
Don't pretend you don't know!
You were serious when you said it!
I'm neither Conan Edogawa
nor a grade school student!
I'm...
I'm actually...
Who are you actually?
Uh, I'm actually...
A genius at getting into trouble!