"Kidnapping"
Kidnapping
Kidnapping.
Abducting frail people such as children or women, and demanding money or goods for their release.
An extremely cowardly crime.
Today, let's play back the kidnapping case
involving our friend Ayumi-chan!
Love lasts forever, riddles are puzzling...
...and Saturday nights are for mystery!
Ayumi-chan was kidnapped?!
Mitsuhiko and Genta's big
Detective Boys rescue operation!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
There's no such thing
as ‘the perfect crime’.
I'm sorry to say this, but your
crime is as clear as daylight.
You've made three very basic mistakes!
Mistake #1: Cans scattered around
the waste bin in an unnatural fashion.
The number of cans is proof enough
that there's something inside the bin.
Mistake #2: The ice cream bar you
were just eating is lying nearby.
Yes. You were in a rush to hide,
so you dropped it on the ground, half-eaten.
Mistake #3: The most
incriminating evidence of all...
...is that I can see your big butt
inside the waste bin, Genta-kun!
You talk too much, you know?!
Ayumi-chan! I found Genta too! Come back!
Already?!
It's no fun when you're ‘it’,
the game always ends right away!
It's no fun for me either!
A high school student playing
detective games in the park...
These badges are so awesome!
‘Detective Boys!’
We're the only primary school students
in the world with badges like these!
Yeah, huh?
There are tiny transceivers built inside!
You can communicate over long distances by using the dial on the back to change frequencies!
It's perfect for kids' games,
but I'd rather not have to play myself...
If they hadn't come over
to invite me to play,
I would've gone with Ran to
Teitan University's school festival!
Don't you worry! I'll have plenty
of fun with the university girls for you!
Okay! This time I'll be the detective
and you guys'll be the criminals!
I have to be a criminal again?!
We only need one detective!
Now get going!
Whatever.
One, two, three...
I love Hide-and-Seek!
Hurry, Conan-kun!
I can't believe I keep
going along with this...
What happens if this keeps up
and I turn stupid?!
Upsy daisy. Sorry!
99, 100!
Here I come! Time to show you all
the skill of the one and only Genta Kojima,
leader of the Detective Boys!
Genta's looking hard!
‘Multiple girls kidnapped and murdered.’
They haven't caught them yet?!
Scary, isn't it?
Ayumi-chan...
Cute girls are the only ones
they're going after.
That means I'm in huge danger, huh?
But I'm not worried.
If something bad ever happened,
you'd be there to protect me,
wouldn't you, Conan-kun?
After all, we're destined
to be together!
Come on now, Ayumi-chan...
Found you, Conan!
You may be good at finding people,
but you sure suck at hiding!
I hate running away
and hiding from people!
That's weird though, I could
swear I heard Ayumi's voice too...
Stupid! Hurry and hide!
Was there something there?
Just a cat!
Let's see... Somewhere for me to hide...
What's keepin' that moron?!
Lucky!
Found Mitsuhiko!
Odd. Scientifically speaking,
he shouldn't have found me.
What was scientific about that?
Okay! That leaves just Ayumi!
That dumb Genta...
How long can it possibly take him
to find an ordinary little girl?!
She is not an ordinary little girl.
Oh, never mind...
Guess l'll tune up the skateboard
the Doc gave me.
Umm, do you mind if I ask you something?
How do you... How do you
feel about Ayumi-chan?!
I'm asking you how you
feel about her as a girl!
As just a friend!
Oh, really?
Mitsuhiko... Don't tell me you
have a crush on Ayumi-chan...
No! I'm simply asking your opinion
to help me decide on my ‘life plan’!
Life plan? You're not talking
about marriage, are you?!
You're so lucky! The Doctor
makes so much stuff for you!
Gimme a break! Kids these days!
What took you so damn long?!
Come on! I already said I'm sorry!
We're in trouble if we don't get movin'!
Yeah.
You still haven't found Ayumi-chan?
Just give up and have her come out.
You moron!
I'd never say anything
that uncool in front of her...
I see! Genta likes Ayumi-chan too!
After all, we're destined
to be together!
What a situation
I've gotten myself into...
Ayumi-chan! Can you hear me?
Let's call it quits.
You can come out now.
That's strange.
Do you think she went
home without us?
Maybe something happened to her?!
I'll turn the volume up...
Ayumi-chan! Ayumi-chan!
Conan-kun?
Ayumi-chan!
Ow!
Conan-kun?!
Where are you?!
I don't know.
Somewhere dark and cramped.
How did I get here?
That sound!
It's a car!
Oh, yeah!
I hid in the trunk of a car
that was stopped in front of the park.
But then I got sleepy...
In front of the park?!
That car?!
What's this?! Awesome!
Money! There's tons
of it in a paper bag!
A million yen times 100, I bet!
A hundred million?!
Awesome!
The car must belong to someone rich!
Why would that much money be in a paper bag?!
Is there anything else
besides the money?
Let me see...
Yeah, there is. It looks
like a plastic bag.
Is there eel?!
Oh, look, a saw.
A saw...?
But what's this thing?
It's slippery!
Hey. You been hearin'
a kid's voice come from the back?
Knock it off. There's no way
that thing could talk.
Yeah, you're right.
Is the saw the only thing
inside the bag?
There's also something round
and wrapped in paper...
Let me see what's inside...
Stop! Don't open that, Ayumi-chan!
It's a head! A girl's head!
A girl's head?!
Don't tell me the car Ayumi-chan got in
belonged to those kidnappers
who're killing little girls!
Hey! Something's not right!
Yeah, I heard it too!
Let me check out the trunk.
Hey, unlock it!
Right!
Ah! So that's what we heard!
That had me scared for a minute there!
Don't cry!
Don't cry, Ayumi-chan!
They'll hear you if you do!
I know! Think of something funny!
Something funny?
Ayumi-chan?
I just remembered how
Genta-kun looked like a bear
when he fell down the stairs
the other day and got two bumps!
Ayumi-chan. You can stop now.
Be quiet and don't move a muscle!
Okay...
I'm coming to save you!
Okay!
But how are you gonna chase them?!
They're in a car, you know!
It'll be hopeless with that skateboard!
The Doc made this for me.
It's no ordinary skateboard!
It's equipped with a
high-performance turbo engine!
But it's solar powered, so you can
only use it when the sun is out.
One hour until sunset...
Are you stupid?
You guys wait here!
That car belongs to
a couple of murderers!
Murder, schmurder!
I can't just sit here
while Ayumi-chan is in danger!
Protecting women is a man's duty!
You guys...
All right, then!
Ayumi-chan! Where's the car now?!
I have no idea!
This car's weird, it keeps
moving and then stopping!
Plus there are weird sounds outside...
Turn up your badge's volume, would you?
Okay...
This sound...
That's it! They're stuck in traffic
because of road construction!
The only place around here
where there's construction
is at the intersection on 2nd Street!
We can still catch them!
Here we go! Better hold on!
Right!
Ayumi!
There's no reason to kill her, you know.
Her parents paid the ransom,
and besides, she's just a kid...
You fool! She's seen our faces.
We can't leave her alive!
Even if she is just a kid!
Bastards!
Hang on, Ayumi! We're coming for you!
Where's their car?!
Ayumi! Are you still stopping and going?!
Yeah. But it's not
the same place as before.
I don't hear those
weird sounds anymore,
plus the car just drove a long way!
Hold on. If they're in a
traffic jam up ahead, then...
That's it! The highway!
This is bad! There's no catching them
if they get on the highway!
Damn it! What do we do?!
There sure have been a lot
of police cars passing by...
Yeah, that's the fourth one...
Inspector Megure?
Is something going on?
...the kidnappers appear to have
escaped to Beika Town.
The authorities have
formed a police cordon
and are trying as hard
as possible to arrest them.
Ayumi-chan! Have you
heard any police cars?!
Yeah! About 3 of them passed
by when we were stopped!
There's no doubt about it!
They've set up an inspection checkpoint!
Probably where the roads converge
right before the highway starts:
on Beika Bridge!
Let's go!
Hey! Beika Bridge is straight
down that last street!
Don't be stupid. They wouldn't dare
go through the checkpoint!
They'd obviously take a side street to get out of Beika without going over the bridge!
They'll have to come down this street!
We're moving! The car's moving!
Bring it on! You're as good as ours!
Where are they?
It's already been 5 minutes...
Hey! What the heck's going on, Conan?!
That's odd.
Ayumi-chan! Is the car stopped
right now? Or is it moving?
What's going on, Ayumi-chan?!
Say something, Ayumi!
Did she go out of range?!
No, these things have a
broadcast radius of 20 kilometres!
There's no way they could've
gone that far in 5 minutes!
Maybe she's in a tunnel
or something?!
Beika Tunnel! That must be it!
No, they'd have to pass through the
inspection point and go over the bridge
to enter Beika Tunnel!
Which means they must be inside a
building that disrupts our signals!
You don't think it's
their hideout, do you?!
In that case,
they're like rats in a trap!
The police'll find them eventually!
Moron!
They'll find Ayumi-chan
before they get caught!
She's seen our faces.
We can't leave her alive!
Even if she is just a kid!
If something bad ever happened,
you'd be there to protect me,
wouldn't you, Conan-kun?
Ayumi!
...na... ku...
Conan-kun! Where are you?!
Ayumi-chan!
Why wouldn't you say anything, you jerk?!
Calm down, Ayumi-chan!
They'll hear you if you yell too loud!
There's no way they would hear me!
The car's so loud that
I can't hear their voices!
Do you know where you are right now?!
No! There was this roaring sound
and then you stopped replying to me!
Roaring sound? So they were in the tunnel?!
But how did they pass
through the checkpoint?!
We'll come after you right away!
Just keep quiet and wait for us!
Come on, faster!
The skateboard'll stop
soon if we don't hurry!
Conan-kun! It sounds like the car's
in some sort of shop now!
Shop?!
I heard someone say, ‘Welcome’,
and this weird sound just started!
Sound?!
A gas station! Which one?!
Ayumi-chan! Let me hear
what's going on outside!
Okay.
We're currently giving away Yaiba towels and T-shirts...
We don't need any!
We're in a hurry!
The only gas station where you can get Kamen Yaiba goods
is Yotsubishi Gas,
which we just passed!
I finally found them!
What was that sound, Conan-kun?!
Ayumi-chan's definitely
in the trunk of that car!
Hey, did you hear
anything strange just now?
It's just some kids playing pranks!
What's going on?
What's going on, Ayumi-chan?!
Ayumi-chan! Respond! Ayumi-chan!
Hey, something's definitely strange!
It's probably just a stray cat.
No need to get worked up!
Bastards! There's no escape now!
Huh?!
What's going on?!
They're getting away!
Oh no! There's not enough solar power!
We have to do something
before we stop altogether!
That's it!
Hey! Stop, you kids!
Stop the car! Or else I'll do this!
Damn kids!
Who were those kids?!
Hell if I know!
Let's just hurry! There's no time!
Move!
Ugh! My hands are going numb!
I can't hold on any longer!
Genta!
Ayumi! Ayumi! Ayumi!
It's those kids!
Who cares?! Let's just get her
out of there and split!
Right!
Who're you?!
Who is this brat?!
Don't kill me!
Stop!
What?!
Ayumi!
Here goes!
Hey, be quiet!
Ayumi! Get down!
Take this!
Ayumi-chan!
You're all here!
I'm so glad you're all right!
You had us worried!
It's all over for you!
You're the ones who've been kidnapping
and murdering little girls!
Murdering?!
There's no point in playing dumb!
We heard your guys'
conversation in the car!
Yeah!
You idiots!
Take a better look!
They're all hand-made props!
Props?!
Our conversation in the car was us
practising our lines one last time!
Practising your lines?
‘Teitan University School Festival’
We're performing in a play here!
Come to think of it!
Let's go to Teitan University's
school festival, Conan-kun!
I hear they're going to have
an interesting mystery play!
And besides, they said on the radio
that they just caught the murderer!
Inspector Megure!
So was that the real killer then?
Look at what you've done!
He's out cold, and the prop head's broken!
Well, it was nice meeting you...
Not so fast!
Yes?
You'll have to take
responsibility for this!
‘Deduction Theatre “We have no Tomorrow”’
Her parents paid the r-ransom,
and besides, she's just a kid...
You fool! She's seen our faces!
We can't leave her alive!
Hey, there's something weird
about that actor.
You think?
He can't stand up straight,
and he keeps blowing his lines!
You're so beautiful, Miss!
Let's do tea!
Let's do tea, let's do tea!
No thanks...
Oh, come on, now! Wouldn't you like
to see my Great Detective skills-
That's enough of that!
Genta! Say the next line!
I don't know how to read this word!
That's right — we were put onstage as a main character.
It reads ‘cruel’!
Incidentally, the role of the decapitated head...
...went to Ayumi-chan herself.
I hate Hide-and-Seek!