The Detective Boys head to a Kamen Yaiba show on the roof of Marutan Department Store.
Not knowing that we would face an unbelievable case there afterward...
Solving riddles with sharp powers of deduction!
The starting points of love and cases always remain the same!
Detectives versus robbers in a closed department store!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Created by
Gosho Aoyama
"Detective Conan"
Serialized in Shogakukan's
'Weekly Shonen Sunday'
Character Design
Masatomo Sudo
Art Director
Yukihiro Shibutani
Art Design
Hiroyuki Mitsumoto
Directors of Photography
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Ogawa
Sound Director
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
Music Producer
Hiroki Horio
(PolyGram)
Music
Katsuo Ono
Opening Theme
"Nazo"
Performed by
Lyrics
Music
Arrangement
Miho Komatsu
Masazumi Ozawa
Editor
Terumitsu Okada
Story Editor
Jun'ichi Iioka
Color Key
Reiko Hirayama
Executive Producer
Satoshi Kojima
Planning Support
Toyohiko Okuyama
Mitome Asai
Kazuhiko Yagiuchi
(Tokyo Movie)
Masahito Yoshioka
Director
Kenji Kodama
Presented by
We have you now, Yaiba!
Send him to hell, guys!
I, Yaiba, shall defend world peace!
Yaiba!
Take care of those jerks!
Use your kick!
Yaiba Kick!
I'm in high school. So what
am I doing watching this drivel?
Don't you like Yaiba, Conan-kun?
I love it! Go, Yaiba!
Okay, say cheese!
Talk about fun!
Thank you for shopping with us today.
Thank you. We look forward to seeing you again.
Bye-bye!
Bye now!
Yaiba! Yaiba! He fights for justice! Yaiba!
It's gone!
Yaiba's autograph is gone!
You lost it?!
Hold on a minute.
When we took the picture with Yaiba,
I seem to remember...
Oh, geez.
Let me see the picture, Ayumi-chan.
OK...
Here you go!
I seem to recall Genta saying that he was hungry when we took this...
Yeah! I bought a hot dog and then—
It's at that shop! I'm going to get it!
But the place is closed by now.
I say leave it for tomorrow.
Do whatever you want! I'm going to go get it!
Genta-kun!
Wait!
Hey!
Whoops. My deductive skills are to blame for this.
Please hurry! The security system
is going to activate in 10 minutes!
Genta-kun. That door's going to lock
when the security system activates!
I can get it in less than 10 minutes!
See you later!
See you tomorrow!
Now!
Wait!
Hey! Stop!
Ugh!
Yikes!
Here it is!
Yes! My treasure's safe!
All thanks to Conan-kun's great detective skills!
No, this was nothing at all...
We better hurry before the
security system activates!
No!
What now?!
If we go to the security guards'
office inside the building
and explain the situation,
I'm sure they'll let us out!
Really?!
Let's see here...
Security Office! Floor B2!
Kamen Yaib—
The jewelry store's on the 6th floor, right?
Yeah. And there are antiques in the
convention hall on the 7th floor.
It's the elevator lady—
Excellent. We have until morning
to take whatever we want.
It's a gang of thieves!
We're in big trouble if they find us!
They'll kill us! Let's get outta here!
But what about the elevator lady
and those other people?!
For now, let's stay hidden
and contact the police! OK?
Yeah!
Huh?! There's no dial tone!
The cord's been cut!
This one too!
They've all been cut!
Let's use this phone!
Nope. It doesn't work.
The phones must be down
because of the security system!
So nobody's going to come to rescue us?!
I want to eat a ton of eel
lunches before I get killed!
It's too early to give up just yet!
Please notice!
Hey!
Help!
Up here!
It didn't work...
Genta-kun!
Knock it off!
The robbers will hear us!
Darn, it won't break!
Give it up! The windows here
are made of especially thick glass!
Alright! In that case...
OK! Cut it!
You got it!
Come to papa!
What's that?!
Security office! There's a weird sound
coming from the 7th floor!
Roger that.
Hey. Use the security cameras
to check out the 7th floor!
I'm pooped...
I told you it was pointless!
Everyone get down!
Hey, Conan! What about the window?!
Oh no!
It's no good! You won't make it in time!
Nothing strange that I can see.
Nothing strange?! Those were
some pretty loud sounds we heard!
Let's go! Let's take the loot and split!
No. Let's check it out just to be safe.
Damn it, aren't there any exits around here?
Quiet!
Someone's coming!
Genta-kun!
Found you, you little brats!
Oh no!
Sorry I'm so late!
I'll make dinner right away!
They've seen our faces! Get 'em!
Everyone get on!
Here goes!
Come back here!
Security office! Do you read me?!
Turn on the lights!
What'd you say? I didn't copy...
There's a bunch of little brats in the store!
Where'd those lousy kids go?!
Hey! What's going on?! Hey!
What's going on?!
The other guys in the security
office know we're here!
They turned on the lights to catch us!
Let's get away from here!
Dad. Dad!
What do you want?
Conan-kun still hasn't come home!
How should I know where that lousy kid is?
Why'd you wake me up?
Dad!
What good timing!
Genta! Get out! Everyone out! Hurry!
What's going on, Conan-kun?
Oh! They almost had us trapped!
That was close!
Thanks, Conan-kun!
Save that for after we get out of this place!
I thought Conan was at the department store.
Didn't he go with his friends
to see some kids' show?
It's pitch dark outside.
Did you try calling the store?
Where's my food, anyway?
Are you trying to starve me to death?!
Not again...
This is Marutan Department Store.
We are currently closed.
Hurry! We need to get as far away
from them as possible!
Got you!
We will be open during our regular
hours tomorrow, from 10 AM—
See? So what do you say you
make me some dinner now?
Now who are you calling?
Is this the Kojima household? This is Ran Mouri.
Has Genta-kun—
Come back here!
Those voices...
They've been caught!
You stay here and hide!
Got it?!
Let go!
Where are the other two?!
Help! I don't wanna die!
Stop right there! This is the police!
We have this department store surrounded!
There's no escape!
Put your weapons down and release the children!
This way! Hurry!
Damn kids!
There's no police here!
Just those kids!
Damn it! They used a bunch
of stupid mannequins!
Don't let 'em get away!
Is this the Yoshida residence?
I'm Conan Edogawa's—
Eh? Ayumi-chan hasn't come home yet either?
I just had a call from Mitsuhiko-kun's family too...
What is it? What's going on?
Get up, Genta! Do you want them to catch you?!
OK, OK...
We're trapped!
Over here!
Damn it!
What is it, Conan-kun?
Did you forget something?!
No, that's not it...
I just realized something strange,
but I don't know what.
What could it be?!
Conan and his friends were kidnapped?
My guess is that they're taking
their sweet time coming home.
They'll be back soon enough.
I wonder...
So how's about some dinner?
Come on! Cook me some food already—
Is this the investigation department?
Inspector Megure, please.
Works better than I expected!
Geez!
Genta-kun!
You're a real liability!
I couldn't help it, I'm hungry!
Come back here!
Sorry to bother you at such a late hour.
Well?
There aren't any incidents at the moment
that might involve the children,
but it is strange that none of
them have returned home yet.
Could something have happened to them?!
I've put out a bulletin.
Don't worry, they'll turn up soon.
Thanks!
Now if you'll excuse me,
I'm in the middle of an important case.
Well, we've done all we can do.
All there is to do now is wait
for any reports about them.
Let's go get something to eat!
Let's go—
I've always wanted to do this at least once!
Forgive us. We'll pay for this
if we make it out alive.
I wonder if we even will make it out alive...
Don't look so down, Genta-kun!
You've had plenty to eat now, so cheer up!
We're going to take care of them
and get out of here!
In the name of the Detective Boys!
In the name of...
...the Detective Boys...
Yeah, it must be a pretty important case
if they're still at it this late...
Are you trying to say that Conan-kun
and the others aren't important?!
No, that's not what I meant...
Darn that Conan...
I'm missing my dinner thanks to him...
A gang of department store thieves?
They sneak in after the stores close
and steal jewelry and electronics...
Could this be the important
case he was talking about?
Department store?!
It couldn't be...
Calm down, Ran!
OK! Commence counterattack!
back mirror ni utsutta keshiki-dake
Baby, stick the view from the rear-view in your window
Now where are they hiding?!
kimi no mado ni kazaritsukete-kure
Baby, stick the view from the rear-view in your window
Over there!
nariyuki-makase no michi mo aru
Some paths everyone can climb easily
sanzan dareka ga to'otta michi
Others are a pain for anyone
I don't handle alcohol well...
tsumazuite mo korogatte-miro
If you trip up, don't bother trying to pick yourself up
oto no niwa de odotte-miru to ii sa
Go ahead and dance in this garden of sound!
Me neither...
Mitsuhiko-kun!
oite-yuku heishi no
The loneliness of the aging soldiers vanishing pierces through my heart,
kiesaru sono kodoku wa
mune o utsu keredo
The loneliness of the aging soldiers vanishing pierces through my heart,
dou-tte koto wa nai no sa Baby
but what's that matter? Baby, the earth still goes round
chikyuu wa mawaru
Damn kids!
Happy End ga matte-iru
There's a happy end waiting for us
You'll pay! We can't let you live!
waraenai joke de mo kuridashite
Go ahead and tell bad jokes one after another
sameteru gaki-domo o kemuri ni make
We'll leave those pretentious brats in the dust
I'm not good with animals!
umaku itte mo utagatte-miro
Even if you're doing well, don't give up your skepticism
That's it...
oto no niwa de hajikete-miru to ii sa
Go ahead and get this garden of sound jumping!
Fetch!
oite-yuku heishi no
The loneliness of the aging soldiers vanishing remains in my heart,
kiesaru sono kodoku wa
mune ni nokoru kedo
The loneliness of the aging soldiers vanishing remains in my heart,
dou-tte koto wa nai no sa Baby
but what's that matter! Baby, the sun will rise again
hi wa mata noboru
Happy End ga matte-iru
There's a happy end waiting for us
We did it!
Hurray for the Detective Boys!
Wait a second!
Aha! Now I get it!
Who's there?!
It's me, elevator lady.
What are you doing here, little boy?
Never mind that, we're in danger—
there are some bad people here.
Let's escape together.
You can drop the act.
I know what's going on, elevator lady.
Or should I say, the 5th member of the thief gang!
W-What are you talking about?
It was a 5th person who
activated the escalator earlier.
This person had been waiting
to catch all four of us at once.
Among the remaining people
in the security office,
you were the only one who knew
how many of us there were.
You planned in advance to get inside
by getting a job as an elevator girl
so that you could scout out the place.
Who in the world are you?!
Conan Edogawa. A detective.
Excellent deductive work, boy.
But it seems you didn't know that
I was actually the gang's boss.
A pistol?!
It's not fair that you have a gun!
Stop!
OK! I'll lure her onto the roof!
The game's over, little boy! Come on out!
There you are!
Basketballs!
Annoying little brat!
Stop your pointless resistance!
Go!
Damn it!
Let me down!
I did it!
What in the world?
These are the thieves! Take them into custody!
I don't feel so good...
What a bunch of silly kids!
You can say that again.
Kimi e no uso
The following day, we were
given an award ceremony
for capturing the thieves.
We didn't have to pay
for any of the things we ate
or broke inside the store.
Is that really alright?
Don't ask questions!
Chalk another one up—
for the Detective Boys!
Yay!