"Closed Circle."
In the language of mysteries,
the words "closed circle" refer
to some sort of situation where contact with the outside world has been cut off.
For example, a mountain villa shut in by a blizzard,
or an isolated island attacked by a storm.
Or...
a luxury liner heading through the big ocean.
It doesn't matter how many times you try,
whether it's in love, deductions, today, or tomorrow!
A chartered luxury liner...
A serial case revolving around inheritance!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
"Detective Conan" is brought to you by these sponsors.
What a beautiful view!
We sure were lucky! I was worried for a while there!
Yeah!
He forgot what time our return ship left,
so we got to ride on this big one instead!
It was a good thing this ship just happened to stop at the island.
We would've been stranded out there for three days if it hadn't.
But I wonder what kind of people would reserve a ship like this...
Is something the matter?
No, it's nothing...
I was just thinking about my parents who died in an accident last year...
I wish they could've seen me all dressed up today...
All dressed up?
Is something wrong, Natsue?
Takeshi-san!
The two of us were married today!
Married?!
Shoichi's 2nd daughter
Natsue Hatamoto (22)
Natsue's Husband
Takeshi Hatamoto (24)
We had our ceremony this morning on Hatamoto Island,
the same island you were on!
Congratulations!
But why did you have it on the island?
The majority of the island belongs to the Hatamoto family.
We honor generations of our ancestors there.
It's a Hatamoto family tradition to hold wedding ceremonies on the island.
You fool!
We reserved this boat for ourselves, so what are strangers doing on it?!
I'm sorry, Father!
They appeared to be stranded, so...
How dare you go over my head!
Mariko's husband
Kitaro Hatamoto (47)
Head of the Hatamoto family
Go Hatamoto (72)
You must think pretty highly of yourself if you're making decisions without approval.
No, of course I don't!
Don't worry about it.
He's been in a bad mood since the ceremony today.
Yes, after he ate my food...
Uncle Joji-sama!
I knew he hated Western-style food,
but I had no idea he'd get that angry.
You call this food?!
Second son of the
Hatamoto family
Joji Hatamoto (41)
It seems my skills still aren't up to par.
Don't say that!
It was really delicious!
Say, lady-killer... What's with the flower on your chest?
Oh, Natsue put it there on the way back from the ceremony.
It's always been my dream since I was a little girl
to give my beloved this flower that only grows on that island.
Kitaro's only son
Ichiro Hatamoto (21)
Too bad it wasn't me...
Like father, like son!
How long are you going to let him to pretend to be an artist?!
You're his father, talk some sense into him!
Tell him to give up his hopeless dream!
Yes!
Takeshi-kun!
Yes?
I need a word with you! Come to my room later!
Yes, sir...
Just have patience, dear.
He isn't long for this world—he'll be gone soon enough.
Eldest Hatamoto daughter, Kitaro's wife
Mariko Hatamoto (43)
And when he is, nearly all of the Hatamoto fortune will be yours!
I wouldn't be so sure about that, Aunt.
What's that supposed to mean?!
Akie-san! Do you know something I don't?!
Shoichi's daughter &
Natsue's sister
Akie Hatamoto (26)
Don't be too shocked when you hear.
I-Impossible! That can't be true!
It sounds like Grandfather's going to make the announcement
when we get back to Tokyo.
Akie's husband
Tatsuo Hatamoto (26)
Gimme a break.
Does he even know we're up to our necks in debt over here?!
We have 24 hours until the ship arrives in Tokyo.
We simply have to do something before then...
It's me, Takeshi.
Enter.
Sorry to disturb you.
That was an exceptional speech you gave at the wedding.
Just what I would expect of the man whom Natsue chose.
Thank you...
Scratching your cheeks when you're embarrassed...
You're just like him.
Just like your father, Isao Zaiki!
Falsify your family registry all you want, you still cannot fool me!
I've known all this time that you joined the company
and got close to Natsue just to avenge your father!
What is it you're after?
Money?
Or my life, perhaps?
What's the matter? Why won't you speak?!
Answer me!
These are the main members of the Hatamoto family.
So all of these people went to your wedding, Natsue-san?
Yes! All nine of them,
excluding my late parents Shoichi and Miyuki.
Say, Takeshi-san is rather late...
Yes. He still hasn't come back from Grandfather's room...
I wonder what happened.
Maybe they're discussing some under-the-table business!
Sister!
You're late.
Sorry.
Dad not here yet?
Hatamoto family butler
Kenji Suzuki (64)
No, though I am certain he will be here shortly.
You're late, Ichiro-san!
Did you make sure to wash your hands?!
Yes...
Say! Do you have a boyfriend, Ran-san?
Of course not, she's still a kid...
How rude!
I'll have you know there is someone I like!
Right, Conan-kun?
Yeah...
What's he like?
Well, he's really smart, good at soccer, dependable, and cool!
What are you acting so embarrassed about?
And he's an even better detective than my dad!
You mean your father's a—
Oh? I didn't tell you?
My dad's a detective!
Sir? Your seat is ready, sir...
A flower?
Takeshi-san! You're really late!
Sorry, I was thinking about some things in my room.
Are you alright? You look pale.
Oh? What happened to the flower on your chest?
That's strange. Where could I have lost it?
Sorry to disturb you, sir.
Everyone is waiting for you—
Whose voice was that?!
The butler Suzuki's!
It came from Dad's room!
What happened, Suzuki-san?!
It's too late. He's dead.
No!
- Grandfather!
- Stop!
Everyone stay out!
Nobody's to enter this room until I say it's OK!
It would seem that 40 or 50 minutes have passed since Mr. Gozo's death.
You were the one who found him, Suzuki-san?
Yes.
Where were you 40 to 50 minutes ago, around 8:00 PM?
I was getting things ready for dinner at 8:00,
so I was in the dining room the entire time.
I did see Suzuki-san working in a hurry around the tables!
The door to this room was locked when you found the body, correct?
Yes.
What ways are there to lock the door?
It can be locked from the inside,
but you need this key to lock it from the outside.
And this window doesn't open, so it's impossible to sneak into the room.
In other words, this room was impregnable!
Impregnable?!
You're saying that my grandfather committed suicide?!
But it's strange.
If it was a suicide, then there's something important missing here.
The weapon.
He died of blood loss after being stabbed in the abdomen.
But the knife used to do it is nowhere to be found.
Are you sure it wasn't a dagger made of ice or anything?
Mystery novels are full of things that melt away and stuff.
Would someone seriously commit suicide with something like that?
I bet this is more of his harassment.
He wanted to torment us by making every Hatamoto here seem suspect!
He hated everyone in the family, after all.
Everyone except Natsue, that is.
Sister!
I wouldn't put it past the old man...
Then it's decided! It was a suicide!
This was a murder.
What?!
And an extremely simple one, at that.
You again?!
Here, take a close look at the doorframe!
See the blood?
If the door was closed when he committed suicide,
none of his blood could have landed there.
So it's more natural to think that he was stabbed while the door was open.
That's it! Somebody stabbed Mr. Gozo the instant he left the room!
Then who locked the door?
No clue...
Hey, you sure you're a detective?
That's it! It was Mr. Gozo himself who locked the door!
Someone stabbed him outside the room and then kept coming for him,
so he locked himself inside to escape his attacker!
But then he ran out of strength and died!
I see. That would make the most sense.
You're such a great detective!
Wait a minute! That means everyone had an opportunity to kill him!
The murder took place at approximately 8:00.
Ran, Conan, Natsue-san, and I were at our table since 7:30,
so none of us could have done it!
The same can be said for Suzuki-san, who was near our table at the time.
In other words, since the killer wasn't in the dining room at the time...
...it was one of you seven!
Suzuki-san.
When you entered the room, did you notice anything out of the ordinary?
No, nothing in particular...
Oh, now that you mention it, I found this flower in front of the door...
Flower?
That's the flower I put on Takeshi-san's jacket!
Come to think of it, you were really late coming to the dining room.
No, Sis, I was just thinking about things in my room...
Don't try to deny it, Takeshi-san.
I happened to hear you and Father shouting in his room!
I thought I was going to faint
when I heard that you're actually the son of Isao Zaiki!
Who's this Isao Zaiki?
He committed suicide when Gozo took over his company, Zaiki Industries, 10 years ago.
One year later, his wife died of an illness,
and their only son was apparently placed in an institution.
To think that that was Takeshi-kun!
Is it true, Takeshi-san?!
Takeshi-san!
Yeah. I'm Takehiko Zaiki, son of Isao Zaiki!
B-But I... I...!
...got close to Natsue-san so you could avenge your father?
You decided to become a member of the Hatamoto family
and wait for the chance to kill Mr. Gozo.
And then tonight, you did just that!
N-No! I didn't kill him!
Natsue! Wait!
I had you pegged as a pretty staunch fellow,
but it looks like I was wrong.
Joji-san!
You gotta be an idiot to drop your flower at the crime scene!
I didn't, I lost my flower somewhere!
There are wiped blood stains on the outside carpet...
Say, was that flower really here on the floor?
Yes, that's right, little boy.
What's this?
A bread crumb!
A bread crumb lying in a pool of blood?
What's it mean?!
Say, Mr. Butler.
Was there bread during the wedding banquet this afternoon?
But of course—it was an extravagant French meal.
Joji-sama made it all himself.
He runs his own French restaurant.
Did everyone eat it?
Yes. Everyone but the master.
He loathed Western-style food.
He said that just looking at bread would make him nauseous.
If Joji-san's a chef, he has kitchen knives of his own, right?
Naturally. Chefs like him always own their own set.
Come now, children shouldn't pry into other people's business.
Get in there!
Cool off in this storeroom for a while.
Open up!
I didn't do it! I didn't kill him!
Here you are.
Thank you!
Here you go, little boy.
You sure are lucky, Aunt Mariko-sama.
Now that Takeshi-san has killed the old man,
he'll never make that stupid
announcement about his inheritance!
That's true.
Now the Hatamoto Group will belong to you,
the husband of his eldest daughter!
And you can draw as much as you want,
now that your grandfather's dead, Ichiro-san!
And eventually, you too will become the Hatamoto Group's—
I don't really want that...
Hey, you ain't thinkin' of monopolizing the guy's inheritance, are ya?
Don't worry! All you grandchildren will get—
Sis, could you not talk about money on the night of our father's death?
Who are you to talk? You left the family to go be a chef!
I know that Father flat out refused you
when you asked to borrow money for your restaurant!
You wanted his money too! So be grateful!
Um...
I'm extremely sorry to say this,
but the master wrote up a will
just in case something was to happen to him...
What?!
I believe it will be read at the main office in the next few days.
Does that mean—
—all of his fortune goes to—
Natsue?!
Yes.
And leadership of the Hatamoto Group is to be given to the man
that Natsue-sama chose.
This can't be!
What? Then what the hell did I marry Akie for?!
Don't tell me you only married me to get my dad's money!
That's right! Why else would I live with a tight-fisted bitch like you?!
Who are you to talk?! You're just a worthless musician!
Go and get a real job!
Natsue-san?
What are you doing out here?
Nothing, just thinking.
About Takeshi-san?
I trusted him...
I trusted Takeshi-san!
But he only married me so he could kill my grandfather!
I'll never trust anyone again!
I trust him.
My gut feeling tells me that he's not a bad person.
He's the one you chose, after all.
He couldn't possibly be a bad person!
Ran-san...
Hey, what are you—
Hey, did you hear anything strange just now?
Did you hear anything, Natsue-san?
No...
No, I did hear something!
The sound of something falling into the water
and then a weird thud from the deck below!
Conan-kun!
Wait, Conan-kun! What's going on?!
The cause of death was most likely brain damage
caused by a blow to the head.
Judging from the wound,
the murder weapon was a steel pipe or something similar.
W-Who would do something this terrible?!
Don't tell me Takeshi's struck again!
Impossible. He was locked in.
Hey! Conan!
The door's unlocked!
Out of the way!
He's gone!
NEXT TIME... "THE LUXURY LINER MURDERS (PART 2)" (DIGITAL REMASTER)
He wasn't in the storeroom?!
We most certainly locked him inside, but he's nowhere to be found.
So Takeshi was the one who killed Father and Tatsuo-san!
The thud that Conan heard
was probably the sound of the killer hitting Tatsuo-san.
The splash he heard
was either the sound of the murder weapon being thrown overboard, or...
...the sound of the killer jumping into the water
after running out of places to hide!
Takeshi-san...
At any rate, there's still a high possibility
that there's a killer aboard this ship.
Let's all withdraw to the dining room for now.
Are you saying he could be trying to kill me?!
Have you forgotten?!
His motive for murder was to exact revenge on Gozo Hatamoto,
who drove his father to suicide 10 years ago!
But for all we know...
...he could be trying to kill everyone in the Hatamoto family!
Next Conan's Hint: Sketch book