"Closed Circle."
Being isolated from the outside world,
the culprit is trapped among people in the same location and situation,
intervention by police and scientific investigation are impossible,
and the answer must be reached purely by logical methods of thought.
In other words, the detectives in attendance are on the same standing as you who are viewing.
Everyone, can you unmask the culprit?
It doesn't matter how many times you try,
whether it's in love, deductions, today, or tomorrow!
The true killer lurking in the shadows...
The Hatamoto family's painful secret!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
"Detective Conan" is brought to you by these sponsors.
We were nearly stranded on an island
before we were picked up by a ship that the Hatamoto family had reserved.
Including the three of us and the butler, there were only ten people onboard.
On our way back to land, Gozo Hatamoto,
head of the Hatamoto family, was murdered in his room.
The main suspect was Takeshi Hatamoto,
who entered the family by marrying Natsue Hatamoto.
He turned out to be the son of Isao Zaiki,
who killed himself after Gozo took over his company 10 years earlier!
Since he had a motive, everyone decided to lock Takeshi in a storeroom.
It looked like the case was closed, but there was more to come.
Tatsuo Hatamoto, Akie's husband, was found dead,
and Takeshi had escaped from the storeroom!
Tatsuo!
Sister...
Akie Hatamoto
It's your fault!
This never would've happened
if you hadn't brought Takeshi into our family!
What do you have to say for yourself?!
Kitaro Hatamoto
Ichiro Hatamoto
You certainly are lucky!
Now that Takeshi-san's killed Father, all of his fortune belongs to you!
Mariko Hatamoto
Y-You can't be serious! I don't care about his fortune!
We're still not certain that Takeshi-san is the one responsible, you know.
C-Conan-kun!
The storeroom door was unlocked when we checked it out, right?
Yeah, that's right...
He couldn't have gotten out
unless someone unlocked it from the outside.
T-That's right...
There were no signs of damage on the door, either...
So if someone did unlock it,
then he has an accomplice in this room!
Takeshi Hatamoto
So let me get this straight.
At the time of Tatsuo-san's murder,
Joji Hatamoto
the three of you were alone in your private rooms,
while you two were together in your shared room.
Well, I couldn't sleep, so I went for a little walk...
Which means that just like the first murder,
aside from everyone who was with Natsue-san,
nobody here has an alibi!
You gotta be kidding me! My husband just died!
Why am I a suspect?!
You're the one who's happiest to see him dead.
I know that you've been seeing other men!
You had a big enough reason to kill Grandfather!
You're the one who wanted his inheritance the most!
Stop it, you two! Please!
Did you draw that, Ichiro-san?
That's Natsue-san, isn't it?
And your son Ichiro isn't exempt either!
Am I wrong?
I'm sure he was pretty pissed
after Grandfather tore up his prize-winning drawing!
That was Father's fault—he never recognized this boy's talent!
Tatsuo always made fun of you, didn't he?
"Depressed introvert" and stuff like that...
No! I didn't kill him!
And the one who wanted to be free of Grandfather the most...
...was you, Uncle Kitaro-sama!
What?
Ichiro! Where are you going?
The restroom.
Will you be alright by yourself?
I'll be fine. I'm not a weakling like my father!
Ichiro...
Hey, Mr. Butler...
Did something happen between Kitaro-san and the old man?
Kitaro-sama has wanted to leave the Hatamoto family for a long time.
He says he doesn't have the ambition to run the family company.
But the master was greatly opposed to the idea...
But even if he wasn't against it,
I don't think his wife Mariko-sama would have allowed it either...
Detective!
It's been 20 minutes, but Ichiro still isn't back from the restroom!
Don't tell me Takeshi got him!
Calm down! Stay where you are!
What?! But Ichiro isn't back yet!
Ichiro!
You mustn't leave the room, ma'am!
Hey! Ran and Conan! Are you there?!
Dad?!
Over here!
I'm going to the electrical room!
You two head for the restroom!
The restrooms were this way, right?
Wasn't that Ichiro-san's voice?!
Dammit!
Ow!
Ichiro!
M-My leg!
Hang in there, Ichiro!
He's alright! The wound isn't deep!
We need to bandage it up right away!
I'll get the first-aid kit!
Who did this to you?!
I don't know...
The lights suddenly went out and then I sensed someone come in...
And then they stabbed me!
That's...
...my knife.
Don't tell me you did this, Joji!
Hold on!
I was with you all in the dining room
when the power went out!
I couldn't have done this!
T-That's true...
There is only one person who could have done it!
Takeshi-kun!
No, that's not necessarily the case.
Let Natsue-san and Ran take care of Ichiro-kun's bandage.
I'd like the rest of you to come to the electrical room with me.
Is there something here?
Yes. Have a look for yourself.
What is this?
It's a type of timing device.
This one is simple enough for anyone to set up.
You attach a heavy weight to the breaker,
balance it around a fulcrum,
and then put a candle in the middle.
After enough time passes, the rope burns apart,
which causes the weight to pull down on the breaker.
Judging from how much of the candle has melted,
this was all set up quite a while ago.
In other words, any one of you could be
responsible for the power outage.
At any rate, I'll take the responsibility of finding Takeshi-san.
Until I do, I don't want any of you
to take a step out of the dining room!
He's not in Kitaro's room.
These two seem to have rather different personalities.
Is their marriage holding up well?
Yes. They're both cousins, and although it may not look like it,
they've been good friends since they were little.
T-They're cousins and they're married?!
Yes. Come to think of it,
the master was extremely opposed to them, too.
"Them, too"?
Doesn't look like he's in Joji-san's room, either.
Hey, is this his knife case?
What?!
Two of his knives are missing!
What does it mean?
One knife we found right after Ichiro-kun was attacked,
but where's the other one?
This must be Ichiro-san's room!
See? These are his drawings!
That's no reason to enter the room carelessly!
Takeshi-kun could be hiding in here with a weapon!
Wow, he's really good!
Who knows, maybe there's a drawing of the murder scene here!
Yeah, right.
Hey now, don't touch those!
Alright.
He's not in here, either.
It would seem not.
Hey, what's this?
Charcoal. You use it for rough sketches.
Then what's this?
It's an ordinary eraser.
I see...
He wasn't in our rooms or in Natsue-san's room.
All that's left is Akie-san's room here...
I guess he's not on the ship anymore—
Did you find something?
No! Nothing at all!
Oh well.
Let's return to the dining room for now.
Hey, hey! Mr. Butler!
Do you know if...
Did that ever happen?
How did you find out?
Only the master and I know about that!
So I'm right!
The first incident, in which Mr. Gozo was killed...
The bread found near the body,
and the location of the murder weapon...
The second incident, in which Tatsuo-san was killed...
The splash and thud sounds
I heard at the time of the murder...
The person who unlocked the storeroom door...
And then the third incident, in which Ichiro-san was stabbed in the dark...
Each of these mysteries is connected by a single thread!
Hey, come here a sec!
What is it?
Did you find something?
Sorry, old man!
Huh? Where's Dad?
He has something important to say,
so he wants everyone to come to Akie-san's room in 10 minutes.
Something important to say?
Tell the others!
Come on! Come on!
The old man's voice is #59...
You know who did it?!
Yes. Someone on this ship was responsible for all three incidents.
Who is it?!
It's obviously him!
It was Takeshi's doing!
Now, now, just calm down...
Before I reveal the killer's name, let us look at the incidents again.
First was Incident #1, in which
Mr. Gozo was murdered in his room,
which had been locked from the inside.
From the fact that there was blood on the doorframe,
Mr. Gozo likely escaped back into his room after he was stabbed outside.
He then locked the door, but fell lifeless soon after.
We later found a flower on the ground, in front of the room!
Yeah! Takeshi was wearing it!
That means he did it!
But there is one strange detail.
Even though Mr. Gozo was stabbed outside his room,
there were no blood marks in the hallway.
Are you sure the killer didn't wipe it up
to delay us from discovering the corpse?
I'm not refuting that fact;
I'm just saying that the flower fell
after the blood was wiped up!
I can understand if the killer accidentally dropped it
while stabbing the victim and then escaping...
But the killer meticulously wiped up the blood.
By leaving the flower there, everyone would've noticed it.
Especially if it was dropped during the middle of cleaning.
In other words, the killer purposely left the flower on the ground
in order to make Takeshi-san look guilty.
Next is Incident #2, in which Tatsuo-san was murdered on the deck.
Unlike the first incident with its flower
and the third incident with its fancy set-up,
this incident lacked any sort of artificiality.
If these were all indeed done by the same person,
my guess is that the second murder was an unplanned one.
Now then, why was Tatsuo-san murdered?
The answer to that question is in this case.
That's my knife case!
Have a look. Two knives are missing.
We found one of them at the scene of Incident #3,
but where did the other one go?
The main point here is in the two sounds that Conan heard.
The thud was likely the sound of the killer striking Tatsuo-san,
but what was the splash that came before it?
Here's what I'm thinking.
The splash sound was the other knife from this case.
If Tatsuo-san just happened to see it thrown overboard,
the killer could have killed him to keep things quiet.
That would make the most sense.
But Takeshi vanished from the storeroom after the second incident!
Yeah! Takeshi is the most suspicious here!
No, that storeroom door was locked from the outside.
Escape would have been impossible
unless someone unlocked it for him!
Who was it, then?!
Who opened it?!
The killer.
Tatsuo-san's murder wasn't part of the killer's plan,
and it took place while Takeshi-san was locked up.
The killer worked so hard to make Takeshi-san look guilty,
but this second murder would do just the opposite and prove his innocence.
So the killer unlocked the door.
This was done to make it look like Takeshi-san
had the ability to murder Tatsuo-san as well.
T-Then why did Takeshi-san run away?!
Yeah! We still haven't found him!
Let's have him explain that himself.
Takeshi-san. Why don't you stop hiding and come out?
He's in this room?!
Takeshi-san!
T-Takeshi-san!
Now then, tell us what happened when you escaped from the storeroom.
I-I thought something happened to Natsue...
I couldn't stand around doing nothing,
and as I was pounding on the door,
it suddenly unlocked.
I ran out of there!
And then when I went up to the deck...
Takeshi did it again!
Tatsuo!
Realizing that I would be blamed again,
I ran into Akie-san's room,
whose door just happened to be open.
After that, I stayed inside the closet the entire time.
So the person who stabbed Ichiro-san during Incident #3
wasn't him either...
Who was it?!
Why would they do something this horrible to Ichiro?!
Because the killer made a big mistake.
Mistake?
Yes. Unlocking the storeroom door.
The killer had managed to frame Takeshi-san,
but now it looked like he had an accomplice who had let him out!
It wasn't until then that anyone started to suspect the real killer!
Flustered, the murderer came up with a scheme
to avoid any further suspicion:
...Incident #3, in which Ichiro-san was attacked in the restroom.
But it was in this incident that the killer dug his own grave.
In the darkness, the killer shouldn't have been able to see Ichiro-kun.
Even so, he was clearly able to see Ichiro-kun well enough to stab him.
How could that be?
Moreover, the weapon was found lying at the scene of the crime.
Unlike the first two incidents,
the attacker didn't leave with the weapon!
No, the attacker couldn't have left with it.
After all, he couldn't go anywhere with his injured leg.
You don't mean to say—
That's right.
The person who stabbed him...was Ichiro-kun himself!
And the one who killed Mr. Gozo and Tatsuo-san...
...was you, Ichiro-kun!
Ichiro...
The reason you put the lights out
was because you didn't want to identify your attacker.
If you said it was Takeshi-san and then he was found innocent later,
then all the suspicion would fall onto you.
This is all conjecture!
Do you have any evidence that Ichiro's the murderer?!
This is the evidence.
The piece of bread that was found near Mr. Gozo's body.
A piece of bread?
Ichiro-san is an art student.
And right before Mr. Gozo was murdered,
he was drawing a picture on the deck.
Bread pieces are sometimes used as erasers for charcoal sketches,
and I hear that these pieces often fall into artists' cuffs.
When he stabbed Mr. Gozo, that piece of bread fell out of his cuff.
It fell onto Mr. Gozo's blood, you see.
What's more, this bread piece has a tiny bit of charcoal on it.
There is no doubt that it was Ichiro-kun who dropped it!
But he has no motive!
Ichiro had no reason to kill Father!
I, myself, couldn't tell what his motive was until the very end.
Until I saw something in his room, that is.
S-Something in his room?!
This.
This is Ichiro-kun's motive for killing Mr. Gozo.
How is a picture his motive?
The answer is in the drawing itself.
I don't see how...
Stop it...
Stop it!
Wait! All these drawings are of Natsue!
That's right.
Ichiro-kun was in love with Natsue-san.
I-Ichiro-san...
I heard from Suzuki-san, the butler.
Unable to reveal your feelings to Natsue-san,
you went to Mr. Gozo and—
It's true! I asked him to let me marry Natsue-san!
But he wouldn't hear me out!
He refused to give his beloved Natsue-san to someone like me!
And soon after that, almost as if to spite me,
he announced that Natsue-san was going to marry Takeshi-san!
And then when he yelled at me yesterday
while I was on the deck, drawing Natsue-san...
Tell him to give up his hopeless dream!
I couldn't forgive them!
Not my grandfather, who refused to let me marry Natsue-san...
Nor Takeshi-san, who stole my Natsue-san away from me!
NEXT TIME... "THE MISSING SWEETS AT THE OLD SHOP"
Takeshi-san.
Do you still feel the same way toward my grandfather and us?
I am the son of Isao Zaiki,
who committed suicide after the Hatamoto Group took over his company.
And it's true that I got close to you because I hated your grandfather.
But ever since I met you...
The tragedy was caused by a shy young man
who was unable to put his secret thoughts into words...
The ship is nearing Tokyo...
while being bathed by the red sunset that is the sadness and despair
of Ichiro-san and the entire Hatamoto family.