Reunions.
Usually a time for former classmates to meet once more,
and be surprised at how they’ve each changed since parting.
But sometimes, they can become
the scene of cases nobody could expect...
We won’t give in to the hot blazing sun!
A gallant and dashing deduction show!
A strange and impossible murder
among judo buddies from university!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Created by
Gosho Aoyama
“Detective Conan”
Serialized in Shogakukan’s
‘Weekly Shonen Sunday’
Character Design
Masatomo Sudo
Art Director
Yukihiro Shibutani
Art Design
Hiroyuki Mitsumoto
Directors of Photography
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Ogawa
Sound Director
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
Music Producer
Hiroki Horio
(PolyGram)
Music
Katsuo Ono
Opening Theme
Performed by
Lyrics
Music
Editor
Terumitsu Okada
Story Editor
Jun'ichi Iioka
Color Key
Reiko Hirayama
Executive Producer
Satoshi Yokoyama
Planning Support
Toyohiko Okuyama
Mitome Asai
Director
Kenji Kodama
Presented by
Why won’t you take us to your reunion?!
What do you mean why? It’s my reunion...
You took me to the one five years ago, though.
But we can’t let the office close!
What if something big happened?
But with you on vacation, the office would be closed no matter what.
We want to go to the hot spring, too! Right, Conan-kun?
Yeah.
Actually, I was going to treat you to a fancy meal instead of taking you!
Then we’ll pass on the meal and take the hot spring trip instead!
Don’t be stupid!
Domestic flights are even more expensive than international ones lately!
I don’t wanna pay for three stinking people! Put yourself in my shoes!
So the truth comes out.
He just robbed the bank!
Why, you!
Wait, you two!
Stop! You’re not getting away from me!
Damn it! Stay back or I’ll shoot!
Why, you!
Amazing! You caught a bank robber, Dad!
It’s like taking candy from a baby
when the great detective Kogoro Mouri is on the case!
But...
Boy! How did you make that brick do that?
Yikes!
I thought he was going to shoot you,
so I kicked it without thinking
and it just happened to hit the robber’s gun...
So you saved his life?
I guess so...
Then you’re obligated to take the person
who saved your life to the hot spring!
And I’ll come as Conan-kun’s guardian!
This has nothing to do with that!
Mouri-kun!
What are you doing here?
Yumi!
My company’s right nearby. I came to have lunch.
You’re Horikoshi-san, right?
Oh? Is that you, Ran-chan?!
It is!
It’s been so long!
Are you coming to the reunion at the hot spring again?
Of course I am!
Hey! Who said—
I can’t wait to see you there!
Wait, Yumi! Ran’s not—
I can’t believe you guys!
Excellent work, Kogoro Mouri-dono!
Thank you for your assistance!
This was nothing at all!
Hey, you’re not going to take the gun the robber had?
Oh, yeah. Over here.
That’s strange. I’m almost certain that his gun landed over here...
It’s gone?!
Don’t tell me someone on this street ran off with it during all the commotion!
Eh?! T-This is bad!
We need to tell HQ and get it back now!
What the heck?!
We only looked away for a second!
Who could’ve taken it?!
Eating while on a trip is the best thing ever!
Yeah!
Why do I have to take that little brat to the reunion?
What’s the problem? You took me to the one five years ago.
You were little at the time, so I couldn’t leave you at home alone.
You wouldn’t be able to attend this reunion if Conan-kun hadn’t saved your life, you know!
I could’ve caught that guy easy enough without the kid’s help!
Say, did they ever find that missing gun?
Yeah, what’s the deal? The police haven’t announced anything...
Apparently the police are investigating really hard,
but it hasn’t been used in any other crimes,
and they don’t seem to have any leads, either.
The gun was a Smith and Wesson M439.
That robber doesn’t know much about guns.
He paid a lot of money for it,
but he didn’t know the difference between a real gun and a model.
“Hot Spring Resort — Benkei”
It sure is good to see you all again.
Agreed!
It’s the first time since our last reunion five years ago...
...that everyone from the Beika University Judo Club has been together.
This sure brings back memories of all those days of intense practice...
Who’re you to talk?
You rarely ever came to practice!
That’s right! You constantly ditched practice
because you thought geniuses didn’t need to train! Right, Mouri-kun?
In the end, you were the only one who never won a single match.
But that was because—
I knew it.
Ran!
You were lying whenever you boasted that you were invincible
during your university days, weren’t you, Dad?
Hey, Ran-chan! It’s good to see you again!
I ran into her a while ago... She really has grown up!
Thanks!
Where’ve you been this entire time?!
The open-air bath.
The open-air bath?!
That’s a mixed-gender bath!
It’s alright, there was nobody there.
Right, Conan-kun?
Yeah...
You mean you two took a bath together?!
Yeah!
It was hard to get Conan-kun to go,
he was so embarrassed!
But that sure was fun, scrubbing each other’s back!
A nosebleed?
The bath must’ve rushed the blood to your head.
You sure he’s not over-excited
from seeing you naked?
Of course he’s not! He’s still a kid, you know!
I am so dead if she finds out who I really am!
Oh, so this is the boy Mouri-kun is taking care of!
What a cute kid!
It’s nice to meet you...
High School Gym Teacher
Yukio Ayashiro (38)
I’m Beika University’s judo ace, Ayashiro!
Nice to meetcha, kid!
Model Shop Owner
Jun Omura (37)
I’m Jun Omura, our judo club’s biggest risk-taker.
I was our so-called “point-getter”!
I’m Yumi Horikoshi, the beautiful manager of the judo club!
Cosmetic Company Employee
Yumi Horikoshi (37)
My name used to be Noriko Kimoto,
Housewife
Noriko Ayashiro (37)
and I also was the manager and idol of the judo club!
Now I’m this man’s wife!
I’m Nakamichi. I was captain and central pillar of the team!
Chiba Prefectural Police Detective
Kazushi Nakamichi (38)
I’m a police detective in Chiba prefecture!
Of course, unlike this guy, I haven’t quit my job halfway through.
That’s enough!
Every one of them is a judo ace or idol...
And as you all know, I’m the great detective and judo master once called “Beika’s Sanshiro”—
What’s that?
Is that our old university album?
Yeah! I brought it so we could all look at it!
Hey, now! Can’t you hear people out?!
May I see?
Sure, go right ahead!
Oh, this is from when we won second place at the city tournament!
Yeah, I remember that!
We’re all so young!
Now that I think about it,
Nakamichi and Yumi were an item back then, huh?
Yup. We cried together back then, didn’t we, Omura?
Oh?
You were definitely the judo club’s Madonna!
That’s enough. You’re my husband now!
Yes, ma’am.
So, are the two of you still—
Don’t be silly! I dumped this clod a long time ago!
And besides, he’s already chosen someone to marry...
Oh?
Hey, now...
You’re getting married, Nakamichi-kun?!
For reals?!
Yeah, well, I had hoped to formally announce it to you guys,
but the ceremony’s going to be sometime this year!
So who is she?!
My boss’s daughter...
We met six months ago.
I’ll introduce her to you guys sometime!
Conversely, the former Madonna is still a single woman...
On top of that, I might lose my job
because of the bad economy...
I really wish I were dead...
Just kidding! I just wanted to see how you would react!
Don’t scare us like that, Yumi!
But that means me and Omura-kun
are the only unmarried ones left.
Maybe we should get married!
B-But...
You’re so stupid! It was a joke!
Don’t take it seriously!
Oh? Isn’t this picture from when
we came here five years ago?
Look! I’m in the picture too!
Oh yeah!
We took this picture in the ping-pong room!
I stuck this photo in here too!
Oh yeah! What do you say
we play some ping-pong now?
That sounds great!
Let’s play!
But we’re supposed to watch
the fireworks in the evening!
Don’t worry. The fireworks start at 6:30.
We still have over three hours!
If we end before 6:00, we’ll make it in time.
I’ll pass.
I’m tired for some reason.
I’ll be resting in my room.
She’s still the same as ever...
She does everything at her own pace...
She just doesn’t want people pulling her down.
Anyway, let’s play some ping-pong!
Hot springs and ping-pong go perfect together!
I haven’t been this raring to go for a long time!
As a gym instructor, I can’t afford to lose to the lot of you!
“Ping-Pong Room”
Yes! Get ready for another!
Bring it on!
Where are you going?
To the bathroom.
You’re up next, so hurry on back.
Got it.
Say...
Didn’t you win an individual award
at a national championship before?
Yeah, only once, when I was in my third year at university.
So you must’ve been the best
member of the club, huh?
No, there was a guy who was much better than me.
I never beat him even once.
You had someone that good in your club?
You know him too, Ran-chan.
He’s even staying at this inn.
Who is he?!
Curveballs aren’t fair!
He’s—
What happened? That was pretty fast...
No, nothing...
Here you go, Yukio-san!
Heads up, Noriko.
You’re so silly!
Come on, how long are you two
going to play so stupidly like this?
Hey, isn’t it time?
Ack! It’s already past 6:00!
Oh no! We have to hurry! The place’ll be crowded!
Okay, let’s hurry!
I’ll return the rackets and stuff.
You go find us a spot.
Got it!
We forgot to wake up Yumi-san!
Forget about her. It’s about to start!
I’m sure someone’s woken her up.
But what if we all forgot?
I’ll go make sure!
Me too!
Hey, wait!
Ugh. They really should’ve left her alone...
Oh no! It started!
We have to wake her up right away!
Room 201. This is her room.
Yumi-san?
Yumi-san.
The fireworks have started already!
I’m coming in, Yumi-san...
Oh? What are you two doing here?
Nakamichi-san!
Didn’t you go on ahead?
We came to wake up Yumi-san...
You’d better not.
She gets real grouchy whenever
somebody wakes her up.
What are you doing here, Nakamichi-san?
I worked up a sweat playing
ping-pong, so I took a quick bath.
That’s when I heard you two running...
I thought it was strange, since we’re
the only ones staying at this inn.
What are you still doing here?!
I could ask you the same thing...
Oh, so you were washing off your sweat too?
Yup. But I was in the public bath unlike you.
But Ran-chan! It was definitely
best that you didn’t wake Yumi up!
She’s really grouchy when she wakes up!
I see...
She’ll still be mad we didn’t wake her up, though.
Of course she will!
It sure is crowded! Don’t let go of my hand, Conan-kun!
Hey, Ran! Over here!
Is it just you two?
Huh? Everyone was just with us...
They got separated from us in the crowd.
In that case, I’ll look around for them.
Wait, Omura!
He seems like a restless kind of guy, huh?
Y-Yeah...
I can’t believe you guys!
Me and Omura went through
the trouble to find a spot,
but not a single one of you came!
Sorry about that!
And Omura went to look for
you but never came back,
as is often the case...
Sorry, I forgot where our spot was...
Have some sake and forget about it!
You guys do things your own way far too much!
Hey, Yumi-san’s still not up?
Oh? Yeah, now that you mention it...
She should be awake by now...
She must be pouting because
she missed the fireworks...
Damn it! You’re all the same!
Looks like we have no other choice.
What do you say we all go and
wake up the judo club’s Madonna?
Hey, Yumi! It’s dinnertime!
Yumi!
That’s odd...
Hey, are you still asleep? I’m turning the light on...
Yumi!
Don’t touch her!
Nobody but me and Mouri are to come in here, since we’re detectives!
Ran-kun! Call the police immediately!
Hurry!
Right!
Yumi!
She’s dead.
A bullet hole in her temple...
A gun in her right hand...
Hey! Isn’t that the gun the bank robber had!
What?!
The gun is a Smith and Wesson M439!
And the barrel looks like it’s
been struck by something!
What’s more, Yumi was at the scene...
What are you doing here?
Yumi!
My company’s right nearby. I came to have lunch.
So Yumi picked up the gun because she
had intended to use it from the start...
Which means she had planned
to commit suicide at our reunion...
N-No way!
Why?
No, it’s too early to make any conclusions!
Let’s wait until the police get here.
Y-Yeah, good call...
What? Two hours until the police get here?!
Yeah.
They said the streets are crowded
because of the festival today.
Damn it! We can’t wait two hours!
We have no choice! We’ll have
to do the autopsy ourselves!
Yeah.
Does anyone have a camera?
I brought one...
Let us borrow it!
I’ll go get it from my room.
Who would’ve thought we would
be giving Yumi an autopsy...
Yeah...
All finished here, Mouri.
Alright.
Her toes are beginning to stiffen too...
Quite a bit of time has passed since she died...
What do you say we check for death spots as well?
Good idea.
But given the amount of blood that
she’s lost, she might not have any...
Hey, she’s not wearing anything underneath!
What’s the deal?!
You’ve got me...
That’s not all that’s strange.
But—
Look, she’s wearing a large yukata.
She was wearing a small one
when she was in the lobby.
And the index finger of the
hand that’s holding the gun
isn’t on the trigger!
But the strangest thing is that this bullet wound—
Why, you little—!
You’re always getting in the
way of my investigations!
Lousy kid!
Did you find anything out, Dad?
Judging from the state of her rigor mortis,
Yumi died over seven hours ago.
Seven hours ago... Which means around 3:00 PM?
That’s when we were in the
ping-pong room, after she left us.
Yeah. Most likely she returned to her room
and shot herself in the head
with a gun she had hidden.
Then there’s no question it was a suicide...
But why would she kill herself?!
Come to think of it, she did say something...
I really wish I were dead...
She really must’ve been thinking about it!
And then she did it...
Say, how did Yumi-san shoot herself in the head?
What are you talking about, Conan-kun?!
Don’t ask strange questions!
How?!
Isn’t it obvious?
She put the gun up to her head like so and—
Wait! Mouri! What is it?!
Mouri!
Tell me, Nakamichi.
Normally when someone
commits suicide with a gun,
they stick the barrel against their head, right?
Yes...
Then her bullet wound is missing something vital.
Y-You’re right! Burn marks!
Yes.
When you shoot a gun, a stream
of hot air accompanies the bullet!
If you shoot with the gun against your head,
it would have to leave burn marks behind!
The fact that there are none here means...
...t-that someone else shot her?!
Someone shot her and then tried
to make it look like a suicide.
Someone in this inn!
Tell me! What are you hiding?!
I saw her!
Saw who? The killer?!
I saw the supposedly-dead
Yumi in a window upstairs!
I’m going to catch whoever killed her!
I’ve finally figured out the trick the killer used!
You were the one who killed Yumi!
Next Conan:
Next Conan’s Hint: Ping-Pong
Look forward to the next episode
You had a bath with Ran-san?!
My nosebleed was twice as big as usual.
You perverted brat.