The telethon "24 Hour Television" is about to start,
so the stage of today's Conan is a television station.
A star who doesn't get along well with his producer...
The greatest trick in the first year of Conan!
Enjoy the atmosphere from back then as well!
Seeking comprehensive answers,
he solves every mystery and code!
A producer at a TV station is targeted with an unexpected trick!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Nichiuri TV
Nichiuri TV programming department.
One moment, please.
Hey, Suwa-chan!
Nichiuri TV Producer
Michihiko Suwa (37)
Call on Line 4 from Takashi Matsuo-san.
What do you want? I already told you no.
The announcement's gonna be next week.
No, I have this idea for a show I want you to hear...
TV Talent
Takashi Matsuo (35)
I was hoping we could meet alone
in the usual room when tomorrow's live show is over.
It'd really help me if you could drive people away right after it's done.
Ugh. All right.
This is the last time.
You're right, Suwa-chan.
This really will be—
—the last time!
Welcome to this week's edition of
"Japanese See-All Detective Station"!
I'm your host, Takashi Matsuo,
and I'm his assistant, Ayako Nagai!
Our staff sorts through all your rare and difficult cases
for us to solve on air!
Today, we welcome a very reassuring guest:
the great detective, Kogoro Mouri-san!
Thank you! Thank you!
Tell us, what was the most difficult case that you've ever worked on?
Actually, whenever I'm done solving a case I'm always overcome with drowsiness...
...so I never remember a thing!
Dad's such a clown!
Naturally. He really does go to sleep.
Alright! Commercial!
Ow...
Is something wrong?
My stomach's been hurting since this morning...
Say. Could you tell me where Suwa-chan is?
Of course!
Yeah, I'm in the 4th-floor meeting room.
Don't worry.
I'm checking the show out on the monitor.
Oh, and tell Matsuo-kun something for me.
Tell him to come here right after the show.
I used to be a police detective,
but I'm not very good with guns...
Aren't guns your specialty, Matsuo-san?
Didn't you train overseas and become a pro?
No, I'm not that good...
...I'm great!
His character is funny and he draws in steady numbers,
but only so much.
If I switched the host to the prettiest newscaster
and included lots of naughty segments, the ratings would double! No, triple!
I'd eventually be promoted—
—to department head!
Eavesdropping is a hot topic lately!
It's not strange for bugs to be planted anytime, anywhere.
That's why I switched to a cell phone!
That shows what you know.
Analog cell phones transmit electronic signals,
so you don't even need bugs to listen in on conversations!
Wow, he actually knows something!
Therefore—
Oh, Izumi-chan! It's me, Kogoro-chan!
Would you like to have dinner tonight?!
My wife?
It's alright! We don't live together!
Let's have a passionate night tonight!
—such dangerous conversations can be easily listened to.
Attention, all adulterers!
Make sure you don't let your guard down!
N-Now for the next segment of our show, "You Did It!"
We're going to play a four-minute video clip,
and it's up to you to determine the culprit!
My name is George Kirishima. I'm a private eye.
I can't believe he spent money on this lousy clip...
Yeah?
It's me, Suwa-chan.
Matsuo-kun?! What're you doing?!
The show's still on!
I wanted you to hear my last words!
Last? What do you mean?
I'm going to die. I'm going to jump off the roof!
What?!
Have a good look at my death!
O-Okay! I'll do something about your host job!
Just don't be rash!
It's too late.
So, do you know who did it?
This drama is excellent, as always!
Do you think them up each time?
Y-Yeah...
Why are you sweating?
It's my stomach today...
The clip's about to end!
I wonder who did it?!
The victim's sister.
So who did it?
The victim's sister!
Really?!
Did you know, Conan-kun?
I had no idea who it was!
See you again next week!
Your frankness really saved the day!
Matsuo-san!
Suwa-san seems to have disappeared!
He isn't answering the meeting room phone or his cell phone!
What's gotten into him? Go and see if he's there.
Yeah.
Eh? Why the meeting room and not somewhere else?
Suwa-san! Are you in there?!
Suwa-sa—
What?! He's covered in blood?!
Alright! I'll be there right away!
The elevator's in use! Let's take the stairs!
These stairs end at the 7th floor!
This way! Hurry!
It's like a maze!
Move, please!
It was him!
The victim is this TV station's producer, Mr. Michihiko Suwa, 37 years old.
The murder weapon was a handgun.
The bullet pierced his head, shattered the glass,
and exited outside...
Inspector. There are other bullet holes in the wall.
Two behind this poster,
and one by the clock.
Inspector. I found shells in the corner.
Four in all.
That matches the number of bullet holes.
And there's only one way in and out of here.
Which means it's simple.
The killer most likely barged in through the entrance
drove the victim to the window,
then shot wildly and killed Suwa-san.
The killer tossed the gun by his feet and escaped.
Has anybody seen someone who might be the killer?
Suwa-san drove everyone out, so...
He drove everyone out?
He was waiting for me.
He said he had something important to discuss after the show.
No eyewitnesses, huh...
But someone might've heard!
See! It looks like he was on his cell phone!
If so, then the other person might've heard something!
Right, old man?
Y-Yeah...
Y-You're right...
Okay! Figure out who he knows and who he talked to!
Yes, sir!
Matsuo-san!
Matsuo-san! What are your thoughts on this?!
Rumor has it you were going to be replaced as host!
Could one of your fans have done this—
Stop it!
Yes, there was talk of me being replaced.
But Suwa-san said he wanted me to remain the host!
But I will say this now!
I will carry on Suwa-san's wishes and continue hosting!
Oh? You called Suwa-san?
Yes. He picked up when I called at 8:15,
but there was no answer when I called at 8:55.
So the murder took place within that 40-minute period...
But why did you call him?
I asked him to find out where Suwa-san was.
I was on the air and I didn't
know his cell phone number...
That reminds me, I hear you're well-trained with handguns...
Y-You think I did it?
I was hosting a live TV show from 8:00 to 9:00!
So you had no chance to slip out...
No, there was a 4-minute video clip during the show.
During those four minutes—
Yes, I did leave the studio, but I went to the restroom!
Are you sure you didn't take a gun and come into this room instead?!
Come on, now! If you think I'm lying,
then try running from the studio to this 4th-floor room and back!
It would take at least six minutes!
I mean, I think it would...
Alright, Mouri-kun. Give it a run.
Me?!
Why do I have to do this?!
Six minutes, forty-seven seconds.
Can't you run any faster than that?
No! My heart's about to explode!
Inspector!
We checked the security tapes but we didn't see Matsuo-san on them.
It would seem my innocence is clear now.
No! Matsuo-san is the killer!
But how did he go to that room and back in four minutes?
R-Ran-neechan!
Where did you go? I was looking all over for you!
I was with the old man the whole time.
Where did you go?
Don't tell me you got lost...
I guess you could say that.
It's like a maze in here...
TV stations are built all complex-like to prevent guerrilla takeovers.
You certainly know a lot...
A TV station person told me earlier!
Yes, it is a maze!
But there has to be a shortcut hidden within it!
A secret path that takes you from the studio to that room and back
in under four minutes!
Oh? There aren't any downward stairs here!
Only the stairs from the 9th to the 7th floor
can be used to avoid the security cameras.
It would be possible to make it
here and back in two minutes...
A storage room...
Wait, Conan-kun!
This window's right above that room!
That's it! Rope!
If you used rope to rappel down!
No. If the killer entered through the window,
the victim would have been driven to the door.
But the victim was driven to the window.
Huh?
That blood splatter...
It stops at the window's edge!
And there's no blood on the window frame!
Conan-kun!
Here it is!
The fact that this is here means there's no doubt about it!
That's where the secret path is!
But I still have no proof!
Clear proof that Matsuo-san was the killer!
Whoops, I left my cell phone on...
Hello? Oh, hi.
Aha! There's the definitive proof
that you're the killer!
Come on, hurry up!
Who's in there?!
Your favorite idol, Okino—
Yoko-chan?!
Hey, now. Is Yoko-chan really in here?
Alright! Now to—
I don't know what to say!
These things don't do the job!
Mister!
Could I borrow that paint gun and TV camera?
Eh? What for, little boy?
The live broadcast of "Kogoro Mouri's Real-Life Detective Show!"
Excuse me, Inspector.
Might I be allowed to leave?
Yeah... You can go for today—
Not so fast, Matsuo-san!
I must ask you to remain there.
M-Mouri-kun?!
I wouldn't want the criminal to leave
when the detective show's just about to begin...
And that criminal is you, Matsuo-san!
H-How can that be, Mouri-kun?!
Inspector!
Detective Mouri asked for an AV feed from in here...
Eh?! Just a second!
I'm a bit fat!
There! All set!
Think carefully, Mouri-kun!
The culprit fired wildly in this 4th-floor room and killed the victim!
But Matsuo-san was hosting a live television show
in the 9th-floor studio at the time of the murder!
How could he possibly have done it?!
It is indeed impossible.
But it would become possible if he used the window
in this 7th-floor storeroom
that's three floors above you.
Yes. It is possible to go from the studio and back in under two minutes!
By using this room!
What?!
Camera! You're too close to the Inspector!
I wonder if they'll get mad that we're
using equipment without permission...
It's just an internal broadcast. They'll never find out.
Alright, now!
Sir!
Sorry! We'll stop them right away!
Who said to stop?!
I'll take full responsibility!
Broadcast this to the whole country right now!
Allow me to shed some light on the subject!
Hey, Conan!
Leave it to me!
Conan-kun!
Matsuo-san most likely stuck himself out this window,
aimed down three floors to the room in question—
The victim was shot in the head here.
And the window was practically closed,
so unless he flew, it wouldn't be possible to—
I'm gonna fall!
Hey, Mouri! What are you doing?!
Hurry and save him!
After Matsuo-san shot him like so,
he dropped the gun into the room.
But Mouri-kun.
How did the killer get the victim to look upwards from the window?
The cell phone.
The person who called the victim right before he was shot
was the killer!
The caller probably said he was going to jump off and commit suicide!
Troubled by this, the victim
quickly opened the window.
Oh? Does that expression mean I'm right?
Then what about the bullet
holes and shells in the room?
Matsuo-san prepared them in advance, of course.
If you want proof he shot from above,
there's a bullet hole on the
ground beneath the window.
Confirm this at once!
Yes, sir!
Matsuo-san.
You left the studio just as the video clip began
and came to this 7th-floor storage room.
After using said trick to kill Suwa-san in the room three floors below,
you returned to the studio before the video clip ended.
Am I right?
Do you have definitive proof
that I used this trick of yours?
Matsuo-san.
You've made one little oversight.
In your haste, you most likely forgot to turn it off.
Yes. Your cell phone is the proof!
I assume you know that the redial
button works if you don't turn it off!
Inspector. Give it a try.
It called Suwa-san's phone!
Matsuo-san.
I thought you said you didn't know Suwa-san's number?
I put this phone on my desk before the show!
Somebody must have used it then!
I'm afraid not.
I used that phone during the show.
Assuming you hadn't called anybody else afterwards,
it would've connected with the bar I called.
Who else but yourself could possibly use the phone
you put in your jacket after I used it?!
Matsuo-san!
I failed.
I guess having you as today's guest was a mistake, Mouri-san.
Matsuo-san! So you really did kill him?!
Yeah.
I didn't want to give up my role as the host of the show we thought up together.
Suwa-san said he thought it up himself...
That was the agreement.
He got credit for coming up with the show's idea,
and I got to be the host.
But then he suddenly told me to step down!
That was the last straw.
Looking back, before the program began,
I had the most fun when we
were planning it out together.
It's like they say—getting ready for the festival
is more fun than the festival itself.
I guess it's too late for that now...
A camera?
Well done, Mouri-kun!
Way to go, Dad!
You truly are a great detective!
What are you talking about?
Yeah! That was brilliant reasoning!
I'll just be going now...
Not so fast!
Alright, kid, what's going on?
Yoko-chan isn't in here!
And for some reason I get sleepy whenever I'm around you.
Come with me! You're going to explain everything today!
Mouri-san!
Yoko-chan!
I saw your incredible detective work on the monitor!
I was in the middle of taping a drama,
but I was so moved I rushed right over here!
Uh... Err...
That was nothing at all!
No idea what happened, but I'm saved!