Poisoning
"Poisoning."
A way to take one's life through poison,
where even the smallest dose is fatal.
When hidden in food or in a drink,
it's almost impossible to escape from it.
So today, let's play back the case where I exposed a skillful poisoning trick!
As quick as a veil of mist clears...
...we see through both love and cases!
A mysterious trick targeting a singer at his live performance finishing party!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Subtitles by Puto
Extra translations by bluesun
http://pu7o.wordpress.com
Why am I stuck with you guys
during Christmas?
That's my line.
Say, what's up with Shin'ichi-kun?
He only calls once in a while.
What's his problem?!
Christmas only comes once a year!
He's such a conceited mystery geek!
That he is.
He's always arrogant,
snobbish, and mean...
But maybe that's what I like about him!
Ran...
What about you? Is there anyone you like, Sonoko?
Of course there is. Tatsuya Kimura.
Tatsuya?
You know, the guy from Lex,
that rock band! Ta-tsu-ya Ki-mu-ra!
Dad got me invited to
one of their live performances!
I get to see Tatsuya in the flesh!
Wanna come, Ran?
You're going to meet them?!
That's the Suzuki Group's connections for you.
When is it?!
Next Sunday!
I'm going, I'm totally going!
You're pretty good!
Tatsuya Kimura (21)
Vocals
That's for sure.
Much better than some bands out there.
Tatsuya! You've had too much!
You know you have
a talk show after this!
Shove it, ugly!
Ugly?
He's totally plastered.
Katsumi Yamada (21)
Drums
Hey, hey, Tatsuya, that's no way to talk to her...
Mari's just doing her job as manager.
And have you been doing
your job as our drummer?
And you, Mieko.
Mieko Shibazaki (20)
Guitar
What was with you today?!
I'm sick of your sucky playing!
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Been waiting for you, Sumii-san.
I had my manager reserve this for us.
Gō Sumii (28)
Karaoke Box Manager
Thanks! I always
appreciate your business!
That said, it's sad that a former band leader
is stuck running a joint like this...
- Shut up. Don't make me take this back.
- Former band leader?
Huh? This song...
It's Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer.
I requested it.
For you, Ms. Manager.
Mari Terahara (23)
Manager
It's perfect for you: you did believe in Santa
until middle school.
Wouldn't you agree, Ms. Snooty Manager?
You jerk...
Fine. I'll sing your song.
Later, Tatsuya!
See ya!
Wow, she's good!
Damn it! What's he up to?!
What's with that sad look?
Hey, why's that lady crying?
Because I'm saying goodbye.
To both Mieko and the band.
You're quitting Lex?!
Yeah. I'm leaving
when this tour's over.
Everyone in the band knows.
Good riddance to that hopeless drummer, that bratty guitar player,
and that snooty manager!
That's...
Hey, that's my song!
Who requested it?
Tatsuya, it's time to go!
We're going to miss the talk show!
Shut up! I'll sing whenever I want to!
Fine, then.
I'll call the studio to tell them we'll be late.
Here we go! Bloody Venus!
Tatsuya Kimura passionately sang
his hit song, "Bloody Venus."
Nobody knew his voice
would never be heard again.
Nobody... except his killer.
That was awesome!
How was my song?
It was great!
Hey, Katsumi.
Gimme one of them rice balls.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Oh, are you really quitting Lex?
Don't worry, my solo debut's coming up soon.
Solo debut?
My new song's already done.
His new song's...
...done?
What's it called?
The title? It's called...
What's wrong?!
Tatsuya!
Get an ambulance... Hurry, go get an ambulance!
Right!
It's no good! He's dead!
That smells like cyanide!
Somebody planned this!
Who could've done this, right in front of me!?
The first suspect was Sumii,
the guy who brought the food.
He and Tatsuya Kimura
used to be bandmates.
But then Tatsuya went pro
and became popular.
It looked like a jealousy murder.
But he was cleared of suspicion
when we learned
that everyone had eaten the food.
Furthermore, toxins were found on the
victim's clothes and microphone,
so he had touched the poison
before eating the rice ball.
Basically, the killer placed poison on the microphone
which indirectly adhered
to him when he grabbed it.
That means it was done by
the person who sang before him...
...you, Mieko Shibazaki-san!
I hear you sang a
farewell song while crying.
Did something happen between you two?
Tatsuya didn't dump me!
He turned me down!
Mieko...
When I told him how I felt...
Sorry, Mieko. I already have someone I like.
She's gone right now,
but I'm waiting for her to come back. And she will.
I'm sure of it.
Then to pay him back, you...
No way! I didn't kill him!
Someone he liked...?
Inspector. It was Tatsuya who requested
the song that she sang!
She had no idea that
he'd be singing next!
That's why she couldn't have
poisoned the microphone!
That is true...
Say, who requested
his Bloody Venus song?
Hey, did Tatsuya-san always take
his jacket off when he sang?
Only at the start of every Bloody Venus.
Could it be?!
Inspector! What part of his clothing
had cyanide on it?!
His left elbow area, I believe...
On his staff jacket?!
No, there was nothing on his jacket.
That's it! Now I understand
how the killer poisoned Tatsuya Kimura!
And that killer is one of those three
who have the same jacket on!
Hey, guitar lady.
The manager and Tatsuya-san
were arguing earlier;
were they always like that?
Yeah. They argued about everything.
Tatsuya always started it, though.
She's not as bad as he claimed.
She's smart, serious, and beautiful...
And she never caused any trouble.
Inspector Megure!
What is it?
We found these in Tatsuya Kimura's locker.
I don't see anything useful here...
A picture... A band picture?
That's from when he and I had a band
before he went pro.
But only he and this person are still
in the music industry.
He wasn't the only one who left your band?
That person over there...
Tatsuya said that person's why he wanted to quit...
But that person's not in that picture...
Look, it's this girl.
She's really changed, though.
No way...
Too much, if you ask me...
There's something written on the back!
Lemme see it again!
I see!
But what a sad incident
this is if it's true...
You know who did it? How?!
Uh-huh. Okay. Got it!
Cancel the investigation!
Get everyone back there!
Did something happen?
He's back.
"He?"
A great detective you know very well.
Shin'ichi Kudō.
Shin'ichi came back. He finally came back!
Shin'ichi!
Welcome! Thank you all for coming!
Shin'ichi?
Shin'ichi Kudō must be watching with this camera!
Move, Sonoko!
Where are you, Shin'ichi?!
Let's begin unraveling this case.
Shin'ichi!
Though, what's with this song?
It's Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer, Inspector Megure.
It's a Christmas song, it's played everywhere during Christmas.
It also stirred up the
killer's hatred for the victim.
In other words, the killer is the one who Tatsuya-san requested this song for.
Yes. Tatsuya-san's killer
was his manager,
Mari Terahara-san! It was you!
The manager killed him?!
No way...
Stop kidding around!
I wasn't even in
the room when he died.
You could've poisoned him
despite your distance,
simply by having him
sing this song.
This was his hit song,
"Bloody Venus!"
Well, could you sing for us,
using the mic I've prepared?
There's no poison on it, of course.
Fine. I'll sing, if that'll make you happy.
Please wait! Why aren't you
removing your jacket?
Tatsuya-san always took his jacket off when he sang this song.
Isn't that right, people?
Y-Yes.
Well then, let's start over.
Oh, yes.
Don't forget the dance.
Wow! She's good!
Of course she is.
She used to sing with
Tatsuya in my band.
The manager...?
Well, are you satisfied?
Yes.
Now try eating
the food I've prepared.
You mean this?
Just as Tatsuya-san did.
Pick whatever you'd like.
Assuming you can, that is.
I'd rather not. I touched him
after he collapsed!
His hands and clothes
had poison on them!
I could've gotten
some on my hands then, too!
Then please check
her jacket, Inspector.
Her jacket?
Same goes for the jacket!
I put it on after touching Tatsuya!
If there is poison on it,
that doesn't mean...
No. It's not poison
I'm looking for.
A lighter!
Yes.
That's Tatsuya-san's missing lighter.
In other words,
that's not her jacket:
she switched hers with Tatsuya-san's
to dispose of the evidence!
She wiped poison on the
inside of the left elbow
so that some of it would
get on his shirt underneath
when he put the jacket on.
All that remained was
to have him sing Bloody Venus.
During his dance,
he threw the jacket off
and touched his left elbow with his right hand.
Afterward, he died of poisoning
when he ate.
But why would she do that?
Her motive is in the
photograph on the table.
It's from when Tatsuya-san was
in Sumii-san's band.
What about it?
There's no one else in the picture...
She is there, Inspector.
In the center of the picture,
with Tatsuya-san.
Can this be?!
That's right. That picture
of her is the very motive
behind this murder!
Don't tell me you...
That's right! I had plastic surgery!
For Tatsuya!
I fell in love with him back then, when we were on the band...
So when he went pro...
Come with me, Mari!
You can be my manager!
I was so happy when he said that.
I thought he felt
the same way about me...
So I got the surgery
to be worthy of him...
But his attitude suddenly
changed after I got it.
He'd constantly call me ugly.
He even had me sing
the Rudolph song earlier!
That's why he requested
the song for you?
He made me his manager
just to insult me!
And I couldn't forgive him.
I couldn't forgive him...
...because I loved him!
You're wrong, Mari-san.
Tatsuya-san had been in love
with you for quite some time.
Nonsense! What would you know about...
Mari! He's telling the truth.
Inspector. Can I have that photo?
This is a love song he wrote about you.
"I want to talk with the real you"
This isn't true!
It's true.
Those were the lyrics
to his newest song.
He always talked about you, you know.
Why's Mari so self-conscious?
Why'd she change her face for me?!
But he always treated me like...
He wasn't good at expressing himself...
I guess he wanted the old you back.
It can't... It can't be...
I see...
I'm waiting for her to come back.
Sorry, Mieko. I already have someone I like.
The girl he liked was the manager...
Tatsuya! Tatsuya!
Tatsuya!
The combination of a man unable to express his feelings
and a woman who hid hers, brought forth a sad ending
in her weeping and tears.
Only her photograph sadly smiled.
Geez. That's what you get for
using the name "Shin'ichi Kudō..."
She's been waiting there 3 hours
for you to come home.
I wish I could help,
but there's nothing I can do...
Ran...
Shin'ichi? Are you in here?
Shin'ichi? Shin'ichi!
Where are you? Say something
if you're there!
The lights...
Shin'ichi!
Shin'ichi?
Yeah, it's me.
I'm finally back.
Shin'ichi...
Don't cry, dummy.
Were you that desperate to see me?
Who would!?
I'm glad to see you, Ran.
Shin'ichi...
Wish you could see
yourself right now.
What's that supposed to mean?!
Well, gotta get going.
Still haven't finished that case.
Later, Ran!
Wait, Shin'ichi...
Shin'ichi!
"Your Christmas present.
Hope you like it! - Shin'ichi"
Now stop worrying about me, Ran.
A mysterious man delivered a sudden threat...
"Leave the jewels alone?"
What the heck?
Sorry, but you ain't stopping the one and only Kid so easily!
The next target's the largest Indian Sapphire, the "Blue Birthday."
The night I announced the heist for is on Aoko's birthday,
so I swore to myself I'd come back quickly,
but then some weird guys attacked me!
What are these guys!?
Detective Conan was brought to you by the following sponsors.
Next Kid's Magic: Moonlight
Look forward to the next episode!
Next time, my beloved Kid...
Sonoko, what about Kyōgoku-san?
That's totally different.