Face packs...
A beauty treatment used by women
to stimulate their skin's metabolism,
so their faces stay moist and supple.
But they can also be used in unexpected ways...
Trace the lines of your hand and you'll find a fuse—
the heart line—to set your deductions alight!
Every woman knows face packs freshen your skin.
But can they transform your mind and body too?
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Kojima-san! It's Beika Security!
Is something wrong, Kojima-san?!
Let's go!
Right!
Kojima-san! We're opening the door!
Do it!
Right!
Huh?
I'm sorry! Did I scare you?
No, no...
I was putting my face pack on,
so I couldn't answer right away.
Your security alarm went off...
did something happen?
No, nothing at all.
Must've been a glitch...
Chiba-san...
Looks like he's the culprit.
He must've crossed the infrared sensors.
They're so sensitive that this happens once in a while.
Oh?
Well, please be sure to lock up!
Thanks for your help.
Boy, am I full!
China has nothing on this place's Chinese cuisine! Don't you think?!
Actually, ramen's pretty much the same anywhere...
Oh, it's already this late?
Not good! Yoko-chan's drama show is on tonight!
Yoko-chan! I'm coming home now!
Wait, Dad!
Dad!
A-Are you all right?!
Idiot! Watch where you're going!
S-Sorry! I, uh...
TM Securities Employee
Takeo Izumi (25)
Watch where you're driving, will you?!
Isn't it your fault for crossing the street without paying attention?
Yeah!
What's your guys' deal?
Hello?
Yes. Megure-san?
Eh?! Police Investigation Section #1?!
Hello! Mouri here!
Why am I here? Oh, that doesn't matter!
What case are you on?
Eh?! He's involved with a murder case?!
Very well! You can count on me!
Wait, Mouri—!
Oh, no, you don't!
Give it up!
You just crossed paths with the peerless Kogoro Mouri!
W-Wait! I have no idea what's going on!
Don't play dumb! You can spout your excuses when we get there!
Would the police call a suspect on the phone?
But he's...
Inspector!
C'mon!
Oh, thanks for coming.
I've brought the suspect, as requested!
Huh? What're you talking about?
Think about it.
If Takeo Izumi-san were a suspect, we obviously wouldn't call him.
Oh, now that you mention it...
Yeah, I figured as much.
TM Securities, Beika Branch.
Takeo Izumi-san. You visited this home tonight, yes?
Uhh, no... Yes.
You came at 8:00 exactly, and left at 8:40. Correct?
I don't know the exact times...
How do you know the times so exactly?
He's on the security camera tape.
Ah! So he did kill her, then?!
Nope.
After Izumi-san left... Yes, at 8:50,
the daughter stopped by.
The victim was still alive then.
What's more, security personnel saw her at 9:00.
Security personnel?
A cat snuck into the yard
and set off the security alarms.
I contacted Izumi-san to learn more about the victim.
Oh, I see.
Who is the victim, anyway?
Ikuko Kojima. She managed a chain of discount electronics stores.
Businesswoman
Ikuko Kojima (50)
She was strangled to death.
Well, now that everyone is here, let us begin.
Mouri-kun.
Victim's Daughter
Chihiro Kojima (28)
This is the victim's daughter, Chihiro-san.
First to Find Victim
Juro Yoshioka (48)
And the one who found her, Yoshioka-san.
Now, then. According to the security video...
Izumi-san arrived at 8:00, and left at 8:40.
Chihiro-san arrived at 8:50, and left at 9:10.
Then Yoshioka-san arrived at 9:20, discovered the body,
and called the police at 9:31.
I assume this is all correct?
If it's on tape, then of course it is.
Her own mother just died! Why is she...
I take it your mother was still alive when you left?
Of course she was!
Or what? Are you suggesting I killed my mother?!
No, no, nothing of the sort...
Basically, that puts the time of death between 9:10 and 9:20.
Was the house locked?
The front door was apparently open
when Mr. Yoshioka arrived.
All other doors were locked from the inside.
Meaning the killer was one of these three who used the front door!
Well, time-wise, we can probably discount Izumi-san.
Hold on! He has a motive for killing my mother!
He was on the verge of being sued by her!
He wasted 300 million of her money on a lousy investment!
T-That was...
So it was you!
W-What?!
I don't think he's the killer.
Conan-kun...
If the time of death was between 9:10 and 9:20,
time-wise, Izumi-san couldn't have done it.
How's that?
Don't you remember? It was around 9:40...
9:40...
Oh, yeah!
What is it?
Come to think of it, he was with us in Beika at 9:40...
I see. It'd take at least 50 to 60 minutes to get there by car...
But he could've done it somehow!
The lady has a point!
But, Miss. Didn't you have a reason of your own to kill her, too?
Come again?!
What do you mean?
Her mother severed all ties with her because of her fiancé.
Apparently, her husband is behind bars...
Mind your own business!
And even if that were true,
why would I need to kill my mother?!
I heard you asked her for a loan,
but were harshly brushed aside!
You're the one who argued with her
and said you'd kill her someday!
W-What nonsense!
In any case, it would appear one of you two is the killer.
So, what brought you here tonight, Chihiro-san?
I was called here. To be lectured at.
And that made you snap and kill her!
Will you get serious, you lousy detective?!
L-Lousy?!
Now, now, Mouri-kun!
And what brought you here, Yoshioka-san?
A work-related meeting.
The circumstances definitely indicate it was one of these two...
Here's the tape. Let me know if you remember or notice anything.
First, Izumi-san arrives at 8:00 on the dot and goes inside.
And it's at 8:40 exactly that he leaves.
Next is Chihiro-san. The time is 8:50.
Then, 10 minutes later, Ms. Ikuko steps out to speak with the guards.
I see. So the victim was still alive at this point.
Huh?
What is it? Something seems different...
At 9:10, Chihiro-san leaves.
Then, at 9:20, Yoshioka-san arrives.
But as there's no response, he looks inside...
...and finds Ms. Ikuko dead.
Wait!
Rewind that!
Right there!
Say, why did you go outside?
T-To contact the police, of course.
Why would you go outside when there's a phone in here?
That is strange...
I was in shock. So I went to my car to get my cell phone.
You can't blame him; he found a dead body.
For someone who ran out shocked,
he did spend 10 minutes in there.
That's definitely strange.
What did you do for those 10 minutes?
And look, he's holding something here.
"Report — Ozawa Detective Agency"
I see. So this shows that you embezzled money from the company.
I'd be ruined if that were made public!
So I came to talk with her...
But that discussion ended with you killing her!
No! She was already dead when I arrived!
Like we can really believe that!
It's the truth! But...
...I thought if this document got out,
I'd be the prime suspect!
So then you called the police after hiding it in your car?
That's right!
You can give us your excuses down at the station.
I didn't do it! She really was dead!
You gotta believe me! I didn't do it!
What is it? Something isn't right about this body!
She was dressed for bed,
even though she was expecting visitors...
That's weird.
What's weird, Ran-neechan?
Her mouth is wide open, but there aren't any wrinkles at all!
That's it! This was a true death mask!
Alright, Inspector. We're ready to take her away.
Alright, then.
Oh no! It'll be too late once the body is taken away!
This body really is weird!
What do you mean?
She's in a bathrobe, and with a face pack on.
There's nothing unusual about that...
It's like she was going to bed,
even though she was expecting company.
That's definitely not how one looks before having company over...
But it was her daughter coming over...
But Yoshioka-san was supposed to stop by after Chihiro-san, right?
And she was strangled to death, right?
Y-Yes.
But Ran-neechan pointed out that it's weird
that her face pack has no wrinkles!
Eh? Oh, yeah.
It should have wrinkles if she was in pain with it on.
Check it out.
Yes, sir.
Which means...
...the culprit applied the face pack after killing the victim!
And put her in the bathrobe...
But what for?!
She was dressed like this when you were here, right, Chihiro-san?
T-That's right.
W-What?!
I wasn't the only one!
The security guards saw her, too!
Y-Yes. When I came over due to a false alarm,
Kojima-san was indeed dressed like this.
In which case, why would the killer redo her face pack?
Did anything seem strange?
It's hard to say...
Are you sure it was her?
What about her eyes, ears, or lips, for example?
Don't be ridiculous.
Her face was covered with the pack and—
Come to think of it,
I was surprised by how her bright purple lips
clashed with her white face.
She's not wearing lipstick!
You mean like Chihiro-san's color?
Aha! So you put the face pack on and met with the guards!
Being turned down for the loan caused you to kill your own mother.
Your first slip-up was the malfunctioning security alarm.
If there was no response,
the guards would've entered the house.
Surprised, you quickly decided to play the role of your mother.
With a face pack and a robe, you could fool them.
You are mother and daughter, after all.
But in your rush, you met them with your lipstick still on.
But you had to remove your mother's lipstick...
Since packs are applied
after washing the face and removing makeup.
Yes, I met the guards and put the face pack on my mother!
But she was already dead when I got here!
Everyone knows that she and I constantly fought...
I thought everyone would think I killed her, so I...
You have to believe me! I didn't do it!
There's no question that she tried to cover things up.
But it doesn't serve as an alibi...
All it does is change the time of death to be—
Change?!
If the time of death is changed...
What's this?
Hey, old man Mouri says...
What now?
No, none at all.
That's strange. Why hasn't it turned up?
Could it be?!
Umm, is it okay for me to leave now?
Sure. Thanks for your help.
I'm sure we'll need to talk to you again at some point.
Right, I understand!
Ow!
Conan-kun!
Geez! I told you not to hang around here!
I-I'm sorry...
Don't worry about it!
I knew it!
Well, goodbye.
Alright!
Here we go!
Dad?!
Hold on, Izumi-san.
How can we end this play if the main character leaves the stage?
W-What do you mean, Mouri-san?
I finally figured out who really killed her.
Dad...
But you just said that Chihiro-san did it!
I said nothing of the sort.
I merely exposed her cover-up.
Her unnecessary tampering altered the estimated time of death,
which ironically created an alibi for the real killer.
The real killer?
You don't mean...
S-Surely you're joking?!
You vouched that I was in Beika when the murder took place!
But if her testimony is true,
then the murder took place before 8:50.
In other words, you could have done it, too.
Ridiculous! Are you saying you believe her?!
And what proof do you have that I killed the woman?!
Chihiro-san. Did your mother have poor eyesight?
Eh? Y-Yes. But she always wore contacts instead of glasses.
Please take another look at the victim's body.
I believe only her left contact is in.
Only the left one is here!
There weren't any contacts in her belongings!
There's no use in looking for it.
Because the killer has it.
Yes. The missing contact lens is in your pants cuff, Izumi-san!
If you'll excuse me...
Here it is!
N-No way!
That's not a place it could just happen to wind up.
It could only happen to someone with direct contact with the victim—
the killer, in other words!
She said she was going to sue me for all I had...
But I only invested how she told me...
But the minute we lost money, she blamed it all on me...
Please! Anything but court!
I'll pay it back, however long it—
I checked the land your parents live on.
I could postpone things if they sold it...
B-But—!
I already spoke with them.
They've agreed to do anything to compensate me.
Family ties are such a wonderful thing, indeed.
She had to pay...
for dragging my elderly parents into this...
Good work! You saved the day yet again!
Oh, I see...
The police lost a great man when you left the force!
Well, see you later!
Right!
Alright!
Ran! Conan! Time to celebrate!
Let's get some food on our way home!
More ramen, I take it?
Don't be stupid! I'm not talking cheap food here!
- Alright!
We'll celebrate with pork ramen!
I figured as much...