When I drank some baigar, an alcohol
that Heiji Hattori brought over,
I temporarily turned back into Shin'ichi Kudo,
but my body shrank back straight after.
I thought it might have a neutralising effect on that drug,
so I went to drink some more, but was spotted by Ran,
who sent me and the Detective Boys off to the Beika Library.
Only the light of deductions can tear apart
black shadows and deep darkness!
In a creepy library at night, the Detective Boys are in trouble!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Beika Library
Geez, they're all such lame books...
I'm supposed to do a book report on this?
And what's with this awkward arrangement?!
Well, guess it can't be helped.
This is the children's section and all...
An imported foreign book...
Huh? It's shrink-wrapped in its case backwards...
Beika Library Director
Shuji Tsugawa (57)
Now, now. This isn't a book for children.
Oh, I'm sorry!
Conan-kun! Look! Police cars!
Eh?!
What do you suppose happened?
Used Books
Sir! There are policemen downstairs!
Eh? Oh, I see. I'll be right there.
I'm gonna check it out!
Eh?
H-Hey, wait up, Conan!
Hold the elevator!
Max Capacity: 7 people, 450 kg
We're over the passenger limit.
Maximum capacity is seven people.
One!
Two! Three! Four! Five! Six! Seven!
There's only seven people in here!
You didn't count yourself!
Told you! Genta-kun doesn't catch colds—
Quiet!
No choice! Let's take the stairs!
You're the director of this library, yes?
Yes. My name is Tsugawa.
I'm here about this fellow,
a librarian named Kazuo Tamada-san.
Oh, yes. He's been taking unapproved leave since yesterday.
Hey, Inspector! What's going on?
Did something happen to him?
Actually, Tamada-san has been missing since two nights ago.
Eh?! Y-You can't be serious!
I hear he worked overtime with you two nights ago...
Yes...
But I left before he did,
so I'm not sure what happened afterward...
Say, then why are you checking the library's storeroom?
He might've been abducted on his way home, you know.
It's just to be on the safe side.
Tamada-san is a meticulous person;
he always called his wife
from this library before leaving for home.
But he didn't two nights ago.
In short, he was either taken away,
or is still inside this library.
But if he is here,
then there's a good chance he's already been killed!
Inspector. We checked all inconspicuous places,
but found nothing...
I guess that means he left...
Alright! Let's go!
I apologize for the inconvenience!
Not at all...
Alright! Everyone's gone!
Geez, I told you to go home!
What now, Conan-kun?!
We find the body.
Eh?! But the police said...
Something stinks about this library...
Stinks?
Huh?
The elevator! Someone's coming up!
Hide!
That's Tsugawa-san, the library director!
What's he up to at this hour?
That's where that weird foreign book was...
Tamada was such a fool.
If only he hadn't looked inside this,
he wouldn't have had to die.
And the police are the police.
They left so easily...
Little did they know Tamada is resting inside this very library...
Just as I thought!
Tamada-san's body is inside this library!
And it was the library director who killed him!
But where is the body?
That's the weird book that was shrink-wrapped backwards in its case...
It's too dark to see anything!
Who's there?!
Is someone there?!
In here?!
I don't think we should leave for a while...
C'mon, Conan, I'm hungry. I want an eel boxed lunch...
Alright! He's gone!
I'll start with the strange books in that box...
Huh? They're empty!
He must've put the contents in his bag before he left!
I doubt it.
Look at all these cases!
His bag couldn't have fit it all!
The ones he couldn't fit,
he must've hid somewhere in this room.
Looks like we'll hafta look for the books before we look for the body.
So it's finally time for the Detective Boys to do their stuff?!
Y-Yeah...
Let's start with this bookcase!
Let's split up and check both sides!
Alright!
I-Idiot! Don't turn the lights on!
But it was dark...
What if he sees?!
Don't worry!
I'm sure he's already long gone!
I sure hope so...
Looks like he's really gone...
Any strange books?
Nope, nothing.
Looks like they're not in this bookcase.
We took out most of the books.
What the—?! They haven't taken any of their books out!
Hey! Genta!
Oh, Conan-kun...
What're you guys doing?!
We took out all our books!
Eh?!
That's strange!
We took all ours out, too!
W-What's with this book!?
There's no spine!
You're right!
H-Hey! All these books are like that!
I get it! These books weren't backwards in their cases;
they never had spines to begin with!
Eh? What do you mean?
Basically, the director put these books
between the ones on the shelves
to make three rows.
So if someone took out a book,
they would see open pages behind it.
They would think it's a book on the other side,
and not realize the truth.
This is the children's corner, which makes it all the more believable.
The books were all skewed because the middle books pushed them.
But why do that?
The fact these weird books are imported from overseas
probably means they contain guns, or...
...drugs!
T-There's some in here, too!
And here!
So basically, that library director is smuggling drugs?!
Yeah. He would store the drugs here,
and then sell them off slowly.
Tamada-san probably discovered this,
and was killed.
By Director Tsugawa...
Huh? That's strange. I can't get through...
Is it out of order?
Yeah. Our only option now is to leave and tell the police directly.
Then let's find the body too while we're at it!
Yeah! Good thinking! That'll double our achievement!
I agree!
Oh, geez...
Once we find the body, we'll be so famous!
This is so exciting!
My shoe came untied...
It's hard to tie it in the dark...
Ayumi-chan!
What're you doing?!
My shoe...
That's what you get for wearing those annoying shoes!
You're mean!
These are my favorite ones, you know!
I guess nobody would hide a body in a bookcase, huh?
But the police did say they searched all inconspicuous places!
There's no place left to look...
Hey! There are weird bookcases in the back!
See?! They got weird handles!
Oh! These are mobile bookcases!
Mobile?
Yes!
Turn this handle, and... See?
Awesome!
I dunno... It would be easy for someone to discover the body here...
This is fun!
- What's wrong, Genta?
- Damn it!
The handle's too hard to turn!
It couldn't be!
Mitsuhiko! Ayumi-chan! Help me move this!
Okay!
Ready... go!
Huh? There's nothing here...
And there's nothing strange here...
Which means the reason it wouldn't move...
...was because you're heavy, Genta!
W-Well, excuse me!
You're too fat, Genta-kun!
How much do you weigh?!
F-Forty kilograms!
That's exactly twice my weight!
Man, I can't stand this...
Just endure it! Today's my last day hanging out with these kids!
Once I drink that alcohol and return to being a high schooler...
Return?
I'm only 15 kilograms! You need to diet more!
S-Shut up!
Oh, yeah! I forgot! I'm a kid now!
Hold on! I was 18 kg when I last weighed myself!
Hold the elevator!
I know where the body is hidden!
Hey, Conan! Wait up!
Hey, Conan! Where are you?!
Conan-kun! Say something!
Conan-kun!
Where were you?!
Just up in the machinery room.
Was the body in there?!
No, I only went there to switch these elevator doors to manual.
The body... is probably in here!
You're sure it's in here?
Yep.
The proof is the overload buzzer that went off
when we all got on the elevator this afternoon.
Eh?
Of course it went off;
there were 8 people in the elevator...
Don't be stupid! We're kids!
All together, we weigh at most 100 kg!
An adult and a half!
Even with the weight of the adults and the box,
there was one whole person missing for the buzzer to go off!
Yes. Someone was riding this elevator from the very start.
Somewhere where nobody could see him...
...on the roof!
It would seem he was thrown down this shaft after being strangled.
It was all Director Tsugawa's doing.
Now let's go tell the police!
What's wrong?
—A-A—
—T-Tsu—
—D-Dir—
Atsudir?
D-Director Tsugawa!
What are you kiddos doing here at this hour?
Come now.
Let's all leave together...
Come...
Listen. Do exactly as I say.
What are you discussing?
Let's leave now...
Don't underestimate us just because we're kids, Director!
What?
We've got the evidence.
The bookcase trick, the hidden drugs,
and the fact you killed Tamada-san after he found out!
Who... Who are you?!
I'm Conan Edogawa! A detective!
D-Detective?!
Oh, no, you don't!
He slides, he's safe!
We did it!
Damn you brats! You can't escape me!
I made it!
It's time to die...
...brats!
T-They're gone? Did they get off?
No matter. With the elevator off,
they're trapped like rats...
Just you wait, little rats.
I'll kill each and every one of you!
Hey! Where are you, kiddos?!
I'm sorry about earlier!
I won't try to hurt you now! Come on out!
In here?
Do they honestly think this is a barricade?
It's leaning...
Ah! They stuck books under it...
Now!
Kids have such shallow cleverness.
Don't worry. You won't be lonely...
Because I'm about to send all four of you to the afterlife!
We did it!
It worked perfectly!
After our call, the police rushed over and arrested Director Tsugawa.
They also recovered Tamada-san's body and all the drugs.
And so Conan Edogawa's final case came to an end.
That was so scary!
I thought we were goners!
Get real! Good always wins!
So now it's goodbye to this body...
Let's do that again sometime, Conan-kun!
Eh?
The detective club!
Together, the four of us can solve any case easily!
Alright! Let's try hard next time, too!
Yeah!
And... goodbye to them, too...
C-Conan-kun?
See you!
It's like he's leaving somehow...
Yeah...
That's right! I'm turning back into my normal body!
Into high school student, Shin'ichi Kudo!
With this alcohol... I can finally be me again!
Conan-kun? Did you just get home?
What were you doing this late at—
Conan-kun?
What?! Your body reverted?!
Yeah! After one drink of this alcohol!
You can't be serious...
If you don't believe me, then just watch!
H-Hey!
Here it comes! My body's warming up!
C'mon, Doc! I haven't turned back one bit!
You probably built up an immunity...
Immunity?
Basically, the alcohol somehow turned you back the first time,
but your body started to produce a substance to counteract the alcohol,
thus rendering it ineffective.
Yeah, right! I just haven't had enough yet!
H-Hey, stop it, Shin'ichi!
Gulp, gulp!
Stop it!
What's wrong, Conan-kun?!
You don't look so good...
Is it another cold?
Don't be dumb. It's just a hangover...