When you mystery fans hear "triplets",
what comes to mind is probably a substitution trick.
Sure enough, this case...
A canvas stained black with crime.
With brilliant detective skills, its color is changed!
A villa connected with the Suzuki Financial Group.
There's someone suspicious among a group of triplets!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Izu
Summer! You got your sun and your ocean!
Still, I can't believe Conan-kun's the only boy on the beach
when there's two hot girls here! How pathetic...!
Well, excuse me.
Obviously! This is your villa's private beach!
Oh, yeah!
We're here to get a great tan
and catch guys all summer long!
You're always talking about guys, Sonoko...
It must be nice to know who your husband'll be!
You bought that swimsuit
to show Shin'ichi-kun, didn't you?
That... was for me?!
Since I'm here, I'll get a closer look!
Yuzo-san!
Young girls are so nice!
Yuzo Tomizawa (28)
Ayako's Fiancée
I shouldn't have gotten engaged yet!
Oh, you! You're supposed to be in love with my sister!
So he's—
Yep!
Yuzo Tomizawa-san, third son of the
head of the Tomizawa Financial Group!
He's marrying my sister in the fall!
Our two family companies are really close!
Tomizawa Family Villa
Suzuki Family Villa
Look! Even our villas are next to each other!
He saw my sister at a party and had love at first sight!
You're embarrassing me, Sonoko-chan...
She's in our villa if you're looking for her...
No, I'm here to introduce her
to my father and brothers...!
So then—
They're all coming?
Yeah. My brothers arrive tomorrow,
but my father should be at the villa by now.
I'll give him a call.
This is the Tomizawa residence.
We're not home right now,
so please leave a message after the beep—
Huh? It's the machine...
Do you have the time?
3:10...
That's weird. He was supposed to be there at 3:00...
What's wrong, Sonoko?
Tetsuhara-ojisama is coming!
This is no time to play in the ocean!
I have to greet him!
Wait! Sonoko!
Oh!
D-Dad...!
Ugh! I said to wait in the villa for me to bring her there!
Tetsuhara Tomizawa (60)
President of Tomizawa Financial Group
I thought we might enjoy your
future wife's cooking tonight...!
Ayako Suzuki
Sonoko's Sister
He sent it flying!
It's gone! Three runs! Kogure sent it
into the right stands in the rain!
Yes!
Dad. You're sure a big Kogure fan...
I sure am!
But you didn't have to watch him here.
I had no choice. I'm getting bad satellite reception.
A pop fly down the center!
The Falcons are on fire now!
It's 9:00, so we bring you a 5-minute news break!
Typhoon 11 has intensified and
is moving northward from Okinawa.
As a result, many planes and boats are delayed.
9:00? It's only the 6th inning...
The rain kept delaying the game.
Ayako-san. Might you have a radio?
It doesn't look like that game's on the radio...
Now, now! It'll begin soon!
How about some coffee?
Suzuki women are so considerate!
Yuzo! You're one lucky guy!
My other two sons, on the other hand...
Taichi, the oldest, ditched the business
and became a novelist instead.
So he's still single.
Tatsuji, the middle son, joined the company
but got engaged with some
nobody without my consent!
Stop talking bad about them...!
You too, Yuzo! With your stupid paintings and all...!
Yuzo-san!
I'll be in my studio. I have an illustration to finish.
Yuzo-san...!
If only he'd quit being stubborn and join the business,
I'd give him a good position!
It's over! The Falcons finally win 9-8 in the 11th inning!
Yes! Alright! Hurray!
This is the essence of Falcons baseball!
Oh, look at the time. I should get back to my villa.
Alright, Ayako-san. I'll bring my sons over tomorrow.
Is that all right?
Of course!
Geez! I wonder if he plans to watch
another night game tomorrow...
Oh, it's already 11:30. We should—
Oh no, a power failure?!
Looks like it.
See? The lights are out in the other villa too...
It must've been the lightning!
What is that?
Someone's there!
Who is that?
What's he doing?!
Y-Yuzo-san!
Conan-kun!
Stop!
Conan-kun! Wait!
Darn it! I lost him!
Sir!
Sir! Sir!
W-What the...?!
I see.
So you witnessed Mr. Tomizawa
being beaten to death by his son Yuzo
at 11:30 last night?
Yes.
Ayako-san. What's all this about?
Yuzo-san!
Yuzo Tomizawa?!
Y-Yes...
Did something happen?
You know full well you killed your own father!
Eh?! Dad?! That's crazy...!
Hey! Let go! I didn't kill him!
What's going on, Yuzo?
Tatsuji Tomizawa (28)
Office Worker
Tatsuji-niisan!
What's all the ruckus?
Taichi-aniki! Looks like something happened!
Taichi Tomizawa (28)
Novelist
Perfect timing. I need an idea for a new novel...
T-Triplets?!
Yuzo Tomizawa! You're under arrest for the murder of your father, Mr. Tetsuhara Tomizawa!
Mr. Officer! Please wait!
We did see the killer's face...
But we only saw his eyes and nose!
We didn't know Yuzo-san had two identical twins!
Which means it was one of you three...
I was in Okinawa last night on a business trip.
I took the first flight out
and landed at Haneda 3 hours ago.
The last flight to Okinawa leaves at 8:00 PM.
I couldn't have been at the villa when it happened!
Say, Mr. Officer.
I'm not sure I can call it an alibi, but...
You have two messages.
Do you have the time?
3:10...
That's weird. He was supposed to be there at 3:00...
3:10 PM.
That was me! I used my cell phone to call him from the beach!
Hello, this is Taichi.
Here's mine.
Glad to see the Falcons won, Dad!
Kogure pulled that homer to the
right in the bottom of the 6th!
What a batter! Well, see you tomorrow!
11:34 PM.
11:34 PM... The time the murder took place.
You're certain it happened around 11:30?
Yes! I had checked the clock before we saw the killer!
Doesn't look like he did it!
That game was only on satellite!
It ended just after 11:25.
He couldn't have known how it ended
unless he watched it all!
Confirm that with the TV and radio stations! Hurry!
Yes, sir!
Say, if neither of us is the killer...
Yuzo's the only possibility.
B-Brother!
No! I'd never kill anyone!
Then where were you last night?
I was in my studio the whole time.
Yes! A fellow illustrator called
and woke me up! Just after 11:30!
He woke you up?
Yes!
I dozed off! I had to pull an
all-nighter to finish this job...
Then we'll check with him!
Detective Yokomizo! About that passenger list...
What? My name was there, right?
Yes, it was.
The issue is the time the plane landed!
The plane you were supposedly on
landed at Haneda 30 minutes ago!
That can't be...!
I guess the typhoon delayed it!
They said so on the news last night!
Yeah, you're right!
How about you tell us where
you really were last night?!
T-Tokyo...! That's right!
I returned to Tokyo last night!
To Hiromi's place in Tokyo!
Hiromi...?
My fiancée. I was worried because
I heard she had collapsed...
I figured I'd catch hell if my old man
found out I'd dropped work for her,
so I had someone cover for me in Okinawa!
It's the truth! Please believe me!
Can anyone vouch for this?
Hiromi.
Yeah! I just mentioned how the game ended!
No news programs were covering it at 11:30!
I know, because I flipped channels,
hoping to see that home run again!
Detective Yokomizo. He's telling the truth.
It was after midnight when TV
and radio stations covered the game.
Say, are you a fan of Kogure?
You were praising him on the phone!
He's awesome! Only he could hit
a home run into the right stands!
Hit?! Explain yourself, Taichi-san!
You said he pulled it to the right on the phone!
Were you really watching that game?!
Guess the truth's out.
So you killed your father?!
Nothing of the sort! I meant that
I didn't see the game on TV.
I listened to it all on the radio
while playing pachinko.
I was taking a break from working on my novel...
I guess the only radio broadcast
was in Osaka, where I live.
He's right, only one radio station
in Osaka aired that game.
Who is it?! One of those three is lying!
And the victim's missing watch bugs me!
Why would the killer take it?
To keep the time a secret? Or—
Huh? This VCR is blinking!
Yeah. It's because of the 10-minute
blackout that happened at 11:30 last night.
Oh, yeah! There was a blackout just before the murder!
A blackout?
Wait, this is strange! What he said is impossible!
And at the time, it was—
Then the watch taken from the victim was...
Could it be?!
No doubt about it! The killer is the one telling two lies!
I have to ask all three of you
to come down to the station!
B-But...!
Hey, this isn't funny!
Why me?
We have no choice.
These folks saw the killer's face
just after the murder!
One that looked just like you three!
In other words, one of you killed your father!
I know who did it! It's definitely
the one with the strange alibi!
Alright! I'll knock Sonoko out
and make her a detective!
What're you doing, Conan-kun?!
What's with this watch?!
It's—
What's the matter?
He was aiming a weird watch at you.
I-It's a toy! Dr. Agasa gave it to me!
A BB comes out if you press a button!
You're such a troublemaker!
I gotta use the bathroom!
Sonoko?! Hey, Sonoko!
I've figured it out.
I know that he killed Tetsuhara-ojisama!
Not one of the three has a clear alibi!
But there's one who's clearly lying!
The killer is Taichi-san!
Taichi-san?!
Sure, kid!
Interesting.
But I was in an Osaka pachinko parlor.
I don't think I could've been here then.
A pachinko parlor at 11:30, really?
Yeah, that's right.
Don't you know that pachinko parlors
can only stay open until 11:00 PM?!
Yes, pachinko parlors are generally
forbidden to operate past 11:00!
Even in Osaka!
That means you're lying!
My mistake!
I heard the broadcast in a taxi
on my way home from the parlor...
Honestly?!
Don't be like that. It was a simple mistake.
Besides, I left a message when the murder took place!
How do you explain that?
I can!
And the major oversight
you made during the murder!
What?!
You should know; you were there!
The power went out for 10 minutes at 11:30!
Yes! The answering machine
wouldn't work without power!
Its batteries power the clock,
but it can't record messages!
So what's your message doing there at 11:34?
But you could ask Yuzo the same thing!
He said he got a call just after 11:30!
You don't know anything, do you?
You can still make calls during a power outage!
W-What...?!
It's true. Telephones receive
power through the phone lines.
S-Someone must've messed
with the clock to frame me—
There's no telling when you'd call.
Nobody could've matched the times just right.
In other words, when the game ended,
you left a message on the machine whose
clock you had set ahead in advance.
Glad to see the Falcons won, Dad!
As if you left the message just
when the murder happened!
Then you turned the clock back,
and waited for your father to return.
Your father, who came next door to see the game!
And then you killed him when he came back!
But I couldn't have known when he'd return...!
No, you knew. You used a transmitter to hear!
A-A transmitter?!
I bugged your villa?
Then go ahead and look! There won't be any!
Nobody said you bugged the house.
Isn't there something unnaturally
missing from the victim?
His watch!
Aha! With a bugged watch,
he could keep tabs on both the victim and the game!
So the watch was taken to remove the evidence?
That's right!
Bugging the victim's watch,
and breaking his satellite receiver
to make him come to my villa...
As his son, you could easily do this!
Nice theory. I almost want to use it for a book.
But it'd be a third-rate novel.
Do you have any proof that I changed
the answering machine's clock?
The times match; even Yuzo's
message had the right time.
You talk big for having no proof—
Quit playin' around!
The fake time and message on the answering machine
actually prove that you're the killer!
B-Brother...!
It can't be true...!
Yeah! This must be a mistake!
You had no reason to kill Dad...!
Stop that, Yuzo. I'm not
the great brother you take me for.
Money. I wanted the old man's inheritance.
So I could keep writing.
Things got tough. I suddenly
ran out of work and money...
I found out when I went to Dad for help...
He had pressured the publishers
to drop each job that came my way!
I guess he wanted me to quit
and follow in his footsteps.
So then you—
Yeah. I used his visit here to kill him.
That's also why I sent him the
bugged watch and broke his receiver.
Yuzo. I was going to try pinning it on you.
To increase my share of the inheritance.
It was all so I could keep writing my novels...
But it seems I wrote a poor mystery.
To think the power would go out just then...
I guess fact is stranger than fiction...
Maybe I didn't have the skill to be a writer.
What's with Sonoko? She's spacing out...
She's probably relieved Yuzo-san wasn't the killer!
Uh oh. She's staring at her arm.
Don't tell me she noticed
I shot a sleeping dart in it...
I failed...
What're you talking about? That was great detective work!
Detective work?
Just look at my arm!
It's totally white!
I was supposed to get a tan and catch some guys!
I know, Ran! Let's go to a tanning salon!
Not now! We have to give our statements at the police station!
What for?!
What a dumb girl...