The Nippon Budokan...
a judo arena built in 1964,
for the Tokyo Olympics,
and is a sacred place for Japanese martial arts.
Today, it is also used as a venue for various music events,
and this time, a music group
was about to hold a concert there.
A racing second hand, a glittering shooting star!
Conan's logic is good medicine
for hearts dried by modern society!
Today's case is music-related
and has my first karaoke performance!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Created by
Gosho Aoyama
"Detective Conan"
Serialized in Shogakukan's
"Weekly Shonen Sunday"
Character Design
Masatomo Sudo
Art Director
Yukihiro Shibutani
Art Design
Hiroyuki Mitsumoto
Director of Photography
Takahisa Ogawa
Sound Director
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
Music Producer
Hiroki Horio
(PolyGram)
Music
Katsuo Ono
Opening Theme
"Nazo"
Performed by
Lyrics
Music
Arrangement
Miho Komatsu
Hirohito Furui
(Spoonful/Zain Records)
Editor
Teramitsu Okada
Story Editor
Jun'ichi Iioka
Color Key
Reiko Hirayama
Executive Producer
Satoshi Yokoyama
Planning Support
Toyohiko Okuyama
Mitome Asai
Director
Kenji Kodama
Presented by
Here it goes!
Okay! Now, let's hide!
Genta just had to kick it so hard...
A high schooler playing Kick-the-Can?
And here, of all places?
What's with this crowd, anyway?
Oh! Conan-kun!
What are you doing here?
What are you guys doing here?
A concert!
We came to see a concert at the Budokan!
Why the flowers?
Oh, these?
The concert starts at 6:00,
but we thought we might meet them if we came early...
Because musicians usually show up 6 hours before concerts!
Who's "them"?
Oh, come on! The two from Two-Mix, obviously!
Two-Mix?
You never heard of them?!
It's the super-famous team of
Minami Takayama and Shiina Nagano!
Oh, that gaudy dance-music group?
That hurt!
Don't talk all big when you never even listen to 'em!
Now, now! Conan-kun is still a kid!
Besides, remember when we took him to karaoke?
Now that you mention it...
he did sing pretty off-key...
Yep!
Just like someone else, he doesn't seem that interested in music.
So, he doesn't get how good they are...
Well, excuse me.
Alright, Conan-kun!
What're you doing?
Please play seriously!
Sorry!
See you later!
Yeah.
Don't go with strangers!
- We won't!
- Don't worry! I'm here!
You're the biggest worry of all!
Bye!
There sure are a lot of people...
Where are they going?
Some Two-Mix concert. Said they're gonna give 'em a bouquet—
For reals?!
The Two-Mix?!
The ones who did the Kamen Yaiba theme song?!
Oh, man! Not them, too...
Hey! Let's go check it out too!
Let's!
Maybe we can get autographs!
Oh, geez...
Let's hurry!
Yeah!
Ow!
I'm so sorry, kids!
Watch where you're walking, Mister!
You're...
...Two-Mix's Minami Takayama!
Did she say Takayama?
Minami Takayama?!
No way!
Say, kiddos! Ya hungry? My treat!
Great! Let's go!
Eat all ya want!
Guess that wasn't her...
Yeah.
This looks good!
Thanks for the food!
This is delicious!
Hey, what happened to not going with strangers?
Geez... They ordered all the expensive stuff...
You're not having any, Minami-chan?
Nah! I'm not that hungry!
I should've brought more money...
But, is this okay? Don't you need to tune up before the show?
Yeah, but my partner, Shiina-kun, hasn't shown up,
and there's no answer on his cell phone...
So, I snuck outside to look around for him.
Why don't you try calling him from here?
I'd like to, but I forgot my own phone at the office.
And that guy's been on the pay phone for a while...
Talk about bad luck...
Yup.
I've been having lots of bad luck lately...
How so?
Like, my office locker getting broken into,
or marks from someone picking my lock at home...
Do you think it's a stalker?
It is a case of foul harassment!
This is a job for...
the Detective Boys!
Thanks...
Consider this meal my payment...
Say, when did this harassment start?
Hmm, last Sunday, I think...
Just after my live radio broadcast...
I heard that broadcast!
So did I!
You played part of a demo tape
of your new song, right?
Demo tape?
I can let you hear it all, if you'd like!
Really?!
Here it is! The only demo tape of it in the world!
What did you think?!
The lyrics and music were cool!
How about you?
It doesn't have any strange voices or sounds...
How rude! Of course it doesn't!
Doesn't seem the harassment is because of this tape.
So, what did you think?
I guess it was okay...
Ah! I figured it out!
You already solved the case?
No! It's their voices!
Something kept bugging me,
but Minami-san and Conan-kun sound just alike!
- Yeah, right!
They do!
Like two geese in a pond!
You mean two peas in a pod!
Maybe you can stand in for me
whenever I get a cold!
That's a bad idea. Conan-kun is tone-deaf!
That's all I'm hearing today...
Aw, man. He's still on the phone.
You can use this!
Here!
What is this?
It's an Earring Cell Phone!
My friend, Dr. Agasa, made it for me!
So, I put it on my ear, right?
No, you dial the number before you—
Takayama-sama!
Is there a Takayama-sama here?
Oh, that's me.
A Shiina Nagano-sama is on the phone.
Thanks.
Where are you?! They already started tuning up!
Sorry! Something came up...
I'm in the car out front.
Car?
Whose car is that?
I have something to show you.
Could you come here?
You have it there?
Y-Yeah...
Don't come, Minami! Stay away!
What? Hello?!
What's his deal?
Thank you!
Why is that guy...
Come on, Shiina-kun! Say something, will ya?!
Freeze.
Shiina-kun!
Now, get in.
Oh no!
Conan-kun!
Minami-chan's been...
Kidnapped!
Damn it! A kidnapping right before my eyes?!
Hello, this is the Budokan.
Sorry, could you repeat that?
I said I have Two-Mix hostage.
Huh?
If you wanna save 'em, call the police right now.
Quit kidding around, will ya?
What was that?
Said he kidnapped Two-Mix.
Excuse me!
These kids claim Minami Takayama-san was kidnapped!
Eh?
What?!
It's the truth!
We saw her get shoved into a car!
Save Minami-chan!
So that call really was...
T-This is bad!
Call the police immediately!
Yes, sir!
Looks like rain...
We're gonna get wet if they don't start soon...
Police cars!
Did something happen?
Inspector! This way!
Split up and question people in the area!
Yes, sir!
Okay, let's go!
So, Minami Takayama-san left by herself?
Yes. We couldn't contact Nagano-kun, so she went to look around.
Afterwards, while dining with you children,
she was called outside and kidnapped?
Yeah. After she got the call and went outside,
the man behind her pushed her inside the car!
What?! So you saw the kidnapper?!
Yeah! He was as tall as old man Mouri...
...and was wearing a ski hat and a scarf!
And round sunglasses!
He had long, frizzy hair and a mustache!
But, it could be a disguise!
And there were at least two kidnappers!
Huh? How do you know that?
After the man pushed her into the back seat of the car,
he got into the passenger seat!
In other words, someone else was driving!
I see. And then you got the call.
Yes. They said they had kidnapped Two-Mix and to call the police...
What exactly are they planning?
You'd expect them to say not to call the police...
Perhaps they're really confident?
Or...
Or, they never intended to release their hostages from the start!
That's terrible...
Inspector! It's them!
Get ready to trace it!
Well, you have the honors.
Right...
Don't worry. Just stay calm.
Alright. Try not to agitate the kidnappers.
Agree to all their demands.
And stall them as long as possible.
Right.
Go ahead.
Hello...
Yes.
Alright.
Inspector, he wants to talk to the officer in charge.
Alright. Hand it here.
Put it on speaker.
Hello? This is Inspector Megure.
Oh, what a pleasant surprise!
It's a real honor to have the Section 1 inspector on the case!
How are they?!
Don't worry. They're taking a little nap together.
What is it you want?! Money?! Or maybe—
Money?
I'm not interested in that.
I'm one of those so-called stalkers.
I want everything that's related to them.
Yes, like the bag she forgot
at the restaurant, for example...
Bag?!
This?!
Alright! I'll have one of my men deliver—
Don't mock my intelligence.
The brats. Have them bring it.
You can't mean...
...those four brats who were eating with Minami-chan.
But...
There's no time to be hesitant.
I have two hostages here.
I wouldn't care one bit if one of them went on to the afterlife.
Just get those four runts to bring the bag!
No! I can't put children in such a dangerous situation!
I'm sorry, but I can't accept that demand!
Is that so?
Then I have no choice.
Guess I'll turn Two-Mix into One-Mix and then get back to you.
Wait!
Alright!
We'll take you your bag!
Yeah, Conan's right!
We can't just sit around while Two-Mix is being held captive!
I'll try my hardest!
Hold on, now...
Great, then it's decided.
Hold on!
In 15 minutes, I'll call a phone at Kudanshita Station.
Wait...
If even one of 'em is late, I'll start blastin' people!
You get a trace?!
I know they're in the direction of Haido,
but he was calling from a moving car
so I can't pinpoint him...
Alright. Contact HQ at once and
get a list of all suspects still at large
from recent cases of mine!
Yes, sir! But why...
The kidnapper knew my name,
and hid his speech behind a voice-changer and polite talk!
It's likely that I investigated him before!
Right!
Conan-kun.
Yes?
I want you to promise me
you won't do anything dangerous.
I promise.
Run away if you think you're in danger!
Got it!
Do you understand, too?!
Um... What should I do about the concert?
Cancel it!
That's not necessary!
We'll rescue them before the concert starts, so just hold on!
Hello?!
Good. Now get on the Toei-Shinjuku Line
and answer the phone on Platform 13 at Shinjuku Station
on the Yamanote Line in 15 minutes!
I dropped the bag in a gutter earlier...
You dropped it in a gutter?
Hey! Is the tape alright?!
You idiot! Have you forgotten we want the tape destroyed?!
Oh, yeah...
So, they are after the demo tape!
15 minutes, now! Don't be late!
But, why make the kids bring it? Especially with police escorts?
Tell cops not to come and they'll come anyway.
Plus, with four kids, they'll assume they'll never lose sight of 'em.
We'll use that to our advantage.
What are you doing?
Writing the lyrics on the demo tape.
The kidnappers are after this tape.
I can't find any strange sounds on it...
In which case, there has to be a keyword in these lyrics
that poses a problem for those guys!
Inspector. We just got word
that the kidnappers' car was abandoned by the Teimuzu River!
Damn! They switched cars!
Which means those four kids
are our only hope now...
I'm dead tired...
All we've been doing is going around the Yamanote Line...
Do you suppose they're toying with us?
No, they're just waiting for their chance!
The moment the police lose sight of us!
Give the tape to someone else?
Yeah. I'll call back in 3 minutes.
Hand it over in the bathroom
and make sure the cops don't find out.
This is weird!
Who did he say to give the tape to?!
Tell us, Conan-kun!
Say, when Two-Mix played this tape on the radio,
did they mention anything else?
Not really.
They did say they thought up the lyrics when they passed by a temple...
Shoenji Temple, I think...
Shoenji?!
Wait! That's near where that murder happened last New Year's Eve!
That was when some creep with a gun attacked a man
but was killed when it went off during the struggle...
I'm pretty sure the man was acquitted for self-defense reasons...
Now I know why they want this tape!
It's almost time!
We gotta hurry...
Wait! I have a good idea!
The phone's ringing. The kids are picking it up.
That's the plan. That'll get rid of those cops.
Don't screw up, now!
The doors are about to close. Please be careful.
Ayumi!
Are you alright, little girl?
Yes...
Anyone manage to get on?!
Just us two...
How about the kidnappers?
No, nobody yet...
The kids are throwing the bag out the window!
There!
So, that was the plan!
OK! You watch the kids! We're heading for the bag!
OK! Let's move!
Huh? Where's that girl...
Wait! Your guys' work is done!
You don't need to run away!
Stop, little boy...
Eek!
"Eek"?
Anyone gotten near the bag?
No one, so far.
Hello?
Good work, little girl.
There aren't any cops around, I hope?
No, there doesn't seem to be anyone...
Perfect.
Ready to come, like I told ya?
Yeah...
I'll try my hardest!
What?! Conan-kun and Ayumi-kun switched places?!
My word...
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Lyrics