When someone leaves behind a will,
civil law specifies a descendant's portion...
A minimum share of their inheritance which is reserved for
the deceased's heirs, so they are not overly disadvantaged.
So long as there's no legal issue
surrounding that inheritance, that is...
Only the light of deductions can tear apart
the pitch-black shadows and bottomless darkness!
Difficult circumstances surround an inheritance battle,
and wine concealing a dangerous motive!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
I don't get it.
Why were we invited, too?
How should I know?
You don't really care?
Of course not!
Kotaro Ichikawa may be president of Ichikawa Industries now,
but he's also a deceitful jerk.
I doubt he has honest work for me.
Then why don't you say no?
Grownups have grownup circumstances to take care of!
Yeah, that's true.
He hasn't had any work at all for a long time now.
Is there a party going on?
The president has a family meeting every year on his birthday.
Mouri-sama is here to see you.
Enter.
This is Ichikawa, the head of the house.
Thank you for coming.
Just so you know, I haven't decided to help you just yet.
Imamura.
Toshiaki Imamura (55)
Ichikawa family butler
100,000 yen?!
You must take the great Kogoro Mouri for a cheap joke!
Hey, Uncle...
What?
It isn't 100,000 yen.
See?
One, ten, hundred, thousand,
ten thousand, hundred thousand...
A-A million yen?!
Kotaro Ichikawa (65)
President of Ichikawa Industries
I've prepared another million yen for you if your job is successful.
So, how can I help you?
Geez...
My two daughters will be in attendance at today's family meeting.
I want you to watch what they do and what they try to do.
Umm, should I leave?
No, it's fine. You can explain my condition to them.
Right.
Hitoshi Okano (30)
Kotaro's physician
If he continues to push himself, there's no guarantee he'll live.
So I'm thinking of retiring now,
but I need to decide on a successor.
It'd be one of your daughters, right?
Not necessarily.
I have no intention of sharing my fortune with uncouth vultures,
which may include my children.
Even so, inheritances are subject to legally-secured portions.
Your children would still get
a percent of it, no matter what.
But not if there's an issue with who it's going to.
Issue?
Something's going to happen.
Something. I can feel it.
Something?
I've told everyone you're a friend,
and that you're with your family.
Be careful not to be found out as you do your work.
Cheers!
Mouri-sama. Over there is Kazue-sama, the eldest daughter.
She currently manages an art gallery.
Imamura. Who might this be?
Yes, this is Mouri-sama, a friend of your father's.
How do you do?
Oh, Father's friend?
Kazue Ichikawa (30)
Eldest daughter
Isn't it a bother, being forced
to attend a gathering like this?
No, not at all! I came with my family...
...and we're having a great time!
Oh, Sister!
I didn't think you'd actually come.
Of course I would attend.
I'm the next in line in the Ichikawa family.
Mizue Ichikawa (27)
Second daughter
I wonder. I somehow doubt Father would give everything to you.
You did act selfishly and leave home after you argued with him.
Who're you to talk?
You got married right away because you were sick of seeing his face!
That reminds me, I hear your art gallery is being sued
for selling forgeries or something like that!
What?!
One is as bad as the other...
Cave
(wine storeroom)
It's Kazue-san!
A syringe! What is she planning to do?!
What's in it?!
Oh no!
C-Chloroform...
Where could Conan-kun have gone off to?
I thank you for gathering here on my birthday.
I intend to give up my position as company president very soon.
In other words, I'm retiring.
Therefore, I've decided to sell all my stock and ownership rights
to Nichiuri Industries.
- What?!
- Come again?!
S-Sir! What happens to us, then?!
If you want to stay with the company,
you'll need to prove your worth to the new administration.
Y-You can't be serious!
What'll you do with the money you make from selling the company?!
How I use it is up to me.
I have no intention of giving any of you a single yen.
Not even my daughters.
Damn, I let my guard down! I gotta hurry!
It was probably poison she put in the wine!
How does she plan to use it?!
I won't object to your decision, Father.
Nor will I.
I brought out a '57 wine to celebrate this new chapter in your life!
It's worth even more for a wine aficionado like yourself.
I'd feel bad for the wine if regular know-nothings like us drank it.
Here you are.
Oh, she's more considerate than I thought!
Hey, I haven't seen Conan-kun for a while.
Ouch!
What was that?
Perfect!
Success!
But ouch!
Ran-neechan!
Oh, Conan-kun!
What happened to Ichikawa-san?!
He suddenly collapsed!
President!
Well?!
- Father!
- Sir!
Call the police!
This is an unnatural death for now.
A police examiner is needed.
So, he collapsed immediately
after drinking the wine?
Yes.
He was murdered!
He did have a weak heart, but one drink wouldn't have killed him!
There was poison in the wine!
Come again?! Are you suggesting I poisoned it?!
That's the only possibility!
You're horrible!
Do you have a basis for your claim?
Dr. Okano knows about our father's condition!
It's true that he had a weak heart,
but something so soon and sudden is out of the question.
See!
Are you still saying it was me?!
Now, now! I'm sorry to ask,
but may we inspect your belongings?
Dr. Okano. Can you tell what's in this vial?
It seems to be a muscle relaxant.
What would happen if this was given to Mr. Ichikawa?
It's very dangerous even for healthy individuals.
Given that he had a serious heart illness...
There's no question she was the one who poisoned the wine.
But just who attacked me?!
Do you have any idea as to Kazue-san's motive?
Her art gallery was in quite a lot of debt.
Maybe she was after the inheritance?
He declared he wouldn't even leave his own daughters a single yen.
How dumb.
We'd still get our legally-secured portions,
no matter what he said.
Even if he said nothing,
we'd still get a percentage of it.
Did the younger sister attack me?!
If she knew about her sister's plan
and locked me up to keep me
from getting in her way...
If the older sister was found guilty,
the huge inheritance would be all hers!
A single key not on his keychain?
Hey! Hey, hey!
What does this key go to?
Oh, I think it might be the basement key.
How odd. He almost never went into the basement...
Wait!
Was it the victim, Ichikawa-san, who threw me into the basement?!
If so, that means he knew the wine was poisoned when he drank it!
That can't be!
A video camera lens!
The cord goes into the ceiling!
Was this to record the person who killed him?!
This smell... Ichikawa-san didn't drink the wine after all!
He knew the eldest daughter, Kazue-san, had tampered with the wine,
so he dumped it into this flowerpot!
Then he pretended to drink it and writhe in pain...
...to see how both daughters reacted!
But there's no doubt that he really was poisoned.
I don't get it! How did he ingest the poison?!
Damn kid, scampering around everywhere...
Maybe they gave him poison in a capsule or something, not wine?
No, the time doesn't add up.
It's no good!
No one could've given him the poison in front of everyone else!
Given?
That's it! Only that person could've done it!
You damn kid, sneaking into a place like this!
What the?!
Now, then!
I'm a pathetic personal physician.
I couldn't save him...
Don't say that! It's not your fault!
I'm sorry to keep you all waiting.
I've finally figured out the truth behind this incident,
so please gather in the business room.
What do you mean by "the truth," Mouri-kun?
Indeed, I have no doubt that Kazue-san poisoned the wine.
However, Ichikawa-san never drank it.
Not even a sip.
What do you mean?
He pretended to drink, but dumped it in the flowerpot by the window.
Then it was his heart?
No. He died of a poison-induced heart attack. I'm certain of it.
What kind of nonsense is this?!
My sister obviously killed him!
I guess he just couldn't accept death normally,
even though he trusted you two
until the very last moment...
But didn't he hire you to investigate because he didn't trust them?
He wanted to trust them. So he tested them.
Ran. Play the video tape.
Oh! Is this it?!
What is this?!
This was all set up by Ichikawa-san.
He probably planned to pretend
to collapse from his heart illness
and then check later on the tape
to see how both daughters reacted.
But the plan changed somewhat
when he learned Kazue-san was planning to kill him.
So that's...
So that's when he decided to pretend to drink the poisoned wine.
Wait, hold on. Wasn't it poison that caused his death?
That, we can be certain of.
But it wasn't added to his wine or food.
It was given to him with a more direct method.
Hold on now. I'm not sure anyone had enough time to do that.
Yeah! Everyone was watching!
Yes. The killer openly gave him the poison while everyone watched.
Ran. Pause the tape.
You don't mean?!
Yes.
Dr. Okano.
You could've given him a shot of poison instead of a heart stimulant.
You knew of Ichikawa-san's plan, did you not?
When you think about it,
he would've required his doctor's help to put on the act.
Otherwise, you would've realized he was faking right away.
Ichikawa-san confided his plan to you alone.
I don't know what that plan was,
but you decided to use it
as a chance to murder him.
Everyone knew he had a weak heart.
So no one would doubt his personal physician's diagnosis.
But why?! He has nothing to do
with the inheritance, right?!
The most likely possibility is revenge.
As his personal doctor,
there was no need to dirty your own hands to kill him.
If you had told him his condition wasn't serious, given how he was,
he would've kept pushing himself, hastening his death.
The fact you instead took direct action...
I despised him.
To that extent.
The president—no, Kotaro Ichikawa—killed my father.
Ichikawa and my father were partners when the business started.
It happened 30 years ago.
The venture business they started together was a great success.
But then he backstabbed my father and kicked him out
without even a yen to his name.
Family life was miserable after that.
He would always utter complaints
to me, just a little kid.
In the end, my mother passed away
before I entered middle school,
and my father hastened his own death.
Then, after I became a doctor, this man appeared before me.
He never realized who I was.
But when he told me about his plan to test his daughters' loyalty,
I suddenly made up my mind.
A horrible backstabber like him,
testing the loyalty of others...
I had to make him pay...
I had to make him pay!
I'm going to be busy now!
I need to organize the things Father left me!
Madam!
Madam! About that...
Your father said in his will that if something should happen to him,
everything should be donated away.
Don't be stupid! I won't allow any such thing!
But he did have the will written in the presence of an attorney...
Listen. There's something called a "legally-secured portion".
I insist on receiving what I deserve!
Mizue-san.
What is it?
I hear you disposed of your father's stock certificates on your own.
I'm told the board of directors
is charging you with embezzlement.
No way! It's not true! It's not true!
In the end, Ichikawa-san's daughters
don't even get one yen of his inheritance...
H-Hey! What's gonna happen to this house?!
What do you mean? It's going to be donated to someone.
Then what happens to my pay?!
You got a million yen already!
What about the other million?!
Just forget about it?
No!