Hostages
"Hostages."
Kidnapping. Hijacking. Imprisoning.
Sometimes, innocent people are endangered by criminals.
Rescuing the hostages is the preferable outcome,
but I will never forgive such vicious criminals.
Today, let's play back the case where I took on an invisible criminal, who took many spectators hostage!
If cases were all men,
then I wonder if the unseen puzzles would be women?
The audience as hostages, a dangerous threat...
Stop the bullet in the blind spot of the case!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
January 1st
National Stadium
Emperor's Cup Finals
We, the Detective Boys, went to the National Stadium to watch the Emperor's Cup Final,
and in front of the eyes of us five, a soccer ball was shot.
At the same time, Nichiuri TV, who was broadcasting the match live,
received a phone call from the one responsible.
He demanded 50 million yen,
and if the match was stopped, the spectators left, or anything strange happened,
he'd indiscriminately start shooting at the people in the audience.
Basically, he had the entire audience as hostages, and was demanding a ransom.
As per the blackmailer's instructions, the bag with money was prepared,
but the officers watching it were too hasty.
He's here, Inspector. A man with a gray coat, a white mask and sunglasses.
The man took the bag.
Anybody around?
No, he's alone.
All right...
Get him!!!
The gun!
Find the gun!
I can't find it!
Where is it? Where do you have the gun?
Don't touch him!
Don't touch my partner!
Or I'll kill someone in the audience!
Let him go, now!
Partner?
So you did call the cops...
That wasn't what we agreed on!
Kaneko-san from Nichiuri TV!
T-That's...
You felt like mocking us. How about I kill someone to show we're serious?
H-Hey, wait!
This guy's dangerous!
So, who should I kill?
There's so many targets around...
Please stop!
I'll do anything you ask.
W-We'll stay out, too.
We don't want any innocent victims.
Very well.
I'll give you one more chance to make up for it.
Make up for it?
That's right.
I demand Nichiuri TV pay me an extra compensation fee for calling the cops.
A billion yen.
Before the game ends, put a billion yen in a bag near the 18th exit gate.
If once the game is over, the money's not there, I'll kill someone in the audience!
A billion?
That's impossible!
What? Are you saying you can't pay my share?
"My share?"
There's only one partner?
Hey. From the eight people we pointed earlier, is any of them using a cell phone now?
No, Inspector.
Everyone's watching the game here.
Same here. Nobody's talking.
Same here. Nobody on the phone, Inspector.
No way...
Where's this guy calling from?!
It's useless.
No matter how much you search, the police can never find me.
What!?
Right.
Please tell your agents watching the stadium to abandon their positions.
Understand?
I have 56,000 hostages here.
You know what I'll do.
Understood. I'll pull my men out immediately.
I don't believe you.
I still see them all in the same place.
The man smoking by the left side of the passageway at the back row of the front stand.
And diagonally ahead, the two men leaning on the handrail in the front row.
They're all cops, right?
I'll tell you about some more.
The fat man next to the goal on the right side of the front stand.
Hey, Genta, Mitsuhiko, Ayumi.
You're in the backstand, right?
Yes.
Is there anyone in there using binoculars?
Yes, many people.
I believe they're looking at the faces of the players leaving for half-time.
Moron!
I'm not talking about people looking at the field,
but at the stands! He's also talking on a phone.
I'm pretty sure there's only one person like that out of the 56,000 in here.
Ah, found him!
There's a weird guy looking at the stadium!
Where is he, Ayumi?
In the middle of the backstand, on the stairs.
But he doesn't have a cell phone.
He looks like he's listening to music.
Music?
Because he has earphones on.
There's something weird stuck on the middle of the earphones' cord, too.
I see. He plugged earphones with a mic to the cell phone.
That's why the officers couldn't find him!
Ayumi! I'm coming over,
so don't take your eyes off him!
He's the blackmailer!
Ayumi!
Ayumi-chan!
Genta-kun, Mitsuhiko-kun!
Ayumi, where's the blackmailer?
It's him.
A hat and a coat...
He's as suspicious as he gets.
Looks like the blackmailer.
Got you!
What are you doing?
Don't let him go!
I'll put him to slee--
Officer Takagi?
Oh, geez.
Officers shouldn't look so suspicious.
That's right.
I couldn't help it.
My radio's broken.
Your radio?
Yeah. Mine was the only one that didn't work.
If I'd used my cell phone, I might be confused with the blackmailer,
so I used my earphone-mic to keep in contact with the Inspector.
And what happened with the blackmailer's partner?
He left the stadium with the money.
The blackmailer said he'd kill an audience member if we followed him.
And he's the only one who left the stadium?
Yeah, that's right. Nobody else left.
Then the other blackmailer's still in the stadium?
We still have a chance to get him!
But he's quite a greedy blackmailer, isn't he?
A billion yen's a lot of money...
No...
I don't think he's after the money this time...
You can't just gather a billion yen in 45 minutes.
Then why...?
The blackmailer intended to kill someone from the start.
The moment the match's final whistle sounds.
Takagi-kun! How long has it been since the match restarted?
15 minutes since the second half started.
In other words, just 30 minutes until the match ends...
Before the game ends, put a billion yen in a bag near the 18th exit gate.
If once the game is over, the money's not there, I'll kill someone in the audience!
Understand? I have 56,000 hostages here.
Damn it!
Inspector!
Inspector Megure!
We lost the car of the other blackmailer who took the money.
What!?
Sorry.
Since he threatened us if we followed him, we couldn't track him too closely.
We did write down the car's license plate number, but it turned out to be a stolen car.
In that case,
we have no choice but to see if we can catch the blackmailer that's in the stadium.
The other?
Does this mean there's only two blackmailers?
On the phone, the blackmailer said...
...words like "partner" and "my share."
Basically, it's extremely likely that the blackmailers are two people.
Furthermore, he noted the positions of every police officer on the phone.
There's no doubt there's still a blackmailer somewhere in this stadium.
But how can we find him?
What should we do? Do we search the spectators one by one, treating them as suspects?
I'll think of something.
What if you watched the video?
When he called, the free cameras were focused on the stands, right?
Then maybe he shows up on the recordings.
There's got to be someone strange who's talking on a phone while using binoculars.
Inspector.
We can't find anyone matching the description in either the main stand or the backstand.
That's impossible!
Did you check all the news people who came?
A camera with a telephoto lens can focus even at long distances.
I checked the cameramen area, but there wasn't anyone suspicious.
Furthermore, if one of the them suddenly started a call while looking through their viewfinder,
the people around them would be sure to notice.
I see...
You've gotta be kidding.
Then how did the blackmailer make the call?
How did he have a full view of the stadium?
And without anyone noticing...
How is this possible!?
Inspector...
About the money... I've managed to gather 100 million yen,
but a billion yen's just impossible.
Can't be helped.
We'll replace the missing money with newspaper clippings and watch for the blackmailer.
Um, Inspector Megure?
What is it, Takagi-kun?
Maybe what he's after isn't the money...
Anyone who's ever been to a bank knows
that nobody can gather a billion yen in 45 minutes.
T-That's why I think the blackmailer's objective was just the 50 million yen they got, and...
Hey, hey, you can't mean...
The blackmailer planned on killing someone when the game stopped from the start!?
No... Why?
There has to be some reason.
Did anyone resent Nichiuri TV recently?
I don't think so.
Hey, mister?
Was the voice of the blackmailer calling you always the same one?
Yes.
In all three calls, the voice was a bit muffled, but I think it was the same man.
Then, we know the one who shot the gun and the one who called you were different people,
so the one who shot the ball was the one who took the money, right?
Yes.
I heard the other guy's voice from the phone that the blackmailer who escaped had.
But the one who escaped didn't have a gun, right?
Why was that?
Could it be...
...that he gave the gun to his partner?
Right!
From when the ball was shot 10 minutes in
to when the money was picked during injury time, it's 35 minutes of video.
Check it immediately!
Find a man who was in contact with the one who took the money.
That's the other blackmailer!
Yes, sir!
Goal!
At 37 minutes of the second half, Ramus's volley shot enters the net! 2-1 for Big Ōsaka!
Found him, Inspector.
That man's in the video.
And did he give anything to anyone?
No. He's just walking around.
Ah, damn. He's off-screen.
Don't give up! There's still time.
Keep searching while there's still a chance.
It's not very likely he'll appear on-screen.
Furthermore, we can't be sure he gave him the gun.
But we don't have any other way to find the blackmailer.
There's no other way!
We're almost up to injury time, Inspector.
Shut up! I know...
Damn, there's no time left!
Where, where, where?
Where could he be?
Please...
Time...
...please stop!
Don't be impatient.
People can't go against the stream of time.
If they try to force it...
...they will be punished.
W... What are you talking about?
Oh, that was close...
That's the third attempt...
This ain't the time to be watching the game.
You're wrong.
We're trying to find someone suspicious among everyone.
But that suspicious man keeps disappearing from the picture.
Disappearing?
Look, when he went to the left.
The camera moved and he was gone.
That's camera #13.
That was unlucky.
Right?
Now that I think about it, back then...
I see...
I see! That's how it was!
Inspector, we've entered injury time.
There's nothing else we can do.
Leave the camouflaged bags in the 18th exit gate.
The rest of you, get among the spectators! Hurry!
Yes, sir!
Huh?
Where's Conan-kun?
Go, Hide!
I finally figured it out, mister.
It's you, right? The one blackmailing Nichiuri TV?
Nobody would suspect you looking at the stands.
And you talking on your cell phone from those earphones and mic would also raise no suspicion.
Furthermore, nobody would think that the one blackmailing Nichiuri TV
would be a cameraman for that same station.
You're well informed, brat.
I saw the video you recorded.
The blackmailer's accomplice was spotted four times,
but all four times, he was immediately out of the frame.
That's when I figured it out.
It wasn't just a coincidence.
You were deliberately trying to avoid showing your accomplice.
Furthermore, all the police officer positions that the blackmailer mentioned on the phone
were on the main stand.
There's only one TV camera in the backstand that could see them all.
In other words, you're the only one who matches all the necessary conditions.
What will you do?
Will you turn yourself in...
...mister?
Yeah, I have no choice...
I'll do that...
Oh, crap!
I'd like to say that, but that's not going to happen.
I have my reasons for what I did.
A Beretta?
Not a Tokarev?
Yeah. My partner's is in some trash bag in here.
I got the Beretta and the Tokarev...
...while we were getting ready to rob a bank last year.
For three years, we did everything we could to come up with a perfect plan to get the money.
But on the day in question, they ran some stupid event
on the talent behind the bank or something.
My wife, who was expecting the money from that heist,
started drinking and ended up committing suicide.
It's all Nichiuri TV's fault for planning that stupid event!
I see...
And you became a Nichiuri TV cameraman to get back at them.
But what are you going to do?
If you shoot me right here, somebody will see.
Nobody will see.
Just look.
Everybody's paying attention to the game.
In the middle of this racket, nobody will hear a shot from a silenced handgun.
Nobody's going to see when you drop dead on the field.
I'll shoot you the moment the game ends.
Their cries of joy will turn into panic.
I'll take the chance to leave in the middle of the mess, and then I'll tell all the newspapers...
"I'm the person who killed a kid because Nichiuri TV wouldn't pay me the money I asked for."
What?
The game's over! 2-1!
Big Ōsaka won the Emperor's Cup!
The man of the match is the libero Ramus,
who played a big part in both attack and defense.
He marvelously defended his goal in the final moments of the match.
Ramus!
Nice clear!
The blackmailer was taken away by the police officers who came in once the game was over.
30 minutes later, they caught his accomplice at his home,
and the Emperor's Cup was over as if nothing had happened.
Oh, man. At the end, we didn't get to see much of the match.
And before we knew it, the blackmailer was caught, too.
The Detective Boys weren't very useful this time.
That's not true.
The Inspector said they couldn't have solved the case without you.
Really!?
That said, finding the blackmailer with such few clues...
...only you could've done it, Kudō-kun.
You're turning into quite an interesting study subject.
That doesn't sound like a comment an 84-year old lady would say.
Oh? I'm actually...
...the same age as you, 18.
Whatever...