Ancient Castle
"Ancient Castle."
An ancient castle with dignity, personality,
and a somewhat mysterious atmosphere.
Today, let's play back the case
which had that castle as its stage!
The flowers dance to a piano's rhythm.
Two people face-to-face are a mystery!
A great adventure in an old castle!
The Detective Boys go on a treasure hunt!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
"Tōbuzankei Campsite"
Yahoo!
This is a nice view!
Hey! Come here, hurry up!
Why'd we have to come camping with this cold?
It's all right. The kids are happy.
Whoa! There's fish!
Where? Where?
Either way, bring out the tent, doc.
The tent, the tent...
What's wrong, doc?
Don't tell me you did something as stupid as forgetting the tent...
W-Well, you see...
Are you serious!?
Man, what a disaster.
Going camping while forgetting the most important part: the tent.
Our vacation just got ruined.
Now it looks like we're lost, too...
Seems we're gonna have to spend the night in the car.
No way!
Maybe there's an inn somewhere around here...
Right! Maybe some sort of castle by the lake?
That's ridiculous.
Oh? Doesn't look so ridiculous.
Amazing!
It's like a western castle!
But what's something like this doing in the middle of the woods?
I'm sure some guy full of cash bought a foreign castle and rebuilt it stone-by-stone here.
All right!
Hey!
What do you think you're doing?
Isn't it obvious? I'm going in.
Hey! Where'd you come from, brat? Entering without permission!
Katsuo Tabata (41)
Mamiya Family Gardener
Oh, no, we're not bad people or anything.
Who are you?
While we were passing nearby we saw this incredible castle,
so we were wondering if you wouldn't mind if we could take a look...
Go home, go home!
This is no place for stra—
Oh? Who are these people?
Sir!
I don't remember any planned visits for today...
Mitsuru Mamiya (49)
Husband to the Eldest Mamiya Daughter
(Adopted into the family)
That stupid-looking geezer wants to see the inside...
Who're you calling stupid-looking?
I'm a brilliant scientist!
Scientist?
Indeed!
I am Hiroshi Agasa, a well-respected inventor.
Then, your intelligence...
...must be far superior to us normal people's, right?
All right.
Please come inside.
Would you like to stay in the castle for the night?
Oh! We appreciate it.
But, sir!
I don't think the Mistress would...
Tell her they're friends of mine.
With the state my mother-in-law's in, it'll be okay.
Geez...
Hey, mister.
Could you please let me go?
Amazing!
What a big garden!
A horse!
You're right.
There's a black one too.
But why is it just the head?
That horse is a knight.
It's a chess piece.
A chess piece?
And it's not just the one piece.
Look at the lawn where you're standing.
It's in a checkered pattern, right?
The lawn's cut up like a chess board.
Does someone here like playing chess or something?
I dunno.
I've always kept this garden like this as the previous master,
Master Sada'aki instructed.
And he too inherited it from the master before, who died 15 years ago.
The previous owner...
Then who was that man from before?
Ah. He's the Mistress' second husband, Master Mitsuru.
He's been here since Master Sada'aki died 6 years ago.
But said Mistress...
She died in a big fire, four years ago...
A big fire?
Yeah, look there.
You can see the burned tower. That's where the Mistress slept.
She'd just returned to celebrate her mother's birthday...
She arrived at midnight, and before dawn, the fire'd already taken over the tower.
And not just her.
Several friends she invited,
the staff who served her mother for years...
About ten people perished among the flames.
The only ones who made it were people like me, who'd just been hired,
her mother, who'd been in another room due to a cold,
Master Mitsuru, since he'd arrived just before the Mistress
and the Mistress and Master Sada'aki's only son, Master Takahito.
Takahito Mamiya (25)
Mamiya Family's Eldest Daughter's Son
He arrived two or three days before the fire.
From what I understand, he was educated abroad, so it was our first time meeting him.
That was also the first time we saw Master Mitsuru.
The Mistress apparently married him abroad, and they'd been living there for all that time.
And for some reason, ever since the big fire, Master Takahito has lived here with us.
And I have a feeling he's obsessed with something.
I imagine they weren't accepted into the castle all that well, since nobody even knew their face.
No. The Mistress sent us photos from when she re-married,
so we all knew how Master Mitsuru looked.
And as for Master Takahito, just look.
His face is the spitting image of his father.
Ah, anyone seeing this can tell they're related.
And what are the other paintings?
Master Sada'aki and the Mistress.
Master Sada'aki was adopted into the family,
and he had a lot of respect for the owner before him, as they were both historians.
But the Mistress was jealous and always criticized him.
Father was just an argumentative egghead who did nothing but complain.
Right?
M-Mistress!
He should've been angry by my words,
Masuyo Mamiya (83)
Head of the Mamiya Family
but he was happy that I was honest about it.
I'm sorry.
Sorry to bring back bad memories.
Don't worry.
I've gotten used to him not being in the castle.
It's like when they changed the size of the passport, or the faces in the bills
It's odd at first,
but with time, you come to understand that everything changes.
Time is a terrible thing...
but it erases both happy and sad times.
Mistress...
By the way, who is this?
Ah! Uh...
A scientist friend of the Master.
A scientist?
That's interesting.
Then they can uncover the mystery that he hid in this castle.
Mystery?
The Master said it in his will.
That he would leave his greatest treasure to the first one who solved the mystery of the castle.
By the way, is my daughter home yet?
She was supposed to come today to celebrate my birthday.
Ah, no.
Mistress...
Tell her to come to my room once she arrives. I'm looking forward to it.
Ever since the fire, she's been a bit senile...
Post-traumatic shock, I guess.
Hey, mister?
Is there any room from which you can see the whole chess board?
The chess board in the garden?
Amazing!
The chess pieces are all neatly lined up!
Where? I don't see them.
Hey, don't push, Genta-kun.
You can see them from this room, too!
Really?
Does the pieces' layout mean anything, or...?
You're happy, right?
It's one of those codes you love so much.
Am I wrong?
No, I think so, but...
Hey, you two!
What are you doing!? You're gonna fall!
Those morons!
What do you think you're doing!?
I thought I was gonna fall...
And now he fell.
Geez...
Huh?
The window's right next to the wall.
but in the other room, it was too.
Then what's between the two windows?
After all, since the old times it's been said...
...just match up the clock's hands and...
Conan-kun?
He was here just now...
I see.
This ain't no normal castle.
This is starting to get interesting.
A staircase...
This is pretty deep...
Where do these stairs continue to?
What...!
Conan-kun disappeared?
But wasn't he in the other room just now?
I dunno.
I looked the other way, and suddenly he was gone!
No way...
The chair fell down and the books are scattered...
And the clock's lid is open...
Haibara-san?
Hey!
Don't do bad things.
Did the kids do something wrong?
Ah, no, just a little prank.
Prank?
No! Conan-kun disappeared, so we're trying to find him!
Disappeared?
He must've gone to the toilet.
It's right under here.
Let's take a look.
If he was going to the toilet, he should've told us!
Ugh...
Oh? That's strange...
There's nobody here.
Is there any other toilet?
This place isn't used that much, so just this one.
Maybe he hid somewhere and wants to scare us.
It has to be that. Sometimes Conan-kun can be so childish...
Right, right!
You're children too...
Master Takahito, dinner's ready.
It's dinner time already?
I had them make dinner for you.
Want to eat?
Eel?
But if we don't look for Conan-kun...
It's all right.
He'll probably come out when he's hungry.
Thanks for the food!
Isn't it nice sometimes for it to be cheerful like this?
Ever since my mother died, less and less people come here.
But why did you two move here after the fire?
I'd long planned to come live here after I was done with the university.
I was worried about my mother-in-law, since she lost her only daughter...
but I've come to love the castle my wife was born in more and more.
What you like isn't the castle,
it's the treasure hidden somewhere inside it!
Grandmother...
Maybe so.
I can't deny that my father-in-law's will does influence my being here...
Hmph. It's hard to believe my daughter could fall for such a greedy man.
I'll go eat in my room.
When my daughter arrives, tell her to meet me there. I have much to tell her.
As usual, Grandmother acts as if Mother was still alive...
It's possible that her memory's bad.
Ever since she broke her legs ten years ago, she never left the castle.
Well, have you solved the mystery, Agasa-san?
Eh?
Oh? You haven't heard about it yet?
Father said he'd leave his greatest treasure to the first one to figure the mystery of the castle.
Ah, I heard about that from the gardener, Tabata-san...
But I don't even know where to start.
The chess pieces in the garden.
If that chess board was arranged by the same person who hid the treasure,
then the position of the pieces must be a hint to find the treasure.
Don't you agree?
Could you have figured out their meaning?
I couldn't have.
You couldn't solve it even though you've had four years.
The only one who could do it is lost somewhere in the castle.
That mystery gourmet full of vigor and curiosity.
Right?
Mystery...
...gourmet?
Here. Will this do?
Thank you.
What do you want that bag for?
I want to save one of my pieces of bread for Conan-kun.
I'm sure he'll be hungry.
That's right, what happened to the boy with the glasses?
We haven't seen him in quite a while.
We'll set out to find him once we finish dinner.
This castle's kind of like a maze.
Maybe he got lost somewhere.
I just hope he didn't end up in that tower.
"That tower?"
Look, that tower to the left of the castle.
It's covered in vegetation ever since my wife burned to death in it, four years ago.
Right. Also, two years ago,
an employee we'd just hired mysteriously disappeared one night.
Speaking about him, it seems that he used to say that there was something
odd about that tower to the employees he was close to,
and so we searched for him there,
and though there were signs someone had been there recently, we couldn't find him.
Afterward we called the police, and they began a big search of the entire woods...
And what happened after?
Ten days later...
He was finally found in the woods...
...having died from starvation.
What happened?
Who knows...
The police concluded that he'd gotten lost in the woods,
in an unfortunate accident, but among the staff,
a mysterious rumor was told for quite a time.
That the souls of those that died in the tower had possessed him.
Since then, the entrance to the tower is sealed.
Then we have to hurry and find Conan-kun before he starves!
I'll save my bread for him, too.
Me too.
Either way, let's split into groups and find him before it's too dark.
Hey, Conan!
Where are you?
If you're hiding, come out!
He doesn't seem to be in the garden.
We looked for him inside the castle, but we couldn't find him anywhere.
Then he might be in that tower.
No.
We checked the entrance just now,
but the door is still locked.
Then all that's left is the woods.
But it's raining pretty hard.
Entering the woods at night is dangerous.
It may be wiser to wait until the morning, then have the police search for him.
All right, you guys, get back to your rooms.
No way!
Ayumi-chan!
Conan-kun!
It's all right.
Don't worry about Edogawa-kun.
He's not a weak man.
He can find a way out of wherever he is.
Instead of crying, how about you tie that bag so the bread doesn't get wet from the rain?
Hey!
You're going to catch a cold!
Come on, let's go back.
Hey...
How do you know Conan-kun so well?
I don't know what you mean.
Could it be...
that you like Conan-kun?
What if I did?
I'm worried.
Don't worry.
I don't see him that way.
Really? I'm so glad!
Really? For real?
Geez. Kids these days...
But it's as you say, Ai-kun.
Shin'ichi's probably all right.
As they say, "no news is good news."
You actually bought that?
Do you really think he'd let us worry for so long without contacting us?
Something happened to him.
Maybe somebody in this castle kidnapped him, and he can't find a way out,
or in the worst-case scenario...
...killed him.
Hey, hey...
Either way, we have to call the police without the owners of the castle finding out,
and continue investigating.
Right. We have to search for him, not in the woods,
but inside the castle.
And I have an idea where to start.
Snap out of it, doctor.
With him gone, you're the only adult we can count on.
Let's see...
Phone... phone...
Found it!
This is Shin'ichi's cap!
What's with this door?
What is this place?
Doctor? If you're going to call someone, call someone who knows us
like Officer Yokomizo, or Inspector Megure.
Doctor?
Doctor...?
Into the darkness of the castle,
her friends disappear one-by-one.
The Detective Boys are in danger!
On the next Conan...
Next Conan's Hint: Passport
Look forward to the next episode!
Of course, Conan-kun has one too.
Eh? What?