Treasure
"Treasure."
Though there are some which bring happiness to people,
there are also those whose glow deludes people's hearts
and leads them to commit crimes.
Today, the secrets of the treasure hiding in the castle are unveiled
as we play back "The Old Blue Castle Exploration Case (Part II)!"
As the Dew
Song by Garnet Crow
The flowers dance to a piano's rhythm.
Two people face-to-face are a mystery!
The doc and I are in big trouble!
The Detective Boys and a treasure that vanished!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Original Comic Books By
Gōshō Aoyama
«Detective Conan»
Serialised in Shōgakukan's
«Weekly Shōnen Sunday»
Planning
Michihiko Suwa
Character Designs
Masatomo Sudō
Art Director
Yukihiro Shibuya
Art Designation
Hiroyuki Mitsumoto
Photography Director
Takahisa Ogawa
Sound Director
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
Music Producer
Hiroki Horio
Background Music
Katsuo Ōno
(Polygram)
Opening Theme
«As the Dew»
Vocals by:
Lyrics:
Composed by:
Arranged by:
Garnet Crow
Nana Azuki
Yuri Nakamuri
Hirohito Furui
(GIZA studio)
Video Editor
Terumitsu Okada
Story Editor
Jun'ichi Iioka
Color Designer
Reiko Hirayama
Production Lead
Hiroaki Kobayashi
Planning Support
Toyohiko Okuyama
Mitome Asai
Chief Producers
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
(Tōkyō Movie)
General Director
Kenji Kodama
Director
Yasuichirō Yamamoto
We, the Detective Boys, went camping with Dr. Agasa.
On the way back, we got lost on the mountain,
and ended up finding a castle in the forest.
Fortunately, they allowed us to stay for the night,
But the owners of the castle, the Mamiya family,
seemed to have some ulterior motive...
Inside the castle, I found a secret passageway,
and a skeleton in the basement.
But then...
le Explo
rt II)
ue Castle Explora
(Part II)
ld Blue Castle Exploration
The Old Blue Castle Exploration Case
(Part II)
What is this place?
Doctor?
Hello? Is this the police?
I'm calling on behalf of Shin'ichi Kudō.
Can you pass me to Inspector Megure, from the 1st division of the investigation department?
Calling a friend, little girl?
Hello, Megure here.
Something like that.
Haibara-san!
So this is where you were...
Geez, where'd you go?
Our beds are ready.
Oh? Where's the doctor?
Wasn't he with you?
Who knows...
Maybe he's trying to find this castle's treasure.
The doctor's bed's still empty.
Something must have happened to him.
Either way, I have to investigate what's going on.
I knew it.
What do you think you're doing?
It's because we're worried about Conan-kun.
The doc hasn't come back, either.
So we thought we'd help with the investigation.
It's a lot easier for four people than for just one.
Right, right!
Eh, fine.
If you get murdered, I don't know anything.
- Hey!
- What do you mean?
That's...
The room we were in during the day.
Kojima-kun, can you please put that chair under the clock on that wall?
Haibara-san...
What on earth are you doing?
What's this?
A secret passageway.
Manually moving the clock's hands triggers a mechanism that opens the door.
Come on, let's go.
Hey, Haibara-san, is that...?
A flashlight-watch that Dr. Agasa gave me.
He gave you one too, huh?
"You too?"
Having fun?
Let's go.
What a long staircase...
What's that?
It's blood.
By its color and dryness, it hasn't been here for many hours.
Amazing! Haibara-san, you look just like Conan-kun!
What are you so happy about?
This could be his blood.
Look at that.
There's something written in the stairs.
"That person trapped me here and is trying to steal the castle's treas..."
Sounds like he meant to write 'treasure...'
Could Conan-kun have written this?
No, from the style, it doesn't sound like it.
And the writing looks old.
Then who wrote this?
I don't know who wrote it, but...
But since the person didn't finish writing 'treasure,'
he or she probably was unable to finish it.
Unable?
You can't mean...
Right.
Right. He or she could have died here.
Edogawa-kun must have found the body, and taking advantage of his distraction,
somebody must have attacked him or stabbed him from the back. That would explain the blood.
Hey! Something fell down here!
They look like glasses...
Wait! Aren't those the doctor's glasses?
What are the doc's glasses doing here!?
They're broken and bloody...
Something must have happened to the doctor...
Haibara-san...
What is it?
This is where I lost sight of the doctor!
This is strange.
This time I can't seem to open the door.
Genta-kun's still in there...
Can't be helped.
We'll have to go back to the starting point and find him.
Damn! What's going on? It just opened...
Seems to have been locked.
Why? It was open before...
Somebody must have followed us.
They locked the door to prevent us from leaving the room.
But we happened to be able to get out with that door.
Then what about Genta-kun?
He must have fallen into the hands of the one following us.
No way...
Either way, let's go find another way onto that passageway.
While there's a chance our three missing friends may still be alive.
What a big room...
Seems to be what Takahito-san uses as a workshop.
They did mention he was a painter.
That's a lot of newspapers!
They're used to cover the paintings, or to dry the brushes.
Either way, these newspapers are very old.
That's...
"Big fire at Mamiya residence"
...the fire from four years ago!
Those are...
Conan-kun's glasses...
Fifteen people died in the fire.
The fire burned the bodies into ash, down to the bone.
Their identities were estimated from the objects they carried.
One person is still missing.
Using that fire, a person could pass off as another...
Hey! Mitsuhiko-kun's gone!
Maybe he went through that door...
That's odd...
That's the door leading to the burned tower, which was supposed to be locked...
Mitsuhiko-k...
Wait.
It could be a trap...
I'll go inside and take a look,
while you go hide in the bushes.
But...
Count up to 300, and if I'm not out by then, run away immediately.
If you take the road through the forest, you can still save yourself.
Haibara-san...
Put yourself together!
You brought that bread for Edogawa-kun, right?
2... 3... 4... 5...
83... 84... 85... 86...
153... 154... 155...
298... 299...
3... 300.
300... I counted them.
Haibara-san!
Haibara-san?
Where are you?
Haibara-san!
Count up to 300, and if I'm not out by then, run away immediately.
If you take the road through the forest, you can still save yourself.
No...
I can't do that.
I can't run away...
Because I have to give Conan-kun this bread.
I'm not... scared...
Haibara-san?
Where are you?
Answer!
Haibara-san!
This...
...is the toilet.
Haibara-san...
No...
It's not Haibara-san!
Looks like he's gone...
What are you doing here? Didn't I tell you to run?
You were saved because I just happened to be in the secret door, but...
...if I hadn't been there, you'd have been killed.
It's just...
With everybody else in danger,
I can't just escape by myself!
Oh, geez...
What a kid...
Here, wash your tears.
And let's go find everybody.
Hey... Where's Mitsuhiko-kun?
I don't know...
If he was in this tower, then that person from now probably caught him.
No way...
Conan-kun and the others are gone...
By the way, what happened with your Detective Boys badges?
They were out of batteries, so we gave them to the doc...
I see...
Look! There's somebody here!
Look, over there!
A skeleton!
This is...
With the bones like this, it's been years since this person died.
But considering the dust, the skeleton was placed here recently.
This might be the person who wrote in that staircase.
I believe the skeleton was moved here after Edogawa-kun found it.
But who is this?
Compared to the other bones, the leg bones are extremely thin.
Furthermore, the teeth are worn out...
And this hairstyle seems to be that of a woman...
No way! Then the killer who's pretending to be her is...
Is something wrong, girls?
I heard voices and came to see what was going on...
Oh? Where are your friends?
It's terrible!
A bad person kidnapped all of my friends...
Haibara-san?
Wait! If we don't take the old lady with us, she might be attacked!
What are you talking about? She's the one who attacked you!
The leg bones in that skeleton were those of a person who hadn't walked in a long time.
Combined with its sex and age, it has to be the body of the family's grandmother!
Then who was that?
She killed the grandmother to impersonate her!
She got plastic surgery and pretended to have a bad memory to fool everybody.
It happened on the day of that fire!
Since the real woman's daughter wouldn't believe her deception she burnt her to death!
She knew about these secret passageways, and used them to start the fire unnoticed.
Afterwards, she got plastic surgery to change her face and returned...
And her objective was this castle's treasure...
That's right.
The grandmother figured out I'd came to the castle for the treasure,
so I got rid of her and took her place.
Our voices were similar, too...
Don't worry.
I won't lock you in that dark basement like I did the grandmother.
You'll be unconscious, and after 2 to 3 days, I'll drop you off in the forest with your friends...
You'll have pale cheeks and look like Smart-san.
Stop that.
Putting kids on a forced diet is wrong.
That's right. They're both fine the way they are.
Right, right. Having a full belly is much healthier.
G... Guys!
Why are you...?
It was thanks to Mitsuhiko.
With my glasses' tracking function,
he followed the transmitters in our Detective Badges that the doc had, and found us.
D-Damn it.
Wait. There's no use running.
You're the missing housekeeper, Mutsumi Nishikawa-san.
When I asked about you to a plastic surgeon who knew your true identity, he knew it right away.
"Have you heard of a weird patient who got surgery to look like an old lady?"
So you saw the corpse too?
Even if we hadn't, we'd still know you're a fake.
If you really were a grandmother who spent the last ten years locked in this castle,
you couldn't have talked about how inconvenient
it was for the passport sizes to change six years ago.
Unless, of course, you had to frequently travel abroad to keep that face.
Congratulations. But I know these secret passageways so you'll never be able to catch me.
Oh? Running away?
Even though I know where the secret passageway is that you want so much?
What? Don't tell me you managed to figure out the mystery of the chess pieces?
Yeah.
A chess piece's position is often determined by an alphabet letter, from A to H,
and a number, from 1 to 8.
From the Knight's face, we can see that the stone path is the right place to watch the chess board.
Looking from that position, putting letters to the white pieces, you get...
In other words, an intellectual person who argues a lot.
Right. This code points to...
...the castle's former owner!
Afterwards, if you turn the painting to the right as the black pieces show...
The secret passageway opens to a smiling face.
Twenty years serving in this castle...
The treasure I searched for is finally...
I won't let anyone have it, it's mine!
On the other side of that shining door...
...is my treasure!
What...
Where's my treasure?
Where is it?!
It says so on the door.
"I offer this wonderful view of the castle to the first person to arrive here."
It can't be...
I killed dozens of people for something like this?
I changed my face to an ugly old lady's for something like this?
For something like this...?
An hour later, the police came and took away the killer.
Having lost her soul, she was a pathetic figure who truly became an old lady...
Mitsuru-san was disappointed with the castle's treasure,
but the son, Takahito-san, was happy that the killer had been caught.
Apparently, he had suspicions about the fire from four years ago,
and had been secretly investigating it.
Those secret passageways were part of the castle's original construction,
and the former owner, a historian, made sure to rebuild them correctly during the restoration.
This castle was pretty interesting!
Lots of thrill and suspense!
Right, right.
Hey, hey. Conan-kun and I were attacked...
Hey!
Master Takahito says breakfast is ready.
Come and eat. The boy in glasses didn't eat anything at all last night, right?
It's all right.
We have food for camping on the car,
and I've got this bread, too.
It looks like it's really tasty.
Well, since you're inviting, I'll go.
Ah! Me too!
You guys...