There are two types of astrophotography,
fixed shooting and guide shooting.
In either case, the shutter speed for taking
the picture may be slow or open,
so that unexpected events may occur in the picture.
In this case:
What kind of thing was captured.
The rhythm on my lips is footloose!
The rhythm of my detective skills is perfect!
Ran and Sonoko make an astronomical observation.
The lens captured an amazing scene.
Seeing the one and only truth,
A child with an adult's intelligence...
His name: Detective Conan!
Gimme Love Gimme Love kimi wa doubt
hidoku chachi na kono torikku nanoni mistake wana ni ochite
mogaku hodo oboreru dream furyo no kisu wa amakute
urunda kimi ga hanarenai no way mujaki ni kakushita
your way doku ga mawaru amai mitsu ni hone made okasare
boku ga kowareteku nante souteigai da
makka na Lip no guradeeshon miwakuteki shoutai
mattaku kaidoku funou nanda yabai kimi no shoutai
denkou sekka de hamatchatte nogarerarenai
kono mune ga haretsu shisou
makka na Lip de bare bare demo damasaretai
choppiri azatoi shigusa mo zenbu dakishimetai
issai gassai itoshikute zettai zetsumei kimi wo mou hanasanai
so I'm going to crazy crazy!
toketeku yume no naka kono mama itsumademo
subete kimi no omoi doori
Nagano Prefecture
Stargazing place
11:20 p.m.
Oh, can see Mars!
Huh? Wait wait, Ran-neechan! Hey, let me see it too!
Sorry sorry, here you go.
Ah, it really is!
Jeez, I don't see any shooting stars...
Sonoko...
Don't just look for shooting stars
Try looking through the telescope.
No way.
I want to see the shooting star with my own
eyes and wish for a nice boyfriend.
Jeez, why did you even bring this expensive telescope then?
Well, it looks weird to come to see stars
if you don't bring a telescope, right?
It's more weird not to use telescope at all after bringing it along.
Ah! Shooting star!
Where, where?
It's already disappeared.
Hey, Ran started talking and caused me to miss it!
Ran-chan.
Yes?
EDA KAZUHIKO (23)
First year of graduate
school at Toto University
Well, you can use it now, right?
Eda-san! Thanks for the help.
Who's that?
He's a student from Touto University, a graduate student, Eda-san.
When you left for a moment,
He taught me how to use the telescope.
Hey Eda.
Ah, Senpai.
Note: Senpai used here is as someone more educationally advanced.
If you have time to flirt, you have time to work on data.
No, it's not like that!
Let's see, this is...
NONAKA KOICHI (24)
Second year of graduate
school at Toto University
My Senpai at the University in the Graduate
Division, Nonaka Koichi-san.
AKIMOTO HIROSHI (24)
Second year of graduate
school at Toto University
This is my other Senpai, Akimoto Hiroshi-san.
Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you, my name is Mouri Ran.
This child is Conan-kun, and she is...
Nice to meet you, I'm Suzuki Sonoko.
I love to gaze at the stars...
Ah, I remember now!
Weren't you on TV yesterday, Nonaka-san?
You were receiving same award.
Yeah. It's the equivalent to a Noble Prize in
astronomy field, called the Star Pioneer.
Also, I'm the youngest to ever receive it
Does he always talk like this?
What's up with him?
Nonaka-senpai, is the filming going smoothly?
Yeah. I was a bit tired so I came back to get some coffee.
Where did you do the filming?
There, that tower. The rooftop with the TV satellites.
It looks pretty far away.
But it's only a minute or two if you drive.
On that tower,
I'm filming with Akimoto, having our
cameras right next to each other.
This guy, he bought the same camera after won the prize.
Has everyone been here since yesterday?
No, I just made it earlier due to the stars I wanted to take photos of.
Hey Akimoto, we need to go.
Yeah, good luck out there.
That's right, between 11:30 and midnight, there will
be a satellite pass in the southern direction.
Ah! Really?
Yes, it will probably be very easy to find.
11:50 p.m.
Ah, my neck is starting to hurt.
I haven't seen a satellite yet
Akimoto-san!
How was it? Did you see the satellite?
No, not yet.
What happened, Akimoto-senpai?
Well, I'm supposed to take photos
from 9:00 p.m. to 3:00 a.m, right?
I'm free during that time, so I just came back.
Is it okay to just leave the camera?
Yeah. The filming method we use right now is called fixed filming.
We just leave the camera shutter open for certain time period.
So while taking the photos, it's okay not to attend.
I've seen that before, the stars are filmed in circles.
Exactly, Conan-kun, you're really smart.
But where is Nonaka-san?
He's on the tower's platform.
His first shift is from 9:00 p.m. through midnight,
And then another shift from midnight through 3:00 a.m.
So he'll be taking two photos.
So he has to adjust the camera at midnight.
That's right! Let's spot him with the telescope.
Since he was tired I bet he's sleeping.
00:15 a.m.
Ahh... I can't really see anything over there.
I can see a silhouette of someone standing though.
He's also looking this way. He's yawning just as I thought.
Oh!
Nonaka just fell!
Akimoto-senpai!
Do you have your cell?
Yes.
Then I will go check on Nonaka!
Hurry over there after you call the police.
Yes!
Ah, wait Conan-kun!
00:20 a.m.
Akimoto-senpai.
Nonaka-senpai!
He's gone.
Nonaka...
00:25 a.m.
Here it is.
The railing is low... the moisture makes this surface slippery.
Possibly an accident.
What's this?
Why is there debris here?
These marks... they're new.
This damage is unnatural.
Both cameras have release button on.
That means... they should still be filming.
Conan-kun!
It's bad to run around by yourself.
Akimoto-san, do these belong to you and Nonaka-san?
Yes, that one is Nonaka's and this one is mine.
I'm in no mood to take photos.
Photo ending at 12:30 a.m.
This is Nonaka's final photo.
02:00 a.m.
I'm ready.
Right.
Everyone: You witnessed Nonaka-san fall from there, correct?
Yes.
I saw him from the telescope.
When his hands side over the railing,
It looked like he lost his balance.
Would you happen to know the time he fell?
I remember it was 15 minutes after midnight.
Since I'm used to observing the stars,
I often look at my watch.
Officer, I believe Nonaka-san was standing a bit to the right.
Since it was dark, maybe you were mistaken.
Oh, I see!
These are photos taken by Nonaka-san.
After an expert examination,
It has been determined this was from 9:00 p.m. to midnight.
And this one from midnight to 3 a.m.
Both have been confirmed to have been taken from that roof.
Akimoto-san, did you close the shutter on
Nonaka-san's camera at 12:30 a.m.?
Yes, that's right.
From these two photos, we can assume,
Nonaka-san probably ended the filming and
started his second photo filming at midnight.
And at 15 minutes past midnight he fell due to losing his balance...
There's nothing unusual at the site.
There's no evidence suggesting anyone
else other than you guys were there.
I believe it's just an unfortunate accident.
Wrong... this is not just an accident.
Akimoto-san is lying.
The relationship between Akimoto-senpai and Nonaka-senpai?
Yes, as they were discussing the Star Pioneer award,
I noticed that Akimoto-san seemed angry, so it bothered me a bit.
Ah, well... That's Nonaka-senpai's fault...
In truth, that research which was awarded,
that was co-research between two.
But Nonaka-senpai announced and turned in the
research analysis saying it's his own research.
Oh, if someone did that to me, I wouldn't ever film
together at the same place with that person!
But, this observation...
Was organized by Akimoto-senpai.
He said he didn't mind the award
What was it that you lost here, Conan-kun?
A button from my jacket, I'm not sure where I dropped it.
Even if Akimoto-san was the culprit...
There's no doubt, he was with us when Nonaka-san
fell at fifteen minutes past midnight.
Hold on.
All we saw was a silhouette!
We didn't see Nonaka-san.
Something that resembles the silhouette,
For example, a doll, we wouldn't be able to distinguish.
Then again...
When we arrived, there wasn't anything like a doll.
And then, when we met Akimoto-san...
He just came out of his door and standing.
He couldn't have hid it.
Furthermore, shortly after Nonaka-san fell...
Akimoto-san was with us all the time.
Huh?
What's wrong, Eda-san?
I dropped my car keys.
Ah, there.
That's called, "it's darker underneath the candle light jar"
I see.
It's there!
Thank you, Eda-san!
It's just as I thought It's possible if you use that.
But we have no evidence. And those two photos...
There has to be a trick involving those two photos!
This isn't good...
I missed the shooting star and then something
unfortunate happens. Such luck...
Sonoko!
I've found it.
The decisive evidence.
Everyone: I'm sorry for the delay, thanks
for your patience until very late at night.
We have declared this incident as an accident.
I really don't get enough sleep...
Wait, Sonoko
Sonoko-neechan, what's wrong?
I'm alright, Conan-kun.
Now, Officer.
Hm? What is it?
Nonaka-san didn't die from an accident.
He was killed by none other than Akimoto-san.
A bit after 11:30 p.m., Akimoto-san...
When he returned to that tower with Nonaka-san,
He pushed him over the railing and killed him.
In order to distract us,
He lied about a satellite.
We paid attention to the opposite side of the tower during that time.
Wait, you said you saw Nonaka-san fall.
That wasn't Nonaka-san, but a doll.
Doll?
Right. After Akimoto-san pushed Nonaka-san over the railing,
He tied a doll onto the railing a bit next to where he was standing,
And quickly secured it with fishing string.
Don't forget, there are fresh marks on the railing.
And fifteen minutes after midnight:
The timer connected to the string...
Dropped the doll.
Akimoto-san used us to witness his location
at the time by watching it with us.
By making himself one of the witnesses of the accident.
He created a seamless alibi.
What are you trying to say?
Sonoko-chan, when you arrived at the tower,
Was there any doll?
Yes there was. It was under your car.
You hurried to the location as fast as possible...
Making sure to stop over the doll,
Easily concealing it from us.
And, while we were trying to help the already dead Nonaka-san,
You moved the doll into the car.
The doll you made with a blanket and fishing string.
Wait, that's just your speculation.
I did use the blanket in my car,
But that's because the tower's pretty
cold, it was only used to cover me.
You were the first one to arrive at the tower,
But the last to approach the body.
Nonaka!
What were you doing?
But... but, Sonoko-chan.
Nonaka was alive at midnight.
The two photos proves it.
Right, that camera cannot be operated without an operator.
That means, I was with you, Sonoko-chan, since 11:50 p.m.
So it's impossible for me to operate the camera from far away.
It's impossible for me to have killed Nonaka.
But if you insist I'm a murderer,
I hope you have some evidence.
Excuse me, Officer Yamata.
This is the photo of Akimoto-san's you wanted developed.
Akimoto-san's photo?
I had Conan-kun assist me.
That photo is the evidence.
What are you talking about?
Analyzer officer: Would you mind comparing Akimoto-san's photo
against Nonaka-san's photo during the 9 p.m. to midnight shift?
I understand.
These are the photos taken by Akimoto-san himself.
What is this?
It's a shooting star.
Didn't you all see a shooting star towards the tower?
I didn't see it myself.
I did see it.
Akimoto-san and Nonaka-san's photos
are taken in the same direction.
Look, on Akimoto-san's photo you'll notice a shooting star.
Nonaka-san's photo has no shooting star.
This is the evidence that Nonaka-san's photo wasn't taken today.
If that's true, even though Akimoto-san was
on this rooftop with others since 11:50 p.m.,
It can't be used as his alibi.
That's exactly right.
Akimoto-san...
You wanted to replicate that same photo,
So you bought a camera like Nonaka-san's.
Then, went to the tower the day before and took two photos.
Unless you had the murder plan, you wouldn't have done so.
And, after killing Nonaka-san today...
You set a doll.
You then removed the recent film from Nonaka-san's
camera, replacing it with the prepared film.
But, there is a flaw in your trick.
That is...
The shutter noise.
The shutter noise?
Right. After changing the film, you can't press the shutter.
That means, the prepared pictures would be distorted.
If you did something like that, it would mess up
the prepared film and your trick will not work.
So you had to just leave the camera
as it was without pressing shutter.
I see!
If you try to imitate pressing shutter of the camera at 12:30 a.m., if
anyone realizes there was no shutter noise, you'd be discovered.
I believe Akimoto-san thought...
The death of Nonaka-san would frighten everyone enough...
So they wouldn't notice such an insignificant matter.
But, Conan-kun noticed it.
Yeah, there wasn't a sound from the shutter.
Akimoto-san was imitating the noise with his voice to cover it up.
It means, Nonaka-san's camera wasn't
taking the photo at that time.
But Akimoto-san said he was closing the shutter at 12:30 a.m.,
And the photo for 12:30 a.m. came out
alright also, so found that weird.
Even if the camera didn't take the picture,
but the film produced the photo.
That means, the film had been changed.
The only one who could do such thing is...
Akimoto-san, you're the only one!
When... did you start suspecting me?
When Nonaka-san fell.
Didn't you ask Eda-san to call the police?
Usually people call the paramedics.
But you called for the police, meaning you
knew Nonaka-san was already dead.
You're such an intelligent young lady.
Akimoto-senpai... you never truly forgave Nonaka-senpai?
Of course not, the Star Pioneer was my dream...
Even if I had to do co-research with someone else
Yet Nonaka took it all for himself.
How could I forgive him?
But, I didn't see a shooting star about 11 p.m. tonight.
While was thinking of killing Nonaka,
I didn't even look at the sky.
why anata no koto wo omou to
Munasawagi ga suru kaze ga fuku no
Konna sabishii hana dakara
Aa kondo koso wa saigo kamoshirenai
Itsu kara konna ni Surechigau you ni nattandarou
Sukoshi zutsu sukoshi zutsu nanika ga henka shiteitte
Anata mo mawari mo kawatte
Watashi no sei nanokatte
Konna ni daiji na hito nanoni
Ahh, I had good sleep.
Amazing, Sonoko.
Another excellent deduction.
Huh, it's morning already?
Yeah.
Ahh! I wanted to make a wish to the shooting
star for a boyfriend before it gets bright!
Why do my princes from shooting star always escape my grasp?!
Everything escapes you like this.