Summer
Summer.
A fun season where you can enjoy yourself going to the sea, the mountains, or under the dazzling sun.
But you never know where danger may lurk.
A fun vacation might take a sudden turn into terror.
Today, let's play back the case where I went to the beach with Ran and Sonoko!
Flowers dance to a piano's rhythm.
Two people face-to-face are a mystery!
A summer beach and a lovely encounter,
but a suspicious man foreshadows a case!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Izu
Perfect!
Hey, Sonoko! What are you doing?
Photographing your butt!
What are you going to do with a photo like that?
Isn't it obvious?
I'm gonna show it to Shin'ichi-kun when he gets back!
Think how happy he'll be!
Don't be silly. Shin'ichi isn't like that.
Don't you agree, Conan-kun?
Umm, yeah.
What does a little kid know?
Ugh... I can't wait to get back to normal...
You've been acting weird, Sonoko.
Why're you picking on me?
Don't mind me.
I'm just a bit jealous.
Eh? Why? Did I do something?
Haven't you noticed, Ran?
Why'd we come on a weekend beach trip to Izu in the first place?
For you, it's your usual man-hunting trip, isn't it?
Right!
And it's a carefully planned "poor girl vacation", too!
What are you on about?
We always stay at my family's summer house, or an expensive hotel!
"Oh, how can I talk to a girl who's so far beyond my reach?"
This time, we're staying at an old inn, where we can reel in unexpecting boys.
I... see...
Some plan.
But... But...
Sonoko...
On the train here...
At the fireworks show last night...
And even at this beach...
All of the guys are after you. Every single one of them, Ran!
Oh, come on... No way!
Well, who cares?
I'll just show Shin'ichi-kun a photo of you in your underwear that I took last night!
Hey!
Don't even think about it, Sonoko!
If you do that, I'll never forgive you for it!
Just kidding. Never took any photo.
For crying out loud, Sonoko!
Oh, she was lying?
Hey, you two...
Are you busy?
Would you like to get some lunch?
Tadahiko Michiwaki
It's on me, of course.
Y-Yes! We'd love...
...to.
You want her, don't you?
Here, take her! She's in season!
Sonoko!
But don't try anything funny!
She's already taken.
I was kinda hoping to get to know you better.
No way!
You did it, Sonoko!
It's great!
Impossible. This is Sonoko we're talking about.
There has to be something behind this...
I've got to stop thinking like a detective all the time.
Shall we go?
Then Conan-kun and I will stay here!
You're a student at Beika University, Michiwaki-san?
Ran's dad used to study there, didn't he?
Yeah!
Come on. Always talking about guys and then she wimped out and dragged us along.
So, Michiwaki-san, what brings you to Izu?
It's just a trip to heal a broken heart.
My girlfriend dumped me.
I was gazing into the sea in despair...
...when an angel appeared before me!
I have a hunch you're the goddess who's going to save me...
G-Goddess?
Here's your draft beer.
Oh, thanks.
Makoto Kyogoku
Sir, please don't drop cigarette butts all over the floor.
They're a pain to clean up later.
Haven't we seen that waiter somewhere before?
Of course we have. His dad owns the inn where we're staying!
He's come to help over summer vacation.
How do you know that?
He was staring at us from the front steps of the inn, so I asked one of the workers.
Then why's he working here?
It's probably run by the same person who takes care of Kawaraya Inn, where we're staying.
Oh? You're staying at Kawaraya Inn?
Yeah, that's right.
Fancy that, it's right next to my hotel.
Then how about we all have dinner at a fancy restaurant by the sea tonight?
I'll pick you up in my car.
Eh, really?
But don't forget to bring your camera!
Huh? Why?
I just learned this from a local,
but there was an incident at the beach near the restaurant.
An incident?
Yeah.
About a year ago,
a girl with long brown hair was stabbed repeatedly in the stomach and killed.
A murder?
Yeah.
She was killed on her way to that restaurant,
but there were no witnesses. The police are still looking for the killer.
It's been a year since the case,
so most people forgot about it, and the restaurant's doing well.
Unfortunately, she seems to have taken a liking to that restaurant, and still drops by...
S-Still...
She appears in photos taken inside the restaurant...
...as a grotesque ghost with her innards pouring out!
Yeah, no.
So let's see if she really appears in a photograph.
H-Hey, what do you think? I still have about ten shots left in my camera...
No! Don't even bring it!
But if we showed it to Shin'ichi-kun, he might notice something.
After all, we're going to show him the shocking photo, too.
What's the point of showing him that one? You can't even tell who it is!
He could figure it out with his super deductive skills!
Come on...
Deductive skills?
Her boyfriend's a detective.
Eh, really?
And what's in that photo?
Well...
Sonoko!
Here's your yakisoba.
We've got a lot of customers waiting, so hurry up and eat.
Geez, what's with that waiter?
Does he have a grudge against us or something?
Shoji Terabayashi
Can't we eat somewhere other than that restaurant?
It sounds creepy.
Don't worry!
The ghost thing's just a rumor, and it's been a year since the murder!
I'm sure the dead woman got bored of that restaurant by now.
Hey, did you hear?!
They found another one in the forest by the train tracks!
Another what?
A corpse!
The bloody corpse of a woman with brown hair!
I'll be right back!
Conan-kun, no!
Conan-kun!
Stabbed multiple times in the abdominal area.
Detective Yokomizo
Shizuoka Police Detective
Just like a year ago.
Yeah.
Looks like another tourist, too.
By the way, what's the time of death?
Between 8 and 9 PM last night.
So it was right after the fireworks.
Hey, isn't that around the time we passed by here?
Yeah...
This is scary...
Don't worry!
There's no way you'll be attacked!
But look at me! I have brown hair too!
There's no guarantee I won't be next!
I don't want to die out here...
Not with my whole life ahead of me...
Sonoko...
Don't worry.
I'll protect you as long as you're here in Izu.
Anyway, I guess we should change our dinner reservations, huh?
Yeah.
And no cameras!
Of course not.
I'll pick you up around 7.
Wait for me in front of the inn!
Gotcha.
Wasn't that guy at the seafood place, too?
See you then.
Yeah. Have fun!
We should go back to change clothes, too.
Yeah!
If it isn't Ran-san and Sonoko-san!
So you've come to Izu, huh?
Yeah, we came for the beach.
So, is Detective Mouri here too?
No, it's just us three.
Three?
Good afternoon!
Ah, you're the knight accompanying these two damsels, huh, Conan-kun?
Be sure to protect them!
Sure!
Please be careful.
As you can see, we've had a troubling incident.
Yeah. We'll be careful.
Then I'll be leaving.
Give Detective Mouri my regards.
Okay!
He's as cheerful as always, I see.
Looks like he's not having any luck, though.
If your dad was here, he'd solve the case in no time!
Detective Yokomizo is far more competent than the old man...
Oh, it's starting to rain...
I hope Michiwaki-san shows up soon.
Calm down!
The hero always appears at the last second!
Stop! You're embarrassing me!
What's with the umbrella?
I guess he wants us to use it.
Maybe he's got a crush on you, Sonoko-neechan.
You're getting popular, Sonoko!
Not the dark guy too!
Of course, you already have Michiwaki-san.
Stop it, Ran, you're making me blush...
Oh, crap. I left my purse in my room.
Hold on, I'll be back in a sec!
Okay!
What's wrong, Ran-neechan?
I know I've seen the guy in glasses somewhere, but where?
Somewhere in this inn, right?
No, not just here.
Somewhere else...
Really?
Where? Where'd you see him, Ran-neechan?
Ran-neechan!
Sonoko?
What's taking you so long?
Maybe she's changing...
Sonoko! What happened?
A weird guy jumped me... he escaped through the window...
What?!
Damn... He's already gone.
I was so scared!
But why would anybody...
How should I know?!
When I opened the door, there was a guy searching our bags.
I tried to shout, and he grabbed me!
Searching our bags?
I bet he was trying to steal our underwear! Yuck!
What did he look like? You saw his face, right?
I never had the chance...
It was pitch dark in here...
But how do you know it's a guy?
I bit his arm in the struggle. It was hairy!
Way to go...
What's wrong?
Why are the lights out?
Michiwaki-san!
My car broke down on the way here, so I ran here as fast as I could.
But how'd you find our room?
I couldn't find you two outside, so I asked one of the staff.
His shirt's wet and his pants are muddy...
What if...
Hey, Michiwaki-san.
Would you mind taking your shirt off?
I was wondering if you could show me your upper arm.
Conan-kun!
I'm not sure what you mean...
Is there anything wrong with my arm?
Nothing. No tooth marks from Sonoko...
Happy now, kid?
Yeah.
Is anything wrong?
A bandage!
What happened to your right arm?
I had a little struggle with a drunk customer.
When was that? Please tell me.
I don't think it was him. The guy who attacked me was hairier.
Attacked?
Yeah. A man came in through this window, ransacked our bags,
and attacked Sonoko when she happened to walk in on him!
But he ran off as soon as he heard us coming.
Must've been a thief.
We've had this happen before.
You did? Then why didn't you tell us?
I did tell you to make sure to lock up, didn't I?
Walking around in a midriff top at this time of night, what are you expecting?
You're practically asking to be attacked.
It doesn't even look good on you, anyway.
This is my favorite top, you jerk!
Don't worry. You look good in anything.
Yukata, swimsuit, whatever!
What are you doing?
I'm going to move you. There's another room open.
Unless you want to spend the night in the room where you were attacked.
No...
I'd also advise you not to go out, and have dinner here at the inn instead.
You never know if that man might be waiting for you outside.
What do we do, Ran?
I guess we'll eat here...
The food's much better than I thought!
If we'd known this before, we would've eaten here last night, too!
We would've been able to get you a nicer meal if you'd made reservations in advance.
Of course, the meal's on the house...
...if you don't spread any "rumors" about a thief lurking around the inn.
Right, right! Whatever!
I won't mention the underwear thief who pulled a knife on me!
A knife?
That's right! I saw it shining in the light coming through the side screen!
It was sharp and gleaming!
Uh-oh...
What if our thief is the same man who killed the woman found in the woods today?
Supposedly a year ago, here in Izu, a brown-haired woman was stabbed.
But why would the killer target Sonoko?
Just because she has brown hair?
Hold on...
The guy who attacked Sonoko ransacked her belongings.
There's one thing in her luggage that could be connected to the murders.
The camera!
Maybe one of the photos captured something related to the murder!
Sonoko-neechan! Did the guy who attacked you steal your camera?
It was still in my bag.
But the compartment where I had it was open.
So he stole the film?
No, it wasn't in there.
I finished off all thirty-six photos, so I dropped it off to get it developed at noon.
I thought we could look at the pictures over dinner.
See? I've got the photos here.
Mind if I take a look?
Go ahead!
Don't worry.
I kept that special photo of you for safe-keeping.
Don't scare me like that, Sonoko!
You know all of these people?
You seem to have interrupted a lot of lovers...
Sonoko was all cranky before she met you.
She kept pranking all the couples we met!
R-Ran...
Strange... There's nothing odd about the photos.
I don't see the victim, either.
We did pass through the forest where the body was found last night,
but Sonoko didn't take any photo then.
So what made the killer think Sonoko'd taken an incriminating photo?
Why?
Maybe someone overheard her at lunch...
He could figure it out with his super deductive skills!
The killer could've been in the seafood shop at the time.
But was it really that suspicious a remark?
Hey, you're going home tomorrow at noon, right?
Yeah.
So how about we stop by the cursed restaurant in the morning?
Let's go, let's go!
It won't be as scary in the daylight!
But no cameras!
I know!
Am I imagining things, or does this guy keep watching us?
And what about that guy in the glasses, the one Ran thinks she's seen before?
And as for the guy who attacked Sonoko...
Was he really just a simple thief?
Huh?
Isn't that Michiwaki-san's car?
It's heading straight for a cliff!
Sonoko! Wake up, Sonoko!
Enough is enough!
If you thought you could run away forever, then you were wrong!
Oh, damn! Sonoko's in danger!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Pantograph!
That's the black and white thing that's famous in China...
It's not a panda, it's that thing on top of an electric train!