Culprit
"Culprit".
Whenever there is a crime, there is a culprit.
And in order to cover up their crime,
they'll stop at nothing to try and deceive us.
Today, the surprising identity of the culprit
who targeted Sonoko is revealed,
as we play back
"Sonoko's Dangerous Summer Tale (Part 2)"!
If we keep mourning the passing seasons,
we can't confront the mysteries in cases!
Big trouble by the summer seaside!
The mysterious man in front of Sonoko!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
The three of us went to Izu to do some swimming.
Ran and I are witness to a strange summer event!
Can you believe it?
Sonoko gets herself a boyfriend. His name is Michiwaki-san.
But while she's in seventh heaven,
waiting for him to pick her up for their dinner date,
someone attacks her!
Is it my imagination, or are we being watched?
What bothers me is that man
with the glasses who Ran saw.
And the man who attacked Sonoko...
Is he really...
just a burglar?
There it is!
What a lovely restaurant!
There don't seem to be
many customers, though.
Maybe we came too early.
Are you sure you aren't coming, Sonoko?
I'm sure.
I was up all night thinking about that burglar.
I'll rest in here.
Oh, all right. But what a waste...
There are drinks in this cooler, so help yourself.
Thank you so much!
Then, we'll see you later, Sonoko.
Have a nice time.
After your nap and if you're feeling up to it, join us in the restaurant.
I will.
I'm exhausted.
You think she'll be all right?
She's sleeping inside a hot car.
Don't worry. I turned the air conditioner on.
Wow, look at this!
Is this for one person?
Yep!
There's plenty and the price is low.
That's the secret to this restaurant's success!
Oh brother, a full-course meal for lunch.
See?
Didn't I tell you the food was great?
Yes, it was delicious!
I'm completely stuffed.
Thank you very much!
I feel a bit bad for Sonoko though.
You're from the inn.
Do you come here often?
No, this is my first time.
By the way, where's your brown-haired friend?
I haven't seen her anywhere...
You mean Sonoko...
She didn't get enough sleep last night,
so she's resting in the car parked outside.
Look!
Isn't that your car, Michiwaki-san?
W-Why's it moving?!
Oh no!
It's heading straight for a cliff!
Please come again.
Huh?
Hey, where do you think you're going? Pay your bill!
That's a lock pick!
The side brake's disengaged!
Sonoko, wake up! Sonoko!
I can't put full strength in while I'm running!
Oh no!
We're almost there!
Conan-kun, let go of the car!
Ran!
Sonoko, grab onto me!
Hey!
Are you guys all right?!
Yeah, somehow...
That was close.
I'm glad you're safe.
Hey, you!
Why didn't you put the side brakes on?
Don't be ridiculous! I did have them on.
If they weren't on, the car would've fallen off the cliff a lot sooner.
Someone released the side brakes.
Someone broke into the car using a lock pick.
Someone who wanted Sonoko-neechan dead.
I see.
So someone broke into the car while Sonoko-san was asleep inside,
and released the side brake,
and made it roll down this slope and off the cliff.
Here's the diver's report.
The side brakes of the car
underwater were disengaged.
Also, we found this lying on the road.
It's been wiped clean of prints!
Did you find anything else?
No.
Just a puddle of water that must've
leaked out of the car's air conditioner
where the car was parked in the parking lot.
Sonoko-san, did you notice any
suspicious figures around the car?
I wouldn't know...
I didn't sleep much last night,
so I was sound asleep in the car.
But ever since we arrived in Izu,
we're being followed for some unknown reason...
That's him over there.
Would you mind identifying yourself?
I work at the inn where the girls are staying.
I came here today to have some tea.
The inn's not busy during the afternoon, and I had some free time.
He isn't behind this.
When the car started moving, he was already in the restaurant with us.
If he'd forced the car door open,
released the side brake, and
then come into the restaurant,
we would have seen him walk in.
The waiter told me that the back door is always kept locked.
We first noticed him when he came out of the restroom,
but there's no window leading out from inside the toilet.
And of course, Michiwaki-san's in the clear too.
He was eating with us and never left the table.
That means...
The most likely suspect is the man following us!
Who is he anyway?
Listen up.
We'll take all your statements down at the station.
So please get into the car.
The car?
Umm, I don't feel like riding in a car just yet.
I'm kinda scared.
Then how about I walk you to the police station?
It's not that far, and we can
enjoy the scenery. How's that?
Yes, sounds good!
W-Wait just a minute!
What if she gets attacked again?
Sonoko-san does have brown hair, you know.
Her assailant could also be the killer from that other case.
You have nothing to worry about.
No one would be foolish enough to attack her in broad daylight.
B-But you never know!
Don't worry, Detective.
Michiwaki-san will be with me,
and so will Ran.
Just don't stop anywhere.
Come straight to the station.
Yes, sir.
But, man...
The attack at the inn last night,
and then the car incident today.
They sure are after you.
Sonoko, are you sure you
don't know what's going on?
No, I have no idea.
Maybe it's because you're so charming?
Right, why is she being targeted?
And if he wanted her dead, why didn't he do it when he broke into the car?
There was no need for the car to be pushed off the cliff.
We planned on leaving Izu as soon as we had lunch, so all of our luggage was in the car.
They've all gone up in flames now.
Sheesh, why is all of this happening?
You might've lost your
luggage, but I lost my car!
Yeah, you're right.
Just because you got involved with me.
I guess I brought you bad luck.
No, I don't think of it that way.
I'm not so unlucky. You lost all your memorable photos.
That's something you can never replace.
All that's left now is that one photo.
One photo?
You know, the one I'm going to show Shin'ichi-kun.
I have it on me at all times—
you have nothing to worry about!
You still have it?!
C'mon, get rid of it! You're making me mad!
That's it! It's that photo.
He wants to get rid of that photo!
He had to send the car over the cliff to get rid of her luggage!
But I don't understand...
Why does he think Sonoko took an incriminating picture of him?
There wasn't a single unusual photo in the bunch.
Or did I overlook something?
It's him again!
I think we're being followed.
Is it the killer?
Can you run?
Y-Yeah.
Then let's go!
Let's go too!
But isn't it more dangerous to go through the woods?
No, this is more thrilling!
Right?
Yeah.
Anyway, let's split up to shake him off!
That's strange.
If he's Sonoko's attacker, why's he still after her?
All the photos were burned!
A train?
Come to think of it, they found a body in this forest yesterday.
When we passed this place a couple nights ago, I'm sure a train went by.
What is this?
I'm missing something here!
Damn! I've lost them.
The situation's turning bad.
Enough is enough!
If you thought we'd just run, you're sadly mistaken!
H-Hey!
You shouldn't have run
through the forest in sandals!
Sandals?
It was you, wasn't it?
You're the one who attacked Sonoko last night at the inn, and sent the car over the cliff!
H-Hold on there! That's—
No use lying!
Your hairy arms are proof enough!
Let's have a look!
There should be bite marks where Sonoko bit you last night!
What? It can't be... No bite marks!
Maybe on the other arm!
Huh? No marks on this arm either!
What's going on?
Who are you anyway?!
Well, actually...
I'm a detective with the Chiba
Prefecture Police Department.
You're just showing me the cover.
You think I'd fall for that trick?
My father used to be a police officer. You can't fool me!
When an officer has to identify him or herself,
they must show the first page of the police notebook
with the photo and corresponding data.
Shoji Terabayashi at your service.
Oh, my. It's the real thing.
I'm on the trail of a suspect.
A suspect?
Ran-neechan.
You don't usually wear socks with sandals, do you?
No, not really.
Oh no!
Sonoko's in danger!
Ouch!
I stepped on a twig.
I guess running about in the forest
with sandals wasn't such a good idea.
Are you all right?
Tooth marks...
Why are you so surprised?
There's nothing to be so
surprised about, is there?
After all...
This is the mark you gave me last night.
I finally get it!
Sonoko didn't bite an arm last night, but his leg!
She must've gotten mixed up in the dark!
He thought Sonoko took his picture
because the sparks the train's pantograph produces
lit his back at the time of the murder,
when Sonoko passed by holding a camera,
and he jumped to the wrong conclusion!
He thought there'd be a shot of him with the victim!
Come to think of it, I remember him saying...
Don't worry. You look good in anything.
Yukata, swimsuit, whatever!
The only time Sonoko wore a yukata was during the fireworks show two nights ago!
We only met him yesterday.
How could he know what
she looks like in a yukata?
Damn it!
Why didn't I...
Why didn't I figure it out sooner?!
What are you doing?!
Give me that picture.
The picture you were going to have some detective look at!
You probably thought you took a romantic picture of a couple,
but I was in the middle of committing murder!
Just like now!
F-Four?
Michiwaki-san killed four people?
If he was responsible for the murder the other night,
then she's probably the fourth!
For some reason, he only
kills girls with brown hair!
I've had my eyes on him for a while now.
I got him on a stolen vehicle charge once,
but there wasn't enough
proof on the murder charge.
I came to Izu because I heard that a similar murder happened there,
and there he was!
But I arrived too late to save his latest victim.
But there's something I still don't get.
How did he make the car move on its own if he was in the restaurant the whole time?
With ice.
He had a cooler.
He took a wedge-shaped piece of ice out,
and placed it under the left front tyre to prevent it from moving.
Then he pretended to talk to Sonoko-neechan who was inside,
and released the side brake!
Then he left a lock pick on the ground...
to divert the investigation!
I see.
That's why he left two spaces open when he parked!
Then there'd be no cars obstructing his car's path when it moved!
On top of that, the melted ice would just appear to be water from the AC.
But why?
Why does he kill only girls with brown hair?
I told you, didn't I?
A heartless girl dumped me.
And that's...
That's why...
Whenever I see flirty girls like you...
I get so mad!
Girls with brown hair, just like the one who dumped me!
Look over there! Isn't that Sonoko?!
What?!
Oh no!
Why? Why?!
Why are all the guys that make a play for me so weird?
I hate you, God!
Are you all right?
Am I all right?
What about you?
Oh, this?
Now I remember!
I knew I'd seen that guy with the glasses before.
It was at the tournament!
He's the captain of the Haido High School Karate Club!
The Prince of Kicks!
Makoto Kyogoku!
Wow.
You're a very reckless lady.
You're lucky I was nearby and had some free time.
"Free time"?
Do you mean you were
following me all this time?
Yes, I was following you the whole time.
Until I lost sight of you in the forest.
I knew you might mistake me for a stalker.
Before he met you,
he'd been flirting with a few other girls.
It got me worried.
Why did you worry about me? You don't even know me.
You probably didn't notice me, but I'd seen you once before, at a karate tournament.
You were cheering on your friend.
I never thought you'd
reserve a room in our inn.
Oh, and...
I suggest you stop wearing
outfits that are too revealing.
It arouses the guys more than necessary.
Of course, you're free to ignore my advice, and pass it off as just another casual remark
made by one of your many admirers.
Teitan High School
Kyogoku-san's gone abroad to study?
But why?
You and he were getting along so well since then, weren't you?
He said he ran out of strong opponents in Japan, so he went abroad to train.
THREE DAYS LATER
Ran!
Let's go see the baseball team's practice game!
The other team's ace is a freshman.
I hear he's so cute and just so adorable!
Good grief.
I thought you were going to wait for Kyogoku-san to return.
That was then. This is now!
I knew it.