It takes about one hour for the Yamanote Line to go around.
The Osaka Loop Line takes about 45 minutes.
And the Toto Ring Road takes 1 hour and 10 minutes.
What happened this time
while going around the Toto ring road?
The rhythm on my lips is footloose!
The rhythm of my detective skills is perfect!
The trick is the short-term absence of the criminal.
In addition, the secret lies in the missing weapon and the alibi.
Seeing through the one and only truth.
A child with the intelligence of an adult.
His name is: Detective Conan!
It left without us.
Yep.
Hey!
I told you to wait for me.
Give me a break.
Uncle has some serious issues.
I just finished working. At least let me have a beer first.
What do you mean "you just finished working"?
You only went to pick up a folder you left behind last time.
Since it's Sunday, no one's even at work.
Dang, this is good!
Anyway, it sure is empty, huh, Conan-kun?
Yeah. Probably because it's Sunday night.
Since this station's next to a business
park, people usually come out in droves.
We sure worked hard today.
I'm sorry about all this.
Man, you sure are ditsy.
Last year's new recruit, Kiyoumi,
caught on much faster than you did.
Kurata Seiji (26)
Speaking of Kiyoumi, she sure left in a hurry.
Did she have plans or something?
Kawai Shizuka (24)
It was probably a date.
Since today's Sunday.
Really. Since somebody messed up the assignment,
we had to came in on the weekend and do overtime.
Mori Yukiko (20)
I'm really sorry. Next time I'll make it up to everyone.
That's what you always say.
Now, now. Don't pick on her like that.
It's not like Yukiko did it on purpose.
There you go again, playing protector of the newbies.
Thanks to that, I look like the bad guy.
Don't talk like that.
Come on. That's enough, you two.
Oh?
The train will be arriving at Platform No. 2 shortly.
I'm going to get a juice.
Hey, the train's almost here.
Don't worry. You get on it first.
Jeez.
Conan-kun, hurry up.
Okay.
Wonder if Yukiko managed to catch the train?
You know how she likes to take her time.
Wanna go check?
Just what do you think you're doing, Yukiko?
Ah, Seiji-san! I made it just in time.
But the juice spilled a little.
Klutz.
Eh?
Yukiko, that's so like you.
Eh, isn't that Kiyoumi?
Oh?
You're right.
I thought she went home a long
time ago. So why is she still here?
She's fast asleep.
You think she's been on the
train so long it looped back around?
She must have been pretty tired.
Kiyoumi.
Hey!
Oh!
Wh... What was that?
Excuse me.
No pulse. She's dead.
I'm sorry. Do you know her?
Yes, we're...
Just who are you?
Me?
I'm Detective Mouri Kogoro.
Mouri Kogoro... That famous detective?
Her earlobe looks like it's been pierced by something.
And this ear has a greenish bruise on it.
Uncle, her ear's...
Don't interfere!
This ear color... is a reaction to poison.
This could be a murder case.
Murder?
Ran! Get the conductor, and the police.
Okay.
Eh?
What's this mark from?
Please stand back.
Until the police arrive, no one is to enter this car.
You, too.
Kiyoumi...
Please don't touch the body.
I'm sorry.
Inspector Megure, I had the other passengers leave a
record of their names, phone numbers and addresses.
The estimated time of death is around a half past six.
I see.
The body was discovered a little after half past seven.
Going once around this Kanjo line
takes about one hour and ten minutes.
There's no doubt that she died on the train.
In other words, the victim got
on the train and died soon after.
Once the train ran full circle, she was
found at the very stop where she'd first boarded.
Right. So, how about the cause of death?
It was most likely an object laced with lethal
poison, like a poisoned pin, that pierced her ear.
Otherwise there's no sign of any struggle at all.
This is the victim's leather handbag.
What are you doing?
S-Sorry.
Hey, Uncle. Wasn't the bag open the whole time?
You just can't stop talking, can you?
Eh? Wait a moment.
Which means, the criminal could have
taken something from the bag at any time.
Inspector, the victim's wallet is still
here. Nothing seems to have been stolen.
Now, we have to ask those
three coworkers about the bag.
Maybe they'll notice something.
Right.
Takagi-san.
Something else fell out over there.
Oh? You're right.
Thanks, Conan-kun.
We'd like you to identify the victim's belongings.
Eh? Where's the third person?
After seeing what happened, she went into shock.
Can't really blame her.
Well, I'll just ask the two of you some questions first.
Conan-kun, that's enough.
Let's go over there.
But I...
Nope.
Are you... feeling any better?
Yes. I'm all right.
Stuff that Kiyoumi always carried?
I can't remember every little thing.
But maybe Seiji knows.
You kept trying to get friendly with
her and gave her presents, didn't you?
Were you dating the victim by any chance?
No. She kept turning me down.
So you have a motive for revenge.
I... Why would I?
Shizuka, how can you say that?
That's enough.
We usually get along really well.
But since this incident happened, today...
Due to your work, you all went to the company office.
Then, Hashimoto Kiyoumi-san later
went back home alone. Is that right?
Yes.
It's Sunday today. Was there work to be done?
We design advertisements.
Because I made a mistake yesterday,
everybody had to came to work to fix it today.
So, when was the last time you saw Kiyoumi-san?
It was at Nibangai Station. We went with her to see her off.
Was there anything strange
about Kiyoumi-san at the time?
We parted company at the ticket
entrance. Nothing seemed unusual.
That was about half past six.
So, before the body was discovered,
you three were together the whole time?
Yes.
Did anyone hold a grudge against Kiyoumi-san?
Seiji-san.
From what was said a minute ago,
since you were dumped by Kiyoumi-san...
Y-You've got to be kidding me!
Besides me, there's Yukiko. You held a
grudge against her for taking your boyfriend.
No, I didn't!
And Shizuka, you once said
that she plagiarized your designs.
Just what are you trying to say?
In other words, everyone has a motive to commit murder.
Wait a moment, Mouri-kun.
The time of death has been
established at about half past six.
That was the time when we left her at the station.
Correct, so it happened right after that.
Were you three really together that whole time?
Yes. We ate dinner together.
It was in the same restaurant we
usually go to. Call them if you don't believe us.
Since they all have alibis, then
they're definitely not suspects.
Why would the criminal kill her on the train?
And it was done by sticking something in the ear.
An ear that shows signs of having been pressed upon.
It's a pretty odd way to kill someone.
In other words, none of you have any idea
Why Kiyoumi-san was killed?
The MD player has foam-covered headphones.
All the MD disks are labeled.
An MD index label.
Eh?
That's odd.
None of them have labels on the front.
This color...
That's it!
I knew something was off.
That time.
I get it.
That's how it'd be possible to establish
an alibi when murdering Kiyoumi-san.
The culprit must be that person.
If I'm right, the culprit is that person.
But there's not enough evidence.
Have they finished checking our belongings yet?
It's probably almost finished.
How could we have stolen anything from her bag?
Give us a break!
That's enough, Shizuka.
They're just doing their job.
Oh, that is...
What are you doing?
Oh, I'm sorry.
Shame on you, Conan-kun.
I'm sorry, Seiji-san. I'm really very sorry.
No matter. I sweat easily anyway.
So I always have a spare set of clothes handy.
Inspector, may I get the change of clothes out of my bag?
Sure. I don't see a problem with that.
You need to learn to sit still.
I'm gonna go apologize to him.
Kiyoumi-san got along with everyone else, right?
Yeah. Even though we were upset a minute ago
and said we all had grudges against her and stuff,
Nobody really hated her.
We were all good friends.
You must be right.
Like today. Yukiko dropped Kiyoumi's
MD machine on the floor and broke it.
Kiyoumi didn't even get mad. She forgave her right away.
Yukiko got along really well with Kiyoumi.
You'd think having a stolen boyfriend
in the mix would ruin the relationship.
Maybe you're too young for that kind of talk.
Kiyoumi-san got on at
Nibangai Station like we all did, right?
Oh, yeah.
But Kiyoumi-san was sitting way up front in the second car.
You'd normally board a train at the first open car or so.
But she went out of her way to go
down to the second car. Isn't that weird, huh?
Yeah. The exit that Kiyoumi uses to get
off the train is closest to the second car.
That's why whenever we went places with her, we
walked down a couple more train cars and boarded.
Oh, really?
Which means that all three of them knew that
Kiyoumi usually chose the second car to ride in.
I've figured out all the puzzles now.
Inspector, we've checked everyone's belongings.
I'm sorry it's taken so long.
You can pick them up now.
If we have any further questions,
please work with us to get them answered.
Here we go again.
You can't leave just yet.
Now what, Mouri...!
That pose...
The culprit isn't some random passenger.
It's one of the three people right here.
You're saying the culprit is one of us?
The murder weapon is also close at hand.
But, Mouri-kun...
We all have the same alibi.
We were eating dinner together.
Even so, there was an opportunity to commit the crime.
First, the culprit, who knew Kiyoumi-san was leaving first,
Saw her off at the station,
And established what time she boarded the train.
From that, the murderer timed how long it would
take for the body to loop back around to the station.
The culprit then had a meal with
the others to establish their alibi.
After returning to the station, the culprit
took back the murder weapon from the victim.
Murder weapon? What murder weapon?
Haven't you figured it out?
You can put them on your ears.
But they don't look so strange there.
Oh!
So that's what happened! She
put poison on the headphones.
Exactly.
The culprit is...
Mouri Yukiko-san.
You killed her!
First, you damaged Kiyoumi-san's MD
player, and then loaned her your own.
Along with the headphones
you had poisoned ahead of time.
Then you said you wanted to buy some fruit juice, and
boarded the car in front to retrieve the murder weapon.
Yukiko-san already knew that
Kiyoumi-san would sit in the second car from the front.
And once her location was known, retrieving
the murder weapon wouldn't take too much time.
However, the headphones were pressed
between Kiyoumi-san's shoulder and the wall.
So you pulled too hard and ended
up breaking one of the earpieces.
I see. It's definitely broken.
An imprint from the headphone card was left on her arm.
And it looks like something pressed down on her ear.
Which proves that she'd been wearing the headphones.
I-I only went to buy some juice.
I don't remember doing anything like that.
When you and the others
discovered your co-worker's body,
Didn't you readjust her shirt collar for some reason?
When you were pulling off the headphones,
you must have jerked her shirt collar up, too.
You just wanted to take away the
murder weapon, and leave the body lying there,
But then Seiji-san and Shizuka-san
were coming up from the next car.
That's when they discovered Kiyoumi-san's
body and you stayed with them on the scene.
So the victim ended up stabbing
her own ear and poisoning herself.
But why'd it have to be inside a train?
On Sunday nights, this route has fewer passengers.
And the second car is usually empty.
So this was the best way to create an alibi.
So that's why.
And with other passengers on board,
People would think it was some random killer.
So, you deliberately screwed up during the work day,
To make everyone meet up on a Sunday.
What about the proof? Where's your proof?
There's nothing resembling a pin anywhere.
She must have removed the pin with her handkerchief.
The headphone sponge cover had a hole in it.
I've been sitting right here with everybody the whole time!
When the victim's possessions were being identified,
You said you felt sick and stayed behind.
You had to be alone to remove the pin.
May I see your handkerchief?
Yes.
It's no use, Inspector.
Oh?
It's a very tiny pin.
It could be anywhere now.
Then Mouri-kun, without proof,
everything you've said is just speculation.
No, the proof is in the MD player.
What?
If you mean fingerprints, of course
mine would be on it since we were friends!
And I didn't lend her anything today.
Well, can you take the disc out of the MD player for me?
Is there a problem?
"Thank you, Yukiko. By Kiyoumi."
"I didn't lend her anything."
That's what you said.
But inside that MD player you didn't lend her,
Why is its disk labeled with today's date?
It's even written with the pink
ballpoint pen from the victim's purse.
That's true.
The color matches the ink in the ballpoint pen.
Yes, Kiyoumi-san left a message for you.
She never dreamed that you'd kill her.
Kiyoumi-san...
I... I just couldn't take it anymore.
She stole my boyfriend.
It's his birthday today. I thought
Kiyoumi-san would be leaving early because of that.
So that's why you chose today to kill her?
Yes.
Takagi-kun, did you find out where she got the poison?
Yes, sir.
It's a kind used in blow darts in
South America. It kills instantly.
She said she came across it a
few days ago on an overseas trip.
She smeared it on a small pin and
put it under the headphone cover.
Blow dart poison...
The poison took a while to trace.
Mouri-kun, without your famous deduction
skills, we might have never solved this mystery.
Blow dart poison...
Oh, I had a feeling it might be that...
Oh, you knew all along. I should have known.
Hey, hey. Maybe Uncle's still
under the influence of my sleep darts.
What! Curse?
Oh?
Oda-san!
This rope.
Impossible.
You can't reach the balustrade on foot.
This is a suicide, no doubt about it.
No. This is a murder.
Next Conan:
The Legend of the Mysterious Pagoda! Part 1.