The glorious future is just one step away.
Naturally, all my preparations are OK!
This time it is the Puppet Ridge—
the frightnening mystery of a curse related to spider webs!
Seeing through the one and only truth,
he looks like a child, but his mind is of an adult.
His name?
Detective Conan!
The Tottori Spider Mansion Demon!
Huh...
That's strange.
I feel like we're goin' around in circles...
Hey, Heiji.
Are ya sure we're not lost?
Our bike is out of gas too.
Maybe we should have come in a taxi!
Ya moron!
Aren't ya the one who said ya knew this area pretty well and jumped onto the back of the bike, huh?
But, what are we going to do?
In the letter ya received,
ya were told to get to Takeda-san's home by tonight, right?
Yeah, that's right.
They didn't even give a phone number, just a weird letter along with some cash.
So now, I got to give the money back to that idiot.
Besides, I thought I might solve the mystery as well, but...
Since the sun's about to go down, it looks like we're going to have to camp out tonight.
C-Camp out?!
No way, no way!
Without any tent or sheets in the wild like this...
It won't be funny if we catch a cold!
We'll just wear a few extra layers of clothing from what we brought,
and as long as we sleep close together,
one night won't kill ya.
Sleep close together?
Stop lookin' at me with those sick eyes, will ya?
Hey, that's my line!
Anon, anon. Fights art not valorous...
L-Let's go, Kazuha.
Let's just say we never saw this.
Yeah, let's.
Please wait!
It was just a joke... just a joke!
My name is Robert Taylor, I'm an American.
Robert Taylor (26)
Photographer
Just a photographer, who loves the nature of Japan.
I was just taking a picture of this
forest that I have not seen for so long.
'Cause the last time I was here, was still the time when I was under Takeda-san's care.
Takeda? Ya know where that house is?
Yeah, I was planning to go there right now.
Wow, you're the same as us then.
In that case, could ya show us the way?
Well, the thing is, I focused
too much on the scenery, and...
You're not goin' to say... you're lost too... right?
But you guys are going to
Takeda-san's home as well, so...
Looks like we're goin' camping.
What?! No way, No way!
What else can we do? No one else is comin' by here, so...
Hey, wait a second!
I told ya to wait, didn't I?!
Hehe! That stopped it!
What the hell do you think you're doing, punk?!
Sorry, sorry. I didn't think it was gonna hit for real—
Aren't you...
Ah, isn't it Hattori-kun?
That would mean...
I thought I sensed something bad about all this.
What?
You guys are goin' to Takeda-san's house to solve a case too?
Yes,
but my letter and yours differ greatly. It's more official.
I was addressed by the head of the
Takeda family, Takeda Nobukazu-san.
Then, what's this thing—
The invitation that came to my house?
Is there another Takeda 'round this place?
Hey, let me take a look.
Sure.
Let's see.
Next Saturday,
before the sun sets,
show up at the Takeda House in the Puppet Ridge.
Or else...
Yet another living doll shall become the spider's prey once more.
The spider's prey?
That's definitely talking about us...
Strange incidents have occurred at our home lately.
And that's how the people
around here started calling it...
Takeda Yuuzou (35)
Takeda Family's third son
The Puppet Ridge's Spider Mansion
There's a curse there so don't get too close!
T-The Puppet Ridge's...
Spider Mansion?
What?
Misa-san died three years ago?
B-But why?
Takeda Yoko (33)
Takeda Ryuji's wife
About two or three days after you left,
she was hanged in the second floor of the doll shack...
Was it... a suicide?
Yes.
Then soon after,
my sister in law,
Misa-chan's mother,
hanged herself at the same place.
Why again?
I have no clue.
But it didn't stop there.
T-There's more?
Yes.
Just a few days ago,
Negishi-san, whom my brother in law was indebted to, was...
found in the tool shack, in the same way.
Did that person come in and out of here quite often?
Yes.
My brother was a puppet maker.
And Negishi-san was in charge of the
transportation and selling of those dolls.
It's about that Negishi-san's case.
The case that my brother wish for you to solve.
Dear...
Takeda Ryuji (38)
Takeda Family's second son
I'm the second son of the Takeda Family, Takeda Ryuji.
Both of you... don't have the Tottori accent...
Yes.
We're usually in Tokyo.
We came because of the long weekend, but...
Because of Negishi-san's death,
my brother told me not to leave until you detectives showed up.
Detective Mouri.
Takeda Nobukazu (45)
Takeda Family's first son
I'm Takeda Nobukazu, the one who requested you.
Sorry to have dragged you all the way out here in the mountains.
Not at all.
Excuse me, Nobukazu-san.
It's been a while since we met.
Oh, Robert-kun.
It's been a while indeed.
It's been three years since the summer break, wasn't it?
I came here to thank you for that time, but...
No problem, you're welcome here.
You see, Sae and Emi, who were very
close to you, have also just come back.
Oh, there they are.
Oh!
Sae-chan, Emi-chan.
You've grown up a lot.
Murderer.
Takeda Sae (9)
Ryuji and Yoko's
older daughter
Takeda Emi (9)
Ryuji and Yoko's
younger daughter
He came back to kill again?
He sure has...
How scary!
Scary, scary.
Hey!
You two, what do you think you're saying?!
Mama's scary too!
I'm really sorry...
That's okay...
Takeda Chie (71)
Mother of the 3 Takeda sons
Hey, mama... Why is it that Emi and I only got half a fish each?
Yeah, why so?
I'm sorry about that,
I only bought enough fish for the planned
number of people... and now we're lacking two.
So please put up with it, okay?
Eh?
Uhh, if that's the case then, this...
What is it, Kazuha?
If you're goin' to leave the fish, then I'll take it.
You...
Huh? Where are you taking those?
Shiotani Miyuki (26)
Housekeeper
Oh, to the grandmother's room...
Ever since Negishi-san's death,
she keeps saying that there is a curse and refuses to come out...
So I'm taking these to her.
I guess I'll go finish up the dolls that I've been making.
In that case, Mouri-san.
Yes?
Starting tomorrow, I hope to see
you do some thorough investigation.
You got it.
Well then, please take your time here.
Yuuzou, you don't need to go help your brother out?
Come on, wait a while.
Just one more cup.
Excuse me, may I borrow your car, please?
I wish to go visit Misa-san's grave.
At a time like this?
Yes.
If I go now,
it'll be just around the time when the moon hangs
between the two mountains behind the cemetery.
Moon between two mountains, huh?
Can I go with ya?
Certainly.
Hey, would ya like to go too, Ran-chan?
Yeah, I'll go too.
Ran-neechan.
Would you like to come too, Conan-kun?
Take this with you.
This should come in handy if something happens.
Like what?
Take it, take it!
I don't know what's goin' on, but I think
that boy's jealous of other men close to ya.
You idiot.
It's nothing like that.
See ya later!
Yeah.
Alright, dear,
we're going to bathe right away...
So keep the fire running, please.
Okay.
Hey, brother!
Brother?
What's going on, Yuuzou?
I can't find our brother!
Neither in his workshop nor anywhere else!
What?
What did ya say?!
What about the tool shack?
Did ya check the shed?
I checked both, but he wasn't there.
That's strange!
The shed's second floor window is open.
That's the place where both of them committed suicide...
It's so creepy that nobody comes close to it anymore!
The stairs are over there.
Hey!
Damn, it won't open! It's locked from the inside.
Can someone bring an axe or something?
Uh, sure.
This is...
Brother...
Bro!
That can't be... Call an ambulance!
Y-Yes!
That's not it.
What ya gotta call isn't the ambulance, but the police.
He's already cold.
It's been 'bout one hour since he died.
A thumbtack?
The surface is rusted, but the needle is new...
But why is it in a place like this?
Anyway.
Can ya hurry and call the police, please?
Uh, yes.
But if you say that this is a murder,
how did the culprit escape from this room?
Probably through that small window.
With a rope or somethin'.
That's impossible!
That window is barely big enough for a child to crawl through.
What?!
Hold on!
Wasn't the door locked from the inside, and we had to break it down to get in?
If that's the case, and no one can
escape from that window either...
Does that mean... this is a locked room murder?
It's the Spider Demon Lady.
The spider demon lady climbed the shed with her claws, came in through the window, and strangled Nobukazu.
To teach a lesson to Nobukazu for building a shed here of all places.
Frightening, frightening.
If you detectives keep on saying that this is a murder,
then you'll be cursed by her as well.
What's this spider demon?
It's an old story that's been passed from generation to generation around here.
Long ago, there lived an angel-like beautiful woman here.
She stopped travelers that walked by the ridge, and gave them riddles.
Do you think that there is a heaven?
Would you like to go there?
The travelers, entranced by her beauty, used to answer yes.
And then they were taken deep into the forest, never to appear again.
A puppet maker heard this rumor.
He prepared a life size puppet, left it on the pathway, and watched from a distance.
As expected, the woman appeared and gave a riddle.
But the puppet did not answer.
The woman got angry and revealed her true form of a giant spider, and attacked the puppet.
Seeing this, the puppet maker shot it with flaming arrows.
The giant spider, engulfed in flames, ran into the forest.
And the puppet maker chased after it, only to find...
Since then, the villagers, fearing the curse of the spider demon
built a temple at its nest,
and began to revere it as the Spider Demon Lady and named this place, the Puppet Ridge.
Oh, it's just a fictional story.
Why do we have to be cursed by it?
The place where they built the temple,
is where this shed is standing right now.
Ya broke the temple?
Yeah.
My brother, who followed father into becoming a
puppet maker, did it against all the villagers' wishes.
Come to think of it,
the cemetery where Robert went was the same place where the spider lady was said to appear.
It can't be!
It was a good thing I gave Ran the cell phone after all!
Hey, uncle!
Lend me your cell phone!
Hey, uncle.
Here.
The cell phone you lent me.
Where are you gonna call?
Kazuha! K-K-Kazuha!
Oh, you're back already...
What's up? You're breathing hard.
When I told them that you guys
went to the place with a shady history...
They turned pale and ran out after you.
Oh, were ya worried 'bout us?
Idiot, it's nothin' like that.
It started to rain suddenly.
So we decided to come back early.
This area gets a lot of landslides, you know.
Hey, honey.
What's up with all the noise?
Oh, you see...
What?!
Nobukazu-san passed away?
In that storehouse's 2nd floor, once again?
Is this true, dear?
Yeah,
locked the door from the inside.
And what happened to the police?
Miyuki-san is calling.
It's terrible!
A landslide occurred on the way here.
They won't be able to get here until tomorrow.
What?!
Guess we got no choice.
Robert-han,
may we borrow yer camera?
Sure.
What are ya goin' to do with his camera?
Isn't it obvious?
We're goin' to do all the investigation ourselves.
We can't wait until the night passes by.
Huh, that's weird...
What's wrong?
My phone strap with the little mascot on it is gone.
I'm sure it was still there when I got in the car...
Maybe it's still in the car?
Guess we'll have to go find it tomorrow.
Do ya want to go search for it right now?
Yuuzou-san left the car keys that he had lent to Robert.
And I got a penlight.
But dad said not to step out of the room earlier.
It won't matter if it's just for a little while.
Well? Did ya find it?
No, it doesn't look like it's here.
I probably dropped it in the mountains.
This is the worst.
Maybe it was when ya got in the car.
Remember, ya dropped yer pouch there.
That's probably when.
Was that mascot really that precious?
Yeah...
It was Kudo-kun, wasn't it?
The one who bought it for ya?
Don't try to hide it,
it's written all over yer face.
It was around here wasn't, it?
The place where Robert parked the car.
And where we ran over to.
Yeah,
then we were called by Ryuji-san.
And when I turned around, I dropped my pouch.
Oh no, the batteries are about to run out!
I have some spare batteries in my CD player. Let me grab them!
She's really a good girl.
Man, leavin' a good girl like that.
Where in the world is Kudo...
What's this... a white marble?
Hey!
Look at this!
On the back of the head, there are some marks of being struck by something.
What?!
So...
The culprit hit him, then...
Yes.
The estimated time of death was 'round 9:00 PM.
That's around the time when
Nobukazu-san left the living room.
At that time, he had probably already been called by the culprit.
Then, the culprit, who met with Nobukazu-san,
killed him, and hung him from the ceiling.
That's right.
He then wrapped his body with lots of strings,
to make it seem as though the
spider demon had gotten to him.
Sorry!
Kazuha-chan, I found it!
The mascot we were looking for...
It was stuck under the CD player's lid...
Kazuha-chan, where are you?
Kazuha-chan's penlight...
Kazuha-chan...
Kazuha-chan.
Ah...
So you were acquainted with Takeda Misa-san, who died three years ago?
Yes.
We were nurses at the same hospital.
But I felt that line of work was too tiring, so I quit...
Misa told me about this place and got me to work as a maid.
Thank you very much.
Misa was really a wonderful girl.
She had a great personality and had a kind heart.
But why?
Why would she think of committin' suicide then?
Maybe its because of that incident.
Misa's father, Nobukazu-san...
For some reason after coming home from the hospital,
he grabbed hold of his wife, Kinuyo-san, and started yelling at her furiously,
you lied to me for the past twenty years!
What did she lie about?
I don't know.
I don't know the full story.
But because of that incident, Misa suffered a huge injury.
Injury?
Yes.
At that time, Misa tried to stop the fight.
But got knocked down by Nobukazu-san.
Her head hit the pillar, and she had to get seven stitches on her forehead.
Ever since then, Misa became depressed.
She even stopped going to the hospital.
Until she met Robert.
Robert?
Yes.
There was a huge landslide three years ago.
Misa coincidentally met him on that day.
When he was filming, he accidentally got caught in the landslide and suffered serious injuries.
It was difficult at first.
The landslide had injured his
mouth so he couldn't even talk.
Even though Robert could speak Japanese,
he couldn't write the script.
His conversations with Misa were only by writing Japanese using Roman letters.
But when Robert could finally talk,
they seemed to be enjoying each other.
They told all sorts of jokes...
He would say, Japanese foods are delicious...
especially the earth and sand on rainy days are the best!
Or I'm a prince of some country,
who has come here to find a bride who shines like light!
After his wounds had healed and he was about to go on his way,
Ryuji-san and his family were home,
and he became friends with them as well.
Misa's personality began to cheer up again.
If that's the case, I'm gettin' more and more confused.
It was two or three days after Robert left...
When Misa-san committed suicide.
Although I'm not very sure,
but when Robert left...
Misa went back to her old way again.
Then one day, I realized she was missing.
I thought she had left home.
But Yuuzo-san found Misa hung to death in the storage room.
Then, a few days later...
Her mother, Kinuyo-san,
followed her down the same path.
After these two people died,
was there any suspicious activity?
Come to think of it...
Nobukazu-san didn't even shed a tear at the funeral.
But, Ryuji-san was the exact opposite.
His crying could even be heard by the neighbors.
Oh right...
Can the string and ropes used to hang Nobukazu-san
be found in this storehouse?
Yes.
There is a lot of the string used to control the puppets in that room.
The rope should be in the shed, but...
Would you like to take a look?
The ropes would be...
Who's there?!
Ran?!
What did ya say?!
Kazuha is missing?!
Is that true?!
The only thing left behind was her penlight.
And when I thought she may have been kidnapped I panicked, and...
Anyway, let's split up and search for her!
Kazuha!
Where are you?
Kazuha-chan!
What's wrong, Hattori?
The door to the warehouse...
I closed it, but now, it's open!
This... This is...
Ka...
KAZUHA!
Kazuha!
Hey, get a hold of yerself, Kazuha!
Heiji...
Kazuha...
What happened to me...?
I remember waitin' for Ran-chan in front of the warehouse door.
Then I suddenly fainted...
Be quiet! I'll cut you loose right now!
K-Kazuha-chan!
Don't worry.
She was only held up by the strings.
Sorry!
Sorry, Kazuha-chan.
I didn't search for you carefully, and I got you into this terrible situation...
It's all because of me.
What about the mascot?
Sorry.
I found it.
It was stuck under the CD player's lid.
I'm really sorry.
If I had looked for it more carefully...
It's good that ya found it.
Don't lose it anymore.
What?
That girl from Osaka was attacked?
Who could have...
How should I know?
Kazuha is in her room resting right now.
But maybe she will remember soon.
Yuuzo-san is missing.
Oh, me?
I was here in the workroom the whole time.
You know how to make puppets as well?
Three years ago, my company went bankrupt...
And when I came back home, my
brother taught me how to make them.
The simpler tasks such as installing the parts I can do by myself.
Three years ago would mean at the time of the incident?
Yeah.
It's the exact same time period when Robert left.
However, my brother wouldn't let me do any of his minor repairs.
For the puppets he made, each
one would sell for a million yen.
And he would charge seven hundred thousand yen for repair fees alone.
One million yen for a puppet and seven hundred thousand yen for repairs?!
People actually buy these?
Yes.
Some people even bring it back
for repairs more than ten times.
The simple string-controlled puppets would be sold for even higher prices.
The profits allowed my brother and
Negishi-san to travel outside of the country.
Ever since having Negishi-san sell these puppets,
these puppets have gone for very high prices.
Hey, what is that oversized puppet over there?
That's the string-controlled spider demon puppet.
When my father was still alive,
he'd take this spider demon puppet out and put on a puppet show.
And it was a sacrificial offering in the village.
Such a huge puppet is very difficult to operate,
and so less and less people used it.
Then, what are those boxes over there for?
Oh, those are the dolls that Negishi-san,
was supposed to take with him the other day.
After Negishi-san died,
my brother discovered that one of the puppets was missing.
The anxious client even made a call to our home.
So, he quickly made another one.
Anyway, please go wait in the room that everyone is gathered in.
Staying here alone is dangerous.
Alright...
This is a good time.
The repair costs for these puppets are ridiculously expensive.
Even then, there are some clients who need it repaired more than ten times.
And the less complex the dolls were, the higher it was sold for.
I'm afraid what's inside would have to be...
Drugs.
And as for the complex mechanical puppets...
Only the head portion would be able to contain the drugs, hence the cheaper price.
If that's the case...
It could explain why Nobukazu-san,
secretly hired a detective to find the culprit.
Sae?
Emi?
What's the matter?
I brought my two daughters to the restroom, and now they've disappeared.
What?
Mama!
Oh my gosh, you guys worried me to death!
Didn't we already agree to wait outside the restroom?
But, we smelled something weird!
I smell it! What a weird smell!
There really is something weird burnin' inside!
What was the incident you two were talking about before?
You said it, didn't you? You called Robert a murderer.
The day Robert was leaving...
Misa-neechan wanted us to go ask Robert what he thought of her.
So we went to the bus stop.
We asked him,
How do you feel about Misa-neechan?
But, Robert wrote a terrible thing down on paper!
Right!
Something terrible?
He wrote Die!
Die?
It's horrible, right?
Horrible, horrible!
Don't mind what they said.
They must have read it wrong.
I shouldn't have let them see that business card.
Business card?
Let's see... I should have it here...
Here, this is it!
After they found this in my purse,
they started to make a fuss about it.
Hey! Look at this.
I finally got it out.
This is...
Could it be...
Isn't this a stun gun?!
Kazuha!
Heiji! I'm much better now.
Take off yer clothes for a second.
Stop stallin' and let me take a look!
What are ya doing?!
Hey, Conan-kun!
Why am I the only one who got slapped?
Because I'm just a kid.
You were right.
There is indeed a small burn mark on her back.
Just as I suspected, Kazuha
was shocked with the stun gun!
And then?
Did she say anythin' else?
She said that she didn't see the culprit,
but she did find a weird marble in front of the storehouse.
Marble?
She said it was about this small.
BB pellets!
I get it now!
The culprit used that method.
If that's the case...
That can definitely be...
Found in this room!
It must be here.
Got it!
I found it, Hattori!
These are marks left by tacks.
I've found it here as well.
A strange string with loops on the beam ends!
Just like we suspected from the very beginning.
Yup.
There's no mistake,
that person is the culprit!
What, he knows who the culprit is?!
R-Really you mean Mouri-san said that?
Yeah.
He told everyone to go up to the second
floor of the storehouse and gather there.
Oh,
and he said to bring that huge
puppet at the workroom as well.
Well now, everyone has come.
Then lets begin revealing,
the truth behind the numerous incidents that occurred in the Takeda family.
W-Wait a moment, Mouri-san.
I don't think that it's the curse,
but if you say there is a culprit, then could you first explain,
the way he managed to escape from this room?
Ha, if there really is a way to do that,
I would love to see it.
Correct.
The culprit had no need to escape from this room.
When he murdered Nobukazu-san,
he wasn't in this room to begin with.
T-That can't be!
Then, how did he do it?
It's the thread you use for the puppets.
The murderer used threads, a rope,
and a few thumbtacks to turn this into...
A locked room murder!
See,
just like this.
Little boy?
Now, all one has to do is to bring Nobukazu-san here,
and make him look outside the window.
Then pull the string from the outside.
And one can kill him.
Then why did my brother lock
the door at the meeting place?
B-Besides,
if you heard from the person
you're supposed to meet to look outside the window,
then I believe almost anyone would feel an uncertainty...
The reason he locked the door...
Was because he had important matters
that he did not want anyone else to find out.
The reason he looked outside,
was probably because he heard a sound.
A sound?
Yes. The culprit used a BB gun and shot
beads up on the window from the outside...
So that Nobukazu-san would look out the window.
It was to avenge Misa-san, who committed suicide in this storehouse three years ago!
The culprit probably thought...
That Nobukazu-san, having found out
that Misa-san wasn't his real daughter...
Went hard on her, and forced her to commit suicide!
N-Not his real daughter?!
W-What does that mean?!
Isn't that right? Ryuiji-san?
Dear?
I'm sorry.
Yoko.
I knew that I had to tell you this someday.
That Misa is...
The daughter that was made between my brother's wife,
Kinuyo-san and I.
That can't... You're lying...
Dear?
It's true.
It was before I met you.
Kinuyo-san learned at the hospital that
my brother could never have children,
and she came begging to me with tears.
Please make his dream come true... He really wants a child.
That was the first and last time.
And since both my brother and I had the same blood type...
He wouldn't have found out.
But three years ago,
the doctor at the hospital let it slip from his mouth...
Because of that, Misa committed suicide,
and Kinuyo-san felt the guilt and followed her.
It's all...
It's all because I accepted her request!
Dear...
But, how did you know that Misa was my daughter?
Kinuyo-san and I didn't tell anyone.
It was the names.
Misa-san's name, and your...
and Yoko-san's daughters, Sae-chan and Emi-chan's names, come back in a circle.
When I realized that, I understood everything.
But, my mother named all of my daughters...
I knew it all along!
I named the three to form a circle for you.
Don't underestimate the elderly!
When Kinuyo-san brought home the baby from the hospital, all I had to do was
look at how you two were acting, and I could see exactly what happened.
But, I didn't think you would hate Nobukazu enough for my granddaughter's sake
that you would take revenge upon her.
That's wrong, mother.
I didn't kill my brother.
Ryuji-san isn't the culprit.
I said it before, didn't I?
The culprit used an air-gun to hit the window,
and pulled the thread when
Nobukazu-san looked out the window,
killing him.
Even though it made it a locked room,
if someone saw him doing such a suspicious act in the yard,
he would become the suspect almost immediately.
But the victim would have struggled quite a bit.
If one was to do this with human strength,
then the chance of failure is extremely high.
If one wishes to succeed in this attempt...
He will need the strength to pull all four thumbtacks out at the same time.
During that time, there was only one person,
That could have done that without being suspected.
Only you could have done that!
During that time,
there was only one person that could have done that without being suspected.
Only you could have done that,
the one who used his car to go see the grave,
Robert-san!
You're the only one!
After dinner, when you went to the grave...
You stopped the car in front of the storehouse.
While you were waiting for
the arrival of Ran and Kazuha,
you had the chance to shoot with the BB gun at the window.
Then, taking the line you left hanging from the window.
As long as you tied it to your car before dinner...
All you had to do was to drive the car,
and you would be able to pull
the thread with enormous force.
Taking the cut line on the car with you,
and saying you wanted to stop and take a look at the view, while removing it.
Throwing them away together with the air-gun into the mountains.
Please wait a minute!
It's true that I was the one who drove the car...
But the one who tied the thread could have been another person.
Besides, I just happen to come back to this house after three years.
I even got lost on the road trying to find the house.
No,
It hasn't been three years since you've come back here.
It was just a few days ago.
That's right.
The day you killed Negishi-san and set up this trap.
W-What?!
That's why he killed Negishi-san inside the house.
Avoiding the trap in this room.
He called the high school detective from Osaka with a strange letter...
And then waited for them on the road.
It was done to emphasize that you
haven't returned for three whole years.
But, why Negishi-san?
Oh, I still have trouble understanding that, but...
At that time, Robert probably found out about the drugs,
and the suicide of Misa-san.
D-Drugs?
Yeah, Nobukazu-san partnered with Negishi-san,
and stuffed the dolls with drugs.
And sold it for large sums of money.
Our brother was dealing drugs?!
Then, after Robert killed Negishi-san.
He took what Negishi-san was supposed to take with him, one of the dolls,
and made an arrangement to meet with Nobukazu-san
to meet with him in this room.
You probably said, If you're interested in drugs...
then I've got some good stuff here,
so would you like to make a deal with me?
Stop joking around, saying
things without any evidence!
And besides, you're forgetting something important!
Please explain it properly.
Explain the mystery behind...
The reason that Nobukazu-san died surrounded by threads!
Was he really?
Huh? Yeah...
Right, right.
Until you just mentioned it, I had completely forgotten about it.
The threads that were tangled upon Nobukazu-san.
But that's all set up too...
Right, Conan?
Yeah, you all probably didn't notice because it was dark...
But the strings are glued on across.
Right above us.
Proof is worth more than words. Let's try it out!
Now then, Yuuzou-san.
Please place the doll you brought in the window.
Yeah, just like Nobukazu-san looking outside the window.
Then, after checking that from the car,
Robert started the car.
When this is done, the thread
attached to the car will get pulled,
and the thumbtacks will come detached.
Then the rope will go around Nobukazu-san's neck,
and pull him in the opposite direction.
Nobukazu-san will hit the back of his head on the beam behind him.
If it was pulled further, the thread would snap,
and he would dive into the ocean of strings below.
As though he had been tangled in a spider web.
He will hang from the ceiling.
The problem that arose here is, Robert-san...
How did you know that Nobukazu-san was tangled in the strings?
Among all of you, the people that knew this was...
The ones that came here: Ryuji-san, Yuuzou-san, Chie-san, Miyuki-san.
Of course, to these four...
I pleaded to them not to say
anything about the murder scene.
And then, one more person.
Meaning that person would be...
The person who set this up so that
Nobukazu-san would end up like this.
The murderer himself is the only other that knows about it.
Robert?
How...
How did you know?
Isn't it weird?!
To tell them from the start not to talk,
about the scene and waiting
for me to slip my mouth!
The number of fish.
During supper time.
The ones that weren't expected was suppose to be me, Kazuha, and ya - three people.
The amount that was not enough was only two.
This means that ya were already
expected by someone in this house.
The reason that ya didn't kill Kazuha and hung her in the storehouse,
Was that the killer wanted to make it seem more like the curse, and...
To lead us into thinkin' that there must be some way to escape from this room.
Well, there's probably the fact that Kazuha found
the beads you shot up as well.
But, why Negishi-san too?
A few days ago.
When I first came back, that person told me.
Misa-chan committed suicide shortly after you left,
when she was told the truth about her father.
But there's nothing anyone could have done.
She wasn't their real daughter, so...
Well... a girl like that, no one
would want to marry her anyway.
And there probably wouldn't be any good
coming out of it, even if she was still alive.
With eyes that were consumed by drugs.
He was exposing things to me, laughing all the way.
To me, who studied Japanese like mad for her.
To me, who took three years to master the Japanese language.
And finally returned to see her.
To me, who hoped to see her
greet me with her gentle smile.
To me...
But, don't ya think ya overdid it when you did what you did to Kazuha?
I didn't care who got hurt!
Or blamed anymore.
Including the ones who watched her die, this entire family!
Listen carefully!
I didn't want to tell ya this, but I'll tell ya anyway!
When Misa-san was in an unstable state of mind...
When she was conversing with you in Roman-Japanese...
Don't do it, Hattori!
The real reason why she committed suicide was...
Maybe... just maybe!
SHINE?
Yes, that's right!
S-H-I-N-E spells Shine.
It means to be bright.
Maybe for Robert, Misa-san was like a bright light.
Light?
Oh yeah, Robert used to say,
That he wanted a bride that shines like light!
We have to apologize to Robert.
Apologize?
'Cause it was the same as in Negishi uncle's name!
So we thought he wrote a horrible thing to her...
Die (shi-ne)!
Morning came...
And Robert was moved to the Tottori Police Department.
In the police car...
Robert kept repeating the same words...
Over and over again.
Why wasn't I Japanese?
Why wasn't she American?
As though he was a broken puppet.
He repeated over and over again...