Apoptoxin 4869.
A poisonous drug used for assassinations, developed by the Organization I used to work with.
High school detective Shin'ichi Kudô took the drug,
and by an accidental use of its cellular selfdestruction program,
his body reversed to the state of a first-year primary school child
instead of dying.
And I too, in order to escape from the Organization, chose the same.
Now we're primary school students, and the Organization still doesn't know.
If we were to be found out, then not just us,
but everyone associated with us would also be killed.
Our first crisis... came that day without any warning whatsoever.
A desperate crisis...
A magnificent revival turns the case's solution around!
Another meeting with the men in black.
What fate awaits the cornered Haibara?
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Hey, did you watch yesterday's match?
Wasn't it awesome?
Yeah. You mean Hide's overhead kick, right?
The time for games is over.
Now, wake up from your dream and celebrate our reunion!
In pure red blood, like the color of your favorite rose.
Eh...? Sherry!
Haibara-san!
Here's the game I borrowed from you.
Please tell the doctor that it was even better than we hoped.
Sure, I'll tell him.
The boss character was a bit lame, though.
But it was still better than the one in the previous game.
Oh! Look, look!
Look, snow's falling! Snow!
Really?!
Snow...
Let's celebrate our reunion!
In pure red blood, like the color of your favorite rose.
Eh...? Sherry!
Hey, come look out of the window at the snow with us, Haibara-san.
Don't touch me!
Haibara-san?
Is something wrong?
I'm tired of this place already.
I wish I could just disappear.
Well, one of these days, I probably will.
Haibara-san, are you transferring to another school?
Could it be that someone's bullying you?
I'll take care of that guy!
So please don't say you're leaving us!
I was just joking! Don't take me so seriously.
I've got a bit of a cold, so I'm in just a bad mood. Don't worry about it.
"I shouldn't be in this place."
"To avoid getting these kids involved,"
"I have to disappear from this place as soon as possible."
That's the kind of nonsense you're thinking right now, right?
Don't worry.
The idea that someone would shrink from a drug is just absurd. Nobody would believe it.
Or even think about it.
So long as you keep acting as a child, you can stay under cover.
Until the time comes.
Kudo-kun, you still don't know a thing.
You can't handle something like them by yourself.
Once you let your guard down, it's all over. The Organization won't let us get away.
Right. Maybe, just like in my dream,
Even now, somewhere in this city,
they're watching us...
What? Is there something wrong with that black Porsche?
A Porsche 356A.
A 50-years old classic car.
The driver doesn't seem to be in it.
Gin...
Gin's favorite car is one of these.
Gin's, you say?!
Hey!
Did you bring them with you?!
Hmm? Yeah. A metal clothes hanger and a wrench.
What do you need them for?
Wait!
To open an old car, all you have to do is this...
Kudo-kun?
What are you planning to do?
I'm planting a transmitter and receiver inside the car.
But we're not even sure this is their car!
Gin! Vodka!
The snow's unusually tattered around the car.
Some civilians probably came and looked at it.
Your car is quite rare nowadays, Bro.
"The German Rainfrog."
It sure became famous.
Bingo.
I never thought I'd find them here.
I'm glad I did, Gin!
Yeah, it's me.
How are things on your side?
What? He still hasn't shown up?
Don't worry.
The target's sure to show his face at the Haido City Hotel, at 6 PM.
He has no idea it'll be his own farewell party.
Target? Farewell party?
Either way, our superior ordered us to kill him before he rats us out.
Feel free to use that drug if you want.
Drug?
Don't mess it up, Pisco.
Pisco?
A reddish brown hair?
Bro, what's wrong?
What's that?
It's probably a transmitter and receiver.
Oh no, they found it!
What?
I never thought you'd be the one to approach me first.
I welcome you, Sherry!
Geez... I thought you had no interest in things like this.
I can't help it. I'm the one who made that drug.
I just don't want you to call me a murderer anymore.
Be careful.
If they happen to suspect that the one who planted those devices would come here...
And if they find out you're here...
It's all right.
Didn't you already erase all the evidence in the car?
They'll think it's either a prank, or that someone who's against the Organization did it.
More importantly, are you sure this is their meeting place?
Yeah.
Gin said it's a farewell party.
Pisco and his target should both be here by now.
Damn. It's a mourning party, so lots of people are wearing black.
Everybody's starting to look suspicious.
Sherry...
Sherry!
What's wrong, little girl? Did you get separated from your parents?
Yeah. We're looking for them now.
Let's go, Hana-chan.
What's wrong with you? This isn't like you.
Weren't you the one who chose to come along?
I had a nightmare...
A nightmare?
On my way home, Gin saw me.
He chased me into an alleyway...
And you were the first one he shot.
And with each reload of his gun, everybody else...
Yeah, just because they were involved with me...
Maybe if the Organisation'd killed me back there,
we wouldn't have as much hassle.
Did you know? Nobody'll ever discover your identity if you wear those.
Even Clark Kent would be surprised.
Oh? Then, having taken off the glasses, does that make you Superman?
Well, I can't fly.
This is a famous director's mourning party, all right.
There are lots of well-known faces.
Well, then? Did you figure out who Pisco's target is?
Yeah.
Gin mentioned on the phone that the target would arrive at 6 PM,
and that he might be arrested by the police tomorrow,
so it can only be that man in the entrance, who's surrounded by reporters.
I see.
Shigehiko Nomiguchi (56)
Lawyer
So he's the lawyer
who the papers all say is taking bribes.
Please answer more clearly.
Excuse me.
Inspector Megure?
I gave him a phone call from the toilet.
I told him someone wants to murder that lawyer here.
Well then, everyone.
Naomichi Mugikura (43)
Announcer
Allow me to present you with a slide-show
of Director Sakamaki's memories.
Now, everyone, do any of you know when and where this photo was taken?
Wait. That lawyer's gone already.
What?!
Hey, hurry up and find him.
Yes, sir.
Yes. This is the work that made Director Sakamaki famous.
The place where he filmed "The Rainbow Handkerchief."
How is it?
We still haven't found him.
Look more carefully!
Yes.
Now let's look at the next photo.
Oh? This looks like the studio cafeteria's staff.
Ok, let's move on to the next slide.
A flash?
No matter how precious this photo is, you wouldn't be able to see it if you used a flash.
What?
What?!
What was that sound just now?!
Hey, what's wrong?
What was that sound?
Hurry up and turn on the lights!
What in the world is going on?
A handkerchief?
I see.
So you were the ones closest to Mr. Nomiguchi when the chandelier fell?
Yes.
Did you see anyone suspicious at the time?
Yoshiharu Tawara (58)
University Professor
We didn't have time for that.
I was almost crushed, too!
Chris Vineyard (29)
Actress
I never saw any suspicious characters.
I see.
Inspector, she says she didn't see anyone of the sort, either.
It was an accident, an accident!
Naoya Tarumi (35)
Music Producer
The chandelier's chains were weak and broke.
The lawyer just happened to be under it.
But there was a message saying there'd be a murder tonight, right?
What are you going to do about that?
Kenzō Masuyama (71)
President of a car factory
I'd like to know more about the sender.
The voice was altered by a machine, so we don't even know if it was a man or a woman.
Then it was probably a prank.
Naomichi Mugikura (43)
Announcer
Mr. Nomiguchi was weakened by his medical condition.
Right, right.
The accident just happened to overlap with the prank.
Yasuo Mihei (62)
Owner of a pro baseball team
The heavens smited him.
You can't do bad things, eh?
How can you eat at a time like this?
An insignificant lad like yourself should keep his mouth shut.
Hey! Someone call the chef!
What's wrong? Was there a cockroach in it or something?
You're eating at a time like this,
so the heavens smited you too.
What did you say?!
This is... a piece of the chandelier's chain?
Why was it in a place like this?
Mika Nanjō (38)
Authoress
Anyway...
Mr. Nomiguchi died when he was crushed
by the falling chandelier, right?
To murder someone that way, you'd have to set a trap on the chandelier,
lure him underneath it when the lights were turned off,
and then activate the trap, right?
Yet, looking at the fallen chandelier or the ceiling it hung from,
I can see no such thing.
Therefore, murder is impossible.
Now that you understand, could you release us already?
It's true.
Dropping a chandelier on a targeted individual without some sort of trap would be impossible.
Hey, where are we going?
We're going to run away.
Staying here and wasting time is too dangerous.
You only have one clue: The piece of chain you picked up earlier.
Not even you could figure out who the criminal is from just that.
What if I have two?
It fell after the chandelier, but before the lights were turned back on.
This handkerchief.
What about it?
It's not like it has the criminal's name written on it.
Look at its corner.
It says "Director Sakamaki's Mourning Party," right?
Its owner probably received it at the front door.
Just look around at the guests.
See, that man holding the glasses,
the overweight woman next to him,
and the elderly man with the mustache in the back,
they all have this handkerchief, but in different colors.
What are you saying?
Likely, due to Director Sakamaki's number one hit,
"The Rainbow Handkerchief," handkerchiefs in 7 different colors were given to the guests.
In other words, if we ask at the front desk,
we can reduce the number of suspects to those that received a purple handkerchief.
Hey, officer!
We can go to the toilet, right?
Sure.
What's wrong with you all?
Did Mr. Nomiguchi really pass away?
We heard it was an accident.
How about it?
We'll explain it later, so please everyone, back away.
Wait! Please answer us!
The people we gave purple handkerchiefs to?
Yeah! I picked one up, so I want to return it to him.
I got it, little boy.
The guests who were given purple handkerchiefs are these seven.
Here.
Thank you.
I see. So it was one of those seven.
I'm not certain, but it's likely that among those seven,
is one of them, Pisco.
Hey, they're coming out!
Damn. Let's go back to the doc's car for a bit.
Haibara.
Hey, Haibara?
Where are you? Answer me!
Wai—
Hey, where are you?
Answer me!
Haibara!
Kudo-kun...?
Haibara? Is that you, Haibara?
Where...?
I'm in the doc's car in front of the hotel.
I'm speaking to you through the microphone and speaker in the glasses.
What happened to me?
That's what I want to know! What happened in the hallway, in front of the party room?
In front of the party room?
Oh, back then I got engulfed by a wave of people,
and got separated from you.
Then someone came from behind me and...
Someone came from behind you and...?
Somebody made me sniff some drug,
and now I'm being confined in some wine storage room.
Hey... By "somebody," you mean...?
Yeah. Likely the Organization member who managed to commit murder in front of the police.
Pisco.
What?!
He's not there, is he? Is he nearby?
No. Whoever he is, he's not here now.
But the door is locked tightly.
The only thing around is a large cardboard box and cart for carrying goods
and some employee overalls.
Overalls?
Yeah.
Yeah. Likely, after making me sniff the drug, he must have taken me to the toilet or something,
changed into these previously prepared overalls, then stuffed me in the box and brought me here.
It was probably ready in case the attempt on that lawyer's life failed.
He'd have lured the lawyer to the toilet and killed him, then brought him here.
Whatever. Just hurry and find a way out of there, and find our next move.
Are you ready, Kudo-kun? Listen carefully.
The Apoptoxin 4869 that shrunk our body's apopto uses apoptosis.
In other words, programmed cell destruction.
Hey, Haibara...
However, this drug doesn't just activate apoptosis.
It also includes Telomerase, and increases a cell's reproductive ability.
Stop it, Haibara! I'll listen to as much as you want about that once you get out of there!
Shut up and listen!
I'll never... never be able to exchange words with you ever again.
What?
Don't you get it?
They held me here despite being in my shrunken figure.
Even if I were to escape from here, they'd find me in no more than two days.
If that happens, the doctor who protected me, and all others who were involved with me
would be killed to preserve their secrecy.
You get it?
No matter if I die here or if I escape,
I've already been forced into a state where I can no longer come into contact with any of you.
Haibara...
Therefore, I'm going to tell you all I know about the drug, as long as I'm here.
Tadah! Dr. Agasa's Great Adventure II!
Hey... what was that just now?
Oh, it's the doctor's game that Tsuburaya-kun returned to me at school.
They were probably checking the M.O. in my pocket.
There's a cell phone attached to the laptop, which means...
I knew it.
They were analyzing my face.
Hey, you aren't tied down?
That's why I'm in such a hurry.
They won't leave me for long without tying me down.
No, he won't be able to come back for a while.
After you disappeared, I called the inspector right away
and told him to not let the guests with purple handkerchiefs leave the Haido City Hotel
with Shin'ichi Kudo's voice.
Then this place is still somewhere in the Haido City Hotel?
Yeah, probably.
If I can prove the murder before he contacts his companions, and bring him to the police,
then your secret will remain intact.
At best, the inspector can hold those seven for another hour or so.
Anyway, I'm going to the hotel's front desk
to ask them if there's any unfrequently used wine storage room in the hotel,
and I'll go and save you.
Idiot.
I told you what'd happen to those involved with me.
Don't blame me for what happens to people who chose to help me.
Then find some way to get out of there by yourself.
That's really easy to say and all,
but there's no escape route in this room!
The only thing here is an old chimney.
Can you climb up that chimney?
No, it's too big to climb up.
If I wasn't in this body, it looks like I could barely manage it by stretching my arms and legs.
Isn't there some sort of rope?
Not sure. Do they keep ropes in a wine storage room?
If it's a wine storage room, does it mean it has a wide variety of alcoholic drinks?
Is there baigar there?
Baigar?
Yeah. It's a strong liquor from China.
I know that, but...
Just look around for it.
Let's see if there's some.
But what do you want that for?
How's your cold?
You said you had a cold in the morning, right?
Your topic seems to jump all over the place.
Whatever, just tell me how you're doing.
After my sleeping on the floor, I think my fever went up.
I see.
Oh?
You sound quite happy about it.
Yeah.
I found the baigar.
But what am I supposed to do with this liquor?
I'm going to get you out of that room.
By casting the ultimate magic spell on you.
Lupin III vs...
...Detective Conan!
On March 27th at 9 PM.
This part was brought to you by these sponsors.
This was the scene inside the hotel, right after the accident.
Even now, many people are still being questioned in a nearby room.
However, those individuals' names have yet to be released.
That is all. This is being broadcast live from the scene.
From that news report, I figured out the rough location of the seven right after the murder.
But this alone...
Hey, how do you spell "Hercule Poirot?"
What the heck are you doing? Did you drink the baigar already?
Yeah, I did.
I don't know what you're planning, but I feel even worse now.
Either way, tell me how to spell Poirot's name.
What do you want to know that for?
I wanted to transfer the drug's data from the Organization's computer to the doctor's M.O.,
but I got stuck on the password.
...R-O-T.
It's no good. It's not Poirot.
Why did you think the password might be "Poirot?"
The people in the Organization called the drug by a name during its prototype phase,
They gave it the serial number 4869/shiyaroku after Sherlock.
They called it "the incomplete Great Detective."
So I've been trying the names of Great Detectives as they popped into my head.
But I guess it's not going to be that easy.
"Shelling Ford."
The spelling is "S-H-E-L-L-I-N-G F-O-R-D."
Does such a detective even exist?
Just try it and see.
S-H-E-L-L-I-N-G F-O-R-D.
It opened! How come?
"Shelling Ford" was...
...a temporary name that Conan Doyle gave to his detective before naming him Sherlock.
In other words, it's the prototype of the Great Detective.
That's kind of clever for the Organization.
Anyway, we're running out of time.
Doesn't your body feel odd?
How could it not, after you had me down liquor like that?
Either way, I'll drop the drug's data on this M.O. and hide it in this wine storage room.
You can come and get it after the Organization takes me away.
Hey!
Shi... Shin'ichi! Look!
It's them. Could Pisco have gotten through to them?
No, that can't be! The Inspector said he'd call me before releasing those seven!
No way!
Could there be a tracer in the PC Haibara's using?
I get it. They called him and there was no answer, so they used the tracer to get here!
Haibara, this is bad!
They're coming! For now, go hide in the chimney or something!
Hey, what's wrong?
Hey!
Pisco's not here.
He was supposed to contact us 30 minutes after finishing off the target, but he didn't.
So we came here thanks to the tracer, and the laptop's here, but not him.
Just where'd he disappear to?
And what's the deal with this wine storage room?
Pisco probably prepared this room just in case.
If he'd failed in the party room, he'd probably kill him elsewhere, and bring him here afterwards.
Either way, we shouldn't stick around too long, Bro.
I suppose.
Hey, did they leave?
Yeah.
And uh... your clothes?
Pervert.
I'm wearing the overalls that were left in the room.
Of course, I have the M.O. with the copy of the drug's data, too.
But I'm surprised. That baigar liquor...
I wonder if it has some enzyme that speeds up cellular metabolism or something.
Don't get too relieved, it's only temporary.
Get out of that chimney before you turn back into a child.
Got it.
By the way, have you figured out who Pisco is?
No, not yet.
There isn't enough information.
Look at this, Shin'ichi. Tomorrow's news photo is on the Internet.
They say a cameraman in the room took it right before the incident.
Wait! Maybe...
A burn mark...
That means this chain...
I see.
That's how it was...
Haido City Hotel, Old Building
I missed you... Sherry!
I'm surprised you knew I'd be coming out of this chimney.
It was this hair.
I found this reddish-brown hair of yours near the chimney.
I could have killed you inside that dirty chimney,
but I thought I could at least let your death flower bloom.
Oh my. I guess I should thank you.
For waiting for me in this cold.
I'll ask you while those lips still move.
How did you disappear from the Organization's gas room?
Eh? A wine storage room?
Yeah. I think it has a big chimney in it.
Do we even have a room like that in this hotel?
Maybe it's in the old building that's going to be rebuilt?
Old building?
Yeah. I heard they were using a room somewhere as a temporary storage room.
Storage... that's it!
What?! Haibara was shot?!
Yeah, on a roof somewhere. Hurry and g—
Hey, doc! Doc!
Damn, the battery must've died.
Haibara!
Bro, this girl's not gonna talk.
I guess there's nothing we can do.
Let's send her to meet her sister, whom we sent first.
A needle?
Bro!
The chimney!
Get into the chimney!
Who the hell are you?!
Hurry!
Bro? What's wrong, Bro?
Oh, amazing!
You were still a baby, so you probably don't remember anymore,
but I was very close to your parents, who were scientists.
I was told a lot about the drug during development.
Who...
But I had no clue that you managed to take it to this point.
Your parents, who died in that accident, would've been very happy.
Who are you?
But this is an order, so don't blame me,
Shiho-chan.
Hold it right there!
Masuyama-san.
Or should I call you Pisco?
Who... Who are you?!
You might think you skillfully dropped the chandelier on Mr. Nomiguchi's head to make it look accidental,
but things never go that smoothly.
You dropped it, right?
With a silencer-equipped handgun.
Your target was the fluorescent substance you painted on beforehand.
Once the lights go out in the room from the slideshow, that light will shine through.
Of course, if you'd fired at it directly, there'd be a spark from your gun,
which would be noticed by the people around you.
But if you cover the silencer with a handkerchief,
the handkerchief will fly off with the bullet and hide the spark.
The reason you used the handkerchief from Director Sakamaki's mourning party
was because it'd be hard to trace even if it was found later on.
But of the guests who received that purple handkerchief, most went home already.
And so the suspects became just those seven.
Tawara-san and Chris-san, being directly under the chandelier with no way to aim, are clear.
Mihei-san, who spat out the chain piece that became evidence from his mouth,
and Mugikura-san, who'd been watched by the guests on-stage, didn't do it either.
Tarumi-san and Nanjō-san, who were embracing each other right before the incident, are also clear.
In other words, the only one that could have committed this crime was you, Masuyama-san!
Over there!
And the reason Mr. Nomiguchi went under the chandelier
was because you put fluorescent material on the floor there, too.
You probably told him you could give him a chance to avoid being arrested,
and to wait for you at the glowing place once the light faded.
Isn't that right, Pisco-san?
A speaker?
Who... Who are you?!
Just what are you?!
Conan Edogawa, detective.
De... Detective?
Could it be that you were the one giving out orders to the police during their investigation?
You and the two above will be caught by the police sooner or later.
Before that, could you tell me?
Why did you have that purple handkerchief during the investigation?
That's why the Inspector had to release you.
Could that handkerchief have been...
There are things in this world that you don't need to know.
And look at the situation. You won't be able to call the police.
You should take a closer look.
At your feet.
Spirytus.
A strong wine, with 96% alcohol.
You know what happens if you smoke near that much alcohol, right?
A fire has erupted in room 404 of the old building.
I repeat, a fire has erupted in room 404 of the old building.
What?!
Let's go check it out!
Hey, brat, where are you?!
Come out, damn it!
Where are you?!
There you are.
What's the meaning of this, Gin?!
It seems you messed up, Pisco.
Why didn't you immediately kill that cameraman or got rid of the film?
Cameraman? What are you talking about?
Tomorrow's paper has been replaced by your photo.
It shows you holding your gun to the ceiling.
Don't do it! If you kill me, you'll never find Sherry!
I have a general idea of her whereabouts.
And if you kill me, who served that person for so many years, then your standing will...
Sorry.
This was a direct order from that person.
What?! Gin executed Pisco?!
Yeah. I was listening to the conversation through the glasses Ai-kun forgot in the chimney.
But I think he ran away through the chimney right after killing Pisco.
That's strange. How can he move after I shot him with the tranquilizer gun?
I thought a huge guy like him wouldn't be able to get away from the police, once put to sleep.
I'm also worried about how well they read Haibara's movements.
It seems like they knew she was going to the party.
Could they really tell it's her just from one strand of hair?
Hey, Haibara? When you were in the Organization, were you...
Well, did they find out?
That my body shrunk.
No, I don't think they know. Don't worry.
So, what are you planning to do now?
I don't know.
Now that they know that I'm in this city,
I can't stay with you guys any longer.
And the M.O. in those overalls is probably burnt up by now.
There's no reason for me to stay here anymore.
Don't worry. I'll leave first thing tomorrow.
Hey, hey, you can't do that with your body like that.
All right, then everything's fine.
You're not going to search this city for that woman?
Yeah. I'm a shōgun who doesn't do useless things.
She's probably long gone by now, with that man who came to save her.
She's not a stupid enough woman to stay in a city where we saw her face.
My, it looks like you're quite caught up with that girl.
Sorry, Vermouth.
We called a lady like you to help that old geezer,
and got you into such a mess.
Really, to think I even gave him that handkerchief before he went into questioning.
And he ended up dead.
But don't you wonder about the man with that girl?
Yeah, the man who is embraced by that woman.
I'd love to see his face.
Yeah. His dead face consumed by fear.
Are you going back to America?
No, I'm going to take a break from being an actress.
I plan to relax in Japan for a while. There's something I'm involved in.
So you watched until the end.
And there you go. Now you're one of the people who knows our secret.
In other words, if the Organization finds us, you'll be killed too.
That's why we have to be careful to not get caught.
So that you yourself can continue to live.
Don't worry. No matter what happens,
I will protect you all.