SOS.
It is widely known as a word for help.
Originally, it was a distress signal based on Morse code used on ships.
That SOS is no longer used now.
This time I'm descending in front of the detective-boys.
In a literal sense.
The rhythm of RIP is perfect for the rhythm of foot loose reasoning.
Today's stage is an ordinary apartment.
The incident lurks behind the door.
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
I wish I could find something interesting to do.
The world is full of cases to be solved, and yet...
It's strange that things are happening
everywhere but around us.
It's not strange, not strange at all.
It's just normal.
What's that?
It's a ring!
I wonder where it came flying from.
There wasn't anybody over here.
Maybe it was thrown out of a window in this building?
But...
I wonder why it's on something like this...
It's an S-shaped hook.
One fell here too.
Maybe that hook was also attached to the ring,
but came off when it hit the ground.
Wait a minute!
Hey, hey. Don't tell me...
Look!
Doesn't this look like a word?
SOS?!
Right.
The ring and the S-hooks are an SOS sign
that somebody is sending us!
I knew he was gonna say that.
If so, the one looking for help is a woman.
There's lipstick on the S-hook.
She's right! There's lipstick on it!
Hey, hey. You're getting carried away.
Mitsuhiko-kun, let me take a look at the ring.
This is a wedding ring!
Look... "M to A".
"March 21, 1999" is carved on it.
This means the ring was sent
from someone with the initial M
to someone with the initial A,
and they were married on March 21, 1999.
It's amazing that you could tell that, Ayumi.
My parents have rings carved the same way.
So this ring is the one the woman was wearing.
Her husband's initial is M, and hers is A.
Let me borrow it for a sec.
The size of this ring is about an 11.
Women usually take sizes 7 to 9,
so this woman must have unusually thick fingers.
There's no mistake about it.
The one who sent out an SOS
is somewhere on the first to ninth floor of this building,
and for some reason is unable to move!
Maybe it's an accident... Or...
Maybe she's locked up.
All the doors and windows are closed.
Which means either that she closed them right after dropping the ring
because she sensed danger,
or that the one confining her closed them, right?
We'll have to find that room in a hurry,
because she may be in danger!
Alright! This is a job for the Detective Boys!
Let's go!
Yeah!
What's the matter?
This building has an auto-locking door,
and it won't open.
Behind you.
Have a nice day.
Well, we're in. Now what?
Let's check the initials of the couples who live in the rooms facing the little window we just saw,
and the numbers of the rooms from the first to ninth floors.
But how?
There doesn't seem to be
a manager's office here either...
When we were on the street, we were facing the building from the west.
We just have to find which floors
have apartments that face west.
This way!
Yeah!
He's pretty good, isn't he?
There's nothing to be amazed of.
Tsutomu Otake-san...
His first initial is T, for Tsutomu.
It's not this apartment.
All the apartments above this one should end in 5.
Let's split up and check the nameplates.
Haibara-san and Ayumi-chan,
check the odd-numbered floors.
We'll go check the even-numbered floors.
You can count on us!
"Go-ju-kaze"...
That's a strange name.
It's not "Kaze", it's "Arashi".
It's read "Igarashi".
"Shima"...
We have no way of knowing
with just the last name.
"Shin'ichiro Koyama"...
His first initial is S...
It's not this apartment.
No...
Yay!
The names of the entire family are written!
Kosaku, Natsue and Yohei Horikoshi...
Too bad, no good again.
Their initials are K for Kosaku and N for Natsue.
And all their initials were displayed...
Akihiko and Misato Uehara...
A and M.
Yay! Isn't this it?
Genta-kun, we're looking for a husband with the initial M and a wife with the initial A.
This is the opposite!
I see...
Look here!
Michihiro Ishida...
The first initial is M.
We can't tell what the name of his wife is...
He may be living alone.
I see...
We've narrowed it down to five apartments.
Out of the five, four only had their last names listed outside.
Hey, maybe their names are written on the mailboxes outside.
Aha! Let's go check.
Good thinking, Ayumi!
Wait! Please stay here, Genta-kun.
If we all go out, we won't be able to get back in.
You're no fun.
205 and 305 have only the last names written, after all.
But 805 and 905...!
Yoshio and Eisuke...
Y and E. It's not them.
That leaves just three...
205 and 305...
I wonder if there's any way
we can check the names...
There is a way.
Where are you going?
Hey! Where're you guys going?!
Hey! Don't leave me here alone!
Here it is.
Beika Town, 4-11-10.
That's the address of this building.
The name is Toru Igarashi.
The initial is T, so it's not him.
Here it is.
Masakazu Shima...
His first initial is M.
Yay!
So the possibilities now are
Masakazu Shima-san in apartment 305
and Michihiro Ishida-san in 705.
But this is as far as we can check...
How about if we check the bicycles?
Good idea, Mitsuhiko!
Damn it! What are they doing?!
Hey!
Oh no, don't close!
What's up?
It seems that you've gotten interested.
They're so serious about it...
Found it!
Shima-san's bike! Look!
Asuka...
Her initial is A!
Then, the husband's initial is M, and the wife's initial is A?
Bingo! We've finally found them!
But there's still Michihiro Ishida-san left.
If it's just one family, I guess we could ask the neighbors.
I guess nobody's home...
If the neighbor's not in, let's try the apartment directly below.
Right.
This is the apartment where the initials
A and M belonged to the wrong people.
I made a mistake.
Hello.
What is it?
We're doing research for our Japanese class...
What? I can't hear you well!
And we're checking on Japanese names in particular.
Do you happen to know the name of Ishida-san's wife who lives above you?
How should I know the name of someone's wife who lives above me?!
What an awful woman...
If right below is no good...
Let's try right above, right?
Ishida-san's wife's name?
It was Fumiko-san, wasn't it?
You spell it with the "bun" in "bunsho"...
Once, a package meant for her was delivered here by mistake.
"Fumiko-san", that means...
Her first initial is F.
Her son is Yuta-kun. He's a smart kid.
But once he got locked in the closet and couldn't get out!
A closet... You mean the room to the extreme west?
Right, right!
What do you think he did?
He dropped toilet paper out of the bathroom window
and let the people passing below know.
Miss!
Do all the people who live in this building know that story?!
Yes, I'm sure they do.
It's a well-known story in this building.
Oh, my God...
It's been done before!
Conan-kun!
What on earth is the matter?
We're going to the third floor.
Because the only ones with the initials M and A
are Masakazu Shima and
his wife Asuka in apartment 305.
What's going on? You're suddenly so interested.
He's starting to think that there's something going on after talking to the lady.
What?
Hide!
Robbers!
They're wearing gloves!
And sunglasses!
You didn't even finish the job right!
Why did you kill?
Shut up.
Kill?!
Damn! We're too late.
What do we do, Conan-kun?
Let's call the police!
Hurry!
Let's get outside before they get into the elevator!
That was close.
Police officers!
Let's tell them!
Big trouble! A robbery-murder case!
In that apartment building over there!
You'd better hurry or the criminals will get away!
Please hurry!
Hold it!
You're not getting away!
What is it?
It's them!
They killed a woman!
What's with you guys?!
What on earth is this about?!
Freeze!
You kids go outside.
Anyway, please check in apartment 305!
The dead body of Asuka Shima-san should be there!
Dead body?
What are you talking about?!
There's no such dead body!
Don't lie!
Then why did you say,
"Why did you kill?" just a while ago?
You're so silly.
We were talking about an insect.
Insect?
I was angry because he
carelessly killed my insect.
Besides, I'm Asuka Shima.
Here's my driver's license.
Geez. Talk about a nuisance.
There was no dead body anywhere!
Besides, we checked with the neighbors,
and they also verified that these two
were Mr. and Mrs. Shima.
Everyone, apologize to them.
Right...
We're really very sorry...
No problem.
We confused you with the subject we were talking about too.
But, Officer, someone is being locked up.
Enough of that!
Don't you ever do something like this again!
Yes, sir...
They were married...
We completely mistook them
for robbers and murderers...
There's no other room where the occupants' initials are M and A, is there?
Maybe they're not their initials...
Something bothers me.
I wonder what it is...
Hey.
Maybe the person in apartment 705 isn't Fumiko, but Ayako?
Right! If it's Ayako, her first initial is A!
We were lucky to find meat so cheap, weren't we, Fumiko-san?
We sure were, Mother.
It was Fumiko.
So they're safe.
Hurry up, Yuta.
He's the toilet paper boy, isn't he?
What a skinny mother.
My mom's so overweight she's wearing Dad's T-shirts.
Overweight?
Ayumi-chan, let me see the ring.
Uh, Conan-kun!
What's with him?!
Hey, Conan!
What's up?!
Open up! What are you saying, Conan?!
He's gone...
You again? What is it this time?!
H-Hey! What's with you?!
This is what was bothering me after all!
Hey, get out of here, will you?!
Are you Akihiko Uehara-san's wife?
Is your name Misato-san?
Y-Yes...
Then this is yours, right?
I picked it up in front of the door a while ago.
The initials A for Akihiko, and M for your first name, are carved on it...
Try it on.
Take a good look at the ring, lady.
The initials "M to A" are carved on it.
From M to A...
From Misato-san to Akihiko-san.
Yes. That's actually Akihiko-san's ring.
But Misato-san was wearing it.
That's why it was hard to tell.
The neighbors said that Misato-san had recently gained weight.
Not being able to wear her own ring, she probably wore Akihiko-san's instead.
Because many Japanese men don't wear rings, even after getting married.
And besides, I think Akihiko-san has slender fingers for a man.
What are you trying to say?
Aren't those shoes a little too small for you?
And your point is?
What I want to say...
is that you're not Misato-san, but an impostor.
If I am...
So what?!
That was close.
You're Misato Uehara-san, right?
Yes. And you?
Me? I'm Conan Edogawa, a detective.
Why is it that, when I think about you
I am filled with uneasiness?
It is because of the wind blowing at such a lonely flower
Ah, it might really be the end for sure this time
Since when did it become like this
Where we would just miss each other?
Little by little, little by little, things are changing for some reason
You have changed, and so has the surroundings
Am I the cause for these?
Even though you are such a precious person to me
Her name is Ikuyo Hasegawa.
She used to work with Misato Uehara-san's husband Akihiko-san.
She was fired when Akihiko-san found that she had embezzled money from the company.
She had committed the crime out of hatred.
She visited the building in order to kill Akihiko-san.
When Misato-san answered the door, she drugged her to sleep
and locked her in the closet.
When she came to a while later,
Misato-san connected the ring to the S-hooks
and threw it out the window, hoping to get help.
But right after that,
she came to check on her, closed the window,
and drugged her to sleep a second time.
Good work!
Take care on your way home.
Yes, sir!
No fair, Conan-kun!
She's right! Taking the best part for yourself...
You get me so mad!
As punishment, you hold all this!
Hey! Am I supposed to hold all of this?!
Of course!
Hey, wait!
Mine too.
Oh, geez. Not you too!
It's my turn to send out an SOS!