Missing Link
"Missing Link."
It refers to that which is hidden behind a series
of incidents or seemingly unrelated victims:
Their common factor or underlying relationship.
If we are unable to seek out that link,
it remains difficult to solve cases.
Today, we will be presenting you a playback of a case
involving consecutive attacks on young women.
Causing your eyelids to swell and permeating your heart...
Tear drops serve as a prelude to a wealth of drama.
A sting operation has reopened the
past wounds of Inspector Megure!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Hello?
It's me.
Sorry for not answering.
My cell phone's battery ran out.
Yeah...
I just got out of the car—I'm in a phone booth now.
Let's see...
I'll be at your place in about half an hour.
Bye, see you soon.
MEGURE'S SEALED SECRET
(PART ONE)
Hey, hey, how's this one?
This is a present for Kyogoku-san, right?
Isn't it a little cute for him?
Guess it is...
If it's him...
This simple one will suit him just fine.
No it won't, it's not hand-knit.
Oops!
Sonoko...
No, I just thought a hand-knit
sweater would feel warm...
Don't tell me, Sonoko!
I unintentionally mentioned it in
the letter I sent him earlier...
"Right now, I'm knitting a sweater for someone I like."
But I never expected it to be so hard.
I see.
So you were going to buy him a hand-knit
sweater from a store and say you knit it.
It can't be helped!
I really don't know how to knit.
Very well.
I admire your bravery in admitting that you
like him, so I'll keep your secret to myself.
Oh, I still haven't told Makoto-san that I like him.
Didn't you say so in the letter?
"I'm knitting for someone I like"?
Stop beating around the bush or Kyogoku-san
might think there's someone else you love.
See, that's the whole point!
Makoto-san will definitely panic a
bit when that comes to mind...
And one day, a package will arrive at his place.
He would think, "What is this, something
from Sonoko-san?" or something like that.
And as he anxiously starts
to open up the package...
"Surprise!"
"The sweater was actually for you!"
What do you think of my marvelous love-love plan?
Even if you say so...
Don't come crying to me if he's not impressed.
But you know...
Makoto-san won't express his feelings, so I don't
know how he actually feels if I don't do this.
I know he worries about me, but...
I still need the courage to ask him directly.
But, Sonoko...
Speaking of which, Ran, do you know?
How Shinichi-kun feels about you?
That's...
Hey...
Hey, hey, hey!
Don't you want to know?
Don't you want to ask him?
Well, don't you?
About that...
I've known him since we were little, so it'd
be a lie to say I don't want to know, but...
But...
"But, but, but, but, but, but, but, but, but...!"
"I want to ask, but I'm afraid to know the answer."
"That's how I feel right now."
I bet you're thinking something
dreamy like that, aren't you!?
I'm not!
Excuse me...
May I go to the parking garage and wait with Uncle?
Tell Dad to go ahead and wait in the pasta
house behind this department store, all right?
Hey, hey, how about this one?
Seems I've come across some idle
girl-talk that I shouldn't have...
No, that one's too tasteless!
Isn't it?
Geez...
Why do girls like to spend so much time
shopping and chatting on the phone?
So true...
Wow!
What a beautiful girl!
It's this cold and she's wearing a mini-skirt that short?
How sexy!
There's a ballpoint pen over here.
I think it belonged to that girl.
Oh, a great opportunity!
Ah, wait!
Miss!
I think this belongs to you!
Arrest him!
Right!
Wait, wait, wait!
Disguised in order to investigate the cases of
the women who were attacked this week?
That's right.
That's why we asked Detective
Satou to dress that way.
But, the announcements said the
suspect is about 150 cm tall...
A quick look at me will tell you I'm
not the suspect you're looking for.
No...
But that attitude you had as you
approached Satou-san was, uhm...
Should I say "very special"?
I felt I was in danger.
How rude...
But it is tough to investigate...
Yeah, since the only common link between the women
was that they were all wearing fashionable clothes.
Even the crime scenes are different.
Could we see the photos of those three women again?
Yes, sir.
The first to be attacked goes by
the name Mizutani Ryouko-san.
One night two weeks ago...
While she was waiting in her car for the traffic
light to change, another car rear-ended her.
Then, as she left the vehicle to complain,
she was attacked with a metal bat.
The next one to be attacked was Endou Hitomi-san.
Ten nights ago, she was struck by a metal bat as
she was coming out of a public restroom in a park.
Then, we have the one from last
night, Ishiguro Michiko-san.
This time, she was attacked after
coming out of a phone booth.
You said phone booth—does that mean...
Yeah, it was where we subdued you earlier.
Fortunately, the lives of those
three victims aren't in danger.
They just share nothing in common other than
the fashionable garb they were wearing.
The three of them also said they
hadn't made any enemies.
How's that, Mouri-kun?
Think of anything yet?
Well, one thing I noticed is...
One thing you noticed?
All three of them are mixed-race —
like
they grew up in a jungle or something.
No matter how you look at it, they aren't normal Japanese.
Oh, how cute!
These three ganguro look amazing!
The one in the middle is gonguro, so she's even darker.
This style is called Yamanba, and it's really
fashionable among girls these days.
Yamanba?
No way...
Could it be you don't know, Uncle?
Ridiculous!
Of course, Yamanba!
I know something that obvious.
Huh?
Where's Ran-neechan?
She said she was going to the restroom and
wanted me to meet her at this pasta house.
But, if this was just a series of random
attacks, there's nothing we can do...
That's true...
To now, there haven't been any cases like this one.
No, there was one before.
There was a string of female high school
students being run over by cars...
Pretty disturbing cases...
I'm certain it was before I became a police detective...
At any rate, we should get back to investigating.
Yes, sir.
In that case, I'll go back to being a decoy.
No, a decoy is no longer necessary.
Start over and investigate whether or not the
three victims had any connection to each other.
Yes, sir.
Well, Mouri-kun, sorry about what happened.
No problem.
Hello?
Ah, Ran.
You can't find the exit?
Well, where are you?
The underground parking garage?
Geez, you have no sense of direction, as usual.
Hey, Sonoko-neechan, about your
ring, necklace, and bracelet...
Don't they look like those worn
by the women in the photos?
Where'd you buy them?
I didn't buy them, they were complimentary gifts
from that department store we just went to.
They're having this Millennium Sale,
and they check your receipt at the exit.
For every 10,000 yen you spend, you
get to choose one of the accessories.
Hey, how about it?
They're wearing them.
Although they aren't wearing the entire set, they
each have a piece that matches Sonoko-san.
Which means these three...
Are all customers of that department store.
Hey, Sonoko?
What is it?
Answer me...
Hey, Sonoko...
Ran!
Hey, Ran!
What happened, Ran!?
What is it, Ran?
Dad...
Are you OK?
What!?
There's a girl whose face is covered in blood!?
The victim is Aizawa Tae-san, 20 years old.
Until one year ago, she worked in this department store.
She's been unemployed since.
So our fourth case is a murder...
It's the same suspect, then?
Yeah.
We never announced the common
characteristics of the victims to the public...
And this is the parking garage of
that same department store.
There's no denying the connection.
In that case, this was done by someone bearing
a grudge against this department store.
Tae!
Who's he?
That's the boyfriend.
He claimed to have been waiting
for her in the department store.
Shirakawa Noriyuki (24)
Cook
His father is the owner of this department store...
And he planned to introduce his girlfriend
at the restaurant where he works.
And that girl?
She's a waitress who works in the
same restaurant that he does.
Konno Yuri (24)
Waitress
Her name is Konno Yuri-san.
She said they've been friends since college,
and that she sometimes gives him advice.
Advice?
Shirakawa-san's father opposed his
engagement with the deceased Aizawa-san.
By the way, Ran...
Did you notice anyone suspicious
when you found the body?
Nobody suspicious.
The only person I passed by was the guard.
Guard?
It was the guard standing by the entrance when I
came down —
a man who was about 40 years old...
Oh, that would be me.
I left my post in order to head to the restroom, so...
Sadakane Yoshio (43)
Guard
The culprit must have got to her while I wasn't here.
That is, if you aren't really the culprit yourself.
Dad...
If I recall correctly, you worked at a rival
department store until half a year ago.
Could you have arranged with your former employer to
cause a scandal here and send my customers his way?
Shirakawa Haruyoshi (53)
Haido Department Store Owner
No way...
Well, at least now Noriyuki can get a new girlfriend.
This time, how about finding
a nice girl with a clean slate?
Dad!
Noriyuki-kun...
Uhm, what did he mean by "clean slate"?
He's probably referring to the automobile accident she
was involved in a year ago, in this parking garage.
She ran over a little boy, and after
that accident, she gave up her job.
Yumi from the traffic division told me about that.
The boy was waiting in this parking garage for his
mother when he stepped in front of a car and was hit.
The driver was going at a slow speed considering
it was the inside of a parking garage, but...
Unfortunately, the boy's vitals were
hit, and he died three days later.
I think the boy's name was Sakurai Akira.
I see.
By the way, Noriyuki-san...
Do you know how tall your father is?
A little over 150 cm.
And the rest of you?
173 cm.
I'm 144 cm.
And I'm 167 cm.
Things aren't looking good for the owner.
Yeah.
He would've known when she would be by her car.
I have a question.
Was your father already at the
restaurant when you arrived?
No, he didn't show up on time, so
I asked her to see if he was here.
I see.
Could you be implying that my father is a suspect!?
No, we only asked because the other victims told
us the culprit's height was around 150 cm.
The "other victims"?
Then, as I thought, this is the work of that
serial attacker we've been hearing about?
That is...
What have you done about that?
You even know the culprit's height,
so why can't you catch them?
If you had caught the culprit, Tae wouldn't be dead!
Wait, Noriyuki-kun...
Tae is dead, and it's the fault of the police!
You police are all useless!
That's enough, Noriyuki-kun!
Useless...
You police are all useless!
Why are you surprised?
I said I was going to play decoy.
Guess... it didn't go smoothly like in the movies...
Inspector Megure!
Inspector!
Are you all right?
Forget it, it's nothing...
My apologies, Inspector.
Noriyuki-kun just went a little overboard.
No, it's fine.
What he said was true.
You know, it might be best for
him to go cool off for a bit...
Understood.
In that case, I'll return to my post.
Keep up the good work.
Say...
Did all three of those ladies attest that
the culprit's height was around 150 cm?
No, only the first and third victims said that.
The second victim was suddenly attacked from behind.
She was unconscious until a passerby found her,
so she didn't catch a glimpse of her assailant.
But, both that did say were certain
that the culprit was about 150 cm.
When we called them down to the
station a few days after the attacks...
Both stated that their attacker was
roughly the same height as they were.
And how tall were those two?
Let's see...
The first was 151 cm, and the third was 153 cm.
We measured them at the station,
so there's no doubt about that.
Hey!
Don't tell a kid too much about that.
Sorry...
Hey, Ran...
Are you sure you didn't see anyone suspicious?
I'm sure of it.
I ran around looking for the exit, after all.
In any case, don't you think something's wrong?
About what?
About that lady there.
Ah, you noticed it too?
You think so too?
Something's weird, but I can't figure out what.
This person... something just isn't right...
Not right?
Speaking of weird, don't you think the
second victim's clothes are weird?
This lady was attacked as she was
leaving a park restroom, right?
Yes, that's right.
We took that picture right after
we arrived at the crime scene.
Look.
The restroom is even in the background.
Since a passerby was the one who found
her, she must have been alone, right?
But if so, why is it she has a
man's coat on her shoulders?
Oh, that's the coat I loaned her at the time.
She seemed to be freezing.
Then, why was she wearing such light
clothes in the middle of the night?
That's true...
She didn't say anything about the
attacker stealing her coat or anything...
Speaking of which, we haven't had time to take her
statement since she's still in a state of shock.
Idiot!
Don't you know it's fashionable
for girls not to wear much?
But what she wore was sleeveless.
That'd be too cold for anyone to bear.
Maybe she was somewhere warm and had planned
to go back there after going to the restroom.
Somewhere warm?
Right, right...
Like maybe...
Inside her car.
Her car?
That's right, the first and third victims were
attacked right after they left their cars.
And then, the fourth happened in a parking garage.
These cases all involve cars!
All right!
Takagi-kun, go contact the second
victim immediately to confirm!
Yes, sir!
Does that mean the owner's no longer suspicious?
No, not just yet.
Thanks for your continued perseverance, Detective.
Matsumoto Kiyonaga (54)
Police Headquarters · Superintendent
Superintendent Matsumoto!
Pleasure to see you again...
Hey, Megure...
The press has already started reporting that
this is the beginning of a serial murder spree.
I advise you pull back for now and start
the investigation anew tomorrow.
No, it's just...
He's right, Inspector.
We already know the girls were
in their cars before the attacks.
I'll just disguise as a ganguro
and act as a decoy in my car.
Didn't I tell you!?
No more decoys!
Superintendent...
Please, allow us to investigate just a little longer!
I'm sure we're getting somewhere!
And I have a feeling that the culprit
is still around here somewhere.
If you must.
Megure...
Could it be that you're still thinking
back to that case from before?
About what it is you hide away under your hat?
No, that's not it...
Is that so?
Sorry I asked.
MEGURE'S SEALED SECRET
(PART TWO)
Hey, Uncle.
Could I borrow your keys?
This case seems like it's gonna take a while, so I'd
like to put my stuff in the car and visit the restroom.
Well, don't be too long.
The store will be closing soon.
Thank you.
Would you take mine too?
Sure.
There it is!
Here, here!
Geez, look at how this other car is parked!
What a strange way to park!
I can't even open the passenger side door like this.
And there.
Inspector, I just heard back from her!
And?
As we thought, she was in her car
before going to the restroom.
I see.
But I still don't understand...
Why is he only after fashionable
young girls who drive cars?
Or is there some other connection?
Something that we overlooked connecting those four...
RESTROOM CLOSED
FOR CLEANING
Please accept our
apologies for the
inconvenience.
Haido
DEPARTMENT STORE
Hey, no way!
Here too?
Why don't they wait to clean until after they've closed?
The next restroom is up on the 8th floor.
I have such bad luck with these restrooms.
Thank you for visiting our department store.
We'll be closing soon.
Please come again soon.
No way...
Already?
We'll take the body now.
Hey, her leg slipped out!
Sorry!
Huh?
The shoe doesn't fit?
Hey, Ran-neechan!
Earlier, you said there was
something wrong with that lady!
Could it be...
Yeah, yeah, that's it!
Since it's part of the ganguro fashion,
they shouldn't have been missing!
Then, that means...
Could the culprit be...
Wait, don't turn the lights off!
I'm still here!
Hey!
Is anyone there?
What?
Platform boots?
You're saying that Aizawa-san, who was killed in this
parking garage, was actually wearing platform boots?
Yeah—it's part of the ganguro fashion, so
they wouldn't wear low-heeled pumps.
Right, Ran-neechan?
Yeah...
But why would the criminal change the victim's shoes?
He didn't want anyone to figure it out.
That he only goes after women
who drive with platform boots.
What was that!?
Speaking of which, the other three victims
followed the ganguro fashion as well...
In other words, those three must
have had platform boots too?
Right.
Speaking of platform boots...
The primary reason that Aizawa-san
caused that car accident a year ago...
Was due to the fact she was
driving with platform boots on...
Which caused her braking to take longer than usual.
That's what I heard from Yumi.
Is that true?
Yes.
The deceased boy's mother and her ex-husband
argued that that was the cause of the accident, but...
The judge overruled them.
The ex-husband?
Yeah.
They divorced after the husband became an alcoholic.
I think that man's name was...
Sadakane, wasn't it?
Right, right, that was his name.
Hey, hold on a second!
Isn't the guard's name... Sadakane?
Hey, then, could that mean the culprit is...
The security guard?
Takagi, go get information on
that accident from a year ago!
Right!
The rest of you, go find the guard, Sadakane!
Yes, sir!
But, how did you know all that?
It wasn't too difficult.
The culprit only attacked women who drove
while wearing platform boots, right?
From outside the car, the culprit can't see
what kind of shoes they're wearing...
But we know that the victims
shop at this department store.
As such, the only way the culprit would know
is to see them getting in and out of their cars.
That's why it had to be the guard.
However, the victims said the
culprit was about 150 cm tall.
Didn't you hear the guard say he was 167 cm?
You're just playing stupid, aren't you?
The girls only said that the culprit
was the same height as them.
At those times, they were wearing
platform boots over 10 cm thick.
What that really meant was that the
culprit must've been 10 cm taller.
Didn't you already know that?
I see.
We measured their heights at the station.
Since they were coming for a police interview,
they wouldn't wear informal platform boots.
But, if he wanted to kill Aizawa-san...
Why do it in this parking complex rather
than just go straight to her house?
Have you forgotten, Mouri?
The victim was 20 years old, wasn't she?
A year ago when she caused the
accident, she was considered a minor.
Minors cannot have their addresses be
made public according to the law.
Because of that, he waited at this department store
where his son died, hoping she'd return one day.
When she didn't appear, he broke down and began
attacking any woman who drove in platform boots.
Inspector, we got the backstory!
As we thought, the guard is the father of the
boy who died in the accident one year ago.
And?
Where is he at the moment?
About that... his car is still in the
parking garage, but he's missing.
What's wrong, Ran-neechan?
Sonoko hasn't come back yet...
She said she was just going to put her things
in the car and then going to the restroom...
Putting her stuff in the car?
Hey, the shoes Sonoko's wearing...
Hello?
Ah, Ran?
Huh, right now?
I'm still in the department store.
Wait until you hear what happened.
It's so cruel!
Right as I got out of the restroom,
they turned the lights off...
What is it?
Something wrong, Sonoko?
Oh, nope.
It's nothing.
Just thought I heard something weird.
She saw me... She saw me...
She saw my face...
Hey, Sonoko!
Sonoko?
He's made a mistake.
The culprit saw Sonoko-neechan doing
something in the car with the keys in hand!
He mistook her for a driver with platform boots!
What was that?
Where is she right now?
Inside the department store.
Is the line cut?
It's still connected, but...
I can only hear a machine's voice.
A machine's voice?
Please choose your background picture!
Press the button when your pose is ready!
That's a print club machine!
In the department store, do they
have a print club machine?
They do.
There's two on the 10th floor, next
to the stairs for the restaurant...
That's it.
The stores are closed, but
the restaurants are still open.
Sonoko-kun was headed up there to use
the elevator to make her way back down!
All right!
Takagi, get the lights in the building back on!
Megure and Satou, take the elevator
and search from top to bottom.
The others, take the stairs and search bottom to top
in order to secure this girl and seize the culprit!
Yes, sir!
Out of the way!
Move it!
Man, the Inspector seems fired up!
It's no wonder.
This case has reminded him of the
first case he was involved in.
By the way, where's your daughter
and the boy with glasses?
Found it!
This is...
It's Sonoko's cell phone, no mistake!
Since the customers in the restaurants
haven't seen them...
Sonoko-chan must've run into the department stores.
Hey, Takagi, where're the lights?
You girls are demons.
That's right.
You disguise yourselves as cute girls in order to
commit crimes—you're nothing but little demons.
Demons have no right to live!
A blackout?
Damn it!
Why now?
Sonoko?
Sonoko, where are you?
Wait a second.
It sounds like a number of things
are falling simultaneously.
Sand?
Rice?
No, something bigger...
Could it be those little stones you put in a fish tank?
The pet shop is on the 4th floor.
That must mean she's on the 4th floor.
Let's go check.
Restaurant Floor
Books & Beauty, Photos, Denistry
Food, Housewares, CDs, Stationary
Children's Apparel, Clocks, Glasses, Toys
Misses & Plus Size Women's Apparel
Forgive me.
I only intended to teach you a little lesson.
But you just had to go and see...
My face.
Sonoko?
That's weird, there's no one in the pet shop.
That's strange...
Nothing's broken and there's nothing on the floor.
Could it have been...
That sound from before...
You just had to see my face!
The Inspector...
Does it...
Feel good?
Hey!
I asked if hurting others feels good to you.
You may think you're punishing evil
and being a bringer of justice, but...
This is just a high school girl who
wanted to put things in a car.
You did this not for the sake of seeking
justice nor for avenging your son.
You did it solely out of rage.
For you it was just a conceited, meaningless
diversion that trifled with people's lives.
Don't you get it!?
I just wanted that woman to apologize...
For her to wear proper shoes and
apologize to my son in heaven...
That's all I wanted...
That really was true in the beginning...
Really...
Sonoko!
Ran!
Are you all right?
You're not hurt?
I was so scared!
Inspector, how did you know they were here?
Well...
I was led here...
By these Go stones.
Inspector, are you all right?
It's nothing to worry about.
It's just my old wound reopening.
An old wound from the past...
Midoridai Police Hospital
He got that wound from a previous case?
Yeah.
Megure hides the scar by wearing that hat.
But for a police officer, a scar is like a badge of honor.
He should be proud.
It was more than twenty years ago.
Right, it was back when Megure
was still a rookie on the force.
You may have heard about it.
The case where someone was
running over high-school girls.
Oh, yes.
The culprit had been bullied by an all-girls gang.
He was running them down in his car at
night, when there was no one around.
He targeted female delinquents
who wore long, tight skirts...
Ones they'd converted from their
school uniforms to be their style.
At first, he only made light contact with them...
But then it escalated and resulted in a fatality.
We warned all students not to wear that style of
skirt, so the case was settled for a while, until...
A high school girl showed up
wanting to be used as a decoy.
She wanted to find her friend's killer at any cost.
Of course we tried to stop her, but it seemed
she despised the police, so she insisted.
With no other choice, I assigned
Megure to keep an eye on her, but...
The culprit tried to run over and kill
both Megure and the girl with his car.
Luckily, Megure remembered the car number, so the
suspect was caught very quickly—but at a high price.
Megure only hit his head, but the girl's
entire body was gravely injured...
By the time we arrived, she was covered
in blood, and barely breathing.
So the reason why the Inspector
has always kept his hat on...
Yeah, that's right.
He doesn't want others to ask him about the scar.
He's always been reminded of that horrible case.
That's why Megure wears that
hat—to seal away that scar.
The scar that symbolizes that tragic memory.
So that's why the Inspector was against using decoys.
He didn't want anyone else to die like that girl...
Hey, hey!
I only said that she was gravely injured!
Not that she died!
In fact, she's Megure's—
Oh, Superintendent Matsumoto!
It's an honor to have you come all the way here.
Megure Midori
Megure's Wife
Shiratori-san and Takagi-san just left a few moments ago.
Oh, they came by as well?
Yeah, they all took a breather from work.
A scar on her forehead?
Don't tell me...
Hey, Midori!
Can you peel this apple for me?
My, he enjoys being spoiled, as always.
Looks like I'll have to toughen him up
so he can return to the force soon!
Yes, if you would, please!
Come to think of it, the Inspector said his wife,
Midori-san, was a delinquent in the past.
Could it be that the real reason he wears that hat...
Is because he doesn't want others to
make fun of how he and his wife met?
Heeey, not done yet?