Translated to En by: Spimer and Ned
Timed and Typesetted by: Ned
The Gathering of the Detectives
(Part 2)
My rental car is...
My Ferrari is being burned too
My Alfa Romeo and the old man's
Oogami's Porsche are burning too
After all this, I guess my car
at the rear has also burnt up
At the rear...? You didn't
park your car here, Ms. Maid?
No
The master told me to
park it by the back door
Oh! It's safe
Doesn't this seem strange to you?
The culprit must've forgotten
to rig a bomb in this car
Let's go check whether the bridge
has really been destroyed or not
I'm coming
I shall come along as well
I'm in, too
There, there... Too many
people will sink the boat
How about we decide who
gets to go with coins?
I happen to have five coins
My, kid! You're thoughtful
It's a primitive method, but
Well, it can't be helped
Those who get heads on their coins
Will go to the bridge with the car
Be careful, dad
T-That's...
Could it...
Could it be?!
Whoa! What a hideous sight
The bridge's been completely destroyed
Hey! Granny Senma
Please switch the headlights to
short range! I can't see the ground
Alright
Hmm, let's see... Short range, short range...
Ms. Senma!
Ehh? Ms. Senma was killed?!
Yeah... It seems that the car was altered
so it'll explode if you touched the lights
If we keep waiting, we'll be killed
Let's split up and search if there's really
someone else besides us in the mansion
Well then... us women will make a team of 3
This way we can go to the bathroom together
Wait...
Where's the brown-haired
and fair-skinned boy at?
No idea
Perhaps he's feeding the
hawk he brought along
Huh...
Stylish stuff we've got here
There are brand new scratching
traces on the piano's edge
Those are probably scratch
marks made by a hawk
It means that that boy
came by to check this room
Ah-le-le! Something's stuck
between the piano keys
Indeed
This is the Luminol solution
that the miss brought with her
So she's also come here
Hey! Whiskers! Turn off the lights!
Hurry!
Karasuma will kill despite
that I finally got the trump
card to solve the cipher
Huh? Where's the maid?
She said she'd wait on the corridor outside
the restroom, will you go check it out?
OK
Ms. Maid
The maid!
So it was you
The culprit who rigged the car with a bomb
wouldn't ride on it and risk themselves
The culprit must be one of us who stayed in
the mansion... You, me, Ms. Ran, and the maid
Oh my, boy... Aren't you
carrying a dangerous toy?
It was beneath the bed's
mattress in my room
You intended to place the
blame on me afterwards, no?
Oh my, what a coincidence
I was thinking the same thing
I had the same deduction as you
A gunfire?!
No good
His heart's been pierced
Shit!
The stairs
Someone's climbing the stairs
This rascal!
A PC?
Ms. Souda!
Look!
It's set up so that a needle pops
out if you turn the inner knob
Whoever inputted the
treasure's location in the PC
would be poisoned when they
tried to leave the room
But, where's the culprit at?
Don't play dumb!
There's no way she'd fall for her own trap
And your daughter and the maid
are napping in the restroom
If that gunfire was fake
only you or I could've killed them
And if it wasn't me
Then it has to be you, right?
Translated to En by: Spimer and Ned
Timed and Typesetted by: Ned
Hmpf, I like to eliminate
trouble at its earliest stage
Don't hate me,
Mr. Sleeping Kogorou
Impossible...
Even the greatest
detectives couldn't solve it
The hidden cameras footage is cut off
What?!
"I've solved the treasure's cipher.
I want to tell you it in person.
Come to the dining room. I'm the 7th deective."
Impossible!
All of the detectives I invited should
be dead! There can't be a 7th detective
Normally, you wouldn't think that someone who rigs a bomb in a
car would ride in that car, unless they wanted to commit suicide
But there's an exception
That's when they want to use the explosion as camouflage,
so it looks like they've died in the explosion
Isn't that right?
Detective Senma
Yes, you secretly came out of the
car before it exploded and hid
How silly... I noticed the
bomb in the last second
escaped the explosion and
just made my way back here
Besides, didn't we decide who'd
ride the car by flipping coins?
You knew you'd ride in the
car even before flipping them
Since you had a coin on your left
hand's palm surface from the start
You hid it by placing your right hand, with
another coin on it, on top of the left hand
You pretended to catch the flipped coin,
but you actually let it fall to the floor
and then revealed the one
you were already holding
so that you'd always get heads
You had a ten yen coin on you when
you checked Mr. Oogami's black tea
so wasn't it easy for you? Ms.
"phantom of the child abandoned by God"
Oh? Are you saying I'm the organizer
of the banquet and Mr. Oogami's killer?
Tell me, then
How did I manage to make just
Mr. Oogami drink potassium cyanide?
And how could I predict when he'd do so?
His black tea had no poison in it
and Mr. Mouri was between our seats
The sitting order doesn't matter
Since you had coated all of the tea
cups with potassium cyanide beforehand
You placed it where the
handle and the cup touched
When Mr. Oogami held the cup, the edge
of his right thumb would touch that spot
And it's also next to his nail, which he
unconsciously bit when he was lost in thought
But all of us did wipe clean all of
the cutlery to be on the safe side
That's true
It was very careless of Mr. Oogami, who
was such a great and renowned detective
But if he was your friend and
an organizer of this banquet
It's not impossible for him
to underestimate the risk
by thinking he wouldn't get
killed and thus be less on guard
Yes
You killed your accomplice, Mr. Oogami, and
then made it look like someone killed you
You invited the detective here to solve the
cipher and to psychologically corner them
have them find the treasure's location
and then finally, you'd kill them all
Like what the millionaire
Karasuma Renya did 40 years ago!
There was a name at the end of the
piano's bloody text... Senma Kousuke
I guess that it's...
It's the name of my father
He was an archaeologist... He was summoned
to this Twilight Mansion 40 years ago
A millionaire that was over 100 years old
had found a clue to a treasure hidden in the
manor he'd inherited from his mother in the past
And wanted to have a look at it before
dying, so he wanted my father to find it
It seemed like it was a very well-paid job, we received big heaps
of money each day along with a daily letter from my father
So both my mother and I were glad
6 months later, both the money and
the letters suddenly ceased to come
And my father, who hadn't told us
where he had been, went missing
I got to know the truth of his disappearance when I held the last
letter he sent us, which I'd kept as a substitute of him, to the light
There were holes in the letter made
by a needle... It was a secret message
There he narrated about the cipher
which told the treasure's location
and that many other scholars apart
from my father had been summoned there
and about how Karasuma, feeling his death looming close,
lost his temper and began to kill the scholars one by one
within the mansion as
a warning to the others
Did you tell that to the police?
No... I didn't discover the text written
with the needle until 20 years after
By then Renya had already died, the Karasuma family had
declined and the mansion had passed to other owners
It all began when I accidentally slipped
this story to Mr. Oogami two years ago
He located this mansion at once, went
mad and began to search for the treasure
but he was unable to solve the cipher
He had accumulated a huge
debt from buying this mansion
and, one day, when he couldn't
waltz out of things, he said:
"Let's gather the detectives
and have them solve the cipher!"
We'll use Kaitou Kid as bait
to lure the detectives in!
Let's make him the inviter and set up
a game in which we stake our lives!
And make it look like, at some point in
the game, that he's killed both of us!
But why did you kill him?
Because I realized that he intended to kill
us, including me, once we found the treasure
Making it look like we'd shot each
other with the guns he put in our rooms
To make the detectives continue to solve the cipher, I had no choice
but to stop that man, who behaved like he was possessed by Karasuma
The result is the same as 40 years ago
The cipher hasn't been solved and
the tragedy has repeated itself
No, it seems like your
father did solve the cipher!
Huh?
Don't you think it's odd that despite that it's such a huge
mansion, the only clock here is this one here in the dining hall?
Yeah, the beginning of the cipher "On the night
that the two travelers looked up at the skies"
means 12 AM, when both of
the clock's hands aim upwards
First step is to return them to 12 AM
And the key to solve the rest of the cipher is the
trump card your father wrote in the bloody text
The trump card... A set of trumps
The king, queen and knight in the
cipher are the K, Q, and J cards
And the treasure is diamonds, the holy
grail is hearts, and the sword is spades
We follow the direction of the faces on the cards in the
mansion and move the hands from the 12 AM position accordingly
13 to the left, 12 to the
left, and 11 to the right
The coating has come off,
and gold emerges from inside
My dear!
To think my father died
over such a trivial thing
I guess this is what reality is
Well then, Ms. Senma... You promised us
Tell me the way to escape this mansion
There was never such a thing
I intended to die here
It seems that Mr. Oogami believed me when I told
him I'd secretly explain it to him after dinner
Hmpf! Thought as much
Granny Senma
Sheesh. And this was my best suit
That's why I said this
child's play was pointless
if you have any complaints,
tell them to the boy
He's the one who said that she might
reveal the way to escape if it was a kid
You actually pretended to be
dead just to make me reveal that?
When did you know I was the culprit?
Since this boy had us choose the coins
You stretched your arm and bothered to
pick the 10 yen coin which was further away
you didn't want anyone else
to pick the 10 yen coin
If you had touched a 10 yen coin when
your fingers had potassium cyanide on them
a chemical reaction would've occurred,
and the trick would've been found out
So we narrowed it down to you, thus
we were able to unite our forces
When we looked at the body's right hand
nail, we saw through the trick you used
This kid!
Well, the issue now is how
do we escape from this place?
Huh? What's that sound?
Ah. It's probably the sound of
the police helicopter I called for
Called?
Watson must've delivered the letter I
put on his anklet to my housekeeper's car
which I had on standby down the cliff
Phew... I'm glad I put an X mark on
it to tell it apart from other cars
If that's the case then you
should've told us earlier!
And yet you let us
in that monkey show
No, it's not only the helicopter's sound
I can hear the sound of something crumbling
Could it be?!
So he didn't come in the end, Kaitou Kid
Oh? Did you want him to come?
Ah, no!
Hey, granny
It was old Oogami the one who planned
to psychologically corner us, no?
Why did you pretended to be
dead after you'd killed him?
I wanted you to solve it... Solve the
cipher that my father left to me
whilst I'm still alive...
Since I thought there wouldn't be another chance like
this one, in which you great detectives would be gathered
It seems that the one who was possessed
by Karasuma Renya was me after all
Granny!
Damn it!
Dad!
Kaito Kid?!
Hey, grandma
Aren't you too old to be in a rush to die?
Don't say such nonsense
I saved you
Huh?
To apologize for organizing
this banquet in your name
If I didn't do this, you wouldn't have
been able to run away from those children
Especially from that small boy who
was aiming at you with his odd watch
Oh! I got seen through, huh?
It was the cigarettes
Mouri Kogorou is a heavy smoker
You hadn't smoked any since
you came to the mansion, right?
Who are those children?
I guess they're like the lover that
you don't want to stumble upon!
But it's a pity
You came because you were
after Karasuma's treasure, no?
Yeah, that was my intent
but I've given up on it
That doesn't fit into a thief's pocket
The walls have crumbled,
and there's gold inside
So that clock was a switch to
make the outer walls crumble, huh?
As expected of Karasuma's mansion
it must be worth a hundred
billion at the least
I see...
Twilight is that time of the
evening when the sky glows golden
It's indeed a golden mansion!
That asides, where's my real dad?
Achoo!
Ha, I'm here...
Next episode:
It's about Maria Higashio
It's Maria's shoes and backpack
It's open
The bookshelves are fallen
There is a high chance she has been
stuck somewhere for more than 6 hours
A phone call from Hattori
Hel—
Idiot!
Search for Maria-chan
Part 1
Next Conan's hint
Cover
What happened to the mansion at the end?
It had a good luck
A word play?