Translated to En by: Spimer and Ned
Timed and Typesetted by: Ned
The Gathering of the Detectives
(Part 1)
Shit! What part of this is a shortcut?!
That old guy from the gasoline stand,
telling me to use this road...!
Say, dad
Are we really on the right road?
For sure!
He had me come inside the store, buy a map,
and then told me this road... That old guy!
If this is the wrong road,
then I'll make him regret doing that!
Looks like we are finally
back on a decent road!
But it looks like it really was a shortcut!
That's it, isn't it?
Where we are heading to...
The "Twilight Mansion"...
Instead of twilight mansion,
it looks more like Drakula's castle
Are we really going there?
Idiot!
I got an invitation which said
"I want to invite you to my banquet, so as to praise your wisdom"
And 2 million yen in bank notes!
We have to go investigate, right?
But didn't that invitation have something
creepy written where the sender's name would be?
Yeah... Something like that...
"The phantom of the child abandoned by God"
Don't worry
It's just a word play
I wonder about that...
A mountain witch?!
What a way for addressing a lady
What's the matter, grandma?
As you can see
My cute little Fiat's engine has stalled
I was waiting for someone to drive by
You're also going to that mansion,
aren't you? Can you give me a ride?
Dad, are we there yet?
Almost... What's wrong?
I need to go to the restroom!
Sheesh...
Why didn't you use the chance you had
when you stopped by the gasoline stand a while ago?
Grandma, how did you know,
that we stopped by the
gasoline stand a while ago?
It's very simple little boy
The ashtray is empty,
and a brand new finished cigarette has dropped below it
If the ashtray was full enough to have spilled over,
that's a proof that it's used by a heavy smoker...
And yet the ashtray is empty
The only place you can do that is
the isolated gasoline stand about 10KM away from here...
Excuse me, but who are you?!
I am Senma Furuya
Senma Furuya (63)
Detective
I'm a detective, like you,
Mr. Sleeping Kogoro!
Senma Furuya?!
The famous detective who solves cases
simply by listening to its details whilst sitting in an armchair?
Well, an old lady like me doesn't
deserve this kind of compliment
Dad, open the boot
Whoa... When you look at it up this close,
it does look like a monster's mansion
I'll go in first
OK
Toilet, toilet
Whoa... It's full of classy cars...
Yeah...
A Benz, a Ferrari, and a Porsche!
Oh! It's an Alfa Romeo, isn't it!
How elegant!
You!
Don't touch my girl!
That's a horse that took me 5 years to win over
It's inconvenient for me if other men are touching her
Right, whiskers?
Whiskers?
Why it has been a while, Mogi!
So you've been summoned as well?
Oh, it's granny Senma!
You too?
Mogi?
Mogi Harufumi (39)
Detective
Is he detective Mogi Harufumi?
Welcome
Mr. Mogi, Mr. Mouri, and Ms. Senma, right?
We were expecting you...
Please, come in...
It is indeed
like a haunted mansion, right?
Excuse me...
You can use this bin for the wet umbrellas
Alright
Hey you!
yes...
Excuse me...
Just checked the kitchen,
If I'm not mistaken, this
is the gourmet detective
Oogami Shuzuken (51)
Detective
Huh?!
The cook suddenly got sick and cannot come?!
This isn't what I've been told!
I came here to enjoy the banquet, you know!
I am sorry, sir... I did buy the ingredients, but...
Fine... Lend me the kitchen, I'll cook it myself
Sheesh!
Sorry for your wait
What's your game? Why did you summon four
detectives to this secluded spot in the mountains?
Ah, no...
There is a total of six detectives who were invited...
Hey hey...
So there's two more?
Y-Yes... A lady, and a young man...
A young man...? Could it be Shinichi?!
Wrong!
It must be Heiji-niichan!
No, those two people were also in the
name of guests I received from the master,
but I couldn't contact Mr. Kudou...
And regarding Mr. Hattori, his mother called
us to decline, saying that his mid-term exams were close
And, where is that mad detective-loving rascal?
I do not know... I have not met him either
Huh? But you got a list from him, no?
Yes, sir... It's true that I got the list
during the interview for the maid job,
but it was an odd interview
Odd?
Ishihara Aki (23)
Maid
Yes
It was a fairly good job so it was flooded with applicants
when I entered the interview's room
There was only a PC, the instructions of the banquet,
and the list of guests above a desk
there was no-one
I had to read the instructions
whilst sitting in front of the PC
Then all of a sudden, a phrase says
"you have been selected" appeared on the screen
I see... That's interesting...
I've finally gotten excited
I've been excited ever since I saw those
odd patterns on the hall's door, you know?
It's an odd pattern, yes...
I wonder what kind of decoration is this
Watch out, baby
Those gotta be old traces of blood
No way!
You are joking, right?
Nope, it's true
They're splash bloodstains which reached
the door with a 45 degrees angle of incidence
It's not only the door
The walls have downward-flowing blood stains
And the floor has dripping blood stains
And it seems that the source of these
Isn't for only one or two people
As expected of you
Luminol...
If you spray it on blood stains, the active
oxygen in the bloodstream oxidises
a bluish purple phosphorescence is emitted
You have good tools...
Ex-coroner, Ms. Souda Ikumi
Souda Ikumi (29)
Detective
I'm honoured by this praise, boy
Hakuba Saguru (17)
Detective
My name is Hakuba Saguru
Nice to meet you
A hawk?!
Ah. Sorry for startling you
Guess it's because I had them with me in England,
it seem it's gotten used to blood
But it was worth coming back here
This is the scene of the rumored tragedy
which has been concealed for a long time
And, after 40 years, I've finally been able to descend on it
Tragedy
Translated to En by: Spimer and Ned
Timed and Typesetted by: Ned
I think I've lost my appetite
Please...
My noble six detectives!
Thank you for coming to my Twilight Mansion
Sit down in your respective seats
Bring out the food in the order I told you to
Yes sir
I invited you here because I want you to search for a treasure
which I've put to rest somewhere in this mansion
Enormous wealth that I've gained over my many years
And you will stake your lives to find it
Our lives?!
What was that sound?!
Don't fret. I've only cut your feet
I destroyed the cars so you won't run away
What?
I'm always being hunted by the
police and you detectives
I thought that you should be the
ones being hunted, for once
I've also brought down the bridge
that leads here at the same time
so it's impossible to flee
even if you had a car left
And, of course, there are no phones here
and we're outside of cell phone range
Thus it's impossible to seek help from outside
Indeed...
To put it another way, this is a game
in which whoever finds the treasure will be given half of it
and told how to escape this place
Are you interested?
I dislike rascals who hide their face and run around, hiding from us!
Alright! You can't fight a war with an empty stomach
make sure to enjoy it... Enjoy your last banquet
A speaker set in a mannequin's head?!
Shit!
Who is...
Who is behind this?!
Oh my...
You, Detective Mouri, actually came here without knowing that?
It was written in the invitation, wasn't it?
"The phantom of the child abandoned by God
The "genie" is a "phantom"...
It's elusive, yet it's not real... It's an illusion
This kanji for child, which has the radical for "human"
attached to it means a beast's offspring
See! You use it for "puppy" or "pony", no?
The child abandoned by God is the yagi
in the New Testament, which wasn't blessed by God
So this phrase means a koyagi
The "yagi" is called "goat" in English, and the "koyagi" is called
"Kid"
Kaito Kid
You mean... Kaito Kid invited us here?
It seems that his intent is to gather us six famous detectives
to pit our wits against each other
Brought the dishes
Say, Ms. maid
Yes
Could it be that the order in which you put the food
in the table was part of the master's instructions?
Yes
I was ordered to start from
Mr. Hakuba and serve clockwise
There's not any poison since I'm the one who cooked it!
How about we do rock-paper-scissors to swap seats?
But what if someone had bad luck and got the poisoned food?!
They'll accept their destiny and cry inside of their coffin
No way!
Delicious!
As expected from the gourmet detective
Brilliant cooking skills!
I went through intense training
to serve my own taste
How was it, my fellows,
the last banquet that I prepared for you?
Huh, here it comes again...
I should begin to explain why I spent a fortune
to make this mansion the stage for this game
First of all, have a look at the
eating utensils in front of you...
A bird?
There's a mark of a bird with
a big beak which is rather creepy
Isn't this a crow?
If that's the case, this might be...
Have you realised?
That's the millionaire who died a
mysterious death half a century ago
Karasuma Renya
The crest of Karasuma Renya
Karasuma Renya?!
True
This happened one night, 40 years ago,
when this mansion was still beautiful
A meeting, to which celebrities of the financial world were invited
Hailed as the Karasuma Renya Memorial,
in honour of the man who'd died at the age of 99 years old
But in reality, it was an auction to compete
for the many highly expensive works of art
which Karasuma had collected during his lifetime
There were more than 300 items to be auctioned
and the auction was scheduled to last 3 days
And on the night of the second day
Two men soaking wet arrived at the mansion
The two men spoke with lips trembling from the cold
"We got lost in the storm... But we found this mansion...
Let us stay here until the storm ceases"
The organizer of the auction was hesitating
about letting them into the mansion at first
But he was given a leaf in exchange...
His attitude suddenly changed
It looked as if it was tobaccos
The organizer rolled the leaf into a paper and inhaled it
He gradually turned jovial, and took them to the mansion
The other people there, who'd seen that, were asked to do the same
And the mansion filled with that leaf's smoke
Could that be...?
Marijuana...
People had some jocosity
Not for long, though...
One of the guests screamed like he had seen the devil
He grabbed the work of art he had bidded on, and ran across the mansion
A woman cried until her tears dried
And a man happily stabbed his hand with the pen he had on him
Eventually the guests began stealing the pieces from each other
And killing each other with the famed and
historical blades which were pieces of the auction
The auction hall turned into a picture of Hell
And then dawn came, after that nightmarish night
It left 8 dead and over 10 people in a coma
And the two men vanished along with the pieces of art
But why isn't such a huge case known to the public?
Amongst the guests, there were probably,
some famous people with political influence,
or the family members of politician
Do you understand now? Understand why I choose this mansion?
It's because I want you detectives to perform that tragedy once again
The disgraceful sight of people killing over this mansion's treasure
Worthless...
Well, it would be cruel to have you search at random
So allow me to give you a hint
A hint?
"On the night that the two travelers looked up at the skies,
the devil descended upon the castle"
"the king grabbed his treasure and ran away, trying to flee"
"The queen poured her tears into the Holy Grail and begged for forgiveness"
"The knight stained his sword with his own blood and died"
At 10:34:51 PM
I confirm, cardiac arrest...
Impossible to revive him in these circumstances
What did you say?
I can see cyanosis, which changes the colour of the lips to purple
And also, the characteristic almond scent of hydrocyanic gas
So there was potassium cyanide in the black tea that he was drinking?
No... There's no oxidation-reduction reaction
It seems that the source isn't this black tea
But then, how was he poisoned
Alright, the dice have been cast
Detective Oogami, he has given such a gorgeous start through his death
to this match of wits in which you stake your lives
So focus your wills into finding the treasure, this is also for his sake
You rascal, don't screw us over!
While you're still alive, that is
A cassette tape?
So the culprit didn't speak as he observed us, but
but he was just playing the voice recorded in the tape
Now we know 2 things
That the culprit always intended to kill Oogami-san...
And it's possible that the culprit May even be hiding amongst us