Hang on...
A shining step toward a glorious future.
Of course, my heart's ready!
On an island that still believes in mermaids,
a battle of deductions with Heiji Hattori!
On the night of a festival, a case occurs!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Geez.
I'd better see some gratitude, kid.
You showed up without so much as calling ahead,
telling me to join you on this stupid trip to Fukui,
and out of the kindness of my heart I agreed.
C'mon, don't be so crabby. I'm paying for it.
So? Where're we headed, anyway?
A tiny island named Bikuni Island.
But most of the locals call it...
the island where the mermaid lives.
Bikuni Island
Mermaid?
Yeah.
Hey...
That letter you got asking us to find the mermaid...
It isn't just some idiot who wants to see one, is it?
Just the opposite.
There was only one line,
written in shaky handwriting...
The mermaid is going to kill me! Help!
The mermaid...
...is going to kill me?
Saori Kadowaki-san is missing?
Yes. Three days ago, she stopped coming in to work.
Three days ago... That's around the time I got the letter.
Her neighbors think she took a boat to the mainland.
It's time!
Ah, right, right!
Sorry, gotta get ready for the festival!
Festival?
The annual Dugong Festival is today.
If you want to know more, try the souvenir shop on the corner. That's where Saori-chan worked.
A lucky mermaid charm...
a mermaid cell phone strap...
and special dugong buns...
This island's full of mermaids, isn't it?
The Arrow of Dugong?
Yes... It's an amulet for immortality.
Only three are given away each year,
at the annual Dugong Festival.
Saori-chan won an arrow at last year's festival, but she lost it.
She was terrified that the mermaid would curse her.
Mermaids, yeah right.
But mermaids do exist.
Oh, Naoko-san!
Naoko Kuroe (28)
Saori's Childhood Friend
Souvenir Shop Clerk
After all, Lady Mikoto ate the flesh of a mermaid and received immortality.
The Arrow of Dugong has her hair tied to it, and anyone who wins one can become immortal!
Arrow of Dugong
I'm not surprised Saori ran away from the island after she lost her arrow. She could be cursed!
And she is...?
Naoko-san, a childhood friend of Saori-chan's.
And who's this Lady Mikoto?
The head of the festival and matriarch of the Shimabukuro family.
She's the icon of the island!
How old is this lady, really?
I don't know. I've heard rumors that she's 100 or 200 years old...
Bikuni Shrine
200 years old? No way.
Kimie Shimabukuro (27)
Saori's Childhood Friend
Bikuni Shrine Maiden
My great-grandmother is exactly 130 years old this year!
You can check her birth certificate if you like!
That's old enough for the Guinness Book of World Records.
So where is yer old lady?
She's in her room, blessing the three arrows that are going to be handed out at the festival.
Then Lady Mikoto really did eat mermaid's flesh...
Huh?
Mermaids don't exist, you know!
B-But the Arrow of Dugong...
My late mother told me it was originally the Arrow of Jugon, an amulet to ward off evil.
Anti-Evil Arrow
jugon
When Great-Grandma started getting attention for her long life,
Arrow of Dugong
jugon
people around here renamed it the Arrow of Dugong!
Your mother passed away?
Yes...
Five years ago, with my father, at sea.
My grandparents were lost at sea too before I was born.
Great-Grandma and I are the only members of the family left.
Then maybe there's somethin' to the legends!
Of course not!
I went to the mainland with Saori just a few days ago and nothing happened!
Say what?
You were with Saori-san?
When was that?
Four days ago.
I went to the dentist and she came along.
We don't have a dentist on the island, you see.
What state was she in when you saw her?
She was terrified because she'd lost that arrow.
I'm cursed by the mermaid!
She wouldn't believe the curse wasn't real.
Silly...
You just don't believe in Lady Mikoto's powers, do you, Kimie?
Toshimi...
Toshimi Ebihara (27)
Saori's Childhood Friend
Daughter of the Head of the Fishermen's Union
She's the real deal! She really ate the flesh of a mermaid!
We even found a mermaid's corpse three years ago.
A mermaid's corpse?
That's enough, Toshimi!
Rokuro...
We've got nothing more to say to outsiders.
Rokuro Fukuyama (28)
Saori's Childhood Friend
Fisherman
If you're looking for Saori,
why're you wasting time here?
Just go to her house.
That's if that drunk father of hers lets you in.
A girl's gone missing, and nobody's freakin' out.
Saori fights with her dad and runs away all the time.
Can you take us to Saori-san's house?
Sure, after the festival.
What kind of festival is it?
People buy tickets,
and if the number on the ticket matches the number Great-Grandma draws,
they win an Arrow of Dugong.
We call it a festival, but it's more like a lottery.
Ah, that's right!
Why don't you two give it a go?
An elderly couple cancelled their ticket order this morning, so I've got two extra.
If you say so...
This is so cool!
Yeah!
Mikoto Shimabukuro (130)
Lady Mikoto
So that's Lady Mikoto...
She's so tiny...
It's just an old lady in lotsa make-up.
S-She...set fire to the paper screens!
The fire is taking the shape of words!
I see...
The winning numbers are under the screens!
Wow! I won!
Hooray! I'm so lucky!
R-R-Ran-chan...
I... I... I...
I won!
Attention, winners.
The time has come to bestow the Arrows of Dugong.
Please follow me...
to the Waterfall of the Mermaid!
Will the three fortunate ones please come forth?
Yes!
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
One more!
Is there one more winner here?
Benzo Kadowaki (52)
Saori's Father
Fisherman
It's me...
Huh?
Weird...
I thought that girl won.
Yeah, and I don't see her around.
But we soon found her...
at the foot of the waterfall.
May fortune light the path for these three!
Hey, what's that?
What is it?
T-Toshimi?
Was it suicide...
Or did somebody...
It might not be either.
This is the rope that strangled Toshimi.
It's part of the rope fence we strung here to keep people from falling in the river.
What did you just say?
I see.
Maybe Toshimi-san fell into the river in the dark.
She grabbed the rope, but the stake slipped out of the mud and the rope wrapped around her.
But doesn't it seem fishy?
The festival was still goin' on at the foot of the waterfall.
So why'd she go wanderin' into the woods?
Maybe she was looking for the mermaid's grave.
What?
There's a mermaid's grave somewhere in this forest.
It contains the bones of the mermaid who was found three years ago,
on the night of the festival, when the shrine's warehouse burned down.
Come to think of it, Toshimi was always curious about that grave.
Hold on just a sec!
You keep talkin' about mermaid this and mermaid that.
It wasn't really a mermaid, was it?
Who knows...
That's what the islanders believe.
But the police from the mainland thought it was the body of a woman.
How could it be an ordinary woman? The bones only went down to the waist!
They did?
A couple of large pillars in the warehouse had crushed the body from the waist down.
But then we moved the pillars.
The leg bones that should've been on the other side of the pillars...
...weren't there.
But the police thought it was a woman's body, right?
Yes.
They said a disgruntled tourist must've broken into the warehouse
looking for an extra arrow,
lit a candle, and accidentally started a fire.
After a year passed without anyone claiming the body,
we decided to give it a proper burial.
Then we ran into another problem.
Problem?
Grave robbers.
Stupid tourists started trying to dig up the body and steal the bones.
So Great-Grandmother had someone move the grave to a secret spot in the forest.
Well, whether this was murder, suicide or accident,
we can't do anything but take Toshimi-san down and wait for the police.
If it was murder, Toshimi was asking for trouble, coming up here alone in the dark.
What a thing to say about your fiancée!
Fiancée?
Our parents arranged that without our consent.
It wasn't my choice.
And now my mom and dad are dead.
Toshimi!
T-Toshimi!
Who's that?
Toshimi's father, Ebihara-san.
He's head of the local fishermen's union.
Dad!
Oh, did you contact the Fukui prefectural police?
Yeah, but they won't be able to come out for a while. The sea's too rough.
Oh, for the love of...
Great! This is perfect!
It means the killer's gotta stay put on the island!
Killer, huh?
We haven't even decided if this was murder.
Take a look at this!
An inner tube?
Heiji-niichan and I found it stuck in the river, between the waterfall and the river mouth.
I'm guessin' our culprit knocked Toshimi-san out at the top of the waterfall,
wrapped the rope around her neck,
an' floated her down the river to fake a hangin'.
Toshimi-san was last seen at the shrine two hours before her body was found.
It takes less'n an hour to climb to the top of the waterfall an' back.
There was plenty of time for anyone to kill her an' make it look like an accident.
And the killer is still somewhere on this island!
What's taking the old lady so long?
Kimie-san said she'll come down to answer questions,
but she's tired from the festival, so she might not stay long.
What's that sound?
Are you the ones who wanted to see me?
Without her make-up, she's an ogre!
W-Well...
I was wondering how you chose the winning numbers...
Er...
At random.
For a while, I picked the winning numbers from the horse races!
Oh, geez.
Then why're ya so stingy with the arrows? You oughta give away more than three!
I can't.
I only have so much hair on my head to tie to the arrows.
Great-Grandma! Your bath's ready!
I'm sorry. If that's all, I'd like to take my bath and go to bed.
Wait! I still have a quest—
You there... Young girl...
The one with your hair tied back.
Me?
The Arrow of Dugong is a charm to ward off evil.
Let go of it, and evil will fall upon you.
Men will return to dust and become heartless devils.
Women will return to water and become speechless mermaids.
Don't ever let it go.
The Next Day
Ebihara House
Aren't ya glad we brought our school uniforms?
Are ya sure we're supposed to be here?
Don't sweat it! It's the perfect chance to snoop around!
You came too, Mouri-san?
Er... Yes...
By the way, Kadowaki-san didn't go home yesterday. Did you see him?
No, but I heard he was picking fights with tourists at the local tavern.
Drinkin' all night, huh?
Huh?
I don't see Naoko-san.
Her name was in the guestbook.
Is Naoko here?
What, Ran-chan? You afraid of thunder?
That's not it!
There's someone outside!
You're right!
What's up?
Ah, Heiji...
There's someone outside!
Say what?!
That's...!
She's been dead less than an hour.
The footprints on the sand are from sandals and boots.
Naoko-san was probably wearin' guest sandals from the house,
so the boots must belong to the killer.
But why would anyone do this to her?
Here's your answer!
Look. Somebody stepped on an Arrow of Dugong.
Judging from the sandal prints,
Naoko-san must've dropped it and stepped on it
while she was struggling with the killer.
So the killer was after the arrow.
Well, if we follow the boot prints, we'll find the killer.
Yeah.
Hey... The prints...
...go straight into the sea!
You're right...
There's something shiny around the prints.
What are they?
Looks like...
Scales...from a fish?
There's a couple scales on Naoko-san's clothes too.
What?
Hey!
What are you doing there?
Investigating the crime...
That's the job of the Fukui Police!
Police?
So you've finally made it.
After that,
the police searched everybody at the funeral,
to see if the killer who stole Naoko-san's arrow was still among us.
But the only people with arrows
were Benzo-san and Kazuha, who'd won them at the festival.
Hey, Kudo. Got any leads?
Not yet.
All I've noticed is that Toshimi-san and Naoko-san, the two confirmed victims,
and Saori-san, who's missing,
all believed in Lady Mikoto's powers
and were obsessed with the Arrow of Dugong.
Yeah. Too obsessed.
If we only knew who had which ticket at last night's festival...
Oh, that's easy!
We have everyone sign a list.
Would you like to come with me now and have a look at the list?
O-Of course!
Careful there!
Geez... Pull yourself together, Dad!
Kimie...
I know this isn't the best time...
but have you thought about what I said?
I'm serious, you know.
I can't.
Not after Toshimi's death.
And I can't leave this island and abandon Great-Grandma.
I'm sorry.
So all five of you went to school together, even college?
Yeah.
We were all big movie fans,
so in college we joined the film club,
and made our own film, The Legend of Bikuni!
When it won the gold medal at a film festival, we were so excited!
We were ready to go to Hollywood!
That's cool!
But in the end, none of us could forget the island.
Who would have thought Toshimi and Naoko would end up like this?
Huh, that's strange.
I'm sure I kept it here...
Isn't it there?
It's gone... Just this year's.
Maybe the ol' lady took it.
That's impossible!
Who else knew the entry books were here?
Most of the locals, I guess.
I'll look through the other rooms.
Let me help you!
M-Me too...
Thank you.
They're all here!
The old foreign minister...
the director of the Secretariat...
the president of the Bank of Japan!
Guess they all wanted to live forever...
Shiho Miyano?
Isn't that... her real name?
Nah, it can't be.
She's not the type who'd care about eternal youth and beauty...
What's the matter?
We just saw her! A woman with light hair and glasses!
She was starin' at us!
You don't mean...
Saori-san?!
Where's Kimie-san?
She said she was going to look through the new warehouse.
Where's the warehouse?
She said it was behind the shrine.
Hey, check out that glow!
I-It couldn't be...
The warehouse kept burning through the night.
It burned to the ground, just like it did three years ago.
Yes, just like three years ago,
there was a body inside.
Half a Day Later
I-I see... Thank you very much.
Well? How'd it go?
They compared the teeth of the burnt body with Kimie-san's dental records.
They were a perfect match.
No...
Kimie-san...
It's not true...
It's not true!
It can't be true!
I see.
So Kimie has died...
I'm sorry, ol' lady.
The killer swooped in the minute we took our eyes off her.
Another innocent young life snuffed out...
while an old fool like me lives on...
Hey, remember when you moved the mermaid's grave?
Who did it for you?
It doesn't matter.
That person has left this world as well...
Hey, old man!
Found anything?
No, nothing.
What kind of case is this?
We don't have a suspect or a motive.
Dad!
What is it, Ran?
Someone just called Kimie-san's place,
and the person on the other end said something weird!
Something weird?
Thank you very much for selling us the arrow.
It was well worth the million yen. Our son's operation was a success!
They bought an arrow?
For a million yen?
They said a man who worked at the shrine sold it to them.
I bet it was that old couple who cancelled their tickets on the morning of the festival.
I think so too.
But who was the guy who sold them the arrow?
They didn't know his name,
but they said he was a big guy, about 50 years old, with a stubby beard.
What did you say?!
Benzo-san?
Benzo-san left last night right after we did?
Yes. He went running out, looking pale.
It's just like I thought. Benzo-san overheard us.
He heard us talkin' about goin' down to Kimie-san's house to look at that notebook,
so he beat us there and stole it.
Now that Kimie-chan has died, I guess this year's Dugong Festival will be the last.
I guess so...
Hey, you!
Could you show us again which footprints are yours?
Yeah, sure.
What the...
What's wrong, Heiji?
A dent on the bottom of the sandal...
It's still fresh...
Kazuha, lend me that arrow of yours, 'kay?
A perfect match.
This is the sandal that stepped on the Arrow of Dugong on the sand.
Which means...
It's just like I thought.
Here's Saori's room...
What's this bag?
What's in it?
Conan-kun!
Saori's run-away kit.
She usually just stayed over at Kimie's place.
She left clothes and an extra pair of glasses there.
Hey, is there a photo of Saori-san around here?
There should be a photo album somewhere.
Ran, was this the person you saw in the garden?
I don't know. It was dark.
Are these photos from the time you guys made your own movie about Bikuni?
Yeah.
Let me see...
This is great!
It really looks like a mermaid's swimming in the sea!
Yeah... And this storm scene looks so real...
The movie won at the film festival
mostly because of Saori's visual effects and Kimie's special-effects make-up.
Wait a sec...
Her account book, bank card, name seal, driver's license and passport are all here,
but I can't find one thing!
It couldn't be...
Don't tell me...!
Hattori here...
Oh, Kudo—I mean, old man!
Perfect timing. I was just about to phone ya!
Remember the sandal prints on the beach?
I found a sandal with a dent mark
from stepping on an arrow.
It proves the killer left the funeral room,
walked out to the fishing net where Naoko-san was waiting,
killed her, then went back to the room again!
The only two people who could've done that were Benzo-san, and Rokuro-san.
But seeing how upset Rokuro-san was that afternoon,
I find it hard to believe he'd hurt Kimie-san.
Which means the killer's gotta be...
Hattori, here's my deduction. Listen to me.
Oh, go ahead.
You idiot! That's crazy talk!
I ain't gonna swallow that!
Hattori...
When you have eliminated the impossible,
whatever remains, however improbable,
must be the truth!
What?
Inspector!
We've located Benzo Kadowaki on the mountain! We're in pursuit!
Good. Let's go, men!
Look, I'll hook up with ya after we arrest Benzo-san!
Just wait for me!
Heiji!
I don't want to believe it either, Hattori...
It's not true! It can't be!
I'm not buyin' it, Kudo!
Huh?
You smell incense?
Ya kiddin' me?
Who'd burn incense up here on the...
Danger - Cliff Ahead
A grave...
The grave of that so-called mermaid...
If that's the case...
The person Kudo fingered...
really is the killer.
The cliff!
Kazuha!
H...
Heiji...
H-Hold on, Kazuha...
I-I'll pull ya up in a sec...
No...
The branch...
It's gonna break...
At this rate, both of us...
I'm sorry, Heiji...
But you've gotta live...
For both of us!
K-Kazuha?!
Bye-bye...
You fool!
Hey, Detective!
I brought you the guy you were asking for.
First, where's the kid from Osaka?
We lost track of him on the mountain.
H-Heiji, why?
Why didn't you let go?
We'll both die if we stay like this...
Let go of my hand...
Kazuha!
D-Don't ya move!
If ya move, I'll kill ya!
Heiji...
What's wrong, Hattori?
Why haven't you shown up?
What're you doing?
C'mon already! How long do we have to wait?
We're busy people, you know.
L-Lady Mikoto?
What's Lady Mikoto doing here?
Well, then. Now that everybody's here, I'd better get started.
Time for the truth behind these three murders.
The first victim, Toshimi-san, was hanged from the Waterfall of the Mermaid.
The second victim, Naoko-san, was strangled and entangled in a fishing net.
And the third victim, Kimie-san, died in the warehouse fire.
To start, let's take a closer look at the second murder.
From the situation at the crime scene,
it looks like the killer walked along the shore to get to and from the crime scene,
with the footprints being washed away by the waves.
The footprints were a trick,
and the killer really snuck in and out of the funeral hall.
And the only people who could've snuck out of the funeral at that time...
...were Rokuro-san and Benzo-san.
It couldn't be...
Let me ask you something, Benzo-san.
On the morning of the festival,
you sold an Arrow of Dugong to an elderly couple for 1,000,000 yen, right?
Yeah. The arrow my daughter Saori won last year.
I'm her guardian, so I got every right to do what I want with it.
That 1,000,000 yen whetted your appetite for more money.
After Toshimi-san won an arrow this year,
you lured her to the top of the waterfall and killed her to steal her winning ticket!
You put her body in an inner tube so it wouldn't get stuck in the river!
But that wasn't all.
Next, Naoko-san, who'd also won an arrow at the festival—
you called her out on the night of the funeral, killed her and stole her arrow!
But if the records at the shrine were checked,
everyone would find out that Toshimi-san's ticket was stolen.
So you went to Kimie-san's house before we got there to steal the notebook,
but Kimie-san caught you, so you locked her in the warehouse and burned it down!
This notebook you had when we caught you is proof!
We found your fingerprints on that inner tube!
No. Benzo-san didn't do it.
If Benzo-san were the killer,
he could've destroyed the notebook in the warehouse fire.
All the locals knew where to find the notebook anyway.
I don't think he'd have to rush over to steal it.
What about his prints on the inner tube?
He probably found the ticket and the inner tube floating in the river.
He must've touched the inner tube while trying to pick up the ticket.
Yeah, the detective's right.
I stole the notebook 'cause I was afraid everybody would think I was the killer
if they knew whose ticket I had.
Then, Rokuro Fukuyama, you must be the killer!
What? That's ridiculous!
No, it wasn't him, either.
What?
The killer used the inner tube trick to hang Toshimi-san.
She'd float down the waterfall without getting caught on anything.
That way it would look like an accident.
But being a fisherman, Rokuro-san has very strong arms,
and Toshimi-san wasn't very heavy,
so it would have been easier for him to just toss her into the river.
He wouldn't have had to use an inner tube, which would only be left behind as evidence.
But if neither of them is the killer, then who is?
The killer made it look like Toshimi-san's death was an accident,
but made no attempt to hide the fact that Naoko-san was murdered.
Do you know what that means?
Well, uh... No, I don't...
When Toshimi-san was killed,
the police didn't arrive right away because the sea was too rough.
Normally, the police would have arrived sometime that night.
And since it was a case of murder,
the investigation would have been intense.
The killer wouldn't have been able to move about freely.
That's why it had to look like an accident.
Which means the killer planned to kill Naoko-san and Toshimi-san from the start.
But no one would have known Naoko had won an arrow until she came forward.
That's right.
The killer's motive wasn't to steal an arrow,
nor was it to kill whoever won it.
It was only made to look that way to mislead the investigation!
You mean...
The reason the killer made it obvious that Naoko-san was murdered
was so that everyone's attention was on the scene of the crime.
The killer used that time to carry out the third murder!
The killer planned and executed each crime very carefully.
It wasn't on a whim.
The only person who could have prepared everything before the festival is...
Y-You don't mean...
Someone who knew beforehand
that Toshimi-san and Naoko-san were going to win arrows.
That's right.
The killer is you!
The killer is you, Lady Mikoto!
You've gotta be kidding!
How could someone who's 130 years old do that?
What if she had an accomplice?
Accomplice?
If neither Rokuro-san nor Benzo-san could have killed Naoko-san,
then the only other person who could have done it
was Kimie-san.
T-That's impossible...
Kimie was the third victim!
What if the victim in the warehouse fire wasn't Kimie-san?
What?
But Kimie-san just told us she went to the dentist!
And those dental records matched the body...
You heard that too, didn't you, Dad?
When Kimie-san said she went to the dentist...
Yes, I heard.
She said she went to a dentist on the mainland with Saori-san.
T-Then...
That's right.
Saori-san was the one with the dental appointment.
Kimie-san went with Saori-san to see the dentist on the mainland.
Kimie-san stole Saori-san's health insurance certificate from her bag in advance,
and offered to let Saori use her own certificate.
That's how Saori-san got her teeth fixed as Kimie-san.
Then Kimie-san killed Saori-san and locked her body in the shrine's warehouse.
She set the warehouse on fire later
so we'd think Kimie-san was the victim when we checked her dental records!
Then the person with light hair and glasses we saw in the garden...
Kimie-san in disguise.
But this is all just guesswork, isn't it?
I phoned the dentist to check.
The Kimie-san he treated had light hair and glasses.
Then Kimie Shimabukuro is still hiding somewhere on this island,
waiting for an opportunity to escape!
Alright then, I'll have this entire island searched from top to bottom!
There's no need for that.
What?
Kimie-san is right here in this room.
Say what?!
Where? Where is she?!
That can't be...
I don't see her anywhere!
You know, don't you, Rokuro-san?
Kimie's make-up skills were good enough to win her a gold medal.
Y-Yeah...
Are you saying she's disguised herself as somebody?
This isn't a movie. It wouldn't work.
Of course, it's hard to pull off a perfect disguise.
But what if it's someone who doesn't show herself to others very much?
And what if the only time everyone sees her is at the festival, when she has on very heavy make-up?
Now your choices have been narrowed down significantly.
T-That's... impossible...
B-But her height...
Think back.
Remember that strange body you found three years ago in the remains of the old warehouse?
The one missing its bones from the waist down,
and the locals said it was a mermaid's body?
It was probably the body of a woman whose legs had been bent and tied behind her.
If my deduction is correct, that woman was Kimie-san's...
My mother.
She took over the Lady Mikoto role from my grandmother,
and kept performing it for the islanders.
It's the sad end of a pitiful woman...
K-Kimie?
I'm impressed, Mr. Detective.
I was pretty confident about this make-up job.
It was that time when we found that the notebook was missing.
Maybe the ol' lady took it.
That's impossible!
You said that without even thinking about it.
I see.
But when we were talking to Lady Mikoto, we heard Kimie-san's voice...
Great-Grandma! Your bath's ready!
Oh, that? I recorded it on tape and played it back.
But why, Kimie?
The three of them and you have been friends since you were kids!
That wasn't enough to stop me from avenging my mother's death.
That fire at the warehouse three years ago...
Exactly.
They didn't win an arrow at the festival,
so they got drunk and set the warehouse on fire,
after seeing my mother, disguised as Lady Mikoto, go inside.
Guess they wanted to see if she really was immortal.
Saori panicked and told me the whole story recently,
the week after she lost her arrow.
But I thought your mother died five years ago while she was out fishing...
She'd been playing Lady Mikoto for a while, and my make-up job was getting better.
We decided to fake her death so she'd only have to play one role.
Then why didn't you tell us after the fire that it was your mother who died?
Mom called me on her cell phone while the flames burned around her...
Kimie... Take care of the people for me...
I love this island...so don't let Lady Mikoto die!
But...
You know what Saori said after losing her arrow?
If I can't have another arrow, tell me where the mermaid is buried!
I want to be like Lady Mikoto!
I want to be immortal, so not even a burning building can kill me!
I couldn't forgive them.
Not Toshimi, not Naoko...
It was easy to get them alone.
I just told them I'd show them where the grave was if they won arrows at the festival.
Their eyes lit up with excitement.
The mermaid's grave is my mother's.
We worked so hard together, all alone...
You weren't alone.
Hattori!
You weren't the only ones who knew the secret of Lady Mikoto.
Ain't that right?
That ol' man said this would be the last festival 'cause Kimie-san had died.
I-I meant...
I'm sorry, Kimie-chan.
Most of the old folks on the island knew the truth.
No...
And we knew it was your mother who died in that fire three years ago.
After the fire, we talked it over and decided to tell you to end the festival.
But after seeing you disguised as Lady Mikoto,
we couldn't bring ourselves to say anything.
After all, this is Mermaid Island.
And if you wanted to continue Lady Mikoto...
We decided to keep quiet, and help whenever we could...
We know you did it for the island. We're sorry.
Forgive us, Kimie-chan...
No... No...
Why couldn't you have told me before?
Yeah, you guys needed to snap out of it.
Immortality ain't nothin' but a nightmare.
Life's valuable 'cause it's short.
We gotta do our best with the time we got.
Right, Kazuha?
In the morning,
everybody from the island came out to see Kimie-san off to the Fukui police station.
But a storm at sea stopped the ship from leaving,
as if refusing to part with the shrine maiden who had supported the island alone
for three long years.
Hey, Hattori-kun, show me the wound!
W-What's gotten into you?
What? Come on...
That's the wound of love that Kazuha-chan marked you with!
H-Hey, Ran-chan!
Oh, that.
The scab had already come off when I woke up this mornin'.
It's all healed up now.
No way!
I should've stabbed you deeper...
Hey, what?
But I'm glad your hand's better.
Now I don't have to listen to you whine about it anymore!
Kazuha-chan, wait up!
That dope.
She got me all fired up back there.
I'm never...
I'm never gonna let anything happen to that girl.
Quit trying to look tough.