Hooligan
"Hooligan."
An outlaw who commits violent and destructive acts in soccer stadiums.
They cause a nuisance, but even so,
they shouldn't have their life stolen from them.
Today, let's play back a case where a proud, violent hooligan was murdered!
If cases were all men,
then I wonder if the unseen puzzles would be women?
Hooligans are troublesome,
in the guise of being soccer fans.
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Tōkyō Spirits vs. Noir Tōkyō!
The score's still tied at 0.
Sounds like we may need to go to extra time.
Wait! The ball was passed to Hide!
Go! Go!
One...
Two...
Three...
Four!
Go for it, Hide! Shoot!
Now Hide's one-on-one in front of the goal! Will he shoot like this?
But the Noir defenders aren't making it easy!
They rush him from behind!
The keeper came out!
The defenders close in too!
Will Hide still shoot?
Oh, he passed it to the side!
And ahead of the ball...
It's Naoki!
Goal!
Naoki's explosive heading shot breaks the tie!
And that's the match's final whistle!
During injury time in the second half, with Naoki's goal, the Tōkyō Spirits defeated Noir Tōkyō,
and have won the Tōkyō Derby...
It's awesome, Hide dribbled through four players!
Yeah!
And everybody on the main stand was excited!
Dodging from right to left like that,
he looked like Baggio!
Naoki was pretty awesome, too!
After all, he'd already jumped
even before Hide passed!
Hide and Naoki:
The perfect revival of the golden combo!
But I had no idea
the Spirits were gonna have such a hard time...
I was afraid we'd go to extra time...
Couldn't be helped.
Noir Tōkyō's best players are injured,
and since the center-forward Higo
signed up for Big Ōsaka,
they're lacking in powerful players.
They toughened up their defense from the start, trying for a draw.
Speaking of Higo...
The other match between Noir and Big Ōsaka was pretty awesome too...
Yeah... but they booed Higo every time he got the ball.
But why did their supporters boo him too?
Isn't it obvious?
After all, there's no place for traitors.
Hey...
Isn't it true?
He's hated by both friend and foe alike, isn't he?
Noir and Big have been rivals for a long time.
The Big supporters can't cheer honestly for a forward who they've seen as an enemy until now.
Besides, even after five matches, Higo still hasn't scored a goal.
Now that I think about it, I remember seeing Higo in a sports newspaper.
"Is he going to Spain?", it said.
Yeah, it was on the sports news too.
They said he signed up with Big to increase the price of his contract when he went to Spain.
What an awful guy...
Hey, hey, take it easy.
It's just a rumour.
But if the rumour is right, then he'll probably be much better off.
It's his chance to forget everything and escape to a place where the booing won't reach.
Just kidding.
Hey.
I think there's a Big match today, too.
Yeah, they'll broadcast it on Nichiuri TV at 5 PM.
Hey! The match's started!
Where? Where?
There is tremendous booing. The source is, of course, Ryūsuke Higo.
Hmph. Serves him right.
That's what happens when you betray us at Noir Tōkyō.
Once you've fallen to Hell, you'll never get out.
Kadotake Akano (48)
Noir Tōkyō Supporter
Hey.
Where have I seen that guy before...?
I saw him in the news on TV!
He tends to get drunk on the field,
fires off smoke rockets at the field, and starts big fights. I think his name was...
Kadotake Akano.
He's a staunch supporter of Noir Tōkyō,
a stupid old man who's proud to be a hooligan.
He's even been blacklisted, and isn't allowed entrance in many stadiums.
What's a "hooligan"?
Obnoxious supporters in Europe who start fights during matches.
That old guy even has a "Tōkyō Hooligan" home page.
He even keeps a diary saying things like what he's done to other supporters on it.
Though I guess he can't do much if they won't let him in the stadiums.
Doc...
Speaking of homepages, did you check that one?
Hey, the one I asked you to look into the other day.
That American movie star's homepage, Chris Vineyard.
Yeah. Like you told me to, Shin'ichi,
I went into the chat and asked fans some questions.
And?
I didn't learn much.
Her mother, Sharon Vineyard, was quite famous...
But the daughter Chris's private life is covered by a veil of mystery.
The only time she appeared in front of the media, other than for photos,
was that day, a year ago.
"That" day?
Her mother Sharon's funeral.
They even aired stuff about it on the Japanese news, remember?
Yeah...
Apparently a particularly unscrupulous reporter snuck into the funeral,
and kept bugging her with questions like...
"What school did you go to?"
"Did you really not get along with your mother?"
"Who's your real father?"
"Do you have a boyfriend? Did he come with you to the funeral?"
But she made no comment.
And frustrated at her attitude,
a reporter asked "Are you trying to hide something?"
She then turned her back to her mother's coffin, and with a slight smile on her face she flatly answered...
"A secret makes a woman woman."
A secret is what makes a woman a woman, huh?
Then, is it true?
Is Chris Vineyard really with the men in black?
Dunno.
I don't have any proof yet. But if it's true...
What happens if it's true?
She'd be a tough enemy to deal with.
Tough?
Hey, Shin'ichi...
You don't happen to be hiding something from me, are you?
I mean, because she's a good actress, it'd be hard to corner her with deductions.
Anyway, shouldn't we be on the train home by now?
You're right.
Hey, guys! We're going home!
Wait!
It's just getting good!
Don't worry.
I brought the radio.
Really?
Let's go!
Okay.
Hey, Haibara-san, we're off.
What's with this train?
It's full of fans of the Spirits and Noir.
That's why I said we should take the next train.
But you were in a hurry to get home...
I wanted to watch the Big match in my TV at home.
Oh, geez...
That hurts, ya moron!
Just 'cause ya won don't mean ya get to push people around!
I can't help it, the train's full...
That old guy's on the same train as us?
No way...
If we don't bring attention to ourselves, he'll probably leave us alone.
True, but...
Haibara-san...
Hey, how's the match?
Right...
It's still 0-0, and we're entering the first half's injury time.
And is Big's number 9 still on the field?
If you mean Higo, he's still out...
But the booing is so loud, that his teammates hesitate to pass to him.
I see...
Umm, Haibara-san?
If something happens in the match, let me know.
Yes, of course.
What!?
Haido, Haido...
Passengers transferring to the Haido subway line change here.
One stab to the stomach with a knife.
Hey, what happened, Conan?
Doc! Get an ambulance and the police!
Got it!
Can I make it in time?
Sir! -san'?}
Don't move this train!
A man's been stabbed!
What!?
Also, please call the ticket control barriers connected to this platform,
and ask them to check all the tickets from Tōkyō Spirits and Noir Tōkyō supporters trying to leave!
Supporters? Tickets?
Yeah. Stop anyone who has a ticket bought before 5 PM from leaving.
But why?
Just do it! If you don't, the killer might get away!
The victim is Kadotake Akano, 48.
The murder weapon was a knife with a 15 cm blade, found at the scene.
(6 inch)
At the time of the murder, there were a lot of passengers on the train,
but no witnesses.
Haven't I seen this man somewhere?
Probably on TV.
TV?
This man was a rather rude supporter,
and appeared often on TV.
I see...
The knife's handle and scabbard both have a rather unusual design.
If we can track its purchase...
About that, I've already asked about that,
and that knife is apparently rare and foreign. It's also not sold in Japan.
It will take a long time to find where it could've been purchased.
I see...
But if a person was stabbed in a train,
how come nobody saw it?
It's natural.
Because the train was packed full.
Y-You...
When we got to the station, everyone rushed out, and that man collapsed.
That was when we noticed someone had been stabbed.
Inspector Megure?
You guys again!?
Anyway, did you see anyone suspicious?
I can't remember. Everybody was dressed the same!
Dressed the same?
A soccer match just ended,
so the train was full of supporters from the two teams.
In that case...
there's a good chance the killer left the station,
or switched to another train.
Yeah, but...
I explained to three passengers what happened, and asked them to stay.
And how did you select those three passengers?
Well, I was really just following what this kid told me...
And "this kid..."
...could it be...
Conan-kun?
Knew it.
But why those three?
It was easy!
You don't just decide to stab someone on a train, right?
That's when I remembered.
The killer must've known Akano-san was going to travel in this train filled with supporters.
Then he must've stabbed Akano-san with the knife just before arriving at this station,
where he knew a lot of people would rush out, then mixed in with the passengers to try and escape.
So basically, it's a premeditated murder.
Yeah.
That's why I asked the supervisor to not let anyone dressed like either of the teams leave.
But why supporters?
Because the train was filled with them!
You wouldn't stand out much if you were dressed as one!
Then only three supporters tried to leave the station?
No, there were around fifty...
Then the numbers don't match.
It's the ticket.
The ticket?
To stab Akano-san, the killer had to follow him and get on the same train, right?
Therefore, the killer had to buy the return ticket in advance.
If he tried to buy a ticket after the match, the line would be crowded with supporters,
and if he tried to buy a ticket then, he would've lost Akano-san.
The match ended at 5 PM.
Basically, only three people had a ticket marked before 5 PM and tried to leave.
I see...
But what if the killer changed clothes before leaving the station?
Or transferred to the train on the opposite platform without trying to leave?
That's not very likely.
He'd look pretty suspicious if he changed clothes on the platform.
And this station's toilet is outside the ticket control barrier.
There wouldn't be a lot of supporters on another platform, so someone could remember him.
While waiting for the train, the police could've caught him.
The safest way would be:
Leave the station with all the supporters,
change clothes in the toilet, and escape.
A lot of passengers get off at Haido Station to transfer onto the subway, after all.
You have a point.
Conan-kun...
I always end up wondering this but...
...just how are you so intelligent?
You deduced all of this the instant you saw the body,
and gave the supervisor instructions, right?
Ah, no...
It wasn't me!
It was the doctor!
I was just following the doctor's instructions!
I see. It was you, Agasa-san.
Oh, right...
Isn't it obvious?
He was just following my instructions.
There's no way a kid could deduce a crime.
This is totally embarrassing...
And have you figured out who did it?
I assume you at least have some idea, right?
Ah, well, that's...
Uh, what did I tell Conan-kun to do after that...
Oh, geez...
Oh right, doc,
you said you'd listen to them after the police arrived!
The three people who the supervisor retained, that is.
Hold on!
You're treating us like criminals just because we bought a ticket at a certain time?
I bought the return ticket ahead of time so I could avoid the crowds later.
Same.
Me too.
But all three of you went on a train full of supporters, right?
If you bought a ticket ahead of time, why didn't you get on a train before it got crowded?
Because...
After the match,
Hasue Kira (24)
Noir Tōkyō Supporter
I got into an argument with a Spirits supporter,
and ended up being late to the station.
I was in the main stand where the Spirits and Noir supporters were grouped together!
I got a phone call from work before the end of the match,
Mitsuaki Funato (33)
Tōkyō Spirits Supporter
since they found out I was skipping work.
They yelled at me a lot, so I couldn't go home.
Because of that, I even missed the two wingers' winning goal.
Etsutoshi Ōba (29)
Noir Tōkyō Supporter
Even though the match had ended,
I was in such shock I couldn't even stand up.
When Hide dribbled past the defenders and approached,
and Naoki scored the goal,
I just went blank...
And which train car were you on?
I don't remember that kind of stuff!
But I'm sure all three of them were on a crowded car.
Well, see...
On your right elbow, there's a mark from the ring on your left hand.
That means you carried your bag on your right shoulder for a long time,
and held the bag shut with your left hand, right?
The watch mark on the long-haired guy's right arm is proof he had his arms crossed a long time.
And the guy with the glasses has marks on his palms,
from holding a bag really hard with both hands, right?
The only time you'd pose like that and not hold onto the straps would be on a crowded train.
And since the train was already full when we arrived, you couldn't find a seat.
Was that all correct?
Yeah...
They say there's a lot of thefts on crowded trains.
I didn't want to be mistaken for a pervert if I didn't keep my arms crossed.
Amazing! It's just like the doc said!
Either way, we know you were in a crowded car.
I'd like it if you could remember what car you were on.
Then if you would please come with me to the car where the crime took place...
I gotta get back to the company...
Really, what is it now?
Eh?
Why is that person...
We have three suspects.
The only thing we know for sure is that they all rode in a packed train car.
But that's not enough to conclude anything.
There's gotta be something... There's gotta be something more!
Some other clue to solve the case!
Kanashii hodo kyō no yūhi kirei da ne
(Today's sunset is so pretty it's sad)
Higo was knocked down!
Listen to the audience's cheering.
Has Higo been forsaken by all who supported him? Is there no field in Japan where Higo can play?
Hold on...
If I recall correctly, today's Tōkyō Derby was...
As I thought...
(Digital Remaster)
On the next Conan: "The Hooligan Mystery (Part II)"
Next Conan's Hint: The goal scene.
Look forward to the next episode!