Geez, Dad!
You left before you finished reading your newspaper,
without finishing your coffee,
and without even turning off the TV!
Hello, everybody! Reporting live from New York!
Behold!
Isn't it amazing?
New York...
Hearing that name...
...always makes me feel a faint pain in my chest.
The case I ran into in that city
was bitter, like a coffee filled with lies,
and with its bad aftertaste,
I ended up locking it out my memory.
The Goddess of Liberty!
Or "Miss Liberty," as a New Yorker would call it!
But I remember everything now.
It faintly warms the bottom of my heart,
along with those precious words...
Ran-neechan?
Dr. Agasa sent me to get some apples, but...
A mysterious new era now begins...
...a Monday 7 o'clock deduction show!
Ran and Shin'ichi's New York trip.
The memory of cold rain and tears...
...holds an unforgettable message!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Wait...
Isn't that...
"Statue of Liberty."
Or the "Goddess of Liberty," as we call it in Japan.
Though a New Yorker'd call it "Miss Liberty."
But why didn't you wake me up?
I'd been looking forward to seeing the view of Manhattan from the Brooklyn Bridge.
And we're almost done going through it...
Hey...
If you'd slept on the plane,
you wouldn't have fallen asleep now.
Now, now, you two.
This place is the greatest date spot, and the delight of lovers throughout the world.
And you're arguing on it? I'm jealous.
It's your fault, mom.
We weren't supposed to be in New York until tomorrow.
You're the one who made us get on another plane as soon as we reached Los Angeles.
Didn't have a choice.
I suddenly managed to get tickets to a musical that I'd given up on.
Oh? A musical?
Look, that one.
The Golden Apple? I hear it's popular right now.
Right. At Broadway's Phantom Theater.
At 8 PM.
It's going to be so fun!
Aren't there a lot more patrol cars than before?
Yeah. They're probably after the serial killer.
Killer?
A serial killer that only targets young girls.
They say he's Japanese, but I dunno.
Don't worry.
That man apparently only attacks after midnight.
So long as we get to the hotel before then, we'll be safe.
And it's not even six o' clock.
Don't you mean seven? Because of Summer Time.
I forgot about Summer Time!
What are you so nervous about?
You can easily get from this bridge to Broadway by car in 40 minutes.
It's not quite seven yet. We have time, right?
You see, I have to see the one who got me the tickets...
If we get there an hour earlier, we can visit the backstage.
Then you might as well give up.
Hey!
What do you think you're doing?
There's tons of patrol cars here!
It's all right. They're on the other side of the road.
By the way, Shin-chan, can you and Ran-chan do that?
This part's a bit complicated...
...okay?
If you please...?
Geez...
All right!
Well, Ran, can you come here for a bit?
What?
Wait, Sh-Shin'ichi...
Hold on tight!
Wasn't that big a deal, right?
How is this not a big deal!?
Exactly an hour left.
See? We're right on time, no sweat.
I hope this isn't over me...
Your license and registration, please!
OK, OK!
40 miles over the speed limit! Are you playing Dirty Harry?
Oh, we were in a hurry...
You look familiar.
Well, you might...
You might have met her in some case.
Because she works with us.
Captain!?
She's an undercover agent.
She seems to have missed the criminal...
Who is this man?
Radish.
Yūsaku met him at the end of a case.
He's the Captain of the New York Police, Radish Redwood.
Thank you, Radish. You saved me.
No, no.
You're thanking the wrong person.
The wrong person...?
If you want to thank someone...
...thank me.
Sharon Vineyard.
Sha... Sharon!
Why...
That police agent is a fan of mine.
I was talking to him while waiting for you when it came over his radio.
That a silver Jaguar was coming here at an unbelievable speed.
That's when I had the idea to disguise myself as Inspector Radish.
You better be thankful.
His coat was quite expensive, after all.
H-Hey, mom, tell me.
Who's she?
Shin'ichi, you don't know her? She's one of America's most famous actresses!
That's why...
Why is such a famous actress disguising as an inspector?
Oh? Didn't I tell you?
When I'd just started working as an actress,
I got a part as a spy girl.
And for that role,
I learned some disguise skills from Japan's most famous magician.
She'd gotten a similar role, so she was learning from the same magician, too.
Well, I can disguise myself as someone else just as well as Sharon.
But every time you put one of those things on, it looked more like a clown suit than a disguse.
Sorry if it's not good enough for you. I did my best.
But it's amazing, meeting someone so famous.
Especially here in New York!
I should thank God for it.
Does this world even have a God?
If He really did exist...
...then people who worked hard on what they like would be rewarded with happiness, right?
Right...
At least, no angel ever smiled on me.
Not even once...
Lila Sanchez (32)
Stage Actress
If it isn't Sharon! You really made it!
Akane Nilsen (27)
Stage Actress
I guess our director does say the truth sometimes...
Rose Hewitt (28)
Stage Actress
How exciting, I feel like I'm dreaming!
Everybody admires her.
Yeah. She's friends with the theater's director.
Oh? Could she be...
Right.
The popular female TV detective...
The Night Baroness!
Yes!
Night Baroness
"Night Baroness?"
That's what they call Mom here.
Since she's the wife of the Night Baron's creator, Yūsaku Kudō.
And she was once invited to a local investigation show on TV,
since she's married to a deduction genius and all.
She analyzed the crime then, and everything she said fit,
so they arrested the criminal right away.
Though, that deduction was really just repeating what Dad said
every day when reading the morning paper.
Then those two are your kids?
He is, but she's not.
Well, she might be my future daughter-in-law.
How marvelous!
Congratulations.
My, my.
And here I thought the Night Baroness'd come to solve
the mystery of the strange present.
But I see she's only here to greet us.
Everith Hamilton (30)
Stage Actress
What a disappointment.
Strange present?
Three days ago, a packet was delivered to the company.
An apple covered in gold spray. A Golden Apple.
With a message in animal blood: "For the Fairest."
«For the Fairest»
I see.
That explains why I felt so much tension when I entered this room.
Now, now, calm down, my goddesses.
Heath Flockhart (33)
Stage Actor
It's probably just a prank.
But Heath...
Who's he?
This theater company's top star, Heath Flockhart.
But since he got a part in a movie, today's his last theater play.
But is this really all right? There's only 40 minutes left, should we be doing this?
Don't worry. The first 20 minutes of the play are a narration,
where the narrator talks about Greek mythology.
What's that up there?
The costumes for the play.
They're up there so they won't get in the way.
Look out!
The armor!
No!
Ran!
You okay, Ran?
I knew it! Someone... someone's after my life!
I don't think so... The rope must have broken since it's so old.
Geez, who put such an old armor up there?
But it could've been worse.
We're lucky that large mirror wasn't broken.
It's our guardian angel.
Hold on, you two. You shouldn't be thanking a mirror or any god.
You should be thanking her.
Thank you! You saved me!
You're welcome...
By the way, we need to get ready.
We'll see you after the play.
Sure!
I cut myself...
Here.
I knew it, there's no such thing as God.
If God existed, this wouldn't have happened.
I'm going home, Yukiko.
Not staying to watch the play, Sharon?
There's gonna be a terrible storm tonight, so...
I'll be going.
It's gorgeous!
It is, isn't it?
You don't see shows like this in Japan.
But someone doesn't seem to agree.
Hey! At least try to pay attention!
What's so interesting about it?
All they did was turn a Greek myth into a romantic comedy.
Then what Greek myth is this based on?
The Golden Apple.
A long time ago, there were three goddesses: Hera, Athena and Aphrodite.
They were invited to a banquet,
but Eris, who wasn't invited,
got jealous and sent the three a golden apple with a message...
"For the Fairest."
Then, back then...
Yeah.
Anyway, the three goddesses decided that
the prince of Troy should choose who should get the apple.
Each of them tried to bribe him with promises if he picked her...
See, the guy we met before is playing the unfortunate prince of Troy.
The actress playing the wife of the rich man is Zeus' wife,
Hera, the goddess of matrimony who promised him he'd be the world's most powerful man.
The Japanese-looking actress with a lot of character is Athena,
the goddess of wisdom who promised him victory in the war.
And that sexy actress is the goddess of beauty,
Aphrodite, who promised him the world's most beautiful woman.
And the one in the last scene with the grim look, who was jealous of the other three
is the one who gave them the golden apple: Eris, the goddess of strife.
But that's the Greek myth.
This musical is quite different.
When you see the prince's identity...
...you're going to be surprised.
Behold, sinful humans.
I am Michael!
Michael? The arch-angel?
You've gotta be kiddin'.
Carefully listen to my answer.
What!?
Mom, take care of Ran!
Shin-chan!
Damn it...
Figured I wouldn't make it in time.
A bullet casing?
This is...
This show is brought to you by these sponsors.
He was shot straight in the heart.
The bullet's lodged into the wings in his back.
The wings in his back?
You mean this?
From the bullet's entry wound, I'd say he was shot from a 40º angle.
40º...
That's a pretty sharp angle.
Of course.
Because the killer was probably up on that terrace.
He used a laser sight to aim.
The Night Baroness?
Is that you, Yukiko?
What are you doing here?
I just happened to be watching the play.
I had no idea the musical would turn into a mystery.
He was shot during the climax where the angel appears.
During that scene, smoke is released,
The actor is lifted while the projection in the mirror slides up,
making it look like he's emerging from the mirror.
It's set up in a way to make it look real.
So basically, the killer shot him from that terrace as he was rising from the mirror?
After that, he threw the gun onto the stage,
to cause a panic, and therefore be able to escape.
But are you sure about this? The killer being in the terrace, I mean.
Of course. Thanks to the smoke on-stage,
I could clearly see a red beam of light pointing to the stage from the terrace.
My son saw it too.
So you're the real one.
So this is the son you're always talking about, Shin'ichi?
Yeah, isn't he Yūsaku's spitting image?
They're just as big pranksters, too.
Captain?
Hold on.
What is it?
Hey, Shin-chan.
Please behave yourself.
Yeah, yeah.
Yukiko!
Seems you were right.
A suspicious person reserved every seat in the terrace a month ago.
But this person was wearing a scarf and hat, so we don't even know if it was a man or a woman.
Then that must be the killer.
But why pick that seat?
Aren't those seats expensive?
The angle from that terrace isn't very good, so they're probably cheap.
And it's easy to leave an impression if someone with their face hidden asks for an entire area,
which is exactly what the killer wanted.
But I don't get it.
What are these two strange marks?
Strange marks?
Yeah, in the neck. Doesn't it look like a burn?
And there's blood in his right hand.
Could the blood be from grabbing his chest after he was shot?
No...
The problem is that it's smudged, like someone tried to clean it.
He must have touched his hand somewhere after it got bloody,
but there's nothing in his clothes, nor is there anything he could've touched in the air.
So, has the Night Baroness solved this mystery?
Ehh... Not yet.
What? The killer's one of the four actresses?
That can't be.
Right as this case took place, I ran over to the terrace.
I found a bullet casing, but it wasn't hot.
This proves someone planted it in advance.
But you saw it too, right?
A laser sight's red light coming from the terrace to the stage.
Yeah, I saw it.
But we can't know which it was coming from or which it was aimed at.
Right.
That laser sight was probably aimed not from the terrace, but from the stage.
In order to make us believe the gunshot came from there.
In other words, the masked person purchasing the tickets, and the strange present
were just a ruse to lead us to suspect someone was threatening the actresses.
I see...
Of course, this is part of the trick, too.
This is where that armor fell before the play started, right?
Look carefully at the floor.
There's a fishing line tied to a nail.
And next to it, there's a mark, as if something had been cut.
It looks like the fishing line was attached to the armor.
Then someone did it intentionally?
Yeah. The killer probably had a knife or similar in his shoe, and used it to cut the line,
bringing down the armor.
The killer knew that we, Sharon's friends, would come this way during the guided tour.
That means that the killer is one of those who was with us when the armor fell,
as well as one of the actresses who was on-stage with Heath.
That way, she could aim the laser sight at the terrace, as well as shoot him.
One of the four goddesses.
It could be any of them.
Hey, is that true, Lila?
Yeah.
Heath and I were dating.
For about five years now.
Then you were dating my boyfriend behind my back?!
Calm down, you two!
You shouldn't be talking about this in a day like this!
My...
You should be the angriest of them all.
Since your boyfriend apparently had two others.
Then... Rose too?
You were dating him too?
I see.
Apparently all four had a motive for killing Heath.
What do you mean?
I understand that he was involved with all three, but...
What reason does Everith have?
Unlike the other three, she doesn't have a photo of him on her mirror.
Actually, Heath and Everith were married.
Sharon told me while we were touring around the place.
They kept it secret even from the other actresses, in case it might affect their popularity.
But right now, we have to figure out how the killer shot him from that height.
Rose was the closest one to the mirror,
but she was acting as if she'd collapsed from seeing the angel.
Everith was sitting,
and Akane was on her knees as if praying.
The one who could shoot from the highest was Lila who was standing and holding her head,
but unlike the other three, her hands weren't hidden by the smoke.
People would've noticed if she'd pulled out a gun.
Could Heath have been crouching?
That's impossible.
Those wings were bound to his feet, making it completely impossible for him to crouch.
Hey, Shin'ichi? Have you thought of something?
Wait, Shin'ichi!
You thought of something, right?
Tell me what you came up with.
Sorry, but could you put this on your head and stand in front of the mirror for a bit?
Wait, Shin'ichi.
What are you trying to prove with this?
H-Hey...
A crack...
kizu
There's a crack.
A crack?
Look, up there.
There's a tiny crack.
That's odd. This mirror's been with the theater for years, and was their guardian angel,
and they'd supposedly get bad luck if they broke it.
That's what Sharon said.
Hey, hey...
It looks like they glued it together. Were they really taking care of it?
Doesn't this curtain look a bit twisted?
Maybe somebody ran into it when trying to get away.
A feather?
How did it get stuck in here?
This flip door isn't used for anything.
Blood!
I see. I understand it now.
The killer used this stage's tricks to commit the crime.
A bloody murder, committed by someone as crafty as the goddess Eris.
This show is brought to you by these sponsors.
From those positions, you four couldn't have shot him from above.
Then can we go change?
Yes, the GSR test came back negative.
Who turned off the lights?
It was me, it was me.
The Night Baroness!
Sorry, shine the light here.
Yukiko...
Hey, mom, try not to screw up the deduction.
Don't worry, I'll say everything exactly as you told me.
Geez...
Hey, are you sure about your deduction?
If you're wrong, then your mom's going to be really embarrassed!
Yeah.
Don't you think it's strange?
Heath's height was 6 feet and 3 inches, about 1.90 meters.
About the same height as you, when you put that pamphlet over your head.
And when I measured you, the pamphlet was visible over the mirror.
Furthermore, Heath's head would've stuck out, since couldn't crouch with those wings,
which means he couldn't fit behind the mirror.
That's why the killer made use of something in the stage.
The actors use it to appear and disappear from the stage.
A trap door.
But there was no trap door behind the mirror.
Only thing that was there was a weird iron thing on the floor.
Moron.
If there's an iron door, then there's gotta be a hole under it.
One of the feathers from Heath's wings was caught in it,
causing his blood to make two semi-circles below it.
And taking into account the donut-shaped floor
and the twisted curtains, there's only one possible solution.
All you have to do is shift the donut-shaped floor...
and the hole will appear.
I'm sure that if they check it,
they'll find more feathers, blood from Heath,
and the bullet casing from the gun.
You mean he was shot at close range?
Yeah. Heath was waiting in the hole for his scene,
so the killer waited for him to come up and shot him.
The door was set against the back of the mirror,
so she just had to put the gun below the mirror and through the grid.
Then the killer's...
Right. Only one person could do it.
The one lying down next to the mirror...
Rose, it was you.
Rose!?
No way... it can't be!
None of us were told that the trap door was going to be used!
That can be explained. It's because...
They didn't tell you because they couldn't.
That the mirror that everyone saw as their guardian angel, was broken...
Rose must have damaged it in secret.
When the staff saw it was damaged,
they cut off the damaged part and glued it back together,
so the actors wouldn't notice the damage.
But due to the shorter frame, Heath's head stuck out.
If they'd put it on a platform, the actors would've noticed something's wrong.
That's why they decided to use the trap door and hide Heath's body.
And that's why they hid it from all but Heath and Rose.
But why would the staff tell Rose?
They had to. Moving the donut-shaped floor would hide the hole, but not the door.
Unless Rose closed the door from below the mirror, the audience would've seen the door.
Then what about the gun?
The gun fell from above, right?
She couldn't have done that if she was lying down.
It can be done.
If you consider that the angel, Heath, was going to be suspended.
Remember how Heath had a burn mark on his chest?
That's because Rose put the gun in his suit right after firing it.
Riding on his clothes, it would've fallen off from the recoil when he stopped being raised.
What she didn't count on, was for him to grab her hand while doing so.
The blood on his hand being smudged proves it.
So it should still be there... On her right arm, inside her right glove.
Heath's resentful, bloody handprint.
She likely put her gloves on inside out.
And after shooting him, she put them back.
That way, she'd be able to pass a GSR test.
But Shin'ichi, how did you know there was blood under the glove?
Because in the dressing room,
she was going through a lot of effort to open the can of juice with the gloves on.
All she'd have to do would be take off her glove.
But she didn't, which told me she was hiding something.
Well, that's when I found out her motive for killing Heath, too.
Motive?
Lila and Akane had pictures on their mirrors, right?
They were alone with Heath on them.
But in Rose's pictures...
Angel.
Just pictures of Heath dressed as an angel.
She wasn't actually in love with him,
but with his role as an angel.
Yeah. That's why I sealed his life while he was Michael.
I couldn't stand the idea of another man playing him.
I couldn't allow it!
But he was only leaving the role because he got a part in a movie...
But it was his choice.
He killed Michael.
When I told him I loved the angel he was playing!
But I was blessed by God, anyway.
Since He saved me when my dress got caught on a nail and the armor fell.
Thank you, sweet angel...
You helped me do it...
What's wrong, Ran?
Don't tell me you're like that over what Rose said.
You understood what she said?
She was speaking English so quickly I couldn't understand it.
Nothing important, wasn't much.
Also, close your window or you'll catch a cold.
Didn't you say you felt feverish?
I'm fine now.
And if I closed the window, I couldn't see the lights of New York.
But if the rain gets in here and wets the seats, the cabby's gonna get angry.
Don't worry. I'll wipe the seat with my handkerchief before leaving.
Oh geez.
Excuse me, please stop.
Stop, please!
Strange...
I could've sworn it'd fallen here.
Was it blown away by the wind?
Forget about it.
Isn't it just a handkerchief, anyway?
It's not just a handkerchief!
It's very important, Sharon gave it to me!
I knew it, there's no such thing as God.
Isn't that it?
Look, the white thing in those stairs.
Seems to be an abandoned building.
I'll be right back.
Wait for me in the taxi, Ran.
If God existed, this wouldn't have happened.
Thank you, sweet angel...
You helped me do it...
Could Sharon have known...?
That Rose was going to commit murder, and that I'd saved a murderer...?
What now?
It's all my fault.
If I hadn't saved her back then, Heath would still be...
It's all my fault!
It's all my...
A gun...
No...
My body won't move...
Hey! Hurry up. Jump in!
He must be the serial killer, come on!
Shit!
Wait!
Are you Japanese?
I asked, "Are you Japanese?"
Yes.
Have you seen a suspicious man?
A Japanese man with long silvery hair and a beard.
No...
I haven't seen anyone.
Did you find him, sir?
No... I found only a tourist.
Anyway, this place is dangerous.
Take a right in this corner and you should get to the main street.
You can take a taxi from there.
Wait...
I'm waiting for a friend.
He's a boy my age.
Then I'll tell you and your friend this yet again.
Get out of here!
Get out of this area, right now!
Can we leave her alone?
No problem.
Every crossing to this street is already secured.
Then it's true.
The serial killer's here.
Hurry, Shin'ichi, we have to run!
Shin'ichi?
Hey...
What was that?
I just saw something red...
Blood!
Could it be Shin'ichi's...?
What happened here?
What happened to Shin'ichi?
Shin'ichi!
Oh no, my cold's back.
Come on, Ran! Gotta hold on for a bit more...
It's your fault Shin'ichi went to get that handkerchief!
Right... It's all... it's all my fault.
It's all my...
Somebody's coming!
Shin'ichi?
Si... Silver hair?
Blood...
Get away, Ran!
He's the serial killer!
That's right, girl.
If you want to blame someone, blame God for putting you in this position.
What are you doing?
Quick, grab my arm!
Quick, the rain's...
Shin'ichi...
Damn, you really are trouble.
Why?
Why did you save me?
I don't understand it.
Do you need a reason?
I don't know what can lead a person to kill another...
But for a person to save another...
...you don't really need a logical reason, do you?
I see...
He's right, isn't he?
I should've realized earlier...
Really...
I'm...
Hey, Ran!
Stop that.
You're injured, so the cops are nearby.
If you shoot us without a silencer, you'll get caught.
Similarly, I can't do anything to catch you.
I'll let you go for now.
I'll catch you next time we meet.
I'll find all the proof necessary to send you to Hell.
I'll make sure you're put away.
Yeah, didn't you see it in the news on TV?
They found the serial killer.
Shin-chan reported him.
But when the police got there,
he'd already killed himself with his own gun...
Oh, Ran-chan's fine.
She had a fever last night,
but after getting some rest, she's much better.
She's pretty much forgotten about what happened yesterday.
Hey, Sharon...
Did you know?
That Rose was going to do something like that?
Yes. I've always had a sixth sense for these things.
But I had no idea she was going to kill someone.
By the way, can you give Ran-chan a message from me?
She was right. There is an angel watching over me.
Oh, did something good happen to you?
Sort of.
You're not having a relapse from the cold, are you?
No, I'm fine.
Let me just check your temperature...
I told you I'm fine...
What is it, Ran-neechan?
Oh, nothing.
Just remembering something...
Remembering what?
It's a se-cre-t!
What, what?
Well, what should I make for dinner tonight?
Wait, Ran-neechan!
For a person to save another...
...you don't really need a logical reason, do you?
Right.
It was then that my feelings for Shin'ichi really...