A shining step toward a glorious future.
Of course, my heart's ready!
The secrets of the organisation hidden in many veils are revealed one by one!
A life-threatening suspense!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Seaside moon Seaside sky
itsumademo kawaranu kokoro o mō ichido kimi ni todoketai
Glorious Mind
Incoming Call
Number withheld
So, give me the reason why
Incoming Call
Number withheld
Leave me here alone
The reason why I don't know how I feel
So must be the true baby
Shall we end it then it's up to me
Tomorrow is a different day, yeah
And I know when I'm ready
Glorious Mind Glorious Sky
omoikiri naitara kinō made no koto wa zembu wasureyō
Seaside moon Seaside sky
itsumademo kawaranu kokoro o mō ichido kimi ni todoketai
Glorious Mind
I don't know the Black Organisation's aim yet.
What I do know is this:
They commit many assassinations in order to gather a large amount of money,
they had people such as Haibara create an odd drug,
and they're gathering talented computer programmers.
It seems that Suguru Itakura-san, a systems engineer
who the Mouri Detective Agency was requested to find,
is connected to a member of the Organisation, Tequila.
We finally found his location,
but Itakura-san was now a corpse.
Have I lost another clue to finding them?!
But I did find a disc with Itakura-san's diary.
Stilling my impatient heart,
I revealed Itakura-san's killer, and finally got at his diary!
Just what is written on it?!
I now take a dangerous step closer to them.
It's here.
It's right here.
In my pocket.
A clue to those men in black...
Later, on the Doc's PC,
I'll go through this disc from one end to the other.
Hey, Conan-kun...
Eh?
Do you think people change?
When you're apart from them, do people's hearts change?
It's pretty hard...
Just waiting like this...
It's okay. Shin'ichi-niichan's probably just like you remember him.
That's why there's no need to worry...
Conan-kun, sometimes I wish you were Shin'ichi...
I must sound so dumb. What am I saying?
Ran...
No...
It's me.
It's really me...
No.
I can't tell her.
Until I figure out who they are...
Until I've taken them out...
I can't tell her who I am.
You're...
Crying again?
Again?
You're always crying.
Always?
Is that a problem?
No...
You just reminded me of someone.
A woman who looked a lot like you,
who pretended to be calm, but secretly cried all the time.
A stupid woman.
A stupid woman?
Hey, Ran-neechan...
Do you know that man?
Yeah.
I met him when I went to New York with Shin'ichi...
When I was waiting for Shin'ichi in front of that old run-down building,
that guy came up to me and said,
'Have you seen a Japanese man with long silvery hair and a beard?'
The building where the serial killer was hiding!
But I don't think he's a bad person...
Why?
He was with a guy who had 'FBI' written on the back of his jacket.
So probably...
FBI?!
Impossible!
What's the FBI doing here in Japan?!
Hey, let's go home, Conan-kun.
Sure.
But was he really FBI?
Somebody murdered that serial killer and made it look like a suicide.
If the FBI had that area closed off,
there's no way they'd have done that.
And...
In the case when James-san was kidnapped, Haibara was getting bad vibes from him...
Shūichi Akai...
Could he actually be...?
What?! You got your hands on a clue to them?
Really, Shin'ichi?
Yeah.
If Haibara finds out, she'll get paranoid,
so let's go through this while she's not here.
Let's see, two years ago...
Two years... ago...
Bingo! Got it!
March 7...
A man speaking the Kansai dialect came to see me unannounced.
He seems to want the operating system I've been developing.
But when he found out my eyesight got worse and I'd abandoned it, he left.
He was dressed in black from head to toe.
I never saw him again.
Hey, don't tell me that's all!
There doesn't seem to be anything written about that big guy in the diary entries afterward.
So all I learned was that Itakura-san was developing some operating system that those guys wanted.
But this Itakura guy doesn't seem to be an organised guy.
Look, the spacing between diary entries is all over the place.
I'd never leave things this disorganised.
Come to think of it, that guy...
He said that Itakura-san would get angry if the papers on his desk were moved by even 10 cm.
That's not it, Doc.
Look!
If you put the cursor in the space...
then drag it to invert it...
T-This is...!
'I'm wiped out.'
'At this rate, I'm gonna be killed...'
Invisible writing.
He probably camouflaged it in case somebody looked at his diary.
Huh?
Shin'ichi, by 'somebody' you mean...
Right. It has to be them!
Doctor?
I finished my bath.
Looks like he started using the invisible writing 10 days after the big guy's visit.
And the next one says...
March 17th.
'The pen on my desk had moved by 5 cm.'
'It looks like somebody went through my office.'
June 11th.
'I changed my locks and installed hidden cameras, but it's no use.'
July 6th. 'Who are you?! Show yourself!!'
January 6th.
'To rid myself of the terror I'm feeling, I left a message to the intruder on the table.'
'I'll do what you want.'
January 8th. 'They answered me sooner than I was expecting.'
'Instead of the message I'd written, the intruder had left a memo.'
'An "O.K." written in red, along with a suspicious-looking phone number.'
January 23rd.
'After thinking for a while, I decided to call the number without telling the police.'
'Surprisingly, a woman answered the phone.'
'A presumptuous woman who talked as if she was a queen.'
'She said she wanted to buy the OS I'd been
developing for a large sum if I could finish it in a year.'
'She's likely with the same group as the big man from before.'
February 13th.
'They changed the contact method to e-mail.'
'I accepted their request, under the
condition that they pay me in advance'
'and that they stop lurking around me.'
December 22nd.
'I can't.'
'Like I thought, I can't do it.'
'I decided to stop developing this OS, not just because of my vision getting worse,'
'but for the sake of humanity.'
For the sake of humanity?
February 9th.
'The delivery date's coming up.'
'The e-mail stating when and where the delivery should take place'
'should arrive at midnight in five days. I have to get overseas by then.'
This entry was written four days ago. It's
9 PM, so the e-mail should arrive in three hours.
It looks like Itakura-san planned to escape abroad before seeing that e-mail.
February 10th.
'Just what did they want to do with this OS?'
'I still remember the chilling words that the woman said during that first phone call.'
'Right.'
'I couldn't stand her presumptuous tone, so I flat out asked her'
"Just who do you think you are?"
'And she laughed at me and answered in English...'
"We can be both of God and the Devil,"
"since we're trying to raise the dead against the stream of time."
W-What does that mean?
'We are both God and the Devil.'
'Since...'
'We're trying to raise the dead against the stream of time.'
H-Haibara!
Ai-kun!
What's that?
Are you reading a fantasy novel about witches or something?
Yeah. T-That's it.
I got addicted to some of these western novels being serialised on the Internet.
And what are you doing here, Kudō-kun?
Ah, me? I'm—
H-He came to try out my new invention, right?
Y-Yeah!
I call it the 'Anywhere Ball-Shooting Belt'.
At first glance, it looks like a normal belt.
No, it doesn't.
But if you adjust the dial and press the button...
...a football pops out!
A-Awesome!
This is ridiculous.
I'm going to bed.
Now what do we do?
Isn't it obvious?
Now we go to Itakura-san's cottage, we get that operating system,
and we'll use the computer there to receive it.
The e-mail that they'll send at midnight.
But is this really a good idea?
What if they've set up an ambush for him?
It's fine.
Itakura-san made them promise they wouldn't follow him around.
They'd never break a promise they made to a guy who's so paranoid that he noticed
when a pen was moved 5 cm.
You have a point.
If they'd angered him before the OS was done, their efforts would've been for naught.
What happens if the news of Itakura-san's murder comes up on the TV or radio?
That's fine for now.
I've been checking the radio,
but all they've been talking about is the jewel thieves on the run.
What worries me the most are those words at the end of the diary.
Yeah.
'We are both God and the Devil,
since we're trying to raise the dead against the stream of time.'
What did they mean by that?
Hey, Doc...
Don't tell me the poison Haibara was working on was actually...
No way...
Meant to make zombies?
Don't be impatient.
People can't go against the stream of time.
If they try to force it...
...they will be punished.
What?
What does she mean by 'punished'?
We're finally here.
Now, how are we going to get in?
Huh? Where'd you get that key?
It was hidden behind the stairs.
Remember what the diary said.
'A friend who I hadn't seen in five years called me from my cottage.'
That means the key was hidden somewhere so that his friends could come here when they wanted.
Ah, I see.
But isn't this dangerous?
That's why he left this here.
Because they'd never imagine that he'd hide the OS they wanted in an unprotected place like this.
And if he doesn't receive the e-mail they're going to send,
they'll eventually come looking for Itakura-san,
and they'll find the OS and the cheque.
That way, Itakura-san could sever his ties with them without needing to meet.
Right...
S-Shin'ichi...
It's almost time...
Yeah...
Come on, men in black.
Come out, you filthy rats!
The e-mail's here!
Okay, let's open it...
A password?
The count keeps going down!
Damn!
T-The e-mail's gone!
It's rigged so that if you don't open it immediately, it'll disappear!
Then...
Do you think they know the e-mail wasn't opened?
Incoming Call
Number withheld
At this moment, we can't come to the phone.
Please leave a message after the beep.
Incoming Call
Number withheld
Yo, what's up?
Vodka!
You're there, aren't you?
We've been discovered!
They know we failed to open the e-mail in this cottage!
Yeah.
Or maybe they've been watching this cottage without Itakura-san realising it.
Hey, hey...
If that's the case, how are we going to escape?!
Incoming Call
Number withheld
Hey, answer!
I know you're in that cottage!
Incoming Call
Number withheld
You hear me?! Hey!
Hey, answer!
Incoming Call
Number withheld
I know you're in that cottage!
Answer me already, Itakura-san!
Incoming Call
Number withheld
Oh, sorry.
It's pretty dark in here, so I had trouble finding the phone.
H-Hey, hey, hey...
The snowstorm seems to have caused a blackout in this entire area.
That's also why I couldn't open the e-mail.
That's what you get for trying to get an e-mail in a cottage like that.
Hey, wait a sec.
How's the answering machine working if there's a blackout?
Oh, blackouts are common around here when it snows, so I got a phone with a battery.
Oh. Makes sense.
But how did you know I was here?
We know everything about you.
Either way, that doesn't matter. I hope you finished that operating system.
Yes, somehow.
Anyway, I can't use the PC.
Sorry, but could you tell me directly where and when I should deliver the OS?
I suppose I have to.
But I'm only going to say it once, so pay attention.
You know Kembashi Station, the one under construction?
That fancy one they want to add to the Tohto Line.
Tomorrow at midnight, in that station's lowest level.
Come to coin locker #0032.
I can't.
Tomorrow's no good.
What?!
I have to go into hospital from tomorrow evening for a scan.
Hey, don't tell me that you haven't actually finished the OS.
This better not be a trick to buy time!
It's nothing like that.
I've already finished it.
If you want me to give it to you before
I get hospitalised, it'll have to be today,
but the construction workers will be at the station from dawn.
And that's not good for you, right?
Fine. Four then.
At 4 AM, four hours from now,
bring the OS to the place I told you.
F-Four hours?!
All the way from Gunma to Tōkyō?!
What's wrong? If you finished it,
it shouldn't be a problem.
All right.
You'll have it in four hours.
Then, four hours it is.
At coin locker #0032 in Kembashi Station's lowest level.
Don't be late!
R-Right.
Gotcha!
Hey, what are you trying to do?
Don't tell me you want to do what they're asking and take the operating system to them?!
Of course not.
I just manipulated the conversation to move the delivery to 4 AM.
W-What?!
In the morning, they'll probably broadcast the news of Itakura-san's murder.
If they learn he's dead, both the deal and the clues we got will become useless.
The jewel thieves are still...
Fortunately, no radio station reported it yet.
Come on. Let's get rid of any traces that we were here
and get out of this cottage in your Beetle.
Get out?!
They could be watching the cottage from nearby, couldn't they?!
It's okay.
If Vodka or his associates were nearby,
they'd have known I was lying about the blackout and being unable to use the PC.
I-I see.
That's why you asked me to turn on the lights, right?
Yeah.
That way, we know they're not anywhere
where they can see this cottage's lights.
Damn, it's no good.
He password-protected the OS, too.
Like with the mail, Itakura-san and those guys established a password for using the OS.
Then copy it.
Can't do that either.
It's copy-protected.
Without proof, the police can't do anything.
H-Hey, Doc!
Don't tell me this is...
A-Ah, probably...
Yeah. It's a flat.
We'll have to call the nearest petrol station and ask them to bring a spare tyre.
Seriously?
Nobody's gonna bring a tyre here this late!
Well, then we'll have to be patient and wait.
If we do that, we won't make it in time!
Maybe this is a message from God to keep you out of trouble.
Damn it...
A-A car...
Hey! Hey!
Is something wrong?
Oh, we just got a flat tyre.
We need to get back to Tōkyō. Could you give us a ride?
To Tōkyō?
Hey, what do we do?
It's fine, we're going that way anyway.
Gramps, do you know these roads?
Yeah.
Then you sit in the front.
Kid, you go in the back seat.
Sorry for the bother.
This is so cool!
This is a foreign car, isn't it?
Hey, is this car yours?
Yeah.
Though I'm a bit tired of it, and was thinking of buying another one.
He might not look like it, but he's the heir to a big company.
Watch out!
Hey, didn't you hear a strange sound just now?
Huh? I didn't hear anything.
The stuff in the boot probably moved around.
No need to worry.
Hey, don't even think about it!
Don't you remember?
I hate cigarette smoke!
Oh? Ah, sorry!
Right.
To go to Tōkyō, take a left here.
Since it stopped snowing, we'll probably get there by 3 AM.
But what were you doing in Gunma?
Did you take your grandson skiing?
Yeah, something like that.
Strange...
These guys are pretty strange...
Don't tell me...
Don't tell me they're...
Would you stop that?!
How many times have we been honked at?
Didn't I tell you? I'm not good on snowy roads.
Anyway, what've you been listening to, kid?
Oh, this?
I was listening to the news on the radio.
The news?
Yeah. There's all sorts of news today.
About the economy improving,
about Big Osaka's new manager...
And about the jewel thieves on the run.
Have they caught the jewel thieves yet?
Nah...
They said they were still
somewhere near Gunma.
But they'll probably get caught soon.
'Cause look...
The police have checkpoints everywhere.
Your licence, please.
Sorry, but where did you come from?
Uh, well...
It's Detective Yamamura!
I-Is that you, Conan-kun?
Hey, Detective Yamamura...
This roadblock's meant to catch the jewel thieves, right?
Y-Yeah.
There were three thieves wearing balaclavas...
After they hit a jewellery store in Gunma,
they abandoned the getaway car they stole in the mountains, and vanished somewhere...
But one of them's injured,
so I don't think they could have gotten far.
Injured?
That's right.
When we were informed of the situation, we
happened to be working on an investigation nearby.
So when I got to the crime scene, I ran into the thieves, who were escaping from the jewellery store.
So I drew out my pistol and told them
'Stop!'
'Stop or I'll shoot!'
What do you think?
So cool!
But since the thieves didn't stop,
I fired off a warning shot!
Hey...
Bang!
And I accidentally hit one of the thieves in the thigh.
Well, anyway, the three of them probably either had another car ready in the mountains,
or maybe they stole a vehicle that happened to be passing by.
You didn't see anyone suspicious on the way, did you?
So you're looking for someone going in a car that's not their own!
That was us.
My car sprung a flat up in the mountains, so these people gave us a lift.
That's right.
Then, your car...
I'll call the dealership in the morning to get it towed.
So I left my keys inside.
Won't something happen to your car?
Huh?
The thieves might see it and drive off in it.
C-Can we go now, Detective?
Umm... I'm sorry, but could you please take that jacket off your lap?
Hey, are you suspecting us?!
Okay, look! I haven't been shot!
I-I guess you're right.
Well, take care.
Agasa residence...
The Gunma Police?
According to Agasa-san,
his dealership was planning to pick up his car in the morning.
But if we leave the car in the mountains,
the thieves might try to use it to escape,
so we decided to tow it.
So please tell him to come to the Gunma Police Station tomorrow for his car.
Of course.
Sorry for the bother.
Thank you.
What are they doing with his car up in Gunma at this hour?
Looks like Kudō-kun stuck his nose in yet another case.
For crying out loud...
Going off after some crime without sleeping...
The spare tracking glasses...
Yeah, you heard me.
I'll be picking up the goods ahead of schedule.
At 4 AM, an hour from now.
Same place.
The lockers on the lowest level of Kembashi Station.
Tell Gin that too.
We're almost there, you two.
Kembashi Station, like you asked.
Hey, Shin'ichi. You still want to do this?
Yeah.
But first, there's something I've got to take care of.
Hey!
I don't know what you want, I don't like people whispering in my car.
Oh, sorry.
Hey, didn't I tell you not to smoke?
Oh, right. My bad.
I'll get rid of it!
Hey, don't just toss it out the window!
Use the ashtray!
Hey, hey, these coins are
covered in cigarette butts!
No matter how rich you may be, you
shouldn't treat good money this way!
Well, you can't blame him.
Since these two are the jewel thieves.
W-What did you say?!
This car isn't his, either.
Probably, after abandoning their getaway car in the mountains,
they stole this one from somebody else.
The real owner is a non-smoker
who keeps loose change in the ashtray to pay highway tolls faster.
This guy threw his cigarette butts in the ashtray
before realising it was full of coins. Even then, he kept doing it...
...until he picked us up.
D-Don't be silly, kid!
Those coins are just a trick I played on him to make him stop smoking!
There's more proof that this car doesn't belong to him.
He's not used to left-hand driving,
so he keeps unconsciously trying to correct his driving position.
That's why he keeps crossing the white line, and why everyone keeps honking.
And when approaching the curve,
he switched on the windscreen wipers instead of the turn signal!
He forgot that left-hand cars have the handles on the opposite side to Japanese cars.
There's more.
When we entered the car the first time,
If you'd opened the left door,
I could've entered more easily.
I was wondering why you made me go to the other side,
but I figured it out when we went through the police checkpoint and heard Detective Yamamura's story.
The seat you're hiding by sitting on it has bloodstains from the other thief,
who was shot in the leg, and was sitting there until a while ago, right?
The other accomplice...
...is probably in the boot.
He or she's hiding in there to get past police checkpoints.
But why did they pick us up?
Of course, ordinary carjackers wouldn't stop to pick up hitchhikers.
But they did, to pass through checkpoints.
The police wouldn't suspect a group that had an old man and a child. We'd look like a family on an outing.
Smart thinking, kid.
But being intelligent when you're this young isn't that good.
Don't you agree?
S-Shin'ichi!
Though, why didn't you rat us in to the cops at the checkpoint, kid?
You already knew then that we were the jewel thieves, right?
We didn't want to lose any time.
If we'd turned you in to the police there,
they'd have interrogated us too,
and we'd be late to an important encounter.
We could catch you anytime.
You're pretty sure of yourself, kid.
I like people like you.
Take the chance to be as cheeky as you want,
because I won't let you go even if you cry 'Help!' or anything.
Grab on to something!
What did you just do, brat?!
Oh, stop that.
Maybe you can fool a jewellery shop with that toy gun, but not me.
What? Just who are you?!
Conan Edogawa. A detective.
D-Detective?
Ah, yeah...
Be careful with that.
It's a ball-shooting belt.
When I turn the dial to maximum...
it'll become as big as an ad balloon.
Now, we'll be on our way.
Call the police, Doc.
Tell them we caught the jewel thieves.
If something happens, I'll call you over the Detective Badge!
Until then, don't come any closer to Kembashi Station!
H-Hey! Shin'ichi!
It's almost time.
Everybody in their places?
All right. Don't let a single mouse leave.
Hey, Itakura!
Damn Itakura. He still ain't here?
A cheque?
It's the same cheque with which we paid Itakura...
What a moron.
He returned the money and ran away with his tail between his legs leaving the OS behind.
Gotcha!
Yeah, it's me.
Itakura should still be lurking around somewhere.
Find him and bring him here!
What? The only people who entered the station were a drunkard and a little brat?
That can't be right. Find him!
What are you doing?
B-Bro!
Gin!
The deal was supposed to be at midnight tomorrow.
H-He griped that tomorrow was bad, so I changed it to now...
I didn't manage to dispose of him,
but I got the OS we came for.
He has heart problems, anyway.
So he'll die soon either way.
Hey.
Do you know why this was taped?
It was to get your fingerprints.
Since you can't take it off with gloves.
And...
When you didn't see the person you were after,
you got nervous and lit up a cigarette.
If somebody analyses the saliva, they can learn what your blood type is.
B-Bro...
Look...
They're even trying to find our headquarters.
Look.
There's a tracer inside the case.
We're dealing with a clever fox here.
Damn Itakura!
No. It's not him.
A man with heart problems would never do something as stupid
as going to a cottage in the
mountains during a snow storm.
T-Then who was the man I talked to on the phone?
Must've been somebody he hired.
But he made a grave mistake.
The fingerprints on this case were wiped, but it's still a bit warm.
Which means...
Yeah. He's still hiding around here.
Oh, hell...
At this rate, they're gonna find me. What do I do?
What do I do?!
There's only one place left.
Bro!
There's no one else here.
What do we do now?
B-Bro...
B-Bro!
There's no way an adult would fit in a place like this.
Oh well.
Let's change our appearances and get out of here.
He might've called the police.
You mean the guy Itakura hired?
Yeah.
Be careful. You won't get a second chance.
There's a rat sniffing around us.
A detective-like fox...
Now what?
Should I follow them?
No, it's too soon.
They could've just pretended to leave to ambush me.
But what's going on? Just what are they after?!
Haibara was creating a strange drug.
But Itakura-san was a system engineer!
It has nothing to do with drugs!
An operating system that he stopped developing for the sake of mankind...
What the hell was it?
What the hell...?!
Footsteps...
Somebody...
Somebody's coming closer.
D-Damn...
I can't...
move...
Haibara!
What are you doing in a place like this?
W-What am...?
Why are you here?
Morning came and neither you nor the doctor had come home.
So I came looking for you with the spare tracking glasses.
D-Did you say 'morning'?!
Did you find your friend, girl?
Yes!
Well, you're in the way of the construction workers.
Hurry up and leave.
H-Hey! Kudō-kun!
I see...
I must've blacked out from lack of oxygen...
So?
What were you doing in a place like this?
I hadn't had any sleep so I was just taking a little nap...
You honestly think I'll fall for that?
Eh, it's fine.
C'mon, let's go back and have something to eat.
I'm starving.
Hey!
What about the doctor?!
He'll be fine.
He's probably with the police by now.
In other news...
Yesterday, at around 5 PM, the body of a man was found in a room at Hotel New Beika.
He was identified as the famous
CG designer Suguru Itakura-san, age 45.
The police have...
It couldn't be...
Hey, what's wrong?
Nothing...