How are you?
Sonoko Suzuki here.
Well then, do you all remember this man?
Yes, Jirokichi Suzuki.
An executive advisor to the Suzuki Financial Group, and my uncle.
Also, Kaitō Kid-sama's destined rival!
Though Uncle's the only one who actually thinks that.
Their cut-throat battle over the legendary mules, the Purple Nails, should be fresh in your minds, but...
Do you remember why Uncle made Kid-sama his rival?
You don't?
Well, that's just terrible!
So tonight, just for you,
enjoy a special project and recall the memorable first battle between Uncle and Kid-sama!
Staking the miracle of the seas, the Blue Wonder, Uncle sends Kid-sama a challenge notice.
And in response, Kid-sama's white guise walks through the moonlit night sky!
It's quite the illusion!
As expected from the moonlight magician, Kaitō Kid-sama!
Well then, everyone. Please take your time and enjoy Uncle and Kid-sama's first battle!
A mysterious new era now begins...
...a Monday 7 o'clock deduction show!
Today, our criminal is Kaitō Kid!
Even though he can fool everyone's eyes,
I'll protect the jewel and my dreams!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
This concludes today's programming.
Thank you for your patronage.
What's wrong, Sonoko?
You're the one who wanted us to see this caper movie.
Yeah, but the first part was so good that I expected more from this one.
But they just did exactly the same thing! What was the point of doing a 'Part II'?
You think so?
I thought it was okay...
'Okay' isn't enough!
Well, that's pretty much what a sequel is.
Why can't it happen somewhere?
A brilliant and huge case with a magnificent daredevil
who'll make my heart pound so hard that I can't hear anything else!
Besides, weren't you the one who didn't want to see it?
Ran, you think so too, don't you?
H-Hey!
Hold on a second!
When you run into somebody, you could at least apologise!
Wait, Sonoko...
Sonoko, your bag...
A purse snatcher!
Sonoko-neechan, stay here!
Why would I listen to a four-eyed brat?
Ah, wait!
Sic 'im, Lupin!
'Lupin'?
P-Please stop!
You sure are rude to go touching a girl's purse!
You'll get a line or two in my documentary, that's for sure.
Young lady, hurry and call the police.
Got it.
And thank you.
Thank you too, doggy.
Ah, it's nothing.
Even if he got away from my faithful Lupin,
he'd never get away from my ultra-classic with a twin-cam 1500cc engine!
And if it came to it, I've put in a few extra modifications to speed it up even more!
Uncle?
Is that you, Uncle Jirokichi?
You're Shirō's daughter, aren't you?
Haven't seen you since your Shichigosan!
D-Does she know him?
Sounds like it.
This is my uncle, Jirokichi Suzuki. He's my father's cousin,
and the executive advisor to the Suzuki Financial Group.
Nice to meet you.
But when'd you get back here? I heard you were on a trip for the last six months.
Just last week.
I was circling the globe to find it, and now I finally did, I came back.
The perfect bait, that is!
Bait?
So many medals and trophies!
The Europe Open Golf Championship...
The USA Cup for Yachting...
The World Hamburger Eating Contest!
You've won them all!
Was this thing always here?
Oh, that's the figurehead from the Sea Goddess,
a ship said to have been unsinkable during the Age of Discovery, when pirates roamed the seas.
The Golden Goddess!
The jewel she's holding in her right hand is said to have been formed from a mermaid's tears.
It's a legendary aquamarine that's said to have the power to prevent shipwrecks.
It's called the miracle of the seas, the Blue Wonder!
Then the bait you were talking about...
Exactly.
This is the bait that'll lure him out.
'Him'?
In the 72 years I've walked this Earth,
nothing has ever escaped me, Jirokichi!
I got every prize I ever wanted...
Fulfilled every dream I ever had...
But one prey slipped through my fingers time and time again.
He can get past the tightest security, and open the toughest safe like magic.
Then that sinner calmly spreads his white wings and vanishes into the night sky.
Wait...
You can't possibly mean...
Yes. His name is...
Kaitō Kid?!
'To Kaitō Kid.'
'I placed the Big Jewel you desire, the Blue Wonder, on the rooftop of my Great Museum in Shiodome.'
'If you want it, come and get it.'
'Jirokichi Suzuki, executive advisor to the Suzuki Financial Group'.
He wasted two pages of the morning paper on this challenge!
This guy's got way too much money.
But isn't it exciting?!
Moron. Of course he's not gonna show.
This rich weirdo must be full of himself to issue this challenge.
What kind of idiot would walk into such an obvious trap?
He has a point.
But Sonoko told me that Kid sent an e-mail to her uncle Jirokichi saying he was okay with the challenge!
Okay?!
W-What?!
He said he'd drop by this Saturday to inspect the place beforehand.
Here, I had her forward the e-mail to my mobile.
Let's see...
'It is my pleasure to accept your challenge.'
'Let us meet on April 12th at 8 PM.'
'I apologise in advance for dropping by on the night before to have a look around...'
'Kaitō Kid'.
He's as snobbish as always.
Hey, there's a 'P.S.' after that.
A postscript?
As befitting the name 'Blue Wonder', I will walk right up to it and take it.
'Walk right up'?
What are you doing?!
I don't care who they are, make sure you check them!
I want a checkpoint on every road that leads to this museum!
Don't let a single suspicious person through!
Got it?
Geez, the helicopters are really noisy.
What? You don't know how to recognise Kid?
Just pinch their faces and pull!
I-Inspector!
And when I say 'pull', I mean a good hard yank!
Really hard!
Got it?
Inspector Nakamori's really fired up...
Hey, Ran!
Sonoko!
Ran!
That's some entrance.
Hey, hey. Has Kaitō Kid showed up yet?
No, not yet.
The man with the tiny moustache is Ran's dad, Sleeping Kogorō-san.
T-Tiny moustache?
I've heard a lot about you!
Well, I'm not that great...
Hey, is it you? Are you the one responsible for this havoc?!
Do something about your helicopters!
They're getting in the way of the police helicopters!
There's no need for police helicopters.
Didn't Kid say in his notice that he'd come on foot?
Then what are your choppers doing?
They're filming the epic documentary about my life.
Documentary?
Wow!
It's like a TV news van!
It's not just the helicopter cameras.
You can view the footage from cameras in over 100 places around the museum.
H-Hey, there's nobody in the museum!
There were too many before! Now even if he does sneak into the museum in disguise, he'll be completely obvious!
All the doors in the museum can be opened and closed from this van.
Even if he does get to the Goddess on the top floor, he'll just be trapped...
Of course, that's if he has the guts to show up like he announced!
Looks like he's here.
Where? Where?
Can you zoom in a bit more?
So he's finally shown up?
Kaitō Kid!
Hey, from which one is it?
Which helicopter's filming this?
Which helicopter is it?
I-It's #7!
I think it's flying behind the museum.
Behind the museum?
Okay!
From behind?
Conan-kun?
W-What should I do?
Just to be safe, should I activate the device that moves the Golden Goddess inside?
Keep your calm!
Tonight, he's just casing the museum. He won't steal it.
And he said he'd walk right up to it.
Hey!
Hey, move!
Move it!
Let's see how the great thief known as the 'Moonlight Magician' makes his appearance!
H-Hey!
Where is he? Where's Kid?
He flew between the buildings and didn't come out.
Come on... Step out of the shadows, Kaitō Kid!
Your feet must touch the ground for you to walk.
Come on... Come out, Kid!
W-What?!
No way... It can't be!
Kid-sama... Kid-sama's floating!
Amazing!
That can't be... It's impossible!
No human being can defy the law of gravity...
...and float in the air!
Don't let him fool you! It's just one of his tricks!
I bet he's just hanging from a wire suspended from a black balloon!
Go over him! Have one of the choppers nearby fly over his head!
T-This is chopper #7.
There's nothing above Kid's head!
S-Say what?!
Kid-sama's so amazing!
Don't you think so, Ran?
This is chopper #7.
What should I do?
Stay where you are!
Roger.
Damn you, Kid! What trick did you use?
He can't just be floating!
Find that rope!
My, such a mess. And this has just begun.
If it's not above him...
It's beside him?
Of course. He strung a wire between the buildings and is hanging from that!
Okay! I'll check the building on the left!
You go to the roof of the one on the right!
Find that wire!
Y-Yes, sir!
Damn...
Damn you, Kid!
You won't make fools out of us!
In the end, it's just a magic trick.
Just you wait, Kid!
Once you know how it's done...
It's not here!
There's no wire!
N-Nothing! There's no wire anywhere!
Inspector Nakamori! We can't find anything in this building either!
Impossible!
Then how's he doing it?!
How's he freely...
Ladies and gentlemen!
Now, for tonight... Pay attention to the miracle that I am performing!
H-He's walking...
Oh, wow! He's walking!
This is chopper #3!
Kid's currently walking in mid-air!
That's impossible! What trick is he using?!
H-Hey!
My Kid-sama's walking!
This is chopper #3. Kid's currently walking over Shiodome Park!
At this rate, he'll reach the rooftop of the Great Suzuki Museum and grab the Blue Wonder
in less than a minute!
Can't we do anything other than watch him steal it?!
Damn you, Kid!
How's he planning to escape?
There are cops on the ground, and choppers in the air!
Advisor! Surely it's time to activate the device!
Very well.
This is it for tonight.
I'll come back tomorrow at 8 PM, at the same place.
Damn it!
What did I tell you? You can't take Kid lightly!
I have no intention of letting him steal it.
After all, I went all around the world
to get my hands on the miracle of the seas, the Blue Wonder!
But why's the golden figurehead indoors, and upside-down?
This is how the mechanism works.
I see, it rotates and replaces the real figurehead with a fake!
Kid's bound to see through a cheap trick like that.
Of course. I don't expect him to fall for the forgery.
Then tomorrow, instead of using your helicopters, you should just let the police take care of things!
On the contrary.
Contrary?
He said he'd appear at the same place tomorrow.
Then I'll be there, waiting to ambush him.
What ambush?
I'll rent every building and fill the block
with an army of helicopters and guards that'll dwarf the ones from today!
I don't know what kind of hocus-pocus he used to walk in mid-air,
but if he shows up again regardless,
I'll catch him and put him in the final chapter of my epic documentary!
Don't move. Don't move.
Don't move!
What's going on?
W-Where is it? Where is it?
No...
There it is!
What's with this dog?
Good old Lupin! Like me, you never let go of your prey!
A contact lens?
I didn't know you had bad eyes, Uncle Jirokichi.
Now that I'm 72, this old body doesn't work the way it used to.
You don't say...
That's why I want to capture him while I still can.
But why are you so obsessed with Kaitō Kid, anyway?
Kid... Kaitō Kid...
Every time I hear that name, I remember that he took everything from me, that damn Kid!
I'll never forgive him!
Listen! I, Jirokichi Suzuki, will capture him, and I won't let anyone get in my way!
Nobody will stop me!
You've seen all the glories and prizes I've attained, right?
Each and every time, I've made the front page of the paper...
...except once!
Y-You can't mean...
That's right! Not only did that petty thief get the front page, he got the second page too!
My triumphant world trip in a self-powered aircraft got pushed back to just a corner of page three!
Can you comprehend the humiliation?
Can you understand the pain I've suffered?!
I get it, I get it...
And when I capture him...
I, Jirokichi Suzuki, shall make my grand comeback to the front page!
I've been expecting you, Sonoko-sama.
Thanks.
I've prepared seats for your guests as well.
Hey, hey, are you serious?
Isn't this the roof?!
Would you care for a drink?
Anything's fine.
This is the first time I can actually see she's a wealthy heiress.
You can really tell this is one of the buildings near the spot where Kid appeared.
Look at all the guards!
I still don't get it.
I got a look at the footage filmed from that helicopter,
but there wasn't anything odd at all.
And then he disappeared in mid-air!
How'd he do it?
I'll get it.
Sorry.
Scratch marks! As if something was hooked here...
And they're still fresh!
Take a look at this!
A veil of helicopters covers the sky!
Countless security guards patrol the streets!
These elite forces were chosen by the Suzuki Financial Group for their supreme vigilance!
Will he dare to appear in such a heavily guarded area?
I'm referring to the one who announced he would steal the Blue Wonder from the Suzuki Museum's roof...
...Kaitō Kid!
He'll come, he'll come. Of course he'll come!
An heiress of the Suzuki Financial Group whose jewels are
being targeted really shouldn't be saying something like that...
But it's Kaitō Kid-sama!
I want to meet him in person at least once!
To tell you the truth, I volunteered to sit on the museum's roof and hold the Goddess,
but Uncle Jirokichi wouldn't let me!
Of course not...
You weren't hoping to get stolen along with the jewel, were you?
You bet! Then Makoto-san would show up to rescue me from captivity!
Just thinking about having two men fighting for me like that...
But I can understand the over-the-top security.
After all, we're talking about somebody who announced he was coming to inspect the scene
and then showed up floating in mid-air, walked to the museum, and vanished!
Honestly, he looked like he was naturally
walking in mid-air, as if there was no trick.
But there had to be, right?
If people could walk in the sky that easily, it'd scare the birdies away!
B-Birdies?
Conan-kun, you're such a cute kid!
I think I overdid the kiddie talk.
Kid's magic should've amazed a child like you as much as the birdies.
Well, I don't know how he did the trick yet, but I think I found a clue!
Look, there's scratch marks on the wall there!
Well?
You found marks there too?
Really?
There are scratches on the wall of the building you're in?
Yes, and they're brand new!
But what are they?
Maybe he ran a wire between the buildings.
Kaitō Kid could've hung from it to make it look like he was floating!
Nope. Inspector Nakamori was on the other building last night,
and he said there were no wires!
Then do you know how he did it, Dad?
More or less.
How was it then?
When people assume something is impossible,
their preconceptions keep them from seeing it, even if it's right in front of their eyes.
Preconceptions?
And?
What didn't we notice?
Well, maybe...
Maybe a huge sheet of solid glass!
Kid placed it between the two buildings and walked on it!
Inspector Nakamori didn't see it because he'd never imagined such an audacious trick!
The scratch marks must've been left by whatever he used to lock the glass down...
You think nobody would notice a giant sheet of glass?
That's why...
And how could he sneak it in and install it?
That's why I said 'maybe'...
Their preconceptions keep them from seeing it...?
Kid! Kid! Kid!
I-Inspector Nakamori!
There's just too many people! We can't check everyone!
The Suzuki Financial Group seems to be handing out 'Welcome Kid Fans' flyers!
Flyers?!
If we don't let them in, they'll riot!
No choice then.
Let them in without checks if you have to!
Roger!
He's flying in anyway...
You must be the owner of the miracle of the seas, the Blue Wonder,
as well as the executive advisor to the Suzuki Financial Group, Jirokichi Suzuki-san, right?
That's me.
With one hour to go before the big moment,
are you ready for Kid?
He'll show off his cheap parlour tricks,
but I'm the one who's going to be the protagonist in tonight's show.
I'll show you a scene of justice that'll beat any Hollywood movie!
Uncle's in really high spirits!
We now return to commercials...
The new place to be in Shiodome. The Great Suzuki Museum, filled with the scent of history and culture!
Hey, hey, even the ads are about the museum!
It's called synergy! Uncle's pretty good at this kind of stuff.
That aerial shot's just a clip from his TV special!
He might not look like it,
but he's a calculating guy!
Hurry up, Kaitō Kid-sama! Come and steal my passionate heart!
It's way too loud here for an intimate moment!
And the wind's too strong.
The wind?
What's wrong?
I'm going down to see Mr. Jirokichi!
I just noticed something neat!
What did you notice?
It's a secret!
What?
You want to look at the footage of Kaitō Kid from yesterday?
Yeah.
Uncle Kogorō told me to watch it again!
But you saw it over and over again last night, little boy!
And we already sent it down to the production staff working on the documentary.
You'll have to hand over all your footage to the police in the end, anyway.
After all, this is the first time that Kaitō Kid's been caught on film casing a target site.
That's right...
Why did Kid put on that demonstration?
Less than a minute to showtime! The Kid fans gathered here have started a countdown!
Stay tuned for the wondrous moment!
He'll never show up.
No magician would let the audience come on
stage and gather around him before the show.
They'd see through his tricks.
He announced he'd be appearing between those buildings tonight, so everyone's watching that spot.
And the wind stirred up by my helicopters is too strong for his hang-glider.
There's no way he can show his face.
Not unless he's a tengu or a wizard.
K-Kaitō Kid!
It's Kid! Kaitō Kid appeared just as he announced!
Kid-sama!
H-He came...
And he's really floating!
I-It can't be!
Where did he come from?!
Oh no, rain! Cover it up, cover it up!
Rain?
Why'd it have to rain?
Talk about bad timing!
Even with this sudden downpour,
the crowd's still chanting Kid's name!
Hey, what's wrong, chopper #7? Hey!
What is it?
The image from chopper #7 suddenly cut out.
This is chopper #7. Everything looks right on my end.
I think the rain's temporarily disrupting the image...
No... Kid's accomplice is probably blocking the image somehow as part of Kid's plan.
What? Kid has an assistant?
Yeah. I've heard conflicting reports that it's either an old man or a young woman,
but we know he has somebody working for him!
H-He's walking!
He started walking just like last night!
What should I do, advisor? If we don't do something, he'll really steal it!
He won't get away with it that easily!
Stash the Blue Wonder inside the museum for now.
Right!
It's his intelligence versus mine.
Scratches, preconceptions, the wind...
An accomplice...
I see! That's how it was!
I figured it out, Kaitō Kid!
I know how you appeared, walked in the sky, and vanished!
And I know how you're planning to steal the Blue Wonder!
Advisor!
We've finished moving the Blue Wonder indoors!
Okay! Then the next move's mine!
Turn off all the lights in the museum!
The lights?
Yeah!
There's a chance he may be
intercepting our camera feeds.
Hey, wait a minute. Isn't that
exactly what Kid would want?
Got a better idea, Inspector Nakamori?
Do you have any idea how to stop a master
thief who can walk in mid-air like a wizard?!
But what good will it do to store the jewel inside a darkened museum?
The point is to stop him from stealing it!
If he can't get his hands on
the Blue Wonder, then I win!
Here's a proposition.
If I place you in command of this control centre,
will you lend me a couple of your men?
My men?
Accept it.
It's a plan I've been working on all night.
Kid-sama!
Hey, Kid-sama!
Now that the helicopters got out of the way, I can see Kid-sama!
But he's already so far away...
Huh?
There's Kaitō Kid! He's less than 100 metres from his target, the Blue Wonder!
Hey! How are things going over there?
Perfectly, Inspector Nakamori!
Not even Kid will see through this plan!
Enough chit-chat! He might be tapping the line.
Don't worry.
It's all going just as planned.
I'll call back to tell you how it went.
H-Hey, wait!
I-Inspector!
There's something weird about Kid today!
What?
You saw something that
looked like a wire? Really?
Yeah! There was a line or something shining near Kid's shoulder!
Hey, wait!
If what you're saying is true, then Kid-sama isn't walking, he's hanging from that helicopter!
Something's off, isn't it?
His legs are moving, but he looks like he's dangling from a rope!
Hey, chopper #7, the one that's flying over Kid! Answer me!
Hey, chopper #7!
Chopper #7!
H-He's gone!
He disappeared just outside the museum!
So it was chopper #7!
His sidekick in chopper #7 used the smoke screen to pull him inside!
Hey, your helicopters are all numbered, right?
Yes. The number's written on the tail.
All helicopters circling the area!
This is Nakamori of the Police HQ!
Kid and his accomplice are in chopper #7!
Report in the position of chopper #7 right away!
Keep it surrounded until
the police choppers arrive!
Chopper #14 here!
I have a visual of chopper #7 above the front entrance to the museum!
Good! Keep tailing it and don't lose sight!
Roger!
Chopper #35 here! Chopper #7's currently over Shiodome Park!
Wait a minute... Shiodome Park is behind the museum!
Chopper #28 here! Chopper #7's currently moving away from Shiodome...
T-This is chopper #9! I see two choppers
numbered seven in front of Shiodome Park!
Hey, hey... What's going on?!
It seems most of our helicopters were painted with the number seven!
Kid must've changed the numbers!
Don't be stupid, how could that be?
Didn't you see the number when you boarded the helicopter?
I-Inspector!
What?
There are some strange people at the museum entrance!
And it's not just one or two people...
Those are my men who I sent in there a while ago.
Don't tell me the Blue Wonder's inside the case that the detective in the middle's carrying...
What are they thinking?
They're carrying it out to him!
Hey, what are you doing?
Hurry inside!
Don't worry, Inspector.
This case is empty. It's just a decoy!
A decoy?
Jirokichi Suzuki-san put the Blue Wonder in a trash bag and left through the back door disguised as a janitor!
What's so funny...
...Kaitō Kid-san?
W-What are you talking about?
I'm laughing because I managed to protect the jewel from Kid!
Moron. I knew who you were as soon as you showed up at the museum on this bike.
Just like now, you weren't
wearing your goggles.
It's very hard for someone with contact lenses to ride a bike without wearing goggles.
Even with a windscreen in front of you,
the pain of the wind hitting your eyes would cause you to tear up.
The old man's a millionaire, but he rides around on this fancy bike without a single bodyguard.
It wouldn't be hard for you to get a chance to drug him and take his place.
By the way, I took the dog you left sleeping in this sidecar, Lupin, and left him in a shady spot in Shiodome Park.
You probably put him to sleep with a sleeping drug too, didn't you?
How could I be Kid?
I was right next to you when Kid appeared this evening!
How could you forget that wondrous moment when he walked in the sky?
That was no wonder.
With an assistant, it's a simple trick.
The Suzuki Financial Group relies on elite security guards rather than the police or the military!
So it probably wasn't too hard for your accomplice to sneak in with a group of temporarily-hired pros.
Last night, you suddenly appeared between two buildings,
and with a helicopter flying over you, it seemed impossible for you to be suspended from something.
After that, when the police and I ran up to the rooftops, we confirmed there were no wires between the buildings,
making it look like you really were skywalking.
But if that helicopter was flown by your assistant,
then the trick becomes simple.
First off, you flew over the buildings in your assistant's helicopter.
From the helicopter, you hooked one end of a wire to the building's roof,
then flew to the opposite building and attached the other wire.
Using the wire linking the two buildings,
and a pulley attached to your body, you moved to the middle of the wire.
You then threw off the black robe you were wearing as the smoke screen billowed around you,
and that's how Kaitō Kid made his entrance.
Next you had your sidekick fly the helicopter over you,
and have them wind up a thin wire made from fishing line until it was taut,
which you'd connected to yourself before leaving the helicopter.
After that, you removed the pulley and had the helicopter quickly retrieve the wire connecting the buildings.
At that point, it looked like you were hanging from nothing, so your levitation trick was complete!
Then you just had to pretend to walk as the helicopter moved forward.
You had a tape recorder in your pocket playing the sound of footsteps.
If the wire swayed a little, you walked a small step,
and if it swayed a lot,
you walked a larger step.
It was an amazing performance to make people think you weren't hanging from anything.
Then after walking for a bit, you cast off your white suit together with the smoke screen,
had the searchlight move off you,
and had your assistant pull you up into the helicopter to make it look like you vanished in mid-air.
But the Kid who appeared tonight was just a dummy with moving legs set up to distract the police.
You made it appear the same way, with the smoke screen and the helicopter.
But it was just hanging there, so it was obvious.
But boy, didn't you climb up to the rooftop to watch Kid?
If there was something hanging off a helicopter, you would've seen it, no matter how thin the wire was!
I blame the wind and my own preconceptions.
It was stupid of me.
I was completely convinced you weren't suspended
by a wire, because I'd seen a helicopter fly over you.
Also, I'd been looking for a wire connected to the rooftop, and didn't find one.
But you left traces of that wire on the rooftops of those two buildings.
Scratches left by the hooks on the end of the wires when they were pulled up by the helicopter.
But still, you checked the footage of Kid from last night over and over, didn't you?
It depends on the video's resolution, but either way it's very hard to see such a thin wire on a monitor.
A downward shot of Kid might've revealed it, as the wires would pass in front of him,
but the only helicopter that could shoot that was chopper #7, piloted by your sidekick.
That chopper sent footage from the previously aired Suzuki Museum TV Special overlaid with your own footage.
You were sending edited footage from chopper #7, so there weren't any wires that could show up.
That's why your accomplice stopped transmitting when the rain started, right?
The aerial shots in the TV special didn't include people with umbrellas.
Your flashy demonstration last night
was to make it look like you'd come from the sky, so checks on the ground would be reduced,
so that you could disguise yourself as Jirokichi
Suzuki and pass through without being checked.
But you got forgetful. I clearly saw you on TV riding the bike without goggles.
Oh, I didn't forget the goggles. I just couldn't wear them.
They'd mess up my disguise!
Are you sure about this?
That accomplice of yours in chopper #7 is probably surrounded by the police by now!
Nah, it's fine. The police are probably in a huge panic
due to all the choppers having the number 7 on their tails.
All the choppers?
I see. You put a sticker with the number 7 on all the choppers,
followed by another, lightly pasted sticker with the correct number.
The second sticker would fly off in the wind.
Yeah. All the pilots got on their helicopters without realising
that they'd end up being chased under suspicion of being my accomplice.
In the chaos, my sidekick will escape.
Into the blue wonder, the miracle of the sky!
The sky? The Blue Wonder's 'blue' represents the blue of the sea.
Same thing. The sea's blue because it reflects the blue sky, right?
It's the same with detectives and phantom thieves.
We may seem like opposites,
but in the end we're both
dedicated to opening the door
leading to the secrets people keep, using curiosity as a key.
Idiot. The sea and sky are blue because of refraction and diffusion of light.
They're blue for completely different reasons. Don't mix them up!
As proof of that, puddles aren't blue!
You never dream, do you?
You can't see the truth if you get hung up on dreams!
By the way, do you really think you can capture me with that tranquiliser dart?
If I fall asleep at this speed, we'll have a huge crash.
It's okay. I won't shoot until the bike stops.
And I already called Inspector
Nakamori to come and pick you up.
Hmph. I'm not going to stop.
Did you forget what old Jirokichi told you?
This bike's been modified to speed it up!
So long, Detective.
You can keep the jewel.
It isn't what I'm looking for.
I only came because the old prune picked a fight with me!
Damn brat!
You never dream, do you?
Don't be stupid. Of course I do.
I have a dream, too...
Did anything show?
Everyone, how was it?
Did you enjoy it?
Though the reason why Uncle took Kid-sama as an enemy was kinda dumb.
In the end, the four-eyed brat saved the Blue Wonder. But...
Hey, you wannabe detective!
Next time, I'll escape from both you and the cops with even more awesome magic!
So prepare yourself!
That goes for you too...
I'll make sure to catch you next time,
so you prepare yourself.