Showing sympathy with others...
If everyone were to interact with sincerity and sympathy...
...then I wonder if most of the world's crimes and sadness would disappear.
kage o mau chō no kodō ga seijaku no umi o saite
kasanariau koe ga ima yami o furiharatta
Only the light of deductions can tear apart black shadows and deep darkness!
A love letter addressed to Ran Mouri?
What will her confused heart decide?
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
haritsuita ase o nugutte nigemawaru light o ketta
kanashimi ni utareta kyō no kizuato kabau yō ni
aseru hodo ni tōku natte wake mo naku imi o sagashite
osanasa no ura ni kakushita yuzuritakunai omoi ni
kizuita nara miushinawanai yō ni
dareka o mamore'ru to motto ima shinjitai
kage o mau chō no kodō ga seijaku no umi o saita
kimi ni miseru itsuwari no subete ga uso ja nai daro
mayo'u tabi suteta kotae mo kitto erabu hi wa mata kuru kara
kono kokoro wa dare yori mo atsuku moyashi tsuzukeyō kienai yō ni
kienai yō ni
Did you hear? Kitada-kun from Class C got dumped again!
Oh, isn't that Mouri?
Hey, Ran! Going home already?
Oh, Sonoko! Yeah.
I was thinking about cooking something good for Conan-kun. He hasn't been eating any dinner lately.
A beautiful young schoolgirl like you shouldn't be thinking about that!
Suzuki, you could learn something from her!
Shut up!
Then I'll head home too!
I'm going to get my bag, so wait for me by the shoe lockers.
Okay.
Don't tell me this is...
.
What should I do?
I'd better open it at home.
Thanks for waiting, Ran.
What's that?
To Ran Mouri.
S.H.?
Hey Ran, it's a...
I found it in my shoes locker.
What should I do?
What should you do?
Isn't it obvious?
A LOVE LETTER TO RAN
Just rip it open already!
Don't rush me.
'Please forgive me for sending you this letter so suddenly.'
'Whenever I'm thinking about you, Ran-sempai, I can feel my heart beating. I can't even sleep at night.'
'I would like to meet you.'
'I'll be waiting for you tomorrow after school, at the fountain in Beika Park.'
Congrats, Ran! It's a love letter!
Since he called you 'Ran-sempai', he has to be a first-year student.
He doesn't know you already have Shin'ichi-kun.
This has nothing to do with Shin'ichi—
Sheesh!
We can't even have a simple conversation here!
Sorry!
Let's go somewhere else!
Wait, Sonoko...
So you got a love letter?
I haven't had any in a while.
What about you?
What?
Don't tell me, it's the first time you got one?!
It is.
I see...
You're always with Shin'ichi-kun, so nobody sends you any.
I told you this has nothing to do with Shin'ichi!
Who's that guy?
Isn't he a former kendō club member?
Look, he's holding a shinai.
But never mind that, focus on the love letter!
Let's go.
Hey, wait!
So, what are you going to do?
You'll go, right? To Beika Park.
I don't know what I'll do...
There's nothing to think about!
You'll go and turn him down in a snap.
You'll say you already have a husband.
Don't act like it's somebody else's problem!
You really do look worried.
I guess there's no choice. Leave it to me!
I'll turn him down for you!
What are you going to turn down?
Oh, it's four-eyes.
What are you doing here?
You look weird, Ran-neechan.
Of course! She got her very first love letter!
Love letter?!
Sonoko!
'Oh, my beloved Ran-sama!'
'I'll hold you close and place a loving kiss on your sweet lips...'
She's lying, Conan-kun!
It didn't say anything like that.
But you really did get a love letter, huh?
Who was it from?
So you're interested, huh?
Don't be stupid, why would I be?
Maybe I am a bit interested...
What a kid...
It's a first-year student with the initials 'S. H.'.
A first-year student?
He wants to meet her tomorrow at the fountain in Beika Park after school.
That's enough, Sonoko!
Ran doesn't know how to handle it, so I'm going to go and turn him down instead.
Got it?
Yes.
Did something happen?
What is it?
If something's bothering you, you can talk to her.
Her father's the great detective Kogorō Mouri.
That's enough, Conan-kun! Sorry.
And her husband's the high school detective Shin'ichi Kudō.
Sonoko!
I know Detective Mouri, and the high-school detective Kudō-kun, too.
I used to be a Teitan High student.
Is that so?
We're second-year students.
What should I do?
Maybe I should talk about it with you, like that boy suggested...
You can, right, Ran-neechan?
Yes, if you don't mind speaking to us...
We'll help you, Sempai!
Come in! Sorry for the mess.
Thank you.
Oh, he's my husband.
He died one year ago.
From illness.
He stayed in the hospital for six months and fought hard, but he couldn't make it.
Actually, it seems someone broke into my house while I was gone.
I went for a walk with Yūto for two hours at around 1 PM.
But I must've forgotten to lock that window.
Also, I usually personally hand the rent to the landlord.
I withdrew some money from the bank this morning and put it in this envelope.
But it seems the money I had in here was taken out.
Taken out?
But it was put back. All the money.
So how do you know it was taken away?
It's because the money was folded even though you got new notes, right?
Exactly. It's a very faint fold though.
See.
And I always leave my diary here too, but it looks like someone's been reading it.
And one more thing.
The best proof is that someone burnt an incense stick there.
So it was still burning when you arrived?
How much of the stick was left?
I think it was about half.
Then the incense stick was lit about 15 minutes before you got back.
After all, incense sticks usually last about half an hour.
You know a lot, Conan-kun!
But what does that mean?
If someone really broke into this house...
The problem is who broke in and why.
He read the diary, so isn't he a stalker?
But except for that diary, it didn't look like anything had been looked through or taken away.
I felt a little bit uncomfortable, so I asked a policeman to come,
but since nothing was taken,
there wasn't anything to investigate.
The incense stick...
That's the most intriguing part.
Is the culprit one of her acquaintances, or one of her husband's?
Say, how did you meet your husband?
Conan-kun!
He's really a curious brat!
He was a classmate of mine in high school.
But we had no feelings for each other back then.
After graduating from university, we happened to meet each other in the city and started dating.
So it's not like Ran.
Of course it isn't.
Say, you said someone read your diary, but what was written in it?
Nothing special.
Things like 'working and taking care of a child everyday is tough,'
'but I get some strength when I think about him.' Childish stuff.
It must be really hard being alone, Yuriko-san.
Actually, I already thought about committing suicide.
But I have a child, and thought about my late husband who struggled so hard with his illness.
I couldn't commit suicide.
After all, it's not just my husband. There are so many people who want to live but can't.
So it'd be unforgivable for me to give up my own life.
That's so sad, I'm shedding tears.
Maybe the culprit felt the same way we do.
If that's true, our culprit would be...
Hey, I saw on TV that a thief broke into a house and left without stealing anything after changing his mind.
It was the house of a teacher who'd been kind to him when he was a child.
But he broke in without knowing that.
Sempai, you wouldn't happen to be a school teacher, would—
No.
But even if you weren't their teacher, you could be somebody they know.
More to the point, you could be somebody special to them.
Maybe I should write a diary, too.
And they read said special person's diary...
A diary that shows so clearly that you're living honestly despite many misfortunes.
I see! That's why they didn't take anything and instead just lit an incense stick!
Exactly.
Maybe he even sent you a love letter during high school!
Stop joking, Sonoko! We're being serious here!
I'm serious too!
What do you think, Sempai?
Yes, I did get a love letter once.
When was it?
The January of my third year.
But if it hadn't been for that letter,
I wouldn't even know his name or face.
We'd never been in the same class at all, from first year to third year.
But apparently he'd always been admiring me, and I just didn't notice.
The king of one-sided love!
The letter said he wanted to meet me at the fountain in Beika Park.
What?
Oh, nothing.
So did you go?
I hesitated, but I went to tell him my true feelings.
What did you say?
'I'm glad you have those feelings for me,'
'but I can't think of anything other than the entrance exams right now.'
After hearing that, he just left without a word.
Let's see...
It was him.
Shūhei Nagai-kun.
Hey! This man!
Nagai-kun was here?
Sempai, were you part of the kendō club?
Yeah, I was the manager during my 2nd year.
As I thought. That settles it.
Most likely, he's the one who broke into your house.
I think so too.
Sempai, have you heard from him since you graduated?
Yes, about two years ago.
From one of my husband's friends...
I never spoke about him to my husband,
but he came up in conversation as one of the many other classmates we had at that time.
He did his best, but he couldn't enter the university he wanted.
And after graduating, he only found a job in a company he didn't like.
In the end, he quit that company, and it seems he's doing part-time jobs now.
Sempai, by any chance did you enter a top university just after high school?
I don't know if I'd call it a top university, but I did enter the university I wanted.
I knew it. I saw through everything.
What do you mean, Sonoko?
Want to hear my deduction?
Oh geez, seriously?
After meeting Yuriko-sempai at the Beika Park fountain, Shūhei Nagai didn't forget about her.
But feeling inferior to her, who'd entered a top university just after high-school,
he couldn't bring himself to contact her.
Later, after graduation, as his professional life wasn't any good either,
he ended up without money.
As he was already familiar with Beika District, he chose it to commit his theft.
Then, he was headed to a rich mansion, probably mine,
and on the way there, he noticed the window in your house was open.
He figured out the house was empty, and he...
And then he saw it.
The woman in the photo was the one he'd fallen in love with in high school.
He also remembered the man with her as a high school classmate!
And from the picture on the altar, he realised that the classmate in question had died.
And while he knew it was wrong, he also read the diary he'd found.
He found out about how you were doing your best to live on with your son,
and thought about his classmate who died in his 20s.
So he started feeling ashamed of himself, as he was taking advantage of people despite still being healthy.
When I see Ran put so much effort into her karate practice,
I sometimes think I should work hard too!
Sonoko.
So Shūhei Nagai decided to redeem himself, and so he put the money back in the envelope,
burnt a stick in honour of his late classmate, and left the house.
Finally, as he knew he would never come back to this city,
he went to see the school he graduated from one last time.
And that just happened to be when the kendō club was practising.
Therefore, he remembered Yuriko-sempai and started reminiscing.
He might be staring at the fountain in Beika Park now even!
No way.
Amazing, Sonoko-neechan!
That was almost the same as what I deduced.
Hold on.
This Nagai guy who I saw in front of the gymnasium seemed a little bit different than you deduced.
How should I put this?
He looked rather languished.
Really?
And I still don't know why he was carrying a shinai.
A shinai?
Yes.
Hey, was there anything else written in the diary?
There's actually something I didn't tell you.
About 10 days ago, I was involved in a small accident with a man riding a bike.
At that time, he said everything was OK,
but he came back later saying he couldn't turn his head any more.
Is that...
I told him that I'd pay for his medical fees,
but he asked for a 'relationship' instead.
Quite persistently, actually.
That's disgusting.
He seemed like a pretty bad guy, so I was afraid something might happen to my son if I'd rejected him too harshly.
So I didn't tell anybody about it.
Where was he today?
He's on a business trip until tonight, and I don't think he was today's intruder.
Hey, everything you just told us was written in your diary, right?
Yes.
And this Nagai guy was carrying a shinai, right?
Could it be...
Who are you?
Are you that girl's boyfriend?
No.
Stay away from her.
And keep your hands off her kid!
What? What are you blabbering?
Take that!
And that!
Conan-kun?
Had enough yet?
Stay away...
Stay away from her!
What are you sayin'? I can't hear you!
Nagai-kun!
And who the hell are you guys?
What do you want, brat?
Oh?
That's odd, mister.
I thought you couldn't turn your neck?
You damn brat!
You despicable monster!
What do you want, girl?
Hey, mister, it seems you can't turn your neck for real now.
Nagai-kun!
Are you okay, Nagai-kun?
Sorry.
I read your diary...
It's fine, don't say anything.
I'm sorry. I wanted to help you.
11 years ago...
I was so glad you'd come to the park.
I never thought you'd come.
Nagai-kun.
I've made up my mind. I'll go there by myself.
I still don't know what I'll say, but I have to tell him how I feel.
I owe him my sincerity for having written that letter.
You're right.
Ima aitakute...
(I want to be with you...)
denwa ga naru tabi kono mune ga zawameku
demo kikoetekuru no wa kimi no koe ja nai
ima kimi wa doko ni iru no nani shite'ru no
kami- sama ni negai todoku nara mō ichido dake
aitakute kimi ni aitakute
ima mo kono mune wa kimi- iro ni somaru (dakishimetakute)
setsunakute nido to aenai nara
maichiru yuki shiroku kono kokoro somete
I made it in time.
Oh, geez.
Ran said she wanted to tell him the truth, but...
Did she mean about me?
Excuse me!
I said I'd wait for you, but you ended up being the one waiting for me, Sempai!
So, you're...
What?
I'm a big fan of you, Ran-sempai, the captain of the karate club!
Please take this.
T-Thanks.
Keep doing your best!
See you.
What was that?
So it wasn't a first-year boy.
Sonoko! And Conan-kun!
And here I thought I was gonna hear Ran's true feelings.
Too bad.
But you're able to grasp women's hearts too!
You're amazing, Ran!
Isn't it great?