Are we good to go? Huh?
It's already recording! Well...
Let's get started, then!
This is Tooru Amuro.
The fact that you found
this secret number
means that you've managed to get
a little closer to the clues of this case.
Cut.
Splendid, Furuya-san.
Scene two, take one, action!
In regards to the request for confidential collaboration to investigate the Tokyo Summit,
I might give you a call back
when the time is right.
If so, I will call you from
the following number,
so please don't forget it.
The number is...
03-6629...
I don't know if I will be able
to call you or not, but if I do,
it will most likely be on a day
that begins with an "S".
Until that time,
please continue to keep
this investigation a secret.
Excellent. Cut!
Furuya-san...
What a terrifying person he is.
To think he pulled it off
with zero retakes!