Thank you for your assistance!
I'm back!
Hey!
FATUOUS DETECTIVE!? MOURI KOGOROU
Ran!
Show me the drama you just recorded!
Geez, Dad...
Ever since we bought a new TV, you've been watching too much of it.
The culprit who murdered Kawada Naruhiko-san...
Is right among us!
Be it reheating or cooking, tastiness is auto-served!
I've got it!
The culprit is Oonuma Shun!
This trick consists of a simple application of physics.
And the murder weapon is something that
will vanish with the passing of time...
Ice!
That's why the air conditioner was set to
an extraordinarily high temperature.
Pursue the perfect close shave.
The culprit who murdered Kawada Naruhiko-san...
Oonuma Shun-san...
It was you!
The trick utilized to commit the crime
was a simple application of physics.
And the murder weapon was ice!
Would you look at that!
I nailed it!
Hey, hey...
It's against the rules to blurt out the name
of the culprit before they do in the drama!
If you've already seen it, stay quiet!
I merely deduced and said it!
This is my first time watching too!
You're lying.
I'd believe it if you had merely guessed the culprit
right, but to think even the trick is right on the mark?
Still, why does something feel out of place here?
That just goes to show that I'm a genius!
The drama just now was produced from an
original TV script and wasn't based on a novel.
The TV in this room is the type that lacks a
recording function —
the Wooo "H" series.
There's no video recorder either.
Since the PC and his cell phone were both in the living room...
It'd be impossible for him to know the
content of the drama from his room.
Wooo "H" series?
And the one in the living room...
Is the type that has a recording function —
the Wooo "XP" series!
Come to think of it, the professor said...
While this may not be my newest invention...
It's called a Wooo.
The unparalleled convenience it brings
surpasses even my own inventions!
So he had bought a Wooo...
These left by those guys from before...
Those two with the TV crew...
Uncle's abrupt display of a great deduction...
The living room that feels out of place...
In addition to this Wooo...
I see, so that's how it was!
The culprit is right among us.
And Kobayashi Hiroaki-san's murderer is...
Pressure and steam produce delicious, fast meals!
It cuts off steam, too!
I've got it today as well!
The culprit is...
Yamakami Yuuhei!
Uncle, you've already watched this drama, haven't you?
What are you talking about?
How could I have had the chance to watch this—
He's right!
The TV in Dad's room lacks a video recording function.
And when this drama aired, we were all
here watching a different show, right?
D L N A.
D L N A?
Right.
Digital Living Network Alliance.
By using that, the recording of a program from the living
room's TV can be watched on the Wooo in Uncle's room.
I didn't know that!
So the Wooo has such a function!
If you hook your Wooo up to the internet...
You can watch recorded programs even in a different room.
That's what I heard from Professor Agasa.
Uncle simply set up the Wooo in the
living room to record the drama...
And, by utilizing the DLNA server function...
He was able to fast-forward and watch
the drama on the Wooo in his room!
What the heck, Dad!?
You cheated by watching the pre-recorded
drama beforehand each and every time!?
No, no, it's not what you...
Ran-neechan...
Do you know these guys?
They're the ones who visited us here the other day, right?
And, this?
"24-Hour Close-Up Series"?
It says a close-up interview, but they haven't returned since...
This is the candid camera.
They planted it here back then.
I thought the room was out of place, turns out
it was this plant that was hiding the camera.
No way—we've been caught on tape this whole time?
No worries.
I switched off the camera beforehand.
Geez!
Dad, why did you authorize those guys to do this kind of nonsense!?
It's just a free little service!
Not to mention that they expected us to go about our
daily lives naturally for that program, didn't they!?
Geez, what were you thinking?
Be it Dad or that Shinichi!
Why do all detectives have to be like this!?
Man, unbelievable!
Why do you have to mention me there?
Unbelievable!
"24-Hour Close-Up Series"!
This time, our camera zoomed in on the famous
detective Mouri Kogorou-san and his family!
Look at me on TV!
What a handsome man I'm coming off as!
I was on tape, too!
They did a good job capturing my cool pose!
It was a facade!
This is the private life of the famous detective Mouri
Kogorou-san, who has solved trying cases left and right.
We were also able to glimpse his playful side as
he cooked up a mystery for his family to solve!
Well, I know he's a deduction freak, but...
If he's like this even when watching TV,
his family must have a really hard time.
"His family must have a really hard time," he said.
What the hell was that!?
It was a close-up interview of the famous
detective Mouri Kogorou, wasn't it!?
You should've focused on my awesome performance instead!
If only this could teach Uncle a lesson about being too showy...
Unbelievable!