"Surprise! An unexpected visit to a star's home!"
I, Tsuchiya Hitomi, now present you our third guest for the
day whose childhood home is in Saga Prefecture, Kyuushuu.
It's a Chinese restaurant!
Our third guest is right behind this door.
Now, let me take the initiative and greet her now!
Our third guest for the day is...
Yuuki Maomi-san!
We've found ourselves in the home of Maomi's parents.
What's this?
This is our specialty bun.
My little brother and I would often
share them when I was a young child.
Excuse me...
Yes?
There's something I'd like to consult with you about...
Yuuki Maomi-chan!
Huh?
TALENT YUUKI MAOMI'S WORRIES
My dad has always opposed my line of work...
My mother on the other hand, has never
ceased in her quiet support for me, but...
Because of that, my parents have been fighting.
When I tried to record a drama the other day...
I'll be recording a show at that time, so you can't!
So he said.
In the end, he always gets to record his show first, regardless of me.
Always like that!
Mom always records my every show without fail.
But, because of that, our hard disk easily reaches its max capacity.
Maybe Dad just isn't pleased about that.
Maomi-san's parents live in a place
that's also a Chinese restaurant, right?
We were just watching it on TV.
Yes, it was a small eatery in Kyuushuu.
I thought I could be of help to my father even just a little, so
I arranged an interview with the show I'm working on, but...
Apparently it had the opposite effect.
We say kids know not the extent of their parents' love...
But it's the parents that know not the child's love in your case!
Conan-kun...
What are you watching?
The show we just recorded.
This is the television in question.
This pork bun has a funny shape!
Yeah!
Ours has two tips instead of one.
It's our most popular dish.
It wasn't on our menu before, I should note.
Is that so?
Dad always treated me with this dish
when I visited the restaurant as a child.
So I've always thought that it was on the menu.
We only added it to the menu after you left for Tokyo, Mao.
It looks just like a cat, which is really cute!
Cat?
I see!
A father who opposes his daughter's line of work...
A mother who secretly records her
daughter's showbiz achievements...
The recorder in the Chinese restaurant that is her parent's home...
And...
The intriguing shape of that pork bun!
My suggestion is that your parents should
live separately for the time being.
Dad?
I was only joking.
I've figured it out...
The cause of your parents' discord and the
strained relationships in your family!
Before I reveal that, Maomi-san...
I should make it clear that your father...
Has ceased disagreeing with your work.
Right?
The person who's eavesdropping at the door—Maomi's father.
Dad?
Conan!
Yes!
Look at the shape of the tips.
Don't you think they resemble cat ears if you just look at it?
It's true!
But, what about it?
Mao!
Right.
In Chinese, cats are called "mao".
Thinking of Maomi-san who's working hard in Tokyo...
And with the Mao, or cat-shaped pork buns...
He decided to honor you with them, right?
Mao Pao.
cat
bun
That's the real name of this Chinese pork bun.
I get it...
That's why you added the buns to
the menu after Mao left for Tokyo.
And ever since, you've been diligently kneading
the dough for the buns every morning.
I didn't know that was your intention...
Lies!
Then, why did you have to pick a fight with Mom?
That's because...
At the time Mao's show was about to air...
Your mom tried to record some frivolous drama!
Is that so?
Oh my goodness, I had no idea!
That problem was the result of the TV and
recorder you're using in your restaurant.
If you had used this new Wooo model to record...
You could've watched your favorite show on one such TV...
And recorded two different programs simultaneously.
Not to mention both programs can be recorded at
8X speed mode for a considerable period of time.
That allows you to use your hard disk
more efficiently and to store more video.
And, if you search by cast names or keywords...
You can effectively narrow it down to the
show you plan to watch and record it!
If we use that, it won't be a problem even if Mao's
show and my favorite drama coincide with each other...
And we'll never inadvertently miss Mao's show!
Conan!
Show them the cassette hard disk.
Ta-da!
If I take the cassette hard disk...
And simply insert it like this...
I can record at 8X speed for a long while on it.
And if I switch disks...
I can record as many as I want!
That means we can preserve every
installment of Mao's shows with this!
By keeping the cassette hard disks handy...
You can take the recorded programs elsewhere to
a Wooo of the same type and watch them there!
So, for some of Mao's shows that can only be seen in Tokyo...
Dad, Mom!
I'm going to purchase a new Wooo, and bring you
my Tokyo shows the next time I come to visit!
Even if we are separated, our family will
always be reunited by Wooo, right?
I'm happy for them, Conan-kun!
There is only one truth!
And families are united as one by Wooo!
Right?
Thank you for everything.
Uhm, where's Mouri-san?
Sorry about that...
Don't worry about Uncle.
He should wake up sometime soon.
Bye for now.
Thank you, little detective!
Ah-le-le?
Your face is all red!
"Little detective"!
What's wrong with yooou?
Just kidding!
I kid, I kid.
Where's Maomi-chan?
Leaving me behind!?
Maomi-chan!
And me too?
Maomi-chaaan!
This production is a work of fiction
(In other words: Although Yuuki Maomi is an actual celebrity,
her character presented here in no way reflects her life)