Hey, hey!
Do you know that recording image
or sound inside a cinema is a crime?
According to the law,
you can be sentenced to
a maximum of 10 years in prison,
a maximum fine of 10 million yen, or both.
Mr. Camera Man!
I know that!
According to the law, you can be sentenced to a maximum of
2 years in prison or a maximum fine of 2 million yen, or both.
Downloading music or
commercially available footage
which you know has been illegally
uploaded is also a crime... Right?
Kid! What are you doing here?
I just dropped by to
give out an announcement...
I think I'll face you some other time, yet...
I'm counting on you, Detective!
He's as smug as always...
No more movie thieves!
Creating, selling, or sharing unauthorized recording DVDs or posting them online is a crime.
Please report them to the authorities when you find them.
"Let's go to the movies!" Executive Committee, Anti-Piracy Division