Hello? It's me.
Can you come here a minute?
Yes, that's right. Lab No. 4.
I'll show you
something interesting.
Yes.
From Episode 772: "The Kudo Shinichi Aquarium Case, Part 1."
The smell?
But I didn't smell anything.
We're just like sharks.
We pick up the scent of blood,
proceed to the scene of the crime...
And use every sense we
have to draw out the culprit.
And once they've taken the bait...
We sink our razor-sharp teeth known as "evidence" into them until they're given up.
That's just what a detective does.
From Episode 773: "The Kudo Shinichi Aquarium Case, Part 2."
Isn't it better to give up on this?
In having your "Big Surprise Reunion and Romance Revival Plan"...
At an aquarium where a
murder took place, I mean.
Yeah, you're right.
Oh, no.
It's started raining.
What?
It really is!
Then, let's run home!
H-Hey!
Didn't I tell you not to run?!
But why?!
Are you kidding me?!
Why was my phone in my hood?
Oh, sorry...
I was thinking about where the killer put her phone to record a video...
And forgot that I put it in your hood.
How could you?!
I just got that, too!
Come on, don't cry!
I'll buy you a new one, eventually.
You're the worst!
Nothing good ever happens
when I'm with you, Shinichi!
Even the time we went to
the US was all spent on a case...
Alright...
Then, I'll take
you to Tropical Land.
Tropical Land?
Why such a cheerful-sounding place?
Yeah! I heard they're
building one in Tokyo.
And I certainly wouldn't expect there to be any cases occurring at an amusement park.
If it's all your treat,
Shinichi, I'll go with you.
Huh...?!
Then, how about...
If I win the regional karate tournament?
Hey, wait a sec...
Weren't you the runner-up last year?
And... Didn't the third-year
who won retire from the club?
It's a promise!
What...?
But my allowance is already pretty small...
And if you're
buying me a new phone...
Make sure you put one of the "Sea Cucumber Man" straps they sell at the Beika Aquarium on it.
Yeah, yeah.
And then...
Huh? There's still more?
Then, I guess I'll forgive
you if you do that much.
Thanks...
Man, the rain's terrible...
The forecast was way off.
I'll have what he's having.
You don't need to
check what's inside?
If it's a fake, we'll just
be taking your life instead.
I'll check mine.
Do whatever you want.
Okay. It's all here.
Thank you for waiting.
So, what's my next job?
For now, I've gotta at least
know enough to get a feel for it.
Then, did you know this?
It seems there's a rat quietly nosing around our organization lately.
So?
D-Dunno...
I haven't heard about that.
I see.
Then, my next job
is looking for that rat?
No.
We have a pretty
good idea about the rat.
Is that right?
Wow, this drink's great.
What's the name of this cocktail?
Rum.
Cointreau.
A bit of lemon juice.
X, Y, Z.
It's a drink
called "This is the End".
O-Okay...
Let me know when
you have my next job.
Is that okay, Bro?
Quietly letting him leave like that.
He's the rat, no doubt.
Yeah.
No problem.
It's a drink
called "This is the End".
It's me.
Understood.
We'll leave immediately.
So, Bro...
What do we do with this?
This weapon smuggling data.
That's of no concern.
We'll proceed as planned.
Have you had him prepare the cash to confirm if our true intentions are getting out?
Yes.
And a trap, as well.
It's not too late to decide on that,
even after we've contacted him.
Yeah, that's true!
Besides...
That place is much
too good to abandon.
Yes?
S-Shinichi?
Oh... It's you, Ran?
What you are doing
here so early in the morning?
What are you talking about?!
It's already 11! 11!
Wha...? Seriously?
Oh, you...
Thanks for having me.
So, what'd you need today?
On a Sunday, and all...
I thought so. You forgot.
Huh?
Were we doing something?
What do you mean,
"were we doing something"?!
When I said that today is the first day off from karate practice I've had in a while...
Weren't you, Shinichi, the one who said, "Then how about we go buy you a new phone"?!
S-Sorry.
I completely forgot.
Honestly.
I bet you were just up reading mysteries until the wee hours of the morning, weren't you?
Bingo.
Anyway, hurry and get changed.
I'll make something you can fill your stomach with in the meantime.
You haven't had
breakfast yet, have you?
Yeah... Thank you.
You got it? Don't forget
the "Sea Cucumber Man" strap!
Roger that.
Huh?
You know how, on the day
we went to the aquarium last week...
A car near Beika Harbor
exploded during the night, right?
Yeah.
What about it?
It looks like it
still hasn't been solved.
You're right. How scary.
Well, but I bet
it'll be solved soon.
Because Japan's
police are amazing.
Heh.
"And I, who gets called in by those amazing police, am super amazing!"
Isn't that what you want to say?
Pretty much.
Act a little humble.
That was a joke. A joke.
Well, how about we head out soon?
Okay.
There.
Mitsuhiko-kun!
Pass it here! Pass it here!
Ayumi-chan!
Here I go, Genta-kun!
Come on, bring it!
Piece of cake, piece of cake.
That was close, Ayumi-chan.
Alright, now it's my turn!
Come on, Genta-kun!
Where are you kicking it?
My bad, my bad.
Excuse us!
Please get that ball for us!
Whoa! That's amazing!
Are you a soccer player?
Yeah.
A former one, though.
Here.
Thank you so much!
Bye-bye!
If only we had a friend who's
good at soccer like that older boy...
Ayumi and the rest
of us could get better, too!
Yes, you're right.
If you hadn't quit
the soccer team, Shinichi...
"Samurai Blue" is the nickname given to the Japanese national soccer team.
You might have been a
member of Samurai Blue by now.
I'm a second-year high schooler,
so it's too early for that.
Is it?
Besides, I only played soccer to build up the motor skills that detectives require.
See, didn't even
Holmes practice fencing?
Isn't that just in novels?
But he's a famous detective that everyone around the world knows.
That's true, but...
He's incredible!
He's always calm and collected, overflowing with intelligence and refinement...
And his powers of observation
and deduction are top notch!
On top of all that, his violin
skills match those of a professional!
Sherlock Holmes,
created by author Conan Doyle...
Is the world's greatest detective!
Someone, catch him!
He stole my purse!
Anyone!
Outta my way!
Excuse me, sorry.
Please let us through.
Who the hell are you?!
Haido High, second year.
Wada Hina.
That girl...
Come on, Ran, let's go.
We've gotta help her out.
No, she'll probably be okay.
Wha...?
Damn you!
You'll pay for getting in my way!
Oh, so you're
pulling out a knife, huh?
Then I guess I'll get serious, too...
Karate?
Yeah.
You still wanna go?
She's incredible!
Wow.
That girl seems pretty strong.
Cease and desist!
No...
She doesn't just
seem strong, she is strong.
"And that was her first encounter with her unavoidable lifelong rival, after choosing a life of karate."
"Mouri Ran, age 16.
It happened in the spring."
Sonoko!
Just kidding!
What's with adding
the random narration?
And it's not even
close to spring yet!
What's the problem?
It sets the mood. The mood.
Besides, it's not my first
encounter with her or anything.
Oh, you know her?
Yeah. We've met a
number of times during matches.
More importantly, Ran!
Come to my house for a bit.
Oh...
But from here, we're going to...
You can go on a date anytime!
Let's go! Let's go!
W-Wait, Sonoko!
I'm back!
Welcome home,
Sonoko-ojosama.
Go on.
Come in, come in.
Thank you for having us.
Welcome,
Mouri-sama. Kudo-sama.
Today, I have the "Soft 'n Fluffy Cheese Tarts" I had ordered from Hokkaido.
What?
The ones with a three
month wait in reservations?
Yeah!
Let's have them together!
I will! I will!
Is that okay?
Eating so much
before your championship...
Don't blame
me if you get fat.
It's fine.
I heard that Kasumi-senpai
will join us for practice tomorrow.
So we'll be moving around
several times more than normal.
Jeez.
What a nagging husband.
H-Hey. What do
you mean, "husband"...?
What is it, Sonoko?
Sorry. Do we have guests?
Welcome home, Sonoko.
Oh, my.
How unbefitting, not even knocking.
Not at all.
It's great that she's so lively.
I suppose you would
be the daughter of the family?
Yes. She's my
second daughter, Sonoko.
It's a pleasure to meet you.
Honestly,
she is very embarrassing.
She lacks in self-awareness as a successor of the Suzuki Financial Group.
Don't you have
my big sister for that?
This is a matter of being prepared.
Oh, that's right.
The ones behind my daughter are her friends,
Mouri Ran-san and Kudo Shinichi-kun.
Ran-san's father is
a former police officer...
And is currently working
as a private detective.
Why not try consulting with him regarding what you told me earlier?
No...
What he told you earlier?
Oh, it seems Sewa-san here
is holding a party this weekend...
And took the trouble to come
with his wife to invite me...
But I have prior arrangements with opening the jewel exhibit at the Beika Museum that day...
And am unable to attend.
Ah, the one that Uncle Jirokichi
was saying about the Black Star.
Yes.
However, from
what Sewa-san tells us...
It seems they have received a threatening letter ordering them to cancel their party.
Saying one of the party
guests will lose their life.
I see.
If that's it...
Then leave it up to
Kudo Shinichi-kun, here!
Oh?
What are you trying to hide?
Shinichi-kun is a high school
detective who's solving countless cases!
This might be rude to Ran, but he might be more reliable than her dad!
If you request me,
I may be able to be of assistance.
That's certainly promising.
However, we have taken precautions by increasing the number of guards...
So we do not require
the skills of a detective.
Therefore, we will be
excusing ourselves now.
Go on.
Right.
Darling!
Man!
What're you doing?!
Can't you be careful?!
O-Oh, no...
I was saved, thanks to you.
Thank you, little lady.
Not at all.
That's Ran, for you!
Thank you so very much.
You are not injured, are you?
I'm fine.
Like my dad,
only my body's built strong.
Oh, did you mind
what I said before?
Sorry!
No, actually...
The Mouri family is incredible.
Oh, come on, Sonoko!
Kudo-kun?
Is something wrong?
Ah, no. It's nothing.
Wow!
This is really nice!
It is made from a newly developed,
extremely lightweight material...
From our very own Suzuki Financial Group's fabric manufacturer!
In addition, the sleeves
are slightly more narrow...
So the lack of bagginess
makes it easier to move in.
You see, despite how I look,
I am quite a martial arts enthusiast.
But is it really
okay for me to have this?
It's fine. It's fine.
Actually, even I took
a tiny part in designing it.
You did?
Yeah!
Call me "Sonoko-sama,
the charismatic designer"!
As long as you
have that uniform on...
You'll win,
make no mistake!
That's the power of love for you!
Oh, about that...
What is it?
What's wrong?
She can't use that
uniform in the match.
What? Is that true?
Yes. There are regulations even about the uniforms used in each match.
I'm sorry, Sonoko.
But I'll wear this during
practice and do the best I can.
Oh, well, I guess.
But you've gotta win to make
up for this, or I won't accept it!
My apologies
to you, too, ma'am.
That is quite all right.
We are unable to go and
cheer for you, but do your best!
I will.
In the end, we missed our
chance to go buy you a phone.
Yeah.
Well, I'm going to head home after picking up some things for dinner.
Sure.
And I'll get you a
phone some other time.
Okay.
Bye.
Take care.
I left my wallet
at your house, Shinichi!
Jeez.
Shinichi!
Shinichi?
I found my wallet,
so I'm going home now.
Sure.
But at any rate, this is
an incredible number of books.
And all of them are
are mystery novels, no less.
It must be because
he read all of these...
That your dad was able to become a world-famous mystery writer, Shinichi.
Though you, Shinichi, only
turned into a mystery geek.
Shuttit.
And to top it all off, your mom is the legendary and beautiful actress, Fujimine Yukiko.
I'm really jealous.
There's nothing good about it.
Hey, I bet your first love
is your mom. Isn't it, Shinichi?
N-No, it's not!
Then who is it?
My first love is...
Who is it?
Can you give me
a break, Professor Agasa?
How's it going?
Is your homework coming along?
I think it's getting close to
the time you should sleep.
But you were probably
wide awake, weren't you?
Oww...
Hold still, Professor.
Sorry.
So, what were you
experimenting with this time?
Oh, so you are interested?
Not at all.
Oh, well. If you're going
to say all of that, I'll tell you.
Ta-da!
It's my "Personal Mobility Rocket"!
No "ta-da"s!
When I've completed it,
traffic congestion will be eliminated...
And I'll be filthy rich!
Accidents will cease,
and I'll be even richer!
Oh, but isn't
that pretty dangerous?
Isn't it basically just like a missile?
What are you saying?
Safety comes first in everything I create.
What happened
before was just by chance.
Shinichi!
P-P-Professor!
Hopeless.
What was that?
You're so irritating!
Quit your nagging!
I wanna turn down
being with you, too!
But Ran, on the other hand...
As a parent, isn't supporting
one's daughter a given?
What I'm saying is...
I mean, don't you have a much more important responsibility that comes before that?
When it comes down to it, you haven't gotten any requests for work this month, either.
Why are you assuming that?!
I looked for
three animals this month!
Three animals?
What is that?!
A 'great' private detective
is looking for some lost dogs?!
It wasn't dogs! It was cats!
Don't take me lightly!
Why, just the other day...
I'm home!
I came on the scene of a famous actress and her producer having an affair...!
What?
That is a case! A very big case!
Then, I'll call you when dinner's ready.
You? A 'first-class business consultant?'
You're acting so smug!
You're trying to
manipulate me, aren't you?!
But that company president...
Why'd he go out of his way to choose a place that draws attention like that...
As the place we
carry out our dealings?
He's probably underestimating us, thinking that even we couldn't cause any problems there.
Even if he brought a partner with him, that crowded place would act as a good front.
So it really is a trap...
Bourbon was saying that company president's been going along with the Deisankai.
Bourbon, huh?
He has a sharp nose, as usual.
Well, even so...
It's not a problem as
long as we know about it.
It just allows us to
beat him at his own game.
Stop!
She did it!
All right!
Blue: one upper kick.
Blue's victory.
Amazing! That's amazing!
Ran's amazing!
The final round's next, sir!
Easy win! Easy win!
Because no matter what, Ran inherited her strength in these matches from me, her father!
I pray she doesn't take after how you instantly get carried away and then have the rug pulled out from under you.
Huh?
Well, Ran is my daughter,
so I don't think I need to worry.
Why, you...
Ran! Put your fighting
spirit into the final, too!
That said, where'd that
guy go at a time like this?
Yes. Yes.
Understood.
I'll head there now.
Inspector.
The final match of the freestyle karate,
women's division, will now begin.
On the red team,
from Haido High: Ms. Wada Hina.
Ready!
On the blue team,
from Teitan High: Ms. Mouri Ran.
Ready!
Begin!
Yes, yes!
That's it. That's it.
Calm down, Ran.
Stop!
Advantage: Red.
Mid-body kick.
Continue!
Stop!
Oh, what are you doing, Ran?!
Ran!
Put your fighting spirit in it!
Fighting spirit!
Willpower! Spirit! Guts!
Calm down!
Shinichi? What is it?
C...
...as...
...e...
A case?
It's always, always that!
Always 'case this, case that!'
You mystery geek!
I want you to get this over with.
I do not have the time to go along with your fruitless investigation.
Now, don't say that.
Because it's certain that the one behind this murder is amongst your group.
In that case, hurry up
and find who this "killer" is...
I already know.
Who the killer is, anyway.
Oh, Kudo-kun!
We were waiting for you.
Sorry I'm late.
Who is that guy?
He seems awfully young.
Have you forgotten?
We met the other day
at the Suzuki residence.
At the Suzuki residence?
What are you trying to hide?
Shinichi-kun is a high school
detective who's solving countless cases!
That high school detective?
The president of
Beika Bank, Mr. Yamazaki...
Was murdered in this
mansion's third-floor guest room...
Right in the middle of
where this party is being held.
The cause of death
is being stabbed with a knife.
The door to the room was locked...
And the key was
in Yamazaki's pocket.
The only way in was from the balcony window overlooking the courtyard.
In other words, the killer sneaked in through the balcony window...
Killed Yamazaki,
who was resting there...
And fled back through
the balcony window.
But there weren't any footprints
under that window, were there?
Besides, all the rooms around the guest room were locked up tightly.
Yes. There were, indeed,
no footprints below the window...
And the windows
around it were also locked.
Then how?
They flew in.
What?
That's ridiculous!
Oh, come on...
W-Wait, Kudo-kun?
Of course, they didn't
come flying through the sky.
You see, there's a small window diagonally across from the window to the crime scene.
The killer flew from that window over to the guest room's window.
Don't talk nonsense!
Those two windows are
at least five meters apart!
There's no way
someone could do that...
Although narrow, there was a overhang that goes along from the small window to the roof.
If one uses that as a foothold, and moves along the edge of the wall...
It's only one or two
meters to the balcony.
In other words, the killer is someone who knows all about the unique construction of this mansion.
And someone who could move around the mansion at that time, without raising anyone's suspicions.
T-Then hurry up and spill it!
Who's the one who
killed President Yamazaki?
It's...
You!
Yamazaki's best friend...
And master of this house...
Sewa Takanori-san!
Stop spewing nonsense!
How in the world could I,
with this leg...?!
The evidence is
already stacked against you!
What're you doing, you bastard?!
D-Dad!
Master.
Huh?
Darling, your leg...
I noticed this when I met
you at the Suzuki residence.
To try to stop your
malfunctioning wheelchair...
You held that
leg out on the floor!
That leg's already healed, isn't it?
D-Damn it!
Stop!
You're not getting away!
Goal!
Oh, we had to rely
on you again, Kudo-kun.
Not a problem.
If you have any more difficult cases, just call for me, Detective Kudo Shinichi.
Hey, did you hear?
That high school detective
pulled off another one.
Yeah, he's awesome!
He can, most certainly, be called
the savior of the Japanese police.
Oww...
What're you doing?
You're grinning and
laughing like an idiot.
Ran, are you
upset about something?
No, nothing.
I'm not upset that my Dad gets less work because you got involved, or anything!
But it's not my fault your dad doesn't get any work, Ran, it's his lack of skill.
Isn't that why
I'm saying I'm not mad?
That's the karate
team captain, for you.
Honestly!
Everyone's making a big fuss about
"great detective this" and "great detective that"...
When you're just
a plain mystery geek!
But look at all these fan letters!
Everyone says they
like this "mystery geek".
Oh, is that right?
Fawning over girls is fine...
But you need to pick
which one you really like.
The one I really like, huh?
I mean, really...
What?
You've been staring at
my face for a while now.
Oh, uh. It's nothing.
If you keep conceitedly
poking your nose into cases...
One of these days, you'll
find yourself in real danger.
Maybe.
But why a detective?
If you like
mystery novels so much...
Why not become
a novelist like your dad?
I don't want to
write about detectives.
I want to be one.
A modern-day
Sherlock Holmes, that is!
The more difficult the case,
the more exciting it is!
The thrill, the suspense you get driving the tricky culprit into a corner!
Once you've done it,
you just can't stop!
That's a detective.
See you!
Hey!
Wait, Shinichi!
Huh?
You haven't forgotten what you promised we'd do tomorrow, have you?
Promised?
Weren't you the one who said you'd take me to Tropical Land if I won the regional tournament?!
Huh?
What're you talking about?
Oh, forget it.
I didn't really want to
go with you, anyway, Shinichi.
Why don't you go play there with one of the girls who sent you a fan letter?
I'm joking, I'm joking!
Don't be mad. I remember.
Tropical Land, tomorrow at 10.
There's no way I could forget that.
And don't forget that
it's all your treat, Shinichi.
Wait, that's right!
Hey!
W-Wait a second, Ran!
You're kidding!
We come back to Japan
for the first time in ages...
And we're going to
leave without seeing our son?
I put a lot of work into this disguise, thinking I could surprise Shin-chan, too...
It was a waste of effort.
Well, I got these old
materials back from Japan...
So why don't we save
these disguises for another time?
Besides...
It looks like we'd
just be pesky bugs.
I wanna bug Shin-chan
and have him get mad at me.
Here.
I bet you're thirsty.
T-Thanks.
This way, this way!
Hey, where're
we going, Shinichi?
Don't worry about that,
just follow me.
Ten...
Nine...
Eight...
Seven...
Six...
Five...
Four...
Three...
Two...
One...
Zero!
Wow! Wow!
This is amazing!
You like this
kinda thing, don't you?
Yeah!
And so, one of the things
that's so amazing about Holmes...
Is when he first
met his assistant, Watson...
And just by shaking his hand...
He could tell he had went to
Afghanistan as a military physician.
Kinda like this.
You're part of a
gymnastics team, aren't you?
H-How'd you know...?
What?
Do you know him, somehow?
Who knows?
It's her hand.
For a girl to have all
these blisters on their hand...
They could only be someone working on the metal, horizontal bar in gymnastics.
But you can get blisters
by playing tennis, too...
Oh, you...
Actually, when the wind
blew her skirt up earlier, I saw...
She has a unique bruise on her thighs that can
develop on those who work the uneven horizontal bar.
Never neglecting one's observations
is fundamental for a detective!
What're you bragging about?
Isn't it cheating if you knew
before you shook her hand?
Hey, you!
Don't be botherin' my pals!
Oh, are these your friends?
Why, yes...
In that case, should
we trade places in line?
No, that's fine.
We would be rude
to bother those two.
Ran, to tell you the truth...
For the longest time, I've...
Shinichi, I have too.
Shinichi?
Shinichi, hurry up!
O-Oh, sure!
Thanks for riding!
Watch your step
on your way out.
Man, that was scary.
I wanna ride it again.
And then, that
was when Holmes...
And two more, come ahead.
You get it?
Conan Doyle must
have wanted to say this.
That Holmes is...
Enough!
Give me a break with all
this "Holmes" and "Conan Doyle"!
You mystery geek!
I had been really looking forward to coming here with you, Shinichi, too...
Why won't
you realize how I feel?
Ran...
Um...
Actually, I, too...
You dummy.
What are you
getting flustered for?
I was obviously kidding!
Wha...?!
Dammit.
Oh, did you
take that seriously?
You won't make it as a detective
if you fall for things like that.
We will now be
heading out of the station!
Off you go!
But you know...
The part about looking
forward to this is true.
Damn. What's this?
We don't get a turn?
Come on,
we're pulling out of this.
He said to withdraw.
What's this?
You wanna ride that?
What's this? Water?
It's salty?
What is this?!
Huh...?!
What the...?!
Thanks for riding!
Watch your
step on your way...
It's an accident!
Someone,
call an ambulance!
Call the police, too!
Why did Kishida-kun have to...?
Shinichi.
What an unlucky guy.
Anyway, this is an accident.
We'll have you let us leave.
Wait.
This isn't an accident.
It's a murder.
And the murderer's amongst the seven of us who rode the same coaster as the victim.
Shinichi.
We can't tag along with you.
Excuse us!
Please let us through! Excuse us!
Sorry, here it is.
Oh, Kudo-kun!
Oh, and Ran-kun's
here with you?
Ah, Inspector Megure.
Kudo?
Oh, so that's the famous
high school detective, Kudo Shinichi?
Having solved countless hard, dead-end cases, he's the so-called...
Savior of the Japanese police!
Hey, come here! Come here!
It's Kudo-kun! Kudo-kun!
I'll take this chance to
see your amazing skills in action!
No, I'm flattered.
Oh, you...
I see.
There's certainly no signs of an accident or malfunction of any kind on the roller coaster itself...
And from looking at his condition, the chances of this being a suicide are also slim.
Yes.
That's why this is
clearly a murder, Inspector.
However,
who killed him, and how?
Inspector.
We'll have those who were
riding with him remain here...
But the rest of
you are free to leave.
Wha...?
Aw...
It's not an accident?
What's going on here?
Please stand back!
This coaster seats eight.
So, excluding you and Ran-kun for the time being, there are five possible suspects.
Riding in the first row were the victim's friends, 'Friend A' and 'Friend B'.
Riding in the third
row alongside the victim...
Was the victim's
friend and lover, 'C'.
And lastly, riding behind the victim were the men in black, 'D' and 'E'.
But that being the case, because everyone was locked in by the safety guard and couldn't move about...
Which means only the woman sitting next to him could have killed him...
Ah, no. It might be
possible for the men behind her.
Hey, hurry this up.
We don't have time to stick around here while you play detective.
B-Bro...
I apologize, but
please stay here a little longer.
What with
this guy's ice-cold eyes?
Those are the eyes of one who's killed countless people and is completely fine with it.
W-Who in the world is he?
Inspector Megure.
What is it, Chiba-kun?
We found this
in this woman's purse.
No way!
I don't know
anything about that!
Aiko!
Why'd you do
something like that?!
Wha...?!
N-No, it wasn't me!
I thought things were going well with you and Chiba-kun, too, so why?!
You have to believe me!
I didn't do it!
Come on, come on.
It's obvious that amateur's the killer.
Hurry and let us
leave, Mr. Detective.
What?
They found the killer a lot
easier than I thought they would.
I thought that
woman smelled rotten, too.
Was this caused by a lover's spat?
Man, women are scary...
Okay, take that woman
in as our prime suspect!
Come along.
T-This can't be...
And as a precaution, we'll confirm the identities of the others who were riding the roller coaster.
That's not a problem, is it?
Please wait, Inspector.
Oh?
What's wrong, Kudo-kun?
She's not the murderer.
S-Shinichi?
Kudo-kun.
The one who murdered the victim, Kishida-san, on this roller coaster...
Is you!
W-What?!
What are you saying?!
You saw the knife that came
out of Aiko's purse, didn't you?
A person's neck cannot be
severed by something like that.
Especially with
a woman's strength.
Besides, if she was the killer...
She would have had plenty of
chances to get rid of the weapon.
There was no reason she would need to wrap a cloth around it and put it in her purse.
In order to frame
Aiko-san for the crime...
You put that in her
purse beforehand, didn't you?
D-Don't say
something so ridiculous!
You know I was riding two rows in front of Kishida-kun, who died, right?!
So how are you saying I
could cut off Kishida-kun's head?
In the first place,
didn't you just say so?
That it couldn't be severed
with a woman's strength?
It's certainly true that it's impossible with just a woman's strength.
However, it's possible if you use
the speed of the coaster...
Along with some
piano wire or steel rope!
Inspector Megure, I'd like
the help of all the officers...
To attempt to reenact the crime.
O-Okay, I don't mind, but...
Everyone understand?
I'm playing the role of
the murderer, Hitomi-san...
And Inspector Megure's taking the role of the victim, Kishida-san.
First, before
lowering the safety guard...
You sit with some sort of bag
or something against your back...
Then lower the guard.
Then, before the crime...
If you pull the bag out from behind your back, it creates an opening...
And see?
You can easily get out.
Next, you pull out the
piano wire or steel rope...
You've pre-prepared as a noose with some sort of hook-like apparatus attached...
Plant your feet on the safety guard, stretch your body behind you...
And place the noose
around the victim's neck.
In the pitch-black tunnel, of course.
And finally, you toss the hook on the end of the noose out, so it latches onto the coaster's rails.
Then the speed and power of the coaster will rip through the victim's neck for you in an instant.
That's nonsense!
Like I could do that
on a fast-moving coaster!
No...
You do gymnastics.
Putting other girls aside...
You, who's been trained
in your sense of balance...
Can do this much,
even atop a coaster.
Hey!
Will you knock this o...
What happened
to your necklace?
The pearl necklace you had around your neck before getting on the coaster.
You swapped out the thread
in your necklace for piano wire...
And had the hook attached
to it hidden in that purse.
Wait a second!
Couldn't the
way you just described...
Be done by those two, who were sitting behind Kishida-kun, just as easily?
No.
Those two do,
indeed, seem suspicious...
But they didn't kill him.
How do you know?
I don't know the reason
they rode the roller coaster...
But from the
moment the police arrived...
It's strange how their
attitude quickly changed...
And wouldn't stop saying they wanted to get away from here quickly.
Because if they were the killers,
they should have known this would happen.
That's right. The killer knew
that the victim was going to die.
That's why they cried.
What's this? Water?
From the minute we came out of the tunnel
and found that the victim had died, until now...
Not much time has passed.
In other words, no one besides the killer could shed a long trail of tears while riding the coaster.
So you're saying you saw
Hitomi crying on the coaster?
Can you prove that?!
The traces of her
tears is unshakable proof.
As long as one isn't
riding a roller coaster...
Tears...
Can't flow horizontally.
It's all...
It's all that man's fault!
Because that man dumped me!
Hitomi, don't tell me...
Were you and Kishida-kun dating?
That's right!
We loved each other long
before we met all of you in college!
But for Aiko...
For this woman, he...!
That's why... That's why...
On the roller coaster
we rode on our first date...
Using the necklace I got from him...
And pinning the crime on Aiko...
I wanted to kill him!
Later, a large quantity of sleeping
medicine was found in her purse.
It seems that
after the murder...
She planned to follow Kishida-san
in death by committing suicide.
Two hours later, the necklace used in the
murder was also located in the tunnel.
The thread had been, as I had thought, swapped out for piano wire...
And most of the pearls scattered.
The ones left basked in the
setting sun, giving off a faint light.
Almost as if they
shed a long trail of tears.
Oh, come on.
Don't cry anymore.
You sure can
take this well, can't you?
Because I'm used
to seeing crime scenes...
You know,
torn-up bodies and stuff...
That's horrible!
No, no...
It's best to forget
about it as soon as possible.
Because this kinda thing
happens all the time, you know.
It does not!
That man...
If I'm right, that's one of the suspicious guys who were riding the coaster.
It was you, Shinichi, who said there wouldn't be any cases at an amusement park...
Sorry, Ran.
Head home ahead of me.
I'll catch up with you in a bit!
Shinichi!
He's leaving...
For some reason, it was
then that I had a feeling.
The horrible feeling that from that point on, I could never see Shinichi again...
Damn... I lost him?
Sorry for the wait, Mr. President.
There he is!
I came alone, as I promised!
Yeah, I know you came alone.
Because I confirmed
from atop the coaster.
Hurry and give me it!
Don't get ahead of yourself.
The money comes first!
Here! With this, I take
it you have no objections?
Whoa! That's at
least a hundred million!
Okay.
This concludes our transaction.
Now hurry
and give me the film!
Film?
Here.
That's the incriminating negatives and prints that show your company smuggling weapons.
You shouldn't be doin' bad things.
Shut up!
Compared to what your
organization's doing, we're just...
Hey.
Exactly what
do you know about us?
Huh?!
Uh, no...
For this mere hundred million...
We're saying we'll settle
this without taking your life!
If you got that, then you'll immediately shut down your company and move elsewhere.
Because we only want that
land to build a new lab on.
O-Okay...
Oh, man. Seriously?
That's as far as your
little detective game goes.
Bro...
You dumbass. Letting
yourself be followed by this kid.
T-This kid's that
detective from earlier!
Damn. Should I kill him?
Stop.
The cops from the earlier
disturbance are still loitering about.
Then what do we do?
Let's use this.
This poison, newly developed
by our "organization".
Claiming to be a poison fully unable to be extracted from the body...
It's a substance that
makes a perfect crime possible.
Though, apparently, it's a prototype
drug yet to be tested on humans.
Bro, we've gotta hurry.
Yeah.
Farewell, 'great detective'.
Damn!
My body's burning up!
It's like...
It's like my bones are melting...!
Damn it...
I can't go on...
Hey, get over here!
Someone's dead!
What?!
So I really did die?
No, he's still breathing!
An ambulance!
Call an ambulance!
I'm alive?
I get it. That drug
didn't work on humans.
How lucky!
How awful.
There's blood pouring down his head.
The police?
And a lot of 'em...
Alright!
At least I'll expose
every one of those guys' crimes!
Come on.
Stay with me, now.
Can you stand...
Little boy?
Huh?
Are you okay, little boy?
Little boy?
What's he talking about?
I'm a second-year high schooler!
How'd you get those
wounds on your head?
Wounds?
Oh, I know!
When I was hit from
behind by that man in black...
Oww...
Huh?
W-What happened to my clothes?
I bet you were scared.
Weren't you, little boy?
But we're here now, so don't worry.
T-This guy...
Lifts my body so easily...
Yes, we're under the ferris wheel...
And we've taken a young boy
with cranial injuries into our care.
We'll carry him to
the medical room now.
He's six or seven years old.
I believe he's most likely
an elementary schooler.
Who's an elementary schooler?!
I'm home!
Oh!
Ran, you're back?
Come on, Dad!
You made a mess like this again?
It's because you're like this
that requests for work never come...
And why even
Mom ran out on you!
Shut up!
I choose which jobs I take!
So what happened with
that so-called detective guy?
Weren't you with him today?
I'll catch up with you in a bit!
I wonder what
happened to Shinichi?
A-ha, did you two
get into an argument?
Just forget him.
'Cause there aren't any good
guys that're detectives, anyway.
But aren't you a detective, Dad?
Haven't I been
telling you this whole time?!
I saw them!
A man who's smuggling weapons, and a man blackmailing him with negatives of that!
But one more of their
companions found me...
And bam! He whacked
me on the head from behind.
Come on, little boy.
You watch too many police dramas.
I am NOT a kid!
I'm a second-year high schooler!
Strange.
Something's weird about this.
We just checked, but it doesn't look like there are any applicable reports of lost children.
Everyone's reactions...
His head is injured and bleeding...
These baggy clothes...
And then...
This voice of mine.
Damn...
Is such a thing even possible?
No...
No matter how
improbable something may be...
There's always only one...
What the...?
This can't be happening, can it?
To think my body has actually shrunk...
Like I said, he doesn't want to go home,
and is telling us these wild stories.
So, there's a high chance
he ran away from home, after all?
For now, all we can do
is contact headquarters...
And have them watch him
in the police child care center.
C-Child care center?
Okay, little boy...
He's gone!
The window!
He escaped through the window!
You've gotta be kidding me...!
Like I'd let myself be put in a place like that!
Hey! Little boy!
It's huge!
There he is! This way!
Damn it...
Stop right there, little boy!
Jeez, am I some kind
of criminal or something?
Hey! Little boy!
Hey!
Hey, what about over there?
Ran...
All right! If I have Ran
come here and pick me up...
But with my voice as it is now...
And this body, too...
Damn...
I know!
If I at least text her...
No.
There's no way I could
explain something like this.
If you keep conceitedly
poking your nose into cases...
One of these days, you'll
find yourself in real danger.
Search that area thoroughly!
D-Damn! Damn! Damn!
Hi, this is Kudo.
I'm currently out of the house.
If you need me,
leave a message after the beep.
He's not back home, either.
He must be out havin' dinner with
that famous author dad of his, or somethin'.
What are you talking about?
Shinichi's parents have lived in the United States for the past three years...
And Shinichi now
lives by himself, you know?
Oh? Does he?
Something really
did  happen after that!
I'm going to
Shinichi's house for a bit!
Huh?
Hey!
What about my dinner?
To think I could be out of
breath after only running this far...
What in the world
happened to my body, anyway?
Wait!
If I remember right,
after those guys hit me...
Let's use this. A poison newly
developed by our "organization".
Though, apparently, it's a prototype
drug yet to be tested on humans.
Don't tell me...
It's because I took that drug?
It couldn't be...
You dumbass!
What're you doing,
standing in the middle of the road?!
Be careful,
you damn twerp!
A twerp?
This's pathetic.
Dammit!
Ah, damn it!
I can't even get
into my own house?!
I can't do
anything like this, can I?!
Oh, no! This is bad!
Huh?
Ah!
Oh?
Professor Agasa!
Oh!
Who are you?
It's me! Me!
Shinichi!
Oh, so you're a child
of Shinichi's relatives?
Come to think of it, you look a lot like Shinichi did when he was little.
No! I'm Shinichi!
Look! Kudo Shinichi,
second-year at Teitan High School.
Hey, Shinichi.
You have a visitor.
Ah!
You don't believe me, do you?!
Ah, oww...
Hey, are you okay?
Then how about I
talk about you, Professor?!
Agasa Hiroshi, 52 years old.
You're an eccentric inventor
who lives next door to me...
You call yourself a genius,
but you've made nothing but junk.
Even worse, you have a mole on your butt with a hair growing out of it.
My butt's...
Only Shinichi
should know about that...
Don't tell me that darn Shinichi's been spreading my secrets around...
I didn't hear
about it, I am Shinichi!
I was forced to take some
weird drug, and was shrunk!
A drug... shrunk you?
Yeah.
A drug?
If there is such a drug,
I want to see it for myself!
Come with me. I'm handing you suspicious little punk over to the police.
Then...
Then how about this?!
Professor, you just got home from the "Columbo" restaurant, didn't you?
And in quite a hurry, at that.
H-How'd you know that?
Your clothes, Professor.
The front has signs of
being wet, but not the back.
Huh?
That's proof you
were running in the rain.
In addition, you have
mud splashed on your pants.
What?
The only muddy road in this area is front of "Columbo", which is under construction.
Furthermore, you have the distinctive color of Columbo's specialty meat sauce on your mustache.
Then, you're...
Elementary, my dear Agasa.
S-Shinichi?
Are you really Shinichi?
Haven't I been saying that all along?
I was shrunk by some drug!
I still can't believe it.
Scientifically speaking,
such a thing shouldn't be...
But the thing
about my butt before...
Just let me into
my house for now!
What?!
Smuggling weapons?
Yeah.
I saw a man blackmailing
him with negatives of it, too.
So they gave you the
drug to keep your mouth shut?
I get it.
So basically, a strange side
effect of the incomplete drug...
Is that it shrunk your body?
Yeah, that's it.
Please, Professor.
You're a genius, right?
Make a drug to change
my body back to normal.
Don't be absurd!
If I don't know the
composition of that drug...
Talk about lame.
The clothes from when
I was a kid fit perfectly.
Then I just need to track
down their whereabouts...
And get a hold of the drug, right?
Yes. If we had that drug,
I might be able to do something.
But, Shinichi.
You mustn't tell anyone
besides me that you've been shrunk!
What? Why?
You're still alive.
In other words, if they
know you're Kudo Shinichi...
Those guys will likely
come targeting your life again!
And it'll put those
around you in danger, as well.
You got it?
The fact that you're really Kudo Shinichi
is a secret between just the two of us.
You mustn't
ever tell anyone else.
Of course, that
means not even Ran-kun!
Okay, I got it.
Shinichi? Are you here?
Oh, you!
If you're home, at
least pick up the phone!
And you left
the door unlocked.
I-I-It's Ran!
This is bad!
Hurry and hide!
H-Hide? W-Where?
Oh, Professor Agasa?
O-Oh, wow.
It's been quite a while, Ran-kun.
Where's Shinichi?
Well, um...
He was just here, but...
Well...
Something suddenly came up,
and he head out again in a hurry.
My dad's glasses.
A disguise, a disguise.
Oww!
Wha...?
Ah!
Who's this boy?
Oh...
That boy's, well...
Oh, you.
You're a real
shy one, aren't you?
Come on, look this way.
T-This is bad!
This boy's...
Crap...
So cute!
Her chest...
Hey, Professor.
Who is this boy?
Oh, um... He's the child
of a distant relative of mine.
How old are you?
I'm sixte... Wait, no.
I'm six!
Oh, so you're a first grader?
Y-Yeah!
What's your name?
My name is Shin-
No...
Um...
Um... My name is...
Conan!
Wha...?
My name is Edogawa Conan!
Crap.
I said that without thinking.
Conan?
That's an unusual name.
My dad's a big fan
of Conan Doyle, and...
He seems
kind of like Shinichi.
"Doyle" works,
but you meant "drill" right?
Professor?
What's with "Conan"?
It's not like you're a foreigner.
What else could I say?!
I couldn't think of anything else!
I know. Ran-kun...
I'm sorry, but could you take care of him at your house for the time being?
You've gotta be kiddi...!
This boy's parents were
hospitalized due to an accident...
I was asked to look after him,
but I'm a man living by myself, so...
Yes, that's fine with me.
But I'll have to ask my dad.
I see, I see!
So you'll take him in?
Oww...
Freeloading at Ran's place?
What do I do if she
finds out who I really am?
Just listen.
Those men in black will eventually find out that your body wasn't discovered.
And when that happens...
Don't you think the first they'll suspect are the ones going in and out of this house?
Then isn't your
house fine, Professor?
For you to go back
to your normal body...
Don't you have to first look for the men who used the drug on you?
Well, that's true...
Ran-kun's home is
a detective agency.
Ah, I get it!
Information on them might come in.
Exactly.
Excuse me, Professor?
Yay! I wanna go
to your house, Miss!
He's so cute!
Okay, Professor.
When Shinichi gets home, tell him to call me.
All right, I will.
See you, mister!
Bye-bye!
See you later, C-Conan-kun.
I hope the rest
goes well for you, Shinichi.
Uh, no...
Edogawa Conan-kun.
Hey, Conan-kun.
Conan-kun?
What is it, Ran-neechan?
I'm not used to this name.
Do you have
someone you like, Conan-kun?
You know, isn't there someone
at school you're interested in?
No, no one like that.
I have someone.
Someone I'm really interested in.
Oh? By any chance...
It wouldn't be that "Shinichi" guy you were just looking for, would it?
It is.
He's teased me
since we were little...
Is always so full of himself...
And is a mystery geek.
But when push comes to shove, he's dependable, brave, and so cool!
I really like Shinichi!
But keep that
a secret from Shinichi.
O-Okay.
Because you're the only
one I've told, Conan-kun.
You really can't tell Shinichi!
Y-Yeah.
This is my home.
It's kind of like I
have a cute little brother.
I feel like I can tell
you anything, Conan-kun.
Ran...
Looks like my dad's home,
so I'll introduce you to him.
Come with me.
Um, Ran.
To tell you the truth, I'm...
What is it?
I'm actually...
Alright!
What is it, Dad?
It's here!
It's here! It's here!
A job! My first direct
request in six months!
Whoa...
Hey, that's dangerous!
And what kind of request?
A rich person's daughter was
kidnapped by some men in black!
Men in black?!
Conan-kun!
Just wait, you men in black.
Because once I've tracked down your whereabouts, gotten a hold of that drug...
And gone back
to my normal body...
I'll expose every
one of your crimes!
Thus, in order to obtain
information on the men in black...
I came to live at Ran's home,
where her father works as a detective.
Even so, this old man's an
unbelievably lousy detective.
Unable to let that slide,
I took the place of the old man...
And using my
natural deductive reasoning...
Along with some gadgets
Professor Agasa invented...
I went along, solving one
difficult case after another.
From Episode 11: "Moonlight Sonata Murder Case."
Don't tell me Narumi-sensei planned on dying from the very beginning...
Narumi-san!
No, Conan-kun!
Lemme go, Ran-neechan!
What's that sound?
It's the code.
He's playing it...
From within the flames.
From Episode 49: "The Diplomat Murder Case, Part 2."
You idiot...
There's no wins, losses, above, or below when it comes to deduction.
Because there's always...
only one truth.
From Episode 78: "The Eminent Family's Strange Consecutive Deaths Case, Part 2."
Hey, Hattori.
Have you...
Ever killed someone?
Huh?
You idiot...
A detective who corners a
murderer with their deductions...
But allows that person to commit
suicide before their very eyes...
Is no different from the murderer.
From Episode 223: "And Then There Were No Mermaids, The Deduction."
Hattori...
When you have
eliminated the impossible...
Whatever remains,
however improbable...
Must be the truth.
From Episode 128: "The Black Organization: One Billion Yen Robbery Case."
Didn't I tell you that
was your last chance?
Masami-san!
Ran-neechan, hurry
and call for an ambulance!
Uncle and the others, too!
All right!
There's no use.
It's already too late.
Don't talk!
If you talk, your wounds will...
Little boy...
Unless I'm mistaken, you're the boy who was at the detective agency, aren't you?
"Organization"?
Yes.
It's a large crime organization,
shrouded in mystery.
All I, who's done for, know...
Is that the color of
the "Organization" is black.
Black.
That's right.
Those in the
"Organization" prefer wearing...
Clothes... as black as crows.
Don't tell me they're...
The men in black?!
I'll leave the rest to you...
Little... detective.
From Episode 76: "Conan vs. Kaito Kid."
He's been given many
different names to describe him.
"The Modern-Day Lupin",
"The Moonlight Magician", and so on and so forth.
But there's just one
alias that most people prefer.
Alias?
Because he leads the police of many nations around by their noses like children...
A certain young novelist
with an interest in Kaito #1412...
Looked at the number
1412 and read it like this.
"K I D".
K I D?
Wait, so...
That's right.
Kaito #1412.
People call him...
Kaito Kid!
Seems you're no ordinary kid, boy.
Edogawa Conan, a detective.
Yes, that's right.
I'm on my way to the
on-location for the drama.
It's a wrap once
that's done being shot...
So I can go there.
It'll be fine if I help Pisco out
so he doesn't mess things up, right?
I happen to have
something to do there, anyway.
And I want to meet him, too.
Okay, I'm hanging up now.
I gotta lose
the FBI's little kitty.
Let's meet there, Gin.
Shoot!
Move it! Out of my way!
Move it!
It's no use.
But, Shuu...
We'll never catch up to
them with your driving technique.
But relax.
I know where she's going.
What? Where?
Japan.
Edogawa Conan?
You know, the boy with
glasses I talked to before!
Weren't you saying you went to someone's house in the Beika district to do something, too?
Yeah, Kudo Shinichi's.
Yeah, that's it!
This boy's at the detective
agency in that same neighborhood.
So what about that boy?
He's kind of strange.
I guess you could say he's
really calm and collected for a child...
Or maybe that he's really mature.
So that's it...