Dimensional Sniper
Detective Conan celebrates its 20 years!
This is a special episode for the premiere of 'Dimensional Sniper',
by Nottv!
Hi, I'm Edogawa Conan.
Have you watched the recently released movie 'Dimensional Sniper' yet?
The case of this movie is set in the tallest tower of Japan, the Bell Tree Tower.
And now, here is the trailer of the movie!
It's high!
Dimensional Sniper
Damn, you can't escape!
That was the beginning of the sniper case...
FBI!
... that opened a door to the past.
What?
So, we are dealing with a sniper...
If only Akai-san was there...
Sera-neechan, what are you doing here?
Don't make that face. Whatever happens,
I'll protect you with my life.
FBI Agent Killed in the Line of Duty
Akai Shuuichi
「Shuu...」
Shuu...
What was the purpose of the sniper who
targeted Akai Shuuichi?
Conan-kun...
And the second sniper attack!
All of Tokyo is in panic!
Begin
This must be a countdown.
Countdown to Death
What do you mean?
Watch out!
The former FBI sniper is missing!
The hidden truth will be unveiled!
Revealed
Hidden
Truth
Where are you, Shin'ichi?
Escape, Ran!
Everything depends on you, Cool Kid.
You are our last hope!
The game is over, Detective!
Dimensional Sniper
Shuu-nii...
Impossible!
This time, it is on Nottv,
for the premiere of the movie 'Dimensional Sniper'.
It had never been animated, except in an opening song of the episodes.
What is its title?
Here it is!
Actually, this story had never been adapted into anime.
On the phone, you can answer questions about this episode to win presents,
so please pay attention!
Welcome, Mouri-san.
Yes, as usual.
I'm Mouri Kogoro, a detective.
A job where you have to reveal actions that would otherwise have remained secret.
It is easy to cause resentment and be targeted.
Dealing with the idiots who do these kinds of things is also part of the job.
But running away is not my style.
Thank you for waiting.
Enjoy your drink.
By the way, Azusa-kun, could you please not tell anyone that I was here?
Huh?
To be frank,
I'm being chased.
Only the light of deductions can tear apart black shadows and deep darkness!
He sees the single truth for what it is
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
You can't escape!
That was the beginning of the sniper case...
An Incredible
Sniper Incident
Conan-kun...
... that opened a door to the past.
Was Sealed
in the Past
Watch out!
The former FBI sniper is missing!
FBI Agent
Akai Shuuichi
The hidden truth will be unveiled!
Revealed
Hidden
Truth
Shin'ichi...
Escape, Ran!
It's over.
Dimensional Sniper
Impossible!
Thank you for the cup.
It's not just embarrassing.
Welcome!
Damn, they are here.
Don't panic, keep calm...
The waitress, Azusa-chan, said she would cover up my presence here...
Everything is fine. I'll hide here, they'll never find out...
Oh, Mouri-san? He's in the toilet...
Darn it. I wasn't supposed to tell...
Are you kidding...
I didn't come here to get caught!
I just have to make it through today, and everything will be okay.
In any case, I need to find another hiding place!
A place where they can't find me!
A place like that...
... could only be there!
A leaf is hidden in a forest...
... and a person in a crowd!
Those annoying people can never find me here.
As expected from me!
Beika city's resident, Mouri Kogoro-sama,
there is someone waiting for you at Gate 5.
Oh no, they found me.
But it's not a problem.
I'll pretend I didn't hear it!
This is a racecourse, there are 50,000 people here!
Hey...
You there.
Aren't you Mouri Kogoro? The detective?
Y-yes...
Then you should get going. Someone's waiting for you at Gate 5.
Well...
Huh, isn't it the Sleeping Kogoro?
Seriously?
It's really him!
What?
Did a criminal take refuge here?
May I click a photo?
Me too, me too!
This is not good, I stand out too much...
Damn, what's with this!
These people are smarter than I thought!
I have to go to someone's place, overnight if necessary.
Overnight?
There is a way!
Mahjong?
Play Mahjong today?
Yeah. When we were in college,
we used to play at your place. I want to relive those memories.
Really...
It's Sunday,
so no one's busy, but...
But overnight? I have to do work tomorrow.
It's all right! Just play until midnight, then everything will be fine...
Everything will be fine?
No, I meant that I will win today.
Well, it's good to know you're coming.
It's good?
Yeah. Someone just called, saying they were looking for you.
What?!
They said they don't have an appointment today, but if you came by,
you should contact them, to clear things up.
Forget it, no more Mahjong!
Please pretend I didn't call!
Damn, what's their problem?
No doubt they tracked down all the people I know!
What should I do?
Think, think...
of a place where those guys couldn't find me!
Damn! I'm out of cigarettes!
That's right!
I found it... the perfect hiding place!
This place is good...
My all-new secret hideout.
What a beautiful Paris style decoration.
The old record playing the music in the background...
So soothing to the heart...
Enjoy your meal.
Finally, I can enjoy the taste of the French cuisine.
Forget those guys and relax a bit...
True, it's a really nice restaurant...
...it's his favorite restaurant.
Isn't it?
Eri? Ran?
But did he really tell you that?
Conan-kun did!
He found flyers of this restaurant all over Dad's desk.
Damn, that brat with glasses...
Huh? Mom, don't you think that person behind you looks like Dad?
No way. He had work to do today.
Didn't he say he'd return late this evening?
What reason would he have to leave work and come to a restaurant?
That's true.
What is this?! What did I do to deserve this?
God, help me overcome this obstacle!
Starring Okino Yoko
Nationwide Release
My Goddess!
As expected from a Yoko-chan movie...
A blockbuster!
This many people in a dark theatre...
and during the intermission, I'll go to the bathroom to hide,
and wait for the last show at midnight to come out.
Take a look at the long queue!
And this is only the first day of release! What a blockbuster!
Eh? TV camera?
Now, let's interrogate the spectators in the queue!
Hello, We're from Nichiuri TV...
Hey, hey, if I'm caught on TV...
it'll be bad!
Ah, it's the famous Detective Mouri!
Er, no...
Those guys would know exactly where I am!
They will come and search the theater to find me!
Even hiding in the bathroom won't work...
And it'd serve me no good to watch some other movie I don't want to see!
Think, think...
THINK!
There has to be a place!
A place where those guys cannot find me!
Think!
The Columbo Restaurant;
the Pachinko Hammer;
the liquor shop, Kousuke.
Ah, damn!
They find me no matter where I go!
They even made it to Poirot!
Poirot?
Wait, come to think of it...
They know that I escaped from there.
If it's them, they would think I won't go back!
I am Mouri Kogoro, a detective.
Mouri-san!
The chase that took place today... is already over.
And, they weren't able to find me.
I was so worried! You disappeared just like that...
Yeah, sorry.
A client called while I was in the toilet.
I see.
But it's good that you're back.
It's good?
You're back!
You guys?!
If it's Uncle Kogoro, it's either horse racing, Mahjong or Okino Yoko-san, right?
First we called your friend at the racecourse,
but as your phone was switched off, we asked them to announce your name!
Then, we called your Mahjong friend,
and asked him to tell us if you called him.
Yes, and when Ran-neechan and Auntie Eri
said they were going to eat out,
Conan-kun told them the name of your favorite restaurant!
Well, being at Okino Yoko's movie premiere...
...was rather risky, as you might get caught on TV.
And I thought you'll end up coming back here again!
Of course we thought of every possible place you could have gone...
I see.
So, now...
Our New Year envelopes!
On New Year's Day, Japanese people have a custom of giving money to children. This is known as 'otoshidama'. It is handed out in small decorated envelopes.
You promised us last year!
That if you meet us on New Year, you'll give it to us!
In Kantou, New Year's holiday is until the 7th!
B-but I didn't bring the envelopes...
I've brought them!
They were cheap, so I bought them just in case...
Okay...
Here you are. Use them wisely!
Thank you!
You guys don't want one?
I'll pass.
Same.
Wait till I get something bigger...
Doctor, Happy New Year!
Oh, same to you.
It's good that you have come.
But I'm a little busy right now.
Do - c - tor.
Happy New Year.
Same to you!
What's better than a quiz to celebrate --
Doctor Agasa. A very Happy New Year to you.
To begin the new year --
Happy. New. Year.
In the beginning of a year --
Happy New Year, Doctor.
Alright, I get it. You want your New Year's money.
You could have clearly said it.
Here, I prepared one for you.
Thank you.
Sorry, for each year.
N-nothing's inside?
Look carefully at the bottom.
Bottom?
Only 500 yen?!
That's right, use it well.
500 yen for a high school student...
Why, you're still in primary school, Edogawa Conan-kun.
Hey!
Act like a schoolboy, not an adult.
As if that's possible.
That's what I do.
I'm only joking.
Did you enjoy watching 'The Fugitive: Mouri Kogoro'?
Well, it's time for the quiz to win presents!
If you carefully watched this episode, it will be easy!
First question:
The case of the latest film, 'Dimensional Sniper', is set around the Bell Tree Tower.
A tower was shown in 'The Fugitive: Mouri Kogoro'.
So, what is the real name of this tower?
Do you know it? And now, question 2:
Actually, in 'The Fugitive: Mouri Kogoro',
high school detective girl, Sera Masumi, was shown.
So, what was the color of her backpack?
(A) Black (kuro)
(B) Red (aka)
(C) White (shiro)
Do you remember?
People who have answered the questions correctly will get presents!
Here are the ways to contact us. Please don't hesitate!
There is always only one truth!