Two dry martinis.
Courtesy of the lady on the stage.
I'll take it with my compliments.
What is the meaning of all of this?
I'm asking what you're up to...
Vermouth!
I'm just kidding.
It's a joke, a joke.
VERMOUTH
Don't make such a scary face!
GIN
Isn't it time you told us what you are up to?
VODKA
Give it up, she keeps her secrets to herself.
Oh that is not a nice thing to say...
"A secret makes a woman, a woman"
It's that touch of mystery that gives a woman her allure.
You make me sick.
Never mind me, what about you?
Did you find that kitten that got away from you?
No.
But it won't be long before I do.
My nose can sniff out traitors wherever they are.
And when I do, I'll show them what real fear is.
Her, and that man she is with.
So...
You will not become a good detective if you are so easily deceived!
it all started that day...
Ran and I came to an amusement park,
and before our eyes there was a murder.
Water?
They were also on the rollercoaster.
So temporarily taking you and Ran-kun out of the picture,
There were 5 passengers total.
Hurry up, will you?
We do not have time for your little detective games!
What is it with him?
What is this icy look?
These are the eyes of someone who has killed many people.
W-Who is he?
And after I opened the case...
That's...
You go on ahead!
I'll catch up with you!
He's leaving...
Here! I take it you have no objections?!
Whoa! There's at least 100 million in there!
This concludes our transaction.
Hurry and give me the film!
That's enough of your little detective game.
We'll use this - the latest poison developed by our organization.
It hasn't been tested on humans yet so let's consider this a trial run.
M-My body is burning up!
I can't hold on!
Can you stand up, boy?
Boy?!
My body has shrunk.
Their code names are associated with alcohol.
The Men in Black.
And so, my battle with them began.
The next time our paths crossed...
An armored car robbery!
Two criminals.
Conan-kun.
W-What was with that car?!
They're bank robbers!
Inspector Megure!
What is it, Takagi-kun?
I just got a report of a car that matches getaway car's description has been found.
Where did you go at a critical time like this?
I'm sorry.
I was on a break.
Should you be working?
This is another option...
Good job!
Hirota Masami.
No...
Miyano Akemi.
A gunshot!
Hold on, Masami-san!
The organization... It's a large criminal syndicate...
I don't know much much more except this organization's color is black.
She entrusted me with the locker key where the stolen money was stored.
This is the real key.
They took the fake.
And she died.
I'll rely on you... Little detective...
Teitan Elementary School
After a while she appeared.
Oh it's a girl, awesome!
This is Haibara Ai-san who will be learning with us from today.
Haibara Ai
Everyone, be friendly, alright?
Okay!
But she...
See you in school!
Apotoxin-4869.
Do you know what that is?
It was the drug you were forced to take.
What are you talking about?
I never took a weird drug like...
I'm sure the name is correct.
Because that's the name...
of the drug that I created at the request of the organization.
Haibara...
She was one of the men in black.
Are you...
It's not Haibara...
Miyano Shiho.
Sherry.
That's my code name.
Well, are you surprised?
Kudo Shinichi-kun.
After the Organization killed her sister,
she decided to die by taking the same drug as I did,
but her body also shrunk.
It was Miyano Akemi, her sister that was killed.
Why?
Why did not you... help my sister?
That person was your sister?
With all your...
your deductive skills
you should have be able to solve her case!
But... But...
Why?!
Thanks to Haibara, we were able access a floppy disk with the data of the Organization.
What's this?
Yet...
What is this?
A computer virus...
Night Baron.
What?!
If accessed by any computers outside the organization,
The virus is programmed to activate.
I was too hasty.
Then all the data is...
Yeah, all of it is gone.
Including all the programs that were on the computer.
Damn it!
It looks like I'm going to be with you for a long time,
Edogawa-kun.
So Haibara and I united with a common goal - to get the Black Organization.
The first major confrontation with them began with a simple accident.
Porsche 356A.
This classic is over 50 years old.
Gin.
This car...
Is Gin's favorite model.
Gin?!
What are you up to?
I'm planting a bug inside the car.
But we're not even sure if it's his car...
You moron!
The snow is unusually trampled around the car...
I'm glad I found you, Gin!
This time, you won't escape...
We tracked down one of the members of the Organization, code-named Pisco,
It's a funeral farewell party, everyone is dressed in black.
who's job was kill a politician.
Everybody's starting to look suspicious.
Yet...
What?
I need to return to the Professor's car.
Haibara.
Where are you?
Answer me!
Haibara!
Kudo-kun?
Haibara? Haibara is that you?
Where am I?
I'm contacting you through the receiver in the glasses.
The flow of people divided us. Then someone came up behind and...
then what happened?
Someone drugged me and I passed out...
and now I'm confined in a wine storeroom.
If it's a storeroom with wines, maybe there are other types of alcohol there?
There are all kinds of alcohol in this room.
Can you see any Paikaru?
Paikaru?
I found the Paikaru.
But what am I supposed to do with this liquor?
It's going to help you get out of that room...
with the help of a magical trick.
After drinking the liquor, she temporarily returned to her normal appearance.
But...
I missed you... Sherry!
Gin...
Let's send her to meet her sister, whom we sent first.
A needle?
Get into the chimney!
Who the hell are you?!
Quickly!
You were still a child, so you probably do not remember any more,
but I was friends with your scientist parents.
And I've heard a lot about the drug under development.
Who...
Yet...
I could not imagine that you managed to take it this far.
But orders are orders. so don't blame me...
Shiho-chan.
Hold it right there...
Masuyama-san.
PISCO
Or should I call you Pisco?
Who, Who are you?
Edogawa Conan,
A Detective.
You know what will happen,
if you smoke next to that much spilled alcohol, right?
A fire has erupted in room 404
What?!
Let's go check it out!
Where are you?
What is the meaning of this, Gin?
It looks like you have failed, Pisco.
It's time for you to go to the next world.
After this case, a new member joined them.
Vermouth.
In the meantime, Haibara and I also had allies.
The FBI have infiltrated the Organization with undercover agents.
The new English teacher at Teitan High School,
JODY STARLING
using the the alias of Jody Santemillion,
is Agent Jody Starling.
The trump card of the FBI is Agent Akai Shuichi.
АКАI SHUICHI
And the head of their group...
JAMES BLACK
Agent James Black.
Now that I've met the irregulars I should treat you to a meal!
Three years ago in New York I met Vermouth.
Have you seen a suspicious man nearby?
A Japanese man with long silver hair.
Silver hair!
Ran, Run!
That's the serial killer!
Shinichi!
Damn, you're really troublesome.
Why?
Why did you save me?
I do not know why you would kill someone,
But as for helping someone...
No reason is required.
That serial killer turned out to be the master of disguise, American film actress Sharon Wineyard.
She and her daughter Chris were the same person...
However, Vermouth played the role of all of these people.
Vermouth killed Agent Jody's father.
Who are you?
Together with the FBI
The second act of confrontation with people in black began.
A secret makes a woman, a woman.
Remember?
Those were the last words you spoke to me.
A secret makes a woman, a woman.
I constantly repeated them,
so I would not forget...
the last words of my father's murderer.
Isn't it so...
Chris Vineyard?
Or would you prefer...
Vermouth?
Well, it's time to end our 20 year reunion...
and say good-bye.
Are you...
Do not move!
Your body is blocking mine from the rifle's line of fire.
What are you up to?
Run, Haibara!
Quickly! Get out!
My negligence allowed me to be put to sleep,
and I became her hostage during a shootout with the FBI.
OK, Boss...
Now...
What should I do with this child, who believes that he is capable of anything?
Electrodes and a heart rate monitor?
With a microphone and transmitter!
Could it have picked up the sound of my phone before?!
I wouldn't do that.
If you disconnect the cable,
it will stop registering my heart beat.
After that, your boss's phone number
will be immediately sent to my partner.
So, what will you do?
Far away from here
my partner is sitting and waiting for a signal.
If you do not want him to get it...
Take me to your boss.
We will deal with this once and for all,
Vermouth.
It's just sleeping gas.
The gas will also knock you out...
Yes, it's a gamble.
If you are first to wake up,
you can call the police to arrest me,
I'll then lead you to my boss's hideout.
But if I wake up first,
you know what will happen then...
This is bad!
I have to wake him up quickly!
When I woke up, Vermouth had destroyed the equipment and escaped.
There was no winner in this confrontation.
Sorry for keeping you waiting!
The third act of confrontation began with her appearance.
Aren't you usually on the Sunday News?
Correct!
TV presenter, Mizunashi Rena-san.
It's nice to meet you.
But, in fact, she...
Ok.
No problem.
At 10, as agreed,
KIR
Gin.
one of the people in black, her code name is Kir.
Why?
In a team with two experienced snipers, Chianti and Korn,
they wanted to kill a prospective politician.
CHIANTI
When I see the game in the center of my scope, I'm so excited!
Oh, Chianti?
КОRN
Korn as well, huh?
How very reliable.
Kir, Chianti, Korn...
Just how many are there?!
I'm counting on all of you.
Hopefully there will be no need for me to play a part.
Vermouth.
Let's see,
It'll only be another few minutes before I arrive.
Report back when you arrive,
Kir.
Yes, sir.
Excuse me?
I have something to ask you...
Could you please stop your bike?
What just happened?
We managed to prevent the murder,
And Kir, who is also Mizunashi Rena, fell into a coma and is under the supervision of the FBI.
Her life is not in any danger, however she has not regained consciousness.
It seems we will just have to wait for her to recover.
They have agreed to keep the fact that she is hospitalized here a secret.
Some time later, a new student transferred to the Teitan High School.
Nice to meet you, Detective Mouri.
HONDO EISUKE
Teitan High Class 2-B - Transfer student
My name is Hondo Eisuke.
You were just joking with us, right, boy?
Takumi-kun, it's true, right?
Yeah.
You're not really lying, are you?
It's not a lie!
It's really not a lie!
He did just what that woman did to me.
With sudden changes in breathing, pulse, or pupil width
you can clearly tell whether a person is lying or not.
Furthermore,
He has the same mannerisms as her...
As I thought, this guy...
And that woman...
Meanwhile, people from the Black Organization began to take steps to retrieve Kir.
The curtain of our fourth confrontation is already rising.
In this confrontation, the fate of one of the FBI agents will be determined...
This was a brief retelling of my confrontation with the Organization.
The fact that I am alive is a secret she keeps.
We still have not managed to reach the heart of the Organization.
We will see how it goes when I manage to get close to them!
At 7pm, watch the new remastered "Contact with the Black Organization"...
Definitely don't miss it!