I hear the CIA is on the move?
Seems like we've caught their eye.
But he says we have no need to worry.
Can we really trust that Japanese guy?
Of course.
In Japan, he's known as the legendary hitman.
He has cost us a great deal.
Is there anything money can't buy?
There isn't.
With this, I'll finally prove to that man
that there are far worse things than death in this world...
I seriously don't know!
I only drove the truck there from the port!
I wasn't told of anything but the destination.
I want to know who hired you.
I already told you, I don't know!
I received instructions from a phone call.
Aren't you widely known as the Carrier Joe?
You want me to believe that a pro such as yourself
accepted this risky job with just one phone call?
I had no idea there were bombs in the truck!
You're lying!
I'm a high school detective, Kudo Shin'ichi.
While visiting an amusement park with my
childhood friend and classmate, Mouri Ran,
I witnessed a man dressed in all black
carrying out a suspicious transaction.
Engrossed in watching the transaction,
I failed to notice the other partner who sneaked up behind me.
That man forced me to ingest a poison,
and when I came to...
...my body had shrunk.
If those guys were to find out
that Kudo Shin'ichi was still alive,
they'd come after my life again,
and put those around me in danger.
That's why I followed Prof. Agasa's
suggestion to hide my identity.
And when Ran asked for my name, on the spur of the moment,
I said I was Edogawa Conan.
In order to obtain information on those guys,
I came to live in Ran's home,
where her father works as a detective.
These guys are my current classmates.
Genta.
Mitsuhiko.
Ayumi.
They formed the Detective Boys and involuntarily dragged me in.
And, this old man is Mouri Kogoro.
I guess no explanation's needed here.
These two gadgets are the inventions of Prof. Agasa.
And since I've gotten smaller, he has created
many unique gadgets one after another for me.
This is the Ball-Dispensing Belt.
By pressing a button on its buckle,
it inflates a ball and ejects it—a superb invention.
By the way, other than Prof. Agasa,
there are others who know my identity.
Haibara Ai.
Her real name is Miyano Shiho.
She was originally a member of the Black Organization.
However, in order to escape from those guys,
she took the same poison I was forced to ingest,
and her body shrunk.
And now, Haibara included, who currently lives
with Prof. Agasa, we lead the lives of first graders.
Even though my body is smaller, my intellect remains the same.
The unbeaten great detective...
There's always only one truth!
Let's go, Mitsuhiko!
I got it!
Here I come!
Go!
Ayumi-chan, above you!
Nice, Ayumi-chan!
There's more where that came from.
Woohoo!
Okay...
Last night, around 10 PM,
there was a report of a home delivery company's truck loaded with bombs going through a residential area of Haido City.
The police also discovered what looked like
smuggled plastic bombs on the truck bed.
I was playing soccer and accidentally broke them.
I heard. Professor prepared new ones for you.
The Tokyo metropolitan police suspects the involvement of the country of Korabia.
It's the shoes fault. They malfunctioned,
which caused the ball to go in the wrong direction.
I sure have had a streak of bad luck lately.
The smuggled plastic bombs were put in containers that resemble cookie cans and put inside the truck.
Where's the professor?
The bath also malfunctioned, so he's fixing it.
A police investigation revealed that the bombs in the truck,
were smuggled aboard a cargo ship at the harbor.
Come to think of it, the place were the bombs were found is pretty close from here, isn't it?
I guess so.
But if this was planned by someone from the Organization,
they wouldn't have made such a mistake.
Yeah, I sure hope not.
Sorry.
Looks like it'll take a little longer to fix the bath.
What?
Our bath?
Of course you can use it.
Wait, how about we all go to a bathhouse?
A bathhouse?
Don't you get the urge to soak
yourself in a big bath once in a while?
Dad, wanna come?
I'm in shock right now. I can't move.
Shocking News!
Aren't those some baseless gossips?
What would I do if they were true?!
The three of us will go.
Conan-kun, wanna come to the girl's side as well?
Huh?
Just messing with you.
Welcome!
Hey, you done yet?
Just a little longer.
I somehow feel jealous of them.
Say, Ai-chan, isn't there someone you like at school?
I can't possibly fall in love with kids.
That so?
Hey.
Is that your locker?
Uh, well... yeah, it is.
Hey, little boy.
Yes?
Did you come here alone?
No.
Conan-kun!
Aren't you lonely all by yourself?
I'm fine!
I just met someone I know.
Who's this someone?
You know him too!
What? Conan-kun slipped?
・ Closed on the 7th, 17th, and 27th ・
Yeah.
A man who knew him carried that boy to his car and went to the hospital.
Do you know which hospital?
He didn't say.
It's probably one nearby.
I'm sorry. I should have asked which hospital he was going to.
Don't worry about it.
I'll look around myself.
Let's go, Ai-chan.
Weren't we going to the hospital?
That kid freakin' peeked inside the locker.
You're on our side, aren't you?
How perceptive of you.
I did hear something about someone keeping an eye on me.
Clues were all over the place.
You have such a nasty look in your eyes.
And what do you want me to do about it?
For starters, we need to ask for instructions.
You think you can do it by yourself?!
You're nothing but a dog who follows orders!
I used my wit to save your ass too, y'know?
Just what I'd expect from Ad Lib Tatsu.
Your tattoo says it all.
I've heard rumors about you.
No matter what irregular circumstances he's in,
he cleverly uses ad lib to get out of them and finish the job.
The man with the dragon tattoo, Ad Lib Tatsu.
You're well-known in the underworld.
I-I don't have the faintest idea who you're talking about.
Hey.
Who are you guys?
Y-You slipped and hit your head in the bathhouse.
Conan-kun, was it?
Conan...?
Little boy, do you know your name?
My... name?
Ah, Professor!
Hmm?
How's Conan-kun's condition?
They said he hasn't been brought here.
What?
It's strange, right?
And this is the closest emergency hospital.
The only other emergency hospital in this area is...
INBOX
Kudo Shin'ichi
Suzuki Sonoko
Mom
A text from Shin'ichi!
Really?
Oh, I see.
That acquaintance he was talking
about turned out to be Shin'ichi.
What?
"My injuries were minor, so please don't worry."
Look.
INBOX
My injuries were minor,
so please don't worry.
I'm going to eat dinner with
Shin'ichi-niisan and
come home later.
Oh, I see. That's a relief.
But what's up with this stupid text message?
If they were gonna have dinner,
couldn't they have invited us too?
Oh, hey, Shin'ichi—
The number you're trying to reach is either
outside of the service area or it is powered o—
That so?
We're leaving.
O-Okay...
I gave him some strong sleeping pills.
He won't wake up any time soon.
I sent that "Ran-neechan" chick a text, so we should be good for now.
The boy's memories seem to be in dismay.
If he'd forget everything he saw,
there wouldn't be a problem.
You're the locksmith, Maru, aren't you?
What's a pro such as yourself doing in a place like this?
I was told to pick the lock on the door and have the sleeping pills ready.
I'll take my leave now.
You can't just yet.
Why not?
Beats me.
I received a text saying to put the
kid to sleep, and for everyone to wait here.
Damn it.
Are you in the same boat and don't know who hired us?
Someone hired me with a phone call.
I wouldn't call that "hiring."
What does he have on you?
Anyway, we better do as we're told.
After being in this type of business for so long,
my hunches have become razor-sharp.
Whoever hired us is, no doubt,
someone not to be messed with.
Prime Minister Babeo from the country of Ameripan
will arrive in Japan early tomorrow morning.
The chief cabinet secretary commented in an interview about the summit meeting being held tomorrow.
The Government's Reply to Prime Minister Babeo's Proposals
Because of the recent aerial
bombings in the country of Korabia,
relentless efforts are being made to ensure
the safety of the surrounding areas likely to be targeted by terrorist acts, and foil said acts.
Hey, the shock has left me starving, so hurry up and make me dinner.
Go eat something at Poirot downstairs.
Huh?
Anyway, I'm in a bad mood, so I'm going to bed!
Wow. What's her problem?
She's becoming more and more like Eri by the day.
Come in.
Excuse me.
Ah, we're already closed for the da—
Is that so?
I shall come by tomorrow, then.
Ah, no, no, no, no...
I can always make exceptions for a beauty like you.
It's still fine. You made it just in the nick of time.
So you want me to investigate whether your husband's having an affair.
Yes.
He denied when I confronted him,
but I find it hard to believe him as he's behaving oddly.
I could've continued the investigation myself,
but there are natural and physical
constraints preventing from doing so.
And I don't want it to affect my job and
cause problems for the company I work for.
That's why I opted to ask a professional such as yourself.
I see...
Any ideas who the other girl might be?
Not a clue.
But when I cleaned his car this morning, I smelled a women's perfume.
What does your husband do for a living?
He's in the middle of job hunting.
For having such a beautiful wife work hard,
and even having the nerve to cheat on her, I sure can't forgive him.
Not a problem.
Let's go to the bathhouse where you last saw your husband right away.
Okay.
We must investigate this promptly.
And after that...
How about we have dinner somewhere?
Just like I thought.
It hasn't moved from the bathhouse yet.
Really?
That means his belongings are still in his locker.
"His belongings are still in his locker"?
Then he went out in the nude?!
We're gonna look for him.
What?
H-His mother?
Yeah, just a while back.
Closed on the 7th, 17th, and 27th
She said, "I've come to pick up my son's belongings."
And informed me that the boy got out of it just fine.
It's moving.
Oh?
Judging by this speed, she must be in a car.
Wh-What's wrong, Ai-kun?
Professor, you chase after his belongings.
Wh-What about you?
Just do it!
All right, then.
Let's go look inside first,
then go dine somewhe—
Good evening.
Ah. You're that four-eyed brat's—
Who are you, Miss?
Hey! We're in the middle of work, so don't you get in our—
I'm hungry.
Then go back home and eat.
But Professor left a while back and nobody's there.
What? He just left right n—
Then wanna eat with us?
You don't mind? Thanks!
But this'll interrupt our investigation...
It's all right. It's not like I'm trying to hide it.
Let's go.
So this is the apartment complex
where your husband used to work?
He's planning to move out shortly.
He used to work as a handyman before.
Come inside.
It seems like he has lots of things to throw away,
so he's yet to clear the place out.
I see.
But man, this is indeed the ideal place to have an affair.
Although he doesn't look like someone who'll do such a thing.
All men cheat with a straight face.
What's inside your bag?
Hey, now!
Work tools.
I edit magazines for a living.
I have to go back to work later tonight.
Sounds tough.
I have a strict deadline.
Oh, I see.
So he's not here after all.
H-Hey! Behave!
It's open.
Hey...
Hey!
What is it?
Don't go wandering around all by yourself.
Professor's calling for me, so I'm going home.
Hey, what about dinner?
Don't need it.
A-Ai-kun! Why are you here?
Why are you here?
I-I chased after the belongings and
ended up at this apartment complex.
Wait! Th-They're coming out.
Lemme see.
Hey, done yet?
That woman was at the bathhouse.
After her!
Yeah!
But man,
is working as a handyman really this profitable?
Just look at this luxury apartment.
No idea...
Although detectives do similar work as
handymen, this sure is a world of difference.
A huge differe—
What?
Ma'am.
Yes.
Did you know about this room?
I see. A "handyman," huh?
Ma'am.
There's high probability your husband's not cheating on you.
What in the world is going on?
I don't know.
But...
I have a bad feeling about this.
Kondou, you say?
Yes.
The man who handed over the keys of the truck told me,
"Don't you dare mess up.
Kondou-san is the one who hired us."
By Kondou, you mean that legendary hitman?
He's a mere urban legend.
Or what? Are you telling me proof of his existence has been—
The police will protect me, right?!
Come in.
Chou-san, got a second?
What is it?
The amount of bombs we had found indeed doesn't match up with the intel we received from the CIA.
What?! There's no mistake, right?
None.
I've had it re-checked so many times,
but it seems we are missing a few.
Damn!
That means we still haven't found all the bombs yet.
What do we do now, Ai-kun?
I'll go take a look at what's happening inside.
You stay here, Professor.
What?
Don't do anything reckless.
I know.
We're moving. We're also taking the kid along.
Wh-Who are you?!
Isn't it better for both of us
if I don't disclose my identity?
I was only instructed to take
the kid's belongings and bring them here.
It was your fault.
You came here without grabbing this!
Do you not know who's behind this either?
I have a rough idea.
Wh-Who is it?
M-My job should be done already.
Indeed, it has.
The jobs of you lot are done!
Let us go, Kondou-san.
Professor, call the police and
tell them you heard some gunshots.
G-Gunshots?
Hurry!
A-Ai-kun!
Chase after that car.
G-Gotcha.
You think he plans on making use of this kid?
Making use of him?
That Beetle's really bugging me.
The radar's not moving.
Another malfunction?
Don't get too close.
We have no choice but to tail
them without attracting attention.
Got it.
Where in the world do they plan on taking him?
Don't get hasty.
If they wanted to kill him,
they'd have done that already.
Professor!
Wh-What is it?
Hey! That's dangerous!
A-Ai-kun!
It was here, wasn't it?
They must've mistook gunfire for firecrackers or something.
Yeah, I guess it's something like that.
Prime Minister Babeo of Ameripan arrived early this
morning via a government aircraft at Tokyo Hadena Airport.
The prime minister plans to visit the Imperial Palace with his family later this afternoon.
Now, let's move on to the next news item.
You poor thing.
A fire outbroke in an abandoned factory in the outskirts of Haido City.
You'll get better soon.
And some unidentifiable body was found as the flames were extinguished.
Mom and Dad are here for you.
Before the explosion, the police received reports about some gunshots.
You're safe.
Upon arrival, the two policemen got dragged in the explosion,
I'll bring you breakfast right up.
and although they suffered serious burns, their lives are not in danger.
I'm scared...
I'll stop for a bit at Shin'ichi's house before going to school.
Jeez.
Someone's a little cranky this morning.
Need you even ask?!
I went to bed last night without eating anything, so I'm starving.
And Conan-kun had left with Shin'ichi and hasn't come back yet!
Yeah, yeah. I haven't eaten anything either.
Why don't you make something for us?
I said I'm leaving!
Jeez!
What an evil daughter...
On the other hand, her father stayed up working all night.
Conan-kun sure is late today.
Ai-chan hasn't come either.
Are they not coming?
Jeez.
And here I thought we all agreed
to go to Yokohama after school.
Yokohama?
Didn't we all agree on that yesterday when we were playing soccer?
We said we'll have Prof. Agasa take us to the
Kamen Yaiba Exhibit at Red Brick Warehouse.
Oh, now I remember!
I wonder if that Conan remembered to ask Professor for us.
I hope he did.
Yeah.
Kamen Yaiba Exhibit?
Wh-Where'd that come from?
The prime minister's kids appear to be huge fans of it,
so they want to go there at the very least.
Good grief.
The official ceremonies are yet to commence,
so naturally, the kids and his wife will go
alone and the prime minister will stay here.
And where will it be held?
W-Well, apparently it'll be at the
Red Brick Warehouse in Yokohama...
Yokohama?!
Y-Yes, sir.
Damn, this is too much!
Okay, I will take care of it.
I'll ask the Kanagawa Prefectural Police to cooperate with us.
You can go back to your work now.
Yes, sir.
Can't you make something more decent?
I'm not a cook, y'know?
Was the taste not to the liking
of the genius swindler, Nana-san?
So you know my name?
Expected no less from the genius hacker, M.
Wha—
Me?
How'd you know?
I had no idea till now.
It's almost time.
This bag is for the kid.
I will take measures to make sure his family doesn't cause a stir.
What the hell is your problem?
What about school?
I received another stupid text from Shin'ichi.
"I'm going to the Kamen Yaiba Exhibit in Yokohama."
The heck that's supposed to mean?!
Yokohama?
The store called Red Brick Warehouse or whatever.
I'll be on my way.
Red Brick Warehouse...
Kamen Yaiba, Yaiba!
Call out to him.
And you'll always find him there for you.
Oh, the "Y" symbol on his mask shines brightly!
What?
So you're telling me her husband is that legendary hitman?
Yeah.
Upon hiring, he devises the perfect plan to dispose of his target without leaving any chance for failure.
Not even the bodies of those he
kills turn up—truly a professional.
I found all the documents and notes for the cases believed to be Kondou's doing
lined up perfectly inside her husband's work office.
Can we really believe an article of a magazine like this?
I dunno.
At any rate, there was one brand new file on the table of his office.
With what looked like a bomb handling instructions,
a rough sketch of the Red Brick Warehouse was inside.
That's a cause for concern, don't you think?
Why don't you report this to the police?
I need solid evidence first.
Otherwise, I won't get to take part in the investigation.
Have you told his wife?
Ever since she went back to finish off some work, I haven't been able to get a hold of her.
I feel sorry for her.
Why?
Inbox
INBOX
My injuries were minor,
so please don't worry.
I'm going to eat dinner with
Shin'ichi-niisan and
come home later.
Oh, hey, Shin'ichi—
The number you're trying to reach is either outside of...
I feel sorry for me too.
Why do guys do whatever they want without thinking of others?!
Argh!
Hey, it's dangerous to walk in the middle of the road!
What do you think you're doing?!
I was in an accident.
Can you give me a ride?
Sorry. Hitchhike on some other car.
Break through the darkness.
Scatter all the bad guys with a Yaiba kick.
One, two...
Kamen Yaiba!
Kamen Yaiba, Yaiba!
A slogan for bravery.
He's our inspiration, Yaiba!
Though it was a rush job, I have a clear view of the grounds from the surveillance cameras.
The sound feed is perfect too.
Kamen Yaiba, Yaiba!
Our rehearsal for using the remote control has been already done in that abandoned factory.
He appears with his machine,
Our target will show his face soon.
Kamen Yaiba, Yaiba!
and gives rise to a storm.
And the bomb's standing there obediently—all alone.
Oh, the green nature is shouting—
Well, I guess this doesn't really feel that good either.
But the targets were kids to begin with,
so I guess this doesn't really change much.
Kamen Yaiba, Yaiba!
Who would've thought I'd have to trigger the detonator?
He appears with his machine,
Here you are!
Kamen Yaiba, Yaiba!
Fifteen more meters.
and gives rise to a storm.
With one press on this key,
Oh, the green nature is shouting.
you'll all go boom!
O, justice energy, inflame inside of him!
Ten meters...
Seven meters...
He's always a fighter!
Five meters...
Kamen Yaiba!
Conan-kun!
I finally found you!
Where's Shin'ichi?
A Yaiba punch symbolizes the power of love.
Who are you, Miss?
What?
A Yaiba kick opens the doors of hope!
Three meters...
Two meters...
Kamen Yaiba, Yaiba!
One meter...
Zero!
He always has a red—
Two Days Ago
Is it not to your liking?
What?
No...
Have you grown to hate me?
What makes you say that?
You've been acting strange the last
few days, so I was getting worried.
That's not it at all.
I'm deeply sorry to have caused you such worries.
Could it be "marriage blues"?
No...
Sorry, but I made plans to meet with someone.
Is that so?
I'm really sorry.
Don't be.
Very soon, a home delivery company's truck will arrive
and drop a package at the corner of the street ahead of you.
You're to pick it up and get moving immediately.
What's inside of that package?
You need not worry about that.
Anyway, some problems have surfaced,
and the said truck is being tracked by the police.
So, I want you to secure the
package and take it to a safe place.
Is that all I have to do?
Yeah.
If everything goes according to plan,
your job will end with this.
Do you have everything ready?
Yeah. Four was the limit.
I couldn't stuff in any more inside.
All right.
The instant you make a turn in the next corner, you're to drop the bag.
Do it without attracting attention.
I dropped it. What now?
That's it.
Huh?
So you just wanted me to carry
some cookies here and that's it?
Carrier Joe sure doesn't live up to the rumors.
What was that?
Did you not notice you were
being tailed by the police this entire time?
Where's the package?
The hell is that?
I put it inside one of the bathhouse's lockers.
That area was swarmed with officers.
I couldn't possibly wander about
with a suspicious package in my possession.
I can't go in there!
You put it in the male side, didn't you?
I didn't think you were actually a woman.
So he says...
Yes, yes...
Understood.
You're dismissed for today.
For today?
He wants me to do more tasks?
I wouldn't know.
Don't ask me.
He said he'll give more instructions later.
I'm sending another guy to retrieve the package.
You're to be on lookout.
Lookout?
Mingle with the other customers,
and keep watch until the other guy
successfully retrieves the package.
Take care of any problems that pop up.
Why're you so against having me retrieve it?
I have my own reasons for that.
Wasn't exactly dying to know.
That's better for the both of us.
This is the very last job I'll have you do.
I promise you that.
One adult.
Welcome.
Hey.
Is that your locker?
Are you all right, little boy?
Hey, you.
I'm taking that child to the hospital.
Help me out.
Please.
You think you can do it by yourself?!
You're nothing but a dog who follows orders!
I used my wit to save your ass too, y'know?
Just what I'd expect from Ad Lib Tatsu.
Your tattoo says it all.
Hey.
Who are you guys?
Y-You slipped and hit your head in the bathhouse.
Conan-kun, was it?
Conan...?
Little boy, do you know your name?
My... name?
Where... am I?
I don't know, either.
Can you really not remember a single thing?
Little boy, this is a good remedy for headaches. Take it and lay down.
Okay.
Indeed.
The jobs of you lot are done!
Let us go, Kondou-san.
The kid has lost his memories.
There should be no problem if we left him behind.
I was told to bring him along.
That's not something for you to decide.
Will I also face the same fate as them after my job is over?
If I get an instruction to do so.
Unless I do as told, I'll be the one facing that fate.
What does he have against you?
It's nothing as big as yours.
It never crossed my mind
that the legendary hit man, Kondou,
is just a man who lets his targets get away.
You pretended to have killed them,
and actually let all your victims go free, right?
You must've made quite the big bucks
receiving money from both parties.
How do you know about that?
He told me about it.
Probably to make sure I'm not
intimidated by you any more than warranted.
What... does he plan to do with the kid?
No idea.
He might put him to some good use.
Good use?
That Beetle's really bugging me.
Is he asleep?
Yeah.
We're to stand by here until the morning.
Will you also have some?
I will.
I thought so.
You sure can keep your cool.
Revolting won't do me any good at this point of time.
You're awake, aren't you?
I put the sleeping pill you
threw away inside that woman's drink.
She's soundly asleep.
You don't need to be scared.
I'll let you go, so get up quietly.
And what will happen to you?
They're blackmailing you, aren't they?
Yeah.
There are bombs inside that bag
in the bathhouse locker, right?
How'd you know?
I heard on the news that they were disguised as cookie cans.
Do you really have no idea what they're after?
They're using quite a variety of people,
but not one of us knows of their true objective.
That's why I have to find the real bad guy who's behind this.
You should get out of here and head to the poli—
If I went missing, you'll be under the most suspicion.
Not to mention—
Hi, there!
So you are that famous Kondou-san, huh?
And you are...?
Your teammate.
So you are that...
Sorry to break this to you, but I'm not the leader.
I'll keep an eye using this,
so you can get some rest as well.
Yeah.
Yes, yes...
Red Brick Warehouse?
Yes.
There was a ticket in that kid's pocket to an event that'll take place there.
It seems there'll be lots of kids there,
so we are to take him there and just leave him.
He still hasn't regained his memories, has he?
Yeah.
What a relief.
What would you do if I told you we were ordered to dispose of the kid?
The prime minister plans to visit the Imperial Palace along with his family later this afternoon.
Now, let's move on to the next news item.
A fire outbroke in an abandoned factory in the outskirts of Haido City.
You poor thing.
You'll get better soon.
And some unidentifiable body was found as the flames were extinguished.
Mom and Dad are here for you.
Before the explosion, the police received reports about some gunshots.
You're safe.
Upon arrival, the two policemen got dragged in the explosion,
and although they suffered serious burns, their lives are in no danger.
I'll bring you breakfast right up.
I'm scared...
You can still get out of this.
Just continue pretending you've lost your memory.
I...
Hm?
have figured out who the real bad guy is.
What?
I'd like to meet the editor of the
"True Tale Dynamite" magazine.
Sure, but may I ask who you are?
It is true he's a person who has been
featured in our magazine multiple times.
So this Kondou person really does exist?
Yes.
We're certain of it.
And we've recently received intel
reporting to us his whereabouts.
Seriously?
And where is that?
Actually, the information provider demanded a large sum of money,
and ever since we told him we can't pay
such an amount, he stopped contacting us.
Excuse me, Ootani-san.
Have you seen our editor-in-chief?
No, I haven't.
Did something happen to Kanae-chan?
Actually, ever since she went out earlier, we've been unable to get a hold of her.
And the deadline is today...
It's almost time.
This bag is for the kid.
Little boy.
What?
Ah, never mind...
Yes.
Once you leave the kid there
and head back, your job is done.
Thanks for your service.
You went through the trouble of
blackmailing me and this is all you want me to do?
Cut the crap.
I already know you're not a legendary hitman or anything.
You're no more than someone who can't bring
himself to finish off his targets and sets them free.
This is just the right job for someone like you.
Don't get cocky.
You're to drop the kid at the set location, and stand
watch until somebody takes him under their care.
If the police gets involved,
I'll have you take full responsibility.
Even a punk like you should be able to do this simple task.
Hey, I have to pee.
Okay, I'll stop at the next rest area.
There's a bomb inside that backpack.
It's a remotely controlled one.
They probably plan to wait for the
right moment to detonate the bomb.
How do you know this?
I didn't really have a ticket for the Kamen Yaiba Exhibit.
I don't know what they're really after,
but I've the rest figured out.
You're that legendary Kondou, aren't you?
Even I've read about you in magazines.
Yeah.
But in reality, you are no more than someone who sets his targets free.
That's right.
Figured as much.
My dad once helped out with a case in which
you were rumored to have been involved in.
He told me,
"I highly suspect that once Kondou is hired, he tells the target about it.
This way, he gets the fees from both parties,
and simply pretends to have killed the target he set free."
There was no evidence for that claim, though.
It's just like you said.
Then if that were to be made public,
your previous employers
would know your targets are still alive.
Is this how they're blackmailing you?
Yeah.
Who in the world are you?
I'm Edogawa Conan, a detective.
Detective?
The real bad guy is probably Ad Lib Tatsu.
What?
At the bathhouse yesterday,
there was this guy who washed his torso over three times while glancing at the locker room.
You done yet?
Just a little longer.
I got curious and once I got to the changing room,
I saw you sitting there.
You weren't wet at all,
so you were obviously suspicious.
You piqued my interest, and once that Tatsu guy
came inside and took the locker key out of his pocket,
I called out to him without thinking.
Then I saw the cookie cans inside the locker.
I thought to myself, "this isn't good,"
since I was naked and there were three suspicious guys.
So I first made sure I had my phone and transmitter on me.
Transmitter?
Yeah.
It's made as a sticker, so you can stick it anywhere you want.
And these glasses are the receiver.
They have a built-in radar.
Hey, little boy.
Yes?
Did you come here alone?
No.
Conan-kun!
Aren't you lonely all by yourself?
I'm fine!
I just met someone I know.
I stuck the transmitter to his jacket,
and thought about calling someone too...
But I didn't have that luxury.
So I intentionally slipped and tried to cause an uproar.
And then...
Are you all right, little boy?
I was forced to inhale a drug,
and truly lost consciousness.
A drug?
Yes.
Which means it's highly likely they had planned on assaulting someone there from the very start.
Yeah.
It must've been me.
So they deliberately had me keep watch with the intention of assaulting me.
The plan might've been to kidnap
a naked man who's incapable of resisting,
and put the blame on me,
making it look like it was the work of Kondou.
But don't the original plans sound kinda sloppy to you?
First, the bombs where found by the police,
and even me being in that bathhouse was a mere coincidence.
The only logical conclusion is that
he kept making his plans as he went along.
And that's the prime example of ad lib.
And that's why you think Ad Lib Tatsu is the mastermind?
But...
He should've met his end at the factory, right?
However,
the news report just said some unidentifiable body was found.
If Tatsu's body, along with the other man's body, was found,
they would've specifically said "two bodies were found."
And so, when I checked with my tracking glasses,
I found out Ad Lib Tatsu was on the move.
I...
have figured out who the real bad guy is.
He's at that house right now.
I'll buy you some time, so please confirm
Tatsu's whereabouts and inform the police.
Got it.
Now we have to figure out what to do with the bombs.
I'll figure something out.
Please do.
One more thing.
My friends might've been captured by him.
What?
Your friends?
Did you catch her?
Yeah.
She immediately came over once I told her I
have something to tell her about her husband.
I put her to sleep in the room for now.
But is there any need to go this far?
I'm a pretty cowardly man.
Anyway, you come back here too.
I'm on my way.
Okay.
Feeling a bit chilly?
Come on!
Why do I have to do that?
I'll explain to you later.
Remember, you owe me one.
You forgot that I let you go the other day?
Today is a little bad...
I have to take care of the cat and finish some things.
I can't trust anyone but you for this job!
Just how small is your circle of friends?
You've reached the voice mail.
The number you're attempting to reach is either—
She's still at work, huh?
Hello.
Call out to him.
Kamen Yaiba, Yaiba!
And you'll always find him there for you.
Oh, the "Y" symbol on his mask shines brightly! Y!
O Yaiba, protect our happiness!
Come on!
What the hell is going on here?
You are a fighter!
And who are you?
Kamen Yaiba!
Jeez.
Hey, it's dangerous to walk in the middle of the road!
What do you think you're doing?!
I was in an accident.
Can you give me a ride?
Calm down.
That boy told me everything.
Here you are!
Kamen Yaiba!
Fifteen more meters.
With one press on this key,
A Yaiba punch symbolizes the power of love.
you'll all go boom!
A Yaiba kick opens the doors of hope!
Two meters...
Kamen Yaiba, Yaiba!
One meter...
Zero!
There really was an explosion.
What did the notice say exactly?
It just said that a bomb was planted, so please evacuate the residences.
What? What's going on?
Kamen Yaiba!
What's happening?
Why isn't it exploding?!
Damn!
Give it up.
Break through the darkness with a Yaiba punch!
You're—
Don't move!
Scatter all the bad guys with a Yaiba kick!
Ai-kun! You're safe?
Kamen Yaiba, Yaiba!
Professor...
A slogan for bravery.
Kamen Yaiba, Yaiba!
Lemme play with it, too!
Wait, Conan-kun, are you okay?
He's our inspiration, Yaiba!
Yes.
It's all good.
Your friends are safe as well.
I figured out who the targets are.
He can't be forgiven.
Is Tatsu there with you?
No, he's not.
Wait, Conan-kun!
Ran-neechan, why are you here?
What do you mean?
I'm looking for him now.
I came here to look for you!
Shin'ichi is here with you, isn't he?
Where is he?
There's a bomb!
Everybody, run!
Ran-neechan, hurry!
W-Wait, Conan-kun!
Hurry!
You all start running!
Run!
Ah, wait...
Get out of here!
It's not safe here, either!
Let's go!
Where is Tatsu?
I don't know.
I really don't know!
He should be here, but something came up and he's running la—
He isn't coming!
What?
You're simply being used just like the rest of us!
Once you have fulfilled your task, you will be eliminated.
If you want proof, the ceiling of the basement has it.
He says he wants to talk to you.
You really pulled off a stupid stunt.
You think you've severed your ties with the
past just by blowing up your own room?!
Who do you think is the stupid one now?
The Ad Lib Tatsu I know is more cunning and carefully finishes his jobs.
Your wife sure has a beautiful face.
Wha—
Are these two...
working with you?
Do you really think you can leave the
underworld just because you fell in love?
Isn't that kinda naive?
I'll have you work for me some more.
If you make as much as one wrong move,
or make a blunder and get arrested by the police,
you can say goodbye to your wife!
Ah!
Conan-kun!
Where are you, Conan-kun?
Conan-kun?
Wake up!
Wh-What's going on?
Hurry!
Start the car!
Jeez.
Now what's up?
Please calm down.
Did Conan-kun go off in that car?
Dad!
It's just like I thought.
This is no doubt Kondou's doing.
That car just now!
What?
Hand it over already!
Keep an eye on them for now.
Roger.
You are coming with me.
Yes, yes!
It's all good.
We still have time.
Yeah, it's all up to you.
What's your relationship with Tatsu?
I'm the one who originally figured out your silly tactics.
About one year ago, I accidentally found out about your revolving door trick.
You were just in the middle of your job then, weren't you?
Hey, come over here.
What is it?
Just do it!
Jeez.
Check that out.
That was what sparked his interest in you, and so he started his research on you.
I see.
So that's how you're related.
Got a problem?
Oh, take a left there.
Was it also you who left the file with the information
about the Red Brick Warehouse in my work office yesterday?
That man is quick-witted, you know?
I wouldn't underestimate him if I were you.
Where did we end up coming?
What a bad kid.
There are lots of hidden cameras around this house, y'know?
Hey! Where did you go now?
Is this shit-face your friend?
Is there anyone home?
That hurts!
Will someone just tell me what's happening?!
Hey, hold it!
I was only asked to help out.
I have nothing to do with this!
So just—
Can you shut up for a sec?
Please don't shoot!
Now, let's have you explain all this.
Ah, that's my phone.
What?
This woman...
Isn't she...
Excuse me! Is there anyone home?
Excuse me!
Conan-kun, are you in there?
Shin'ichi!
Ran-neechan, was it?
If you are looking for Conan-kun, he's inside.
So that shit-face who was with him is Shin'ichi, huh?
Anyway, do as I say or—
Wh-What happened here?
There's a bomb inside that truck.
You're to drive it and be on stand by.
We'll contact you with the details later.
This is your last chance.
If you want to save your wife, don't mess it up.
If that explosion plan at the Red Brick Warehouse had succeeded,
you planned to go back to that house on top of the mountain too, right?
He planned to get rid of you too.
It's no use trying to win me over to your side by such lies.
Your husband has left
a message on the voice mail for you.
It might be the last time you ever hear his voice,
so pay close attention.
Hello.
I know this is sudden and I'm sorry for it,
but I might not be able to meet you for a while.
I must come clean about my past job to the police.
I don't what'll happen once I do.
I won't ask of you to wait for me, but...
In any case, I'm glad to have met someone like you even after leading a scum's life.
I'm really grateful.
This is the end of the message.
To replay the—
Had he not met you, he might've led quite the happy life as the young scoundrel he was.
What a sinful woman.
The madam is wondering about
when will they be able to go back.
We're still inspecting the area to make sure of its safety.
Please wait a little longer.
Are you all set, Kondou-san?
What are you plotting?
The car with Ameripan's prime minister's children will
soon pass on the bridge you can see from your position.
Your job is to cause an accident and drag that car in it.
I'll press the detonator.
Why are you targeting the kids?
Because that's the job I was hired to do.
The deal is to blow them away with the bombs.
It's just business, man.
Besides, you were originally requested for this task.
What?
I had gotten interested in you, and so I entered
your work office without asking for permission.
I was really surprised.
Who would've thought that the
legendary Kondou actually exists?
Moreover, upon inspecting the documents inside,
I found out that Kondou didn't kill even a single person.
I found out you were just
a bogus bastard who spared his targets.
In that instant...
It was a request for you from overseas.
It looks like they had been looking for the best hitman in Japan.
They said they were finally able to get a hold of your contact information.
And you...
You accepted that request?
Yeah.
They offered a huge sum for the services after all.
I told them my number and accepted the job.
I also made use of the lists of the famous criminals which you worked so hard to keep them on file.
It's almost time to get moving.
Go to the base of the bridge.
Don't hang up.
Damn it!
Just a little more...
A little more...
Hey.
Wh-What's wrong?
I thought I told you to go back to that house.
He didn't have a phone on him.
He said he gave his phone to that kid at the Red Brick Warehouse, so I lent him mine.
What?
So if you want to get a hold of him, call my phone.
I figured I had to inform you right away,
but there were so many checkpoints along the way.
But I'm talking—
Police! Nobody move!
H-How...
You just have to give it up.
This was just too big of a job for you to do, after all.
By the way, everything that has been said up to now...
is being recorded as evidence.
But how did you find this pla—
Hey!
Who are you talking to?
Hello?
Hold it!
You can't go any further!
Let me pass through. I'm begging you.
Are you an occupant of this apartment complex?
No, I'm not...
Hey, police officer.
This man is the husband of the
woman who's been taken hostage.
Is that true?
Uh, yes.
You should've told us that from the very beginning.
Your wife is safe now.
She should be coming down here soon.
Go ahead.
Thank you.
You're the one who stuck the
transmitter on that Nana lady, aren't you?
Yeah.
Call the police immediately!
There's a bomb downstairs!
What?!
Wait, Conan-kun.
Explain to us what's happening here.
It's moving.
Mister!
What now?!
There!
Mister, it's that sky-blue car!
Got it!
Are you all set, Kondou-san?
What are you plotting?
I see.
What about the bomb?
I delivered it to the police.
Ah, hello, is this the police?
I-I've stumbled across some bombs...
Yes, inside a cookie can. Yes...
But how did you find this place?
That's because Tatsu found out about the explosion of that room incredibly fast.
So I thought he'd at the very least be
somewhere where he can directly see that room.
Then just tested my luck.
As to be expected of the legendary Kondou-san.
I already told you, I know nothing!
My friend asked for my help,
and all I did was take the kid to the Yaiba Exhibit!
Hey, little boy.
Huh?
This area is dangerous, so you should stay away.
Are you from the neighborhood?
Yeah, I'm sorry.
Wait!
Hey! Explain to them about me!
These guys won't listen to a word I say!
Who was that guy with Conan-kun just now?
Dunno.
I see...
And where did Shin'ichi run off to, anyway?
Jeez! None of this makes sense!
Gentlemen! Let me explain it to you!
All of this is the deed of that legendary hitman, Kondou.
The reason I got involved in this case to begin with was...
With regards to the bomb smuggling case the other day,
high-ranking executives of Korabia were found to have been involved in it,
thus the Tokyo Metropolitan Police Department have contacted the embassy of the said country and...
I'm begging you!
Just this once, let me go back to being Shin'ichi.
No.
Come on. Please don't say that.
I can't come up with a good excuse for why
Ran received all those texts from Shin'ichi's phone.
That wouldn't change regardless, would it?
Of course it will!
I'm begging you.
Please give me that pill!
No can do!
Stingy.
It's for your own good.
Whatever you say.
Guess I have to come up with some good excuse.
Oh, and one more thing...
Thanks.
For searching so hard for me that
your clothes ended up being so ripped.
Don't flatter yourself.
Yeah.
This sure looks awful.
I forgot our bath's not working properly.
What do I do?
He's still trying his best despite having become smaller.
Now, it's almost new year.
Guess I should also...
take up a new challenge!
Showings begin on April, 2015.
Detective Conan the Movie: The Sunflowers of Inferno.
Things won't go the same way this time.