Just a moment.
This time I will be playing the lead role.
Kaito 1412.
This is what the police refer to me as.
They call me the Phantom Thief.
A menace to society.
How dare they compare me to petty thieves.
I play the game on a grander scale.
An artist with amazing creativity.
That is who I am.
I am "Kaito Kid".
This time I prepared another chance for us to meet.
To demonstrate to you that gorgeous wonder.
My plans failed because of that kid detective.
Painfully I lost my precious goods.
This time it won't be that easy.
Everyone, please be witness to this.
The incident aboard the soaring silver wings in the night.
The next 30 minutes.
You might as well believe that I, Kaito
Kid, will give you all another challenge.
Ladies and Gentlemen.
It's showtime.
Detective Conan.
Magician of the silver sky.
Please look forward to the show.
Wonderful! It's complete.
This will definitely help Shin'ichi and Mouri.
By only entering the criminal's data,
it can automatically pull up the criminal's profile.
Christies YP.
My own invention.
Well, let's do a test run.
This is the first time we've met, Professor.
I am Christies YP.
Startup is a success!
I'll start with this data then.
Let's see what this guy's true identity is.
Kaito Kid.
Know the answer already?
Of course.
Kaito Kid's true identity is...
True identity is...
Kaito Kid's real identity is...
Kudo Shin'ichi.
Stupid, what are you talking about?
That's impossible.
I just analyzed the data,
there's no way it can be wrong.
Oh yea, Kaito Kid doesn't have
any criminal records as of yet.
That's why it came to this conclusion.
Better do some more data inputting...
Yeah... we can't go on like this.
I will go check the timeline.
Go collect Kaito Kid's, Kudo Shin'ichi and Conan's data.
Let's research.
Where is Kaito Kid's data...
Ah! Got it.
This guy is Kaito 1412.
People call him "Kaito Kid".
His white suit makes him look like a bridegroom.
This cannot be wrong.
Yo brat.
What are you doing here?
Kaito Kid has no shame.
Kaito Kid's image is so eye-catching.
He seldomly makes an appearance,
hence the name Phantom.
He has only appeared in the theaters once.
Even though he has only appeared once,
he's popular among girls.
Maybe he's trying to aim for their love.
Letting others believe he's a heart thief.
As for the Kid's first encounter...
Conan and Kid first met in this case.
Looking at the letter's elegance,
Could you say he's a very discreet person?
I'd also like to see,
the real person behind these letters.
The big bandit's true colors.
Kid wants to steal Suzuki Financial
Group's "Black Star" jewelry.
The police are ensuring the safety and protection,
but that guy is completely disregarding that fact,
and landing on the roof.
The one who appears in the moonlight
is not a bird but rather Kid.
Yes. That guy always uses some different
way of appearing from the sky.
But this time the one with the upper hand is Conan.
Even Kid has no way out of it.
What, you also thought of it too?
Naive, too naive?
You're not an ordinary kid.
Edogawa Conan.
I'm a detective.
Ahh... This is Chakiwa.
This is Kid's little trick.
He can impersonate the voices of important
personnel, so be careful.
If he entered into an impersonation
contest, he'd be the champion.
Don't move, Kid!
Ah, It's Officer Nakamori.
You came pretty fast this time.
Quick, grab him!
Move!
Flashbomb...
Just like that.
He'll flash...
And disappear...
Amazing.
He's gone!
Actually, before this incident, these two have already met.
It happened when Kudo Shin'ichi hadn't
transformed into Conan yet.
It was when Kid hinted us that he'd
go steal the Time Skyscraper.
Shin'ichi came in time to stop him.
Well done.
Then...
Who are you?
I am
Kudo Shin'ichi.
A detective.
Let me borrow this.
Even if you are a detective.
Can you borrow things like this?
Normally from this distance you can't shoot him.
Damn.
Not bad!
Then how did Kid shoot under these circumstances?
What actually came out of the gun was a card.
Not harming people is actually one of his common routines.
What?
People say he's not such a bad guy.
Then.
Kid's greatest method of stealing is through his disguises.
His face and voice will all change.
Blending in with any circumstance is not a problem.
He can even disguise as someone close to you.
The person next to you might even be Kid.
He's just a guy who loves using flashbombs.
Dad!
Kaito Kid?
He falsely posed as Mouri Kogoro.
Then the only person who hasn't been posed is me?
What are you thinking of doing first?
Mr. Thief.
The battle between Conan, Kid, and Shin'ichi has begun.
The latest movie details are in all these scenes.
You can't miss it.
Where is Kid's next profile report?
This one.
It's the latest theater version.
The latest movie "Magician of
the Silver Sky" premieres at...
Tokyo's theater.
At the universal theatre...
Well then, let's do the introduction.
During this play,
there is a piece of jewelry used by Josephine.
Star Sapphire.
This time, this is Kaito Kid's target.
Dressing Room
Maki Juri
Maki Juri.
Mouri-san is here.
Please come in.
Sorry to interrupt.
Welcome Mouri-san.
Hello.
The one invited here is Mouri Kogoro.
The group of people in the same performance.
Heard that Mouri Kogoro had arrived.
The people involved in this play one by one came out.
Kid should be one of them.
That's right.
I am Narusawa Bunjirou.
Narusawa Bunjirou (34)
Actor
Actor Narusawa Bunjiro.
He is Maki Juri's ex-husband.
Actress: Tajima Tenko
Tajima Tenko (36)
Actress
She is Maki Juri's old friend.
He is Tajima's husband, he is an actor and stage manager.
Ban Tooru (45)
Director and Actor
Actor Shinjou Isao is Maki Juri's current boyfriend.
Shinjou Isao (28)
Actor
However, he's not able to hold his ground
in front of Yaguchi Makiyo.
Yaguchi Makiyo (32)
Manager
Yaguchi Makiyo is Maki Juri's manager.
She often gets scolded.
This is Maki Juri, the star actress, getting
her own make-up artist of course.
Maki Juri (37)
Actress
She's the professional, Sakai Natsuki.
This person's background is secretly complicated.
Sakai Natsuki (26)
Hair Stylist
Quite scary.
Lastly there is one more person.
Hello everybody.
I am Kudo Shin'ichi.
What?!
High school student, Kudo Shin'ichi, has finally appeared.
Who did Kid exactly disguise as?
Is it them?
Nope.
Can't be a child right?
However, Genta-kun could be a possibility.
Kudo Shin'ichi.
Suspicious.
No, everyone here is suspicious.
So who did he disguise as then?
Kaito Kid.
Profile: Saved by Kaito Kid.
The Conan then was very cool.
Almost like Shin'ichi.
Yes.
Kid also disguised as Kudo Shin'ichi.
Ran...
Because the lonely Ran rarely sees
Shin'ichi, she sheds tears.
Conan is held without an answer.
And therefore can't help her.
It's gotten to a serious point now.
Ready to reveal himself,
he finally makes the decision.
Speaking sincerely.
Actually...
I...
really...
It is at this time.
Shin'ichi.
the Kid disguised as Kudo Shin'ichi appears.
That's right.
Jerk! What is wrong with you?
You don't even call me.
Sorry, Sorry.
I got caught up in cases.
I also have to leave tonight.
Hold on, let me get something for you to dry yourself with.
It doesn't matter if she knew if he was
an impostor. Kid helped out Conan.
But don't you think he went overboard with the doves?
Mouri Ran's profile.
Shin'ichi and Ran were childhood friends.
Ran, who likes Shin'ichi, is supposedly very gentle.
But sometimes she can be very vicious.
Please be understanding of her.
He is one who is arrogant and causes trouble for others.
But he has his good points.
Trying to let others praise your courage?
Conan, how do you know?
Could it be...
Could it be that this kid is...
Conan can't help changing his habits and personality.
Where have I seen this face...
Wait a minute, this is...
Boy! Shin'ichi was quite cute when he was young.
Looks exactly like Conan!
She should have noticed that by now.
Planning on collecting evidence to have him tell the truth.
Conan.
This is too weird.
As an elementary school kid, his actions are too weird.
What elementary school kid?
This kind of speed is even faster than any ordinary adult.
Too fast.
Too late, he's been suspected.
Ran, hurry up and bring Ougawa here.
We're running out of time.
Hurry!
There's no time left.
There's no mistake (Yes).
That attitude (Yes), behavior (Yes),
reasoning (Yes)...
No matter how you look at it, it's Shin'ichi. (That's right!)
Can't be wrong.
She said it to my face.
Yes.
I just feel there is something wrong.
You are Shin'ichi!
But, But... this
Absolutely correct!
Conan, who is Shin'ichi, is lying,
saying how it will bring danger to Ran.
Actually, you were enjoying these situations.
You were always lying, right?
Right?
Shin'ichi.
Every time when Conan's true identity
is about to be revealed,
there'd always be someone who knew
the truth to come save him.
First, it was Shin'ichi's mother.
Not good!
If mom said something she shouldn't...
Isn't this Conan?
Long time no see!
You know this kid?
Of course.
Because this kid is my grandfather's, brother's,
daughter's, cousin's nephew.
What?
Grandfather's, brother's, daughter's, cousin's nephew?
This also counts as a relative?
It's basically a stranger.
How can Ran fall for such a lie?
I'm sorry Conan.
Big sis got it all mixed up again.
She fell for it...
He can also get away like this...
Long time no see
Shin'ichi.
No way!
Because Shin'ichi, he...
Hey, hey You couldn't have already
forgotten my voice have you?
How cruel and thoughtless.
I can't help but make the tone of my voice younger.
Better borrow this first then.
Isn't this Conan?
Yes.
Edogawa-kun.
Kudo Shin'ichi.
Aren't you...
Heiji, What are you doing here?
Kazuha!
I thought I told you not to come.
You should really think about changing accents.
Not exposing your true identity in front
of Ran means she won't meet Shin'ichi.
Just when the hopeful Ran can't
see Shin'ichi, she becomes sad.
Being a girl it can't be wrong.
Uh.
Shin'ichi-niichan said.
No!
Don't say anymore.
I don't want to hear it.
Ah! Ran's sorrowful heart has also been downloaded.
Sorrow.
Ran's sorrowful heart can't even be described on TV.
It has finally flooded into the movies.
We'll be together when we die.
Shin'ichi.
I love you...
Because I love you!
I love you more than anyone on this earth.
I understand your feelings right now.
They have elevated their relationship to another level.
This new work, Magician of the Silver Sky,
also contains a new and improved,
romantic scene with the sudden
appearance of Kudo Shin'ichi.
If you like him, why don't you come out and say it?
What nonsense are you saying!
I already told you it wasn't like that.
But this is a movie.
Until now, Ran has not revealed her true feelings.
3, 2, 1.
I love you Shin'ichi.
Whoaaa! She said it!
This was actually her first time confessing.
Let's rewind that.
3. 2. 1.
I love you Shin'ichi.
I said it for you.
I am such a good person.
Following is a spectacular advertisement...
After the advertisement, it's even better.
What is the next profile?
Found it.
It's the music.
How did Kid become this uncle?
Who is this?
I see, this is the person who composes
the music for Conan.
Where will the music be amazing this time?
It will feel like it blows you away.
I feel that the music is really good.
This doesn't look like something I should say.
He said it himself, so how is it?
Is there some place where it's even more amazing?
Rina Aiuchi created the theme song.
It is an "I am by your side" kind of song.
Which also means it speaks out Conan's heart.
How about we let Ran know Conan's real feelings?
If that were to happen, Conan would probably end.
This would be serious then.
What do you say?
Forget it.
At the end of the show, there will be a
very exciting present. Pay attention.
To obtain this present.
It is you!
How did Shin'ichi become Conan?
The cause of his small stature...
The reason Shin'ichi became Conan is because
of those Men in black.
From crimes, to managing a first-class enterprise,
their activities are numerous.
The whole organization's size and goals are all unknown.
The story goes as deep as the FBI.
The Japanese police force doesn't even
know the existence of this organization.
When Shin'ichi was on a date with Ran,
he stumbled upon a location where the Men
in black were making a transaction.
He was knocked cold.
He was forced to take a mysterious drug.
And his body changed to the size of a 6-year-old.
His body shrunk.
Why?
Could it be.
The name of this drug is...
APTX4869
The one who invented this drug was Haibara Ai.
Very cute, huh?
A very good match for me.
This woman, who created this chemical
drug while in the organization,
refused to continue the development
on this drug and was held captive.
Therefore, to escape, she took the drug she created.
and like Conan, became a small child.
And thus escaped from the organization.
I don't know if this is good or bad fortune,
but I feel it's a good thing.
Another person involved with the development
of the drug is this mysterious person.
What a group of shady operations...
What exactly is their true purpose?
The only clue is.
The ones who want to eliminate the rebel
Sherry, also known as Haibara, are
the most important people to pay attention
in the organization, the duo Gin and Vodka.
There is also Vermouth, who has
been keeping an eye on Sherry.
They should be careful.
Being eyed by these dangerous people
is certainly not an honor.
Maybe it's best to continue as a child.
Be patient for a while.
I'm very sorry.
These are the newest orders from a certain person.
About that person.
Who is that man?
Him?
Who... Who exactly is it?
What... What is this?
It's no good.
What is happening?
Better go back.
I'm back.
I'm finally back.
What is it, Christies YP?
Ah, Haibara is really cute!
Have you clarified the information on Kid?
What have you found out so far?
Stop always researching the past. You
should also go collect the newest data.
Ok. Off I go.
About the theme song.
In regards to the movie's theme song.
Rina Aiuchi's new song Dream×Dream.
So what is the meaning of Dream×Dream?
Personal dream.
Then the opposite party's dream is also yours.
Becoming one,
Becoming one big dream.
Therefore I wrote these lyrics for the theme song.
With this much said, any theme song in each of the movies
in the Detective Conan series is a new song.
That's right
About the movie's theme song.
These songs are so fast and so fresh.
The theme song for the television
series "Start" is also new.
I feel that the feeling the lyrics give is
very suitable for the Conan's opening.
Everyone, please listen to it once.
I am Rina Aiuchi...
There is more news,
Kaito Kid has appeared again.
This time while attempting to steal Blue Wonder,
Kid performed a stunt by walking in the air.
Committing a crime in front of such a large
audience? What is wrong with this guy?
Disguised and changing voices,
Defying the laws of gravity,
These techniques by Kid are indeed well planned.
No wonder he is Conan's strongest rival.
Yes.
What is his next target?
Here it is.
About the newest movie.
The story starts with an undated letter.
These 26 letters of the alphabet
dance like circles in the air.
I've come for the "Gem of Destiny".
Kaito Kid.
Should we determine victory or defeat in one move.
Yeah, your lover is at home waiting
for you to come to dinner.
Conan and Kid face off.
Even in mid-air,
he will not let go of Kid.
He should appear again somewhere.
At 10,000m in the air, a murder occurs.
Who is the criminal?
Then Shin'ichi appears before Conan.
I am Kudo Shin'ichi.
He's not Shin'ichi-oniichan.
Then who is it?
Who did Kid disguise as?
Is it her?
Or her?
Everyone is involved in this puzzle.
It's a race with the incident at hand.
All of these people have complicated
backgrounds and circumstances.
How does Conan, Shin'ichi confront these situations?
Then there's also the most critical event.
The crew and passengers fall into a panic state!
Can Conan rescue them?
A mystery filled with twists and turns.
Conan's deciphering ability is the key.
Everything is determined by the people's imagination.
Add on Ran's burning emotions.
Conan and Kid.
This pair's eternal gamble for pride.
Finally, the battle that will decide it all.
Who wins the battle?
Detective Conan: Magician of the Silver Sky.
I love you, Shin'ichi.
With this, the software will finally be functional.
Right, Christies YP?
Yes.
Originally, I was worried if I could
get along with an old man.
It looks like it's not a problem anymore.
That's right.
That's what I wanted to say.
But...
Careful...
What is it, Christies YP?
You will never find out my true identity
using this kind of software.
In fact, I think it's better if you go to
that glasses-wearing kid Detective.
Professor Agasa.
I've been hacked again.
That guy Kid...
I guess I still need Shin'ichi.
Don't worry, Professor, there's still the present.
Magician of the Silver Sky Original tape and CDs.
The complete music CD set will be
given to 30 audience members.
There's also Detective Conan photo
albums provided by SOURCE NEXT,
which is also 30 sets
will be given as gifts.
People hoping to get these gifts should write down the
following information and send it to the following address.
See you in theaters!