We've arrived at the spot.
We shall now begin.
All clear. All units in position.
All of you, wait here.
A large group serves only to scare the game away.
I shall take that.
I taught you how to use that.
You remember, right?
Indeed, quite well.
Oh, should I have forgotten?
That would assist me greatly.
Here, take these.
Oh my...
It is indeed a privilege to be served by Your Highness.
Mother, will you really not come with us?
No, thank you.
I do not like barbaric activities such as hunting.
It isn't barbaric.
Hunting happens to be a noble sport.
It's all right, Prince.
Let's have a man-to-man, one-on-one challenge.
Only men are able to truly enjoy hunting.
I overheard that.
Oh dear!
You mustn't be here.
Hurry. Run away.
Mother?
No...
This can't be...
This can't be happening!
It's an emergency! Hurry!
Sir!
You, have a car ready!
Yes, sir!
Duke Gerard!
I was unable to stop him.
Again!
That's yet another walk!
This is getting scary.
The bases are now loaded, with no outs.
Yeah!
More beer!
Yum!
Dad, that's your fifth!
That's too much!
Give him a break.
This is his only joy.
Go get them, Rumi!
A sac-fly would do!
Or better yet, hit it out of the park!
Why did you bring two again?
Don't strike out.
Dad!
They really need a strikeout here.
What will be Coach Hoshino's decision?
We interrupt this sports telecast to bring you breaking news.
Oh hey! Come on!
At approximately 10:20 AM local time,
Not now!
Queen Sakura and Prince Jihl of Vespania were killed in a hunting accident.
I repeat.
Queen Sakura and Prince Jihl of Vespania are dead.
The Kingdom of Vespania recently garnered worldwide attention after a special mineral was discovered there.
A hunting accident?
Queen Sakura, noted for her fondness of Japan—
We've delayed the funeral service a month from now, with only a select group of guests invited.
We cannot help but wait so long after such an incident.
Such a terrible thing happened, despite my presence at the scene.
We have to at least prevent the princess from committing suicide.
We can't change what has already taken place.
Please don't blame yourself too much.
Let's think about what is to come.
I am pleased to hear you say so.
How is Princess Mira doing?
The same as before.
She's insisting on not becoming queen.
We can't blame her after she lost both her mother and brother on the same day.
And...
there is that matter as well...
We don't want Princess Mira to be the next queen!
Don't let a brat rule our country!
Abolish the monarchy!
The anti-princess faction...
They have the nerve to call Her Highness a brat?
I've even heard that some are willing to carry out acts of terrorism.
I'm counting on you to protect the princess.
Yes, sir.
Don't just stand there!
Hurry and shut them up!
Princess Mira, please calm–
Quiet!
You're okay with them calling me such things?!
Keith! Where's Keith?!
Bring Keith here right now!
I'm right here.
Is there a problem, Princess Mira?
Can't you hear them shouting?
Those are the cries of our people.
They don't need to tell me. I never wanted it in the first place!
I will never be queen!
You are the heir apparent.
Please do not throw a fit. Rather, compose yourself.
I won't have any of that.
I thought my brother was being groomed as the heir apparent to the throne...
I always thought so...
Your first engagement is to fly to Japan for official business.
To Japan?
No!
I've heard there are people out to harm me!
I'm not leaving this room!
We'll protect you even if it costs us our own lives.
Additionally, I'm sending an ideal bodyguard to accompany you.
You may come in.
Hey, Princess.
I detest bearded men.
Hey. Good work.
Please train me in marksmanship again!
Any time.
Master Jigen!
Stop calling me master.
I thought you had already left for Japan with Her Highness.
But the princess seems to abhor me.
What?
By the way, is the Queen Crown that the princess will wear at her coronation over there?
Yes. Would you like to take a look?
Oh, I can see it?
That's the Queen Crown, huh?
It's the country's most prized treasure; passed down from queen to queen for generations.
Oh, that really is something.
Please don't, Master!
I'm not swiping it.
It isn't that.
The security beyond that point can't be disabled from this station.
You'll be locked up the moment you step inside.
We don't even have the password to disengage that lock.
Oh?
That sounds problematic.
Yeah, that sure is problematic.
It's guarded so diligently.
It's overprotected.
First...
If I set even one foot on the floor,
I'd get caught out by the weight sensor.
Even if I get past that,
I'd get caught out by the infrared sensors.
And even if I get past those,
I'd get caught out by the thermal sensor.
Three outs and you're outta here!
The security was perhaps needlessly heightened since a certain someone made a hash of stealing it once.
I didn't make a hash of it!
So, now what?
Give up and go sightseeing?
Using my salary?
Have I ever given up on anything?
That's why I get into all kinds of trouble.
Take a look at this.
Showing off your hacking skills?
No.
This stone here could be our lucky item this time.
The Vesparite Stone.
Chopper #2 to HQ.
We are now circling above Sakurasaku Hotel.
Have you received any requests to guard a VIP?
This is HQ. Negative.
Jeez!
This was supposed to be her chance to meet all kinds of suave celebrities and sportsmen,
and she's caught herself up in a karate lesson.
You sure are fond of that kind of stuff, Sonoko.
Yeah, Ran's sure got some taste. I just don't get it.
I was actually talking about you.
She said she'd come even if she was late.
Anyway...
And where has he gone off to?
Don't you get it?
He's trying to find Okino Yoko.
As always.
Are you crazy?!
You want me to attend some party when I'm feeling like this?
I already said no!
All right, Your Highness.
So, you wish to cancel this party planned by your late mother,
and return home without saying a word to the people of Japan who too are mourning our loss?
Quiet!
Princess!
It's already past the scheduled time.
Have Her Highness ready quickly.
Y-Yes, sir.
Princess Mira...
I hate this!
So, have you found Yoko?
She's not here.
Ladies and gentlemen, I apologize for having kept you waiting.
Please welcome her with a warm round of applause:
tonight's surprise guest, Her Highness Princess Mira of Vespania!
Please welcome the surprise guest. Here is Princess Mira!
The princess has made her entrance.
All units, keep your eyes on the guests.
Follow anyone who attempts to leave the room from this point onwards.
Affirmative.
This is the main entrance.
We're cordoning off the entrance for now.
We'll send all further guests to the side doors.
Did you get that, Unit B?
Yes, sir.
Please have a seat, Your Highness.
Ran?
She looks just like Ran...
Ran never dresses up like that.
Oh, did I catch a cold from the shower?
Shoot, it's this late already!
Sonoko must already be upset.
Princess Mira, may we have a few words from you?
Princess Mira has been enjoying her first visit to Japan.
Hey, that guy behind her is doing the talking.
The princess looks mean.
You think a princess would want to come to a mere hotel reception?
The name of this hotel is "Sakurasaku."
The late Queen Sakura loved the cherry blossoms with which she shared her name.
And this happens to be the reception of a hotel which shares the name of that very tree.
Had she not had that accident, she would most certainly have been the one attending this event.
The princess' visit would normally have been canceled,
but Vespania must want to be in a better position with Japan so as to make more profitable business dealings.
I have to feel sorry for her.
Is there any place in Japan that you wish to visit?
Princess Mira has always wanted to visit Kyoto.
I-I see.
How about any Japanese food that you like?
Her Highness loves sushi.
Man, he's answering everything.
Here, hold this for a minute.
I'm heading over to the restroom.
Don't go off handing wine to a grade schooler.
Now, I would like to request Princess Mira to grant us a toast.
Ladies and gentlemen, please lift your glasses.
I'm totally out of juice.
I'll go get us some.
Oh, thanks, kiddo.
Yeah, right. You motioned at me to get them.
Hurry up, okay?
Princess Mira, will you grant us a toast?
Princess Mira, can you give us a toast?
Don't drink that!
I'm sorry, Your Highness.
But could you have that man who poured your wine sample it first?
Someone! Please...
Please grab that man!
Get him!
To the kitchen! Contact the exterior unit too!
Everyone! Please stay calm!
Please don't run! It's not safe!
Outta my way!
Uncle! Stop that man!
To point a knife at me, Mouri Kogoro—
Hey, w-wait! I haven't finished my line yet!
A lethal dose of poison was discovered in the princess' glass of wine.
Mr. Keith, while a surprise visit is fine,
we can't protect you if you keep it a secret from us as well.
I had determined that our royal SP units were enough.
Enough?
Enough that no guards were spared for the kitchen?
Takagi!
From the outset,
we had advised Her Highness not to have contact with food or drink at the party.
That being said,
I must thank these two gentlemen.
Princess Mira?
No!
P-Please don't worry.
We prepared this glass of water ourselves.
That's enough. Leave this room at once.
Leave me alone!
We are right outside.
Summon us if you require anything.
Mother...
I can't...
I can't do this.
I'll go check the roof.
Don't allow anyone inside.
Yes, sir.
I've had enough.
I can't take this anymore.
The man who had attempted to poison the princess said that he was hired to do it.
He was told that it was just a prank, and that the drug had been a mere laxative.
He's cooperating with us now.
Who hired him?
It was a man he met for the first time today: a foreigner.
Sheesh. Committing a crime merely for some quick cash.
From the information we've gathered, there are extremists within the anti-princess faction.
Can you really protect her just by yourselves?
There is nothing that we wish to request of the Japanese police at this point in time.
By the way, Conan, how did you realize that the sommelier was a fake?
What gave him away?
Well, he smelled of cigarettes when he passed by me.
I've heard that high grade sommeliers don't smoke, so I thought it was peculiar.
This is a five-star hotel, right?
While there might be sommeliers who are smokers,
they wouldn't smoke right before offering wine to a princess.
Conversely, many smoke right before committing a crime so as to compose themselves.
That was a great catch, Conan.
Princess!
Princess Mira!
Has a fire broken out?
No, none whatsoever.
Princess Mira is nowhere to be found!
Why...
Hasn't anyone been keeping watch over the other door?!
No, sir!
Idiots!
Princess Mira!
W-We're sorry, Chief.
Let's take the stairs!
Do you seriously think we can make it from the top floor?
Contact the lobby unit at once.
Assign men to the basement as well!
Yes, sir!
Keep your eyes on the elevator she took.
Get in touch with me if it stops at any floor.
Yes, sir!
She lit a cigarette lighter by the fire detector.
And fled from the other room during the commotion?
She wouldn't have been able to, if this weren't the royal suite.
It is imperative that we form a cordon.
That won't be necessary!
It'll be too late if something happens to her!
I repeat.
This is Kyle.
I've found Princess Mira.
I'll be securing her safe retrieval.
Princess Mira!
I wonder if the party's over by now?
I-I'm sorry!
Sheesh!
Where... were you looking...
Let's head back, Your Highness.
No! Let go!
Let go of me!
Princess Mira, please...
Excuse me, let go of her arm!
Can't you see that she's rejected you?
I'm sorry, but this does not concern you.
Help me!
He wouldn't leave me alone!
Let her go!
I cannot.
Stop! Do you want to get—
Hurry!
Impossible...
What?!
You were... what?!
What were you doing?!
Takagi.
Yes, sir!
Form a cordon!
Understood, sir!
Cordon! Cordon!
I'll be taking this down as an official request from Vespania.
Any objections?
Excuse me, I'd like to take something.
Yes, one moment please.
Here.
Is this your item?
Yeah! Thank you!
You're a real princess?!
Is it really that surprising?
Y-Yes, of course it is!
Then that man from earlier was...
He's my bodyguard.
Thought so!
I'll apologize to him, so let's head back!
Stop it.
I ran away because I didn't want to be there.
I'm not going back.
Why?
Why did you run away?
I got tired of the party.
I wish I could say such things.
Hey, do you have a smoke?
A smoke?
I'm a minor! I don't have any!
How old are you?
I'm seventeen!
I'm a second year at Teitan High School! A young and peppy high school girl!
Don't snap at me.
Really, let's head back.
The party should still be going.
No means no.
I thought we might be of the same age, but it looks like I'm a whole two years older.
So you're nineteen...
You're still a minor!
We can drink and smoke at age eighteen in Vespania.
Really?
What?
This is a bit surprising.
A princess who smokes, huh?
Sorry for shattering your dreams.
Is it wrong for a princess to smoke?
I have a life too! I'm not a doll!
I-I'm sorry. I didn't mean it that way.
It's fine.
I'm used to it.
Everyone says the same thing.
But any girl would envy you.
I'm sure any girl would want to be a princess at least once.
Want to be... a princess?
Wait! Wh-What?! What?!
Inspector Megure, we're in position.
Now it's just a matter of time till we find the princess.
Hey, Takagi! You seen Conan around?
Conan's not here?
That damn brat!
He had the nerve to leave me behind!
Wait! Why?!
Oh, come on.
I'm bigger there though.
Shut up! Listen to your elders!
But!
No! No! No!
There. You can let go now.
See? With this...
you're now a princess.
Right?
This is... me...
But...
P-Princess!
I'll come back when the party's over!
You can't! Don't do this!
You better hurry back, or that bodyguard might come after you!
This can't be happening!
But I'm not coming back.
Was I too naive to think that because she ran off in that dress, I'd find her in no time?
Ran!
You're late.
Sonoko's mad.
Ran?
You were at the party...
W-Wait!
Crap, I didn't realize it for a second there!
Hop on.
Think about it. I know who you are.
If I was an enemy, I'd have hit you just then.
Trust me.
What should I say?
It was too long for a bathroom break.
The place was so huge I got lost!
That won't do.
I just need to tell them the truth.
Please, nobody come out.
Princess...
Princess Ran!
So this is where you were.
Sh-Shin'ichi!
Come on, everyone's waiting.
Let's go, Princess.
W-Why are you dressed like that?
Is something strange?
Well, you look like a prince...
A prince?
Are you playing a trick on me?
What a bad girl.
Come on, Shin'ichi! Let me down!
No, I won't.
What's this, all of sudden?
I have news for all of you!
I am taking Princess Ran as my bride today!
Shin'ichi...
I've already decided.
O-Oh my...
What's the princess doing?
Who knows.
She must be admiring herself.
This glass just shows her reflection on the other side.
But that's so sudden...
N-No, I don't hate it...
But, oh, this is too much!
HQ to all units. HQ to all units.
We've secured the target.
The target was secured at 19:53.
We are now returning to standard operational procedure.
Okay. Now, let's head out.
Who exactly are you?
Like I said, I'm Lady Long-Legs.
Are you making a fool of me?
What an unadventurous princess.
I could just leave you here.
Or would you rather go back to the hotel?
Wouldn't it be more fun to play with me till morning?
A transmitter?
Yes. It was on your choker.
Then...
They could locate you no matter where you went.
Keith must have set it!
That's fine then.
It could have been someone who...
was after you.
Hang on tight!
That's your enemy.
But I'm not wearing the choker anymore!
Maybe they watched you swap places at the park.
Just like I did.
It's tough to be–
Stop talking and let's just go!
Okay!
Let me use your restroom!
Hey, are you enjoying this?
Oh, you can tell?
Don't worry.
I'm not clumsy enough to get us caught while riding this.
What if they shoot at us?!
We're in Japan.
I'm sure they'd want to make this look like an accident.
Oh my, I guess we need to get serious.
If you want to be the bad guys...
D-Did you kill them?
Oh no.
I'm not that bad.
I don't screw up against amateurs.
Amateurs?
But they had a machine gun.
That doesn't mean anything.
Only using two cars for a chase, with just two men per car.
Shooting from the backseat at a moving target that's in front of you is a definite no-no.
And they missed while aiming for my tires.
They didn't even compensate their aim for nighttime.
They're just some hired guns.
Wow...
You're so cool!
Hey, is that your friend?
That boy!
He anticipated me?
I was outwitted?
We'll up the gears a bit.
Gotta do it!
Oh!
Make way!
I'm so sorry.
Was that a little immature of me?
But you're at fault for making me get serious.
Who... was that?
She doesn't seem like an enemy.
Are you really... Ran?
Can't you even recognize your own daughter?
You do look a bit cleverer.
You want me to get mad?
So, Ran, the real princess told you that she'd return by the time the party ends?
Yes.
But I didn't know an incident like this happened at the party.
Had I known...
I'm sorry.
No, you don't need to feel responsible at all.
It's all...
I see.
Please.
Mr. Keith,
as you must have heard earlier, we're resuming our search for the princess.
There's no need for that.
Don't be ridiculous again!
Listen here!
Tell us why you think it's unnecessary.
Search?
Just who do you intend to find?
Sonoko!
J-Jeez! Give me a break!
Where have you been? I've been looking for you!
I'm sorry. I got lost.
Got lost my ass!
You always bring back trouble when you do that!
Say, has Ra—I mean, the princess, returned yet?
Well...
The princess is probably upstairs.
She was with Inspector Megure earlier.
Let's go!
Wh-Wha—Hey!
Do you realize what you're saying?
If someone from this country abducted the princess,
what would happen to Japan–Vespania relations?
That really makes me angry!
You're thinking about using her as a substitute?!
I cannot allow that.
Ran is only an ordinary citizen.
We will not allow you to involve her in something that would endanger her life!
Go get changed, Ran. We're going.
U-Um, I...
I could do this until the princess comes back.
Stop talking crazy!
Yeah!
What if the princess never comes back?
That's right, Ran.
As we told you earlier, you don't need to feel responsible.
We'll be protecting Her Highness.
Please observe appropriate diplomatic protocol from this point onwards.
Inspector Megure, I'd like to request a search for Ran.
U-Um...
Understood!
We'll get on it right away!
I have no idea what's going on at all!
I'll have another room ready.
Watch Her Highness till then.
Yes, sir.
Oh gosh, that's him.
E-Excuse me...
I didn't know you were the princess' bodyguard...
Um, I'm sorry for that!
You don't need to apologize.
My carelessness lead to this situation.
I'm the one who has to apologize.
N-No, not at all!
I think that's when...
your button came off.
Around six months ago, a tectonic deformation took place nearby.
Well, whatever.
Anyway, what they discovered here was...
an unknown ore.
Vesparite.
Is that the whole thing?
No.
They found it here, but only by coincidence.
By coincidence?
What kind of power does this stone have?
Wanna know?
In terms simple enough for our aging brains,
it's the ultimate in stealth.
Stealth?
You've heard of fighter jets that don't appear on radar, right?
This stuff can perfect that sort of stealth.
Ferrite-based radio wave absorbing materials have been improving by the day,
but they only account for early detection and can't provide total stealth.
So using this, you can completely disappear?
That's right.
It looks like they've been using lots of scanning devices,
but they're up against a tough one.
Vesparite won't even show up on these.
I see.
So just how do you plan on finding this elusive stone?
Dowsing.
Oh, man.
Have you even tried that before?
Nope.
The things I believe in are Fujiko and dowsing.
Idiot!
Yeah!
Go! Go! Go!
Hey!
I had one! I had one!
You're always keeping watch.
A person generally would, after abducting a princess.
Yum!
Can't you act more like a hostage?
Okay.
Don't put a plate back after you've used it.
I don't know what you're after, but you're not a bad person.
Or are you going to tell me...
what Lady Long-Legs is really after?
See, that shut you up.
But I've already decided to trust...
you and my instinct.
You have rice stuck on you.
I told you not to put the plates back.
What do you mean?!
No, I'm not satisfied with that!
Yes.
Yes, okay.
I'm going over to talk with HQ again.
Stay here.
Have they put pressure on HQ?
Most likely.
Don't make any hasty moves till I return.
Understood.
Hey! You better catch that selfish princess, or Ran's—
We know that!
Then why hasn't the search request been accepted?
That's...
How do you know that?!
Anyone could tell by your reactions!
But why?
Why would they be trying to stop us?
Would it benefit them to have Ran act as the princess?
Takagi...
If I need you, will you lend me your help?
Of course.
You'll bet your life?
Y-Yes, of course!
Here we go!
Right here!
You're the one, eh? I so wanted to see you!
Have you found it?
Yeah, it's one hot babe.
H-Hey!
This piece of stone will change the world?
Get this...
What if a missile equipped with that emerged above your head?
You'd never know where it came from.
No, you wouldn't even know you were hit.
The world's still doing that kind of stuff?
It never ends.
We're in an era where you're being peeped at from outer space.
You can't blame people for wanting to hide from all these towns full of cameras.
Guilty men do.
Should a thief be saying that?
I'm glad this stone wasn't unearthed in some nasty country.
Vespania's only got nature and peace—
What's with that Oh crap! yell?
Why are you hiding your face now?
Good hit!
Why are you so satisfied?
Let's run!
But that's the wrong way!
Our other car is that way!
I taught them to expect two or more getaway cars!
Taught who?
My little SSK...
Hey! Explain this in five words!
I coached this country's guards!
Let's go!
First: target them as they emerge with their treasure!
Second: don't let them get away!
Third: corner them immediately!
Don't hold back!
It's time to put Master Jigen's teaching into practice!
Roger!
Don't shoot those at us!
Man!
Don't tell me you told them about the helicopter!
Remember to watch out for a chopper with a TV station logo!
One identified! 200 meters below!
And it has a TV station logo!
The chopper is our last resort!
What're we gonna do?
Run for it!
Best of luck, Mr. Coach!
An economic downturn won't defeat me!
You don't need to check whether the culprit's chopper is chartered or not.
Just shoot it down first.
If you're wrong, you're wrong.
This is great!
A veteran's knowledge...
That's the hard-boiled world.
The heck with hard-boiled!
A press conference at Haneda Airport?
Yes.
It will begin at 10 o'clock tomorrow morning.
We shall then fly straight to Vespania afterwards.
Fly?!
I can't!
And I wouldn't know what to say at the press conference.
There's no need to worry.
I'll be doing all the talking.
Also, the real princess will be the one flying out.
Oh, so the princess is safe?
Then, Her Highness can attend the press conference, and not me.
The purpose of tomorrow's press conference is to announce that you were a fake;
that the princess had gone missing in Japan,
and the existence of an exact lookalike.
That's what we'll announce to the public.
I know this is of great inconvenience to you,
but will you assist us until we find those who are after the princess?
So, are you satisfied?
It was the best!
I've never had such freedom.
Where are we going today?
Well, wherever you're supposed to go.
No. I'm not going back.
Oh, did I say anything about going back?
So, that's where you're supposed to be after all.
I-It's not!
Did you find any place here that you felt you belonged to?
Is there anything you can do in this country?
Do you want to find out...
what only you can do?
Remember, we'll take Ran back as soon as the press conference starts.
Yes!
I've even prepared my letter of resignation!
I don't know if just a resignation is gonna cut it.
You only need to sit there.
Please remain calm.
Yeah.
But, even if it's fake...
it's my first... press conference...
The flight is ready.
As expected from a girl who managed to knock you out.
It took a while to take effect.
Take her away.
We're taking off immediately.
Now?
What's going on?!
The princess is unable to attend the conference due to a last-minute emergency back home.
Please quiet down!
Where are they now?!
They're about to take off!
What?!
Damn!
Royal Flight B-1027, you are cleared for takeoff.
Good luck.
Thank you, flight control.
Your cooperation is appreciated.
Gear up.
Retracting gears.
Ran!
Mr. Mouri...
There you are.
You'll be leaving right away, Mouri.
We're going after them?!
Not us.
You're the only one who'll be going, Mouri.
What do you mean?
Allow me to introduce my old friend...
Inspector Zenigata of the ICPO.
Hello.
So you're the renowned detective, Mouri Kogoro?
Y-Yes.
Inspector Zenigata holds jurisdiction in all countries for one particular case:
the apprehension of Lupin the 3rd.
I've heard your story.
I'll take you to Vespania as my assistant.
Thank you!
That's great!
I'm transferring my hopes onto your fists!
Give that guy a good wallop!
Yeah! Leave it to me!
Here, use the letter of resignation I wrote.
Who am I supposed to give this to?
Thanks for letting me borrow this!
Yeah! I love you, Fujiko!
Hey, seriously, who are you?
CIA?
FBI?
Secret agent?
No, nothing like that.
Just an ordinary person.
I just happen to have a lot of friends.
A ordinary person who's about to take off in a F-18 from an aircraft carrier?
You should stop talking.
Queen Crown?
That's what Lupin's after?
It's confirmed intel.
But Lupin the 3rd really exists?
I thought he was just a comic book character.
What?!
You're a detective and you don't know about Lupin?
Ran!
Shin'ichi...
Are you awake?
Where...
Would you please explain what's going on?
Who are you people?
I'm the one who's asking!
A normal girl would start screaming and making a scene.
You want me to do as you expect?
I can scream pretty loud.
We had an incident in-flight while you were asleep.
That boy who found the fake sommelier at the party...
He performed an audacious jump onto the jet, just as it was about to take off.
Conan...
We can't ascend if the barrier beneath the cockpit is open.
So, we reduced altitude at once to examine the barrier.
There, we found...
that boy.
The pilot was astonished at his level-headed judgment and knowledge.
If he had been careless, he could have endangered us 10,000 meters above sea level.
But instead, he located the sensor and alerted the cockpit.
All from the intensely cold and thin-aired front gear compartment.
Is he all right?
No need to worry.
He's only suffering from minor frostbite.
I will not tell you any further lies or fabrications.
Please listen.
Lupin, I borrowed your shower.
Okay!
F-Fujiko?
When did you get here?
Laundry...
Didn't I say borrowed?
Silly.
Too bad...
Still, it was such a pleasant view.
Toilet seat...
No wonder you have so many bags.
You didn't open them?
I thought they were Jigen's.
Home delivery services have gotten so good these days.
Too good.
How did you know about this hideout?
There's nothing I don't know about you.
Why did you leave me out of this?!
I was about to tell you.
You were?
Great! That's why I brought the princess with me.
I'm taking her back to the palace tomorrow.
Maybe we can get in easily.
Anyway, good night.
I haven't slept since yesterday.
Y-You're going to sleep?
To all of you eighty million adult viewers!
Thank you for your patience!
Chow time!
See you tomorrow.
You forgot these.
Damn.
How is the princess doing?
She's settled down now.
She's finished her breakfast as well.
I apologize for all this trouble.
You don't have to apologize.
But to learn that the anti-princess faction had sent agents to Japan...
That was completely unexpected.
Because of the situation, I'd like to move the date of the coronation forward.
Move the date of the coronation forward?
Thank you for waiting.
Where's the princess?
She hasn't arrived yet.
Hey, I heard most of the story from her,
but isn't it a stretch to pair me up with this kid?
You look like a Japanese father–son pair.
Gimme a break!
You're going to get Conan involved as well?
I'm ashamed to admit it, but the only people I can trust are in this room.
It was Count Keith's idea to send Her Highness to Japan at a time like this.
But as a result, we've managed to identify several suspicious individuals among the SP.
This is too pathetic.
The one who'll benefit from the princess' death is the next in succession.
Even this kid would know who's behind all this.
Yes.
I'm certain that it was Duke Gerard who killed the two and made it look like an accident.
Hey, is it all right for you to say that aloud?
You've already found evidence then?
No, none at all.
We've served the royal family for generations.
That includes Duke Gerard as well.
You're asking us because you're unable to take action yourselves?
The judicial system of this country has gone to hell, huh?
Only the queen can pass judgment upon members of the royal family.
As of now, Princess Mira doesn't have that authority yet.
Do you live in the 19th century?
Please.
We have no time left.
The coronation parade has been scheduled for the day after tomorrow.
No way...
If we can't find the real princess by then...
Ran would be in the parade...
Conan...
Princess Ran, please close the curtains.
You never know where a sniper could be.
Don't call me princess.
I'm only a look-alike.
Um, have you two been serving Princess Mira for long?
Yes, I've been serving Her Highness for five years.
I came to the royal palace three years ago.
I've only seen her tomboyish side.
Has she been like that since she was young?
No.
Her Highness is caring and can be easily moved to tears.
But she hasn't...
Hasn't?
What hasn't she done?
Her Highness hasn't cried in anyone else's presence.
She lost two members of her family at once,
so she must have been overwhelmed by grief.
It's so hard to see her in that state!
She's not allowed to.
So...
She had to create a different side of herself.
Are you wondering why I entrusted it to those two?
Yes.
Master Jigen I understand, but what could we possibly expect from that boy?
I don't know how it could be possible, but that boy...
Is he really just a boy?
It's as if he has the body of a child but the mind of an adult.
Fujiko? It's morning.
Quiet!
Did you catch a cold?
Don't pass it on to us.
You think you have any right to talk?
Whose fault is it that I slept in a park last night?
Oh my, he's blaming you.
You're the worst.
Am not!
Either way, can't this car go any faster?
This is the fastest.
What about your usual ones?
They've both passed away.
Hey, I'm thirsty.
Go buy me a cola.
Yes!
And iced coffee for me.
Yes, yes!
You only need to answer once.
Damn...
The tallest building along the parade course is that one.
Say, Daddy, where would you snipe from?
The tallest building, right?
Don't get carried away.
Get off!
Stop acting cute.
Stingy.
Come on, tell me!
You could even make a quick escape from that building, right?
Wait up!
I'm not a hitman.
I wouldn't know where to snipe from.
I never said you were a hitman, Daddy.
But, Daddy, you have callouses on the second joint of your right index finger and on your left palm, don't you?
Isn't that a sign that you use a revolver quite often?
When did you see them?
I always keep my hands in my pockets.
For a second, over at the palace!
Hey, kid...
Let me tell you something:
don't call me Daddy ever again!
You shouldn't!
It's still daytime!
You said we were going to the crime scene!
It's not my fault.
It's this place's fault for opening so early.
That's a very obvious excuse, you know.
Don't worry, I'm only having one drink.
Here.
That's the equivalent of a 500 yen coin.
Go get yourself some juice or something and keep the change.
Just one, right?
Man, it's like I have two princesses with me...
First, cola.
Huh? Hey, cola?
You're not giving me the cola.
And now you're not paying me back?!
Oh yeah?
If that's what you want...
I'll attack one of the Hidden Pressure Points, iwillgiveeverything!
You didn't have to give me any tips!
Mister, you shouldn't steal.
Don't blame me, kid.
I put the money in.
One can's worth, yes.
It's all right!
It's begging me to take these.
Are you really a bad guy?
You don't look like one.
You better be careful.
I might just be a heartless thief!
I see! That's why you carry a pistol in your shoulder holster, right?
I thought that might be the case since your left shoulder has a bit of a bulge.
Say cheese!
Too bad, huh? It's only a video camera.
I'm sorry. I thought you really might have been a bad guy.
Good.
It's not safe to say that to someone who's actually a bad person.
Hey, you're only taking one?
You can take more.
Let's be partners!
You shouldn't steal.
What's up with that kid?
He probably doesn't have many friends.
I left two cans' worth!
Welcome.
You must be from the ICPO.
Yes, I'm Zenigata.
Now, please—
Let's not rush.
Why don't we talk inside?
And who is this?
I am Mouri Kogoro, Inspector Zenigata's assistant!
Inspector, I would like to start off with a patrol!
No need to hurry.
We have tea prepared inside.
Patrol!
Where are you, Lupin?!
Let's just ignore him.
Lupin!
Ran!
Where are you, Ran?!
It's delicious!
Ran!
That voice... Dad?
Please wait here, Princess Ran.
It might be a suspicious person.
Ran!
It is someone suspicious!
It's a man with a tiny mustache! He looks scary!
There's no way that's your father!
That's him all right.
Ran! Ran!
Are you all right?!
Dad! Why are you here?!
Ran, everything's fine now. We're leaving this place at once!
It's so good to see you! Please help Conan!
What's all this ruckus?
Count Keith.
How dare you!
Listen to me, Dad!
You're—
Prepare yourself, damn it!
Stop it, Dad! Listen to me!
I'll punch you for starters!
No!
Don't worry! I have a resignation letter!
Please allow me to expla—
Later!
So, is Lupin really after the Queen Crown?
Yes, most definitely.
But, I was under the impression that Lupin had tried to steal it once but gave up.
He has never given up on anything in the past.
I see.
We shall defeat Lupin once again.
Should he be able to breach that security system, we'd be happy to hand the crown to him.
I hope that he does give up.
I have a meal prepared for you in the other room.
I'd like to see the safe first.
That man over there will show you the way.
Thank you.
Go ahead and make a big scene.
Conan and that man are trying to find evidence, and I want you to help them out.
Since he couldn't go himself, he recommended that I go instead.
Are you satisfied now?
Hell no!
Dad...
Conan and that man might not find the evidence by themselves.
We still don't know for sure that Duke Gerard is the culprit.
But at the scene...
Don't be so naive.
Maybe they're just saying that.
You're a count, right?
It's possible that you'd want to frame Gerard as a killer so you can be the successor.
No way! Mr. Keith was at the palace that day!
Even if he didn't do it directly, he could have easily hired a hitman.
A hitman...
Oh? Do you have someone in mind?
You're correct.
I now see how your son grew to be that way.
He's not my son!
I'm just looking after him!
I would like to ask someone like you...
to undertake a fair investigation.
It's not much, but we can pay this amount in Japanese yen.
Would you accept this?
Ye-Yes, absolutely!
Th-Thank you...
Dad...
A place she has to visit before heading back, huh?
Those two died just past this point, right?
Yeah.
Was it all right to leave her alone?
She's good at running away.
She wouldn't have come back here if she intended to run away.
Besides, she can't cry if we're around.
You sure know a lot about her, huh?
It seems suspicious.
Stop it. It's just...
Just?
She carries a resemblance...
Mother, Brother...
This is the only place for me...
I can't do anything.
I can't do what everyone expects of me.
No one loves me...
But, there's nowhere else...
where you two are.
This is the only place!
Even if an ant were to get inside,
this superalloy door would seal the entire room and lock the intruder inside.
Is this area guarded round-the-clock?
Yes, three shifts of eight hours each.
Should we increase the number of guards?
No, that's not necessary.
I'm sure they'll all be put to sleep.
We control weapon storage ourselves.
Not even the royal family can use them without us knowing.
It says here that no bullet was found in Queen Sakura's body.
The bullet...
passed through her.
It was found in the dirt nearby.
And the rifling matched the shotgun that Prince Jihl had.
I can believe what's written in this case file, can't I?
Yes.
I was there at the investigation as well.
You may take that notebook.
Is that allowed?
As leader of the SP...
The queen, the prince, and Princess Mira—I failed to protect them.
And, as a result, your daughter was endangered as well.
I'll find out the truth.
This is the place.
It was pretty close.
The cherry blossoms sure are pretty.
Hey, why are you here?
Oh, Princess? Why are you here?
What a surprise! We didn't know you were here!
Did I overdo it?
Are you guys pretending to be detectives?
Well, do your best, sommelier boy.
Hey, did Queen Sakura fall on the ground over there?
That's what I heard.
Then...
Hey, Uncle...
Can you give me a piggyback ride?
What? Stop getting cocky—
Want me to call you Daddy?
Thank you, Uncle.
It's been burned!
You have a good nose and eyes.
That branch broke the same time my mother fell.
That means...
Hey, can you make a shot from there?
Huh? You mean the cherry tree branch?
No.
My brother shot the fox behind this cherry tree from that hill.
But, at that moment, my mother was trying to chase it away.
And then my brother grabbed a pistol from our uncle who had just arrived at the scene.
Grabbed?
What are you going to do now, Princess?
Wanna go back with us on our chopper?
This man is pretty amazing.
He can ask pretty much anything of the soldiers in this country.
No thanks. There are people waiting for me.
Waiting for you? You mean that pretty lady?
Yes. She said she's an international lawyer.
She really enjoyed that chase.
Lady?
International lawyer?
Hey, did she give her name?
She said it was Fuji Mineko.
Oh man...
You know her?
And this has that kind of power?
It emits a special signal.
It'll last at least 30 seconds.
Don't want it.
Hey now...
I expected it to be a bigger treasure since you were after it.
But a mere crown?
It doesn't even have that many stones.
It's just some cheap item.
That's a terrible way to put it.
There's incredible history behind it.
Price takes precedence over history.
Aren't you bothered by something she said?
I see why Prince Jihl would opt for a pistol instead of a long-barreled rifle,
but why was the uncle carrying a pistol?
Even though the SP was there, he carried a rifle and a pistol.
Let's inspect those guns once we get back.
You're gonna help me?
Well, I have no choice.
It's my job.
Have you decided on becoming queen?
I'm only going back because I have no other choice.
I'm not thinking about becoming queen yet.
Whether you become queen or not, my job is over as soon as I drop you off.
Call me again.
Here goes Fuji Mineko.
And she's gonna rip her off.
Did you say something?
Not a thing!
Oh, stop here!
What?
We girls have lots of necessities.
Princess Mira!
Are you angry with me?
I'm not.
Why?
I made you go through so much trouble.
Well, you didn't really do that.
I heard the whole story.
You told her?
Count Keith told me.
Keith did?
Thank you.
No problem.
I'm just doing my job.
Is cash really acceptable?
We could have arranged a check or bank transfer as well.
I don't trust anything except cash.
Is that so?
So, did the princess enjoy herself?
Yes.
I believe she was able to be a normal girl and forget about being a princess for a night.
I see.
You're so kind.
Why don't you tell her the truth?
That you wanted to grant her freedom for a day?
I couldn't possibly do that.
Don't worry.
I keep my clientèle's secrets.
I'm a lawyer, after all.
Thank you for feeding a mere driver.
Delicious!
Bring us beer and juice.
Y-Yes, sir.
What?!
Yo.
Don't yo me!
Huh? Isn't that...
You!
Come with me!
Uncle!
Don't uncle me!
What's going on, Lupin?
I gave the princess a ride and they offered me dinner.
Not that!
About Fujiko!
Oh, that?
No, I snuck into the plane and it was freezing...
Not that!
Acting all cocky and playing the detective.
Oh, that?
Has anything good ever come out of her getting involved?
You'll only hinder the investigation!
But she said she'd help.
I'm just trying to help.
Huh?
Yeah, right!
Nothing good has ever come from that!
Whatever the case, let's just get it over with and get out of here.
Yeah.
So, what did the scene look like?
You checked the rifling, right?
Here you go.
Miss, can I have coffee?
Yes, sir.
Oh?
Is something wrong?
Weren't they just here?
Dad, Conan.
That's Ran, right?
Be careful.
If we get them mixed-up now, it'll get scary later.
Those two...
Ran!
Unbelievable!
You're both scum!
Don't be so upset, Ran!
Ran!
Here is your coffee, sir.
Thank you.
You're still here?
Yes, sir.
There are only two of us left: the chef and me.
Sorry.
I'll only be here a little longer.
Why is the Old Man here?
As if I know.
It must be that woman.
I don't think so.
Anyway, now that we're all here, shall we begin?
Mother's fragrance...
Princess Mira?
The door's open.
Excuse us.
I brought them.
Is this really all right?
It's fine.
This is my mother's room.
Everything has been left just as it was when she died.
I haven't allowed anyone to touch anything.
You're investigating, aren't you?
I'll help.
Then, let's begin.
But how funny is this?
My uncle killed my mother and brother, and I'm helping you find evidence.
We don't know that for sure...
I'm sorry.
Why are you apologizing?
This country has been cursed...
by that stone.
Mira...
Awesome...
This is...
I now understand Queen Sakura's feelings...
The queen's great love...
Oh?
A thief's going to come in if you leave the door ajar, you know.
Sleep spray!
See?
Why are you asleep?
Why is it open?!
Why is it not here?
Why did I build this?
Who are you?
Sorry, Lupin.
No... Impossible...
Sorry, Lupi—
I set off all the sensors.
Sorry, Lupin.
Get captured in my place, okay?
What's going on?
They got here too quick!
Thank you for your cooperation.
No problem.
And Lupin appeared as expected.
Your foresight is rather impressive.
I'll see you later then.
Lupin! Lupin!
I shall use the gazebo.
Is everything ready?
Yes, sir. All is in order.
It's finally going to end.
Hello, can you hear me?
Yeah.
I got locked up.
Can you come and get me?
What about the treasure?
It's not here.
I'm turning back.
Aw, come on.
Learn your lesson already!
Okay!
Master, it's your turn.
Yes, understood!
He's cutting more than usual.
I have slashed through several worthless objects once again.
Isn't that pose tough to keep?
Y-Yes...
Thank you!
Now, back me up!
Only Jigen and Goemon left.
Just as I predicted.
Is everyone here?
I believe we're the last ones.
Is something going on?
Why's everyone been called here?
The inspector requested it.
Is this what you wanted, Inspector Zenigata?
Yes.
Thank you.
The reason I asked you all here...
is because a short while ago, the Queen Crown was stolen from the palace safe.
In order to apprehend the thief and take back the Queen Crown,
Sorry, but let me talk first.
I had to empty the palace as much as possible in order—
Damn!
Gotta go with it!
Is something the matter?
It's someone here:
the one who's trying to kill Princess Mira.
But, you were investigating that.
What? Me?
It all began with that peculiar hunting accident.
Was he...
No, I don't think so.
That boy and Ran's father were investigating this, weren't they?
It was no accident.
Yawning?
Huh?
Are you serious?
That's supposed to even keep an elephant down for thirty minutes!
Yes, it was a murder that was disguised as an accident.
What was I...
That thief guy?
This seems interesting, kid.
Can I talk for a minute first, Old Man?
Is this for real?
Fine, man.
Play along with me.
Duke Gerard testified that Prince Jihl was on the hill aiming at a fox behind the cherry tree,
but instead, hit Queen Sakura, who had just stepped out from behind the tree while chasing the fox away.
Isn't that correct, Princess Mira?
Yes, that's what I've been told.
Don't tell me you mixed the two of us up again, Dad.
I'm your father?
Why is that girl here?
So, you knew about that Japanese girl?
Y-Yes, I had overheard some of the SP talking about her earlier.
I apologize for bringing her to the palace without permission...
and without notifying anyone.
I see, so that's how it is.
Prince Jihl committed suicide while holding the pistol in his right hand.
The shot was to his right temple.
And it would have been natural for him to hold it with his right hand.
Is that right, Princess Mira?
My brother... was left-handed.
Oh?
That means someone had him hold the pistol in the wrong hand.
Why did that person think the prince was right-handed?
I saw a photo of the prince in Queen Sakura's room.
It was of him playing baseball when he was younger.
He was wearing a glove on his right hand.
Since he was young, my brother had been taught to eat and sign his name with his right hand.
I see.
There must be a number of proper mannerisms to become the nation's ruler, after all.
Kyle, did you bring the rifle?
Yes, it's right here.
That boy said you wanted me to bring it.
The two of them were using the same model.
Unless they're custom-made,
all bolt-action rifles are operated with the right hand.
That's because the bolt used for loading ammunition is positioned on the right side.
Huh?
Oh, so that's what's going on!
Don't talk on your own!
Now I know who the killer is.
Uncle!
I want to hear the rest of your deduction!
Conan!
Don't climb up there!
S-Sorry!
Duke Gerard...
Give me a minute.
That's where you made your fatal mistake.
After seeing the prince handling the rifle with his right hand,
you didn't think twice before putting the pistol there.
Why...
Why?!
Why did you shoot her?!
The one who shot the queen was you.
Did you really do it?
Is this what you wanted to discuss?
Inspector Zenigata, it seems your assistant wants to turn this into a murder investigation.
What shall we do?
Mouri, is that all you have to say?
No, I'm still getting to the best part.
You're talking again!
Ahem, internal memo.
I saw the bullet inside.
Let me show off.
Now then...
You insist that it was all an accident, right?
And that this is the rifle that was used to shoot Queen Sakura?
So?
You switched them, didn't you?
Because of the rifling, you swapped your rifle with the prince's after killing the queen.
Right?
Are you done?
If you'd like to turn this into a murder investigation, please present your evidence.
D-Dad, what have you done?
It was a blank.
A-A blank?
What bothered me was the part about Queen Sakura going along on the hunting trip.
Did your father know my mother?
I've never heard him mention it.
And he's not even acting like his usual self.
His usual self?
He's...
His usual nickname is Sleeping Kogoro...
I can't believe he's talking about the case so boldly...
Isn't that strange, Gerard?
Why were you shocked?
Has he gone crazy?
We're doomed.
This is—
This rifle is the one you were using that day, correct?
I had Conan ask Kyle to bring the rifle that Duke Gerard was using that day.
Yes, that's what he asked me.
That means you were hunting without realizing that your own rifle had blank shells, correct?
Queen Sakura never liked hunting because animals were killed under the label of a sport.
Perhaps that lead to her wanting to ensure that Prince Jihl disliked it as well.
Thus, she gave Prince Jihl shells that were missing bullets.
Mother...
Kyle and the others recorded that in great detail in the case file.
But I can't believe a queen would have such in-depth knowledge about weapons.
Great question!
Keep quiet!
Fine.
I noticed the many trophies in Queen Sakura's room.
She must have been quite good at sports.
In fact, when she was young, she'd been the winner of a modern pentathlon.
And, naturally, a pentathlon consists of...
equestrianism, swimming, running, fencing, and...
marksmanship.
I also noticed that you had won a trophy yourself, Duke Gerard:
a marksmanship competition, just three years previously.
What a great—
That's enough, Detective.
If I am indeed the culprit, why am I merely standing here unconcerned and doing nothing about all this?
I'll answer that.
It's so you can eliminate all your pests with one sweep.
Great work, Detective!
I'll save killing you for the very end.
That's so uncool!
What are you gonna do about that pathetic move?
Oh? I guess that was it.
Is this all?
How drab.
Well, our opponents were pretty shabby.
The rest is all yours.
Guards!
Keith, none of the palace guards will listen to you.
Oh?
You're saying you were prepared for this situation?
Well done, you petty scoundrel!
And how's this?
Don't move!
I have a little surprise hidden inside the center pillar.
With that, you can all go visit the queen together.
And what're you gonna do?
Be blown up with us?
At this range, it's possible that I'll be caught in the blast.
So, please, don't make me press this.
And I'll give you one last chance...
Keith,
it's yours.
Come with me, and let's make Vespania prosper together!
The title of count has no meaning.
Are you really content babysitting in the palace?
Does this chance not excite the blood that runs in you?
I'll save Kyle as well.
How about it?
If you're a man, wouldn't you want to make a big dream come true in this world?
And it's all for the benefit of our nation!
Right now, Vespania is on the verge of acquiring power.
A new energy!
An infinite power coveted by the entire world!
Keith!
Count Keith!
The Stinger family has served the royal family for two hundred years.
The blood flowing in me...
Every last drop is loyal to the Vespania Royal Family!
That's a deal!
Wh-What's this?
I thought you were about to make a run for it.
Weren't you going with your usual pattern of fleeing amidst the panic, Lupin?
Oh, so you knew?
Remember what you said nine minutes and thirteen seconds back.
Can I talk for a minute first, Old Man?
You called me Old Man, didn't you?
Oh my, but what's with this timing?
That guy over there's being a real man.
Come on, don't ruin the atmosphere.
Can't you see?
Like I care?
All I'm concerned with is arresting you!
You bastards!
Was it all really...
your doing?!
Yes.
I couldn't entrust this country to my sister.
Once the mining commences and reaches full speed, we will all but lose the natural environs of Vespania!
You just don't understand how valuable this country is now!
The one that doesn't understand is you!
We would lose a priceless treasure in exchange for earthly wealth.
The small-minded one is you!
Those who abuse the earth will be abandoned by it!
How can you not understand that?
A ruler who has lost their ambition is no longer fit to rule.
It would not change if this country was to be inherited by her children.
That's why my brother and I...
Such a shame for you, Keith.
But I'll grant you your last wish.
I pressed the switch.
All right!
Caught one!
Pull, Old Man!
What?!
Duke Gerard!
Kyle!
Yes, sir!
Mineko!
Isn't this ball something?
I no longer consider you my uncle.
How could you do that to your own sister and nephew?
I will not forgive you.
I will not hand this country over to you!
The ruler of this country...
is me!
Princess Mira!
Hey, biker lady.
How long will this thing keep working?
About three more seconds, I think.
Jump for it!
I met your mother here.
Please steal me along with the crown!
I don't want to be a bird in a cage.
I want to fly the vast skies!
That's not something I can do.
Why?
Listen here.
Just like how my grandfather was a great thief,
your father is the king of this country.
And eventually, you'd have to rule this country.
Wearing this.
Instead of going with me, you have to fly the vast skies of this country.
Lupin...
See ya.
Once this country becomes a great nation with your help,
I'll come and steal it one more time.
She was just like you are now.
The strong mother I had known was once just like me.
I had long since forgotten that promise,
but I suddenly remembered when I heard that Sakura had died.
Hey there, stealing is a crime.
It wasn't me. The biker lady was the one who took it.
But isn't she your partner?
Don't be so picky. Is this what you want?
I'm returning this to you.
Like I thought, it looks best on your head.
By the way, kiddo.
Let me ask you something.
Why did you think that Sakura wasn't shot on accident?
I heard from your daddy that you made up your mind the second you came here.
It was because of that broken branch.
That branch?
Prince Jihl was aware that your mother loved this tree, wasn't he?
Yes.
So, I figured he'd never point his gun at her precious cherry tree.
I see.
That's why the prince couldn't have been the shooter.
It was the cherry tree that showed me.
Oh yeah, can I ask you a question too?
I haven't heard your name yet.
You haven't, huh?
My name is...
Lupin the 3rd.
Was it all right to keep this a secret from Zenigata?
It's the princess' order.
We can't disobey that.
Damn that guy!
I'll catch him the next time I see him!
But, I'm relieved.
All the bad guys have been caught.
Lupin!
Well, I guess not all of them...
They've left already.
I see.
One of these days, I must get him to come steal the Queen Crown again.
But, unless this becomes a beautiful and peaceful country,
I can't ask him to come back.
I'm truly grateful to you.
Thank you so very much.
Ran, I had a great night with you.
It's all because of you.
No, I got to be a princess.
Princess Mira, it's time.
Huh? Where's Conan?
What?
Wasn't he just saying that he wanted to see the coronation?
Agents from the Japanese Embassy came for him earlier.
After all, he did enter the country illegally.
That's true.
Then, shall we get going?
Oh my, how terrible!
This is bad.
If I apply for a passport, the fact that Edogawa Conan doesn't exist will...
Looks like even the great detective is about to give up, huh?
Uncle—I mean, Mr. Lupin!
That sounds like a mouthful.
You can just call me Uncle.
We haven't been in disguise for a while now.
You hadn't noticed?
Biker lady?
And Daddy!
What'd I tell you about calling me Daddy, eh?
Your beard stings!
He most certainly looks like a child.
But inside, he's an unfortunate high schooler.
Isn't it agonizing to have the body of a child?
Talking dirty?
I'm not talking dirty at all, Mr. Old Fashioned.
Now, now.
I happen to have the mind of an adult...
and the body of one as well!
Ouch...
Still in the gutter...
Don't worry.
This lady will take you to Japan, Mr. Kudo Shin'ichi.
My friend's ship just happens to be nearby.
Thank you.
But, if I find you stealing again,
I'll come catch you.
What are you gonna do, Lupin?
He'll catch you if you meet again.
Are you kidding me?
Detective Conan, huh?
Now, we have plenty of time.
Let me check you out.
C-Check out what?
What do you mean? The secrets of rejuvenation, of course.
Rejuvenation? I just shrunk.
I don't care either way.
No–hey–um...
Could you stop touching me?