What? The professor?
He asked if we could all go over to his house this Sunday at 10 in the morning.
We're going camping?
Genta-kun, didn't we just go camping?
And don't people usually set out for camping earlier in the morning?
Ah, well then...
Perhaps it's flower watching? Aren't the cherry blossoms in full bloom along the Temuzu River?
Or perhaps he wants us to test a new game prototype he's writing?
At any rate, we'll find out when we get there.
It's bound to be something pointless anyway.
A Challenge from Agasa!
Agasa vs. Conan and the Detective Boys
What?
Kidnapped?
The professor!
Here, look.
O-Okay.
Detective Boys: I've been taken away by bad guys.
Please go to three places in Beika City and save me.
The first location is 5 minutes walk from Teitan Elementary,
Ten minutes from Beika Station,
And 15 minutes from Touto Tower.
You'll find me waiting for you under an oak tree.
Signed, Agasa.
This is terrible!
We've got to save him quick!
Wait a sec. This is a game the Professor set up for us.
Right, Haibara-san?
Beats me. But he was doing something by himself until late last night.
He had a map of Beika City laid out.
A map of Beika City? I knew it! I knew it was a quiz.
So he hasn't been kidnapped?
Thank goodness.
Three quizzes, eh? Still, it was a bit irresponsible say you've been kidnapped as a game, Professor.
Haibara-san, where's that map of Beika City?
There it is, over there.
Then, let's get started thinking!
Yeah!
When you said by himself, you mean you didn't help him this time?
Yeah, so I don't know the answers either.
Kudou-kun...
I probably don't have to tell you this, but you should let them figure it out since the Professor made it for them.
Of course. But if I don't give any hints,
I don't think first graders will be able to figure it out.
So this is Teitan Elementary.
And this is Beika Station!
Let's see, my house is...
Who cares where your house is! Look for Touto Tower.
Ah, here maybe?
Found it!
But where's a place that's 5 minutes walk from the elementary school?
It definitely can't be any of our five houses,
Since we all walk more than 5 minutes.
I can make it in 5 minutes if I run.
The hard part of this quiz is that it also has to be 10 minutes from Beika Station,
And also 15 minutes from Touto Tower.
Ten minutes from Beika Station...
Fifteen minutes from Touto Tower...
Argh! I don't get it!
Yeah, if only he'd written distances instead of times, this would be a little easier!
Mitsuhiko, if you approximate, there's a way to convert time to distance.
A person's walking speed is approximately 4 or 5 kilometers per hour.
You can think of that as 80 meters per minute in a residential neighborhood.
80 meters per minute? In other words...
Five minutes if 400 meters; ten minutes is 800 meters.
And 15 minutes is 1200 meters, right?
And since that map is 1/10000 scale,
Forty meters is 4cm, 80 meters is 8cm, and 1200 meters is...
Twelve centimeters, right?
Mitsuhiko-kun, I have a ruler!
A place 4 centimeters from Teitan Elementary...
Eight centimeters from Beika Stations...
What are you waiting for? Do mine too!
And a place 124 centimeters from Touto Tower!
What? That's weird.
How come they don't match up?
So, why don't you tell them about that?
No, I'll watch a bit longer.
I know, I can use this!
Oh? What's that?
It's a compass. I've seen my big sister use it.
The area inside the circular line is
Places within 5 minutes walk of Teitan Elementary.
And this is...
Places within 10 minutes of Beika Station.
And lastly...
Places within 15 minutes of Touto Tower.
Beika Park!
Oak tree, oak tree.
Isn't that it?
OAK TREE
It's an oak!
Just like the park guide said!
There are two quizzes under this tree.
I don't see any.
That's odd.
An umbrella.
Why is it up there?
A little further to the right. The right!
Ouch, my leg.
I got it!
Agasa
"Agasa" It's the professor's!
Just a moment. Could it be?
Agasa. A-gasa.
A-kasa. Aa, kasa. (kasa = umbrella)
It's a pun!
What's this?
Something is written there.
Wow, it's long!
It's got a lot of letters too.
N YU E U TE SA KA NE RO SU KO KI YO SE TA MO NA O SHI MI RA RE Rl MA TO TSU NI ME HE A
What the heck is this?
It's some sort of code.
This code must indicate the other two locations.
Maybe if we read it backwards? a he me ni tsu to ma ri."
Or if we take every other syllable? "n e te ka ro ko yo ta?"
Ge-n-ta-kun is awe-some."
What? How?
I just figured it must say that.
I don't have a clue.
Conan-kun, do you?
I wonder why the ribbon was wrapped around in a band.
In a band?
Genta-kun, let me see that!
Ayumi-chan, that's backwards.
I wonder if there's another hint somewhere around here?
Could it be?
Hey, the letters are lining up.
You're right.
A MA O KI SA
HE RI NA KO TE
ME RE MO SU U
NI RA TA RO E
TSU MI SE NE YU
TO SHI YO KA N
It's the library! (to-u-sho-ka-n)
BEIKA LIBRARY
That ribbon quiz, that was actually a code used in ancient Greece.
It's called "scytale.
Scytale?
Yeah. They used a rod of a set diameter,
And wrapped a message written on a leather strip around it.
Very astute observation.
Probably every detective knows...
Not you. Those kids.
They're growing up before we know it.
Yeah.
Conan-kun!
Ran-neechan and Sonoko-neechan! Why are you here?
What, is it weird for us to be at a library?
O-Of course not!
Not for Ran anyway, but it is for you.
It's Ran-oneesan!
The brown haired girl is here, too!
Hey! Who are you calling "the brown haired one?" Call me Sonoko-oneesama.
Auntie Sonoko!
Professor Agasa was here earlier.
He noticed us, and said:
Perfect timing.
Could you hand this to the kids?
He said you guys would be here in 30 minutes or so.
What are you guys doing?
Nothing much.
See you later, Ran-neechan.
(Envelope: To the Detective Boys)
I am 〇〇〇〇, have the appearance of a 〇〇〇〇, but I'm still 53 〇〇!
What is this?
Probably we fill the blanks with letters, and then take the letters from the red circles to get the next location.
What's "youbou" mean?
It means personal appearance, or features.
Let's starts at the first 4 letters.
Okay, I'm a blank blank blank blank.
I know! It's "genius."
He's always saying he's a genius (te-n-sa-i).
It could be "famous" (yu-u-me-i)
Couldn't it be "rich?" (ka-ne-mo-chi)
Or single? (do-ku-shi-n)
Or maybe instead of rich it's "poor. (bi-n-bo-u)
Or it could refer to his personality. Like "eccentric. (he-n-ku-tsu)
He's wears glasses, so it could be "nearsighted." (ki-n-ga-n)
Maybe it's "childlike." (do-u-ga-n)
It can't be "skinny." (su-ki-ni-i)
His face is "chubby." (ma-ru-ma-ru)
He should put "big nose." (ha-na-de-ka)
That's mean, Genta-kun.
How about homely? (bu-sa-i-ku)
That's worse!
Hang on. How long are you going to take?
This is enough, we're not getting the answer.
We have to figure them out in order.
It must be "genius," after all.
It's "bucktoothed!"
"Eccentric" is the best answer.
Okay! That's enough!
We'll figure that out later. Let's try the next four blanks.
The next four letters?
I have the appearance of a 〇〇〇〇.
Since appearance means features, maybe it's "elder?" (ro-u-ji-n)
Isn't it Old man?" (ji-i-sa-n)
I agree with Genta-kun!
Looks like another differenced opinion.
Then let's look at the final two blanks first.
I'm still 53 〇〇!
That's easy!
Translator's Note: Putting "ja" here is a common sentence softener.
I'm still 53...
"You know!" (ja-ayo)
And so if "elder" is the word that comes before that? (ro-u-ji-n)
"Ronja?" (not a word)
And if it's "old man?" (ji-i-sa-n)
"Jinja? (shrine)
Beika Shrine!
Maybe I should have made a reservation.
Oops!
Are you all right?
Like I was saying, the first word is eccentric!
It's "round-faced!" (ma-ru-ka-o)
No, it's "big-eyebrowed" (ma-yu-de-ka)
They're still at it.
When we get to the shrine, we'll see him, so we can just ask him. Eh?
What's wrong, Haibara?
They're the professor's.
What?
What are the professor's?
They're cracked.
Skid marks.
And paint scratches from a car body.
Could he have been hit by a car?
No, if he were, then the glasses would have been further to the front of the skid marks.
On top of that, there aren't any pieces broken off the car during an impact.
Then what on earth?
I can't say for certain,
But something is happened to him.
But couldn't this be another part of the game?
He said, "Please go to three places in Beika City and save me."
He didn't say he would be at the third place.
No, I think he meant to meet us here at the Beika Shrine.
And then take us out to lunch.
Lunch?
He said he'd found a good restaurant we should try near Beika Shrine the other day.
He was looking at this flyer.
Western Style Menu
I see. So he was waiting here to get some food.
At any rate, I'll call his cellphone.
Professor Agasa
No good, it's not connecting.
Damn. If only he had a detective badge.
He does! I gave him mine!
What?
I left it in my pocket and my mom put it through the wash,
So it wasn't working right.
I saw him in front of the bookstore yesterday, and asked him to fix it for me.
Sure, no problem.
He should be wearing the same jacket today!
So he might still have it!
Got it.
Due south, about 2 kilometers.
Crap, I lost it.
He must not have fixed it yet.
The transceiver might still work.
Hello? Professor?
Sh-Shinichi?
Oh, it's you, Conan-kun.
It looks like my game has become a reality.
What? Don't tell me, someone kidnapped you?
That's right.
The criminals are a young man and woman.
I saw them kidnapping a middle school girl in a car.
They knocked me out with a stun gun, and I'm being held somewhere in an abandoned building.
Where are the criminals and the girl?
I think they're in the room next door.
They were just making arrangements about a ransom on the phone, so we need to save her quickly.
Got it Can you tell where the building is?
No, but there's a gap in the window, so I might be able to see outside.
There's a telephone pole, and there's a person wearing blue hiding behind it.
Wearing blue clothes? Can you see anything else?
Well I don't have my glasses, but from what I see I think I'm on the second floor.
What about sounds? Can you hear anything, Professor?
A noise or maybe a voice? I've been able to hear a bustling sound for a while now.
What did it sound like?
Gi-gue-ge-ge or maybe ji-ji or ge-kyo-ge-kyo or something.
Ah, I have to go.
Professor!
What's wrong?
Probably the criminals came in or something.
If we don't hurry, his life will be in danger.
Two kilometers south of here would put us in about the 4th block of Beika City.
Let's go!
Somewhere around here.
It's still no good.
Our only choice now is to try and figure it out from the clues he gave.
First the abandoned building. Probably either a high-rise or a building that's still under construction.
It has a telephone pole nearby!
And there's a person in blue hiding behind it.
Could someone be standing guard over the professor?
No.
He said the two criminals were in the room next door.
There's no reason for them to go outside to guard him.
Then what could it mean?
There's also that voice. I wonder what the voice the professor heard was.
He said it was gi-gue-gue, right?
And ji-ji-ge-kyo-ge-kyo.
Could it be a frog? Or a bird?
I don't know. There's nothing to do but look.
I'll contact the police, you guys split up and search.
Blue clothes?
A crow-repellent net?
To the professor, who can't see well without his glasses,
Wouldn't this net look like a person wearing blue hiding behind a telephone pole?
All we have to look for is a building with a telephone pole and a net like this one in front.
But there are so many trash around...
But, all we can do is search.
Say, about that voice the Professor heard...
Could it be cicadas?
Cicadas?
Cicadas only chirp in the summer!
There are something that chirp in the spring too.
They're called Spring Cicadas. They usually chirp from 10 AM to 2 PM and they're known for their distinctive chorus.
Chorus?
Yes. When one chirps, all of those around it begin to chirp as well.
Their other distinctive quality is that they only gather in pine forests.
Pine forests?
But, there aren't any pine forests around here.
There is in just one place.
Oh, wow.
This could certainly be it.
I remembered finding this place before when I went looking for spring cicadas.
Great work, Mitsuhiko!
Conan-kun, look!
See? The telephone pole over there!
A blue net!
Well now, looks like it's time for us to get our money.
This girl's our precious hostage, but, old man...
You're just in the way.
Old man? I may have the appearance of an old man, but I'm only 53, you know!
What's he babbling about?
Who the hell are you?
Edogawa Conan, a detective.
Are you screwing with me? You're dead meat, kid!
Osamu!
Damn it!
What are you doing?
We did it!
With a crow-repellent net!
We caught the kidnapper!
Are you all right?
I knew you'd find me.
Geez, next time give easier hints.
This place has a nice atmosphere.
Doesn't it? A nice quiet place in the middle of a residential area.
Don't they call that a hideaway?
Then let's make this the hideaway of the Detective Boys!
Seconded!
Now, now, this is still a restaurant.
Now this is really a nice place!
The food's good, and the restrooms are clean, and on top of that, the owners are two beautiful sisters.
A guy could come here every day!
It's not a hideaway any more.
What should I get?
Only for the time being, until I tell Ran about it.