Good morning, Shinichi.
There's a favor I'd like to ask of you.
Pardon me, but can you come to the baseball field in Beika Park?
The baseball field?
Are you gonna play baseball, Professor?
Don't forget to eat
your breakfast
Ran
I'll tell you in detail after that.
I'll be waiting!
Play ball!
The Miracle Of Excalibur
I've been waiting for you, Shinichi.
What was it?
This favor you wanted to ask me for.
And besides, why here?
Don't try too hard, Minae!
It's all right to just play small ball!
Or you could ask your childhood pal Akira-kun to let you hit it!
Yo, Minae!
Even though I'm your childhood pal, I won't go easy on you!
Akira...
That's my line!
A girl...
Here goes!
Out!
No good...
I'm overwhelmed by the ball...
I don't have enough strength!
Don't mind!
If only I had more strength...
Two outs, two outs!
I would've crushed Akira's ball if I could...
Ow-ow-ow...
A bat?
What's...
This?
That's a legendary bat.
A legendary...
Bat?
Right, a long time ago, Team Giants' player Oh Sada...
Oh, no...
Matsui Hideki drove it into the ground, according to legend.
The Giants' player...
Matsui Hideki?
What's this, what's this?
Awesome, is that for real?
So this is Matsui's bat?
And...
Whoever manages to pull out the bat...
Is said to be able to obtain the
strength of a genuine baseball player.
The strength of a genuine baseball player?
What was that just now?
What's the matter, Minae-san?
If I can pull this out...
I might be able to gain super strength, right?
Stop fooling around.
What was that, Akira?
Shouldn't you still be playing?
We're changing sides.
Hurry and go on defense.
Well?
What's the meaning of this?
The bat.
Well, I dug the hole and buried it with the help of the coach.
The coach and I are long time friends...
And he asked for my advice.
He wants to know whether there's a way to boost the confidence of that player number 9, Minae-chan.
I swear, back then, electric sparks zapped through my hand.
That bat is not an ordinary bat.
If I can somehow pull that bat out...
Maybe I'll get that strength!
Right!
What're you doing!?
Lucky!
You're a slowpoke as usual, Minae!
Akira, you hit to the right on purpose, didn't you!
Oh, now you know?
Damn!
Give me a break!
To think a stupid slip-up like that cost us a point!
Ken-chan...
We could've won but now we can't!
Hey, don't put the blame on Minae only!
How about you try catching the ball Akira hit?
What's that?
If you want to argue, why don't you guys start hitting strikes?
The only run we have was scored by me, wasn't it?
Say what!?
You punk!
It can't be helped.
It was a losing game to begin with.
Cause we have someone who'd drag us down.
Our team balance is too lame.
Then, are you guys saying you can do better!?
Better than you!
What do I do?
It's all my fault...
Now, now, it won't do if you're feeling down, Minae.
Coach...
What's your jersey number, Minae?
Number 9!
Then, you gotta pull yourself together, all right?
Since you're carrying the fate of nine on your back!
That's so much wittier than the professor's puns.
Very true.
Pull myself together...
That's right.
I need to pull myself together!
If this bat is the real thing, it'll give me the strength...
I'll pull this thing if that's what it takes, and knock everyone's socks off!
That's just some sort of made-up story.
Ken-chan?
Besides...
No way a girl like you can pull it out, right?
You never know if you don't give it a try!
Idiot.
I see.
I get what the professor and the coach are up to.
Oh, you mean that.
They plan to let her pull out the bat and boost her confidence.
Right.
Strike!
Batter's out!
By the time the bat is pulled out, I bet...
By the way, about this idea...
The Legend of King Arthur serves as a hint towards its conception.
That King Arthur extracted the sword and was made king?
That reminds me, Mouri-kun also owns a bat that belonged to Matsui Hideki.
Yeah.
He said he got it from the producer at Nichiuri TV.
And?
What exactly do you need my help for?
About that, Shinichi...
I want you to use this when the time is right.
Professor...
That's...
Around the patch of soil where the bat was buried, I've sprayed a chemical to make it firmer.
So I'd like you to shoot a chemical that will liquefy the soil when the timing is right.
"Pew," like this.
Would be suspicious if I were to do it, right?
So I'm counting on you, Shinichi.
Geez, you called me just for this?
I'd also like you to keep an eye on the bat so that no one else tries to pull it out.
Can't you do something like that yourself?
Professor's fortune this week is under water.
It'd be best if he asked a younger friend to do him favors.
You asked me because of that?
Why couldn't you just ask Haibara for help?
I don't feel like doing something like that.
Figures.
My fate...
"Attract the attention of that guy on your mind by being as mean as you can!
"Your lucky item is a different than usual persona."
Hey, hey, a scientist shouldn't believe
that fortune-telling nonsense!
Not to mention in a young ladies' magazine.
First of all, that sort of made-up legendary bat is so fishy...
No one in their right mind will try to pull it out.
Well, you can't say that for sure, can you?
Why can't I?
Hey, what the hell's with you?
Uncle!
When'd he appear?
This bat...
What's the matter, Uncle?
About this bat, I'm getting the feeling that this belongs to me.
Oh?
This is the legendary bat of Matsui.
Hey, Uncle has nothing to do with that!
I see, as I thought!
Uncle, hold on a second...
Shut up, this is my bat!
What do you mean?
Now, now, Mouri-kun, calm down.
Why don't you tell us the whole story?
Actually, yesterday, I was planning to show off to my buddies back at school during our drinking party...
So I brought my most cherished Matsui bat with me there.
But when I woke up this morning and checked...
My bat had been switched to a different one!
A different bat?
What happened?
I was wondering about what happened too, and I traced my memory from last night...
And recalled that I stopped by this field on my way home after the drinking party.
Now, bases loaded, two outs in the bottom of the ninth inning...
Number 4 Mouri Kogoro in the batter's box...
With a three-point difference!
The pitcher's winding up and...
He threw the pitch!
A hit!
The ball kept flying up towards the centerfield screen!
It's a turnabout game-ending home run!
And, as I was rounding the bases and my tipsiness was getting worse...
I can't quite recall what happened next.
But without a doubt, I picked up the bat lying near home base...
Put it back in my case, and headed home.
I see.
It's possible that the bat had been switched when Uncle picked it up at home base.
But if that's the case, where could Uncle's bat be?
About that bat...
This field is also where I met with the coach yesterday.
During my walking routine, I saw the coach deep in thought...
And that was when he consulted with me about Minae-chan.
Although we tried to rack our brains at the nearby cafe...
Unable to think of a good idea, we went home for the time being.
Just as I returned home, the Legend of King Arthur idea hit me...
So I relayed the idea to him so he could bring the bat...
And I the hole-digging machine, and we agreed to meet at the field at 10:00 PM.
Then the coach came empty-handed.
After seeing the bat in my hands...
He told me it was the exact bat he had forgotten on the bench in the afternoon when we met.
So we buried the bat there.
The buried bat belongs to Uncle, that's probably undeniable.
However, it bothers me that the bat the coach left on the bench would somehow turn up lying near home base.
In that case, that bat...
Belongs to you without a doubt, right?
I know, right?
As I thought!
Hey!
Excuse me for a bit.
That bat is my precious bat.
So would you step aside and let me have it?
No way!
No, no, no, that's my bat, you know.
This is the bat of that legendary player Matsui!
Uncle, forgive me.
That's right, but not anymore...
Hideki...
What choice did I have?
I'm in the same boat now.
What happened to that man?
Looks like he fell asleep.
Oh...
Say, why don't I keep an eye on that bat for you?
You will?
Thank you!
I knew it'd go well if I called you.
Hey!
What're you doing!?
Stop it!
What's the big idea?
Dig.
Hey!
Pardon me.
Sorry about that.
This one here likes tennis balls.
So whenever it detects the smell, it'll always plunge ahead.
I see.
But...
Just give it up.
No way!
I don't see any tennis ball there.
You're right.
Sorry for the trouble.
Now, let's go!
First Uncle and now the dog?
What the heck's going on here?
Hey, look what we found!
A bat!
So perhaps this is it!
All right, let's pull this out!
Hey, you guys!
What are you doing?
Conan-kun, get a load of this!
We followed this treasure map we picked up and came here...
And we're thinking this is the treasure bat we seek!
No, no, you're wrong, this is...
Well, speaking of treasures, a treasure bat comes to mind, right?
You're doing it again!
So that's indeed the case, huh?
Great, I'll pull it!
Wait, wait, wait!
So, it was the professor who buried that treasure bat!?
In that case, was it the professor who drew that map?
So that he won't forget the place he buried it?
No, I don't recall drawing this.
That treasure map...
Who on earth drew that?
I wonder who's gonna win?
I wonder?
Yo, Minae!
What've you been doing this whole time?
Shut up!
Once I pull out this bat, I'm gonna
hit away any and all of your pitches!
How is it possible for you to hit my pitches with that?
How would you know if you don't give it a try?
But it is impossible for Minae to gain strength even if she does pull it out.
What he said, Minae!
We shall see about that!
Isn't that the thing?
So this is it?
Don't tell me...
Shall we pull it out?
Yeah, let's.
What's up, you two?
Mouri-san!
What happened?
Can you tell me, if it's all right with you?
Yes.
Actually, last night, an owner of a jewelry shop in Beika City...
Was hit in the head by a dull instrument by someone that had snuck into the store after closing time.
And while he was unconscious, valuable jewels were stolen.
And after we did some asking around...
We were informed that two suspicious people were seen burying a bat in the field at Beika Park late last night.
We suppose those two were the jewelry robbers and
came to dispose of the weapon, so we're here to check.
About those two...
Weren't they the professor and the coach?
Hey!
Conan-kun!
I see, so that's how it is.
In that case, that wasn't the weapon.
Say, about that jewel robbery, couldn't it have
been staged in an attempt to collect insurance?
Conan-kun, I'm surprised you'd know something like that...
Uncle was talking about that the other day...
Oh, it was Mouri-san?
But, I don't think that's it.
The shop owner was hit on the back of his head.
Although hitting yourself on the back of your head isn't impossible, it's still difficult.
But, the owner has a slightly clumsy younger brother...
And it intrigues us that the younger brother's alibi is still shaky.
All right, I'll make it this time!
Certainly there's something fishy behind that bat.
And, I'm afraid that everything happened so far is related to the bat in some way.
The jewel robbery...
The treasure map...
The smell of a tennis ball...
And the switched bats.
Hey, that Minae girl is still at it!
Seriously?
That bat could be a fake, and yet...
The bat?
That reminds me, the bat currently in Uncle's possession...
This is...
So it's indeed as I thought.
Say, Detective Chiba.
I think it'd be best if you investigated this bat at once.
It's about time, Shinichi.
Yeah, the bottom of the ninth inning is when I should use the chemical.
I doubt she'd be up for this, but I'll have
Haibara assist me even if it's just a little.
Haibara-san!
Watch out!
Are you all right, Haibara?
Yeah...
My precious chemical!
Are you all right?
Are you injured?
No, we're fine.
But it's not fine on my end!
Why were you spacing out anyway?
Geez, all because you were in that unaccustomed disguise.
Not like you at all.
Professor, sorry 'bout that.
Any spare ones?
No, only this.
I'm afraid the bat can't be pulled out.
Second!
Right-on!
Safe!
You dumbass!
You should've caught that sort of easy ball!
What'd you say!?
Unbelievable.
Ken-chan.
Don't mind.
Minae...
That girl, coming all the way from the right field...
Hey!
Hurry up already!
Akira...
Over my dead body that I'd let you hit it!
Oh yeah?
Right!
She got it!
Out!
Are you all right, Minae-san?
It's nothing, I'm totally fine.
Now, it's the last inning, last inning.
Let's hit it this time!
I feel like we should let her swing.
Yeah.
Who's up next?
Number 5, Kiyoshi-kun.
If two players can advance, it'll be Minae's turn.
If you keep giving her the cold shoulder, you won't be able to change anything.
Be true to yourself already.
What was that?
No good, it won't budge...
But I have to pull it out!
Ken-chan...
I'm gonna help you, so...
Hurry and pull this thing out.
Don't you go and lose to Akira.
Kenta...
All right, we should go and help.
You guys do your best so Minae can have her turn!
Everyone...
That's not gonna come out, is it?
Right...
They can't pull it out.
Wrong, even if the bat won't come out, its purpose has already been served.
Those kids are trying to accomplish something as a team.
Not for any selfish purposes, but for the sake of Minae alone, they have become one team.
One, two!
And, that shall serve as the strength of the team...
Before you know it, they have built up the confidence of a certain player.
Right, this is indeed...
Play ball.
I'm counting on you!
Leave it to me.
If I can advance base...
Minae will get her turn.
One, two!
...The true strength of a baseball player!
And that strength...
They have now...
Acquired it in their hands!
Dead ball!
Ow-ow-ow...
Good, it's her turn!
Three-to-one, two outs, first and second base!
Isn't this the chance for a turnabout homerun?
I'm getting excited!
Yes, speaking.
Oh, Chiba?
What's that?
The big brother's blood and the younger
brother's fingerprints were found on the bat?
You go, Minae!
You definitely can hit it with a bat like that!
Hit 'em hard and high!
Minae, huh?
Aren't I lucky?
Akira, it's on.
Take this!
Left!
Foul!
Scaring me like that...
That was too close.
That should've been a homerun!
Minae, what's wrong?
It broke...
Why?
Why did it break?
Please don't give up!
You don't have to use that bat to
be able to hit the ball, Minae-san!
Minae, you're now the only hope for us Guts!
Everyone believes in you, Minae!
Use your own strength and get three points from Akira!
But if the legendary bat is in this state, then...
Allow me.
Time out!
The hell's with her?
What now?
Does she think she can hit my ball with a bat like that?
Play!
King of Giants, Matsui-san...
And the gods of baseball!
Please, bless Minae with your strength!
If you think you can hit it, prove it to me!
Damn!
Damn, damn, damn!
Why'd I lose to her!?
She did it!
A turnabout walk-off homerun!
Awesome!
Hey!
What's with you all of a sudden?
Huh, a tennis ball?
Detective Takagi...
Yes?
Can you slice open that tennis ball for me?
Slice open the ball?
How come the jewels are...
Hidden under the legendary bat is the truth of a certain case.
The sequence of events is likely as such:
First of all, the older brother—jewelry shop owner—thought up the staged robbery...
Stuffed his own jewels inside a tennis ball
bought at a 100-yen shop or the like, and...
Dug a hole in the field and hid it.
After that, Team Guts' coach came to this field and met Professor Agasa...
Having forgotten his bat on the bench, they went to the cafe.
Meanwhile, as the owner was letting the younger brother in on the plan...
He gave the younger brother a map as to where the jewels were hidden just in case they forget...
And directed him to supply a weapon from
somewhere so that he could commit the assault.
Then, the slightly clumsy brother wanted to check out the hidden jewels spot before finding an assault weapon...
So he came to this field while looking at his big brother's map.
He then discovered the coach's bat left on the bench...
And thought it was the perfect weapon, taking it home with his bare hands.
Then, he just carried out the attack
per his big brother's instructions.
I see!
Since the younger brother hit the older brother with the bat...
The little brother's fingerprints and the big brother's bloodstains were on it!
The big brother probably directed the little brother to get rid of the bat while he himself contacted the police...
And the clumsy brother, of all places, disposed of it near home base on this field where he'd found it.
He probably also dropped the map where the jewels were hidden on his way home.
So that's why Ayumi and the others found it!
After that, I came to the field feeling tipsy...
Mistook the coach's bat discarded by the younger brother as Matsui's bat and took it home...
And furthermore, the professor, who was waiting for the coach's arrival...
Picked up the bat left near home base.
I see, so that's what transpired.
The professor was looking for a soft spot on the ground near first base in order to dig a hole.
The spot was already softer than elsewhere since the owner already dug a hole and buried the tennis ball.
I see, as expected of Mouri-san!
I shall go and question the owner immediately!
Excuse me!
Who would've thought something like that happened to the bat?
Yeah, I was doubting myself until I saw Uncle's bat.
But is it all right?
About that bat.
I feel sorry for Mouri-kun now...
It served as the initiative to reunite that team.
Isn't it fine?
Sunday Baseball Class
Days Later
Now, you guys, I'm going harsh on ya!
How come you're the coach?
Bring it on!
Let us do our best!
What's this?
Coach!
What on earth is that?
What's wrong?
I found this.
Hey, isn't that...
Could it be...
That, that's...
The legendary glove.
If you put on that glove, you'll be able to pitch at 200km per hour... they say!
Are you seriously saying that?
Shut up!
You never know if you don't give it a try, right?
So you're really being serious...
Is this the beginning of a new legend?
No.
It's the beginning of a new love.
Hey, what do you mean by that?
Hey, Haibara!
Hey, how are you gonna make up for my bat!?