Hello! This video is a special release
provided to all of you by Shonen Sunday.
Please watch this video in a bright room,
and don't sit too close to the screen.
Caviar, foie gras, oysters! I can't resist!
In that case, I'll also have...
Professor.
I'm sure you're aware.
I-I have to watch my calories, right?
How miserable.
Hey, Mitsuhiko,
I don't know if I can eat it all.
Don't worry, Genta-kun,
this food isn't just for you.
Hey, Inspector Shiratori,
these are called hors d'oeuvres, right?
That's right.
Oh yeah, Sato-san.
Since you're not all that
fond of French cuisine,
I've prepared these appetizers for you.
Here you go.
T-Thanks, they look delicious.
What?
Oh, no, nothing.
They really do look delicious, don't they?
Well, Mouri-kun?
How about a glass of champagne?
Oh, Inspector, that's very kind of you.
Hold on, dear.
You're holding the wrong glass.
This one is for champagne.
Don't nitpick every small detail.
I can't drink enough with this one.
Unlike with free liquor, you don't
drink this nonstop. It's perfect.
Bossy woman, mind your own business.
Now, now, Mouri-kun.
The air is so fresh!
It sure is.
Aren't you glad we came, Conan-kun?
Yeah!
Ah, seems we really chose
a perfect time to come visit Tokyo.
Exactly! This is the first time
I've been to Karuizawa.
Me too, me too!
I expected your family to have
a holiday home in Karuizawa, Sonoko.
Unfortunately, we don't
have one in Karuizawa.
We have holiday homes in
Hawaii, Nice, Monaco, and...
Is that so?
On an autumn day,
Inspector Shiratori invited his friends
to a housewarming party
for his new holiday home.
The highlight of the party was
Inspector Shiratori's collection of expensive wines.
Tell me, Inspector Shiratori.
Yes?
Where is the wine you mentioned?
Ah, that's right.
Well then, shall I show everyone?
The stairs are steep, so please be careful.
These are the toilets.
The women's on the right,
and the men's on the left.
And over here we have...
I'm amazed. Is this all the wine cellar?
Wow, he's got even more than we do!
You're right.
Your house has a wine cellar too?
No, that's not it.
Genta-kun's parents run a liquor store.
Please come buy at Kojima Liquors!
I-I see.
W-What's that?
This is a wine rack that I had
specially made from real oak.
This is where I keep
my most precious wines.
For example,
this is a 1979 Château Margaux.
A 1985 Château Lafite.
A 1992 Le Pin.
And this is today's selection.
A 1961 Château Latour.
Hey, I think I just saw
something floating in there.
That's true, has it gone bad?
This is called the sediment.
It's formed when the wine ages.
Only mature wines have it.
If the precipitation process fails, sometimes
even half of the wine is ruined and thrown away.
Tell me, Inspector Shiratori,
is that wine really that good?
Yes, it's completely different
than a cheaper one.
You can tell right away when you taste it.
Wow, is that so?
Hey, the next slot is empty.
There used to be a bottle
of 1989 Sassicaia here.
My sister and her husband
drank it yesterday.
All right, everyone, shall we
return to the living room?
Heiji, look, the floor in
this section is made of marble.
You're right,
it musta been terribly expensive.
Well, everyone has their own hobbies.
I guess you're right.
Well now, everyone,
I'm going to prepare the main dish.
Please relax for about an hour.
What's wrong? What's with the big sigh?
Ah, well, it's just that
Inspector Shiratori has so much money.
You know, this is the wealth of
his family, not Shiratori-kun himself.
W-Well, that's true.
Come on, you're a man,
don't worry about stuff like that.
Oh, right.
Mouri-san!
It's about that case the other day.
Oh, what?
It's because I'm a man
that I have to worry about it.
Hey, I wonder what
the other rooms here are like.
Oh yeah, let's go explore for a bit!
Great idea. It'll be fun!
Genta-kun, let's go!
Ah, hey, wait up.
Hurry, hurry!
Hey, wait for me!
Hey, let's go for a walk
around the neighborhood.
Sure, but I'm not familiar with the area.
Then let me show you around.
What? Ran-chan, you've been here before?
Yes, Shinichi's parents brought me here once.
Ah yeah, I forgot.
Okay, let's all go together.
Okay, Heiji?
Guess I have to.
Ah, I'm okay, I have something else to do.
Eh? You do?
Yeah, just something small.
Haibara, what about you?
I'll pass too, but the four
of you can go ahead.
Sheesh...
What a wonderful place, ain't it?
Yeah, this street is called
the "Whispering Lane".
Oh, the "Whispering Lane", eh?
Hey, Heiji, whisper something.
Okay. Bring your ear closer.
Come on...
You are...
A BIG DORK!
Gotcha, gotcha!
Brat.
This is Kyu-Karuizawa's Christian church.
Oh my, a wedding!
How beautiful!
It's so romantic.
So, Ran-chan?
Were you just imagining
doing that with Kudo-kun?
What are you talking about?
I wasn't imagining anything!
Oh really? Then what was with
that dreamy expression on your face?
And what about you, Kazuha-chan?
What are you talking about?
We don't do that kind of thing!
Oh my, what kind of thing don't you do?
And who is this "we"?
Shh! Not so loud!
Oh, I'm sorry.
This is Kumoba Pond.
Shinichi and I rode our bikes here
from their rental vacaction home.
It's so beautiful!
It's just like Ran-chan said!
I know, right?
It seems so long ago though.
I wonder why,
it's only been two or three years.
Kudo!
What's the matter, Heiji?
Did something get in your eye?
Oh, nah.
Say, let's walk a bit farther in!
There's an island called
the "Water Bird Island" this way.
Hey, Kazuha.
What?
Let's go back.
Eh? Why?
It's okay, let's just go.
Geez.
Hey, Heiji, wait up.
A swan!
Sure is.
Out!
Ah, dang it!
Love - 40!
Hey, Ran.
Can we use our feet?
Of course not, this isn't soccer!
Wait, Shinichi!
Where are we going in such a hurry?
Just follow me and you'll know!
Geez.
It's so quiet here.
Yeah.
Hey!
Where did Hattori-kun
and Kazuha-chan go?
They're not here.
Could it be that they left without us?
Sheesh, Hattori, oh you.
Everyone, sorry for the wait!
Today's main dish is ready.
I'm starving!
It looks delicious!
It sure does! What kind of dish is this?
Roast lamb shoulder.
Ninzaburo-style.
Who's that?
Did you make this too, Shiratori-kun?
Yes, cooking is another hobby of mine.
Not bad!
You'd make a great son-in-law.
Eeek!
No, no.
Well then,
I'm off to get our precious wine.
We're back.
Welcome back, Ran-chan!
So you two did come back without us.
I'm sorry, but Heiji suddenly
said he wanted to come back.
Are you all right, Hattori-kun?
Oh, yeah, I'm fine now.
Sonoko-neechan, what are you looking at?
Nothing.
By the way, Ran,
is it okay to leave him like that?
Dad!
Geez.
Don't sweat it. He's probably
just tired from drivin' here.
I-It's terrible! My Château Latour...
Has been smashed!
What?
This is horrible.
Shiratori-kun,
how much was this wine worth?
To get this kind of wine now would
probably cost several hundred thousand yen.
S-Several hundred thousand yen?
This is a catastrophe!
So, it's either slipped from
someone's hand when they took it out...
Or someone broke it on purpose.
Sheesh, that's completely obvious!
Ah, I guess it is.
But who could have done it?
The problem is, there isn't much chance that it was an outsider.
Common sense dictates that
someone here must've done it.
In any case, let's discuss it in
the living room instead of down here.
I agree.
All right then,
I'll come back and clean it up later.
Hey, did you find it?
No, I haven't found anything.
Hey, what are you guys doing?
Oh, nothing.
W-We're not doing anything.
Come on, we should get going too!
Oh, yeah.
We currently know that sometime
after our visit to the wine cellar,
and before Shiratori-kun's
second trip down there,
is when this case
must have occurred.
"Case"? Sato-san...
Say, did anyone go down to
the cellar during that period of time?
Y-You guys?
We were exploring inside the house.
And we went into the wine cellar too.
But we never touched that bottle!
Oh, really?
Don't be so childish.
Come to think of it, what about you?
Are you sure that in your drunken stupor,
you didn't wander into the cellar after
going to the toilet and broke the bottle?
No way! How could I have...
D-Dad?
Actually, I can't remember anything
other than going to the toilet.
Did everyone hear that?
He's the most likely suspect.
Say what?
Calm down.
Lots of people went to the toilet.
For example, I also went...
Could you have broken my Latour
out of jealousy, Takagi-kun?
T-There's no way I would do that.
Really?
Can we really rule out the possibility
that you broke it yourself?
H-How rude!
Knock it off, you two.
That's right, behave yourself.
What's wrong, Heiji?
Ya know, ya have been quiet
for a while. That's not like ya.
It's nothin'.
I'm just thinkin' about somethin'.
Did you notice anything?
Nothing really.
But there was someone who left here
looking serious and holding a handbag.
Her?
But, where could that thing have gone?
I told you, someone picked it up and ate it!
No way, only you would do that.
Hey, you guys.
Are you hiding something from me again?
It's nothing important.
Genta-kun dropped a grape in the wine cellar,
And it rolled underneath a wine rack.
But when we looked recently, it was gone.
Someone must've picked it up
and thrown it away.
Oh, it was just the wind.
With this... Could it be?
What's this?
This bottle is new!
Odd, ain't it?
I noticed that too.
Hattori.
So this means...
Yeah. After hearin' what that
li'l girlie said, I finally grokked it.
Only she coulda done it.
Am I right?
You've solved the case?
Is that true, Hattori-kun?
Yeah, the one who broke that bottle is...
What's wrong?
Don't keep us hanging, spit it out!
Ah, sorry, Kudo...
Ah, no, Conan-kun, you do it.
What's wrong, Heiji?
It's okay. Go ahead
and tell us, Conan-kun.
Ah, okay.
Actually, the culprit is
a dormouse that snuck into the house.
Dormouse?
Dormouse? You mean those
little guys that look like mice?
Yeah.
What do you mean?
The dormouse that snuck in
was drawn by the sweet aroma of the wine.
So it went downstairs to the door of the wine cellar.
And, at the same time, Mitsuhiko and
the others were checking out the wine cellar.
And it got into the wine cellar.
That's it! The dormouse must've
eaten the grape Genta-kun dropped.
Yeah.
Later, after the three of them left,
it was startled when Uncle came in.
The dormouse climbed up
the special wine rack,
and hid inside the empty wine slot.
Uncle didn't notice this...
And he mistakenly put the wine in the
empty slot that the dormouse had gone in.
Eh? In that case...
Yeah, after Uncle left, the dormouse
pushed the wine bottle out and it smashed.
As for evidence...
Look.
I found it behind the wine rack.
It's already halfway into its winter sleep.
What will you do now, Dad?
You'll have to pay for it.
I don't think that will be necessary.
Because that wine was a forgery.
F-Forgery?
Isn't that right, Heiji-niichan?
Ah, yeah, the real one is...
Here.
It really is my Château Latour!
What's going on?
Sonoko-neechan, you don't
have to pretend anymore.
Oh no, I've been found out.
The thing is, not long ago at a family party,
we finished a bottle of the same wine.
A light bulb went off in my head,
and I switched the label with a cheap Latour and brought it with me.
Consider this a little girlish prank!
Oh brother.
Come on, Sonoko.
Sorry.
Well, in the end,
it worked out in our favor.
That's right, it was because
of you that the wine was saved.
Well, in that case,
shall we all make a toast?
Cheers!
Thus the case got solved,
and the party became happy once again.
Other than Uncle, who was
forbidden to drink by Auntie, and...
Hattori Heiji.
Hey, Hattori.
Why is your sock rolled up?
Is there some reason for that?
Ah, this? This is the latest style in Osaka.
You broke the wine, didn't you?
W-Wh-What are you saying?
Under the rolled up part of your sock,
is a wine stain from when the bottle broke.
That's solid evidence.
So you did know.
When I went to the restroom, I wanted
to look at the expensive wine once more.
But when I went to the rack,
It wasn't in the same place as before
and it was stickin' out a bit.
"That's strange..." I thought,
and as I was pullin' it out...
How dim-witted. It was the worst
blunder in Hattori Heiji's life.
Kudo, I wanted to own up
right away, but...
I know.
Kisaki-sensei also noticed.
And she said, "This is a perfect way to restrict
my husband's drinking, work with me."
She found me out.
It must have been written
all over your face.
At any rate, that naive honesty
is one of your good points.
Kisaki-sensei is just
looking out for Uncle's health.
I won't say anything either.
Sorry, Kudo,
I owe ya yet another favor.
No, I'm just returning your favor.
You silly, because of you, I was able to
re-experience that day long gone by.
But I won't say it even if
you pry my mouth open.
When it was just the two of us... I could never say
How with a little kiss, time just stopped
I need your love tonight
The two of us found that fated
moment we were looking for
I remember that snowy train platform
as your shadow became smaller
I'll always give you these winter bells
The snow piling up on the window
brings us closer, day by day, so hold me now...
I'll give you these winter bells
Hold me now, tonight, beneath the stars