After being invited by Diana-san, a British woman
we happened to make the acquaintance of...
We found ourselves preparing for a trip to Great Britain.
Of course, since I can't fly overseas as Edogawa Conan...
I temporarily returned to Kudo Shinichi's form
by taking medicine developed by Haibara.
But, at the same time I was headed for the UK...
I had no idea something like that would happen.
10:00 AM
Oh, right...
Yoshida-san allowed me to stay at her place.
A huge difference compared to my room.
Ai-chan, you awake?
Papa and mama had urgent errands to run, so they went out.
I see.
Mama's made some sandwiches for us, so let's eat together!
Now, rise and shine!
Wash your face!
I've finally found you.
It's me.
I've tracked down her location.
Yeah, no doubt about it.
I'm counting on you, as we planned.
Yes, understood.
TSUBURAYA
Geez, sis!
Stack them up neatly before throwing them away!
Who do you think is doing it for you every time!?
American Beauty
Grace Aihara
Grace Aihara, 8.
This stunning little lady
is hot in the USA drama showbiz.
Her favorite food is... Guess what?
Peanut butter and blueberry jam sandwich!
Grace Aihara...
This kid looks just like Haibara-san!
Mit-chan!
Phone.
All right.
It's from Conan-kun.
From Conan-kun?
Sounds like he's in a hurry.
Hello?
Mitsuhiko?
Do not let Haibara go near the Professor's house anytime today!
You can go keep her company, but do not
take your sight off Haibara, got it?
Hello?
"Do not let Haibara-san go near the Professor's house"?
Why in the world...
A Secret Order From London!
TSUBURAYA
See, she looks just like Haibara-san, right?
Who the heck is she?
Grace Aihara.
She's a well-known child star in the American drama showbiz.
Her hair color and hairstyle look strikingly similar...
And not to mention her eyes are an exact copy of Haibara-san's!
That so?
"Her favorite food is peanut butter and blueberry jam sandwich!"
Sounds yummy!
The only difference is her age.
That magazine came out a year ago, and since it says she was eight years old...
It means she should be nine now.
Haibara is seven just like us, right?
But it's not uncommon for celebrities to fake their ages.
And—I'm talking about speculation and what-ifs now...
But I think it's possible that she is Haibara-san.
Well, didn't she tell us this a while ago?
That Haibara-san was in the US and her mother was British.
She said something like that?
It's the same for this girl!
She's a half, born from her Japanese dad and British mom.
Half?
If... I mean if...
If this girl is Haibara-san herself...
Why did she have to change her name and come to Japan?
No, hold on a second.
This girl's name is Grace.
Gray in Japanese is haiiro.
And her surname Aihara can be taken as Ai and Hara...
I see!
"Grace Aihara" is likely to be Haibara Ai's stage name altered from her real name!
But...
Why would Conan call and tell you not to
let Haibara go near the Professor's house?
That's...
It says something right here.
"Grace Aihara announced her shocking retirement half a year ago...
"And her whereabouts after returning to the UK are unknown."
UK?
Conan and the Professor are going to the UK too, aren't they?
So did he give you a call from the UK?
I don't think it's possible.
Conan-kun and the others should arrive in London in...
About seven hours still, so it was from their plane.
Can you even make a phone call from a plane?
You can't with a cell phone, but I
think they have in-flight phones.
The fact that he went as far as to call me in that situation...
There must be an urgent reason not to let Haibara-san near the Professor's.
Perhaps Conan-kun and the others' reason for visiting the UK was related to this!
We can't just sit here.
Genta-kun, let's go!
Go where, the UK?
Now that's impossible, isn't it?
I mean Ayumi-chan's house!
It could be that danger is lurking around Haibara-san right now!
Ai-chan, delicious?
Yeah.
Yoshida-san's mother is pretty good at cooking, I see.
Ayumi loves ham sandwiches and egg sandwiches...
So mama always makes these for me.
Ai-chan, what kind of sandwich do you like?
I guess...
Peanut butter and blueberry jam.
Peanut butter and blueberry jam?
Yeah.
Spread each on one side of separate pieces of bread and stick them together...
And you get a peanut butter and jelly sandwich.
It's a staple in American lunches.
Even now, I can't help myself but to yearn for that sandwich from time to time.
But, one time I was eating some at the Professor's...
He was looking at me with puppy eyes.
That's why I gave up eating that.
I understand!
If the Professor were to eat any of that, he'd become more overweight, right?
That's right, Ai-chan!
Let's go and get some!
But, what they have in the nearby supermarket is completely different from what I had in America.
It's no good if they're not from an import food shop.
I know just the place that's on the opposite side of Beika Station!
Well, let's go and buy some!
Ayumi wants to try it out too!
You're right.
I'm in the mood for some as well, after such a long time.
Then, we should get going right now!
But, before we do that...
Well, aren't you getting ahead of yourself?
What's this "danger" about, anyway?
I don't know.
But, judging from the nervous tone in Conan-kun's call...
Something bad is bound to happen.
Hey, should we make a detour in front of the Professor's?
No, let's go straight this way.
It will be closer to Ayumi-chan's condo from here.
Genta-kun, I'm leaving you behind!
Ayumi wants to try this just once!
Ai-chan, do this with me!
But, why do we have to apply make-up?
The supermarket in front of the train station is a fancy store celebrities always go to.
That's why we have to make ourselves look like celebs as well!
But still...
Why not?
Let's try it out!
You're right.
It's been too long for me anyway.
Huh?
Ai-chan, you've already tried putting make-up before?
No, I didn't mean it that way...
Whew, I was so shocked!
Sometimes you mumble weird things, Ai-chan.
Same for Conan-kun, though.
Mama won't return home until this evening.
Let's give ourselves a grand transformation!
Done!
How's it, Ai-chan?
Maybe I put on too much eyeshadow...?
Right...
I think a more natural look suits you...
"Natural"?
Don't worry, I'll do it for you.
It doesn't look like Ayumi at all!
Ai-chan, you're really good at make-up!
It's because you have large eyes and a cute face to begin with, Yoshida-san.
Thank you!
Ai-chan looks very pretty as well!
That so?
She came out.
So she thinks she'd fool me with that make-up?
Nah, I'd say this is even better.
It's me.
Target's on the move.
I'm counting on you.
Did you see that, Mitsuhiko?
Yeah.
Haibara-san and Ayumi-chan both look even more beautiful and cuter than usual!
Their mouths were all red.
Did they have ketchup on them?
That's lipstick!
They put on make-up, both of them.
Make-up?
Yes.
It's likely that Ayumi-chan's make-up was done by Haibara-san.
A child star should be good at putting on make-up.
As I thought, Haibara-san is...
What do we do now, they're leaving!
Let's chase them.
Although I don't know the reason...
It'd be best if we followed Haibara-san as Conan-kun suggested.
That sounds like fun!
Hey, Ai-chan...
Yeah.
Although I don't know what those two are up to now...
Don't tell me, that man...
Ai-chan, what's wrong?
No, nothing.
Let's go.
It can't be...
She's headed towards Beika Station.
Yeah, don't screw up.
This store looks pretty awesome!
This is a fancy supermarket where they carry imported goods from foreign countries.
Usually, Haibara-san would never come and shop here.
This is too odd.
Let's see...
Peanut butter here...
And, blueberry jam here.
When I was young, around Ayumi-chan's
age, these were my favorites.
Isn't she the same age right now?
If I recall correctly, that report...
As I thought.
Her favorite food is peanut butter and blueberry jam sandwich.
And what Haibara-san said just now...
When I was young, around Ayumi-chan's
age, these were my favorites.
That must be the truth coming from a slip of the tongue.
So if Haibara-san isn't seven years old...
But in fact older, like nine or ten...
Then it's a match to this girl idol's age of eight years old a year ago.
Right, this girl is indeed Haibara-san!
That's why Haibara-san always looks more mature than us.
In American supermarkets, they have dozens of kinds of items on display, even for peanut butter jars.
Some stores even have machines that can squeeze out peanut butter as you would for soft serve ice cream.
Sounds interesting!
A woman in black...
Don't tell me...
The man from before...
They've cornered me?
I don't feel the organization vibe.
Pretty!
But...
Why did Haibara-san...
Our next story:
Supermodel In Fact
An Undercover Spy
A supermodel playing an active part in the showbiz around the world...
Was discovered to be an undercover international spy.
She was a frequent icon in fashion shows from well-known brands...
My proposition is that Haibara-san's true identity may be that of a spy!
And enjoyed resplendent celeb stardom in many countries.
This incident has caused a massive
ripple across the fashion gamut...
A spy?
Isn't she an idol?
Haibara-san, as known as Grace Aihara, the flourishing girl TV personality in America...
Was trying to sniff out the dark connection
between the American showbiz and the Mafia.
What is a Mafia?
But with her identity exposed by the Mafia, Haibara-san fled to the UK.
In other words, Haibara-san was working for...
The UK's Secret Intelligence Service—MI6!
MI...?
And Haibara-san came to Japan in order to escape from the Mafia's pursuit.
She hid herself in the house of the Professor as his relative...
And transfered to Teitan Elementary School.
She's actually nine or ten years old, but deliberately lied about being seven.
On the other hand, the American Mafia followed Haibara-san's footsteps and arrived in Japan.
The reason Conan-kun and the
Professor flew to the UK in a hurry...
Must be because they've noticed this and decided to ask for help from the UK's Secret Intelligence Service.
However, the Mafia found out about the Professor's house.
They learned this fact on the plane, and contacted me in great haste...
Telling me not to let Haibara-san go back near the Professor's house.
A perfect deduction!
Say, what's a Mafia anyway?
Genta-kun, a Mafia is in fact...
They just came out.
And a Mafia is...?
An American gang.
A gang?
Do they wear black suits and sunglasses by any chance?
Correct, that's absolutely right.
In that case, there's one behind you.
When did that man...!?
I dunno, but he was in that supermarket.
Yeah, that's right.
Let's get those two at once.
He's going to get those two at once?
So he's aiming for not only Haibara-san, but also Ayumi-chan!?
You should cut them off from the front.
We'll corner them.
Corner them?
He has an accomplice?
Haibara-san and Ayumi-chan are in danger!
Yeah, I'm about to finish this up.
After you.
I can't...
They're not opponents I can deal with!
But...
Hey, little princesses.
Over here!
Can't you give us a bit of your time?
These two are so cute!
My radar's never wrong, see?
Gun?
No way, in the middle of the street!?
Both of you, run away at once!
What the hell are you doing, brat!?
Hurry up!
What the hell are you doing to Mitsuhiko!?
You guys...
What's going on!?
A talent production!?
Yeah.
We merely wanted to scout her.
Scout?
TMS Agency
Kurokawa Youji
Manager
Tokyo Prefecture
Beika City 1st District
Block 16
No. 20
TMS Agency
Seino Chiharu
Manager
Tokyo Prefecture
Beika City 1st District
Block 16
No. 20
So you guys aren't with the Mafia?
Mafia?
I see, you mistook those two as part of the Mafia?
That's just a huge misunderstanding!
I'm sorry...
It's just you guys were following them...
And you said something like you're getting those two at once.
Geez.
We were informed that there's a elementary schoolgirl nearby who looks just like the American child star Grace Aihara.
We've been tracking her down since.
Grace Aihara!
What?
Nothing...
After a month's work, we finally found you.
And, just as we thought we'd arrange for a chat today...
We saw you and your friend coming out, all dressed up and with make-up on too!
That's when we decided to get you both for our scouting.
So was that what you meant by "getting those two at once"?
What else did you think we meant by that?
And, if I'm dealing with a little girl like her...
I figured it'd be best if I had a young
woman along rather than just myself.
That's why I called her in for backup.
That sums up what happened.
Now that we've cleared our misunderstanding, can you listen to what we have to say?
I think if you guys were to team up and become a princess unit, you'd sell big!
Princess unit?
I refuse your offer.
I don't care what went wrong.
But I have no intention whatsoever of cooperating
with a man who would hit a child's head with a wallet.
Same for her.
What a waste of time.
Bunch of stinky brats!
Let's go!
Wait for me!
Hey, well said!
Just like you said, it'd do you no good to go to a company that's willing to employ such ill-mannered staff.
Good thing you refused.
And, you guys who stood up to them in order to protect your friends...
Were splendid as well!
Nah...
But, you're too young for make-up, little princesses.
Yeah...
It seems those two weren't related to the organization after all.
Then, the pressure I felt at the beginning...
Was it just my imagination?
I see.
So that's why you followed us.
You're right!
She looks just like Ai-chan!
I know, right?
That's why I thought she was indeed Haibara-san.
But your theory concluding Ai-chan is a spy, was being chased by the Mafia, and hid herself in the Professor's house...
That was really clever of you, Mitsuhiko-kun!
Well, some of it wasn't exactly wrong.
Nah, don't worry about it.
But if that's the case...
Why did Conan-kun tell me not to let
Haibara-san go near the Professor's house?
Come to think of it, when we were
near the Professor's house earlier...
I saw someone going through the gate.
It was that Okiya guy living next door.
While the Professor and I are absent...
What on earth is that person up to?
Ai-chan!
What's wrong, Ai-chan?
Running away all of a sudden!
Huh, what's in that cardboard box?
What are you planning to abscond with...
From a house that's currently vacant?
Oh, no.
It's a package delivery.
Package delivery?
The Professor asked me to get the package that's scheduled to arrive today for him.
I'm counting on you then, Subaru-kun.
Yes, understood.
That's why I've been checking the
Professor's house from time to time.
And that's when Genta-kun saw you!
But again, how come Conan-kun...
Told me not to let Haibara-san go near this house?
If a package delivery is scheduled,
why not just ask Haibara-san to get it?
Let me see the receipt.
Delivery Receipt
Deliver to
Address Tokyo Prefecture, Beika City, 2nd District, Block 22
Name Agasa Hiroshi
Note
Return to sender if recipient is absent. Do not redirect. Fragile.
Customer Service: 0120-867-5309 Mon-Fri 9:00 AM-7:00 PM
Don't tell me...
Is it all right to open it?
As I thought.
Peanut butter?
Blueberry jam?
Items
Peanut Butter (3)
Blueberry Jam (3)
Thank you for your continued patronage.
Points earned from this order: 50P
Total: 650P
You may redeem 650P on your next purchase.
"Your continued patronage"?
"Continued"?
Could it be that the Professor...
Keeps buying these when Ai-chan's not looking?
Pro...fess...or...
The Professor went to the UK without
remembering a package was coming for him.
Then, was that the reason they called Mitsuhiko?
But, the way Conan-kun panicked didn't feel like it was anything ordinary.
You need to use a credit card when using in-flight payphones...
And the charge is pretty expensive.
That's why he was in a hurry.
I see...
Here's an idea.
Why don't we enjoy this together?
Is that OK?
After all, the Professor's being so kind as to order these just for me!
No, didn't the Professor...
Want to splurge on these...?
Ai-chan, you're kind of scary...
Peanut butter and blueberry jam...
They go with sandwiches very well.
That's right, earlier I bought some bread at the bakery in front of the station that's famous for its tastiness.
Shall we make sandwiches with them?
Don't tell me, the pressure I felt at that time...
Was coming from this person at the bakery?
I want some sandwiches now!
I'd love some too!
Me too!
All right, follow me.
I have great hot chocolate too.
Ai-chan, let's go!
Sandwiches!
Yes.
Awesome!
Working on my appetite!
Oh, Professor Agasa.
I can't wait!
Yes, I received the package, but...
I'll take over.
Professor...
Thank you so much for the peanut butter and blueberry jam!
Ai-kun!?
You must've wanted me to enjoy some peanut butter and jelly sandwiches—my favorite.
That must be why you ordered them behind my back.
But you didn't realize they'd be delivered today until after you already got on the plane...
So you placed an in-flight call in a hurry, right?
That's right...
I only wanted to surprise you and make you happy, Ai-kun...
It's not like I'd secretly order those to enjoy all by myself without you knowing...
No, no, this is definitely not an excuse...
You're so busted.
Thank you, Professor.
Since I feel like it, I'll invite everyone to dig in!
Thank you for your treat, Professor!
I'm gonna eat a bellyful!
I'll bring some home for mama and papa!
That's right, can I talk to Edogawa-kun?
She wants to talk to Edogawa-kun.
Hello?
Edogawa-kun, I'd also like to thank you for calling Tsuburaya-kun about this.
You've got quite a personality, you know.
And you have a nice trip too, buddy!
Geez!
If Haibara-san and I can get married...
I'll be able to enjoy a sweet life where Haibara-san makes me sandwiches like this everyday!
Here, enjoy.
Let's dig in!
This is so tasty!
Delicious!
Too sweet...
I don't get to play my role at all...
Is that even fair?
That's even fairer.
Yeah, right.