This video is a special release provided to all of you by Shogakukan.
When watching this video, please brighten the room and watch at a distance from the TV.
Last week, you all explored Beika City and found many different stores, right?
What kind of stores were there?
A grocery store!
A flower shop!
A bakery!
A supermarket!
A liquor store!
Right, Genta-kun's family owns a liquor store, right?
It's called Kojima Liquor Store.
Now you need to pick one store as your example.
Find out what the store is selling, the plans of the owners, and so on.
Of course, it doesn't have to be a store, for example, a post office or a library.
Ask what kind of work they do, what is difficult about their work...
Find out as much as you can and then make a presentation about it in the class.
Well then, you can start discussing which store you're going to pick.
Okay!
So, which one will we choose?
Well...
I know, let's go to a store that sells rice with eel!
If we do, they can treat us with delicious food!
You guys are awesome!
All right, this one is on Uncle!
Eh? Where's mine?
Uh, Genta-kun...
Thanks for the food!
Something like that.
That's impossible, Genta-kun.
That is so Genta-kun.
But I think it's possible.
Ai-chan, where do you think we should go?
That's right! What do you think, Haibara-san?
Well, I would be interested to go to that beauty salon in front of the station.
B-Beauty...
Beauty saloon? In front of the station?
In front of the station?
What is it, Mitsuhiko-kun?
That's it! That's a great place!
It is unique and will be very helpful for the development of Detective Boys!
Unique and helpful for the development of Detective Boys?
Hey, could it be...
THE TARGET IS KOGORO!!
THE DETECTIVE BOYS' SECRET REPORT
So that's how it is!
Please help us out!
Since this is related to the school, I guess I have no choice.
Jeez, dad...
Everyone, don't hesitate to ask any questions.
Okay!
Then, let's get straight to it.
What kind of work you do?
In general, being a professional means receiving different task from clients.
From investigations to direct assistance.
But for me, wherever I go, cases just seem to happen.
And I have to unravel the tricks of the criminals instead of the police.
Except the one who does that is me.
Here you go, Conan-kun.
Thanks.
What do you do best or what do you like the most?
Best at... Like the most...
Of course, investigations with young girls.
And tons of free drinks while investigating at club is lots of fun!
Oh, what I mean is, there is no place for preference in detective work.
Speaking of young girls, my dad recently dated one.
And then my mother severely scolded him,
It's because of some smell of perfume from his clothes.
Tell your dad to go to a restaurant with tempura after the date.
After sitting at the counter for an hour, he will carry smell of oil instead of perfume.
No wonder you're always go there so often.
Oh, no, I really love tempura.
Uncle, you brought that on yourself.
Uncle, since you are married, why don't you live with your wife?
I'm sure your wife just kicked you out because he played around with young girls!
That's what I figured too.
It could be irreconcilable differences.
Or it could be because of financial problems.
By the way, what is your annual income?
Are these kids really elementary school students?
Dad, just answer their questions.
Don't joke with me.
If I keep hanging around with these little monsters...
Oh no, is it so late already?
Well you guys, I'm sorry, but I have work to do.
What was that? Did he just ran away?
Then we should get going too.
Are you going home?
No, we're going to go shadowing Detective Mouri to observe his actual working environment.
That sounds fun!
Let's go, let's go!
Thanks for the treat!
You're welcome.
Hey, you guys!
Haibara-san, we'll go ahead!
Well, what are you going to do?
Conan-kun.
Make sure he doesn't go to any tempura restaurants.
Oh, here comes the great detective.
Which way did they go?
That way.
Just like the ninja from the manga.
He will notice them right away.
And send them away or shake them off.
Doesn't look like it.
Yeah. Notice them already. Are you a detective or what?
Thank you very much!
On the first track from the Touto loop line, a train will arrives at Sibahama station.
Oh, no!
Wait.
He will notice you if you get off now.
But he just left before the doors closed. That means he's already noticed us!
No, I don't think so.
He jumped off because he thought there was 500 yen on the floor.
But it looks like it's just a game token or something.
He'd get off because of that?
What should we do now, Conan-kun?
We can't follow him anymore.
No, in 8-9 out of 10 he will take the next train, so we just have to wait for him at the next station.
However, he will most likely now on the train a bit further back.
See?
Amazing!
He really is one train further back...
The trash can was a little further.
And he was embarrassed, so he wouldn't get on the same train.
It's the same happens when you miss the train.
Conan-kun is so smart!
Just like a real detective!
I am a detective.
Masaya Murakami (26)
2-3-2-4-2-7.
Looks like he's staking out that guy.
If I remember correctly, his name is Murakami Masaya.
10 days ago, a wealthy family asked him to find out about the life of their only daughter's boyfriend.
Like that! Come on, come on!
His acting skill is so good!
Is it so that no one knows he's a detective, right?
I recently read about this.
The basic rule for a professional stakeout is to blend in with the environment.
Surely his stupid behavior is planned to be part of this Saturday park.
He's truly a great detective!
That was his true face,
the face of a mad horse-racing fan.
I think he's a nice guy.
Even though he's not my type.
He's being cautious for some reason, and that bothers me.
Oh, no!
What are you guys doing here?!
Uncle!
Wait!
Damn it! Right in front of my eyes!
But we've called the police right away.
And we remember the car's license plate number!
Shouldn't the criminals have been caught already?
If so...
Why was he kidnapped?
The criminals must have a purpose.
Maybe this was done by people from the finance company.
Finance company?
That Murakami is an ordinary employee at a credit company.
So there is nothing unusual.
He gave out the loan to help his friend.
No, that's not right, the subject of an investigation should be kept secret.
He is responsible for the debt, right? And his friend disappeared.
And now the finance company wants him to pay it back, right?
How did you know?
I just guessed from what you said.
So that's why he was being so cautious.
When I was on stakeout, I noticed them.
Even though it was only a split second, it was definitely those two.
Do you know the name of this financial company?
No, I was going to figure that out soon.
And you guys should go home.
But, Uncle, what do they want to achieve by kidnapping Murakami-san?
Even if they grab Murakami-san, they won't get their money, right?
Well, you right.
Then why?
What is the criminals' objective?
Could it be?
One hour later
Etsuko Yano (24)
It was just as I thought.
She use six different ATM's at two banks.
She's definitely withdrawing a lot of money.
One ATM can only withdraw not more than 2 million yen,
And it is possible to cash out at most 5 million yen per day.
So, most likely she's withdrawn about 10 million yen.
Yes, it looks like that.
Who's that lady?
The girlfriend of the kidnapped Murakami-san, Yano Etsuko-san.
Why would Etsuko-san do something like that?
I see! I understand!
The scoundrels from the finance company are most likely using Murakami-san,
To force his girlfriend to pay off the loan.
She's the daughter from a wealthy family.
She definitely be able to prepare that amount of cash.
Hasn't she go to the police?
As far as I can tell, she hasn't even consulted with her father yet.
It's unfortunate, she's already worn out, waiting for a call from the criminals.
Looks like they just called.
It's time to start tracking.
She seems to be looking behind her a lot.
Most likely, the criminals told her to beware of cars that might follow her.
Perhaps the criminals noticed that Uncle was stakeout Murakami-san.
That's why I told you to get in the car.
Who would believe that the detective will be accompanied by five little brats with him?
I see! It's called camouflage, right?
Was this rent car is part of a camouflage too?
No, he just doesn't have his own car.
After all, cars are very expensive.
The cost of maintaining car is also very expensive!
That's the reality of being a detective.
But, having her bring the money directly is very unusual.
Are the criminals planning something else?
She turned around again!
It looks like she's saying something to the driver.
We've been following the taxi for half an hour.
The driver might be getting suspicious.
They're slowing down.
Maybe they want to check whether our car will pass them or not.
What happens if we pass them?
We will no longer raise suspicions, and we will also not be able to track them.
You right.
What should we do next?
If they find out about us, we will not be able to track them.
Really?
The key of shadowing someone is to be unnoticed.
Even for a professional detective.
If you are exposed, then your cover will be useless.
Professor!
Finally he caught up with us!
Did you call him, Conan-kun?
When Uncle was in the bank a while ago,
I went out and called him.
I asked the professor to use the spare criminal-tacking glasses to find me.
Finally, I can focus on the road!
So we can use the professor's car...
They're stopping! Is this her destination?
Don't open the door!
Looks like they are only checking if this car is actually following them,
So they stopped temporarily.
But if we don't have a reason to stop, it will be even more suspicious.
Genta, get out of the car quickly and do something!
Anything! Hurry!
Oh! I have to go, what should I do? Oh, I'll go there!
Ayumi-chan, Mitsuhiko, let's get into the professor's car!
Haibara, stay here and keep in touch.
Roger.
Hey! Wait! Wait for me!
This time, Ayumi-chan sit at front!
I said wait!
It looks like we won this round.
This is Conan. We caught up with the target.
Roger.
Let's go.
Oh, okay.
Take the fourth Kojima intersection.
Drive past the Koichi entrance to the Okahata Highway and continue forward.
Roger.
It's just like in the movies!
This is the shadowing method used by professional detectives!
I really need to go to the toilet right now.
It looks like she's getting a little antsy.
We should be getting closer to her destination.
Haibara!
We saw it.
Professor, let's turn around here.
Okay.
Contact the police for me.
Where is Uncle?
All right, let's go too!
You can't.
You can't go there.
Why not?
Isn't this a good time to show the skills of Detective Boys?
Courage and recklessness are not the same thing.
If you guys really want to help,
Do something harmless and within your capabilities.
Something harmless...
Within our capabilities...
Masaya-san!
I brought the money as you requested.
Please let go of Masaya-san!
Sorry, but it's not gonna happen.
Now we're going to use you as a hostage to get money from your father.
How could you? This isn't what we promise!
Agreements are made to be broken, little lady.
I knew you would do something like that.
Who is there?
Sleeping Kogoro!
Agreements are made to be fulfilled.
Let me teach you guys that.
What?
Take this!
Victory!
Hooray!
We did it!
Amazing!
After all, we're the Detective Boys!
These guys...
So that was Izawa-san, Yamamoto-san and Kaneko-san with their report on the music store.
The next is...
Here!
It's us!
Let's see, Yoshida-san, Kojima-kun, Tsuburai-kun, Edogawa-kun and Haibara-san.
Let's hear to your report, "Being a Detective is Fun!"
Thank you! Thank you!
When Detective Mouri is stakeout on someone, he becomes part of the environment.
So it's impossible for his opponent to notice it.
This is how a real professionals work!
Later, we accompanying Detective Mouri,
For the first time we experienced the shadowing method used by professionals.
What? Take this!
Our report on the activities of Uncle and Detective Boys...
Was a big success with the teacher and classmates.
However...
Our Keron-chan hasn't been home since yesterday!
I lost my Kamen Yaiba's card somewhere!
Can you find out where my friends from kindergarten are now?
Wait! Wait a minute!
How come we don't even get any case?
It looks like we really miscalculated...
Why do they only need Uncle?
Please babysit my little brother!
Isn't this great, dad? Business is booming!
A-Are you kidding me!?
Well, maybe this is better suited to Uncle's talents.