This special video has been provided to all of you by Shounen Sunday.
When you watch TV, please brighten the room and don't sit too close to the screen.
Shounen Sunday
I'm tired...
Hey, Mitsuhiko, what is this?
Come on, did you forget?
I promised to lend you my manga the other day, didn't I?
B-But, this much?
By the way, there are only 24 volumes!
Only twenty four?
Well, you can return it to me any time.
Hey, wait!
Oh yeah, when you want to give them back, return it one by one.
Carrying all of it is pretty heavy.
Okay, I got it.
You could have brought one by one too, you know.
Why are you smiling?
Nothing...
Great detectives also like to read manga, right?
Reading can help you relax sometimes, don't you think?
Well, it certainly can be...
But don't get too carried away.
Give me a break...
Ta-da!
I finally bought it!
Dream Station Bug, "Kamen Yaiba III: The Three Magician"!
This time, the game takes place in the magical world.
Does the old witch appear again?
Let's go play it at Conan's house!
What? My house again?
Why not?
Your house is the secret base of the Detective Boys.
A secret base?
Hey, kids!
Would you like to know about your future?
C-Could it be...
It's the old witch!
How rude!
I'm still seventeen years old.
What's with that outfit?
Koizumi Akako
Wow, awesome!
This ball is floating in the air!
Amazing!
It looks like a real magic ball.
Exactly!
My family has passed this magic ball from generation to generation.
It will answers any question I ask.
So, magical ball!
Do you have anything you want to tell the boy with glasses?
Eh, me?
At the place where you will meet a tiger, a vulture and a giant frog.
Be ready to find a way out of the situation.
Tiger?
Vulture?
A giant frog?
Well, if that's the case, you should be careful.
Sh-She disappeared.
She really is the old...
...witch.
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
Are you worried about the prediction?
No, not at all.
Other than the fortune telling, there is something else that's strange.
Mouri Detective Agency
Here you go.
Thank you.
I'm back!
Good afternoon!
Ran-neechan, we have clients?
Yes.
I'm sorry, you guys, but...
Okay, we understand.
So, you want me to protect the treasure sword mentioned...
In this announced from Kaitou Kid?
Yes.
Mine Shizuka
Mine Sayaka
You are the famous detective Mouri Kogoro-san.
So, I'm sure you can defeat Kid.
Right, Mom?
Of course.
"Tonight at 8:00...
I will enter your noble home to retrieve your treasure sword.
Kaitou Kid."
I see.
Man, can't let down my guard for even a second.
In any case, I, Mouri Kogoro, will take on this case.
And not only protecting your treasure sword...
I'll catch Kaitou Kid at the same time!
All right!
We are in your debt.
Eh? Come to think of it, those two...
Where have I seen them?
Mine family house
Get out! Get out!
We don't need your help!
But we talking about Kaitou Kid!
Kiddo-schmiddo, your help would be completely useless.
But...
Shut up!
Retired Person
We will protect the sword ourselves.
Fine, don't come crying to me later!
Grandma!
What are you doing?
Oh, Sayaka.
I was dealing with these men.
These men? Aren't these policemen!
By the way, Sayaka, who are these people behind you?
This is Detective Mouri Kogoro-san and his daughter Ran-san.
And also the Detective Boys.
They might can help protect the sword from Kid.
Good for nothing!
All of you, go home!
Grandma, wait!
Is everything all right, Inspector Nakamori?
Thank you, just a little embarrassed.
I'm very sorry.
No, it's okay.
This grandma is harder to deal with than Kid, right?
Indeed...
It can't be helped.
Secure the perimeter of the house!
Shall we go inside, Mouri-san.
Are you sure?
It's okay, come in.
Kurogane Yaiba
Tell me, who is this Kanchou Kid?
He's just a lowly thief.
Bad guy?
Something like that.
That jerk!
Yaiba-kun will give him what he deserves!
Fine, do what you can.
Oh, how cute!
What's your name?
I am Yaiba.
Wh-What's so funny?
It's because you don't look like Kamen Yaiba at all.
You're completely wrong.
I am not Kamen Yaiba, I am Kurogane Yaiba!
What is Kamen Yaiba?
I wonder where the kids went.
They're probably playing around outside.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Not at all.
Pleased to meet you.
Mine Raizou
I am Mine Raizou, the head of this house.
My name is Mouri Kogoro.
This is my daughter Ran and our house guest, Conan.
I hear that my wife and my daughter invited you here on their own.
Yes.
My family and I are all students of kendo.
In other words, when Kid shows up, he will understand that the advantage will be on our side.
Therefore, please rest here.
After Kid is arrested, we can have a little something to drink.
Sounds good!
Wait, Dad...
This is a very big yard.
You can even play hide and seek here.
Look...
What is that?
A kitty?
I knew it!
Kitty!
Come out!
T-tiger!
What's going on, gero?
F-Frog!
And the vulture!
Save us!
What was that?
Everyone attack!
Why were you shouting?
Where is Kid?
Where is Kid? Kid!
Tiger...
Vulture...
Giant frog...
It's not Kid...
Hey!
What are you doing? Kagetora, Shonosuke, Gerozaimon!
You're scaring the guests!
Kagetora?
Shonosuke?
Gerozaimon?
These are his friends.
Man, they're just pets.
Gave us a fright for nothing.
This place is from a prediction.
But what's going to happen?
And what is this strange feeling?
Honestly, those little kids with their false alarms.
Yo!
"Y-Yo"?
Who are you?
Kurogane Kenjuurou
Me? I am Kurogane Kenjuurou.
Want to drink with me?
Grandma.
Where do you keep the treasure sword?
Sorry, I don't know anything.
But Uncle can't protect it if he doesn't know where it is.
Is that...?
Paikal?
When I drank it before, I returned to my original form.
As I said, we don't need a detective's help.
Grandma, do you often drink that liqueur?
I use this liqueur for various herbal treatments.
Can I have it a little bit?
I think I have a cold.
Okay, why not.
But only a sip.
Oh, not that one.
This is a secret medicine that has been passed down in our family from generation to generation.
It can cure any disease.
Is that so?
It may not taste very good, but it will help with the disease.
Here you go.
Drink it all in one gulp.
My body is burning...
Maybe something is about to happen...
What's wrong?
Looks like it wasn't enough.
One more!
Conan-kun, what are you doing?
What do you mean, "one more"?
Conan-kun...
It's not what you think...
I only lost sight of you for a moment, and look what you've done!
Children should not drink liqueur!
I tell you, it's not what you think!
Don't be like my dad!
Ko-go-rou; go = five
I'm Kogorou!
Ken-juu-rou; juu = ten
And I'm Kenjuurou!
Juugo-rou; juugo = fifteen
And together we are Juugorou!
Kid should appear in 5 minutes.
Everyone take your positions.
Great, great!
That mansion is very big.
Well, this is going to be even more worth doing.
For me, Kaitou Kid-sama.
So, where could that sword be?
It's hurts, gero!
What is it? What happened?
Don't scream for no reason!
Go back to sleep!
Sorry, gero.
Hey, is this a monster's house?
In any case, I should get my work done quickly and leave this place...
What?
You're Kaitou Kid, right?
Don't be so upset.
You'll ruin your pretty face, young lady.
If it doesn't bother you, I would like to know where the sword is.
It's in the kendo dojo.
Thank you, young lady.
Kid-sama...
They have a dojo here?
Stop right there!
I won't let you pass.
Throw your bamboo sword away.
Beautiful flower is more suitable for beautiful lady.
Oh, my!
Well then, madam, excuse me...
Kid-sama...
Damn, who's next?
Stop, Kaitou Kid!
I'll take care of you, thief!
Damn, another one?
Damn you, Kid! How dare you fool my wife and daughter!
Wait, Kid!
Crap!
You are the most charming person I have met this evening.
Idiot, your charm won't work on my mother!
Kid-sama...
Damn it!
I don't have a chance with this body.
That's right, that medicine.
It's possible with this medicine.
It starting, it starting!
Hold yourself, Dad.
I'm going to be sick...
Hi Ran, long time no see.
How are you?
Dad?
Dad...
Split into two?
A mustache? Oh, no!
It's Kid! He disguised himself as me!
What?
Where is he? Where is he?
Where is Kid?
Crap!
Hey! Kid is over here!
Wait!
Mine Dojo
Finally, I'm almost there.
So...
Where did they hide it?
There it is!
Hey, little boy.
Could you give me that treasure sword?
I've been waiting for you, Kanchou Kid!
Ka-Kanchou?
It's Kaitou, you pinhead!
I'm Yaiba!
You're very skilled, Kanchou Kid.
It's Kaitou.
Thank you for the sword, pinhead-kun.
Damn it! I have to do something quickly.
Maybe if I drink a little more...
Where the hell did he run to?
Is there a problem, Inspector Nakamori?
Aren't you...
Hattori-kun!
Yes, I'm Hattori... Hattori!?
Stop, Kid!
How dare you!
See ya!
Thank you for the sword!
Jirokichi, the Japanese Robin Hood who was a theif in 1800's Japan
(nicknamed Nezumi Kozo, "Rat Boy") who stole from the rich and gave to the poor.
I must say, you are great. You remind me of that rat boy thief, Jirokichi.
Sorry, grandpa.
I'm not some chivalrous thief.
So long, pinhead!
Get him, Yaiba!
What the hell is going on?
Why is this happening?
Damn it!
What is this strange feeling bothering me since this morning?
Could it be?
By the way, those guys...
And that guy...
That's it.
I got it!
That's Kurogane Yaiba!
I'll show him something.
Are you ready?
Ready!
Fire!
The sword!
Oh, what a wonderful fireworks.
Oh, could it be, that sword...
Yes, this is the treasure sword that Kid tried to steal.
I return it to you.
Thank you.
What about Kid?
Well, you could say that Yaiba-kun took care of him.
I see, Yaiba did?
Oh, yeah.
You not introduced yourself yet.
I am Kudou Shinichi.
A detective.
That famous high school detective?
By the way, I've been bothered by a strange feeling since this morning.
And I finally understand it now.
First, the Detective Boys.
Ayumi-chan isn't wearing her usual head scarf, instead she's wearing a ribbon.
The 10-yen bald spot on Genta-kun's hair should be on the right side,
But today it's on the left.
And Mitsuhiko-kun doesn't have freckles.
Next, Detective Mouri.
The two locks of hair he always has dangling in front have become three.
And finally, Ran.
Her bangs are parted differently than usual.
Why could this be?
It's because...
Conan-kun?
Hey, Conan-kun, wake up!
Come on get up, they will come for you soon.
See what happens when you read manga late into the night? You can't get up on time.
Yeah...
Hurry and get ready, I need to clear the breakfast table.
I thought so.
It was just a dream.
Just a dream...