This is a request from the Detective Boys!
This special DVD is presented by Shogakukan for everyone.
When watching a DVD, please keep the room bright...
And be sure to watch the monitor or TV...
From a distance!!
On the Sea 1000km North-Northest of Tokyo
Koyakejima
Artemis's Teardrop?
Indeed looks like something Kid would aim for.
Only five minutes until Kid appears!
Damn, a small island like this...
If we use helicopters, Kid would have nowhere to run!
Today is our hotel's first anniversary and we're having a huge ceremony!
Nezu Shinzou (58)
President of Nezu Corporation
I don't want to scare my guests.
Please guard this place discreetly.
Fine.
My men may intimidating, but they are all handpicked elites.
I've also made sure that none of them is Kid in disguise.
Plus, we have a secret weapon.
Retinal Recognition System.
This glass cane cannot be opened or closed without data on my retina.
Not to mention the visor is always with me.
Come here if you dare, Kid!
Yagami Toshihiro (28)
Nezu's Secretary
I'll definitely capture you tonight!
Prepare to be dominated!
Keep Out
One minute left...
Thirty seconds left!
Seven, six, five...
Two, one...
Kid will steal the diamond while we're blinded by light!
Stay focused!
Inspector, put on the sunglasses.
Thank you.
Bastard...
You're Kid!?
How's that?
This plastic face is just like the real thing, right?
Kid!
Buh-bye, baby!
Wait, Kid!
Kid...
After him!
The elevator!
Hurry!
Drive!
What the...
Damn it!
We chase by foot!
Kid!
You're not getting away!
Every single time...
They fall for my dummy trick.
"He really never learns, does he?"
"That inspector."
Right?
Kaito Kid-san.
How'd you know it was a dummy?
Easy.
The wind was blowing from the west...
Hang gliders usually fly against the wind to progress.
But that hang glider was heading east.
I really must hand it to you.
By the way, was it my manifesto that brought you here?
No, just by chance.
Sonoko's family received invitations to celebrate the anniversary of this hotel...
But no one except Sonoko could make it...
So she invited us instead.
Then...
I happened to see Inspector Nakamori patrolling this hotel.
That's why I thought something like this would happen.
I see.
However...
Isn't Inspector Nakamori's security net a little bit too loose this time?
Yeah.
Although it looks like the inspector wanted to set up a gigantic cordon with helicopters as always...
Everyone, regarding our hotel's anniversary party...
But President Nezu not allow it.
He firmly requested the security to kept discreetly without media interference.
I see.
Well then...
Chitchat time is over.
Hey...
Don't tell me you're going to shoot the soccer ball at me again!?
You got that right.
Damn it!
He's smiling?
Even though his precious diamond was stolen? Why?
Well, now we're finished our desserts...
Let's leave this party and go play elsewhere!
Huh?
Where are Conan-kun and the others?
Now that you mention it, they're gone.
Where could they be?
Couldn't they have returned to their rooms to sleep?
It's past 8:00 anyway.
Let's not worry about the kids.
Now it's quality time for adults! Let's enjoy ourselves!
Wait...
How is it, Ayumi?
Have you see Kid yet?
It's too dark to see well.
If only the moon would come out...
There he is!
I can see him too!
So he really flying to the west.
Just like I predicted!
Paper airplane, launch!
What is it?
Got it!
Awesome!
Genta-kun, do it now!
Go!
Got it!
It's too heavy!
Genta-kun!
Kid just crashed!
Right in front of us!
We can't go in like this.
We can, if we get through this hole!
I wonder who made this hole...
Doesn't matter who!
Let's go!
All right.
Private property - Do not enter
NEZU CORPORATION
All right...
Now what?
I crashed, got fished, and I fell...
What a bummer...
I can't fly like this.
Kid's hang glider!
And his costume!
Kid must be somewhere near!
Oh, no! They saw my face!
Shin'ichi-san...
Is it?
That's right!
It's Shin'ichi-oniisan!
Who's that?
Come on, Genta-kun!
He is Ran-oneesan's childhood friend...
And a high school detective, Kudo Shin'ichi-san!
Oh, right! Right! Right!
I am Kudo Shin'ichi!
Long time no see, guys!
Shin'ichi-oniisan, did you come to catch Kid too?
Yes...
But he got away as I was getting close.
In that case, let's chase him together!
I don't think he's gotten that that far away!
Well...
What's the matter?
Aren't you here to catch Kid?
Well...
I suppose so...
Then, it's decided!
We Detective Boys...
And a high school detective...
Make for a stellar collaboration!
Awesome!
Cool!
What a drag...
I need to figure out how to get out of here.
Is it Kid?
A boar!
Could it be that the hole made by that boar!?
That's not what you should be worried about!
Wait for me!
Where exactly are they planning to go?
Shin'ichi-san, hurry up!
Hurry! Hurry!
Give me a break already...
We'll have to chase him to the end!
I'm too starved to move an inch...
Then, let's have our bagged lunched!
Bagged lunches?
First, let's spread this out.
Ta-daa!
My main dish!
It has eel in it!
I've brought sandwiches and pizza!
And I've brought dessert!
Are these all from the party?
Let's eat!
Delicious!
It's so nice to eat under the starry sky! It's really great!
These kids...
They think they're on a picnic or something?
Next is...
Mitsuhiko, eat some carrots too!
I don't like carrots...
Shin'ichi-oniisan, is there anything you don't like to eat?
I can't deal with fish.
Can't deal with fish...
Are you afraid of them?
So funny!
Is it that funny?
So thrilling!
Coming up is a bridge!
Is everyone all right?
Barely...
A spy camera...
We've been spied?
Look at this!
What is it?
It's Artemis's Teardrop!
Kid must have dropped it...
Well done, Ayumi-chan!
So this is the diamond worth 100 million yen?
Awesome! Awesome!
Carefully!
Genta-kun, your snort just got the diamond blurred!
Let me see.
This is...
A fake.
Fake?
If you breathe on a real diamond, the vapor will immediately disappear.
Due to the high thermal conductivity of the diamond.
However, the vapor on this didn't disappear.
But, why would Kid steal a fake diamond?
We'll have to ask President Nezu personally about that.
Did you hear anything?
Yes...
The noise is closing in...
Crocodile!
Run!
Everyone, here!
Why are there crocodiles here anyway?
Now that you mention it, I heard that they build a crocodile park here!
That means we're in the crocodile park now?
No...
Someone released them!
To get rid of us!
Now what?
I could run away if I was alone.
But I can't leave them...
You guys!
Give me those rubber bands you tied on your lunch bags!
Rubber bands?
Hurry!
Here.
Stay here.
Now everything is all right.
Using only rubber bands...
Crocodiles are powerful when closing their mouths, however...
It's not so easy to opening them.
Now let's get out of here before it gets really bad.
There's a door there!
No time to think!
Just get in!
Strange...
Why it has a room in this cave like this?
I wonder what's in this room.
So many gems!
Awesome!
No.
There's no way that they'd let real gems just lie around here.
These are all fakes!
Fake?
Looks like President Nezu is in the business of counterfeiting gems and art...
And also...
The illegal smuggling weapons.
The reason he let Kid steal this fake diamond...
Is to get insurance in the amount of 100 million.
I think you saw something that you shouldn't.
President Nezu...
I will let you see at a real diamond as a parting gift.
I appreciate for your generosity.
But you carry the real one out of fear, huh?
You think Kid will take away the real one after discovering the fake.
Shut up!
Because you know our secret, you have to die.
Damn...
These guys are more troublesome than the crocodiles...
Fire!
You...
Damn it!
President Nezu specifically refused to use helicopters...
to let you escape, am I right?
Yeah.
Even if I return the fake to the police later on...
He'd say that it was Kid who made the switch.
And he'd hold to claim that the real one was truly stolen.
That's how he planned it.
If you give me the Artemis's Teardrop, I'll make an exception for you and let you go.
As a means of repaying the favor for saving the children.
My, how kind you are.
To be honest, these kids completely wore me out.
But I can somewhat understand it now...
How does it feel to you from day to day.
Well, then...
Until next time, Great Detective!
I'm really surprised about that President Nezu had counterfeited gems and works of art.
And about the smuggling of weapons too...
But the biggest disappointment is that I didn't meet Kid-sama!
I'll go walk a little.
Where are you going?
I'm going to find Shin'ichi!
He didn't answer my call!
And ignored my text messages.
I'm sure he's still on the island somewhere.
He'll get it when I find him!
I'm already here...
Then let's search together!
We've come to know this place pretty well.
Detective Boys...
Let's go!
Really?
By the way, how did he escape without a hang glider?
Jii!
Hurry and get me out of here!
FISH!