This video is a special release provided to all of you by Shounen Sunday!
When you watch this video, brighten the room and don't sit too close to the screen.
One day in the spring,
Ran and I accepted invitation from Hattori and Kazuha...
To visit Osaka again.
This time we were suppose to be there only for sightseeing.
So the first thing we did was go to the Floating Gardens Observatory, which offers a stunning view of Osaka.
Hey, look over there!
That is the famous Six Gods Mountains over there.
And over there, the thing that looks small from here, is the Akashi-Kaikyo Bridge.
And look over there.
That is Osaka International Airport.
Over there is Expoland.
And there is Osaka Dome.
Tsuuten Tower.
And Osaka Castle!
Well?
Isn't this...
A great place?
Osaka!
It sure is.
Jeez, these two are so alike.
All right, let's move on!
This way, this way!
What is it, Ran-chan?
Those kids...
They have been sitting there since we came here.
Were they?
Huh? Those three...
They look just like them!
You're that high school detective Hattori Heiji, right?
Well, yes.
My name is Esaka Mayumi.
ESAKA MAYUMI (7)
I'm in first grade of elementary school.
This skinny one is Yagi Mikihiko.
YAGI MIKIHIKO (7)
And the fat one is Osawa Kenta.
OSAWA KENTA (7)
Ayumi, Mitsuhiko, Genta?
No, no!
Mayumi, Mikihiko, Kenta.
Hey you, you got something wrong with your ears?
Even their names are eerily similar.
You should see a doctor if you have earing problem.
Speaking of doctors, I went to see them yesterday.
"This cavity isn't good..."
"Looks like we have to yank it."
You know?
That's a dentist.
But my grandpa is even cooler!
He pulls out his teeth every night.
Those are dentures.
You two are so noisy!
Kenta's story was so lame!
Looks like their personalities are different.
You're looking for someone?
And you want me to help?
In general, yes.
To be specific, we are looking for a place.
The place where Satoshi is now.
Satoshi?
He's our friend.
We agreed to meet near the shop at 1:00 in the afternoon, but he didn't show up.
1:00?
Now it's already 2:00.
Did you call his parents?
We called, but got the answering machine.
Probably he forgot about us and still playing at his secret place.
A secret place?
He said he'd be there until noon.
It's located where the train from the red line passes in front of the T-Rex's hand.
Even though it's really fun, that place sometimes can make you cry.
What are you talking about?
That's how Satoshi said it.
It's probably a "CONT".
It's "HINT".
In Osaka, the only line with red trains is the Kanjo Line.
Wait...
From the Kanjo Line, you can transfer to the Yumesaki Line.
That's it! I understood!
It's US...
USJ is wrong!
(Note - USJ - Universal Studio Japan, the Japanese amusement park of the Universal Studio)
At first I thought so too, but he said it was wrong.
What is it then?
I'm not familiar with the Osaka's railway...
Hey, can you see a T-Rex model or a billboard of one from the Kanjou Line?
Well, I just remembered that people in Osaka like this kind of thing.
That's right, we have huge figures of crabs, octopuses, puffer fish and others.
But there are no dinosaurs.
Well, Heiji.
There's only one way to find out.
Let's take a ride on the Kanjo Line now!
Idiot! We have two guests...
No, we don't mind at all!
Right, Conan-kun?
Compared to what Heiji-niichan has showed us so far,
This will be much more interesting.
Then it's decided!
That bastard... I'll remember this.
That hairpin is really pretty!
Can I see it for a second?
Sure.
Satoshi gave it to me.
A present from your boyfriend?
This is so embarrassing...
Hey, Ran-chan, look over there!
What is it?
It's the Floating Garden Observatory where we just went.
It's beautiful!
T-Rex, T-Rex...
Hey, is that a highway going through the building?
Oh, yes.
Cool, isn't it?
Osaka has it all!
If that so, even a dinosaur is quite normal here.
The mountains!
What's so special about mountains?
I get it, it's because people from Tokyo rarely get to see the mountains.
I don't see any T-Rex billboards.
Ohtaki-han!
Kudou, did you see a white car surrounded by police cars?
Yes, it was a sedan.
They found it.
The robbers' car!
This morning at 11:30, the credit union in Namba was robbed.
The criminals were a young couple.
They disappeared from a white sedan.
Let them take care of the dinosaur.
Our stop's coming up.
Our stop?
Ohtaki-han!
Hei-chan, what are you doing here?
We saw you from the train.
This is a robber's car, isn't it?
Yes, the witness remembered part of the license plate number.
So, the criminals switched their car here, right?
Little boy, aren't you that one...
Heiji!
Conan-kun!
Really, you're always like this...
You're Mouri-han's daughter, right?
Inspector!
Take a look!
What is that?
This is...
A red hairpin.
That hairpin...
It's the same as Mayumi-chan's!
Mayumi-chan?
This little girl.
May I?
Go ahead.
They are very similar.
Little girl, where did you buy this hairpin?
I didn't buy it, someone gave it to me!
Someone gave it to you? Who?
A friend!
He said he found it at a secret place.
A secret place?
I see.
So you all took the Kanjo Line...
The hairpin found in the car must have been dropped by the criminals?
That seems likely.
Both criminals were wearing ski masks.
It probably flew off when the woman took off her mask in the car.
So, the hairpin which was given to this little girl, and this hairpin that was dropped...
I think we can reach a conclusion.
If you look closely, you can see that both hairpins were painted red, right?
The criminal probably painted them with nail polish.
If you try to scratch them, the paint will come off.
You're right.
Which means...
The secret place of Satoshi...
May have something to do with criminals.
Mayumi-chan, does Satoshi often break his promises?
No, this is the first time.
This is bad.
Since Satoshi didn't show up,
It's likely he ran into the criminals at his secret place.
What did you say?
If that's so, this could be dangerous.
The criminals have guns...
Who knows what they're capable of?
But we cannot be sure about this.
Anyway, let's go to the kid's house and check.
With this bag, we can completely say goodbye to work!
But what are we going to do with this kid?
MORIGUCHI SATOSHI (7)
He saw our faces.
We can't leave a witness.
It looks like we'll have to take him to the mountains and finish him off.
MAEJIMA TSUYOSHI (26)
What a pity, but it seems there is no choice.
KOMIYA KAORU (21)
MORIGUCHI
What an impressive house!
And it was built recently, too.
It looks like it.
As we thought, no one is home.
If only his mother was at home...
We could find out where Satoshi's secret place is.
All the flowers have dried up...
Strange!
There is only one lock on the door!
So what?
Since the house has a security system, you don't have to worry, right?
Do you kids know where Satoshi's father works?
No.
I see. Well, with some investigating, it'd be easy to find out.
Satoshi-kun doesn't go to the same school we do.
Satoshi goes to a private school.
While we go to a public school.
Then how did you all meet him?
We met him at the nearby pond.
He was looking up at the sky when we first met him.
What are you doing?
Look up there.
Those clouds look like a rabbit and a turtle chasing each other.
You right.
They really do.
What an unusual kid...
Ohtaki-han, we will back to the Kanjo Line and continue looking for the T-Rex.
All right then.
Heiji, how is it going?
Not well, we couldn't find anything.
We, too. Even we split up, we couldn't find anything.
We even went as far as the building of the Yomiuri TV.
But we didn't see anything like a T-Rex.
I guess it wasn't the Kanjou Line after all.
All the trains here are orange.
Did Inspector Ohtaki come up with anything?
He called recently and said that...
They were able to contact Satoshi's father.
But he doesn't seem to know where this secret place might be.
What did he say about Satoshi's father works?
It looks like he's a businessman.
He started his own business few years ago, and they recently moved to that house.
But Satoshi is not very happy.
He recently complained that his dad works hard and fights with his mother all the time.
Right?
He was almost crying when saying that.
By the way, I just remembered something.
At the museum in Nagai, I saw a large dinosaur skeleton!
What did you say?
Speaking of Nagai...
It seems to be in the south of Tennoji...
Which is where the Midosuji Line and the Hagane Subway Line intersect.
And the trains to Midosuji have a red stripe on their bodies.
And take a look at this.
The color of the line on the map is also red!
So, the "red train", he meant the Midosuji Line?
Not to mention, Satoshi's home is located near Nagai.
This time we were definitely not wrong.
This is, of course, a dinosaur, but...
This is not a T-Rex.
Found it! It's a T-Rex!
This is useless, it doesn't have hands.
Damn it!
Then, this was also wrong?
Hey, Heiji, it's getting dark.
So the Midosuji Line is also not connected to the "red train", huh?
It's a T-Rex!
Look at the line diagram. They look a lot like a standing T-Rex, don't they?
You right!
Here is the head.
Here is the body.
And here are the hands!
You right, I can see it too.
This must be right.
So the station "in front of the hands" is...
Nakamozu!
But why is Nakamozu more interesting than others?
Ohtaki-han said he would question the boy's father,
So I hope we find out about it before we get there.
Hey...
Why did you asking...
There is only one lock on the door!
What's you mean by that?
I just thought they had double-lock...
Because Satoshi always carries two keys with him.
One of them is normal key and the other has long teeth.
Two keys...
Hattori!
Yeah...
That might be the case.
I got it, Hei-chan.
The Moriguchi family...
Lived in Nakamozu before, right?
Right, but how did you know?
So, it was what we thought.
They lived in an apartment near Shinnou Pond...
It's called Nankaisho.
Wait.
Will you give that kid to us?
Who are you guys?
Take this!
Satoshi!
Just one second.
Mayumi-chan! Mikihiko-kun! Kenta-kun!
Don't worry!
I'm glad you're okay!
Me, too!
You all saved me!
We were so worried!
Apparently, only these two criminals lived in this apartment.
Since Satoshi-kun had the key to the old house even after the move,
He sometimes came here himself.
But why did he come here?
I think it will be better...
If you two, his parents, see for yourself.
In the middle of this room...
There was a dining table.
Dad was sitting here, and Mom was over here.
And I sat right here.
Mom, today you look more beautiful than ever!
I'm always beautiful!
And me?
That's right...
Kenta-kun, you can be that pet, Noraya, who often came to play with us!
Noraya is a cat.
Satoshi said that in this place...
"Even though it's really fun, it's also a place that can make you cry."
Satoshi, we've come to get you.
Dad! And Mom! Don't you have work to do?
No, no more work today.
Let's buy Satoshi's favorite food before we go home.
That'd be great!
It all ended so well!
BIZEN HEISHIROU (34)
Well done, Hei-chan.
By the way...
I wanted to bring them here to try some takoyaki before returned to Tokyo.
But I forgot again.
Well, next time you will definitely bring them here.
And I will give them the best service.
In that case, thank you.
You brought us souvenirs?
I'm touched, Conan.
Is that fried eel?
Of course not!
This is for Mayumi-chan.
This is for Kenta.
And this is for Mikihiko.
Mayumi?
Kenta?
Mikihiko?
Conan-kun, did something weird happen to you there in Osaka?
Maybe it did...