This is a request from the Detective Boys!
This special DVD is presented by Shogakukan for everyone.
While watching this DVD, please keep the room bright...
And be sure to watch the monitor or TV from a distance.
Are you all right, Conan-kun?
I'm fine...
The temperature from my fever isn't very high, anyway...
If I sleep for the whole of today, I'll recover.
Well, I'll call the school about it.
And...
Ran?
If we don't hurry up, we're gonna be late.
Coming!
I already talked to Dad about getting lunch.
Just keep warm and sleep well, all right?
Got it.
See you...
I'm off then.
Sorry for the wait.
The little guy came down with a cold, huh?
That's it.
He said he was all right, but still...
Have you heard from Shin'ichi-kun lately?
Nope.
Why?
You're really hopeless...
How about dumping that heartless fellow...
And jumping into the arms of another guy?
"Jump" into?
For instance...
How about Araide-sensei?
He's a doctor, and older.
He might even be more reliable than Shin'ichi-kun.
Damn it, that Sonoko...
High school, huh?
Am I going to remain like this forever and never change back?
This won't do, this won't do!
Is it because of my ill health?
That I'm having such negative thoughts...
If I don't hurry and recover from this cold...
The Stranger From 10 Years Later
Hello?
Sleeping?
Haibara, huh...
I heard you came down with a cold.
Yeah...
Isn't this convenient?
The antidote to that drug.
I've created a new prototype.
That drug...
Apotoxin-4869!?
Well?
Want to try it?
Of course I do!
Where are you right now?
At the professor's?
Yeah.
I'm on my way back from school now.
Then, I'll be right over too!
Hey, lunchtime.
He's gone?
That's right...
I need to bring some clothes along...
Where's the professor?
He had something to do and went out.
Is that your school uniform?
Yeah!
I thought I'd suddenly turn up in school and surprise everyone!
That's foolish.
After doing that, what will you do if people get wind of it?
All right, let's get to it now.
First—a temperature check.
Fine...
38.7° Celsius...
That's markedly high.
I just ran all the way here.
That's why it's so high, right?
Are you sure this is all right?
With such a high fever?
There's no need to worry!
Come on!
The antidote's effect, like the previous
ones, should last approximately 24 hours.
That said, it's designed for a quick reaction, so you'll change immediately upon ingesting it.
With this...
With this, I'll be able to return to being Kudo Shin'ichi again...
It's happening!
Huh?
Haibara?
Haibara!
That's odd...
Where'd she get off to?
It's only 12:30...
I can still make it for lunch.
All right!
Is the tree in my yard really this tall?
I guess I'm just used to seeing it from
a different angle at Conan's height.
Oh, well.
Has that building always been there?
When'd they renovate that apartment complex?
Wow, there sure is a lot I can't see from a child's perspective.
It's Gorilla!
It's only been a little while but he's aged so much!
It isn't this one?
That's strange...
Could it be that someone's been using my locker in my absence?
As I thought, it isn't here...
Everybody's gonna be so surprised.
Hey, guys!
Huh?
Why isn't anyone surprised?
And these people...
Just who are they?
I don't know any of them...
This must be the wrong classroom.
But this is it!
How bizarre...
At any rate, I should find Ran first.
She's usually in the karate club room during lunch break.
The door's locked...
The Detective Club?
Was there such a club?
You're finally here!
As I thought, you went somewhere else to eat, didn't you?
We agreed to eat lunch here every Tuesday and Thursday, remember?
I had to try so hard to prevent myself
from having an early meal, you know.
The smell of Genta-kun's eel rice ended up filling the whole room.
Genta-kun is probably the only one who would still include eel in his bento, huh?
Genta...
Mitsuhiko...
And Ayumi?
What's going on here?
Why are they here?
And why do they look like high schoolers?
Huh?
Conan-kun looks strange today...
Conan!?
It must be because he isn't wearing his glasses.
Why'd you take off your glasses?
Oh, that's it!
I thought so!
That's more like Conan-kun!
Hey, Ayumi-chan, you're too close!
Exactly!
Draw back some!
Don't tell me...
Is something wrong, Conan-kun?
You look like a pigeon getting hit with a water gun.
Genta-kun...
It's actually a pigeon getting hit with a bamboo stick.
You guys...
Are we actually...
In our second year of high-school?
What're you saying?
Of course we are!
Really, Conan-kun!
Really?
I must be dreaming!
The dream probably started with Haibara's phone call, right?
It isn't a dream?
What's really going on here?
Hey...
You're in the way.
Haibara!
Ai-chan...
Not eating lunch again?
That's bad for your health.
Even without going on a diet...
Haibara-san already has a very nice figure.
Haibara!
Come here for a second!
Just come with me!
What's going on here?
I should be back to being Kudo Shin'ichi!
Why am I still Conan?
Not to mention...
Why did we both end up going from first year elementary students to being second years in high school?
Although I'm not sure exactly what it is you're referring to...
I can tell you what has happened over the past ten years should you wish.
As for the Organization, we never reached a conclusion...
And attended middle and high school as time passed.
Over that time...
You changed back so many times with the antidotes I created for APTX-4869 that...
You ultimately ended up developing an immunity.
Accordingly, you haven't been able to
change back during the past five years.
You look as though you're considerably shocked.
Did you lose your memory over lunch break by any chance?
The afternoon classes are about to start, but...
Maybe you should head home and get some rest.
Yeah...
I'll do that...
For today, we'll be interviewing...
The famous detective from Naniwa, Hattori Heiji-san!
He has brilliantly solved numerous intricate
cases and is now recognized all over Japan!
He's even opened his own detective agency!
It must be very active right now, right?
No—no, no, no, no.
I've heard that the young ladies have a certain nickname for Hattori-san...
"The Lady-Killer of Naniwa."
What do you have to say to that?
That's a bit much, huh?
What do you mean by "lady-killer"!?
He's just a dark-skinned man!
Hey, Kazuha!
Don't just suddenly jump out like that!
What are you being so cocky about?
How undignified...
What do you mean by "how undignified"!?
Hattori...
Kazuha...
Pardon my interruption, but when do you plan to get married?
Married?
M-M... Married?
This place seems to have gotten old, too...
Look who it is...
You're home pretty early...
Uncle...
He hasn't changed a bit.
It looks like the brat ended up skipping his afternoon classes, huh?
Sonoko!?
Well, I guess I'm in no position to lecture you.
Due to lack of interest, I left school early...
Must be great being an heiress, ya know...
You getta live how ya please...
Uncle, that's too much drinking.
Quiet!
Well...
Now that Yoko-chan's retired and married...
I'll get depressed if I'm not even allowed to drink...
The teaaaars of a maaan...
I'll have a beer, too.
These two...
They don't seem awkward toward my existence at all...
Apparently, I've been freeloading here for the past ten years...
Did I really lose my memory?
Speaking of marriage...
It seems Ran has finally decided, huh?
"Decided"?
Her marriage, of course.
To Araide-sensei.
Marriage!?
To Araide-sensei!?
Why're you so surprised?
You knew about it, didn't you?
About Araide-sensei proposing to Ran two years ago.
But, Ran...
She's been waiting for Shin'ichi-kun, who still hasn't come back...
In order to resolve her feelings once and for all...
Ran said she was going to the place of
memories she shared with Shin'ichi-kun.
Our place of memories?
And where is that, Sonoko-neechan?
How am I supposed to know that?
Damn it!
Ran!
Excuse me...
It's Ran!
Ran...
Don't turn on the lights.
After all...
I don't want Conan-kun to see me crying.
This place is filled with memories between Shin'ichi and me.
The marriage...
Will you...
With Araide-sensei?
Don't do it!
Don't get married!
Why not?
Because I...
Would be troubled by it.
Because...
I'm Kudo Shin'ichi!
So, please...
Don't get married!
Ever since you became a high-schooler...
You really have started to look very much like him.
That's because...
I'm not like him, I am him!
Thank you...
For saying that and trying to make me feel better.
But...
I've already made my decision.
I've already waited ten years...
So another ten will be just fine.
I'll be turning down Araide-sensei's proposal tomorrow.
Ran, I really am...
Conan-kun!
My body's burning...
What's going on!?
3 hours and 20 minutes.
That's over twenty hours shorter than usual.
It would seem this experiment ended in failure.
Have you...
Been observing the effects of the antidote?
Yes.
Even though you did change back after taking the antidote...
You remained unconscious and continued having nightmares.
It is possible that you had those hallucinations
because your temperature was too high.
Although the antidote requires cold symptoms to take effect...
It seems to be ineffective when your body temperature is too high.
I've collected valuable data thanks to you.
I'm tired...
I'm going back to sleep.
Did I wake you?
I'm sorry.
Ran... neechan.
You're sure looking better.
Araide-sensei...
You have to thank him!
After hearing about it from Ran, he came specially to see you.
Sonoko... neechan.
Conan-kun!
We've come by to visit you!
But this room sure is messy, isn't it?
Well, I'm sorry about that.
This is my room, after all.
You guys...
Your fever's gone down.
You should be fine.
Thank goodness.
Say, did you go somewhere around noon?
When I brought you lunch...
You weren't here.
The bathroom...
Just went to the bathroom...
Really now?
I was sure you just went out to play after recovering.
Of course not!
Why would I do that?
Isn't that right?
See?
That's just what I said.
Still weird...
Well, then!
I'm going to prepare dinner!
Why don't you guys stay for dinner too?
Yes!
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
For the first time, it actually feels good to change back into Conan...
The food is exquisite.
Thanks.
It's all very delicious.
And I might have just spotted another problem...