Notice:
This DVD is a special gift from Shogakukan to all of you.
When watching this DVD, please turn on
the lights and sit away from the TV.
Kaito Kid?!
Detective Conan:
FOLLOW THE VANISHED DIAMOND!
CONAN & HEIJI VS. KID!
Follow the Vanished Diamond!
Conan & Heiji vs. Kid!
What would you like for dinner, Conan-kun?
Anything's fine.
Honestly, I really want to make sukiyaki, but my dad hasn't had much work lately.
So we have to save up.
Oh, Ran-chan! Today we have a discount on beef.
That's good, I'll make croquettes.
Can I have 150... I mean 100 grams, please?
And eggs as well.
Of course.
Ran-chan, who's this boy?
This is Conan-kun, he lives with us.
He's not Mouri-san's illegitimate son, is he?
No way, Auntie.
Of course not.
Here, with 20 grams on the house.
Thank you.
Potatoes, onions, cabbage, tomatoes...
Ran-chan, this is on the house.
Thank you very much!
But who would have thought that Ran-chan had a little brother.
No, it's not like that.
Come in everyone! Cheap fish!
Well?
Well, I guess we can have
that for lunch tomorrow.
You look as energetic as ever, Ran-chan.
Come to think of it, Ran...
She's always shopped like that.
Here, take these clams.
Perfect, now I can make miso soup!
But, she's just as popular.
Thank you.
That was "Cooking with Okino Yoko"!
Today's guest was the great detective, Kogoro Mouri-san.
Well then, until next week!
Bye-bye, Yoko-chan!
Geez, how many times does he have to watch this video before he gets tired?
This tape must be worn out by now.
Quiet!
Who cares? We don't have any customers anyway...
It's here!
What is it?
Thank you very much!
What is that, Dad? Who's it from?
It's nothing.
It's just a package for me.
I get that, but from whom?
Nobody.
Is that true, Dad?
Is it true, father?
Wait up, Dad! It's not anything indecent, is it?
You idiot! What are you talking about? I need it for work.
Then why are you going upstairs?
You're so annoying!
Geez.
What do you think, Conan-kun?
It's suspicious, isn't it?
Right? He must be hiding something...
Hello?
Do you have the money ready?
Huh?
Don't "huh" me, do you have the...
Who is this?
It's blackmail.
I'll record it.
Good morning!
Damn it!
Hello? Hello!
What's up, Conan-kun?
Private Number
As I thought...
Conan-kun?
A blackmail phone call?
But the phone number didn't show up, we can't return the call.
And the man didn't mention
who he was trying to call, did he?
Since he called here by accident, our number must be similar to the one he was looking for.
Dad, we should hurry up and call the police!
Forget about it, what you guys just told me doesn't hold much water.
There's no proof that there's been a crime.
But...
It probably was just a debt collector calling.
Well, I've arranged to play mahjong.
Hey, listen to what Conan-kun has to say!
It's true that there's no proof that it's a crime,
But if there's a kidnapping, we don't have time to waste.
Bye!
Dad!
But first...
Do you have the money ready?
Huh?
Don't "huh" me, do you have the...
Who is this?
That voice... I've heard it somewhere.
Besides...
Good morning!
Damn it!
I'd say I've heard that voice recently, but where?
Wait a minute, the only voices I've heard recently...
Geez...
Cheap fish!
Well?
You look as energetic as ever, Ran-chan.
We're having a discount on beef today.
He's not Mouri-san's illegitimate son, is he?
Cabbage, tomatoes...
Who would have thought that Ran-chan had a little brother.
Could they be...?!
That's because we don't use pesticides.
I guarantee it's delicious!
No...  It's a little similar, but it's not that voice.
Thank you very much.
Where was it? Where did I hear it?
Where was it?
Good morning, did I catch you at a good time?
I'm Moriwaki from TM Trading. Is the chief in?
Heiji-niichan!
Kudo... I mean Conan-kun.
To make me come all the way from Osaka,
This must be very important, right?
That's right.
It's about...
A call from a blackmailer?
He says the man's voice sounded exactly like yours, Hattori-kun.
I thought I heard that voice before.
But he spoke in a strange way,
so I didn't recognize it.
So the reason why we called you was...
To find out who the man was trying to call,
by having me place calls as the blackmailer...
To every single number similar to that of the detective agency.
We'll know from their reaction.
That's right, as I expected from Hattori-kun!
Kudo...
No, no, no.
C-Conan-kun, I can tell it's your idea.
I've already compiled a list of
phone numbers, so we'd better hurry.
Well then, without further ado...
Could you leave the rest to me and the kid?
Well, then I'll be preparing dinner.
If you need help with anything, just ask.
Preparing dinner?
This is a very homely detective agency, isn't it?
Hey, this is no time for small talk. Let's get started!
Very well!
Hello? This is Inoue.
Hey 'tis me... It's me.
Huh? Who is it?
Sorry, I must have the wrong number.
It's me.
Huh?
I'm sorry. I've got the wrong number.
Ah, sorry.
Hello? This is Iwatsume.
It's me.
Y-You!
What more do you want now?
You filthy thief!
I've handed over the ten million yen and
haven't spoken with the police, as we agreed.
You shouldn't have any more business with me.
I'll call you back.
Bingo, eh?
By the sound of it, the man has already paid and closed the deal.
But he called me a filthy thief.
What exactly did he mean by "thief"?
Here we are, eh?
Huh?
Isn't this Inspector Nakamori?
If I'm not mistaken, you're the boy who's always with Mouri-san...
You've come to visit Iwatsume-san?
Who's Iwatsume?
We're investigating a fraud case.
A jewelry theft?
Yeah. Iwatsume is a rare name, isn't it?
So after looking him up on the internet we found out he's a jewelry appraiser.
Which means that there probably was a jewel robbery.
But we're not sure how blackmail is related.
Alright! Let's meet this Iwatsume.
But, Inspector...
Aren't robberies handled by the third division?
You're from the second...
Well, I'm already here... and I can't ignore it if they tell me about a jewel robbery.
Oh, that's it!
Wait a minute!
I have an idea.
Did you see something just fly by?
Yes, probably a giant flying squirrel.
Yeah, right.
What do the police want with me?
Do you remember hearing this voice?
Do you have the money ready?
Did you catch the criminal?
What criminal?
What criminal? I'm talking about the jewel thief!
Jewels?
Yes, we've got him!
Please tell us the details,
we need the victim's testimony.
Sure, no problem.
The day before yesterday, 100 million yen was...
Hey, could you say that again?
Oh, no!
Do you have the money ready?
One more time.
No, this is not the criminal!
He didn't have such a strange accent!
What do you mean, strange?
Are you making fun of the Osaka dialect?
Hey!
Who the hell are you?
Me?
I am...
The Naniwa high school detective, Hattori Heiji!
You idiot...
Officer! What's the meaning of this?
Regardless, the fact is that a hundred million yen
worth of jewelry has been stolen, right?
No, it hasn't been stolen.
I have it.
And this is the proof.
But a moment ago you said...
That was a joke.
A joke?
I see, so that's what it's all about.
That's it, then.
That jewel was stolen, but he offered to return it if you paid him 10 million yen, right?
What? Why would I...
The thing is, you had already sold it to someone else.
And even if it cost you 10 million yen,
it would still be worth it to get the jewel back.
Did I get it right, Iwatsume-san?
Iwatsume-san, please tell us the truth.
If we don't arrest the criminal now,
He may strike again, maybe a second or third time.
That's right, just like Kid.
Kid?
That's right! I have a lot of bad memories because of that bastard!
Damn it! I won't forgive you, Kid!
Inspector, please calm down!
Speaking of which, I wonder if he'll be coming for this jewel.
Wait a minute, this jewel...
This thief isn't very greedy, is he?
Who is this boy?
It's been bothering me.
Please don't pay attention to him.
For a jewel worth 100 million yen, he only got ten, right?
If it were me, I would have asked for at least half of what it's worth.
It's definitely strange to ask for only ten percent of what it's worth.
Maybe the jewel you got back is a fake?
No way.
E-Excuse me for a moment.
It's a fake...
I thought so.
I guess it's a case of fraud, too.
Do you admit it now, Iwatsume-san?
Yes.
So, do you know anything about the criminal?
Well, although I gave him money, we didn't meet in person. I only heard his voice.
On the phone? Did you record it?
No, I didn't...
Seems like the old man and the girl are asleep.
Hattori...
I know, you don't have to say it.
You want me to re-enact the call we had, don't you?
Right. Since it's not the thief's real voice,
we can't use it as evidence,
But that should help us find him.
Alright!
Let's get started.
Do ya have the money ready?
No, not like that! "Have you got the money ready?"
Isn't that what I'm saying?
It's not, and that's precisely why Iwatsume-san figured you out.
Come on, one more time.
"Do you have the money ready?"
Do ya have the money prepared?
Not like that! Why can't you say it like me?
What can I do? I'm an Osaka man from the bottom of my heart.
Geez, at this rate, you'll never get these lines right.
So what if I can't say it?
If you were asked to speak in the Osaka dialect, you wouldn't be able to, it's the same thing.
It's not the same! I can at least
speak the Osaka dialect.
You can? I do recall that you once explained your deductions in a very strange Osaka dialect.
And on top of that, using my voice.
The voice-changing bowtie!
That's right!
It'll only take one try with that!
Why didn't I think of that earlier?
This is what they call having it right under your nose, eh?
Hattori, you can go home now.
Kudo!
I'm kiddin'.
Please listen to the voice of the suspect in the theft of 100 million yen worth of jewelry.
Do you have money ready?
Don't "huh" me, do you have the...
Who is this?
If you recognize this voice, please call the special phone line of the Metropolitan Police Department.
That was Hattori-kun's voice, right?
Your standard Japanese accent is very good.
Well, 'tis quite useful for a detective...
But I'm surprised they didn't realize it's you.
Actually, Inspector Nakamori realized that it was Heiji-niichan's voice right away.
But even knowing that, he dared to have it broadcast on TV.
That guy seems to have some guts as well.
The influence of TV is huge,
there'll soon be an avalanche of calls...
It's Kazuha.
'tis me.
Heiji! What're you doing?
Your voice was just on TV!
It was in a weird Tokyo dialect, but it was definitely your voice!
Is your family in so much financial trouble
that you'd have to steal jewelry?
You idiot! How can you expect me to steal jewelry?
But even if you say that...
Don't be ridiculous!
The phone calls really are pouring in, huh?
Yeah, really...
By the way, Kudo, about that
"good morning" you heard on the call...
Do you remember where you heard it?
No, although I've thought about it a lot.
Come to think of it, it sounded more muffled than the man's voice.
Huh?
What's this?
"Okino Yoko's Special Figurine Alarm Clock"?
What's that?
Isn't it the package Uncle recieved yesterday?
I can't believe it.
Why would you want this?
Limited to members only
Alarm clock of Okino Yoko in an apron
Serial number
Let me see it.
Wait a minute, Okino Yoko...
This is well made, eh?
Good morning!
It's morning, please wake up!
I-It's that voice!
Ran-neechan, that's the voice from the call!
Don't touch it!
This is a specially made alarm clock that's only available to members of Yoko-chan's fan club.
Father, how much was it?
Does it matter how much it cost?
How much?
Two... Two thousand yen.
Liar!
Twenty thousand yen...
Twenty thousand yen?
I'm barely making ends meet right now,
And you spend that kind of money on a toy?
That's why you were hiding it from us, right?
Only two hundred of them were made,
And I wanted one so badly...
Dad!
Only two hundred were made?
We can get the names of people from the fan club.
Yes, the criminal probably bought the clock and set the time wrong.
So when he was talking to me...
Good morning!
Damn it!
Hello? Hello!
The next day, thanks to the fan club's list and
a call from a viewer, the jewel thief was identified.
Stop!
If you come any closer, I'll throw this into the sea!
Dang it...
His voice really does sound like mine...
Kid!
Give it to me!
Good morning! It's morning, please wake up!
Come here!
Wait up!
Damn it!
Why is Kid...?
He probably was after the jewel too...
I guess he saw us going investigating before he sent the warning note.
That's why he was up to date on the case...
It was no flying squirrel...
Congratulations, little detective.
And to you too, detective of the west.
After him! Don't let Kid get away!
That's what they call having it snatched away from right under your nose.
That's why I came all the way from Osaka for?
Yoko-chan!
What an idiot... I'm going.
Same here.
The Whimsical Kaito Kid
Returns Hundred Million Yen Jewel to Its Owner
Ran-chan, one more! Pretty please!
No! From now on, no smoking, and you're only allowed one beer a day!
No! Such a waste of life!
It's a very homely detective agency, isn't it?