This video is a special video brought to everyone by Shogakukan.
When watching this video, please keep the room bright and sit away from the TV.
CONAN, KID, AND THE CRYSTAL MOTHER
This luxury train is our pride,
The Royal Express.
How do you find it, Your Majesty?
I find it very nice.
We have actually made a very special reservation for her Majesty...
No. I wanted to meet the Japanese, even for a little, so I requested this.
Selizabeth
Queen of the Principality of Ingram
Even if you say so, the Japanese government feels...
Shinna Jikan
Ministry of Foreign Affairs
I was even able to meet one famous person.
Oh, are you talking about Inspector Nakamori, who was responsible for escorting you?
No, it was the person I met in my private room a few minutes ago.
I'm talking about the thief, Kaito Kid.
What did you say!?
What? You met with Kid?
Did you really, Your Majesty?
Please stand back. This gentleman is from the Japanese police.
So what exactly was Kid doing here?
He came to steal the treasure of our Ingram Empire,
The largest topaz in Europe, Crystal Mother.
What's going on?
So the note that we received was real...
But why did he not manage to take the jewel?
It only took a glance for him to realize...
This is...
What? It's fake!?
I see...
The real one is well hidden elsewhere.
So, Your Majesty, where might that be?
That's something I can't even tell the Inspector.
Kid may very well be eavesdropping on this discussion.
Alright! Kid is on this train!
Search everyone suspicious!
Search all passengers from beginning to end!
Understood!
Stop it. I cannot allow you to disturb the rest of the passengers for the sake of the Queen of Ingram.
But, Your Majesty...
There are still two and a half hours before we reach Osaka.
He may try to steal the jewel as he wrote in the note...
But I will protect it, and I'm willing to risk the name of my country for it.
Your Majesty, but...
Hey, Mother...
Phillip?
About that necklace...
SIlence. Actually, didn't I tell you that you're not supposed to leave the room?
And how many times have I told you to call me "Your Majesty" in public?
Who's that boy?
Prince Phillip. Son of the late Ingram's ruler,
Henry, and Her Majesty, Selizabeth.
Phillip
Heir to the Principality of Ingram
He's the heir to the throne of Ingram Empire.
I'm sorry. But that jewel looks different than before...
What?!
This is a bug.
He probably planted it when
he went into Her Majesty's room.
Hey! Can you hear me, Kaito Kid!?
As long as I'm here, you won't lay a finger on this jewel!
Remember that! Take that!
What's wrong with you all of a sudden?
I was just yelled at by your father, damn inspector.
It's nothing.
What're you getting mad for? Weren't you the one who wanted to ride this train?
That's why I asked my dad for tickets.
Yeah, yeah, I'm immensely grateful to your father.
Jeez, you'd better get your act together.
We're going to meet Her Majesty later.
Her Majesty's probably in the saloon right now.
So I made an appointment and I'm going to greet Her Majesty with:
"I'm the daughter of Inspector Nakamori,
who always gets beat by Kid!"
Are you serious?
Yay! We really are lucky, aren't we?
We're riding on the same train as Her Majesty!
We'll have to thank Kazuha-chan
and the others for inviting us to Osaka.
You're right.
However...
Why is Inspector Nakamori escorting her?
Could it be that Kaito Kid
sent a warning note?
Wanna go to the saloon car?
We might able to meet Her Majesty.
Of course, let's go. I want to go!
Perhaps we'll meet Kid too.
I'm sorry, but the saloon car is fully booked for tonight.
We're having a lot of visitors today.
Is that so? Jeez...
My deepest apologies.
That's too bad. Right, Conan-kun?
Yeah, but when we get to Osaka, we'll definitely get to see her.
But I can't sit here and wait.
I have to find out whether or not Kid sent a note.
Rose
Damn, because of Kid and his unnecessary warnings, this place is crawling with cops.
Now it won't be as easy to get that jewel.
Then, wouldn't it be easier to steal it from Kid?
Along with his life.
Then that's what we'll do.
He's gotten in our way too many times.
And in the confusion, I'll take Her Majesty's life.
It's the perfect opportunity to become a famous sniper in the blink of an eye.
Your Majesty, isn't it about time to tell me where you're hiding the jewel?
If I don't know its whereabouts, I won't be able to help.
If you're so worried, then please stay by my side and protect me.
Shall we have a drink?
Sorry, I'm on duty right now, so wine is...
Oh, you are the first person to refuse my offer, Inspector.
Okay, I've changed my mind, one glass won't hurt.
Oh, Dad.
Dad!
I knew Europe had the best wine!
Once you start, you can't stop!
Dad...
He's drinking.
Your Majesty, this is my daughter Aoko
and her classmate, Kaitou-kun.
Pleased to meet you.
Pleased to meet you, Your Majesty.
These two said that they had to be on the same train as Her Majesty, so I couldn't stop them.
And Kaitou said that he had to see Her Majesty at all costs, didn't he?
That was you...
Reserved
Aoko, don't get in the way of the security!
Okay!
And you call this security?
But, at least I got into the saloon car with Her Majesty.
Now I can search for the jewel's hiding place to my heart's content.
What good fortune for Kid-sama.
But... where could it be?
I checked earlier, so I don't think
it's in Her Majesty's room.
Which means it must be within her reach...
Or maybe...
A cat? No way...
You know, Kaitou, you've been staring at Her Majesty for a while now.
You idiot! I was looking around
the saloon and saw Her Majesty's cat.
You mean Caesar? Cute, right?
He's turning two this year.
Who're you?
Phillip Maximilian of Ingram.
Don't tell me you are...
The Prince?
Caesar, come here!
Here, this is Caesar.
You wanted to see him, right?
Yeah...
Let me hold him for a second!
So cute!
He's gone under the table.
This is my chance!
What a naughty cat.
Right eye looks normal. Left eye...
Are you alright, Kaitou?
Damn, it's just a normal cat.
What a cute stuffed animal!
Dad gave it to me, it's my treasure.
Oh, let me see it for a second.
Looks like it's not here either.
Hey, onii-chan...
What is it?
You're actually...
...Kaito Kid, right?
Please stop joking like that. Of course I'm not!
I guess I was wrong, though I know where the jewel is.
But I'm not going to tell you.
This little brat...
Prince Phillip, it's dangerous here.
Please hurry back to your room.
Her Majesty is not pleased with your behavior.
Mother?
Well, looks like you need to go.
I'm not going, I have to protect mother and the jewel from Kid.
You're worried about your mother, aren't you?
I hate my mother!
Now, now.
She used to be caring and kind,
but she changed after Father passed.
She always gets mad at me,
and never listens to me.
I'm sure she hates me.
But I promised to my father...
I would protect my mother and my country.
Mother!
It seems like no matter how many times
I say it, you still don't understand.
And it's not "mother", but "Her Majesty".
Your Majesty!
Mother!
I forbid you to leave this room again! Got it?
Your Majesty, you don't have to...
No, leave it. He won't understand until I do it.
Mother!
Hey, you're Prince Phillip, right?
And you are?
Edogawa Conan, a detective.
I see. As I thought, Kid sent a note.
But you're amazing.
You're a kid, but already a detective.
I wonder if you can find the jewel.
I don't really know where my mother hid it.
If you want to hide a leaf, hide it in the forest.
See, now you can't tell which piece I just moved, right?
If there is no forest, you make your own.
Just like in Gilbert Keith's story
"The Sign of the Broken Sword", right?
Yeah, these are the words of a famous detective
said to be Sherlock Holmes' rival, Father Brown.
In the story, the trick was more violent and frightening, but your mother's trick is similar.
No, I think she did a much more devious thing.
"If you want to hide a leaf, hide it in the forest.
If there is no forest, you make your own."
I see, so that's why my mother...
That was probably after Kid stole it...
You know so much about Kid, Conan-kun.
That's because we're closely related.
What is it, Uncle?
Nothing, excuse me.
How troublesome, I got the wrong room.
Jeez, Papa, pay attention!
That man was clearly eavesdropping. Is he Kid?
No... I've seen that face somewhere...
Oh, Conan-kun!
Oh, Ran-neechan...
You went to the restroom and never came back.
You can't just running around like that.
We'll be in Osaka in ten minutes.
It seems like even the famous
Kaito Kid didn't accomplish his goal.
This time, the victory is mine.
Seems that way, doesn't it?
So, where is the jewel?
I'll tell you as soon as we get to Osaka.
Anyway, how about another glass? To victory.
I already...
Don't be that way.
Damn, where is it?
Where in the world is it?
Damn. If I don't hurry up, I'll run out of time.
Where did I see that man?
Damn, I can't remember!
That's strange... it hasn't changed in a while...
Usually the shape would...
That's it! I remember!
To victory!
Sorry for the wait.
Thank you.
I see, now I know...
where the jewel is hiding.
Thank you.
Where are you going?
Oh, to the restroom...
Have a save trip.
What a cute coaster!
It even has pressed flowers on it, and it smells nice.
Sorry, Aoko.
I can't become Kid in front of you.
He was on the Professor's computer!
Jackal
His name is Jackal.
The world-famous jewel thief.
And a brutal one...
It's a blackout!
Has Kid finally shown up?
Your Majesty!
Don't misunderstand! I was only protecting Her Majesty!
What?!
Which one is your glass?
Well...
All of you, divide them up and check each one.
Could you have hid the jewel in my glass?
How bold...
Here it is, I found it!
The Crystal Mother is safe!
It is a great honor to be deceived by you again, Your Majesty.
Kaito Kid? You fool, we're on a train.
There's nowhere for you to run.
Your Majesty, please remember:
Kaito Kid is like a ghost in your bedroom.
And do not forget that before you're a Queen, you are a mother with a heart.
Halt, Kid!
Damn it!
What are you all doing? After him!
Yes, sir!
It's emergency! Let us pass!
What have I done?
Because of me, the treasure of our country is now lost.
Phillip!
You're as naive as ever, Inspector.
Always falling for that dummy.
You're the naive one, onii-chan.
Give back the jewel.
Without it, the people of my country will be in trouble, so give it back!
But how did you know that I was here?
Conan-kun told me.
Conan? I see. So he's on this train, too?
And to get up here, that uncle helped me.
Uncle?
Yeah, he's behind me, the kind...
I've waited for this moment, Kaito Kid!
You're...
Sorry, but I don't have time to play with you.
Put the jewel down and turn around.
You don't want the kid to die, right?
Don't, onii-chan, don't give it back!
That voice... Phillip!
Oh no, it can't be!
Prince!
Your Majesty!
Don't try anything funny.
You're always given me a hard time...
Come on, turn around!
The immortal Kaito Kid...
...will meet his end here!
Well, I wonder about that.
Damn you! Don't underestimate me!
If this guy's the Jackal, then the other one...
Ah-le-le, lady.
Your socks are different!
They were white before,
when'd you change them?
Why you!
If you're going to disguise yourself,
then do it properly, Lady.
As I thought, he got out of here.
That means, Kid...
Conan-kun!
What are you doing? This is someone else's room!
Ran-neechan!
Well, it is him. He wouldn't die that easily.
Jeez.
Hey, are you alright?
Give back the jewel!
What for? And is that what you say to the one who saved your life?
Without it, the people of my country...
Nope! I'm not giving it back to a liar.
What?
You're doing this for your mom, right?
You want to return the jewel
so your mom will praise you, right?
Well?
Am I right?
Then there's an even better way to reveal your mom's feelings.
Phillip, Phillip...
Your Majesty!
Mother!
Phillip!
Forgive me mother, I chased after Kaito Kid
to retrieve the stone, but he got away.
M-Mother?
Why don't you ever listen to me?
Why do you always do dangerous things?
Why then did I become stricter,
trying to replace your father?
But... But... Thank goodness!
You're okay... thank goodness.
Mother...
You see, Prince,
Your mom's a genuinely grief stricken Queen of Heart.
Come on, boys don't cry.
And how many times do I have to tell you?
You are to call me Your Majesty.
As I thought.
Come on, let's go!
Oh, Kazuha-chan and the others are waiting for us at the gate!
Then we should hurry.
That jewel is the real thing.
So that Kid didn't manage to steal it.
Or is it...
Next time, I'll get to the Jewel of Destiny.