WEEKLY NEWS
The deceased is...
The editor-in-chief and president of the magazine "Weekly News"...
Ooshita Takeo (54)
Weekly News President & Editor-in-Chief
Ooshita Takeo-san, age 54.
The estimated time of death is yesterday at around 11:00 AM.
It's already been 24 hours now.
Stabbed in the back with a knife, huh?
Yes.
Judging from the bloodstains on the floor, the
arrangement of the items on the table...
As well as the direction of the TV set and the surroundings...
It would seem Ooshita-san was sitting on the sofa
at the time, eating pizza and watching TV.
Given that yesterday was a holiday, the office was closed.
As such, we can conclude it was someone who knew Ooshita-san
would come to work even on a holiday...
And could pay a visit to kill him.
And this "someone" you're referring to
is one of these four employees, right?
The first to discover the body was you, right?
Minamisawa Junbei (26)
Weekly NEWS Employee
Yes.
My name is Minamisawa Junbei.
This morning, you arrived here at work around
10:00 AM and found the body of the president.
At that time, was the door locked?
It was.
And the TV screen?
It wasn't on.
In other words...
After the culprit killed Ooshita-san...
They turned off the TV and locked the door from the outside.
Yes.
The culprit must have had the key to the room.
Speaking of which, Ooshita-san's key was left on his desk.
And the only ones with spare keys are these four.
I see.
Furthermore, each of these four have motives for killing Ooshita-san.
First is Higashida Naoya-san.
Higashida-san is in charge of editing the magazine.
He would argue with Ooshita-san several times a day.
The night of the incident, the other three employees saw both of them arguing feverishly with each other.
Higashida Naoya (32)
Weekly NEWS Employee
But I didn't do it.
I have nothing to gain from it.
Next, we have Nishizaki Eiko-san.
This magazine company was originally founded by her father.
But, after it was taken over by Ooshita-san...
Her father became depressed and died of an illness.
You could say the victim was an enemy that killed her father.
That's right.
I kept waiting for the opportunity to get my revenge.
But it wasn't me.
Nishizaki Eiko (30)
Weekly NEWS Employee
If it had been me, I'd have put him through much greater agony.
Maybe by poisoning him, for example.
The one who loves to gamble, Kitano Tsuyoshi-san...
Owed Ooshita-san a large sum of money...
And was being forced to return what he owed.
Should Ooshita-san have died, he'd be absolved of all his debts.
Well, I knew this was going to happen.
Kitano Tsuyoshi (28)
Weekly NEWS Employee
It wasn't too hard for me to predict.
Moreover, Minamisawa-san found evidence that supported
allegations of corruption that some politician was facing...
But the draft was rejected by Ooshita-san.
It seems that he and the politician in question had vested interests in one another.
It was really hard to get that evidence.
But still...
In other words, each of you has admitted to having a motive...
But not to doing the deed, correct?
What do you think, Mouri-kun?
Inspector...
I already know who the culprit is.
What'd you say?
Please look closely at Ooshita-san's body.
The way his finger is extended like that...
Reveals the killer's identity...
As his dying message.
That means the killer is...
Kitano Tsuyoshi-san...
It's you.
The evidence is...
Ooshita-san's finger pointing towards the north.
Detective Takagi...
The end of his finger seems to follow an Amidakuji pattern along the cracks between the floorboards.
Amidakuji is the practice of following vertical and
horizontal lines from a top point to a bottom one.
Let's see...
North Star Beer...
North Star?
Kitano-san is the culprit?
That's ridiculous.
How can you use a stupid game like that to call someone a killer?
I feel the same way.
Just before dying, being able to notice the case of North Star Beer...
Then being able to do the Amidakuji from there to where he was...
And putting his finger in the correct spot, is that even possible?
Besides, his finger is pointing in the north-east direction.
North-east?
In that case, Higashida-san must've been Kitano-san's accomplice.
What kind of joke is this?
Knock it off with those hack deductions!
Hack?
Really now.
The great detective seems a bit shocked to hear that.
No, no, but...
You're too naïve, Detective Mouri.
You can't solve a case with that kind of deduction.
Female high school detective...
Suzuki Sonoko, is here!
FEMALE HIGH SCHOOL DETECTIVE
SUZUKI SONOKO'S CASEBOOK
"Female high school detective, Suzuki Sonoko, is here!"
"At that instant, magnificent sound effects chime in while the spotlight is turned on."
"Then, our heroine Sonoko makes her grand entrance."
Sonoko-neesan is so cool!
It really does feel like a main character making her grand entrance.
I was actually gonna write "Deduction Queen Suzuki Sonoko is here!"
Say, say, neechan...
Is this supposed to be an essay?
Not at all!
This is a play script.
Our school's second-year students are raising
money for charity by putting on a play at a church.
I'm writing the script for it.
Didn't I already tell you that!?
Did you?
She did.
She also mentioned buying herself the roles of both director and the main character.
Hey...
Don't make it sound so sinister!
We decided it after talking it over.
Kind of...
Yes!
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes!
Yes, yes, yes!
I would!
I'd like to be the main character!
I'll even write the script and direct!
And so, that's how everyone decided on her.
I knew it'd be something like that.
But it does seem interesting.
So far, at least.
Right, right?
That's the main focus of the story.
The names of actual police officers and detectives will be included to make the story play out like reality.
Of course, we'll be the ones acting it out.
Speaking of which...
Doesn't it make my dad seem a little...
I mean...
It is true that, before he was "Sleeping Kogoro," he would act stupid, but...
Sorry, sorry.
I'm the starring character this time.
He won't be turning into Sleeping Kogoro this time, all right?
Of course not.
I'm not in it, after all.
But is it all right to have those three people up there?
I think using a murder plot for a church charity play may be a bit...
It's fine, it's fine.
There's nothing to worry about as long as it's funny.
Hey, hey...
Anyway, hurry and tell us the rest of the story!
Ayumi wants to hear the rest too!
Sonoko, what comes after that?
Nothing.
The script only goes up to there.
I can't think of what to write for the rest.
Then, who was Ooshita-san's finger pointing to?
I don't know.
Who's the culprit?
We'll make Higashida the murderer for now.
Anyway, I only focused on how to make my grand entrance.
I kinda pushed the rest aside.
That's just like you.
But there's only a week before the show starts!
That's right!
We still have to rehearse the lines, prepare costumes, set up the stage, and even the music's barely ready at this point.
With all of that in mind, we have to finish the script today!
Today?
Right.
That's why I was thinking I should get some pointers from a real detective, like your dad.
Like my dad?
But, I would be having him in a supporting role and I haven't discussed that with him yet.
Showing him the script all of a sudden
probably isn't the appropriate thing to do.
That's why I asked you to come along, to see what you had to say.
So...
Why are you guys here, anyway?
Why are you asking this now?
Forget it.
The problem is the true meaning behind the dying message.
Are you sure that's the only problem?
Firstly, something is wrong with the setting of your plot.
Why is Detective Mouri even at the scene of the crime?
Did Inspector Megure call for him?
Or, perhaps...
He was walking along the street, and all of a sudden saw a patrol car pass by?
The four suspects somehow have the directions east, west, south, and north in their names.
Well, they're not even real names, so I'll let that go.
How do you plan on showing the cracks
between the floorboards to the audience?
If they're forced to understand the lines without seeing the props...
It won't be nearly as interesting.
Those are all completely trivial!
I never even considered any of that!
Is that so?
But the biggest problem is...
Even if we can think of the true
meaning behind the dying message...
It will only serve as circumstantial evidence.
There would still be nothing physical there.
You should cancel the play while you still can.
Wouldn't singing a song be better?
She makes me sound stupid...
At any rate, let me call my dad first.
I won't mention that he's in the script, or else he'll
start spouting off all kinds of weird deductions.
He must have some good ideas.
It's abrupt to ask such a thing.
How do you expect me to think of that kinda stuff for you?
Just try your best.
Sonoko's feeling really down about it all.
Jeez...
I don't feel like dealing with that right now.
Oh, then how about this?
Beginning from the tip of his finger, the cracks in the floorboards follow an Amidakuji pattern.
Then, at the end of the pattern, there's a can of beer...
The brand of which is "North Star Beer."
Get it?
North Star...
The star is "north."
Therefore, Kitano is the culprit.
Thanks...
I'll pass that on...
Amazing!
It's exactly how Sonoko-san wrote it in the script!
A hack deduction!
Dad's not sleeping yet...
Saw that coming.
Then, why don't we ask Shin'ichi?
He's a second-year student at Teitan High School too.
He should help us out.
Going to the bathroom!
Understand?
You need to help too!
I get it...
But I'm a little busy right now.
I'll call you back.
See you.
What did Shin'ichi-niichan say?
He said he'll call me back later.
Seems he's busy right now.
Could it be that even Kudo-kun couldn't think of something?
That can't be it.
That's true.
Be quiet.
Then, for the time being...
Let's think while we wait for Shin'ichi-san's call.
I'm sure we can figure it out.
Yeah...
I have an idea!
You're too naïve, Uncle.
"sweet"
It won't do if you're as "sweet" as the sauce in the eel rice.
Who's there?
The leader of the Detective Boys...
Kojima Genta!
Isn't Ooshita-san pointing at something?
He's trying to say the number "one."
The number "one"?
The culprit, Higashida Ichirou...
Is you!
Wait right there!
You're talking nonsense.
Higashida's given name is Naoya!
Can't we call him Ichirou instead?
No is no.
In that case...
Ooshita-san wanted to say "1" in English...
Which is "one."
And "one" would be the sound a dog makes.
wan
Do any of you have a pet dog?
That's not what I mean!
Higashida-san is actually a dog!
My head hurts...
Then, how about this?
The reason Ooshita-san extended his finger...
Was to point out the presence of an alien!
Alien?
Higashida-san is actually an alien who just wants to make friends with earthlings.
When Ooshita-san found out, his heart was temporarily stopped.
Ooshita-san!
Are you all right?
Catch him!
This way!
Wait!
Excuse me...
What are you doing!?
Mitsuhiko-kun!
Wait!
Get on!
Conan-kun!
Conan!
What the...
Stop!
How can we perform something like this on stage!?
Not to mention that Uncle somehow disappeared...
It is quite interesting, but...
No way!
All rejected!
I'm hungry.
Then, let's all go to my place and order pizza.
Sonoko-neesan will buy it for you guys, right?
Huh?
Aren't you going to eat, Sonoko?
I don't feel like eating at all.
I still haven't figured out what the true meaning behind the dying message should be.
Even if I did, it's like this little brat said...
The lack of physical evidence hasn't been resolved yet.
That's true...
What do you think, Conan-kun?
You're pretty good at this sort of thing.
It's not quite the same as a real case...
Jeez, Genta-kun...
You should use a handkerchief!
The grease from the pizza is dripping everywhere.
Uh oh, Mom's gonna scold me now.
Found it.
I'm going to the bathroom.
Again?
So frequently...
But there's a bathroom just over there...
Three...
Two...
One...
It has to be Shin'ichi.
Caller Kudo Shin'ichi
You're too naïve, Detective Mouri.
You can't solve a case with that kind of deduction.
That voice is...
Shin'ichi!
Long time no see, Inspector Megure.
It's been far too long, Kudo-kun.
You're that famous high school detective?
Inspector Megure...
These blinds...
They were up when we arrived.
Takagi-kun was worried that someone in the building across the street would be able to see inside, so he lowered the blinds.
The time of death is estimated to be about 24 hours ago, right?
That's right.
In that case, Detective Takagi...
Would you please turn off the lights?
With this, you'll understand what it was the victim was pointing at.
Inspector Megure...
Ooshita-san's extended finger is pointing to this!
The word "NEWS"...
Can be used to represent North, East, West, and South.
E is for East, Higashi.
In other words...
Before his death, the victim used his finger to...
Point at the name that carries the word "higashi".
EAST
Higashida Naoya-san...
It's you!
When you stabbed Ooshita-san to death...
It was cloudy outside, so the sun couldn't shine through.
After you left...
The sun emerged from the clouds and cast a shadow of "Weekly News" on the floor.
At that time, Ooshita-san was still breathing.
When the inspector and the others arrived this morning...
The sun was obscured by the clouds, leaving us with no shadow.
That's why it wasn't noticed.
Do you have proof?
Proof that I killed the president?
Inspector Megure...
Please check Higashida-san's belt.
The victim's fingerprints should be on it.
What?
That's fine.
You can check if you'd like.
Oh, it's not the belt around his waist.
It's the belt on his watch.
Looks like you've remembered.
After you stabbed him in the back with a knife...
He stood up and grabbed your left arm with his right hand.
That's when he left his prints.
Prior to being killed...
He was sitting on the sofa eating pizza,
so his right hand was covered in grease.
Furthermore, Ooshita-san, didn't wear a watch...
So he instead grabbed the belt around his pants before he died...
Leaving behind a dying message.
May we examine your watch...
Higashida-san?
There's no need.
I couldn't forgive him.
We were both journalists by trade, but that man...
The president was so materialistic.
He said the only thing that mattered was that the magazine sold.
He didn't care about legal cases that didn't appeal to him.
The president even ordered us to
write fake reports a number of times.
There were quite a few times I didn't want to do it.
But I just couldn't let go...
I love it, this magazine...
Ever since the time her father was
the president, of Weekly News...
And that's why you killed Ooshita-san?
He often said he wanted this magazine to be number one, even if it was just once.
Maybe that dream can be realized.
It'll be up to this week's issue of "Weekly News."
However, the one to announce that will not be you.
It doesn't matter what your reasons were.
The moment you used your hand to
lift a knife and rather than a pen...
Was the moment you ceased being a professional journalist.
Right.
You are nothing more than a murderer!
It's been a while, Ran.
What, still trying to act cool?
Where have you been?
Sorry, I've been busy with cases.
You always say that!
You're just going to leave again...
No, I'm not going anywhere.
I promise you.
Really?
Uhm, excuse me, but...
Do we really need to continue this
story with Shin'ichi-kun and Ran?
It's not like that...
The deduction was impressive, though.
I hate to admit it, but that's Kudo-kun for you.
But, why did female high school detective Suzuki Sonoko...
Turn into high school detective Kudo Shin'ichi?
And it's not like Shin'ichi-niichan would make an appearance playing the violin or something.
What's wrong with that?
It makes him seem more like the main character.
Because I'm the main character.
What does "materialistic" mean?
It means that the most important thing in his life is money.
While it's true that money is important...
The most important thing is love.
Well, in any case, this should be fine.
Thanks, Ran.
Say hello to Kudo-kun for me.
Thank goodness.
Thank you!
But, Shin'ichi...
I wish you really were like that.
North-east?
In that case, Higashida-san must've been Kitano-san's accomplice.
What kind of joke is this?
Knock it off with those hack deductions!
Hack?
One week later —
the performance of the play.
Was it not a good deduction?
But...
Sonoko caught a cold and couldn't say a single word.
Her replacement...
You're too naïve, Dad.
Or should I say, Detective Mouri!
At the last minute, it was decided
that Ran would be the main character.
Female High School Detective
Ran's Casebook
Teitan High School
Stage Play for Charity
Because of that...
What was meant to be a clean surrender of the culprit...
Dang!
Turned into a quick action scene.
Dear Lord...
I knew this shouldn't have been held in a church.