So? How's the view from the Bell Tree Tower, built by the power of the Suzuki Financial Group?
It's amazing, Sonoko! Thanks for inviting us!
You lot should show some appreciation too!
This opening ceremony is supposed to be strictly for those who helped build the tower!
Yeah!
It's the best!
Thank you!
You can sure talk. You're the one who asked us if we wanted to come in the first place!
Hey! Is it time to leave yet?
Why would we be leaving, Dad? We just got here!
How'd I end up being dragged this high up again?!
Dad, come over here with us! The view's great!
Hmph! Don't be stupid! I'm leaving!
Geez...
Besides, haven't you heard that saying? "Only fools and so on like high places"!
But the truth is that you're scared, right?
D-Don't be stupid! B-Being up
this high d-doesn't bother me at all!
Then you wouldn't be scared at all if you looked at the floor, right?
Huh? The floor?
There's no floor!
I'm scared! I'm scared! I'm scared!
Hold on, Dad!
I'm scared of high places!
Excuse me!
That lift goes to—
This lift goes to the special observation deck. Please enjoy the view from a height of 460 metres...
Get me down!
Oh, Dad...
I'm sorry about this, Sonoko.
Don't worry. This is normal for him, isn't it?
What's he doing?
Now let's enjoy the great view from the Bell Tree!
Hey, Sonoko, what's that building?
Oh, that small thing is the Asakusa Sky Court.
No connection to the Suzuki Financial Group.
Even after it's finished, it'll probably only come up to this first observation deck at the most.
That's a win for the Bell Tree then.
Of course!
Hey, have a look at that river! It's got so many bridges!
Yeah, that's Sumida River.
The blue one over there is Komagata Bridge.
The red one is Azuma Bridge.
And that railway bridge right ahead of us is the Tohto Bell Tree Line.
Oh! There's a train!
It's so cool!
Huh? It's stopping on the bridge...
It's just slowing down. Asakusa Station is right on the other side of the bridge, after all.
That's it!
How about we make a miniature model of the Tohto Bell Tree Tower and its surroundings for our summer homework project?
Oh, that's a great idea!
It sounds fun! Conan-kun,
Ai-chan, let's all work together!
Hey, that sounds like a lot of hard wo—
We'd be happy to.
Yay!
Then it's decided!
Let's make an awesome model!
I guess it's a good thing we came here.
Let's all take lots of photos!
I'll take some videos.
I'll read up about the Bell Tree.
Sure! Go ahead!
But I wonder if a certain somebody will be fine not doing any summer homework.
I'll use these binoculars to decide how wide an area we should make for our model!
Leave me alone.
There! The yellow building.
Oh, wow! It's amazing!
Oh, I see it. What a lovely building.
This building was built 30 years ago.
And now, with the completion of the Bell Tree Tower, the view alone is worth four stars.
It is definitely a five star property.
Wow!
Built 30 years ago, isn't that a bit old?
Darling, I think this may be our lucky day!
I absolutely love this house!
I think so too, this property is...
What is it?
No, it's nothing...
It's a sniper! Everybody get down!
You're too heavy...
Everyone, please stay calm!
Damn, everyone's panicking!
So it really was from there.
Where's Ran?
All right!
Doc! Give me your car keys!
My car keys?
I'm gonna go get my skateboard.
Doc, you're too heavy...
Oh, wait!
Everyone, please stay calm!
Conan-kun...
I'm Shin'ichi Kudo, a high school detective.
While at an amusement park with my childhood friend and classmate, Ran Mouri,
I witnessed a suspicious deal involving a man in black.
Since I was so focused on watching the deal, I didn't realize his partner was sneaking up from behind me.
He forced me to consume poison, and when I came to...
...my body had shrunk!
If those men learnt that Shin'ichi Kudo was still alive,
they'd come back to finish me off, endangering everyone around me.
At Dr. Agasa's suggestion, I hid my identity,
and when Ran asked my name,
I blurted out "Conan Edogawa".
To find out more about those guys, I ended up living with Ran and her detective father.
The enigmatic Black Organisation...
I'm not the only one who's secretly working to find out their identity.
The Federal Bureau of Investigation —
the FBI.
James Black, André Camel, Jodie Starling...
And Shuuichi Akai.
He was the sharpest agent at the FBI, and an expert marksman, but then a CIA agent that had infiltrated the organization went and...
And also, some new characters.
Masumi Sera. She transferred into the same class as Ran and I, and calls herself a detective.
And finally, Subaru Okiya. An engineering post-graduate university student, who is living in my empty house.
But his identity is really...
My body shrunk, but my mind didn't!
I'm still an undefeated great detective!
There's always only one truth!
Sniping someone that accurately from so far away... Don't tell me that they're behind it?!
I have to know for sure!
I think this was the way to that building...
Oh no!
What?
A boy fell in!
This goes right next to the building!
There it is! All right!
He couldn't have gone too far...
To escape without getting caught in traffic, he'd need to walk or go by bike.
Could that be him?
That size and thickness...
It must be! That's a rifle bag!
Haibara, can you hear me?
Damn, this piece of junk!
Haibara! Haibara! Answer me, Haibara!
What is it? I'm getting a lot of static, where are you?
I'm chasing what I think is the sniper's bike!
Doctor! Call the police!
Huh? Right...
The number plate's "Shinjuku Se 3317"! He's heading north on Mitsumedōri!
He turned left!
Damn, you're not getting away!
What is it? Edogawa-kun, are you okay?
Yeah, I'm just crossing Kototoi Bridge over the Sumida—
Damn, was that the badge's limit?!
Oh no! I'm in a blind spot!
Where is he?!
Heading the wrong way up a one-way street? It couldn't be!
Look out!
This is like Yaiba!
Damn, did he notice me after all?!
What the hell are you—
I mean, what are you doing here, Sera-neechan?
I'll explain later! Let's go!
The number plate of the suspect's bike is "Shinjuku Se 3317".
According to the latest report, he has crossed Kototoi Bridge, and is heading south along Sumida River.
All cars currently on patrol nearby, head to the scene immediately! Arrest him!
What? You were at the Bell Tree?
I was following the man that was shot. As a detective.
Then you were there when it happened, weren't you?
Yeah. I never thought he'd be murdered.
I see him! Hold on tight!
Right!
He's turned left off National Route 6 and headed onto Kuramae Bridge! Block him in from both sides!
Roger. All sealed off here.
Damn! Hold on, we're going after him!
No, provoking him further is too dangerous.
Don't worry. I'll know where he's headed soon enough.
He stopped.
He might have another getaway vehicle there.
This is bad... Let's hurry!
Yeah. But be careful!
I know! We're just going to check!
...fleeing on a bike with the number plate Shinjuku Se 3317, currently headed south along the Sumida River...
It appears he headed this way.
Right.
That bike!
Yeah. That's it.
So he went on foot from here...
Damn...
Sera!
Hey, Sera!
Agent Camel!
You're mine!
Bring it on!
Ouch...
Are you okay, Sera-neechan?
Y-Yeah...
If I didn't have this, I'd be dead for sure...
Looks like neither of you are hurt.
Never mind that, are you okay, Agent Camel?
No problem.
I was wearing this.
I see.
But about Jodie-san's gun...
Keep it a secret, right?
It's no use. He got away.
It can't be helped. Let's leave the rest to the Japanese police.
I'll tell them to search the cliffs near the bay right away.
Right.
Well, it's going to be hard to arrest him.
The sea's like a garden for the SEALs.
SEALs?
Have a look at this.
From the photos we have obtained and his sniping technique, we believe the sniper to be this person.
Timothy Hunter, 37...
A former sniper in the Navy's Special Ops squad "Navy SEALs", who fought in the war in the Middle East for three years from 2003.
He's a war hero who accomplished many great deeds.
So why would a hero do this?
We believe the reason to be this, the Silver Star.
The Silver Star?
It's a medal of honor awarded to soldiers who have shown gallantry in action against an enemy of the United States.
Hunter was awarded this medal of heroism in 2005,
but the next year, he was stripped of it on suspicion of violating the Rules of Engagement.
Stripped of it?
Yes. An Army officer put in a complaint saying that he shot an unarmed civilian.
Of course, Hunter denied it, and the case didn't go to court due to lack of evidence,
but that one case took him from being called the "Battlefield Hero" to the "Suspected Hero".
And perhaps due to being stripped of his Silver Star,
when he returned to the war zone, Hunter had lost his usual calm, and alone on the battlefield...
...took an enemy bullet to his head.
Oh no...
Then what happened to Hunter?
Luckily, the surgery was successful, and his life was saved.
But he was discharged due to his wounds.
He returned to America, but his misfortune didn't end there.
Seeking a peaceful life back in America, he moved to the countryside of Seattle, Washington,
but his terrible memories of the warzone never left him, and have pained him ever since.
But his misfortune still wasn't satisfied, and extended to his wife and sister living with him.
He was bankrupted by a flawed investment.
His sister committed suicide due to being abandoned by her fiancé, and his wife died from taking an overdose.
Hunter lost his honor, his fortune and his beloved family one after another.
Then we have no knowledge of his whereabouts for the next six years.
Why is he a suspect in this murder?
Because of what happened three weeks ago.
Brian Woods, a reporter for a local newspaper in Seattle, was sniped with a rifle and died.
When the police investigated that victim,
they found that he'd been hounding Hunter and his wife while writing a series of articles on the 'Suspected Hero',
and had driven them both to have mental breakdowns.
Because of that, the police and FBI investigated Hunter as a suspect, and found he entered Japan two weeks ago.
And so, since we were on holiday in Japan,
FBI HQ contacted us and ordered us to arrest him.
I see. And that brings us up to now.
Yes. By the way, what about
Hunter's whereabouts since then?
We've been searching the bay, but we haven't found any real clues yet...
That's no surprise.
As you know, the the 'SEAL' in SEALs was taken from 'sea', 'air', and 'land', and swimming is supposed to be one of their talents.
Another of which is sniping with a rifle.
As for the sniping, we discovered some strange items from the roof of the building suspected to be the sniping position.
Strange items?
Chiba-kun.
Right.
In the space for the window cleaning rails on the side facing the Bell Tree Tower,
we found a die and a 51 mm bullet shell.
The shell has the same caliber as the 7.62 mm bullet used in the crime.
It also matches the NATO bullets used by the MK11, Hunter's favorite rifle.
Then it was him...?
About this die... Was there a die left with the shell at the sniping position in the Seattle case as well?
No, I haven't heard about anything like a die being found there, but there is a connection between Hunter and dice.
Hunter loved playing dice games, and has a tattoo of dice here on his left arm.
I-I see.
It's a tenuous connection, but it means Hunter could be trying to leave some sort of message with this die.
Yes. And the greatest piece of evidence that Hunter was behind this lies with the victim.
You mean that Hunter had a definite motive for murdering Fujinami-san?
Yes.
Seven years ago, Hiroaki Fujinami sold Hunter substandard Japanese property, and is responsible for bankrupting him.
What?!
Then that's why...?
That means Hunter's the culprit for sure.
Speaking of Fujinami-san, why
was Sera-neechan tailing him?
That's right...
Why were you tailing Fujinami-san?
A relative of a classmate of mine was thinking about marrying Fujinami,
but she thought he was involved in something fishy, so she asked me to conduct a background check on him.
And during my investigation I found out about Fujinami swindling good-natured foreigners
You doing a background check?! Some nerve...
by selling them substandard Japanese property.
Right, even back then...
Well, it's awful that he was murdered,
but it's good in the sense that the relative isn't interested in getting remarried anymore.
Oh, that's right. From what you've said, I doubt this will be the end of Hunter's crime spree.
Yes, you're right.
Is there anyone else that Hunter might want dead?
Jodie-kun, the photos.
Right.
The FBI believe there are at
least three people he may be after.
T-Three people?!
Yes. We believe he is likely to
try and murder these three people.
Jack Waltz, 45. He's the former Army captain who reported that Hunter violated the Rules of Engagement.
He currently runs a factory making military equipment in San Diego.
Next, Bill Murphy, 35.
He's a former Army sergeant who worked under Waltz, and was a witness to Hunter's violation of the Rules of Engagement.
After being discharged, he joined
Waltz's company as a secretary.
I guess he can't murder them if they're in San Diego.
No, they're both currently in Japan.
What?!
Waltz arrived in Kyōto with his family two days ago, and Murphy's staying in Nikkō.
Kyōto and...
Nikkō, huh?
Yes. They're planned to be in
the country for another eight days.
And finally...
Hitoshi Moriyama, 34. He is the ex-fiancé who was reponsible for the sister's suicide.
Moriyama lived in Seattle, and worked at a trading company, but retired four years ago, and we don't know where he is now.
So two out of the three are in Japan...
He's going to target them for sure!
Right. Alert the Kyōto and Tochigi Police immediately.
Okay! Put out an urgent warrant looking for Timothy Hunter as a key person in this case!
Right.
Right!
A former SEALs sniper... Looks like quite a shocking guy has turned up in Japan.
Yeah. And why did he have to choose Japan as the site of his revenge...
But at least I found out that they don't seem to be involved...
Still, I wonder why that Hunter guy decided to seek revenge now, six years later?
Right...
I see what you mean.
It just happened to be now, that's all.
Still, you better stop playing your detective games! You almost died out there!
And brat!
You better not go wandering off either!
Okay!
Honestly...
Sera-san, I am glad that you weren't hurt...
But please don't put Conan-kun...
Don't put Conan-kun in danger again, okay?
Ran...
Don't worry! I'll make sure to protect Conan-kun.
Not to mention, there's no bullet that can shoot through Conan-kun's heart right now.
Or your heart either, of course!
Huh?
Bye! My bike's over this way.
See you later, Conan-kun!
Unbelievable. Doesn't she realize what almost happened?
I wonder why she said no bullet can shoot through my heart?
Oh, maybe because you can flick them away with karate, Ran?
Of course I can't!
No, Ran might just be able to...
What's wrong with you guys? I thought you'd be happier, with fireworks and all.
Isn't it obvious? We watched someone being murdered!
Well, I guess...
And that's not all!
Huh?
They took all the photos we took!
And all of our cameras!
They're just holding onto them. They'll give them back soon.
They might have something
useful to the case, you never know.
Oh, it went out...
Oh, mine did too.
Mine too.
And that's the end of that.
How about it, was that a nice diversion?
It wasn't enough!
It felt like something was missing...
You should've bought some more fireworks!
I thought you'd say that, so I got this ready!
A Ball-Shooting Belt?
This one's upgraded!
Kick it as high as you can!
I know, just hurry up and do it.
Okay, let's set the timer...
Here goes!
Wow! It's really high!
Okay! That'll do!
Wow, that's great! Good work, doc!
It's wonderful!
I call them Firework Balls!
The neighbors are going to complain about this, you know?
That might be a problem! What now, Ai-kun?!
Geez...
Must be great to be Conan-kun.
You're so mean, doc!
Don't you have anything for the rest of us?
Well, you've got me there...
Morning already?
That Hitoshi Moriyama... I was sure I'd seen him in something like a newspaper article!
Maybe I confused him with someone else.
This is a list from FBI HQ, of the people Hunter is most likely to contact.
Right...
We've split into three teams to question them, but could you go over what the FBI knows about them once again?
Of course.
First, Scott Green.
A former Navy chief petty officer who now runs a bicycle store in Machida to enjoy himself while earning money.
When in the SEALs, he taught at the sniper school, and Hunter was one of his students.
Next, Kevin Yoshino.
A former Marine Corps staff sergeant who now runs a military shop in Fussa.
He uses his special connections to buy up former US military equipment for his shop.
And finally, Mark Spencer.
He wasn't on the list you read out yesterday.
Right.
Hunter has no direct connection to him, but he's an ex-admiral who former US military soldiers in Japan often contact for advice.
Since Hunter doesn't have a wide circle of friends, it's possible that he might be in contact with him.
I see...
He must've obtained his rifle and equipment from somewhere, so one of them might be helping him.
Right.
Tim—
I mean, Hunter-san, wanted for sniping someone?!
Well, we can't be completely sure yet...
Apparently Hunter-san saved your life during the war in the Middle East?
Yeah. I'd be dead if he hadn't been there.
What if your rescuer came asking for your aid?
For example, for an MK11, the gun used in the sniping?
I don't even have one to give him!
You think that's the real thing?
You can buy it if you really want to check.
You met Hunter?
Yeah, he said he'd just arrived in Japan.
Where is he now?
Sorry, but I wouldn't know.
The sniper fled by bike.
It was a recently repaired second-hand bike with a fake number plate.
You trying to say I helped him?
Sorry to disappoint you, but I only sell new bikes.
How do you feel about Hunter-san's violation of the Rules of Engagement?
I can't reject the facts.
Overeager to protect his comrades, he misjudged and shot a defenseless civilian.
You're wrong! Hunter-san would never have done that! He was framed!
Framed?
That Waltz guy was jealous of Hunter-san, his replacement.
So Jack Waltz was a sniper too?
So he stole away Hunter-san's Silver Star...
...and even...
You think there was no violation, then?
Yeah, of course.
Hunter-san was a hero, he saved the lives of lots of soldiers out there...
And if he did come and ask for my help...
I'd gladly help him.
I wouldn't know.
I've never met Hunter, and
haven't heard anything about him.
Is that right...
Then how do you feel about Hunter-san's violation of the Rules of Engagement?
It doesn't matter whether it happened or not.
If Hunter was behind this sniping, then I can never forgive him, on my pride as a fellow former Marine.
Shoot him dead the moment you find him.
S-Shoot him...?
Your police snipers don't have a hope of beating him. Why don't I lend you my chauffeur?
Carlos!
Sir.
Carlos Lee. A former Marine sniper.
He picked up 36 kills in the Middle East.
That's just counting confirmed kills. If you include the unconfirmed ones, it's 78 kills in all.
Oh, right.
Well, even so, it doesn't match up to Hunter's 79 kills.
But only a sniper can beat a sniper.
So how about it, do you want him?
If he wasn't in any of the newspapers, then he must've been in a girls' magazine.
But this is going to be a big job...
Okay, let's spread out the map on the table.
Right!
First, we should decide how
big a range we want to include.
Oh, I see you're jumping straight into your homework!
Of course!
That's wonderful! And wonderful kids deserve a reward.
What is it? What is it?
You're giving us Firework Belts too?!
Well, no, they'll annoy the neighbours.
So I've got something more practical for you.
Huh? Detective Badges?
They've been upgraded.
I made some improvements, and now they've got better reception.
It seems someone called them 'pieces of junk', and really hurt his feelings.
What, you could hear that?
They look the same as before...
The reception's the only change?
That's so boring...
That's not all that's different!
If you change the setting, and then press the button to talk...
Ah! They lit up!
LED lamps, right?
Wow, they're cooler than before!
Yeah!
You can even choose the colour,
and which badges to light up!
Wow! That's great!
But they're making a weird noise, aren't they?
Huh?!
Ah!
I can't hear a thing...
What? You can't hear it, doc?
That's mosquito noise.
High-frequency noises get harder to hear when you get older, so adults can't hear it.
I guess it must be an accidental side-effect of the improvements I made...
I'll fix them later.
Aren't they're fine like this? Who knows, the mosquito noise might come in handy.
But I guess this means they're faulty...
That's so lame!
And I was just getting excited about them...
All right! Then how about an exciting quiz!
What?
Another one?
It'll just be another pun...
It won't hurt to hear him out, right?
R-Right!
Well, if you say so, Ai-chan...
Only for you, Haibara-san...
Oh well...
All right! Then here goes!
A sniper looking for vinegar challenges you to rock-paper-scissors. What should you play to beat him?
The English word 'sniper' is a hint!
What's a sniper?
English, huh...?
Did you work it out, Conan-kun?
Y-Yeah. But you won't like the answer.
I don't know English!
We give up.
What's the answer?!
The answer is scissors!
su nai kaa?
sunaipaa
You're up against a sniper, who's asking "Got any vinegar?", so scissors would beat him in rock-paper-scissors!
"Got any vinegar"?!
So it's "kaa" and "paa"?
paa
And so you're saying scissors would win because he'd pick paper?
"Got any vinegar"?
Well, since he's a sni—
Ahem.
Huh?
Which of these three sports are snipers best at?
1. Baseball.
2. Football.
3. Golf.
W-Well, it's...
The answer is number three.
naisu paa
sunaipaa
If you rearrange the word "sniper", it makes "nice par".
SUNAIPAA
NAISU PAA
Amazing, Ai-chan!
That was great, Haibara-san!
Nice par?
I guess Haibara can do the quizzes from now on.
T-Then all my clever wordplay counts for nothing?!
Hey, let's forget about him and go do our homework!
Right.
Let's do it!
I should've done my homework...
Oh, you lost your phone, right?
Apparently the police were in contact about it.
Oh, doc...
Surely that's more important than a quiz.
Also, about Masumi Sera...
Be careful. She's dangerous.
You're one to talk.
Huh? Conan-kun?
Huh?
He's going to pick up his lost phone.
Let's start without him.
Thank you for your patronage. Beika Library is about to close. Please return any books you are reading to their shelves.
How weird... Maybe I really did
confuse him for someone else.
Oh! Bingo!
Hitoshi and Nami Yasuhara
Hitoshi Yasuhara.
Huh? Not Moriyama?
He started a private import service four years ago...
His wife is a charismatic cooking expert.
She runs cookery classes in Honjo, Sumida City...
Excuse me... We're about to close.
Oh, right. I'll tidy up in just a moment.
Sorry for the trouble.
"Hitoshi Yasuhara-san chose to take his wife, Nami-san's surname when getting married."
I get it! His name changed
because he took his wife's name!
We should be chasing after that Organization, but now we've ended up involved in this tough case...
Yes.
Still, we're outclassed. To think we're facing a former SEALs sniper...
If only Akai-san was here...
I'm sorry...
It's fine. I was thinking the same thing.
Shuu, there's something I'd like to ask. Who has the best sniping technique —
police shooters or military snipers?
It depends on the conditions.
Huh?
If the range is less than 100 meters, then police shooters. They are trained to be more precise with their shots.
Really?
Yeah...
Police shooters are usually called in when hostages are involved.
They need to have extremely accurate aim, to be able to stop the target from moving in an instant.
There's only one spot where you can kill someone with a single bullet, and cut off all possible convulsions.
The brain stem...
Right.
If you hit anywhere else, for example, even if you shoot through their heart,
targets can keep fighting for anywhere up to ten seconds.
And so there's the danger that they'll take their hostages, and even other police officers with them to the grave.
But where should you aim?
Face the target head on, and aim for the tip of their nose. How about it, think you can do it?
Don't worry. As long as I'm around, you'll never have to do something like that.
I promise.
Shuu...
Thank you!
Be careful not to lose it again, okay?
Right!
Conan-kun?! What have you been doing?!
Oh, I lost my phone.
So that's why you weren't answering...
Sorry. But did something happen?
Yeah. I found who I think is Hitoshi Moriyama.
I'm about to go and meet him to find ou—
Wait! I'll come too!
But where are you right now?
Outside the Azuma Bridge Police Box in Honjo, Sumida City.
That's a surprise. I'm in Honjo too.
What? Really?
Yeah.
It seems fate wants us to solve this case.
Yeah. Just turn left.
You got here quick, Conan-kun.
Yeah. Have you spotted any signs of movement?
Don't worry, nothing yet.
Okay, ready to go in?
Yeah.
A vehicle is about to leave. Please be careful.
Oh, no!
Oh, crap! Run, Conan-kun!
N-No...
There's two places that shot could've come from. Which do you think it was?
I bet it was the higher one. What do you think?
Yeah. I was thinking it was the taller one too.
If you connect the bullet holes in the windscreen and Moriyama-san with a straight line,
the closer, shorter building looks
like it was the sniping position...
But Moriyama-san's car was still halfway in his underground garage when he was shot.
Which means you have to add in the angle of the slope to calculate the real angle of the shot.
And there's only one tall building in line with the shot!
This is it, right?
Wait, Conan-kun! You can't just go in there alone!
Damn!
Excuse me! You need to be signed in!
Damn, he's so reckless!
And Hunter could still be here too!
A three? Don't tell me...
Conan-kun!
Hey, look at this...
Then he really did snipe from here...
Yeah.
Police HQ
So Moriyama-san was back in Japan too...
Yes. We were careless...
With these two being murdered, I think we can conclude that Hunter is the sniper for sure.
Right. The bullets were even 7.62 mm caliber, matching Hunter's favorite gun, the MK11.
Also, the scenes of the snipings themselves tell us that Hunter was behind them.
What do you mean?
Akahoshi-kun, if you would explain...
Right.
Fujinami-san always invited his marks out to visit high places, to make their property viewings into a deluxe show.
He probably tricked Hunter in the same way.
You mean that's why he chose to snipe Fujinami-san during a property viewing?
Yes.
According to an estate agent he worked with, Fujinami-san bought up lots of pre-opening tickets to the Bell Tree Tower
through a backroom deal, and was showing off properties from that spot almost every day.
And Moriyama-san broke off his engagement with Hunter's sister, and married another woman.
That's probably why he picked the home of his love to be his murder scene.
Moriyama-san went to meet his wife at her cookery classes at the same time every day.
We believe that's what Hunter was aiming for.
But on the days of both snipings, doors and cameras had been shot through with a gun to let him through.
He must've visited again and again to check beforehand and gather information.
His snipings were carefully thought-out and meticulously planned —
exactly what you'd expect from a SEALs sniper.
Yes.
Speaking of careful plans, did he leave a shell and a die at this sniping too?
Oh, yes. Right at the sniping position. Here's a photo.
This time, the die shows a three...?
Last time it was a four, wasn't it?
Could this be... a countdown?
I see...
That means Hunter has four targets in Japan in total.
He killed Hiroaki Fujinami-san
and Hitoshi Moriyama-san already,
and is planning to murder two more people, leaving dice showing the numbers two and one where he snipes them.
This is terrible...
If this theory's right, then the other two victims will be...
Yes. He's sure to go after Jack Waltz-san and Bill Murphy-san.
Speaking of those two...
The local police forces have told each of them about the snipings, and they've changed their sightseeing schedules.
Originally, they intended to meet in Tokyo in two days,
but now they've both decided to stay in their hotels until the case is dealt with.
Waltz-san's family wanted to head straight back to America immediately,
but there's a chance that Hunter may have anticipated and planned for that, so they're stuck at their hotel for now.
That may be the best choice...
Right...
With the local police on alert, he won't be able to get to them easily,
and with strict checks set up around Kyōto and Nikkō,
it won't be easy for Hunter to enter either city anymore.
Still, that doesn't give us leave to sit idly by.
It's likely that Hunter is still in Tokyo! We have to find him, no matter what!
Right!
What is it, Conan-kun?
Yeah. Right...
What?! Hunter was shot dead?!
They still haven't confirmed his identity, but I doubt it could be anyone else.
Early this morning, an American man was shot dead in an abandoned building in Azuma Bridge first district, Sumida City, Tokyo.
Right. I'll let you know when I know more.
He is believed to be Timothy Hunter.
We found a diary in Hunter's hideout, and after translating it, we were shocked by what he had written.
Here's a photo of it.
"August 3rd. He is challenging me, stealing my prey again."
"He obviously wants a piece of me."
"I have to find a way to kill him and get the last two targets myself."
From this, we can understand that someone else killed Fujinami-san and Moriyama-san before Hunter had a chance to.
Then, the real sniper challenged Hunter to a direct contest, and won...
If so, then that means the man
we saw wasn't Hunter either...
We believe his sniper shot from a floating platform in Sumida River facing the hideout,
and found a shell and a die showing the number two there.
One thing was different this time.
Despite having the closest range of any of the snipings at only 150 meters,
there was a bullet embedded into Hunter's door which we believe to be a missed shot.
There was also a bullet mark on the floating platform which we think was a missed shot,
and forensics are searching the area for anything else.
We told the media not to mention
the shells and the dice, right?
And so to find them at this sniping position means that all three snipings, including Hunter's, were likely by the same man.
And there was no shell or die at the first sniping position in Seattle to begin with...
Perhaps Hunter was responsible only for the sniping of Mr Brian Woods?
Right. That would explain it.
And if that explanation is right, we need to pay attention to the numbers on the dice.
Four, three, two, and then... Next would be one?
Then there's going to be another sniping?!
Yes. But we have no way to stop it.
I see...
The reasons we expected Jack Waltz-san and Bill Murphy-san to be targeted no longer apply.
Yes. And now we have absolutely no idea who will be the next target.
The worst possible development...
Early this morning, a third sniping occurred in an abandoned building in Azuma Bridge first district, Sumida City, Tokyo.
The victim is thought to be Timothy Hunter-san, 37,
an American and former US SEALs sniper who the police believed to be behind the recent sniping spree.
The police haven't given out any details yet, but shouldn't we consider this sniping to be by the same sniper as the last two?
Huh? But that means...
That this won't be the end of the sniping spree.
And we don't know who'll be the sniper's next target.
What?! Then it's an utterly random killing spree?!
Oh, I wouldn't go quite that far. But if they don't catch the sniper soon, people will be scared to go outside.
Did you hear? It's a random killing spree! Scary!
There's tons of helicopters flying around Sumida River!
Is it dangerous to be in Shitamachi?!
No, I heard Shibuya was next.
Really?! I better take the underground...
That's right, I heard Harajuku's dangerous!
It's all fake, don't let this rubbish fool you! Idiots!
Not a soul in Takeshita Street! What a sight!
There's never been anything like this before, has there?
Asakusa's gotta be the key. Apparently children are banned from going outside there.
You an idiot? All the previous victims were adults!
There ain't even any old folks visiting the temples... What's going on?
The Bell Tree Tower was where the first one took place, and it's still being repaired, right?
By the way, apparently you could see the Bell Tree from where the other snipings happened!
You could see the Bell Tree, that's right!
Does that mean the Bell Tree's the key to this case?!
That means it doesn't matter how far you are, if you can still see the Bell Tree!
Umbrellas! You can't be seen from above with an umbrella, so you'll be safe!
That was awesome!
In all, five people were wounded, several with severe injuries. And that ends our report from the scene at Kinshi Town.
Looks like all of Tokyo's in a panic...
Word of an 'utterly random killing spree' spreads quickly...
Well, it's no surprise. This is the first time there's ever been a sniping spree in Japan.
Here.
Thanks, Ran-chan.
Thanks for the tea.
So, any idea who the sniper is?
Well...
To be honest, Hunter's death
threw our investigation into chaos.
So we came to ask if you had any ideas, Mouri-san...
I see...
Come on, asking that old man ain't gonna help you...
Well, let's see...
First, we can be sure that the sniper was connected with Hunter somehow.
Right.
And the only people in Japan that
knew Hunter were Scott Green,
his former teacher at sniping school, and originally a SEALs sniper himself...
...and the ex-Marine, Kevin Yoshino.
To tell you the truth, both of them vanished last night...
What?
But neither of them had a motive for murdering Hunter.
Then what about his murder...?
We suspect it's a third party who we haven't found yet.
No, there's one person you're forgetting!
The former admiral of Yokosuka Base, the retired Rear Admiral, Mark Spencer...
What?
But—
His chauffeur. The ex-Marine sniper, Carlos Lee!
But neither Spencer-san nor Lee-san
are connected with Hunter...
Right! To begin with, what motive would he have?
His motive is his pride as a sniper!
Pride?
Yeah.
Hunter managed 79 kills on the front line. How about Lee?
U-Uhh... 36 kills in the Middle East.
That's just the confirmed ones.
If you add in the unconfirmed ones...
U-Uhh, right...
I think it was 78 kills.
Right!
And Lee couldn't bear it. He thought his skills as a sniper were the best. Then, he heard Hunter killed Woods in Seattle.
Hunter got his 80th kill. So Lee decided to anticipate his next move...
And killed Fujinami-san and Moriyama-san!
That makes it 80 versus 80. Lee finally managed to catch up with Hunter, so he decided to challenge Hunter to a final contest.
Bang!
Got it! We'll look into it!
R-Right...
Thank you so much!
Thank you!
That was amazing, Dad!
It was an odd deduction, but it makes sense.
Well, whether the old man's theory is right or not, I need more information.
New information, huh...
That's right, the size of the bullet retrieved from Hunter's corpse was 5.56 × 45 mm.
It's lighter than the previous bullets, and didn't go all the way through his head.
Huh? It was a different type of bullet?
Yes. The wounds on the corpse were so light that despite having been shot in the head, we immediately knew it was Hunter.
He used another gun's bullets because of the closer range?
Right. They'd have less recoil, and be more accurate.
And yet he missed a shot...
That is strange...
Have you found out anything else?
There is one thing that bugged me.
When I saw Hunter's body at the university hospital, he seemed to have lost a lot of weight.
He lost weight?
Yes. He looked like a different man to when he was awarded the Silver Star...
I think you better do a clinical autopsy as well as the forensic autopsy.
Also, do an X-ray of his skull.
Got it. I'll go and talk to Inspector Megure.
Okay, I'll talk to you later.
Conan-kun!
Where are you going? It's dangerous
outside, so don't go too far.
Sure, don't worry. I'm just going to get my skateboard back from Dr. Agasa.
Oh, wait, Conan-kun!
Yeah, I heard. But who'd want to kill Hunter?
Yeah, I have no idea...
Well, at least I don't have to worry about Hunter coming after me anymore.
Remind me to thank his killer...
Right. But we still better be careful.
Yeah, as always...
Setting aside the shooting in Japan, the fact that Brian Woods has been killed means we're also still in danger!
You always did worry too much...
Even if I was just following your orders, I still regret what I did on the battlefield back then...
What're you going on about now?!
You lead a life of luxury precisely because you followed my orders, and took the Silver Star from Hunter! Don't forget it!
Y-Yes, sure. I-I'm sorry...
Ah, forget it. Look. My family is going back to the US as soon as we get tickets.
The Japanese police are useless. You'd better get out of here, too. Get on home, and quick.
Yes, sir...
I'll see you stateside.
Mr Murphy?
I'm at the front reception.
We have a special delivery for you.
Oh, right. Thank you.
From Yokosuka Base?
But who...?
"I know everything you did in the Middle East"?!
What?!
God...
"I don't want to cause a stir. But we need to look into Hunter's breach of Rule of Engagement"?!
"Your ticket is enclosed. Come to Tokyo or face court-martial"?!
"Do not tell Waltz, and destroy this message immediately."
M-M-Mark Spencer?!
Nikkō → Asakusa
Oh, Christ...
It's really strange... It's the closest-range sniping yet, but they both missed once.
Yeah...
Maybe they were both nervous about facing another sniper.
I'm concerned about all the snipings being near Asakusa too.
Right...
Maybe there's some other special meaning behind the dice, ranges and lines of fire...
Oh!
What is it, Jodie-sensei?
We did that clinical autopsy of Hunter, like you suggested.
There were a lot of painkillers in his stomach, really strong ones.
Painkillers?
And we found out why when we did an MRI of his skull.
There was a bullet shard embedded near his brain stem. And it wasn't recent...
The bullet he took in the war eight years ago, right?
Yes.
The removal was deemed a success,
but a fragment must've been left behind.
It would've put pressure on his
nerves, especially his optic nerves.
He would've suffered from frequent and intense migraines, and was probably nearly blind.
Nearly blind? Must've been hard for him to snipe Woods in Seattle, then...
What if the current sniper was behind that too?
But then there's no reason for the showdown with Hunter...
No. There's one possible reason.
You can't mean...!
Yeah.
And if so, then there's another meaning behind the second Japanese sniping and the sniping of Hunter-san.
Hi, this is Takagi.
Oh! Conan-kun!
You've got great timing. Could you tell Mouri-san that Lee-san actually happened to have an alibi, and also—
Never mind him, what about Waltz-san and Murphy-san?
Huh? Oh, Waltz-san's still in Kyōto,
but Murphy-san said he felt safe now, and left without a word to the local police guard
boarding the Ōruri Express train leaving for Tokyo at 9 AM.
Apparently someone sent him a ticket, and he'd promised to see them.
Sent him a ticket?!
If he left at nine...!
Apparently he's going to arrive at Asakusa Station at eleven.
No!
What if that was a trap set by the sniper?!
He'd be watching the platform with the perfect sniping point!
His target would even be sitting in the seat he picked!
He's got to be near Asakusa Station!
Anyway, we've got to hurry! There's only three minutes!
This is bad! He's gonna go after Murphy!
Conan-kun?! What's going on, Conan-kun?!
The express! It's already here?!
That's right, it slows down for the bridge...
What's that van stopped on that bridge...?
Don't tell me...!
A rifle!
Don't tell me he's going to shoot from there?!
There's no time to get back there!
Conan-kun!
Don't tell me he's going to shoot him while the train's in motion?!
I've got to block the shot until the train passes!
Please make it in time...
Go!
Hey! Over here, Murphy-san!
We will shortly be arriving at our destination, Asakusa Station...
Come on, realize what's going on!
Hey!
No!
Hey! Murphy-san!
Conan-kun!
Look out!
Se... ra...
Huh?
What?
What's that?
Die!
Sera! Hold on, Sera!
How'd this end up happening...
Damn! Damn! Damn!
Goddamn!
You're sure you're okay, you're not hurt?
But there's blood on your clothes...
It's not my blood...
Conan-kun!
Inspector Megure!
Can we talk?
#18, please head to counter five. #19...
I hate needles...
Wanna go home?
I wonder when Mum'll be back...
So it wasn't a random murder —
he was deliberately aiming for Murphy-san.
Yeah.
Thank you. We had to know for sure.
So the sniper really was working with Hunter?
Huh? What do you mean?
Thanks to the FBI, some new facts have just come to light.
New facts?
We found the bullet that Hunter took to the head eight years ago left him in a state where he could no longer snipe anyone.
Huh? But Hunter's diary suggested he was in a contest with the sniper...
We believe that was all a lie,
and he hired the sniper to shoot him.
No way!
But why...
His death would throw the investigation into chaos, since he was the top suspect,
and it would cause his next target, Murphy-san,
to let his guard down so he could be sniped more easily.
He probably planned everything out before he began.
The reason he missed a shot when shooting Hunter, despite the short range of 150 meters,
could have been from a moment
of hesitation in killing his client.
And we believe the sniper's use of smaller bullets from another gun,
just for that sniping, was an expression of his desire to not hurt Hunter's corpse any more than necessary.
I see...
Then that means when Hunter fired back despite his bad eyes, it wasn't to try and shoot his sniper...
It was a reply from Hunter,
who'd sensed his sniper's hesitation...
Yes.
And that gives us an explanation for the mystery of why two skilled snipers
each missed a shot despite facing one another at close range.
But isn't it dangerous to decide all that just on circumstantial evidence?
No...
We have found evidence to back up these theories.
Huh?!
Evidence?
When FBI HQ analyzed the videos that Conan-kun's friends took at the Bell Tree Tower, where the first sniping took place,
we discovered they showed not just the culprit, but a suspected accomplice as well.
It's true!
There's two of them!
Hunter probably accompanied the sniper, as a spotter for Fujinami-san's sniping.
But the SEALs don't usually use spotters!
I see. It wouldn't be a surprise if he had an accomplice to manage to carry out such a perfectly planned murder spree.
Was he nervous about it being his first sniping in Japan?
Or perhaps...
Suffering intense migraines and losing his sight...
Hunter probably realized he'd never escape his pain as long as he lived,
and hired the sniper to murder him and take revenge on his behalf.
Hold on, there's still the riddle of the dice.
Yes.
We also found a shell and a die at the latest sniping position.
How many dots on the die?
Actually... It wasn't one, but five.
What?!
Wasn't it a countdown?
Four, three, two, but then not one?!
What's the meaning of this? We thought they were a message to Waltz-san, each dot vanishing representing a murder, but now?
It seems we may have been too hasty in coming to our conclusions.
There may be another reason he has to single out Waltz-san, instead of the men who made his family commit suicide.
Anyway...
Kevin Yoshino and Scott Green.
Find out where they are immediately!
They're sure to have some connection with this case!
No matter what happens...
I won't let that sniper have his way!
I'll stop the next sniping for sure!
Got it?
Do you know anything about the Asakusa area or these dice?
Like I told you, I don't care about Asakusa or dice or whatever!
Just put out an arrest warrant for Scott Green! He's got to be the sniper!
B-But at the moment, we don't have enough evidence...
Honestly! Talking to you Japanese police is just a waste of time!
Waltz-san.
No matter what happens, promise me you won't go to Tokyo.
You just need to look at a map. The sniper will be already planning for his next murder in Asakusa.
Who'd want to go somewhere as sinister as Tokyo?!
Just get me tickets to go back home from Kansai International Airport.
Murphy told us the sniper's location at the cost of his own life.
If I don't leave the country now,
his death will have been for nothing!
What a horrible man!
His secretary's just been murdered!
If someone's taken up Hunter's will, that means they must know about the crimes I committed eight years ago...
Damn... I've got to do something!
What the hell?
Hello?
Y-You!
Conan-kun...
We'll make sure to look after Sera-san.
Right.
Don't worry, she'll be fine. The doctor said her injuries aren't life-threatening.
I'll let you know as soon as she wakes up, okay?
Then see you tomorrow.
Still, I'm glad nothing worse happened...
If Sera-san hadn't been there for the brat, he'd have been in danger...
She risked her life to protect Conan-kun...
She really did put her life on the line. Remember what she said before?
Don't worry! I'll make sure to protect Conan-kun.
Not to mention, there's no bullet that can shoot through Conan-kun's heart right now.
Or your heart either, of course!
That reminds me, she said there's no bullet that can shoot through your heart either, Ran...
I can't forgive that sniper...
For putting Conan-kun and Sera-san through all this...
I'll never forgive him!
Ran...
Shuu... ni... Shuu-nii!
"Shuu-nii"?
Maybe she's calling for her late brother?
She mentioned she had a brother who'd died before...
Huh? Was that bouquet there when we came in?
Oh, you're right.
Was someone else just here?
Who's it from?
I can't tell...
But look, Sonoko, they're really beautiful!
So they are! Let's put them on her windowsill.
Yeah. I'll go and ask for a vase.
What's wrong, Ran?
Oh, it's nothing.
Do we know where Green and Yoshino are?
Apparently there's been reports of someone who looks like Green in the Kansai region,
and a large-scale search has been started, centering on Ōsaka.
Maybe he intends to target Waltz-san on the way to Kansai International Airport after all...
This isn't good.
The timing's too perfect. What if he's a decoy to draw attention away from Yoshino?
It's Inspector Megure.
Yes?
James-san, I have some news for you.
What is it? If you mean the reports about Green, I've already heard about those from Camel.
No, something even worse. Waltz-san vanished.
W-What?!
We were just as surprised...
According to the Kyōto Police, after they questioned him,
he told his wife he'd be back tomorrow, and left his hotel through a back door...
But why?! What possible reason could he have?!
Looks like something's happened.
Yes, right. I'll be in touch the moment we discover anything new.
Yeah.
What is it, Jodie-sensei? Yeah, I already had Detective Takagi tell me about the reports of Green being spotted.
Yeah, and then?
What?! Waltz-san?!
I wonder what he could be thinking...
If we figure out the riddle of the dice the sniper left behind, we should be able to tell where Waltz-san is headed...
You mean he's going to the site of the next sniping?
I don't know...
But there might be a special connection between the sniper and Waltz-san —
something that we don't know yet.
Right. I'll check through the connections between the victims and the suspects again.
Okay, I'll call you again later.
Sorry for the wait, Camel! Let's go.
Right.
We'll meet up with Investigation Division One, and go over everything once again.
Right. I'm counting on you.
Waltz-san told his wife that he'd be back tomorrow.
That means there's going to be another sniping in the next 24 hours!
I got everything you wanted. All untraceable.
And the scopes?
All adjusted.
Ha, I expected nothing less from you, Carlos.
You are the best, after all...
You and Hunter, that is.
How 'bout I let you take out the shooter this time?
Then you'll truly be number one.
Weren't you one kill behind Hunter's record in the war?
Rear Admiral Spencer's orders were just to procure the weapon.
Never mind.
If I know the target, I don't need your help anyway.
Thanks for the gun.
I have a message from Admiral Spencer.
He says there will be no inquiry into the origin of the shooting spree.
Just eliminate the sniper at all costs.
Preserve the credibility of the US Military!
The origin of the shooting spree?
How much does the admiral know?
Probably... everything.
What?! But how?!
Only one person alive knows about
that operation, and that's me!
The sniper used the admiral's name to threaten Bill Murphy.
Murphy was scared.
The day before he was killed,
he asked for a reduction of charges.
He e-mailed the admiral, confessed —
the plan to steal Hunter's Silver Star, your orders afterwards, everything!
What?!
Your crimes from eight years ago... They're unforgivable.
But...
We have to stop a former American soldier from committing any more murders on foreign soil.
Well, if he knows everything anyway...
Please tell the admiral... After this case is settled, I'd like a meeting.
There's one more thing.
What?
Did you figure out the meaning behind the dice?
Why bother? They're irrelevant now we know the shooter.
And now for some breaking news.
Bill Murphy-san, who was sniped to death aboard the Tohto Railways Ōruri Express at 11 AM yesterday,
has been linked to the previously murdered Timothy Hunter-san.
Also, the girl who was injured in the sniping is also expected to make a full recovery. And that's the end of the breaking news.
Huh? So it wasn't a completely random killing spree then!
I did warn you! Your careless remark had the whole of Tokyo panicking for the last two days!
Oh, really? Well, sorry about that...
Geez... What a troublemaker.
Uncle!
Apparently Sera-neechan woke up.
We're all going to visit her...
Sorry, but you'll have to go without me.
I've still got some thinking to do about this...
Old man, you've been up all night thinking about the case?
And if my theory about the last die is right, I've solved the riddle of the dice!
What?! Really?!
Huh? Yeah! One night's more than enough for a Great Detective like me to solve this!
So what do they mean?
They're... a countdown!
...Huh?
The bridge must've shook. And so the last die changed from a one to a five!
See? Once you realize that, everything fits—
Huh?! Where'd that brat go?!
That's not a countdown. There's another meaning to it.
I should get there quickly and go over what happened yesterday with Sera.
Here! A clear line of fire...
Yes, I've found it!
The perfect position to target Chigusa...
Ha! The game is mine!
Y-You!
I've taken care of Murphy. Now it is your turn.
W-Why? Why you?!
Is it the money?
How much did he pay? I'll double it!
You never change, Waltz.
I... uhh...
Look, let's make a deal. You, here in a foreign country... You could use some cash, right?
Tomorrow night, come to Chigusa in Asakusa at 8 PM sharp. We'll discuss it then.
Uh, yeah, okay. Chigusa in Asakusa...
If you confess everything... Admit your guilt... I'll let you live.
However, if you're even late, say goodbye to your family!
Understood?
Hello? Hello? Hey, I...
Argh, damn it!
Helen... Sarah...
Waltz-san!
We've got a problem!
Scott Green's been spotted by
the cameras at Shin-Ōsaka Station!
It's too dangerous to go to Kansai International Airport at the moment!
I'm sorry, but you'll have to abandon your plans to leave Japan tomorrow.
Damn! Then it's kill or be killed.
Here, the perfect position to target Chigusa.
He'll pick this spot —
it's textbook!
Any sniper's dream!
But tonight it's not me that's going to be the target —
it's him!
Takes a sniper to beat a sniper...
It all comes down to second-guessing...
Anticipating your opponent's moves, gaining tactical advantage...
Most of all, superior position guarantees victory.
The fact that I have found this position means...
Victory is mine!
You challenge me, you lose!
Say 'hi' to Hunter in Hell!
Huh? Conan-kun, you're here all by yourself?
Yeah, everyone else is coming by car.
Ah.
I was just about to go to the shop downstairs, want to come with me?
Nah, I'll wait here.
Okay, let's go, Sonoko!
Right! Sera-san, we're heading out for a bit.
Okay, thank you.
We'll be back before long.
Let us know if something happens.
Sure!
Hi, Conan-kun.
Looks like the bullet really didn't hit you.
I never got a chance to thank you for saving me...
Don't worry, I was just keeping my promise with Ran-kun.
But what about the sniper...?
Both of the suspects are still in hiding...
Is that so?
Yesterday, I noticed something when I was shot...
The sniper was using a laser sight at the time.
Isn't that strange?
Snipers don't usually use them —
their targets would realize they're being targeted, and they can even give away their location.
I get it. That's why Hunter faked that shootout instead of committing suicide...
Huh? What do you mean?
If he'd committed suicide, the investigation would've been completely called off,
and Murphy-san and Waltz-san would've let their guard down even more, right?
But he didn't.
I get it. That was a final test for the killer, he was making him into a true cold-blooded sniper!
Yeah.
The first sniping was the maximum range for an MK11.
The second sniping was a moving target at night.
And the third sniping was to check that no emotions could ever change his mind.
Hunter was making his killer into the ultimate sniper, right up until his death!
Then that means the sniper is—
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'll be fine...
Hey! We've come over for a visit!
Hey, Genta-kun, you're being too loud...
Oh, sorry...
Oh, Conan-kun!
What's all that stuff you guys brought?
Something really amazing!
Right!
We thought it might help cheer her up. Right?
Huh?
Wow, that's great!
You made that all by yourselves?
Yeah!
It's for our summer homework project!
It's not exactly finished yet...
...but we wanted to show it to you!
Thanks!
It really is great!
Yeah, it's very well-made.
They may not be the same shapes as the real buildings, but they're the same sizes and in the right places!
Ai-chan checked all of them!
Okay, that's the last one!
Though one of us hasn't bothered to help with anything at all.
Yay, it's all done!
It's not finished, but it is complete!
You've done all that, but it's not finished?
It looks good just like that.
What's left to do?
We gotta paint 'em...
But we only had a chance to take photos of the west side when we were at the Bell Tree,
so we don't know what colors the rest should be.
We would've liked to go up one more time before we start painting it, but well...
Then why don't we take another look?
It hasn't reopened yet, but the repairs are all done, so you could have the whole tower to yourselves!
Really?!
You mean it?!
Yay!
But Sonoko, they haven't caught the sniper yet, have they?
What is it?
That'll make our summer homework project perfect!
It's fine! Do you really think he'd
turn up at the same place twice?
Haibara... That model's got the right scale, right?
And even the TV said that it's not actually a random killing spree after all!
Yes.
I guess.
Okay! Then let's hurry back and get our cameras!
Yeah!
Huh? What is it, Conan-kun?
Huh?
What's this feeling?
I feel like I just spotted something
I couldn't see before on a map...
Hey, make sure you help us paint it, you hear?
What is it, Conan-kun?
What is it?
Did you spot something, Conan?
Wow, that's interesting!
Huh? What is?
If you look at it from down here, it looks like some of the buildings we made are the same height!
Conan-kun!
Genta... Sorry, but can you show me?
Huh? Take a look.
Wow, you're right!
That is interesting!
That's because things close to you look bigger than things in the distance.
I get it! That message wasn't supposed to be seen in two dimensions...
...but something you have to see in 3D!
Here!
If you look from here, the height of the first and second sniping positions match!
What about the others?!
The third was a floating platform, and the fourth was Komagata Bridge...
If I add those and look at all of them from the same place...
It's an isosceles trapezium!
Hold on... If I add the observation deck of the Bell Tree Tower, right in the middle...
It's a pentagon!
This shape wouldn't just appear by chance! It had to have been planned intentionally!
Ran-neechan! I've got to go, I forgot something!
H-Hey! Conan-kun! Don't you want to go to the Bell Tree?!
What, you're running off on us again?!
Be careful, Conan-kun...
No, I'll pass for today!
When he vanished, Waltz-san said he'd be back in Kyōto today.
That means he'll have to finish up here by around 8 PM so he can get on the bullet train.
Damn, I gotta hurry!
Hi, Cool Kid. I've got new info.
The Ōsaka Police have arrested Scott Green.
Apparently Hunter asked him to sneak into Ōsaka and avoid being caught until just now.
Then like I thought...
Yes. Apparently he did have some notion that Hunter was in Japan to enact his revenge,
but when he actually saw him and the determination on his face,
he decided to help him achieve the closure on his life that he desired so much.
If he was a decoy, then the sniper must be...
Yeah!
Oh, and I've got some new intel from FBI HQ as well.
Apparently there were reports of Hunter living with an Asian man after he lost his family!
And if that man was Kevin Yoshino...
Then he could be behind it all!
Yeah. Thanks, Jodie-sensei.
By the way, where are you now, Conan-kun?
I'm heading to what I think is the next sniping position.
What?! You solved the riddle of the dice?!
No, I can't be sure yet, so I'm headed to check, but there's no time...
Is there any way I can help?
If my deduction is right, the observation deck of the Bell Tree Tower will be involved again.
The Bell Tree...
Okay! We'll head there now!
Right.
Just make sure to be careful!
Let's go.
Right!
From the model, it should be somewhere around here...
From the top of that building...
You might be able to see it!
Where's the Bell Tree?!
The building where he shot Fujinami-san
and the building where he shot Yasuhara-san...
It's just like I thought with the
model —
they make a horizontal line!
And that means...
If I connect up the positions for the third and fourth snipings, it's an isosceles trapezium...
And if I add the first observation deck of the Bell Tree Tower...
That's definitely a pentagon!
If I consider the dice left at each sniping position too, and put the remaining faces at the Bell Tree Tower...
I get it, so that's what it means!
What the sniper wanted to show Waltz-san, his last target...
Was a star!
A star that represents that Silver Star stolen from Hunter!
Hunter and the sniper intended for Waltz-san to see this star, the Silver Star, from the very beginning!
And that means...
There's been a 'one' die at the first observation deck of the Bell Tree Tower all along,
and the sniping position for the sniper's next murder is the first observation deck too!
There!
So the sniper really was...
Kevin Yoshino!
Damn! Where's he aiming at?!
A slightly taller building would be able to see the star better...
That must be where Waltz-san is going...
There?!
Say 'hi' to Hunter in Hell!
Come on, Waltz.
Come to the window...
The moment you decipher our message will be your last!
This time I'm going to stop you for sure!
Today I'll finally be rid of Hunter's ghost...
Settle the score, once and for all!
W-W-What the...?!
T-That wasn't here before...
Did they leave this for me to see?!
Go!
Die!
What?!
That flash...
It came from that building...
What?!
That kid, interfering again?!
Crap!
You...
You'll pay for that!
You brat!
Damn, there's nowhere to hide on this roof!
M-My leg...!
Oh, crap...
You twerp!
You ruined everything! Everything!
No way! He was sniped?!
But where could someone even target somewhere that high?!
From there?!
Another sniper?!
But how?!
The only place with a shot is Asakusa Sky Court...
But that building is...
Finally, if you shoot from the Bell Tree here, you'll be safe.
But what if Waltz figures out the Silver Star message and targets me from the Asakusa Sky Court...?
Relax...
The one sniper who could make such an distant, upward shot is gone.
O-Oh, right. Your eyes, Tim...
No. I'd never have been able to pull off a shot with this long a range.
Are you saying there was a better sniper than you, Tim?
Yeah, in the FBI.
They had a sniper with amazing skills, dubbed the 'Silver Bullet'.
But you've got nothing to worry about.
He's missing, presumed dead.
I-Impossible... It was him?!
The Silver Bullet actually appeared?!
Subaru-san?!
Why is he there?!
I see. Subaru-san figured out the riddle of the dice too!
Conan-kun! We're at the Bell Tree. We're asking to be let up there now.
Great. Head straight to the roof of the observation deck! Yoshino's there!
Then he really was the sniper.
Yeah. So how about it, can you get up there?
No luck! Apparently the owners have it reserved for today, they won't let us in!
That's right...!
Jodie-sensei! It's Ran and my friends up there!
Explain what's going on, come up to the observation deck and arrest Yoshino!
Got it! I'll get Inspector Megure to make them let us in!
Wow, it's really beautiful!
Isn't it? The Bell Tree has the best views at night too!
It's so cool!
It's even prettier at night!
That's right!
Now, let's go to the other side we haven't photographed yet!
Yeah!
Let's go!
S-Shin'ichi?
So that shot didn't completely neutralize him?
I've come so far, I can't give up now!
I promised Hunter-san...
Good. You've improved.
Now all you need is actual experience.
Right! I'll start with Brian Woods. And I'll make Waltz pay...!
Are you really sure about this?
Huh?
It's a bit late to worry about it now, but I regret getting you involved...
What's got into you, Tim?
You saved my life so many times out there on the front line.
And now, I finally have a chance to repay you!
Still...
And I can never forgive Waltz and Murphy.
He falsely accused you and took away your Silver Star just because your deeds were overshadowing his!
And then just when we asked for the case to be re-opened, he ordered Murphy to kill you!
Yeah, that's right...
If you hadn't had your suspicions and compared the surgically removed bullet with Murphy's gun,
the truth would've stayed forever in the dark.
But then they even stole the proof out from under us, and we couldn't do a thing!
Kevin, I'll say this one last time.
Avenge my wife and sister, and send Waltz and everyone who destroyed my life straight to Hell!
Sure! I promise!
I'll do it!
I'll make sure to send them all to Hell!
I'm counting on you!
That's right. I can't give up now!
I can still get away if I use my escape plan...!
And Waltz has to pay!
Right! So you have to get everyone out of there right now!
But what about the sniper?
Don't worry! The FBI are coming up to deal with him!
Okay, got it!
The emergency stairs are this way!
Right.
Sonoko!
Who the heck are you?!
Give us back Ayumi-chan!
What're you two doing?! Run and hide!
But...
He's got Ayumi!
Get back, you brats!
No...
Sonoko!
Don't cause any trouble, you brats! Just stay where you are!
I'm gonna borrow this girl!
Stay back!
This is the FBI! Drop your gun!
Shut up! If you come any closer, I'll kill this girl!
Muzzle flashes...!
Damn, he still hasn't given up?!
Don't let him head around the back.
Bring him this way...
Stop running around!
You want me to kill the girl?!
Drop your guns and let me through!
All right, we've gotta save Ayumi-chan!
Okay! We'll do what you say, so just calm down!
Right!
Don't be stupid! He's got a gun!
But we do have to save her somehow...
Sonoko! Come on! Sonoko!
What should I do, Shin'ichi?
Help me...
Damn! I can't do anything from down here!
That's enough!
Do it now or I'll kill her!
To ensure successful recovery of hostages, you have to disable the target instantly.
But to do that...
There's only one spot where you can kill someone with a single bullet, and cut off all possible convulsions.
The brain stem...
Right.
I have to do it!
Damn, they won't let me through...
Jodie-san!
Yoshino!
You're mine!
No! What's going on?!
I can't see a thing!
A power cut?!
Quiet, both of you! Get back!
Damn! He got the lights!
Now Subaru-san can't...
I see.
He intends to escape under cover of darkness.
What should I do?
We're in trouble!
He'll end up taking Ayumi with him!
NIGHT VISION MODE
Don't tell me... Night-vision goggles?!
Run, Jodie-sensei!
Yoshino! You can't win, so give up!
Camel!
Say something, Camel!
Damn it, he's going to kill everyone!
If I can just shine light on him somehow, Subaru-san should be able to snipe him.
But I can't support myself with my leg like this!
How can I let him see Yoshino?
Hold on! Those night-vision goggles are old style ones...
That means I just have to shine light on the Bell Tree!
How about that?!
If I use this height, it might work!
No, it has to work!
Edogawa-kun?
Hello?
Light! Shine light on the sniper!
He's wearing night-vision goggles. It'll blind him!
But where is he...?
Right. Use that.
Got it.
He'll be passing by you soon.
Don't move for thirty seconds, so he doesn't get suspicious.
I'm hanging up!
Listen. You have to stay perfectly still for the next thirty seconds!
Right.
Sure!
I'll get one more chance.
I can count on that boy...
Please, let this work...
You ready?
Right!
Here goes!
Where is it?! Where's it coming from?!
Hold on!
Over there!
All right!
Here goes!
Now!
What?!
Yoshida-san, over here!
Ai-chan!
You dumb brats!
Everybody run!
Ran-san!
Stop, Ran!
Ran!
Damn! I can't just sit here!
What should I do, Shin'ichi?
You had to try and be a hero...
Now I've got a new hostage.
It's now or never...
I've got to do this!
Just hold on...
Ran!
Go!
Now!
Hmph...
What?!
What is that?!
Ran!
This is for Sonoko!
And Ayumi-chan!
And Sera-san!
Right. We've secured Yoshino!
That was great!
You were amazing, Ran-san!
Ran!
Sonoko!
That was so cool, Ran!
Are you feeling okay, Sonoko?
I have no idea what's going on, but I'm perfectly fine!
Huh? Wait, why are the lights out? Was there a power cut...?
Oh, Sonoko...
Damn, she's relentless...
Target silenced. All clear.
Right. I just heard from Jodie-kun. Good work. I'll be in contact again.
Roger.
So you're finally going home tomorrow?
Yeah. Thanks for looking after me for all this time.
It's fine. Don't worry about it.
Oh, right. Waltz-san was on TV.
Apparently the sniping spree brought to light all of the crimes he committed in his past.
He'll be spending the rest of his days in prison.
It turns out that the pair behind the snipings were victims of his, just trying to get revenge.
Even so, Ran...
I can't believe you took on that man with a machine gun!
I was just in a trance...
Really, I'm glad that you got off with just a few scratches!
What if a bullet'd gone through your heart?! I can't help but worry...
Well, you know I've got good luck...
It'll be fine!
There's only one man who can snipe Ran-kun's heart!
Right, her beloved Shin'ichi-kun!
Oh, Sonoko...
For now, anyway...
Are you okay, Conan-kun?
You better not be trying to get out of this.
You're going to make up for all the work you left us to do!
Okay, let's go to the pool!
Sure!
Sorry about leaving you behind, Haibara-san,
but thanks for agreeing to watch Conan-kun!
Sure.
Your hands aren't moving.
Don't tell me they expect me to finish this all by myself?!
Movie 19 —
In Cinemas April 2015