Now then, Tokyo Governor, Asakura...
Would you please deliver your address?
To my fellow thirteen million Tokyo citizens...
And to all railway line enthusiasts across the nation...
Thank you for your patience.
The operation of Metropolitan Subway Line
No. 15—the Tohto Line—is now underway!
A threatening letter!?
To the governor!?
This was delivered to the Asakura residence yesterday afternoon.
There was no return address on it.
"By the haughty and arrogant means you've
operated your 4-year Tokyo administration...
"Divine punishment shall ensue."
"Haughty and arrogant"?
Hasn't Asakura-san and the first term of his
administration been highly regarded?
Well, people have differing feelings and opinions.
There are no doubt dissatisfied and enraged
people motivated by irrational beliefs.
It's as Shiratori-kun has said.
Tomorrow, Mr. Asakura is scheduled to
attend the Tohto Line opening ceremony.
We've been assigned the task of guarding the governor.
Do not let your guard down under any circumstances.
The governor has now boarded the train.
I'm really excited!
About this "Big Universe Exhibition"!
I heard they have spaceship simulations!
Ayumi wants to give it a try!
But, it seems a certain someone is preoccupied with something else.
You're intrigued, then?
About what Mouri-kun heard from Inspector Megure...
The threatening letter addressed to the governor.
Yeah.
I really hope nothing comes of it.
We're about to enter the Shin-Yamate Tunnel.
That reminds me, this tunnel...
It'll run alongside the Tohto Line!
Yeah.
It meets up with the Tohto Line and passes below it.
They run parallel for about a kilometer.
That's the curve.
After taking this curve, we'll be at the Tohto Line junction.
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
Who was that shadow just now?
That was a stopping area, but I didn't see a parked car or motorbike...
They were also holding something in their hand...
Don't tell me!
Professor!
Stop the car!
What?
Bombs!
Someone's planted bombs in the tunnel!
Bombs!?
Did you say bombs!?
But...
I can't until we reach the next stopping area!
Conan-kun!
They've activated the detonator!?
Damn!
Megure here.
This is Kudo!
Hurry and stop the train at once!
There are bombs about to blow!
Bombs!?
Takagi-kun!
Stop the train!
There are bombs!
An earthquake?
No, that's not it!
The train's coming out!
That's the Tohto Line!
Kudo-kun!
This is bad!
If I recall, there's a curve up ahead!
Stop!
We're saved...
Mr. Governor!
Are you hurt!?
I'm all right...
Thank you.
l'm high school detective, Kudo Shin'ichi.
While visiting an amusement park with my
childhood friend and classmate, Mouri Ran...
I witnessed a man in black in the midst of a suspicious transaction.
While caught up in watching the deal...
I failed to notice his partner sneaking up behind me.
That man forced me to swallow poison...
And when I came to...
My body had shrunk.
If those guys found out that Kudo Shin'ichi was still alive...
They'd come after me again and put those around me at risk.
At Professor Agasa's suggestion, I decided to conceal my true identity.
When Ran asked for my name, in that instant...
I became Edogawa Conan.
In order to obtain information on those guys...
I went to live with Ran, whose father is a private detective.
These kids are my current classmates...
Genta.
Mitsuhiko.
Ayumi.
They formed the "Detective Boys" and forced me to join.
And...
This is old man Mouri Kogoro.
Need I explain more?
These two devices are inventions of Professor Agasa.
The professor has come up with unique devices one after
the other, all tailor-made for me in my shrunken form.
The Anywhere Ball Dispensing Belt...
Pressing a button on the buckle inflates a
soccer ball and ejects it—a nifty invention.
And the spotlight this time around is on
this high performance snowboard.
Stepping on the acceleration pedal enables
autocruise even when not on a slope.
Of course, like my skateboard, it has a turbo engine.
By the way, as for those who know my true identity...
There's someone other than the professor.
Haibara Ai.
Her real name is Miyano Shiho.
She was originally a member of the Black Organization, but...
Following a certain incident, she decided to take her own life...
And took the same drug I was forced to,
but her body ended up shrinking instead.
As such, with the addition of Haibara who now
lives with the professor...
We set out on our newfound lives as first graders.
Even though I've become smaller, my mind remains the same.
The unbeaten great detective...
There is only one truth!
What the perpetrator utilized were plastic explosives.
The mechanism was set up in a way that enabled
the timer to be engaged via remote control.
Regarding the timer...
According to Edogawa Conan-kun, who witnessed the culprit...
After confirming the train had passed overhead,
they pressed the switch on their remote.
The train was traveling at 60 kilometers per hour.
The distance from the stopping area where the
culprit was seen to the bombs was 250 meters.
As a result, our calculations suggest the
timer was likely set to 15 seconds.
Had the driver not applied the brakes immediately,
the train would have entered the blast radius...
Which would have no doubt ended in dire tragedy.
Inspector Megure, who was the person that called
your cell phone and ordered the train be stopped?
That was...
A certain police assistant.
That's all we can say.
At any rate, including Governor Asakura...
No passengers on board were injured.
Inspector...
As always, I request my involvement remain confidential.
Due to my line of work, I'd prefer to not increase my number of enemies.
His "line of work"?
Isn't he just a high school student?
And, thanks to that young boy, Conan...
The fact that the number of vehicles
damaged by the explosion remained zero...
Was indeed nothing but a miracle.
This Edogawa Conan-kun...
How come he noticed the bombs?
That's because this Mouri Kogoro sitting right next to me...
Mentioned to him that the perpetrator might
utilize explosives to carry out their crime.
As expected of Great Detective Mouri!
Did I say something like that?
Mouri-san, can you share with us any comment regarding the culprit?
Their crime carried out with the purpose
of claiming Governor Asakura's life...
As well as their sabotaging one of the highlights of his
second term in the new metropolitan subway line...
Will never be tolerated!
Is anything already known at this point regarding the culprit?
Unfortunately, the security camera installed in the tunnel did
not capture footage of the aforementioned stopping area.
Moreover, the culprit likely used the
emergency exit and nearby slope...
In order to escape to the main highway from the ground level.
But, as of now, no known witnesses can confirm that.
Conan-kun also said he couldn't tell the culprit's face, age, or gender.
We police consider this a crime against Governor
Asakura's 4-year Tokyo administration...
Motivated by one-sided dissatisfaction and hatred.
MPD PRESS CONFERENCE
Our investigation is focusing on that angle.
That will be all.
This has been a live broadcast from the press
conference held at police headquarters.
What, so that's it?
They didn't even say a word about us Detective Boys, did they?
How boring!
All right, let's play a game!
A game!
Good idea!
Looks like the search for the culprit is rough going.
That threatening letter...
Isn't it possible it was just camouflage intended
to hide the culprit's true motive for the crime?
Camouflage?
Say, Professor...
Wasn't Governor Asakura once the Minister of
Land, Infrastructure, Transport and Tourism?
During his term as minister, didn't he tear down
a village in Niigata in order to build a dam?
Oh, I remember that.
If I recall correctly, it's the Kitanosawa Dam.
Back then, Minister Asakura went to the village himself...
Along with plenty of security money and nice replacement land to offer.
He stayed in the village for a week...
Engaged every villager in intense, personal conversation...
And received their near-unanimous approval after gaining their trust.
Then, after taking only three years to build the new village...
And requiring an unprecedented record of just five years to
construct the dam, he'd accomplished a magnificent feat.
That's what they say.
All in spite of the fact that there were villagers
who opposed the proposal all the way to the end.
I see!
If we assume a grudge over the construction
of the dam was the culprit's true motive...
Then our culprit may be one of the
villagers or someone connected to it.
I was only stating one possibility, though.
It so happens that next Sunday...
They're having a ceremony at the replacement village
commemorating the fifth anniversary of their relocation.
I heard the governor had been planning to attend and stay for a night.
But, due to the bombing incident, it was canceled.
I get it.
You want to visit that village and investigate the matter?
Yeah.
Professor, can you take me there?
Where are you going?
Bring us along too!
It's always just Conan, how unfair!
Weren't you guys playing games?
If the professor's going, I'll tag along too.
Haibara...
Whenever I take my eyes off him, even for a
moment, he starts hitting the pound key.
Nah...
He's already been overweight for ages though.
Kitanosawa Dam
Kitanosawa Village
It'll be our turn soon.
I'm really excited!
So cold!
But the snow is so soft!
This is fantastic!
All right, let's slide one more time!
Yeah!
They sure look happy, those kids.
You're right.
I'd say...
It's a good thing we brought them.
Well, regardless of those guys...
Let's go, Ran!
Wait...
Sonoko!
Geez, don't push me!
Sorry, sorry.
Geez, why did Ran and Sonoko come?
Not to mention...
There it is...
The elusive open-air spa.
What's more...
It's a mixed bath!
It's the mixed bath open-air spa of my dreams!
Who awaits me?
A sexy lady?
Maybe a beautiful virgin?
All right!
Here comes!
My...
Nice water temperature, right?
Being like this beneath an unfamiliar sky...
Gazing upon the snowy view while immersing in a hot spring...
Poétique, isn't it?
Young miss.
Which one should I eat?
They all look delicious!
Takoyaki is the best!
Ikayaki is awesome, too!
Isobeyaki are delicious too, you know!
All right, I shall eat 'em all one by one!
Before that, here's a quiz!
What's the most suitable menu for a food
stand in a plaza covered in powder snow?
Number one:
Yakiimo
baked yam
Number two:
grilled food with seaweed
Isobeyaki
Number three:
Ikayaki
baked squid
Number four:
grilled octopus balls
Takoyaki
What does powder snow mean?
It means light dry snow.
Powder snow?
Powder snow...
Powder, powder...
I know!
It's number four, takoyaki, right?
Why?
Because only takoyaki requires baking powder, right?
Ayumi's mom always makes it!
Beyond that, in Kansai, they nicknamed it
"powder cuisine" according to Kazuha-chan.
I see!
But if that were the case, wouldn't it be too easy?
It needs a twist.
Excuse me, for not putting in a twist.
Well, I have a pop quiz of my own.
Which of those is most suitable for the professor?
The answer is none of them.
They'll all make you even fatter.
For starters, that wasn't even a quiz...
Now then, we should...
Go eat some!
I'll eat a bellyful, including the professor's share!
We should go eat as well.
Yeah.
The professor's share, too!
Ai-chan and Conan-kun, what will you do?
I'll pass.
Me too.
I wanna take a walk through the village.
Then, I'll go with Conan-kun and...
You can't.
Professor, you'll have a cup of tea with me.
The map fer Kitanosawa Village?
And also the guide for the dam, please.
Understood.
Hold on just a moment.
Say, Yamao.
I heard that ski site got shut down.
Yeah, I heard about it too.
They said avalanches have been hitting hard.
Thank you fer waiting.
This is the map fer Lake Kitanosawa.
And this map is fer the original Kitanosawa
Village drawn to the same scale.
Well...
This guy said he really wanted to know where exactly
in the dam reservoir his childhood home had sunk to.
Dat so?
Well, let's go.
No good, no good.
Say, mister, isn't that a stun gun?
You know a lot, little boy.
It's for my protection!
When you're working as an insurance investigator in Tokyo...
You constantly run into dangerous situations.
That's why I always carry this whenever I go out.
Well, see you later.
Sorry fer the wait.
Let's see...
A map fer Kitanosawa Village and the guide to the dam, right?
Here ya go.
Thank you!
Say...
About the villagers who opposed the construction of the dam...
Are they still living in the new village?
Why ya asking somethin' like that?
Just...
For my winter vacation school project...
What grade ya in?
First grade...
In that case, why don't ya choose a subject more suitable fer your age?
Fer example, look.
Near this village, in Lake Sawajiri, a lotta
swans've come over to stay fer now.
Observin' the swans is a good idea!
Since Lake Sawajiri's full'a hot springs,
it dun freeze even in the middle of winter!
Is that so?
I'll give it some thought!
No surprise he's not gonna tell a kid, huh?
It hurts...
All right, here's your medicine.
Thank you very much...
If you take it, you'll get better soon.
And that overfilled stomach of yours will, too.
Geez...
All because you got carried away and ate ten plates of takoyaki!
You're flattering me...
It wasn't praise.
I'm sorry.
What grade are you guys in?
First grade!
I see, first graders?
Desu.
That was delicious!
So true!
If they'd had eel rice, I would've had nothing to whine about!
But your stomach sure can take a lot,
even after eating so much for lunch!
He has more than one stomach, that Genta-kun.
I can still stuff more in it!
That's right.
Hey, let's buy a souvenir for Kobayashi-sensei!
Great idea!
They also have my eel pies on sale!
Geez!
He's planning to eat even more?
Conan-kun, let's go take a look.
I'll be heading for my room.
"Snowshoe Trekking"...
Lake Sawajiri?
Hey, hey, miss!
What is it, young boy?
About this snowshoe trekking tour, does it go near the dam?
Let's see...
At a guest's request, we can tour nearby.
Boy, are you interested in the dam?
Could say that.
What would be best?
Must be these bear buns, hands down!
No, owls are better!
It gives off an intellectual vibe, too.
Ai-chan, what do you think is good?
A coffee mug?
"I love swans"?
白鳥
"I love Shiratori"!
What's wrong, Shiratori-kun?
A cold?
No.
Until we apprehend our culprit...
I can't be sitting around catching a cold.
Can I even finish this before next winter?
Say, Ran, what's your opinion on this?
My opinion?
It's a souvenir for Makoto-san!
It's nice, isn't it?
Really cute.
Even looks a little like Sonoko.
That so?
Are you all set, Ran?
All set on what?
What else—on a souvenir for Shin'ichi-kun!
It's fine, it's fine!
I bet with all those investigations he
wouldn't be available even if I did buy one.
If you allow him to wander around without putting a collar on him...
Maybe some random girl will show up
and put one around his neck instead!
A collar?
She consider me a dog?
Well...
Regarding the "wandering around" part,
I could say the same for Makoto-san.
Well, maybe I should call him just in case?
No good!
Hello?
Shin'ichi?
Where do you think I am?
I'm in Kitanosawa Village in Niigata Prefecture.
We're all here for the Snow Festival...
Amazing!
What is it?
The illuminations are so fabulous.
And since it's snowing, everything looks so magical!
I want you to see this too, Shin'ichi.
If it's that impressive, I'd love to see it too.
What kind of souvenir do you want?
Anything is fine.
I can't decide if you say anything is fine!
Just name something.
Geez...
Well, what do they have there?
Lots of things.
For example, there are bear buns...
クマ
Wooden owl sculptures...
フクロウ
And mugs with swans on them.
八クチョウ
Swans...
What the hell?
Then, the owl.
フクロウ
Got it—the owl, right?
Well, I don't know when I'll be able to receive it, so...
Just leave it in my living room or something.
Geez...
You need to come back once in a while!
I know I should.
Where are those guys going this late?
Hey, Shin'ichi?
Sorry, I'm kinda busy right now.
Talk to you later.
Shin'ichi!
Geez...
As a precaution...
Oh, no!
Damn it...
This is...
A list of the souvenirs I just mentioned...
Then, the owl.
Could it be...
Shin'ichi...
Awesome!
So fast, so fast!
I've been wanting to ride one of these for so long!
Yeah, this is the best!
Isn't it!?
Amazing, amazing!
Just like a roller coaster!
Totally thrilling!
There's more to come!
Hold on, Genta-kun!
It's dangerous!
Don't worry, don't worry!
Just leave it to me!
Genta-kun!
Ahead, ahead!
What?
Hey, Genta-kun...
Could we have gone off the course?
Think so?
This is bad!
I don't want to ride on a public road!
Really?
Then, let's go back!
Hey, you alive?
Barely...
The snow acted like a cushion...
This is bad, huh?
It doesn't look like we can flip it back over with only our strength.
What do we do?
I don't think the snow's gonna stop...
And it's too far to walk our way back.
On top of that, I don't think any cars are going to pass here!
We'll be fine!
We're carrying this, aren't we?
Geez, those guys...
Doing whatever they like!
But isn't it a relief?
That you have your upgraded skateboard to ride on snowy roads.
Yeah, guess so.
Over there, huh?
He's so late, that Conan...
But, the inside of a snow cave is quite warm, isn't it?
Yeah.
Did you guys hear something?
It's Conan-kun!
You're too late, Conan!
So Ai-chan came too!
Since we're all unfamiliar with these snowy roads,
I felt uneasy letting Edogawa-kun go alone.
I see.
Without calling an adult, there's nothing that can be done.
We'll have to call the professor and have him pick us up right away.
But I didn't want the professor and the others to know!
That's why I had you help us in secret!
What choice do we have?
Besides...
It's all Genta-kun's fault!
You were in way over your head!
Weren't you really excited about it too, Mitsuhiko?
But there's a limit to everything!
You need to think things through before you act!
What'd you say!?
Calm down, you two...
You're talking like I wasn't thinking at all!
Well?
Did you think anything through at all?
Of course I did!
You're the one always pretending to look smart!
What do you mean by that!?
Genta-kun, you're a—!
Mitsuhiko is a—!
Knock it off!
Both of you.
Say nothing more than that.
Once those words leave your mouths,
you'll never be able to take them back.
But—!
Words are like swords.
If you use them the wrong way, they'll turn into ugly weapons.
There are cases of broken friendship that could
have lasted a lifetime if not for verbal abuse.
Once you sever your ties, you might not see each other ever again.
A car's coming!
Yeah.
Well, we'll be back soon.
Please tell the others there's no need to worry about us.
Got it.
Stay safe then.
You guys...
Apologize when we get back.
Understood...
Yes...
My bad, Mitsuhiko.
No, it was my fault.
You guys are lucky!
If I hadn't agreed to meet someone at the lodge,
I wouldn't have been passing by at this hour.
Mister, you don't live in Kitanosawa Village?
I live by myself in a cottage I built in the mountains back there.
Carving owls as a pastime.
The wooden owl sculptures?
Mister, you made those?
I made the small ones at that cottage.
And the big ones at the workshed near the dam.
Dam?
I once lived in the village, but...
It got sunk by that cursed dam, so that's why.
Say...
Could one of the people who opposed the
construction of the dam to the end be...
Yeah, I was.
The villagers who originally opposed the plan, and my own parents...
In the end, they all goddamn moved to the replacement village.
That village is just shit to me!
We're sorry...
You brats—!
Now, now, Mouri-kun.
Those three regret their actions, after all.
Yeah, but...
Plus, look.
Thank you very much!
For going through the trouble to bring them back.
Nah.
I happened to have things to attend to at this lodge.
Is that so?
Then, I'll get going.
Yes.
Thank you again.
Hey, you guys need to thank him.
Thank you very much!
Don't make others worry again.
Yes, sir!
Now, how about we go back in?
Bet you're all freezing, right?
Yeah.
I thought I was gonna freeze to death.
Who was it that made a fuss about wanting to ride a snowmobile?
IT WAS GENTA-KUN!
Hey, Mutou.
Over here.
You're late.
It's the nurse from earlier!
You're right!
Thank you for earlier!
Good evening.
How's your stomach doing?
It's all perfectly fine now!
Genta-kun has a stomach made of iron!
Huh?
Those two...
Excuse me, but could you be that famous detective Mouri Kogoro-san?
You got it...
I'm the Great Detective Mouri Kogoro!
As I thought!
Then, are you here investigating some sort of case?
Nah...
We're here for the Snow Festival.
Would we bring kids with us to work?
Guess you're right.
Of course!
Well, to think we're able to meet with
a great detective at a place like this!
Right?
Allow me to introduce ourselves.
The guy sitting next to me is Yamao Keisuke.
Yamao Keisuke (34)
The ladies facing him are...
Toono Mizuki (33)
Tachihara Fuyumi (34)
Toono Mizuki and...
Tachihara Fuyumi.
Mutou Takehiko (34)
And this is Mutou Takehiko.
Hikawa Shougo (34)
Finally, I'm Hikawa Shougo.
Everyone here was born in the original Kitanosawa Village.
Yamao and I got out from Tokyo and came all
the way here in order to attend the ceremony.
Then, you guys are childhood friends?
Yes, we were elementary schoolmates.
But, since it was a branch school in the village...
The five of us were all that made up our class.
Only five people?
Yeah, that's right.
It's been what, eight years since the five of us got together?
Eight years?
It's literally a touching class reunion!
But, say...
Why hadn't you met up in the past eight years?
Well, about that...
It's due to this.
Wait—not now, Hikawa-kun!
Isn't that...
Eight years ago, this guy was still living in Tokyo...
And while en route to his grandmother's place in the original village...
This guy, scared, left her body alone like that,
and escaped by hiding himself in the village.
Then, after a few hours, he changed his
mind and turned himself over to the police.
He gave himself up?
Yeah.
M car was almost totaled...
And I didn't think I could flee from it.
At the same time, he owed a huge debt to loan
sharks as a result of his gambling problem.
His life was a complete mess.
In court, he was found guilty of speeding, DUI, hit-and-run...
And on top of all that, his driver's license had already been suspended.
After serving the time from all of his punishment,
it wasn't until this summer that he was set free.
Then, while Yamao-san was still in prison...
The proposal for the dam came in, and the
whole village ended up being sunk into it.
Yamao-kun's grandmother...
Fell ill due to the shock of her grandson's incident...
And drew her last breath.
Then, she didn't get to live in the new village?
Adding insult to injury, the victim killed in his accident was...
The then 18-year-old Mizuki's little sister, Natsuki!
Yamao-kun...
I still haven't forgiven you for what you did, even now.
I too haven't forgiven a certain someone.
Hikawa!
When the proposal for the dam dropped in...
You were the first to support it and sold
the replacement land for a huge sum.
You and your family then made off
for Tokyo—I'll never forgive you lot!
Hey, hey, Mutou...
The one who coached your parents into
something so dirty was you, wasn't it!?
You sold our long-cherished hometown land!
Don't you realize that!?
You can't live in this world without putting your wits to good use!
Well, we've intruded enough.
Let's head back to our rooms.
Good idea.
No good bothering these good folks any longer.
Everyone, return to your rooms.
Let's do that.
Sorry to have bothered you all.
That woman...
The one named Fuyumi...
She seems to have her own troubles too.
Yeah.
Even though they're elementary schoolmates...
They've already gone separate ways in life.
You're right.
Don't worry, I'm certain that you guys will do well.
Why...?
Of course I know!
What you're thinking about right now.
"I wonder what will happen between Shin'ichi and me?"
Like that!
Not that...
I was only thinking about those people just now...
And nothing about him!
Well, about the souvenir we were discussing earlier...
Has Shin'ichi-kun really come to this village?
Yeah.
But it doesn't seem he's staying at this lodge.
Still...
I have a feeling that Shin'ichi is somewhere really close to me.
Then again, I always have that sort of feeling.
You sold our long-cherished hometown land!
Don't you realize that!?
Is that Mutou-san related to the bombing incident in some way?
And, those so-called classmates...
So white!
Snow, snow!
Let's brave a snowball fight!
Let's do it!
Conan-kun and Ai-chan, join us too!
I'll pass.
If we don't watch those guys, we'll never know what they're up to.
We did it!
All right, you guys!
If you want a fight, you got one!
Here he comes!
Let's run!
Here goes!
Wait up, you guys!
We're right here!
There they are!
There!
Someone's watching us!
Looks like he has something to say to us.
Good morning!
I...
We're sorry...
For stepping on your property.
Can I...
Join?
Your group...
Can I...
Join you for a...
Snow fight?
That big bro looks a little weird, huh?
Yeah...
He seems childish or something...
To...
Touma...
You finally woke up!
Touma!
Touma...
Huh?
Mommy?
This is great!
I finally get to see Mommy!
Touma...
This is great...
Tachihara Touma (15)
Fuyumi's son, Touma...
One morning eight years ago, he fell into a
brook from a cliff near the original village.
He was found in an unconscious state.
Touma was immediately transported to the
hospital at the foot of the mountain...
And though his life was saved...
He had never regained consciousness over the past eight years.
Eight years?
The day also coincides with Yamao's hit-and-run incident.
The same day?
Yeah.
In a laid-back, literally peaceful village like ours...
The fact that two major incidents occurred on the same day...
It sent the whole village into chaos.
What's the nature of Touma-kun's case?
According to the police investigation, it was an accident.
That cliff was close to Touma's favorite
lake, where the swans would gather.
And since he had binoculars hanging
around his neck when he was found...
They deemed it an accidental slip and fall.
The one who found Touma was the neighbor's
dog—a dog he considered a dear friend.
Where were Fuyumi-san and her husband then?
She was an unmarried mother.
Fuyumi was on call for an emergency patient at the
hospital near the foot of the mountain where she worked.
So he doesn't have a grandfather or grandmother?
Right.
Fuyumi's parents got caught in an avalanche a while back.
So they died?
By the time they were found, thirty minutes
had passed since the onset of the avalanche.
We were told they could've been saved if they
had been found fifteen minutes earlier.
Once you're caught in an avalanche, it's
said you have a time limit of fifteen minutes.
Fifteen minutes?
That quarter-hour determines life or death.
It's too short if it's only a quarter.
Well, it's all right for you to take a break from the clinic...
So please keep Touma-kun company.
Yes.
Thank you very much.
How was it, Fuyumi?
Mizuki...
Mutou-kun...
He said Touma was physically fine.
That so?
But...
His mind...
He has no memory of the day he fell from the cliff.
So things like, "Why did I sleep for the last eight years?" are...
Incomprehensible to him.
But this is great, Fuyumi.
This is truly a miracle.
Sorry for saying this...
But would you consider switching to contact lenses?
A beauty like yourself is suited for
contacts much more so than glasses!
I cannot help but view glasses as cold...
And do not like them.
Hold it, Dad!
Geez!
You look intrigued.
About Touma-kun's incident coinciding with
Yamao-san's traffic accident from the same day.
Yeah.
Was it just a coincidence...
Or...
Auntie!
Is it true that Touma-kun regained consciousness?
So you all came!
Please, come in!
Will he be all right?
Isn't it too early for him to see them?
You're right.
Touma, look, it's Kaori-chan and the others.
Hey, doing all right?
It's been a while, Touma-kun!
Let's take a rest now.
Yes!
So many swans here!
Huh?
Mizuki-san!
Yeah...
I decided to try contact lenses.
I did have some ready.
My, they suit you better!
Your beauty just rose to another level!
Geez, shame on you, Dad!
Hey, didn't she change her hairstyle a bit too?
Maybe she really has a thing for Uncle!
Knock it off, Sonoko!
Wow, in all seriousness, you are beautiful!
Say, say...
The lake was right around here, right?
That's right.
Where was the cliff where Touma-san fell?
Touma-kun?
Right here.
That's weird.
If he was coming from this way, then the direction would be a bit off.
He was lost, wasn't he?
That's enough, you!
Then, the place where Yamao-san had
the accident was on this curve, right?
That's true, but...
Why do you ask?
Take a hike over there!
Conan-kun!
It's snowing...
It really is!
Geez...
Did you find something out again?
Sort of.
Whether Touma-kun really came to see the swans or not.
Pretty!
Looks like it's going to accumulate.
It's all right.
It'll stop soon.
Well, we should get going now.
It really stopped snowing!
As expected, locals know best.
Mizuki-san, would you consider visiting Tokyo next time?
I can show you around!
Then, how about the Sky Tree?
Anywhere but that place...
Are you afraid of heights, Mouri-san?
This is embarrassing...
Anything you're afraid of, Mizuki-san?
I can't stand dark, narrow places...
Why'd you butt in like that!?
So what, I felt like it!
What's wrong, Mizuki-san?
Say...
That jacket, isn't it Hikawa-kun's?
Hey, Hikawa-kun!
He can't hear us?
What's he doing out in a place like that?
Hey...
Isn't that weird?
Yeah.
Everyone, please wait here for a bit.
Hikawa-kun!
What are you doing out in a place like that?
Dad...
Yeah.
I'll go check it out.
Hikawa-kun, what's the matter?
Hikawa-kun!
Mizuki-san!
What's wrong?
Hikawa-kun doesn't look right!
Back off!
Yes...
Hikawa-san...
Is something wrong?
Hikawa-san?
Hikawa-sa...
Dad!
Don't come!
Stay back!
It's no good.
He's dead.
Are you all right?
Yeah...
Looks like there are no external wounds.
Froze to death?
No...
Cardiac arrest?
That reminds me, Hikawa-kun has had
a heart problem since he was a child...
So that was the case?
Ran, contact the police!
Got it!
Hey, this is strange.
His stun gun is missing.
Hey!
Go somewhere else, brat!
Hikawa-san said he always keeps a
stun gun in his pocket as self-defense!
The fact that it's missing means someone
else was with him and took it away!
No, that's not it.
How come?
Look at that.
There's only one set of shoeprints.
And there's no doubt they're from those snowshoes.
In other words, Hikawa-san...
Walked here alone alongside the brook from the village...
And while walking on the snowfield,
underwent cardiac arrest and died as a result.
That must be it.
Then, what about the stun gun?
He must've left it back at the lodge!
That can't be the case.
But, those shoeprints...
Could that have been a trick used by the culprit?
What?
Well, don't you hear it often?
Mysteries about shoeprints left atop the snow!
Look, you...
Shoeprints...
Atop the snow?
I got it!
This was indeed the culprit's trick!
All right?
Near the brook, the culprit already drugged
Hikawa-san with poison or something...
In order to kill him and disguise it as a heart attack.
They then changed into a prearranged pair of
boots like those Hikawa-san had been wearing...
And carried his body on their back here.
Then, they set Hikawa-san down...
And stole his stun gun.
On their way back, they followed their own shoeprints...
And walked backwards by stepping on them!
Backwards?
Is something like that possible?
Of course it is!
Just you watch!
Why is there so much snow inside his hood?
I see...
I got it, Uncle!
The culprit's super easy trick!
What?
See, it was snowing earlier, wasn't it?
The culprit walked alongside the brook with Hikawa-san to here...
And killed him off while disguising it as a heart attack.
Then, the snow that was coming down
wiped away both of their shoeprints!
And, after waiting until the snow stopped...
The culprit changed into a prearranged
pair of boots similar to Hikawa-san's...
And walked backwards without concern for the
length of their stride as they returned to the brook!
See?
If we do this, there will be only one set of shoeprints left, right?
As for proof, look over there.
The inside of Hikawa-san's coat hood.
Lots of snow has built up, right?
I bet the culprit, after the snow had stopped...
Wiped off only the snow on his head and shoulders.
All in order to make it seem they had come here after the snowfall!
But, this trick...
It wouldn't work if we hadn't quickly!
arrived here and found his body, right?
If his body were left unfound, and should the snowfall again...
The shoeprints they had left would've been erased again.
Which means the perp is someone who was sure
of our coming to this place beforehand, huh?
Or maybe, it was the one who guided us here...
About our coming here around this time...
I think they could have estimated the time by
using the snowshoe trekking information packet.
She has a point.
Say, say, Mizuki-san...
Where do those shoeprints lead?
Mutou-kun's mountain cottage is that way.
Mutou-san's?
But...
There's a village road for cars that goes
from the village to the mountain cottage.
Was it the road we were riding on the snowmobile last night?
Why didn't Hikawa-kun take that road?
No.
Hikawa-san and the culprit purposely avoided that road...
Instead walking from the brook to the mountain
cottage via the snowfield, where they wouldn't be seen.
Why is that?
Thank you for your patience.
Hikawa-san's body is now at a university hospital...
And is being thoroughly investigated by the medical examiner.
Detective Watanabe
Niigata Police
Detective Sasamoto
Preliminary results confirmed the cause
of death was cardiac arrest, but...
Whether it was due to natural causes or human-induced...
Cannot be determined without a thorough investigation autopsy.
Human-induced?
Are you saying someone murdered Hikawa?
We cannot say at this point.
Yamao-san, at around 2:00 PM, what
were your actions and whereabouts?
This afternoon, Hikawa and I went our separate
ways, and I took a stroll in the east side woods.
All alone?
Yeah.
Did you bump into anyone?
No.
Understood.
Next...
Tachihara-san?
I was with Touma, who was sleeping due
to the fatigue from his morning checkup.
So I was at my house.
Can anyone verify that?
I'm afraid not.
Mutou-san?
I'd returned to my workshed near the dam and kept working.
Workshed?
Not the mountain cottage near where
Hikawa-san's body was found?
Right.
Is there anyone who can verify?
No one!
I don't meet up with people while I'm working!
But, why was Hikawa-san walking toward
your mountain cottage if that's so?
How would I know about something like that?
Were you really not at the mountain cottage?
What?
You called Hikawa out and killed him, didn't you?
By telling him you wanted to talk about Mizuki or something!
What do you mean by that?
When Hikawa was younger, he once
proposed to Mizuki but was rejected.
But Hikawa still had lingering feelings for Mizuki even now.
So if her name were to get mentioned, he would definitely go there.
So that's how it was.
I thought it was definitely Mutou-san who had the crush.
How could you say that I was definitely the one who killed Hikawa!?
Because it seems you guys were fighting about the dam!
I'm too flabbergasted to reply to bullshit like that.
Well then...
Lastly, Toono-san?
She was with us the entire time, so her alibi is solid.
Is that so?
I understand.
That will be all for today.
Once we confirm that Hikawa-san's death was a homicide...
We will conduct another round of detailed questioning.
Uhm, should we check their belongings?
At this stage, we can't force them to comply, can we?
Moreover, even if someone did steal the item,
they would have hidden it somewhere by now.
Everyone, thank you for your cooperation.
That mister speaks really slowly, doesn't he?
I thought I was gonna fall asleep...
So cold!
Why must we endure this in order to watch the sunrise?
Stick with it, stick with it.
I wonder who it was?
The culprit who killed Hikawa-san.
Yeah...
If it's Mutou-san...
Based on the shoeprints...
I think instead of the mountain cottage, he
was waiting in the middle of the snowfield.
And after the murder, he backtracked to the brook.
Just...
I don't understand why Hikawa-san had to walk past the brook
and through the snowfield where no one could see him.
Even if Mutou-san ordered him to do so, don't you think it's unnatural?
You're right.
I would've gone by car via the village road.
Moreover, is there a connection between
Hikawa-san's murder and the bombing incident?
Even if there is, I don't think this is the end of it.
Something else will definitely happen.
Not again...
I can't come to the phone right now.
Sorry for any inconvenience...
Not again.
You got Shin'ichi-kun's auto message again?
I wanted to talk to him about Hikawa-san, but...
Could he really be here in this village?
That deduction geek.
That's what she said.
Leave me alone.
And, please, what time does she think it is?
Hey, isn't that Touma-san?
Kuro...
Touma-kun!
Touma!
What's the matter, Touma-kun?
"Kuro's Grave"...
Kuro is the dog who found Touma-kun eight years ago?
Why...
Is Kuro really dead?
Touma!
What are you doing out here!?
Mom...
Why did you come out without telling me!?
Now, now, ma'am...
Why!?
Why did I become like this!?
I don't get it...
All my friends have become strangers...
And Kuro is dead...
I don't know what I'm supposed to do!
I don't get it!
Kuro...
Kuro!
Touma...
You can't blame the kid.
His body is that of a fifteen-year-old, but at heart he is still only seven.
It's probably hard for him to keep a grasp on reality.
That's just the opposite of us, isn't it?
Touma...
Mom!
Look!
The snow is glittering!
This isn't snow, but...
Diamond dust.
Diamond!?
There are gems coming down!?
That's not it.
The water vapor in the atmosphere solidifies due to the cold...
And becomes tiny crystals of ice, creating the phenomenon.
Here.
Touma-kun, look!
It's really pretty!
Awesome, right?
It's a treasure!
Touma?
What happened?
Are you all right, Touma?
His memories...
What was that?
I saw the same lights before...
No good, I can't remember!
Touma!
Touma-kun!
Touma-san...
Touma...
I can't...
Remember...
The diamond dust was really pretty, wasn't it?
Definitely!
I felt like I was in a fairyland!
Hostess!
One more helping!
Hey, the thing he was trying to remember...
Yeah.
It was likely part of his memories from
when he fell from the cliff eight years ago.
I tried to investigate it, but...
Because it had been snowing from dawn that day,
there hadn't been an occurrence of diamond dust.
In that case...
What exactly was it that he saw?
Oh yeah, where are Genta and the rest?
They said they were going to play with Touma-kun and went out.
Geez...
They'd better not be up to no good or something again!
Hey, where are we going?
If we go too far, I'll be scolded by my mom.
Hey, Touma-kun!
Shall we go near where you fell from the cliff?
If we do that, you might start remembering lots of things!
But...
We'll be with you!
Well?
Gather your courage and go for it!
Let's go!
Yay!
Let's do this!
Now...
Where did those kids go?
Probably to the campsite?
They're having the commemorative ceremony there.
Yeah, it's said to start at 10:00 AM.
Still a little over an hour.
It'll be fine as long as they aren't up to any mischief.
If they are, I'll definitely use my fist this time!
It's the people from the dam.
They probably came down to participate
in the commemorative ceremony.
That aside, is it really all right to leave the dam alone like that?
No worries, there are two caretakers back there.
You overheard me?
At least let us have some coffee here.
Thanks for the concern!
Geez, Sonoko.
I'll join you later, go ahead without me!
You'll fall if you run!
Got it!
Hello!
Miss, you're one of Touma-san's classmates, right?
Did you come to see Touma-san?
Yeah, there was something I wanted
to show him, but he seems to be out.
What's this thing that you wanted to show him?
So this is a photograph from eight years ago, huh?
We were about the same age as you.
Huh, those binoculars...
This was at school, right?
Yes.
He wore them around his neck even at school?
Right.
They were Touma-kun's trademark, so he'd
always wear them whenever he went out.
If that's so, he wasn't necessarily out looking for swans.
That was something Touma-kun gave me.
He really loved Kuro, didn't he?
I thought I'd show him the drawing and
photograph while having a chat, but...
That might hurt him more, I guess?
Back then...
Hikawa-san opened up the printed article that was folded
twice from the outside and showed it to everyone.
But, doesn't one usually fold the printed side
inwards to prevent it from getting dirty?
Something wrong with that drawing?
Nothing at all.
Thanks for showing it to me.
I gotta get back to the lodge!
You'll fall if you run!
I'll be all right!
Hey, can't I change the sheets inside?
Hold on, ya opened the door?
I wasn't supposed to?
Of course yer not supposed to!
They're gonna come and search fer fingerprints and shoeprints.
No way!
What should I do?
They're gonna suspect me!
Right, they're gonna catch ya!
Dun scare me like dat!
This is it.
Jewelry shop robbery...
"On the 15th at around 11:00 PM...
"An unknown perpetrator broke into Misuzu Jewelry
located in Yaoi City, Shinjuku Ward, Tokyo...
"And stabbed 51-year-old company president
Misuzu Eiko to death with a sharp blade.
"The robber allegedly made off with one billion yen worth of jewelry."
This incident...
If I recall, it happened when I was still in third grade...
They still haven't found the culprit.
But, why was Hikawa-san carrying this article?
Wait, this date...
It was the night before Yamao-san's hit-and-run accident!
That reminds me, at that time...
Yamao-san was sitting next to Hikawa-san.
Which means Yamao-san wasn't looking at the same side we were...
But instead at the opposite side.
In other words, he frowned because he saw this article.
Could it be...
Kudo-kun?
I lost contact with Tsuburaya-kun and the others.
What now?
Also—
Hello?
That was the cell phone base station, wasn't it?
Both of them!
Even the landline connection is cut!
So the base stations for both cell phones and the landlines were...
Hey, hey, an accident happened right on the day of our ceremony?
No, this isn't an accident at all!
Huh?
My cell phone isn't connecting...
It's out of range now...
Can you hear me, Haibara?
I can hear you.
How's the situation over there?
The cell phones aren't working, so people are in a bit of a panic.
As I expected.
And also, about the kids...
There were people who saw them with Touma-kun.
Afterward, the four of them seem to have gone somewhere.
Come back here Immediately!
Got it.
Those guys...
Don't tell me...
♪With overflowing strength...
♪Let's try out our courage!
Does this place look about right?
Yeah, I think so.
♪By uniting our hearts as one...
Hey, you're too noisy!
♪Let's leap forward and I'm sorry!
♪We know we're being noisy!
♪Step firmly on the ground...
How's it?
Someone still there?
♪And resoundingly we need to...
Keep walking...
Still there!
Why's this happening!?
What are you talking about?
Let's run!
Good idea!
Hold on!
We'll explain later!
Anyway, please run!
What's this about?
Since when were we being followed?
No idea!
By the time we realized, they were already there!
Some bad person?
No idea!
I'm so scared!
That's why we're running away!
At that time, I was also running away...
You hear that?
Yeah.
This is bad.
You should wait h—
There's no way I'm going to wait here!
Aren't you being a little too forward for a kid?
Yeah, yeah.
A cave!
Let's hide in there!
Hurry, hurry!
Wait, you all!
This is bad!
Haibara, they're all yours!
Got it!
Geez, those guys...
Why'd they have to go in?
Let's head further in.
This goes on for quite a bit!
Wait!
Haibara, hurry and get in!
You shouldn't have come in!
Do you want to die here!?
But adults can't come in here, can they?
Touma-kun was able to get in, wasn't he?
Moreover, what would you do if you were shot from the entrance!?
Geez!
You guys!
Why did you come in here!?
Just said that.
Now we have no choice but to go further in!
Yep, yep.
You were running from someone?
I just remembered that.
As I thought.
I can see the truth now.
This is bad!
If my deduction's correct...
Hey...
What's the matter?
Hurry up!
We have to get out of here and reach
the dam before the culprit does!
Something at the dam?
I have no idea what this is about!
Please explain properly!
I don't have any proof yet.
It's only my deduction, but...
The culprit behind all the incidents is...
Yamao-san!
If we assume he broke into a jewelry store in Tokyo eight years ago...
Killed the president and made off with jewelry worth one billion yen...
Everything falls into place.
Being pursued by loansharks over his debts, Yamao-san...
Headed for his grandmother's house in
his hometown of Kitanosawa Village.
And on the way there...
At the entrance of the village, he ran into Natsuki-san.
Yamao-san panicked.
If he were caught by the police right then,
the murder-robbery would be discovered.
Not to mention the stolen jewels were still in the car.
After hitting her, he stopped the car to
check on the victim as people normally do.
As he was looking at Natsuki-san under the cliff...
Most likely, he was spotted by someone...
Touma-san.
Me?
Touma-san, on that day, didn't you go after
your mother who had left before dawn?
You planned to meet her at the hospital so
you walked to the scene of the incident.
That's why...
Huh?
Mommy?
This is great!
I finally get to see Mommy!
Then, Touma-kun thought that was a continuation of eight years ago?
Yeah.
It must have been easy for Yamao-san to
knock Touma-san out and put him in the car.
The reason he kept driving was because he
couldn't decide what to do with Touma-san.
But, at that time, his cover had been blown.
Because Touma-san woke up and witnessed
the scattering of the stolen diamonds.
Then, what he was trying to remember
when he saw the diamond dust...
Was in fact the real treasure!
Since the jewels had been seen,
Yamao-san likely decided to take action.
Were the jewels at his grandma's house?
He must've hidden them somewhere.
Right.
Yamao-san was checking for the location of the old house.
He turned himself in because he was
sure he would be out in a few years.
However, the punishment was heavier than he thought...
And in the meantime, the village had sunk to the bottom of the dam.
In order to retrieve the jewels, he had to
somehow drain the water from the dam.
The water?
Drain it all?
That's why he targeted this ceremony.
Why is that?
Because the dam personnel would also participate in the ceremony!
Only two people remain as lookouts.
They would never dream of someone blowing it up.
If he does that, the village will—I
Everyone will die!
We have to get to the dam before he does!
Look!
There's light!
It's the exit!
We're out!
All clear.
You guys can come out.
The discharge conduit.
If we go in there...
No doubt about it.
It's the shortest distance.
Then, the one who killed Hikawa-san was also...
Yeah, it was Yamao-san.
On top of carrying out his plan, he had two obstacles to overcome.
One of them was Hikawa-san.
As a classmate in the village's branch school
and also an insurance investigator...
He found out that Yamao-san was
responsible for the jewelry robbery...
And on the condition of getting his share of
the loot, he offered to help with the crime.
So if we assume Yamao-san pretended to agree...
But in fact planned to murder Hikawa-san before blowing up the dam...
Then everything fits.
It didn't look to me that Hikawa-san
was merely blackmailing Yamao-san.
Moreover, for both the crime of blowing
up the dam and killing Hikawa-san...
The ideal scapegoat would be Mutou-san.
He made it seem as if it was a crime by M utou-san who loathed
Hikawa-san's betrayal of his hometown as well as the dam project.
But, how did he talk Hikawa-san into going to that place with him?
Well, this is just a guess, but...
What?
Mutou did?
It seems he got wind of our plan...
And said he wanted to meet up and talk.
Depending on the situation, we may have to finish him off first.
He likely said things like that in order to
get Hikawa-san willing to take action.
That's why the two of them walked through the valley
and the snowfield, to stay out of people's sight.
And the other obstacle was that the governor
would attend the commemorative ceremony.
If the governor were coming, the press and related
company would naturally come along with him.
Even if the base station explosions should
disable the cell phones and landlines...
It'd be unavoidable that news of
the dam's breakdown would leak.
I see.
Even if he managed to sink the whole village, he'd need time
afterwards in order to find the location of the hidden gems.
Therefore, in order to stop the governor from visiting the village...
And to test his explosives along the way, he blew up the tunnel.
However...
Touma-san returning to consciousness
was completely out of his expectation.
The sheer coincidence of Touma-san having amnesia over the
day of the incident was a reassuring break for him, but...
Due to the diamond dust acting as a trigger, his
lost memories were on the verge of returning.
So he figured he would just finish all of you at once.
After he gets the jewels, all he needs to do is take off.
He should already have a getaway plan in place.
Yeah.
What's wrong, Touma?
Are you tired?
No.
Did something I said ring a bell?
Yeah.
Somehow, something seems wrong.
I wonder what...
I'm sorry, but right now we have to hurry.
It took time for Yamao-san to attack Touma-san...
So he likely hasn't set the bombs on the dam yet.
Besides that, there are personnel there, right?
If that's the case, there's still hope.
Are we there yet?
Why is it nothing but uphill?
It's safe.
Come on up!
Be careful.
I'm tired...
Touma, you're nearly there, come on.
Somehow we managed to get into the dam without trouble.
It's nothing but trouble!
Are you all right?
I'm not...
I'm so exhausted I can't take another step...
Guess not...
You guys stay here and protect Touma-san.
I'll go notify the personnel on lookout.
Roger.
Please leave it to us.
I'll go look for Mutou-san's workshed.
It should be near here.
Be careful.
Yamao-san might have already beat us to it.
Got it.
You guys better go hide immediately.
All right.
This is...
Are you all right?
Please hang in there!
No external injuries...
They must've been knocked out with the stun gun.
Wait...
Don't tell me!
Those are the same types of bombs from the capital highway!
Damn, how did he...
Did he get here by car or snowmobile?
What's up?
Kudo-kun...
I've reached the workshed, but...
This is bad!
Mutou-san has been knocked out cold!
As I thought.
The dam personnel over here are also out cold.
The stun gun attack likely took them by surprise.
Wait a minute...
This is strange...
This is some incredibly fast work...
Kudo-kun!
What happened!?
Answer me, Kudo-kun!
Don't tell me...
Bombs!?
You're too loud!
We only confided in you since you're the famous detective Mouri-san.
If others hear of this, it'll likely result in panic!
My apologies.
And?
Have they been confirmed to have been time bombs?
We've received a report that fragments
of a timer were found at the scene.
We're worried about the two guys left
at the dam, so we're heading back.
We can't communicate with them from here, after all.
Is it impossible to use cell phones at the dam?
If you go near the dam, you'll see a base station.
I might be able to call Conan-kun's cell phone.
Yeah.
We'll go as well.
A gunshot again...
I wonder if Conan-kun is all right?
I'm worried...
I can't stand it anymore!
Let's go too!
Idiot of a brat!
If you simply enjoyed the Snow Festival like you were supposed to...
You could have died without any pain.
Out with it!
Where are your friends!?
I don't have any friends with me...
Looks like you won't know your place
without experiencing some more pain!
Bastard!
You brat...
The nerve of you!
I don't have time to play with you!
There ain't much time, so I'll trust you've really come alone.
Don't worry.
In fifteen minutes, when the explosions start...
Heaven'll immediately become really crowded!
Farewell...
Brat!
Mizuki-san...
The gunshot just now sounded different.
We have to hurry!
Hang on!
You guys!
Thank goodness, you're all right!
Ai-chan!
Haibara-san!
Haibara!
Mizuki...
Damn you!
Give it up, Yamao-kun.
Are you all right, Conan-kun?
Yeah.
That aside, why are you here?
Somehow, I had a bad premonition.
So I decided to hurry over.
What about your gun?
I have a license for shotguns.
I am a good shot.
Yeah, it seems that way.
Look out, Mizuki-san!
Hand it over, Mizuki!
Touma-san?
Hey...
What's the matter?
You're the...
You're the lady from back then!
You were wearing glasses before, but there's no doubt about it!
Sis, you don't understand anything about my dreams at all!
What're you doing!?
Ouch...
Why'd you do that!?
I see.
What Touma-san saw eight years ago...
Was Mizuki-san, wasn't it?
That's why you couldn't follow us into the cave.
You told Uncle Kogoro yesterday, didn't you?
I can't stand dark, narrow places...
Mizuki!
What in the world is this about!?
Conan-kun...
You mentioned the cave, but...
Don't tell me!
Yeah...
The person who attacked us earlier was Mizuki-san.
Mizuki-san was afraid that Touma-san, who witnessed
the whole incident, would regain consciousness.
As such, she began working the front desk of the
new village's lodge in front of Touma-san's house...
And secretly watched over him for eightyears.
Is that true, Mizuki?
After Touma-san regained consciousness...
You switched from glasses to contacts,
and altered your hairstyle slightly.
It was all to prevent Touma-san from recalling
who you were should he see your face.
You made use of Uncle's advice, didn't you?
I decided to try contact lenses.
But, it was to no avail, as Touma-san's
memories gradually began to return, so...
Before he could completely regain his
memories, you thought you'd silence him.
But, you're one mean elder sister.
To thrust your younger sister in front of a car.
I never meant to kill her!
I only wanted to make her fall and hurt her a little...
But, I didn't know Yamao-kun's car would happen
to pass by exactly where my sister had fallen!
If anyone found out, I wouldn't be able to stay here anymore.
When I thought of that, I was so afraid...
By the time I realized it, I had already grabbed my gun.
But...
But I just wanted to keep Touma-kun away from me...
That's why...
I really never intended to kill anyone!
I know.
I know Mizuki-san never intended to hurt anyone.
Because, if she had the skill to shoot through Yamao-san's shoulder
from that distance, and to accurately send the dropped gun flying...
We definitely would have been shot.
I'm sorry...
I'm sorry!
But, isn't it great, Mizuki?
With this, you can finally be freed from the eight years of
continuous torment brought about by that nightmare.
Thanks to that, I also got to see your pretty
face without it being covered by glasses.
Mutou-kun...
Well, I'll be waiting patiently.
For you to return here.
Always.
Edogawa-kun!
The light is blinking!
What!?
Damn it, back then...
Yamao-san said we had fifteen minutes.
Damn!
Everyone, run for it!
It's gonna explode!
Stop wasting time!
Hurry!
Touma, hurry!
Ayumi-chan!
Don't stop, keep going!
You all right?
Run!
This is bad.
If the explosions continue at this rate...
The whole dam will collapse!
No good, that sound...
It's the sound of the outer walls crumbling!
If I don't do something...
The collapse will only be a matter of time!
If all the water flows out from the dam at once...
The village will be completely destroyed!
Is there...
Is there nothing that can be done to save the village!?
The ski area?
Is anyone hurt?
Is everyone here?
Conan isn't here!
There's a boy who's missing!
What!?
I think he went missing after he saved me!
Conan-kun...
What are you doing?
What!?
There are still bombs left!?
Damn!
No good!
The dam's collapsing!
Everyone, please stay back!
No!
Conan-kun is still—!
Until Conan-kun comes, we won't move!
Conan!
What are you doing, Kudo-kun!?
Awesome!
Go, Conan!
Where's he going?
He intends to stop the flood!
Too reckless!
There's no way a kid can do it!
If he gets caught up in it, he won't have a chance!
He can do it!
Conan can do it!
Nothing is impossible for the Detective Boys!
It's all up to you...
Kudo-kun!
If I recall, there should be an unused ski area just in front of the village.
If I use that deep snow, maybe it'll work!
What the hell is that!?
This is bad!
The dam is...
It's dangerous!
We hafta retreat!
Damn...
At this rate, I can't make it in time!
It's risky, but I'll have to go through the forest!
Good...
That was close!
Damn!
Come on, just hang in there a bit longer!
Hey!
If all the water comes down at once, what'll happen to the village?
It'll be really bad!
We don't know how bad it'll be!
Without a doubt...
The whole village is gonna sink!
No way...
I can see it!
Conan-kun!
That kid...
What's he up to now?
An avalanche!
He's planning to start an avalanche to change the flow of the water!
Conan-kun!
Damn!
Not now!
Conan-kun!
No!
Shit...
Shit, shit, shit!
SHIT!
Not good!
That brat...
Freaking did it...
Run!
Please make it in time!
LOOK OUT!
Ran...
Conan-kun!
Brat!
Where are you!?
Conan!
Conan-kun!
Where are you!?
You there!?
Brat!
Conan kun!
I can hear everyone's voices...
Looks like they avoided getting caught in this...
I have to get out of here too or else...
This is bad...
I can't move...
Gotta...
Gotta do something...
Conan-kun!
Conan-kun...
Brat...
Brat!
How many minutes!?
How many minutes have passed!?
It was...
Eleven minutes and 50 seconds.
It's been almost twelve minutes since the avalanche occurred!
What'd you say!?
That means...
We only have three minutes until the 15-minute golden time is up!
No way!
Everyone!
Help them find Edogawa-kun!
Don't tell me, Conan-kun was...
Caught in the avalanche!?
Please...
Go through!
It went through!
Everyone, keep quiet!
Listen carefully for the kid's cell phone!
Conan-kun, where...
Where are you?
There!
What now!?
Conan-kun!
Where!?
Conan!
Conan-kun's cell phone!
Please...
Please come out, Conan-kun!
Over here!
Comb through every inch of this area!
Conan-kun!
Damn!
Not here either?
No.
No way...
Conan-kun, where...
Where are you!?
Please, come out!
Your hands are bleeding!
Why?
Why aren't you here!?
Conan-kun!
Conan-kun...
Will we ever see him a again...?
Once you sever your ties, you might not see each other ever again.
No way...
You're kidding, right...?
Conan-kun...
You can't die!
Less than one minute until the time limit!
Ran...
Don't give up!
What's wrong, Ran?
Shin'ichi...
Please...
If you're nearby...
If you're somewhere close, please help...
Help us, Shin'ichi!
Shin'ichi...
That was Ran's voice...
I have to tell her where I am...
That's...
A soccer ball!
Don't tell me!
Conan-kun...
Conan-kun!
He's here!
Over here!
Conan-kun...
Hang on, Conan-kun!
Please, Conan-kun...
Open your eyes!
Conan-kun!
Ran... neechan...
Thank goodness...
Thank goodness, Conan-kun...
All right!
As usual, he's a tough guy.
The following afternoon...
From the backyard of Yamao-san's previous
home that had sunk to the bottom of the dam...
A suitcase full of gems and jewelry was recovered.
Presented with the solid evidence,
Yamao-san confessed to everything.
And thus, the case was solved.
Mizuki-san also confessed to what she did to her sister eight years ago.
She would face police questioning.
As for Touma-kun, he hadn't yet regained the entirety of his memory.
But for the time when he recalls everything...
And showcases the smile he originally had...
One needs not wait too long.
About your baggage, I have scheduled a delivery to this address.
Thank you very much.
We're grateful for everything.
Although things turned out this way...
Please still feel free to come again!
Yes!
We'll come again!
We'll definitely come!
Hey, you guys, hurry up already!
If you mess about, I'm gonna leave you here!
Why's your dad in such a hurry?
I haven't bought a souvenir for Makoto-san!
Me neither!
Hold it, you guys!
We don't have that sort of time!
That reminds me...
What was it I needed to buy?
We also haven't finished buying a souvenir for Kobayashi-sensei!
It was the bear buns, right?
What are you talking about?
It's been decided she's getting the mug with swans!
I think the owl is nicer.
Huh, aren't those...
If it's too much of a hassle, why not get everything?
It's the professor's money anyway.
Hey, hey...
I see.
It was the kids who wrote this.
You guys, hurry up if you're gonna buy some souvenirs!
Hustle up!
If we don't hurry home, I won't be able to catch Yoko-chan's drama!
Only fifteen minutes!
I'm driving out in fifteen minutes!
No way!
Let's hurry!
Geez, a quarter-hour again?