♪ Cello Sonata No. 3 in A Major, Op. 69
Ludwig van Beethoven
Kabe Souko...
If you want to blame something, blame yourself...
That talent of yours...
It's all for the sake of the silent night.
I'm high school detective, Kudou Shinichi.
While visiting an amusement park with my childhood friend and classmate, Mouri Ran...
I witnessed a man in black in the midst of a suspicious transaction.
While caught up in watching the deal...
I failed to notice his other partner coming up from behind me.
I was forced by those men to swallow poison.
And when I came to...
My body had shrunk.
If those guys found out that Kudou Shinichi was still alive...
They'd try to kill me again...
And the people around me would be at risk.
At Professor Agasa's suggestion, I decided to conceal my true identity.
When Ran asked for my name, in that instant...
I became Edogawa Conan.
In order to obtain information about those guys...
I went to live with Ran, whose father is a private detective.
Let's go, Mitsuhiko!
Please leave it to me!
All right!
Mitsuhiko!
Conan-kun!
Huh?
Get it, Ayumi-chan!
Me?
Leave it to me!
Hooray!
These guys are my classmates now...
Genta...
Genta... Ayumi...
Genta... Ayumi... and Mitsuhiko.
They formed the Detective Boys...
And forced me to join.
There's one other member.
She is Haibara Ai.
Real name: Miyano Shiho.
Her parents, who passed away when she was a child, were scientists with the Black Organization.
Under the codename Sherry, she worked for them...
And developed that drug...
Apotoxin 4869.
However, her only sister, Miyano Akemi, was killed by those guys for resisting the Organization.
In order to end her own life, she took the drug...
And her body shrunk.
That's how she encountered us.
We are both living the lives of first year elementary school students...
Until I reveal those guys' true identities.
However, this tiny detective keeps forgetting his own situation.
In conjunction with his superb deduction skills...
Using inventions created by Professor Agasa, he has solved many cases one after another.
Thanks to him, I'm always having shivers run down my spine.
Well, it's music class now...
And he's sending shivers down my spine for a different reason.
Look, it's the usual people.
Even though I've gotten smaller, my mind remains the same...
The unbeaten great detective...
There's always one truth!
Doumoto Kazuki?
You've heard of him, haven't you, Shinichi?
Yeah.
Isn't he the founder of that music academy where that bombing occurred last week?
Actually...
I'm at that very place right now.
Doumoto-san was a renowned pianist.
But, unexpectedly, he switched to the organ.
And so, not only did they build a new concert hall...
They're bringing over a pipe organ from an old church in Germany.
You mean the one that Bach himself played?
We're going to be able to attend the opening concert of Doumoto Hall.
Furthermore, we even get to watch the rehearsal!
All thanks to Sonoko.
Oh yeah, Doumoto Hall was built by Suzuki Construction, wasn't it?
A piano key?
Did it fly all the way over here?
Say, why don't you come with, Shinichi?
You'll get to hear a Stradivarius played live.
Didn't you say you would like to hear one for yourself someday, since you play violin?
What's that person doing?
Hey, are you listening, Shinichi?
Oh, sorry, sorry.
Unfortunately, I'm in the middle of a case at the moment, so I'm a little busy.
Can't you take even a little time off?
The rehearsal is the day after tomorrow.
Sorry to disappoint you, but I'll have to pass.
The concert is next week on Tuesday.
I really can't go.
Like I said, I'm working on a case—
But, you might be done with it by then.
I already asked Sonoko to reserve a seat for—
Didn't I just say I couldn't? Don't go meddling in my affairs.
Damn.
I'm meddling?
Ah, no—
Ah! I see how it is!
I guess I'm just some meddlesome karate idiot.
You don't have to go that far...
Whatever.
Even if you listened to a Stradivarius, you'd never be anything like Holmes.
What?
Because, Shinichi...
You're tone-deaf!
Ran, you...
Well, keep on doing your best, Mr. Tone-Deaf Detective!
Jeez...
That deduction geek!
I'll never invite him again!
Jeez...
Hello?
Conan-kun?
What would you like for dinner tonight?
Uhm...
How about curry? Or is there something else...
Ah, no. Curry is fine.
That's good.
I'm really glad you're so agreeable, Conan-kun.
Well, be careful and come home before it gets dark, all right?
Yes!
See you!
So when I'm Conan, I'm "agreeable", huh?
♪ Toccata and Fugue in D Minor, BWV 565
Johann Sebastian Bach
Doumoto Kazuki Organist & Composer
Wonderful! Very well played!
That was excellent, Doumoto-san.
That had a different sort of charisma, as compared to the piano.
Wow, just like you'd expect from Doumoto Kazuki. That was magnificent indeed.
I've seen that person on TV before.
There, the man with the glasses.
Ah! That's Fuwa Takumi-san.
Fuwa Takumi Doumoto Hall Director
He has been Doumoto-san's sole piano tuner for the last 35 years.
He's now the director of Doumoto Hall.
That person...
The one who just turned around is a German, Hans Müller-san.
He's a pipe organ tuner.
Hans Müller Organ Tuner
He seems to be at ease now, but...
He's had frequent disputes with Doumoto-san in the past.
And, the one interpreting next to him is Doumoto-san's son...
Doumoto Genya Pianist & Doumoto Kazuki's Son
A pianist, Genya-san.
He's the organizer for the upcoming performance.
After that, we have those two ladies over there.
Both of them are Doumoto-san's pupils...
The lady on the right is from Doumoto Academy's 9th class...
Chigusa Rara Soprano
A soprano, Chigusa Rara-san.
The nervous-looking person next to her is from the same academy, from its 8th class...
Yamane Shion Violinist
A violinist, Yamane Shion-san.
Oh, she's substituting for the person who was injured in the bombing incident, Kabe Souko-san, then?
Right, right.
Kabe-san's Stradivarius just so happened to be away for adjustments at the time of the incident, so it wasn't damaged.
Shion-san is just borrowing it for the performance.
And, the person sitting in the very first row is...
Akiba Reiko-san, right?
The soprano.
I figured you would know her.
She is pretty famous, after all.
Akiba Reiko Soprano
All right, Shion, get ready.
Yes, sir.
We will start from the first piece, Ave Maria.
Judging from that, it seems you aren't ready to rehearse it with me yet, are you?
Oh, sorry, wait just one moment please.
My apologies.
We finally get to hear a Stradivarius in person, Sato-san!
If it were up to me, I'd prefer an Amati.
Be quiet!
♪ Ave Maria
Charles-Francois Gounod
That won't do, that won't do!
That's completely unacceptable!
What have you been doing for this past week?
My apologies.
Was there something wrong with it?
No, I thought it sounded perfect.
No...
For a Stradivarius, the sound isn't projecting properly...
One more time, from the top.
Yes, sir!
What?
What happened?
It looks like one of the violin strings snapped.
My apologies!
I'll go replace it immediately!
How is the sound balance with the organ?
Hmm, there's no problem.
My, my...
I wonder if I'll even get to sing today.
Akiba-san, a moment of your time?
Will you at least let me visit the powder room?
Mouri-kun...
Do you have any leads on the culprit behind the bombing?
No, not yet.
Plastic explosives were used though, right?
Yeah.
We also found a timer.
It was set to the time of the two victims' performance.
Then, wouldn't that mean...
Sorry, Mouri-kun.
I can't discuss details pertaining to the investigation here and now.
Especially with children around...
Children?
Go play with the other children!
Yeah, yeah...
It's so huge!
It's not just big, but beautiful as well.
It's amazing, isn't it?
Hey, how do pipe organs make sound?
The principle behind the sound production here is the same as with the recorders you play at school.
Look, there are a lot of pipes lined up together, aren't there?
Just like when you blow into a recorder, sound is produced when air passes through each of these pipes.
Air?
Really?
But there aren't any holes on those pipes like on a recorder!
Right.
For a recorder, you cover the holes with your fingers in order to produce notes of different pitches.
But, for a pipe organ...
You press keys. Then, sound comes out of the pipe corresponding to the key you pressed.
Each pipe produces its own unique sound.
What are those switch-like things?
Oh, these?
These are known as stops.
When you pull these out, each one causes a different tone to be produced.
For instance, if I pull this one out...
That's a trumpet!
A flute!
Organists use a combination of all these sounds to add variety to their performance.
I see!
We learned something new today!
And now, once again it's...
Time for the long-awaited quiz!
No one's been waiting...
A certain opera singer had a sore throat and was awaiting an operation.
However, they decided against the operation and got better after taking a pill they got from an old man.
And now, from the following options, who was the singer?
1. Soprano.
2. Alto.
3. Tenor.
4. Bass.
This one's difficult...
Professor, how about a hint?
How do you say operation in English?
Operation.
We usually just say "ope".
And also, it's an old man's pill, right?
Conan-kun, you already know?
Yeah.
It's easy.
First of all...
Number one.
The answer is number one: Soprano.
An opera singer gave up on an operation...
So you take away ope from opera, leaving ra.
A pill is some medicine that's small and round.
Thus, the "old man's pill" means using a small circle with the word sofu (grandfather).
When you combine that with the ra from before...
Ra...
"Sofu" with...
A small circle...
Soprano!
How stupid.
You're right, but you didn't have to say it was stupid...
Excuse me, Akiba-san.
We've been waiting to talk...
Sheesh.
This had better be over quickly.
We would like to ask you one more time about the e-mail Kabe Souko-san sent you just before the explosion.
It's impossible to work with a bunch of amateurs who can't differentiate between sounds.
What is the meaning of this e-mail?
The meaning?
It's just like it says.
I've mentioned it before, Kabe-san and I are...
You met her for the first time during the press conference for this public concert, right?
Yeah.
At that time, she said she would listen to the performances of those two who passed away...
And would e-mail me her thoughts.
In other words, based on the difference between those two people's style and Kabe-san's style...
As a musician, her remark that they couldn't tell the difference between sounds...
Meant they couldn't perform together, isn't that right?
Something like that, I suppose.
Why don't you ask her directly?
Hasn't she regained consciousness yet?
Yes, she is awake, but...
Due to the shock of the explosion...
She's lost her memory of the incident.
Is that so?
There's one more thing.
This item was found at the crime scene.
The body joint of a flute!
That's right.
The head joint, the body joint, and the foot joint. A flute can be separated into those three sections.
Could it be that some student left it behind?
That's possible, but only the body joint being there makes it strange.
Does anything come to mind?
Akiba-san?
No, nothing.
I've had enough.
Wait, Akiba-san!
What's that?
What's that you're drinking?
Tea.
Let us have some too!
Nope.
Stingy.
Could it be that there are ingredients
in it that are good for the throat?
Nothing like that.
If that were really true, we might be able to get first in the chorus competition if we drank it!
Chorus competition?
Yeah!
There's an inter-class chorus competition coming up.
I know!
Why don't you coach us for the competition?
We'll be practicing in our school's music classroom the day after tomorrow starting at 2:00 P.M.
Even though Ran-oneesan will be playing the piano for us...
The person showing us how to sing is the problem.
Hey, you brats!
Who did you say was a problem?
Jeez!
I'm sorry. Please don't mind them.
I hope the song isn't the 9th (daiku).
I don't like that one.
It isn't the Carpenter's (daiku) Song!
It's Teitan Elementary's school song!
When she said 9th (daiku), she meant Beethoven's 9th Symphony.
Is that true?
Fine.
I'll be your chorus coach.
Think of it as a favor from a Teitan Elementary alumnus.
Is that so?
Therefore, please go home now.
And stay out of the way.
Yes...
Although I'm glad to have her be our chorus coach...
That old lady is kind of rude...
A bit.
She seems to give off the stereotypical celebrity aura...
Yeah.
She's a little like you, Haibara.
No, I mean, she's really pretty...
I can't tell whether Akiba-san is actually ill-tempered or kind.
Yeah. But perhaps...
Maybe she chased everyone out because she was being considerate of Shion-san, who was so nervous.
Aren't you reading too much into it?
You think so?
Love - 30.
Jeez, getting all serious against an impromptu opponent.
A lion goes all out even when chasing a rabbit.
Yes, yes...
I guess I'm the "rabbit" then.
Oh yeah, let's do mixed doubles next time.
We can call Makoto-san and Shinichi-kun.
Shinichi?
That deduction geek...
No way...
I see, so you're having a fight with Shinichi-kun.
I can't do anything about a matrimonial quarrel, you know.
It's nothing like that!
But you two are always like that...
You always make up right away afterwards.
But it lasted a long time back then...
You didn't talk to each other for about a week, right?
When was that?
Remember, when we just turned twelve...
Ah, I remember!
That's the time...
Wait, what were we fighting about?
Then, how did the both of you make up?
You forgot everything?
I think it was...
Stop, stop. Hold it right there.
Why did you two go home together when you were fighting?
Because our houses were in the same direction.
I give up.
Continue.
At that time, someone was singing...
At that time, we heard someone singing by the river bank.
And, as we listened, somehow we just...
You made up!
And? What song was it?
What was it?
Huh? I think it was a famous song, but...
Hey, hey...
But, how should I put it...
It was a song that reached into my heart.
How was it?
The children's singing?
Let's see...
Firstly, you!
Your voice is too loud.
Try to blend in with the others!
And the freckled boy next to him.
Even though you're in tune, occasionally you're lacking in feeling.
Could it be because you keep staring at the face of the girl in front of you?
In front?
Isn't it Haibara?
And, this girl.
You sing well...
But you should sing more like a child.
It's because I'm not a child.
Hey, hey...
Your pitch is accurate and you sing with expression, well done.
As for you, don't be cramped by voices around you.
Have more confidence.
She's just like you'd expect.
Even without listening properly, she can tell everyone's voices apart.
Yeah.
A musician's ears.
The problem is...
You!
Yes?
You were completely out of tune from beginning to end!
You weren't doing it on purpose, were you?
No.
It wasn't on purpose!
It's just that Conan-kun is tone-deaf!
What sort of follow-up is that?
Worst of all, the piano sounded weird too.
The sound was flat the whole time.
Hasn't it been tuned properly?
Really?
No way. I didn't notice anything.
I thought so too.
This person...
Akiba-san...
Do you have perfect pitch?
Yeah, you could say that.
What's that? "Perfect pitch"?
It's the ability to listen to a sound and be able to name the pitch and note immediately.
For instance...
E5 - Mi.
B3 and F5's - Si and Fa.
That's right!
Amazing!
That's why you are so good at singing!
Well, I wonder...
I don't know that perfect pitch is absolutely necessary for a musician, but still...
It seems to be an inborn ability for me.
I've heard you can achieve it through training as well.
I believe that was likely the case with the former piano tuner, Fuwa-san.
Well, that's all for me.
For the rest, please practice on your own.
If your singing gets better...
I'll listen again.
You're leaving already?
We would like to hear a demonstration before you leave.
Agreed!
How much are you paying me?
Professionals don't sing without being paid.
See you.
This is it, this is it...
Hey! That's my tea!
Thanks for the tea!
What's wrong, Genta?
What's going on?
Genta-kun!
Are you all right, Genta-kun?
Someone put something in there...
That's what you're thinking, right?
Impossible!
How could this...
At any rate, let's get him to the hospital.
Will Genta-kun be all right?
He seemed to be in a lot of pain, huh?
His eyes were all red.
When was the last time you drank any of that tea?
Sometime before noon, I would think.
Where?
I borrowed a practice room at the Doumoto Academy...
In order to practice my singing.
Before leaving, I went to the ladies' room.
During that time, I left that bottle, along with the rest of my things, in the practice room.
If someone had put something in it...
It would have been then.
But, who could it be?
Thank you very much.
Genta-kun!
Are you all right?
Not all right at all...
What did the doctor say?
His throat is quite inflamed, but...
He'll recover in four or five days.
You'll recover!
Thank goodness!
But, on the contrary, it means that he can't speak properly for the next four days.
Yeah.
There are three more days until the Doumoto Hall concert.
If Reiko-san had drank from it...
She might have been unable to perform.
Tell Inspector Megure...
To analyze the contents of that bottle.
Then, I'll go report it.
But, before that...
As for Genta-kun, we'll get him home.
Me too.
I'll go too.
I must meet this boy's parents and ask them...
"How can he take someone else's drink without permission?"
"What sort of upbringing did he have?"
I'm sorry...
Genta-kun...
Cheer up, Genta-kun.
Those four days...
Will pass by in a flash.
I also want... to take... the old man's pill.
It's really the professor's quiz come true.
Everyone, step to the side.
No!
Run!
Hurry!
Damn! I can't see their face!
Now! Turn right!
What!?
Are you all right!?
Shit!
Are you all right?
Yeah...
What was with that truck?
Going the wrong direction on a one-way street!
Reiko-sensei!
Your leg's bleeding...
It's no big deal.
Did the attack stop because of the taxi?
Or was it...
Well, sorry, but I'll leave these kids to you.
I'm going home in this taxi.
Tell the police about what just happened.
You're leaving?
Being with you is just bringing me bad luck.
How could you...
That's mean.
Inspector!
What about the cause of the explosion?
Yes.
We've determined that the room was filled by leaking propane gas, which was ignited by the lighting of a match.
However, there's evidence that the gas detector had been deliberately broken.
That means it wasn't an accident; it was murder.
The deceased was the shop owner...
Shida Osamu-san, aged 36.
Shida-san was a violinist and was from Doumoto Academy's 1st class.
The 1st class?
It's the same as the two victims of the last bombing incident.
I don't think that's just a coincidence.
Yeah.
It wasn't a coincidence.
Detective Sato.
We found this inside the shop.
What's this?
The foot joint of a flute.
There's no doubt about it.
This is a series of murders committed by the same culprit.
Furthermore, the culprit has left us a message.
The body joint and the foot joint, huh?
There's still the head joint left.
In that case, there will be another murder...
The man who drowned after falling from his paraglider yesterday, Sone Hisao-san, right?
Yeah.
He seems to have been a viola player...
The thing is, we've found out that he was a student in Doumoto Academy's 1st class.
In that case, could it be...
Yeah.
He was a classmate of the victims from last week, Mizumi-san and Renjou-san...
Along with Shida-san, who died in an explosion two days ago.
Furthermore, until two years ago, the four of them were members of a piano quartet.
As I thought, it was a series of murders by the same culprit.
There's no doubt about it.
According to what the prefectural police said, the cloth wings...
And the canopy showed traces of minute cuts from a bladed object.
And on top of that, under the seat in Sone-san's car...
You found the remaining section of the flute, the head joint, right?
Y-Yeah...
But if all the flute parts have been assembled...
Doesn't that mean this is the end of the serial murders?
I would hope so.
Oh yeah, Ran-kun.
Yes?
In the thermos that you left with us...
The forensics examination found that...
Chemicals of a highly irritative nature were present.
It's too serious to be passed off as a prank.
And the truck that attacked us?
It had been stolen somewhere near the scene.
In other words, since placing a drug in the thermos...
Failed to hurt Akiba-san...
They went to their next plan and stole a truck to run her over...
All to achieve their original objective.
That objective being, to render Akiba-san unable to perform at Doumoto Hall's opening.
Say, if Reiko-san couldn't appear for the public performance...
Who would replace her?
Most likely Chigusa Rara, I'd imagine.
Initially, she was the first choice for the soprano part.
She's a member of Doumoto Academy's 9th class, and also Doumoto-shi's pupil.
But at this point...
The already confirmed performer, Kabe Souko-san...
Recommended Akiba-san, with whom she had desired to perform, for the part.
And that's how they decided on her.
And so, the next question would be...
How do these four factor into the case?
As of now...
We haven't found any connection between Akiba-san and the four others.
All that we know is...
The connection between Kabe-san and the first two bombing victims.
But there's still the issue of the performance...
The bomb was planted under the floorboard near the two victims.
If that's the case...
Kabe-san was simply unfortunate to be involved?
It's too early to decide that.
There are others with motives to kill Kabe-san.
You mean the candidate before Akiba-san, Chigusa Rara?
There's one more.
Kabe-san's replacement, Yamane Shion.
Her too?
Yeah.
If, after borrowing the Stradivarius from Kabe-san...
She were to perform at this concert, which is attended by internationally renowned musicians...
And give an outstanding performance...
She could become world famous overnight.
However, there's one more possibility.
She was one of Doumoto-shi's prized students.
The truth is, the reason that Kabe-san was selected for the performance...
Wasn't that he wanted her, but rather he had his eye on her Stradivarius.
He had always intended for Shion-san to perform.
And so, he designated her as the stand-in at the onset.
Then, he ensured that Kabe-san was seriously injured in order to get his hands on the Stradivarius.
This possibility cannot be dismissed either.
Human relationships are so complicated; it's becoming even harder to understand.
In short...
The person who has a motive against both Kabe-san and Reiko-san is Chigusa Rara-san, right?
Those who have a motive only against Kabe-san are Doumoto-san and Shion-san.
But we still haven't discovered what motives these three may have had for killing the other four.
Is that right?
Yeah, that's right.
Oh yeah, the piano in the practice room where the explosion occurred...
Could there be anything special about it?
No, I haven't heard that there's anything special, but...
Why do you think that?
When I went there the other day...
I saw Fuwa-san holding onto a fragment of a piano key, as though it were really precious.
So I thought there might be something special about it...
Hey!
Don't go wandering around on your own!
Sorry...
That piano was the one Doumoto-shi played in his home for more than 30 years, wasn't it?
When he retired from being a pianist...
He decided to move it to the academy so that the younger musicians could practice on it.
Of course, when the piano was in Doumoto-shi's home...
And even after it was moved to the academy...
It was always tuned by Fuwa-shi.
Well, perhaps to him, the piano was just like a son.
Got that, brat?
Come to think of it...
Fuwa-san was criticizing those four before...
He said their problem was their shallow approach to life or something.
But there's no way he'd kill the four of them over that, would he?
I guess not.
If, for the sake of argument, you assume he wanted to kill them because he couldn't stand their approach to life or whatever...
That still doesn't connect to what just happened with Akiba-san.
Inspector-dono...
Wouldn't it be best to consider Akiba-san's case separate from the other four?
But, all these cases so far have been centered around Doumoto-shi...
I don't think that can all be a mere coincidence.
I suppose...
Still, at any rate...
At the very least, before the end of the concert in two days...
We have to consider whether to guard Akiba-san.
I already sent Takagi-kun, but...
Um...
She turned me away, saying I was annoying...
Jeez...
What the hell were you thinking, Takagi?
If Reiko-san is attacked again...
Not even a written apology will help anything.
Ah, but she said she would be staying home today and tomorrow...
You idiot!
Is there anyone who would just say "Oh, I see," and leave!?
I'm sorry!
I'm leaving!
Conan-kun!
Morning, Conan-kun!
Good morning!
What's with you guys?
So early in the morning.
We're going to see Kamen Yaiba!
Kamen Yaiba?
They'll be filming in Ryokuchi Park today, by the Teimuzu River...
According to the top secret information I got!
We think that Genta-kun will recover after seeing that.
I can't see how that would make him better...
So we came to invite you, Conan-kun, but...
Are you going somewhere?
Yeah, sort of.
Sort of?
It's nothing big.
Could it be more important than your friendship with Genta-kun?
I guess I have no choice.
I'm going to Reiko-san's.
Reiko-sensei?
You'd better not!
She'll get mad again.
Yeah, I guess, but if I don't protect her from the bad guys...
By "bad guys," you mean from that time?
Why do you have to protect her?
Yeah, I wonder why that is...
I don't really know myself, but...
Somehow I feel that I can't live with myself if I don't.
He must mean that he's in love...
Conan-kun prefers older women.
How can that be?
Anyway, I'll leave Genta to the two of you.
I'm relying on you.
Conan-kun!
Does that mean that he trusts us?
Probably.
Yes?
Good morning, Reiko-san!
I'm coming in!
Hey, you!
This is a nice apartment!
And it seems to be a really quiet neighborhood.
Wait, you...
How can you go suddenly barging into people's homes?
What do you want?
Singing lessons.
I was thinking of some intensive training.
Now that you mention it...
You're that tone-deaf boy.
But I can't today.
Are you going out?
I've heard that on the day before an important concert or recording...
You always go soak in the forest air to refresh yourself.
Since you already know, why are you still here?
I was thinking of going along too.
Sheesh...
Didn't I say so earlier?
I have bad luck when I'm around you guys, so just stay away.
So if you keep your distance from us...
You will guarantee our safety.
That's because you believe you're the one the culprit's after.
When you said you wanted to go to Genta's house back then...
It wasn't to complain to his parents...
But to ensure Genta reached home safely, right?
What kind of stupid talk is this?
Oh yeah, can I have some juice before you go out?
I'm thirsty.
I suppose I must...
It'll have to be 100% orange juice.
Don't ask for the moon.
Yeah, that's fine.
A flute.
And that man is...
Hey!
It's ten years too soon for you to be interested in a lady's bedroom!
Say, Reiko-san, do you play the flute too?
That's none of your business.
Go home as soon as you're done drinking that.
I'm not giving you any singing lessons...
Nor am I taking you along to the forest.
OK...
I'm just following you on my own. Don't mind me.
Whatever...
It's not my fault if you get lost.
No worries, no worries.
Inspector Megure!
We've found the connection between Akiba-san and those four.
What?
Three years ago, in January...
At a Doumoto Academy lodging house in Izu...
A flute player who was lodging with them...
Got drunk, fell from a nearby cliff, and passed away.
Souma Hikaru-san, age twenty-eight at the time.
He was in Doumoto Academy's 6th class.
Could it be that they...
Yeah.
They forced him to drink, even though he couldn't hold his liquor...
As this had no direct relation with the fall, it was handled as an unfortunate accident.
I see.
Then, what's the link with Akiba-san?
The thing is, this person, Souma-san, was Akiba-san's fiancé.
What?
Inspector...
That does mean it's likely that she would have a grudge against those four.
But why would she be attacked as well?
Hello!
Hello.
Are the two of them mother and son?
They don't look alike at all.
Why are they walking so far apart?
Maybe he made his mother angry?
Jeez...
Say...
Do you know why I am taking a walk through the forest on the day before a concert?
I want to capture the natural world inside of me.
It's because European music is born out of the natural surroundings.
Do you understand what I mean?
Yeah.
I have a hunch that I do.
Are you all right, Reiko-san!?
Yeah...
Run!
Go on ahead!
The attack came, like I expected...
Damn it!
About to fire...
Reiko-san, this way!
Why?
Why didn't they shoot?
What are they after?
Say, don't you think we should report this to the police?
We can't.
I already said, if we were to take this to the police...
It would take up a lot of time and interfere with tomorrow's concert, right?
I understand that, but...
If you understand, then keep quiet.
After the concert, I will tell them properly.
All right?
Yes...
Detective Takagi?
Akiba-san?
And Conan-kun?
Akiba-san, where did you go?
Didn't you say you wouldn't be going anywhere today?
I had a date with this boy.
A d-date?
Akiba-san, we'd like to talk with you...
Some other time.
And if it's about Souma Hikaru-san?
Souma Hikaru-san was your fiancé, wasn't he?
Inspector...
I will tell you everything that I know...
But, I only ask that it be after tomorrow's concert.
Say, Inspector...
Did Souma-san have a mole here?
Yeah, that's right, but how did you know?
There's a photo of him in Reiko-san's apartment.
There's one in Akiba-san's apartment?
I know! How about you take me home...
And I'll tell you everything there?
And so, we brought Conan-kun home...
But in the end, all he knew was that she had a picture of Souma-san and a flute displayed in her apartment.
Jeez...
But, Inspector-dono...
Even if she had a motive to kill those four...
That alone doesn't make her the culprit, does it?
She was actually attacked by that truck.
Say...
Does Souma-san have any relatives who would want to avenge him?
No, I don't think there's anyone.
Uhm...
I made some tea.
Oh, thank you.
Sorry to trouble you, Ran-kun.
Help yourself.
Let's see...
His mother was reportedly unmarried,
she passed away five years ago.
He had no siblings.
And his father?
No, we don't know.
We're uncertain as to whether he's even still alive.
What's that?
There's one other issue with those four that died.
They once performed a concert while drunk.
Afterwards, they were all severely scolded by Doumoto-shi.
What!?
When did that happen?
R-Right!
Let's see...
Found it.
It was at a concert one year ago.
The performance piece was Beethoven's Piano Quartet.
I understand it now, Inspector-dono.
The motive and the culprit behind the deaths of those four, the grave injuries of Kabe-san and the attacks on Akiba-san...
Really, Mouri-kun!?
Yes.
The culprit is...
Doumoto Genya-san...
It's you!
The reason is...
You're an avid Beethoven fan.
And...
To the point of being an extremist!
Hey, hey...
What are you talking about all of a sudden?
You murdered the four of them because they got drunk and performed Beethoven's work so poorly.
It was an insult to the great composer.
You injured Kabe-san because when you last performed together, her interpretation of the piece completely opposed yours.
This was also mentioned in great detail in Kabe-san's short essays collection.
Finally, you attacked Akiba-san because she said, during rehearsal...
I hope it isn't the 9th (daiku).
I don't like that one.
That was an insult to Beethoven's 9th.
Hold on a minute please!
Indeed, I like Beethoven...
And I respect him, but I wouldn't do anything like that.
No, there's no doubt about it.
The fact that you have the same hairstyle as Beethoven is the proof!
M-Mouri-kun?
Don't joke around!
This hairstyle is natural!
It's just that I resemble my late mother!
If you think I'm lying...
Please look at this!
Indeed.
It's just like his.
What do you think?
Regarding the four victims and Akiba-san...
Other than Beethoven, there is no relation whatsoever!
Both Kabe-san and I are musicians.
We do sometimes have vehement disputes due to differing interpretations.
However, all of that is limited to the performance!
We will never come to hate each other for such absurd reasons!
Don't say such ridiculous things!
No, I mean...
Inspector!
You intruded on us at this time of night just to have us listen to such a lame-brained deduction?
Furthermore, there's a very important concert tomorrow.
That's very true.
In any case, please leave for tonight.
When the concert is over, we will answer any questions to your satisfaction.
Gee, I really thought I was right.
Where did you get that confidence from?
Say, Detective Takagi...
Kabe-san still hasn't recovered her memories?
Yeah, that's right.
She's starting to be able to chat about things, but...
She's saying stuff like how she notices the pitch of the sound the air conditioner makes and can't sleep.
She's sure saying some incomprehensible things, huh?
The pitch in the sound of the air-conditioner?
Could it be...
You don't have to take it out now.
Oh, sorry.
Please, use this.
Yes.
It will be exactly the same as the public performance.
To be able to choose your seat in an empty concert hall and listen to them play makes dress rehearsals worthwhile.
Our seats for the public performance are upstairs.
I asked Papa to get them.
You mean balcony seats?
There are a total of ten seats, all reserved for us.
Ten of us?
I invited Professor Agasa and the kids as well.
And one more for Shinichi-kun...
Let him know about it.
The ticket will be left at the reception desk.
There's no need to worry about him.
It's all right. Hurry, or the seat will be wasted!
I guess I have no choice.
But I don't think he'll come.
I'm sorry, Ran.
About yesterday, it seems you kept it from the police.
You have my gratitude for that.
Don't worry about that...
How's the wound on your leg?
It won't affect my singing.
Say...
Kabe Souko-san has perfect pitch as well, doesn't she?
Yeah, I figured that out when we met face to face.
We got along pretty well.
Does that mean anything?
It's nothing.
Oh?
Well, I have to go.
Good luck with the concert.
Both Reiko-san and Kabe-san have perfect pitch.
That means...
I'll get upset if we talk over the phone, so I just sent an e-mail.
Oh?
It'll be good if Shinichi-kun can come.
I'm fine with it either way.
It's just that the seat will be wasted...
That's what I said before.
Oh, really?
It can't be helped, let's start without him.
Is something wrong?
Oh, Mouri-san.
Müller-san hasn't come.
You mean the organ tuner?
We agreed that he would be present at the dress rehearsal to do any fine tuning.
Jeez, this is really troublesome!
He didn't take any of my calls, and the hotel staff said he hasn't returned since last night.
Since last night?
Well, it's only the fine tuning that's left, so it won't be a problem even if he doesn't come.
But doesn't that mean he's gone missing?
Have you reported this to the police?
No.
It'll be troublesome, since the questioning will take quite a bit of time.
For now, we want to concentrate on the concert.
Shion-san seems like a completely different person.
♪ Ave Maria
Charles-Francois Gounod
Her voice...
Shion-san's violin playing was fantastic!
Really! It was completely different from the last rehearsal!
She really made that Stradivarius her own!
What would you know about it?
Not to mention, Reiko-san's singing was wonderful!
Conan-kun!
You guys are way too early.
That's because you aren't allowed in even if you're only a minute late.
We asked the professor to bring us here early.
Hey, what's that you're holding?
Isn't that a recorder?
Are you an idiot?
Who would bring something like that to a classical concert?
Don't scold him.
Genta-kun can't talk, so he wanted to at least make some sounds.
Even so...
Of course, he won't play it during the performance.
Isn't that right, Genta?
That means yes.
Keep it hidden when you're in the hall!
Cellphones are forbidden too.
They know.
They even left their detective badges behind.
Hey, I'm hungry.
Well, if we're hungry, let's get something to eat.
Sounds good.
The performance is at 5:00, and it wouldn't do if our stomachs were growling then.
He's saying eel rice, eel rice!
If only you could hold a conversation with a recorder, huh?
Well, it's not like you couldn't do it.
All you have to do is to change the notes into letters.
Change the notes...
Into letters?
However, I mean using the alphabet, so Kojima-kun wouldn't be able to do that yet.
That sound is bothering me...
Ran-neechan, I just remembered that there's something I have to do.
I promise I'll be in my seat before the curtain rises.
Wait, Conan-kun!
What a selfish brat...
That note!
Isn't that note a little flat?
Yeah.
I have the same feeling.
I noticed it while singing.
But, even though I know which key it is...
I don't know which stop and timbre it was.
That's because there were several pipes sounding at the same time.
It does sound slightly flat.
There's no doubt about it.
It's coming from somewhere in that area.
I think it's probably one of the short, inner pipes.
One of them must have gone out of tune.
It will need tuning prior to the performance.
But aren't Müller-san's whereabouts unknown?
That's true.
At any rate, we have to inform Doumoto-san...
He doesn't seem to be in.
Guess not.
Perhaps he went out for tea or something?
Or maybe he's there...
But, you know, I'm surprised you noticed the note.
My ears are sharp.
They're more than good.
Maybe you have perfect pitch too.
If only that were so.
Doumoto-san doesn't seem to be here...
Do you know of any other places where he might be?
Not really...
Maybe he did go out for tea, just like you said.
Ladies and gentlemen, your attention please.
Please bear in mind that smoking is permitted only in the designated areas.
Akiba-san's still not here?
No.
I called her cellphone but no one picked up.
I have the staff searching the area for her as well, but...
Could she have gone missing?
I don't know.
Müller-san, and now even her...
Why the heck is this happening?
There are only fifteen minutes until the performance.
If she doesn't turn up by then...
Please allow me to take her place.
Because of what happened to Kabe-san...
I thought that something like this might happen too...
And I've been practicing very hard.
But...
I beg you, Sensei!
I promise I'll sing better than Akiba-san!
There's no need for you to sing better than her.
Music is the connection between us humans and God.
You must sing as though in prayer.
Shinichi-kun didn't turn up after all...
Even so, what's happened to Conan-kun?
It's going to start soon...
Really, where could Conan-kun have gone?
Still, since it's Conan-kun, I'm sure he'll be all right.
I believe in him.
That's right.
Just like Conan-kun believed in us...
We have to too!
Conan-kun will definitely be all right.
Ladies and gentlemen, your attention please.
Due to unforseen circumstances, Akiba Reiko...
Will not be performing today.
She is being replaced by Chigusa Rara, of Doumoto Music Academy's 9th class.
We seek your understanding on this matter.
Why?
But she sang so well during the dress rehearsal!
Could it be that she and Shinichi are in trouble?
A vinyl sheet?
What?
Reiko-san!
What!?
Where are we?
This is probably downstream on the canal.
The culprit who attacked us...
Set us adrift from the lake behind Doumoto Hall and let the canal carry us here.
But, who would...
I don't know.
Moreover, why did he bother to put us in a boat after knocking us out?
Anyway, if we don't return soon...
The concert will be...
But, even if we were to swim across...
That wall is too high for us to climb.
There doesn't seem to be anyone around.
But, look!
There's a telephone on that wall over there!
If we can reach it, we can call for help...
Hold on a second.
Even if we can't reach the phone...
If we can remove the receiver, we may be able to call for help.
How are we going to do that?
When you dial the numbers to make a call...
It makes those "pi, po, pa" sounds, right?
That's known as the DTMF signal.
It uses a combination of both a high and a low signal...
To transmit the telephone number.
So, if we can successfully produce those sounds...
We can make a call, right?
The "1" in the emergency number "110" is 697 Hertz and 1209 Hertz.
"0" should be a combination of 941 Hertz and 1336 Hertz.
All right.
I can remember the dial sounds.
But first, we have to get the receiver off...
Leave that to me.
However, the problem is that after the receiver is off for a while...
You can no longer make a call.
That means we can only challenge this once.
If we fail, we'll have to wait until someone finds us.
We don't have any time to waste.
Let's do it!
Since we've decided...
Let's have a quick rehearsal!
What was that just now?
An explosion...
Something exploded!
It was in the direction of Doumoto Hall!
Could it be...
We are on-scene at Nishitama City's Music Woods.
Just moments ago, two explosions occurred here at the Doumoto Hall.
The explosions were at the innermost section on the left and...
At the stage door, center section on the right.
The concert began five minutes ago.
The situation inside is currently...
Another one...
Hurry! Next is the sound for "0"!
That should do it.
Let's row the boat over.
This will do.
Stop the boat.
So, how do you intend to remove the receiver?
Just wait and see.
Amazing!
Let's do it!
Hello, this is the 110 communication headquarters.
Akiba-san and Conan-kun are?
Yeah.
It seems they were knocked out by someone, placed in a boat, and washed downstream on the canal.
The location is in Nishitama City, at the Nishitama Reservoir Sluice Gate Operations Center.
They're here!
I see them!
Over there!
It really was Doumoto Hall?
There have been over ten explosions so far...
All of which were on the external pillars of the building.
The cause is still...
Someone planted bombs there.
Even though we don't know whether they're on a timer or remote-controlled...
Most likely, we're dealing with the same person responsible for killing the four musicians.
Exactly.
The first incident was also an explosion.
But...
Why didn't he just kill us instead of sending us away from the concert hall?
Could it be that she...
Another one.
Say...
Can't you contact anyone inside?
Ran-neechan, Uncle and the others are all in there.
Yes, but we can't get through...
The culprit may have cut the lines.
But what about cellphones?
That won't work.
It's courteous to switch off cellphones during the performance.
The interior of the hall is out of range aside from one area.
Besides, I think it should be all right inside.
The interior of the concert hall is entirely soundproof and fireproof.
It's possible that they haven't even noticed the explosions.
In that case, the possibility that the concert is still in progress is...
Yeah.
It's possible, I'd imagine.
But, the explosions will not be limited to the exterior forever...
They'll eventually occur inside too...
No...
It may have already happened!
Ran...
♪ Jesu, Joy of Man's Desiring
Johann Sebastian Bach
Cantata, BWV 147, Chorale No.6
Ladies and gentlemen, good evening.
A warm welcome to all of you here tonight.
I am Doumoto Kazuki.
As you are all aware, in this very hall on this very night, this pipe organ...
Hurry!
Quickly, over here!
What are you doing?
Hurry and get that hose over here!
This is bad...
But the center section seems to be unharmed.
The people inside should be all right.
It's still too early to rejoice.
All of the access points to the outside have been sealed!
A rescue operation is impossible!
No way!
Moreover, we don't even know which pillar will explode next.
There are a total of 23 pillars on the exterior.
Perhaps they're planning on blowing them all up.
Damn it, what should we do?
We can only get in from the rooftop...
Is that possible?
It should be possible, for now.
However, there isn't a proper heliport.
We don't know if the roof will be able to withstand the weight of the helicopter or not...
Very well.
Please descend to the lowest possible height.
We'll jump from there.
I'll show you the way.
The passageway from the roof to the fourth level is complicated.
Therefore...
But, that's...
There's no time for arguments, right?
We have to hurry while the explosions have stopped!
Go lower!
More!
Just a little more!
A little more!
I can't go any farther!
The turbulence is worse than I expected!
I can't keep it steady!
If you want to go, go now!
Come on, Akiba-san!
Now, Conan-kun, stay in the helicopter and...
Conan-kun!
I'm staying here!
Until Ran-neechan and everyone else have been rescued!
Conan-kun!
And, I saw the culprit's face!
Even though we don't know the culprit behind the explosions...
I saw the one who attacked us!
Isn't it possible that he's inside the concert hall?
So...
Hurry! I can't hold it much longer!
It can't be helped; we'll have to bring him along.
Takagi-kun, hurry!
Right!
This is an internal corridor on the fourth floor.
Didn't we simply descend directly from the top?
If I didn't say that, you wouldn't have allowed me to come along, would you?
It's the same with this boy.
Did you really see the culprit's face?
♪ He Shall Feed His Flock
George Frideric Handel
Messiah, HWV 56
This is surprising.
It was a possibility, but to think that they really haven't noticed the explosions...
Yeah.
Anyway, let's search for the bombs.
It won't be possible to evacuate so many people.
Above all, if the objective was to destroy this concert hall...
There should be bombs installed in here as well.
Got it.
Conan-kun, wait here with Akiba-san.
All right.
Let's go.
Yes.
Ran...
Wait for me.
How is it?
What's the situation inside?
The culprit, knowing the structure of the hall very well...
Placed the bombs accordingly.
It is probably one of the staff.
That note really does sound strange.
Even Doumoto-san didn't notice it...
He'd probably notice if it was piano, but...
He's only been playing the organ for the last two years, so he probably can't tell the difference...
The difference in sound...
"A bunch of amateurs who can't differentiate between sounds."
So that's what it was about...
Kabe-san noticed the difference...
Because she has perfect pitch.
Wait!
Then why did that person...
Could it be, that person...
If that's the case...
Why was she...
His mother was reportedly unmarried...
I see. So that's how it is.
But, what does the difference in sound have to do with the explosions?
Hey, it just occurred to me, but...
When the explosions stopped earlier...
It was during Doumoto-san's speech, wasn't it?
Perhaps it was really because they didn't want people to notice the explosions?
No, that's not it!
The explosions will not occur unless the performance is underway!
I got it! So that's why the note sounded strange!
It's that note again...
Say, how many times has it sounded?
From the start of the concert up to now...
Do you know how many times that off-key note has sounded?
Let's see, I think it was...
Twice during the first Ave Maria...
And during the Cantata after that...
Ten times.
And, eight times for the current piece...
That's twenty in total.
Then, there are probably four more.
That note is linked to the explosions.
That's why no explosions occurred during Doumoto-san's speech.
There are 23 pillars on the exterior of the concert hall.
In other words...
To destroy all the pillars...
And the interior of the concert hall...
24 explosions are required.
That means...
Exactly.
If we don't stop the performance before that note sounds for the fourth time...
The bomb inside the concert hall will explode.
It's that note again.
Damn.
It really is linked to that note.
The culprit should be observing from somewhere.
Again!
Found them...
So it was that person after all.
All right, I'll get on stage and stop the performance.
Wait!
If you don't handle it well...
They'll set the explosions off via remote control.
I've found him, the culprit with the remote control.
But...
Damn it, what should I do?
Isn't there some way to stop the performance...
Is there no way to stop the explosions!?
Three minutes.
Will three minutes be enough?
But...
Well, I'll leave it to you, little detective.
It's Reiko-sensei!
This song...
It's "Amazing Grace", right?
What's she up to now?
♪ Amazing Grace
John Newton
The person from that time...
It really was Reiko-san.
I knew I should have eliminated her back then.
I won't let you erase it.
Not this voice raised in song that warms people's hearts.
That's why you were hesitant, right?
Moreover, this song was...
Your son's, Souma Hikaru-san's, most beloved song.
And the person singing was the person he loved.
The crux of my deduction...
Lies in the irregular note.
At first, we believed the irregularity was because it was out of tune.
But, that wasn't so.
Inside one of the organ pipes...
There is a small sensor which is set to detect minute changes in air flow.
Due to that, the sound generated from the pipe is slightly off.
When the sensor in the pipe detects a change in air flow...
It sends signals in a sequential order to the bombs you had set up earlier, which subsequently detonate.
And then, when the one final bomb explodes...
That will achieve your long-cherished desire to destroy this hall.
There were no explosions during the dress rehearsal...
Because the detonators had not yet been activated.
Isn't that so?
Director of Doumoto Hall and former piano tuner...
Fuwa Takumi-san?
There's nothing here either.
This isn't good.
If this continues, the bomb will explode before we locate it!
Be quiet.
What's that sound?
Don't move!
This is the police!
Müller-san!
How did you know it was me?
Perfect pitch.
Fuwa-san, even though you have perfect pitch...
You didn't point out the irregular note during the dress rehearsal, did you?
That made me suspicious.
I see.
Then, what you said about me being Hikaru's father...
Your car's license plate number is 52-83.
You took that from your son's birth date, didn't you?
You used it as a testimony of your connection to your beloved son...
Even though you could not proclaim it to the world.
Moreover, that photo in Doumoto-san's house from when you were younger...
Your son looked just like you.
You killed those four musicians...
To avenge your late son who died in the accident.
You left the flute parts at the crime scenes...
In order to mislead the police into thinking that the serial murders had ended at three.
You ensured Kabe Souko-san was severely injured...
Because you were afraid she would notice the irregular note, since she has perfect pitch.
Someone who fears those with perfect pitch...
Must be one with perfect pitch himself.
From that point alone, the culprit had to be you, Fuwa-san.
There is another.
Akiba Reiko-san also has perfect pitch.
But, as your late son's fiancée...
You couldn't bear to treat her as you did Souko-san, using life-threatening explosives.
Therefore, you chose to put irritants in her drink...
And attacked her using a truck and an air rifle.
In order to prevent her from taking the stage...
You wanted her unable to speak...
Or at least have her leg broken, right?
That chord...
The note!
Why?
Why didn't...
It won't explode.
Before I came here...
I removed the sensor from the pipe.
Three minutes.
No, it took me two minutes.
That's remarkable, little boy.
What was your name again?
Edogawa Conan, detective.
Bravo!
Bravo, bravo!
There he is.
He's holding a remote control.
Then it really was him...
What should we do?
Rush in before he sets off the bomb?
That won't work!
If we rush in, he'll set the bomb off by remote control.
Then, what can we do?
That room...
We might be able to do something from that room.
Something?
Shoot him.
Before he presses the remote control.
Unfortunately, little detective...
This remote control can also set off the explosion.
You have lost.
I wonder.
We still don't know that yet.
What don't we know?
Even though I don't know how you got into the concert hall...
Seeing as how the police haven't raided the place yet...
The hall is probably engulfed in a sea of flames and inaccessible, just as I planned.
The removal of the sensor was a miscalculation on my part, but...
No matter.
At least now I will be able to choose the moment of the explosion.
As a parting gift...
I'll send you to heaven while you're performing...
Damn, at that time...
Just as you perform on your precious organ...
Doumoto Kazuki!
Conan-kun!?
It's no use.
I can't fire like this.
That's it.
Hurry and begin your performance, Doumoto.
What should I do?
If I can't use my stun-gun wristwatch...
What else can I do?
Move aside, Conan-kun...
Please!
Give me that!
My recorder!
My voice is back!
Yes, just like that...
This is bad!
Farewell, little detective.
Like I'd let you!
Mi-La-La-La-Fa?
"SHOOT"?
Someone's shooting?
What was that sound?
It's the sound that signals the end of the game.
What?
This is the police!
Don't move!
I have lost.
♪ Chaconne in G Minor
Tomaso Antonio Vitali
Fuwa-san...
Where are the remaining bombs?
Inside the ceiling above the stage.
Takagi-kun, contact the inspector.
Yes!
I'm sorry, but...
Would you allow me to listen to the rest of the performance?
I'll tell you everything afterwards.
Understood.
The fire on this side has finally been put out.
We'll be there shortly.
Inspector!
There's an opening on the east side.
All right, let's go.
I'll get back to you.
Say...
Why did you plant bombs in this hall?
For the last 35 years, I was his...
I was Doumoto Kazuki's exclusive piano tuner...
We had walked through life together.
And then, two years ago...
He suddenly retired from being a pianist.
And then he told me...
That he hoped I would become the director of Doumoto Hall, which was to be completed in two years time.
Of course, I could have refused.
I was free to continue as a piano tuner.
But, after being the sole piano tuner of the internationally renowned pianist Doumoto Kazuki for the last 35 years...
I couldn't permit myself to accept another pianist after so long.
My pride wouldn't allow it.
Even having said that, I am just a mechanic.
I couldn't believe I was suited to the work of a director.
I fell into despair.
Two years ago, my wife passed away due to an illness.
A year after that, my son died in an accident.
In addition, after losing my job as a piano- tuner, the only meaningful thing in my life...
I was left with nothing.
Even the music which I once loved so much...
Had become nothing but dissonant sounds that hurt me to listen to.
Right...
Even in my dreams, I could hear them...
They would give me nightmares, and one night I decided...
I would erase them...
I would erase everything...
In order to retake the silent night!
Of course, the four who stole my son's life...
The ever-selfish Doumoto...
Whose interest in the piano was snatched away by the pipe organ and Doumoto Hall...
And even those people who had come to hear the organ...
The lives of the musicians and audience members from all over the world.
I accepted the offer to become the director of Doumoto Hall...
To gain access to the organ.
To carry out my plan to plant the bombs here in the hall...
It was best for me to go ahead and become the director.
On the other hand, the piano which was abandoned together with me...
I couldn't help but pity it.
That means...
Blowing up the piano alongside the practice room...
Was your way of showing your love for the piano, huh?
That's all I have to say.
And now...
Call Doumoto here right now.
Fuwa-san, calm down!
Don't be alarmed.
This is for me to commit suicide.
I have no intention of hurting anyone.
Conan-kun, please leave the room.
Forget it!
Despite your numerous dreadful deeds...
For you to die before atoning for them...
I won't let you to do something so unfair!
Conan-kun!
Fuwa-san, please don't do anything foolish!
Shut up!
Call Doumoto here right now!
Fuwa-kun.
I'm right here.
Doumoto-san!
Fuwa-kun, I'm truly sorry.
I failed to think you would brood so much over it.
You've finally realized?
Due to your selfishness, I was so—
It wasn't like that, Fuwa-kun.
The reason I retired from being a pianist was...
Because I realized that your tuning had started to fail slightly.
I considered your pride...
And couldn't bear to make it known to you.
Having said that, even now, I still cannot work with another tuner.
So, I retired from the piano.
Nonsense!
I have perfect pitch!
Indeed, you have perfect pitch.
But with age, your hearing has deteriorated, hasn't it?
There were times when you let the sound go out of tune without realizing it yourself.
Lies! Lies! Lies! All lies!
If I had known that this would happened, I would have told you the truth back then.
I'm very sorry.
It's too late to apologize now!
It's all your fault!
That's not true.
If my close friend did something like that to me...
I would wonder whether she had some unavoidable reason...
And whether, perhaps, it might have been done in consideration of my own situation more than for my friend's personal benefit.
That's what I would think.
That's because...
I trust that friend.
It's the same for me.
To think that all these explosions happened outside...
I didn't notice anything at all.
It seems Conan-kun really played an active role too.
I knew it! It's just as I said, isn't it?
At any rate, I'm surprised that Shinichi actually understood the recorder code...
Replacing the notes with letters from the alphabet...
It's something that happens in detective novels too.
Even though in German notation, the note "C" means "H"...
He knows that my mother is British.
So "C" becomes "B", because he knows that I used the British names for the notes.
I figured he would deduce that instantly.
Besides, I was counting on his perfect pitch.
Oh, I see.
Moreover, I also believe in him...
As his partner.
And I was so sure that the Beethoven guy was our culprit...
Dad, you're still saying that?
But, you know, he never did show up in the end.
That deduction moron.
Oh, Shinichi?
I can't be bothered with that guy.
Let's go, Conan-kun.
Huh?
He was here just a moment ago.
Hey...
This sound...
A violin.
"Amazing Grace", right?
Not that. This playing style...
Playing style?
Shinichi?
Wait, Ran!
Shinichi!
Shinichi-niichan already left.
Conan-kun!
He said he had a case.
Shinichi really came then?
Yeah.
After hearing Reiko-san's song...
He remembered what happened three years ago...
And he used this violin from the school to play the piece just now...
So that he and Ran-neechan could hear it together...
Shinichi-niichan said he did something bad to you.
Did you have a fight or something?
It was nothing.
I would have forgiven you even if you hadn't come...
Idiot.
I used to come here with him often.
This is where we walked on our dates.
Oh, I see.
During the spring after his accident...
At the place filled with our memories...
I sang his favorite song.
That was "Amazing Grace", wasn't it?
Yeah.
As for me...
At first I really resented those four people...
To the point that I wanted to kill them.
But, I forgave them...
Because "Amazing Grace" is a song of forgiveness.
Well, I'm off.
Conan-kun, let's sing in harmony again sometime.
See you.
Goodbye.
By the way, Ran-neechan...
How did you know Shinichi-niichan was the one playing then?
That's because he has a weird habit when he plays.
I could tell immediately.
Is that so?
What's this "weird habit"?