It can't be! That's a...
This is serious!
This is an urgent call from Kurata to the Wakasa Coast Guard!
While on patrol, I found a boat containing explosives rigged to blow it up by the rockface near the fourth district!
And now for the news.
The suspicious boat spotted in Maizuru Bay by the Coast Guard contained data and components not found in Japan...
It is believed to have entered the country illegally, and will undergo further investigation.
This is Maizuru Bay, isn't it?
Yeah.
Did something happen?
What is it?
A suspicious boat was spotted on the coast this morning.
What's a suspicious boat?
Hey, brats! Move up, don't leave a gap in the line!
Right...
Come on, Dad!
You're the adult here, you're supposed to be watching the kids!
Oh, shut up.
I'm only here because you said somebody needed to come with you.
But it's so rare to get a chance to go aboard an Aegis Destroyer!
Getting tickets for one is ten times harder than for other ships!
If only you used that luck with the horses.
Geez!
Geez, the old man's rude wherever he goes...
What is an Aegis Destroyer anyway?
Umm...
Aegis Destroyers are warships fitted with a weapons system developed by the US Navy!
They're really strong warships!
Yeah!
That's a pretty simple description.
Are you even interested in warships, Ayumi-chan?
No.
But I love the sea, and we did win the tickets.
That's right!
It's a once-in-a-lifetime experience!
This transmission...
So just forget about horses for now, Dad!
Okay, okay!
Conan-kun?
I gotta go to the toilet.
Well, be quick.
We'll be boarding soon.
Sure!
What's up, Doc?
Oh, I just wanted to see if your
new satellite phone was working.
We haven't boarded the ship yet, let alone set sail.
Huh, they must really be taking a long time.
Yeah, they probably increased the security checks with the commotion about the suspicious boat today.
I see...
Even though you made it just for the trip,
I might be better off not using the satellite phone.
By the way, did that conference in Ōsaka go well?
Yeah, thanks to Ai-kun's help.
We got great ratings.
I see. Then how about we meet up after the public exercises are over?
I better get back to the line—
By the way...
The kids must be getting bored, waiting so long.
No, not really...
All right, here's a quiz for them!
That's why you called me, huh?
The 'Aegis' in 'Aegis Destroyer' comes from the name of the shield to drive away evil
that Zeus gave to his daughter Athena in Greek myth, as I'm sure you know.
When Zeus fought the demonic Hydra, its sharp fangs are said to have bit him everywhere on his body.
However, there was one place he wasn't bitten.
Where do you think it was?
1. His neck.
2. His chest.
3. His stomach.
4. His back.
And that's that.
The doc really wanted me to have you answer it.
Wait, Conan-kun, when did you talk to the doctor?
Huh? Oh, when I was just in the toilet.
Hey, Conan-kun, I can't solve it.
Me neither!
What's the answer?
The answer is number four —
his back.
How come?
It's the 'god's back', so it 'wasn't bitten'.
kami nokoshi
kami no koshi
Just another pun, huh?!
Would the next group please get their winning postcard ready and come forward.
Oh, our turn's finally here!
Yay!
I'm tired of waiting!
Hey! Don't run!
Please open any hand luggage you may have so it can be checked, and place it in front of one of the inspectors.
Also, mobile phones are not allowed aboard, so we will hold onto them for you here.
Aegis Destroyer Hotaka
Thank you for joining us on these public exercises aboard an Aegis Destroyer.
My name is Inoue, and I'll be your guide today.
Chief Navigator of the Hotaka
Lt. Commander Fumitada Inoue
It's a pleasure to have you here.
I'll start by explaining the
details for today's public exercises.
First, please look at the map on the front screen.
You're free to look around the sections marked in red.
However, please avoid going into
any other corridors and rooms.
You'll find further details on the pamphlets in front of you.
Next, I'll talk about the schedule for today...
Sonoko...
At noon precisely, we have a roughly 15-minute video showcasing the Japan Maritime Self-Defence Force for you to watch.
Huh?
What time is it?
Let's see...
Ran-neechan, where's your watch?
It broke, so I sent it to be repaired.
Afterward, at 12:20, I'll explain to you how to use lifejackets.
I'd been using my mobile phone in the meantime, but...
When out on deck, please make sure to always wear one of these.
You can't because it was confiscated.
If you want to, you can use my watch.
The deck is a very dangerous place while we are at sea, so please follow any orders you may be given,
Huh? But what about you, Mitsuhiko-kun?
My digital camera has a clock, so I'll be fine.
and remember the set gathering times.
Got it? Keeping time is very important while aboard a ship.
You heard him.
Then at 12:40, we'll be holding the main event of the day, anti-air training exercises at sea.
Why say no?
Yeah.
Thank you, then, Mitsuhiko-kun.
Sure.
It's completely waterproof, so you don't have to worry about the sea breeze.
At 13:00, you can head out onto the deck, and observe the various weapons and radars, and the on-board helicopter.
And it's a radio clock, so it's very accurate.
What's a radio clock?
After that, at 16:30, you all can enjoy the JMSDF specialty, Navy Curry.
You don't know?
It's a clock that sets itself several times a day according to radio signals transmitting the correct time.
Wow...
Incidentally, that one sets itself at 5:00 AM and 5:00 PM.
After the meal, we'll be holding a treasure hunt for items hidden in the cafeteria and on deck, so look forward to that.
Where do the signals come from?
Uh, well...
Around here, it'd probably be the transmitter in Fukushima.
During the game, we'll be heading back to Maizuru Harbour.
Really?
You sure know a lot, don't you, Conan-kun?
We expect to arrive back at the harbour at 17:30.
O-Oh, I heard about it from Shin'ichi-niichan...
Huh? What's that?!
What?
What's that creepy sound?
What? What happened?
Please calm down.
Everything's fine.
Huh?
The sound you just heard was made by our pumping system letting in a large amount of sea water.
Hey, Dad!
Please calm down and sit down.
Oh, and...
It seems the pump valve in your
mouth came loose, so be careful.
Oh, sorry, sorry.
Dad!
Sit down, I'm begging you!
Geez...
Since the pumping system started up, we may be about to leave Maizuru Harbour.
But would a pumping system really make a sound like that?
I'm Shin'ichi Kudō, a high school detective.
While at an amusement park with my childhood friend and classmate, Ran Mouri,
I witnessed a suspicious deal involving a man in black.
Since I was so focused on watching the deal, I didn't realise his partner was sneaking up from behind me.
He forced me to consume poison, and when I came to...
...my body had shrunk!
If those men learnt that Shin'ichi Kudō was still alive,
they'd come back to finish me off, endangering everyone around me.
At Dr. Agasa's suggestion, I hid my identity,
and when Ran asked my name,
I blurted out 'Conan Edogawa'.
To find out more about those guys, I ended up living with Ran and her detective father.
These are my classmates now...
Genta.
Mitsuhiko.
Ayumi.
They formed the Detective Boys, and forced me to join.
And this old man is Kogorō Mouri.
I don't have to explain that, right?
These two gadgets were made by Dr. Agasa.
He makes all sorts of unique gadgets for my vertically challenged body.
The Instant Football Belt.
When you press the button on the buckle, a ball pops out —
pretty nifty.
And the main focus this time is on this watch, and its new functions.
It has a satellite phone and a USB flash drive built-in.
Now that it's powered up, it's really nifty!
By the way, the doc isn't the
only one who knows my identity.
Ai Haibara.
Real name: Shiho Miyano.
She used to be with the men in black,
but to get away from them, she took the same drug that'd been forced on me, and ended up shrinking.
Haibara came to live with the doc, and joined me as a first-year primary school student.
My body shrunk, but my mind didn't!
I'm still an undefeated great detective!
There's always only one truth!
Prepare for anti-air combat drill!
All units in position.
This ship will now enter anti-air combat.
All hands, hurry to your positions!
If you have children with you, please come to the front.
We will now perform a publicly observed combat drill.
There's not much space, so if you're in the front line, please stay behind this point.
Keep a close eye on the sky!
This is the heart of an Aegis Destroyer, the CIC.
Anti-air radar ready!
SPY detected a target! 40°, 70 miles.
Target #1 approaching!
35°, 66 miles.
Is it coming here?
That's just how it's set up...
I see.
Oh... Don't scare me like that.
They seem to be taking it quite lightly...
New target detected! 30°, 40 miles.
Yeah, they're not acting too well...
Designated as target #2.
Ain't that because this is the real thing?
Target #2 is heading straight for us.
Target #2 is determined to be a threat.
Prepare to attack immediately!
Anti-air combat drill target designated by CIC.
Begin attack!
Prepare the main gun!
Prepare to fire the Mark 45 Mod 4.
Remote aiming at target #2 complete.
The target has entered the firing range.
Prepare to fire!
Begin firing procedure!
Fire!
30 seconds to target.
Huh, it's just images on a screen...?
Come on, Dad...
Even just watching a screen in here is impressive...
This is an Aegis Destroyer's most confidential room —
it's the first time civilians have been allowed to be here.
I guess it does give off that feel of secrecy...
Target #2 hit.
It's like some sort of game!
Target #2 confirmed to be hit.
Do you think they'll let us have a go too?
Not in a million years.
He's right! It may look easy, but...
Hey, hey, not you guys too...
Ready to fire!
Fire!
Automatic mode!
Mark intercepted!
Target #1 is descending!
12 seconds to target #1.
Target #1 hit!
What happened, did it hit?
Yes, with that, all of the enemies were shot down.
Wasn't that great?
Yeah!
It's already over?
I couldn't quite tell what was going on...
That's all for—
There's a sonar response! Nationality unknown!
It's heading straight for us!
Direction: 5°.
Distance: 8000!
This is the CIC!
Captain...
This is your captain, Tateishi.
Capt. Yukio Tateishi
Captain of the Hotaka
Begin search with all radars.
I'll head to the CIC.
I'll come with you.
I'm going to the CIC.
I leave the vice-captain in command of the bridge.
Roger.
Be ready for any change in course or speed from the target!
Be ready for any attack from the target.
It is not an animal or a natural phenomenon!
No response to IFF signals!
It's a submerged, non-allied ship!
Start the Nixie! Stop the ship!
Full speed astern! Hard a-port!
Aim the bow towards the target.
Roger.
Full speed astern!
Hard a-port! Pivot by 90°!
Did the ship actually stop?
Looks like the performance suddenly got a lot more realistic!
Yeah, it's really intense.
Prepare for anti-submarine combat!
Send out a warning signal!
Roger!
Signal ready.
Warning signal fired!
Showing it on the third main monitor!
Amazing!
That was so cool!
Yeah!
Wasn't that cool?
I wonder if that light was the real thing?
No way...!
Prepare for anti-submarine combat!
Red alert!
Aye, sir!
The ship may shake slightly, so if you have children with you, be sure to keep an eye on them.
Have Ichigaya check the data against nearby submarines.
Did something happen?
This is just training, right?
Of course it is!
They just finally spiced it up a bit!
No, this might actually be...
The echo is dull.
What's the situation?
The image quality isn't clear.
It's not good enough for detection.
Stop the SPY!
Confirm target with the SH-60K!
Target still approaching!
Distance: 3,200 metres!
We'll be in the target's torpedo range soon!
What?!
Still no response from the target?
Negative.
Target still approaching!
Distance: 3,100 metres!
Only 100 metres left before we're in torpedo range!
Captain...
What should we do?
All hands, prepare for an ambush!
Hold on, Captain!
If you do that...
We might start a war.
Target speed: 10! Distance: 3,000!
We're in the target's firing range!
Maintain a distance of 3,000 metres from the target.
Start the engines at full speed!
Roger!
Starting engines at full speed!
Take evasive manoeuvres!
Hard a-starboard! Full speed ahead!
It feels so tense in here!
It's even better than a game!
It's a bit scary.
It's no surprise that they're scared.
This Aegis Destroyer...
...really is being attacked!
No response from the target.
Approaching at a 40° angle from the left.
I want to see the enemy. Prepare light torpedoes!
Light torpedoes ready!
Engines to full power! Hard a-port!
Anti-submarine light torpedoes ready!
CIC to the bridge, engines to full power! Hard a-port!
Full speed ahead! Hard a-port!
Hard a-port!
This is the left torpedo launcher.
Anti-submarine torpedo loaded!
Launch torpedo!
Fire anti-submarine light torpedo!
We'll have a clear visual soon!
Showing it on the third monitor!
Shockwave incoming!
The ship will shake slightly.
Make sure to keep an eye on your children!
Hey, are you guys okay?
Yeah.
That shake was awesome!
It was so cool!
Huh? That kid doesn't have any adult with him.
What's that?!
A submarine?
No, that's not it.
A fishing boat?
A shipwreck?
Is that...
No risk of explosion.
It's a shipwreck drifting with the tide...
Cease use of anti-submarine weapons!
Now returning to the route planned for the public exercises.
I repeat, now returning to the route planned for the public exercises.
Notify US Navy and SDF submarines that we have ceased combat...
Is it over?
Yes, that's the end of the anti-air and anti-submarine combat training.
Wasn't that amazing?
Yeah!
I thought it was a real fight!
I even forgot I was hungry!
So they're just calling it training...
Well then, please enjoy looking around the bow.
Sure!
Isn't the SDF cool?
I want to try on an SDF uniform!
It's so cool!
Conan-kun, hurry up, hurry up!
This Aegis Destroyer's really big!
This cannon's amazing!
I wonder how big it really is.
It really feels huge when you see it close up...
We saw it being fired on that video earlier.
Conan-kun, let's take a photo with all of us together!
S-Sure!
Over here!
Let's go, Yūki.
Come on, take my hand, Yūki.
Unless I'm mistaken, that kid...
Hey!
Is your name Yūki-kun?
Huh? Yeah.
What a relief, huh?
You managed to find your dad!
What do you mean, little kid?
You weren't with him when the ship shook, right?
I was worried about him.
Oh, that must've been when I was in the toilet.
Oh, so that's what happened...
So you were all alone then, right?
Well then, let's have a look at the other side, Yūki.
Okay.
Even if he was in the toilet, he should've felt a shake that big.
But even after the drill in the CIC ended, he didn't show himself until the free time on the deck had already begun.
I wonder...
Hey!
Don't go wandering off!
Geez...
You vanish as soon as I take my eyes off you!
I'm sorry...
A female SDF member on an Aegis Destroyer?
Hey, brat!
Are you really sorry?
Oh, how cool!
Huh?
It's a female SDF member!
Huh?!
It's rare to see female SDF members, so let's get a group photo with her!
It's true!
She's beautiful!
Let's do it, let's do it!
Hey!
Miss SDF member, can we take a photo with you?
Captain
Nanami Fujii
A-A photo?
What a beauty!
A great detective and a beautiful SDF member. Miracles can happen!
Miss!
No, divine devotee to the SDF, please pay no mind to the bad manners of these children.
Hey, Dad!
What? I was about to ask her
if we could take a photo with her!
You don't have to get that close to her to do it!
Mitsuhiko, can I borrow your camera?
Huh? Okay.
Thanks.
Okay, everyone look this way!
But I don't...
You don't mind if we take a photo, right?
Just look around!
Take a photo of us this time!
Am I doing the salute right?
Well, I guess you're right...
All right!
I'll go next to her!
I want to be next to her!
Me too, me too!
Conan-kun, are you okay with not being in the photo?
It's fine.
Anyway, you should move closer too, Ran-neechan.
Right.
Okay, I'm taking it!
Oh, sorry...
One more time!
Huh?
Hey, do you know how to take a photo?
Yeah, but it was set up wrong.
Okay, now it's perfect!
Okay, this time...
Say 'Aegis'!
Yay!
How was it?
Did you take it?
Yup! It was perfect this time.
Let me see, let me see!
Thank you.
Here!
It was nothing. Anyway, I better be goin—
Lemme see!
I wanna see!
Hey!
Miss SDF member...
What is it?
What kind of job do you do here?
I...
I cook everyone's meals.
I see...
She's lying.
Her rank insignia is that of a captain.
She has the same rank as the captain of an Aegis Destroyer.
Excuse me, but I have work to do, so I have to leave now.
Thanks a lot!
Oh, let me give you my business card!
Sorry about this.
Damn it! This jacket really gets in the way!
Don't mind him, head back to work.
What's with these flashy cards?
Good catch, brat!
Wait for me!
You beautiful lady!
What a disgrace...
Sorry, Sonoko, could you hold these for a second?
What's with these ugly cards?!
He had them made recently, saying he wants to stand out at every crime scene.
But I think he's missing the point a bit...
Mitsuhiko, can I borrow your camera again?
All right.
Here.
Give these cards to Ran-neechan.
Okay.
I've got to go to the toilet.
Huh?!
Conan-kun!
What's he gonna take a photo of in the toilet?
By the way, Ai-kun...
What is it?
I wonder if the kids liked the riddle I gave them earlier.
They'd like it as long as the answer wasn't number four, his back, right?
Hello.
Doc...
There's something I want you to investigate.
Oh, it's you, Shin'ichi?
Yeah...
You sent a photo to Ai-kun's phone?
Got it, I'll check it out right away.
By the way, did some kind of case happen?
No, there's just something that I'm wondering about.
Did she get the photo?
Yeah, it was delivered fine.
It looks like a female SDF member.
Just the one photo, right?
Yeah, I want you to look into what department the woman in the photo is stationed in.
Only 4% of the JMSDF's personnel are women, and many of them are used in adverts, so she shouldn't be hard to find.
Okay, got it.
Then we shouldn't have too much of a problem.
By the way, about the quiz earlier...
He hung up.
What a shame, huh?
A satellite transmission?
Whereabouts on the deck?
It's coming from the right side of the deck.
That's near the civilians.
Have it investigated.
Yes, sir!
This is a transmission from the CIC to all areas.
A satellite transmission was detected on the right side of the deck. Watanabe and Abiko are to head there immediately...
Captain!
X couldn't be among the civilians, could he?
Maybe the shipwreck earlier was connected with X as well...
X...
This radar could even be called the eyes of the Aegis.
You wouldn't know just by looking at it, but this radar can cover over 450 km, and identify over 200 objects at once.
Amazing!
It really is a great detective of the seas!
It's so cool!
That place...?!
That's where I just called the doc...
Did they find out about my satellite communications?
Or perhaps...
The Aegis System is only given to countries trusted by the US, who developed it.
And we, Japan, were the first country it was awarded to.
Yeah, got it.
I guess I better report it in.
I'm counting on you. I'll check out the deck.
Now, my next topic is the helicopter stationed at the stern: the SH-60K.
Wow! They've even got a helicopter!
Huh? What's wrong, Conan-kun?
Whoa! How exciting!
Oh, I gotta go to the toilet.
Huh? Again?
Hold on, Conan-kun!
Huh?
I'm going with you.
Oh, you don't have to!
Of course I do!
You vanish as soon as I take my eyes off you!
I don't—
You just did, remember?
Come on...
Let's go together.
Okay...
I nearly got lost when I went to the toilet earlier too.
This destroyer's full of twists and turns...
Even though you're in high school?
That's right, she's not too good with directions...
Geez... How far away did you go?
Sorry, sorry! I forgot the way back here.
That's why I said I'd come with you.
But...
Don't go wandering off by yourself again, okay?
Next time, you mightn't be able to find me.
It's fine!
Huh?
No matter how lost I am,
you'll always manage to find me, right?
You're a great detective, after all!
It's cold!
Geez!
Don't you worry!
Huh?
I'll always find you, wherever you are.
That's for sure.
Huh?
I thought this way led to the toilet...
Sorry, Conan-kun! Looks like I got us lost...
Come on... Don't actually get us lost...
What was that scream just now?
Hey, Conan-kun!
Sawamura-san!
Something terrible got sucked in!
Something terrible?
Hey! Don't tell me that's a...?!
You guys!
Could it be?!
This area's off-limits!
That's a human arm!
We're very sorry, we got lost on the way to the toilet...
What a mess...
What should we do?!
For now, you better tell the Captain about this.
Understood.
I'll take these two children back to Chief Navigator Inoue.
Ran-neechan, let's tell Uncle Kogorō.
Roger.
You're right.
Umm...
Maybe you should consult my father?
Huh?
It's a human arm that you have on that table, isn't it?
That's...
My father's Kogorō Mouri.
Have you heard about him?
He's the great detective known as 'Sleeping Kogorō'.
Yo! What's up, Kudō?
Huh, a corpse?!
Ya found a corpse aboard that Aegis Destroyer?
No, all that was found was a left arm.
But most likely...
The left arm was clothed in a JMSDF uniform.
So whoever was murdered was in the JMSDF?
I don't know if it was a murder or an accident yet.
But whoever died was a Lieutenant.
Interestin'...
'Kay, gotcha.
I'll go there right now.
I'll wait for your call.
Found ya!
Clubs have already started, you know?
I ain't got time.
Gotta go to Maizuru.
Huh?
Maizuru?
Hey, Heiji!
Nothing here.
Yeah.
We can't find any machine capable of satellite transmission.
Keep checking the corners not covered by surveillance cameras.
So they did find out about my transmissions...
X may be hiding in a corner somewhere.
Copy that.
X?
Oh, crap!
What was that strange noise just now?
Shin'ichi hung up on me...
I wonder if something happened...
And just when we were about to tell him what he asked us for...
We must've just imagined it.
Yeah.
It was nothing.
We'll keep looking.
That was close!
Well, this is an Aegis Destroyer. Top-notch security indeed.
But I better find a different way to communicate...
I'll be caught right away if I use that without permission.
That mark...
It's the mark signifying a strong magnetic field!
This room should do...
I'm the captain, Tateishi.
You must be Mouri-san.
The one and only Great Detective Kogorō Mouri, at your service.
I heard about you from Capt. Sekiguchi.
Wakasa Military Police
Capt. Makoto Sekiguchi
I'm Sekiguchi, from the Military Police.
The Military Police are the
internal police of the military, right?
Correct.
I see.
So, this is the dismembered part of a corpse you mentioned?
Yes.
Here it is.
I see...
It doesn't seem to have been removed using a sharp blade.
Also, the wound shows no signs of life.
Then you're saying it was severed post-mortem?
Correct.
Where was this arm found?
In the pumping system's filter.
Wasn't the pumping system what we...?
The sound you just heard was made by our pumping system letting in a large amount of sea water.
So that's what happened when we heard that sound...!
Sometimes, when leaving Maizuru Harbour, large pieces of debris carried by the ocean current are sucked up.
This arm must've got stuck in the filter at that time.
What do you mean by 'the filter'?
It's a net placed in the pump gate to stop large pieces of debris, fish, shells and so on from getting in when we draw in sea water.
So how did this end up here?
When a piece of debris obstructs the filter, we collect it to find out what it is.
It's typically a large piece of seaweed or a plastic bag.
By the way, do you have any idea who this arm belongs to?
You do, don't you?
Who is it, Capt. Tateishi?
Judging from the rank markings
on the cuff and the wristwatch,
I think it's Lt. Sasaura from the Wakasa base.
When I asked the base to check, they told me they didn't know the whereabouts of Lt. Sasaura.
Then you're probably right.
His watch stopped at 5:30 AM.
How can you tell that it's AM?
Look at the position of the calendar.
You can still see a part of yesterday's date,
so it had to have been in the morning.
Sasaura-san was one of the people who normally boards this Aegis Destroyer, right?
He sometimes comes aboard, but he wasn't planned to be in today's shift.
You started the pumping system when we left Maizuru Harbour, right?
Yes.
I think this left arm got severed by the pump gate at that time.
I see.
So at the time, his body was already drifting in the sea, near Maizuru Harbour.
Then, the pumping system activated, and his body was sucked in with the sea water.
But his body got caught at the entrance, and only his left arm made it as far as the filter.
Am I right?
Yes.
I believe you're correct.
And when do we get back to the harbour?
We plan to return at 5:30 PM.
Then you should contact the Kyōto Police so they can be ready to conduct an autopsy as soon as we get back.
This doesn't look good. Looking at his arm, it needs to be taken for an autopsy soon.
Understood. I'll call them right away.
Oh, yeah!
There's a helicopter on this ship!
Wow, amazing!
This is where you drive the ship!
Conan-kun...
Hey, brat, don't stick your nose where it doesn't belong!
I heard your voice while looking for the helicopter, Uncle!
Helicopter?
I see...
We can take the arm to shore immediately with the helicopter.
But the passengers might notice if we send out the helicopter.
This isn't the time to be worrying about that!
Mouri-san...
If the civilians find out about this, it may cause a panic.
I wish I could see the helicopter flying!
Like when you showed us the cannon before!
If you pretend you're doing a demonstration like you did earlier and make the helicopter fly...
You're right!
We can avoid exposure that way!
Capt. Tateishi.
There's no time to waste.
Understood.
I'll get the helicopter ready straight away.
Tōkyō Police HQ
What?
On an Aegis Destroyer?
Got it.
We'll contact the Kyōto Police right away.
And we'll head there too as soon as we get authorisation to come aboard.
Please do.
There's a chance that the killer's
still aboard this Aegis Destroyer.
First of all, I'm counting on you to investigate this left arm.
And now we'll show a demonstration
of the helicopter taking off.
It would be dangerous to get any closer, so please stay behind the barrier.
Phew.
Somehow, we made it in time.
You're...
What's wrong?
Did you lose your dad again?
You were alone before too.
Are you okay?
Where are your parents?
His father's supposed to be here, but it seems he got lost.
Really?
Your name was Yūki-kun, right?
Yeah.
Then you stay with him, Conan-kun.
I'll talk to an SDF member about Yūki-kun's situation.
Stop! If you do that...
If I do that...?
I'm fine.
I'm fine!
Hold on, Yūki-kun!
Here, you dropped these.
What kind of medicine is it?
It's for hives.
It stops me itching.
Do you have problems often?
I can't drink things with milk.
Oh, food allergies.
Wait, Yūki-kun!
Dad told me...
'You'll be strong!
That's why I named you Yūki.'
courage
So I'm fine!
Yūki!
So that's where you were!
Are you his father?
Yes.
Great. It seems he got lost...
Sorry for the bother.
See, that's what happens when you wander off on your own.
Hey, aren't we in Maizuru now?
Yeah.
But first, we gotta get some intel nearby.
What's with all those people?
To think something like that
happened on that Aegis Destroyer...
I was surprised too, to be honest.
There's a lot of noise. What's going on?
Oh, I'm in hiding so my satellite
transmissions don't get traced.
That way you're protected against being traced.
So, what about that SDF lady?
I searched, but I couldn't find any
SDF member that looks like her.
It really is a person!
Heiji, what is it?
Don't worry, just wait for me here.
Wait, Heiji!
He doesn't have any left arm!
Did you call the police?
They're coming now.
A corpse without a left arm?
A lieutenant's stripes.
There's no doubt then.
It's the body of Sasaura-san —
the guy Kudō was talkin' about.
Is that blood?
No, it ain't blood.
Then what is it?
You can't, you can't!
What is it, kid?
You can't touch or move the body until the police arrive!
I'm Megure from the Tōkyō Police.
We came on board along with these people from the Wakasa Coast Guard.
Welcome. I'm Tateishi, the Captain.
I'm Satō.
I'm Takagi.
Wakasa Coast Guard Security Dept.
Masaaki Kurata
I'm Kurata from the Security Department.
Tsutomu Munekawa
Wakasa Coast Guard Criminal Affairs
I'm Munekawa from Criminal Affairs.
Let's talk inside.
Right.
What?
At the shipyard in Wakasa Bay?
Yeah.
I'm pretty sure.
The body has the same rank and missin' body part.
That means Sasaura-san got his arm swallowed by the Aegis Destroyer at Maizuru Harbour, and then his corpse drifted here.
It drifted...? But how?
Wouldn't it have drifted on the ocean currents?
Is there even a current going that way?
Well, I'll check into that.
Along with the substance I found on his body.
Substance?
Yeah. I don't know what it is, but there was a red substance on his neck.
A red substance...
Hattori, meet up with Dr. Agasa.
Chow time!
Yummy!
Navy curry is so good!
It's the best curry I've ever had!
Right, it's really good!
Yūki-kun...
Maybe I'm just overthinking this.
I wish I could cook curry like this!
'Yes, yes, it's really nice!'
What?
Why don't you call him saying 'I cooked you some delicious curry, so hurry back!'
Don't be stupid. He won't come back just for curry.
She's right.
I'll go call him.
Now you've got it!
No, it's not that.
I just have something I want to tell Shin'ichi.
Yeah, yeah. See ya!
What does she want to tell me?
Oh no, she's gonna call me!
Conan-kun, where are you going?
To the toilet.
Again?
I'll be back soon!
That's my deduction and everything we know so far.
I see.
So there hasn't been a thorough investigation yet due to the public exercises.
Right.
Where are the civilians now?
Eating lunch in the cafeteria.
Then now would be the perfect time to investigate the areas open to the public.
But I heard that Lt. Sasaura's body was found at a shipyard in Wakasa Bay.
Do we need a thorough investigation?
Just to make sure.
There's still the possibility that he got sucked into the pump gate before the ship departed.
Understood.
I'll guide you around.
That you, Ran?
How did you know it's me?
Never mind that, just tell me what's up.
Never mind? But...
Well, Shin'ichi, at the moment...
...you're aboard an Aegis Destroyer, right?
You're really lucky. I'd love to ride on one too!
Wait, how did you know?
Didn't I tell you before?
I can find you no matter where you are.
Shin'ichi...
Oh, I get it!
It was Conan-kun!
He told you over the phone!
Y-Yeah.
Don't worry.
I'll finish up the case soon.
Don't say things you don't mean when you're that far away.
What about it?
You don't feel safe if I'm not with you or something?
What are you talking about?
That makes no sense!
That's the spirit!
See ya!
Do your best!
Wait!
Though I'm actually pretty close to you.
Jerk.
It seems Inspector Megure's group found it on the deck.
Where on the deck?
I don't know that...
Anyway, let's hurry.
Did they find something on the deck?
Over here!
Yes, right here.
Sasaura-san's mobile phone was on these missile launchers.
Where exactly?
In this gap.
Let me see.
When was it last used?
The last e-mail was yesterday after 9 PM.
And the last call was this morning at 5:30.
5:30 this morning?
That's when his wristwatch stopped.
It's also his estimated time of death.
According to the autopsy, Sasaura-san died this morning between 4 and 6.
In other words, Sasaura-san was aboard this Aegis Destroyer until then.
Did you find out the cause of death?
Yes.
Drowning.
So are you saying Sasaura-san fell from this Aegis Destroyer at 5:30 AM?
It seems so.
I see, I got it!
At 5:30 this morning, Sasaura-san was fighting with someone right here.
That's when he dropped his phone.
Then, Sasaura-san ran away, but was probably trapped somewhere nearby.
And then he was pushed into the sea.
If you're right, it's a homicide.
Then Sasaura-san's body was swallowed by the ship's pump gate and got stuck in there before the departure.
Yes.
Then the ship's pumping system was started again after they left Maizuru Harbour, severing Sasaura-san's arm.
Then, his body drifting in the sea was taken to Wakasa Bay by the ocean current.
Thinking about it, the fact that his phone is here also—
This phone has the microSD card slot open!
I don't remember it being open earlier.
Does it have a card in there?
No.
Could the killer have taken it?
So the killer murdered Sasaura-san in order to steal the data card from his phone!
Damn, I can't see the phone from here...
I guess I'll have to get closer.
I won't let you get away!
What is it, Mouri-kun?
No, it's nothing...
Upstairs?
No...
It's broken!
What happened?
What?
The captain's quarters?
That's a microSD card!
Go!
So this really is the data...
I'll be in my room.
Call me as soon as you find out something.
Oh, Captain!
Can I take a photo with you?
Kid, this area is off-limits, so how about we take the photo over there?
Okay!
Figures —
she removed the data card.
But she didn't have time to completely delete the data she extracted on this computer.
So where is the phone now?
In the meeting room.
And the Tōkyō Police?
They're inspecting the contents of the phone.
Why is the Captain here?
Oh, crap.
That voice was...
Did she figure it out?
If only I had more time...!
Don't move!
He got me!
Damn, I didn't manage to copy everything.
Why would X be interested in this data now...?
X?
I better put everything back the way it was.
That reminds me...
We couldn't find any traces of X either.
X?
Anyway, I better get out of here as soon as possible, and send what I could copy to the doc.
No, wait.
If I make a satellite transmission
here, I might find out who she is.
I'm getting satellite signals again!
They're coming from the captain's quarters!
What?
The Captain's in a meeting now.
Could it be X?
Go confirm the Captain's whereabouts!
Sir.
This is a problem.
There's important data in the captain's quarters.
Download complete.
What did Shin'ichi send us this time?
Who knows?
But since it's from Kudō-kun,
I suppose he wants us to investigate it.
Oh, we've arrived in Kyōto!
Don't move!
What are you doing here?
You don't need to know.
Capt. Fujii.
Was it you?
Captain, I'll explain later.
Oh, it's you!
Who is she?
It's okay.
Please get out.
Yes.
Wait!
We came here because a
suspicious transmission was detected!
Yes, and when we arrived, she was here.
I think we have the right to ask your identity.
I'm sorry, but we can't reveal her identity to outsiders.
Outsiders?
Are you joking?
They're right!
Be it the police or the Coast Guard, we're all partners investigating this case, aren't we?
Ah! It's the SDF lady!
You're wandering around again?!
A friend told me it's very rare for an SDF lady to be aboard an Aegis Destroyer.
That's enough from you...
He's right!
Are female SDF officers even allowed to be on board an Aegis Destroyer?
Yes.
There are recent plans that allow female SDF officers aboard Aegis Destroyers too.
So she's here to guide civilians around...
I see. That explains it.
Huh? But she said earlier that she was in charge of cooking!
Ah, that's right.
How do you explain that?
Well...
If you keep acting like this, we'll have no choice but to assume Sasaura-san's killer is one of you.
Wait.
We'll cooperate as much as we can.
Captain!
Since things turned out this way,
maybe we should tell them...
Yes.
I'm a member of Intelligence Security Command.
Intelligence Security Command?
The one that reports directly to the Minister of Defence?
Yes.
Our job is to manage the SDF's information and to monitor the ideologies of SDF members.
But why is a Intelligence Security Command member on this Aegis Destroyer?
Oh! It's because of the suspicious boat found this morning, isn't it?
Yes.
We think it might be a spy ship from a certain country.
There was an antenna for wireless communication, as well as a bomb planted to blow it up.
You sure know a lot about it.
I was the one who found that suspicious boat.
That's why I was put on this investigation.
Since the suspicious boat was found near Maizuru Harbour, where this Aegis Destroyer was anchored,
we believe a spy might be on board.
A spy?
Yes. In our investigations, we named him 'X'.
X?
What's the spy's goal?
We believe he is trying to obtain classified intel on Aegis Destroyers.
Intel?
What would happen if that intel leaked out?
We'd lose a lot of trust with the US, who provided the Aegis system.
But more importantly, if the routes of the Aegis Destroyers leak out,
then Japan's line of defence would be known by everybody.
We'd be defenceless to military
aggression from other countries.
In other words, it would cause a national crisis.
Can I presume then that the victim, Sasaura-san, knew about the spy?
Yes.
He knew about it because of his job.
His job?
What was Sasaura-san's job?
As a Lieutenant, he was part of management, right?
Lt. Sasaura was the Director of Intelligence for the Wakasa JMSDF base.
Director of Intelligence?
His duty was to safeguard information on Aegis Destroyers.
And so he was murdered by X, who wanted to steal that information!
So whoever took the data card from Sasaura-san's phone is X?
No doubt about that.
No, she took the card out...
Then we should search this ship for X.
But why is she keeping silent about it?
Excuse me, please let us through.
Sorry, but we have to inspect the communication tools in this room.
We will also have to inspect your belongings, so don't leave the room.
Crap!
Hey, Uncle!
What?
I forgot I ordered an extra portion of curry.
Curry?
Geez, what are you doing here in the first place?!
Hurry up and get out!
Okay!
Nice, old man!
Welcome.
Hattori, can you hear me?
Yeah, I met up with Dr. Agasa.
Did you find out anything about the red substance?
We're examinin' it now.
Hold on.
Though, bein' able to do an examination like this in a car is pretty awesome!
Well, Ai-kun was a scientist, after all.
A scientist?
What are you blabberin' about? She's just a little kid.
Don't mind her age.
Got it. This is it.
TBT?
Anti-fouling paint.
A special paint used for ships.
Ship paint?
Can you check if that paint is from this Aegis Destroyer?
Got it. I'll get the little lady to check it now.
The little lady?
Oh, and about the ocean currents...
There wasn't any current that could've brought Sasaura-san's body from Maizuru Harbour to Wakasa Bay.
So how'd the body end up in Wakasa Bay?
Oh, and what about the data I sent you?
Oh, that?
Kudō wants to ask you somethin' about the data you got earlier.
Shin'ichi, it looks like it's a piece of data about the Aegis Destroyers.
I knew it.
And there are some traces showing it was copied from a certain company's cloud.
By cloud, you mean a service to store data on the Internet?
Yes. If we can work out the ID and password, we should be able to get the original data from the cloud.
I see...
That means that Sasaura-san first stored the Aegis data on an online cloud service.
And later, he copied it to the data card in his phone.
But storing Aegis data on a cloud
service aimed for public usage?
Why would Sasaura-san do something like that?
Doc, please use Sasaura-san's ID to access the data on the cloud and send it to the captain's room.
But how—
It's okay.
I just used it, and I remember the e-mail address.
I'm counting on you.
Sorry to ask you this right when you get here, but could you please tell us the results of your investigation.
Of course.
Captain...
Before coming here, we investigated Sasaura-han's last actions before his murder.
Fumimaro Ayanokōji
Kyōto Police Detective
Detective Kurumazaki
At 5:30 this morning, Sasaura-han was seen waving a Japanese flag on a cliff at Maizuru Harbour.
An employee from a sightseeing cruise witnessed it.
Why would Lt. Sasaura do such a thing?
We don't know...
But what happened yesterday is even more suspicious.
You interrogated Sasaura-han
at the Wakasa JMSDF base, right?
Sekiguchi-han.
Why did you question Sasaura-han?
It's because...
You're still hiding things?!
Fujii-san, you can't even tell us?
We're part of the JMSDF too!
Unless we get approval from the Ministry of Defence...
That's enough! Sasaura-san was murdered!
We can't help you if you don't tell us the truth...
He was part of your team, wasn't he?! Your friend was mu—
That man was no friend of ours!
If you don't mind explaining...
What's this?
Why is the data about the Aegis
Destroyers being sent here...?
Inspector.
Right.
If you won't cooperate willingly, then we'll have to force you.
What's this...?
It's being received under Sasaura-san's ID from a cloud service, right?
Nice timing, Doc!
Cloud?
It couldn't be to show it to X
aboard this Aegis Destroyer, could it?
Hold on!
Storing data about Aegis Destroyers on the Internet is a breach of protocol!
I see...
That's why you questioned Sasaura-han...
And that SDF lady knew about it too.
Where are you going?!
Hold on, we haven't fini—
Let go!
Unlike all of you, I work for the sake of this country!
With that way of thinking, you won't be able to catch X, let alone protect your country.
Let's work together.
For Japan.
Data about Aegis Destroyers has been being leaked from the Wakasa JMSDF base.
Not another word, Lt. Sekiguchi!
I was ordered to investigate it by Capt. Fujii!
I thought so!
Was it Lt. Sasaura who leaked the data about the Aegis Destroyers?
Yes.
Where did he send the data about the Aegis Destroyers to?
To a detective agency run by a man called Takekawa, that ceased activity a few years ago.
A shell company?
The company was bought by a spy who called himself 'Takekawa'.
It's a common technique used by spies in Japan.
And Sasaura-san was sending
the intel to this 'Takekawa', right?
Yes.
The day after we discovered this fact,
we were informed by the Coast Guard that a suspicious boat was found near Maizuru Harbour.
A suspicious boat happening to appear near Maizuru Harbour, where this Aegis Destroyer was anchored...
It couldn't have been a coincidence.
And components from that country were found in the boat.
Yeah.
When we heard that, we figured a spy from the same country as Takekawa had arrived in Japan.
Don't tell me...
It was X?!
We thought X might attempt to board this Destroyer with Lt. Sasaura's help.
If so, it would likely be today, when the security would be lowered due to the sailing experience.
Why didn't you say that in the first place?
An SDF member might've leaked information about Aegis Destroyers to a foreign spy.
Do you really think we could openly talk about such a huge scandal?
We decided to investigate it on our own until we could find out the truth.
So when I found his mobile phone on the deck...
Did one of the civilians lose this?
Why is this here?
It's Lt. Sasaura's phone...
Well then, let's begin our investigation on the deck...
You found it before I did?
Then Sasaura-san really did board this Aegis Destroyer.
And was then murdered by X...
Excuse me, I must contact the Ministry of Defence.
You were the source of the satellite transmissions?!
I apologise.
But since you started worrying about it, I've been using it in the Degaussing Chamber.
Phew, we must've almost bumped into each other...
Fujii speaking.
The police and Coast Guard found out about the classified case we were investigating...
What? Takekawa?
Around two hours ago...
Yes...
He was confirmed to have entered Kyōto.
They found Takekawa?!
Right, I'll do so now. I'll be in contact.
The fact that Takekawa came from Tōkyō to Kyōto means...
That he might be trying to meet up with X, who's aboard this ship.
Where's Takekawa now?
Intelligence Security Command have entered Kyōto and are searching for him.
Then where was he spotted two hours ago?
He turned up on a surveillance camera in a hotel in Kyōto.
You have a photo of Takekawa, right?
Y-Yes...
We can track him with the N System, Orbis, and outdoor surveillance cameras!
If that is your wish, the Kyōto Prefectural Police offers its full support.
Please accept the help of the Coast Guard as well.
Please send the footage from all the cameras to this Destroyer.
I see!
We can use the Aegis Destroyer Hotaka to quickly analyse all the footage!
All right!
See, things worked out pretty well!
This is the footage from the cameras in Kyōto, two hours ago.
I asked for footage from the cameras around the hotel where Takekawa was spotted to be sent first.
A message from the Maizuru base!
After towing the shipwreck, they found components from that country in the boat's structure.
I'm putting it on the main monitor.
It's from the same country as the one on the suspicious boat...
But it's unthinkable for foreign ships to be passing through Japanese waters...
In other words, this shipwreck approaching us can't have been a coincidence.
Don't tell me...
Are you saying it's an act of terrorism using the tide?
No, that can't be.
This morning, before departure, we calculated the tides and the routes of the boats in the nearby area,
and decided to change our planned route to the left.
It was changed this morning?
It was changed this morning...
So the route...
At 5:30 this morning, Sasaura-han was seen waving a Japanese flag on a cliff at Maizuru Harbour...
Don't tell me that the reason for that was...
I'll just have to check!
This route change was decided this morning...
Without knowing about it, it would have been impossible to target us so precisely with the shipwreck...
Yes.
Who knew about the change of route?
Only people from the Wakasa base.
I see. So the spy couldn't have known about it.
Wait, kid! Kid!
Kid, you're coming here without permission again?
You can't!
What is it?
I'm so sorry... He just ran past me...
Is that it?!
Hey!
Don't come in here without permission!
Oh? This isn't mine!
Of course it's not!
How many times do I have to tell you—
Wait!
You told us that only people from the Wakasa base knew about the change of route, right?
Yes.
Then Lt. Sasaura knew about it too.
Look at this signal flag!
In the dim early light of dawn, it wouldn't be hard to mistake it for the Japanese flag.
Indeed.
I see!
Sasaura-san used this flag to send X a signal this morning!
A signal?
What does that flag mean?
'Change of route to the left'.
Then...
Yes.
X knew about the change of route.
Oh? I guess I must've left it somewhere else...
I better get back to the cafeteria...
Of course it's not here!
Hold on, kid.
Crap...
Target spotted!
Really?
Yes.
It's a 93% match.
It has to be Takekawa!
Where is he?
Ponto Town Park, Kyōto.
12:03 PM.
Zooming in!
Ponto Town Park, right?
Yeah, hurry there!
If we don't hurry, they'll beat us there!
Stop badgerin' me!
Oh, and get a picture of Takekawa too.
A picture?
Why?
I'm counting on you.
He hung up...
Anyway, hurry up!
Here we go!
Crap...
Conan-kun spotted!
Where did you go? The treasure hunt's already started!
Target spotted!
12:10 PM, a platform at Gion-Shijō Station on the Keihan Main Line.
That platform's for trains to Ōsaka, right?
Ah, he's getting in!
It's an express train!
So there won't be many stations it stops at.
I'll ask the Ōsaka Police to cooperate.
The kid's gone...
Ōsaka Police HQ
Please send all surveillance footage
from cameras at stations served by express trains on the Keihan Main Line between Gion-Shijō and Yodoyabashi to this location.
The CIC of the Aegis Destroyer Hotaka?
I'm counting on you, Ōtaki.
It's urgent!
Yes, sir!
For this treasure hunt, we've hidden five types of items around the cafeteria and the front half of the deck.
Try and find them all!
Found one!
Guys, I got one!
Cool!
Congratulations.
That's the third one.
So there's only two remaining.
Let's find them quickly and get to the deck.
Yes.
Ran, come help us!
Right.
The discovery of a suspicious boat...
The sudden switch into combat...
And Sasaura-san's death...
If they were all the work of that country's spy, 'X'...
We believe he is trying to obtain classified intel on Aegis Destroyers.
Kid...
Can I ask you something?
Ponto Town Park
Something smells burnt.
Yeah.
This must be what Kudō asked us to find.
The police are here.
Found it, there it is!
Okay, report it in quickly!
Right!
Conan-kun...
You did a great job back then.
Huh? What do you mean?
Just who are you?
Just what kind of data can only be obtained on this ship?
Is it data about situations like what would happen if a submarine suddenly attacks?
How do you know about...
That's what I thought...
Do you mean X sent us the shipwreck to get this data?
Where can the data be accessed?
In the CIC we were just in...
...and in the captain's quarters.
That's it!
During the training, the captain came to the CIC because of the sudden emergency.
So there was nobody in the captain's quarters at the time.
I see.
So that's when X went into the captain's quarters and stole the data!
Then X is that person!
Hold on!
Conan-kun!
That brat again?
I'm a bit worried, so I'm going after him.
W-Wait, Ran!
Wait, kid!
Capt. Fujii!
Takekawa entered Ōsaka!
Ōsaka?
Yes, at Yodoyabashi Station.
Kudō?
What Takekawa threw away is some kind of memo.
A memo?
Yeah. Most of it is burnt though, so I can't read it.
It seems Takekawa went to Yodoyabashi Station in Ōsaka.
Go after him!
Gotcha!
Yūki-kun. Yūki-kun.
Amemiya-san? Amemiya-san!
Amemiya-san!
Oh, it's you.
Hey, is Yūki-kun okay?
Now that you mention it, where is Yūki...
He told me he went to the toilet because his eczema flared up.
Oh, his eczema.
Yeah.
When that happens, he has to wash his hands and put on some cream, right?
Y-Yeah.
So he's in the toilet...
Are you worried about Yūki-kun?
Of course I am.
But when the boat shook, you weren't with him...
I told you I was in the toilet!
No, you were in the captain's quarters.
You didn't react when I called you Amemiya-san either.
And Yūki-kun isn't carrying medical cream, but pills.
And they're not for eczema, but food allergies.
There's no way his father wouldn't know something like that.
In other words, you're not Yūki-kun's father.
Isn't that right?
Mr. Foreign Spy.
Who the hell are you?
Conan Edogawa...
Detective.
You're just a kid.
What can you do?
You okay, kid?
Wait!
Stop!
My dad'll be killed!
Damn it, old man...
This is the only part I could make readable.
Senshu...
What's that at the end?
senshu
If it's related to an Aegis Destroyer, isn't it the bow of the boat?
And if it's about boats, isn't that an anchor?
No! The bottom half of an anchor sign is longer!
It looks more like an arrow than an anchor.
An arrow?
Like an arrow telling you to look up at the sky?
The sky?
Oh, I got it!
Kazuha! That was a great idea!
A great idea?
Hey, pops, it's Senshu Airport!
What?
This isn't an anchor or an arrow.
It's an aeroplane!
An aeroplane?
Is there even a Senshu Airport?
It's also known as Kansai International Airport...
Kansai Airport used to be called 'Senshu Airport'!
He told me that his father vanished at Maizuru Harbour before departure, and he boarded the ship with a man he didn't know.
He said he'd kill Dad if I didn't do what he said.
The man who wasn't with us in
the CIC during the training, right?
He had to be stealing the training data from the captain's quarters.
Which means he's X.
Do you remember his face?
Yes.
Will you help us?
I will!
I remember his face!
Then come with us to look at the surveillance camera footage in the CIC.
Okay!
Let's go.
Let's go, little boy.
Your dad told you why he named you Yūki, didn't he?
yūki
So be brave and do your best.
Takekawa and X...
It seems we haven't been able to catch either of them yet.
I see.
It's Kansai Airport!
There's a high chance Takekawa went to Kansai Airport.
What?
How do you know that?
Well, Hei-chan...
I mean, your son...
Heiji?
Then?
I tried to stop him but he's already heading there.
Tōyama, set up an emergency deployment at Kansai Airport.
Ōtaki, you meet up with the Kansai Airport police!
Don't let him get away!
Here it is...
And where did Takekawa go after that?
We last spotted him at Namba Station. Nothing after that.
Is that so?
What about the eyewitness for X?
Conan-kun ended up helping us with that.
Okay, sit here and check the monitor.
Okay!
How come he knows X?
Tell me if you see the man from before on the monitor.
Yes...
No, the footage is disappearing!
What?
This is footage stored in the server room.
What is it?
He got us. He must've deleted the footage from the server.
Damn, he beat us to it.
Don't you have any other footage?
We can still monitor the real-time camera footage.
Switch to those, now!
Right.
Just hold on for a bit, kid.
I doubt X would screw up and expose himself to a camera at this point.
The only thing we can do now is ask Yūki-kun about the routes X tended to use.
A message from the Ōsaka Police.
There's a high possibility that Takekawa's headed for Kansai International Airport.
What?
Is he planning to escape on a plane in plain sight?
We apologise, but we have to
stop the treasure hunt on the deck.
We will continue it in the cafeteria, so please head back inside.
Where did Conan-kun go?
Sorry, the waves are getting
rougher, so please head back inside.
Have you seen a boy wearing glasses?
A lost kid?
No, it's not like that...
Then please get back inside...
We're sealing off the deck.
R-Right...
It seems Takekawa's heading to Kansai Airport.
I'm going to ask the Coast Guard base at Kansai Airport for their cooperation.
Inoue-san, I leave the rest to you.
Right.
Now we just have to find X in this ship...
Your dad told you why he named you Yūki, didn't he?
yūki
So be brave and do your best.
I...
I want to help catch the spy too!
Target spotted at Kansai Airport!
It's a 89% match!
The North Wing of the terminal.
This is footage from the surveillance camera outside gate #3.
He's heading into the airport.
We'll be there soon, Yūki-kun.
Excuse me, can I ask you something?
Yes. What is it?
Could it be... You're X—!
What is it, Yūki?
Did you think I'd just let you go, when you know my travel routes?
Stand up!
Hurry and stand up!
Geez, that Conan-kun!
Next time I find him, I'm never going to let him go about freely again.
Huh? Is that Yūki-kun and his dad?
Didn't they know the deck's off-limits?
Are you sure he's here?
Yes, Takekawa's definitely here.
Then we'll follow you after we park the car.
Okay, we'll go ahead.
Hey! Wait, Heiji!
Why are we here?
The police know Takekawa's face now.
He can't mix in with the regular passengers.
Where did you get this picture?
I made Ōtaki-han send it to me.
So the only way to board a plane without exposing his face is... freight.
In other words, the only thing he can do is hide in the international freight.
Hey, kids!
This place is dangerous, move it!
Right!
We're waiting here until the next patrol comes.
Got it?
If you stay quiet, you'll get to meet your father.
Excuse me!
Have you seen Conan-kun?
He's the boy with glasses who was with me.
No, we haven't seen him.
Is that so?
You haven't seen him either, Yūki-kun?
Yūki was with me, so I doubt he saw him.
Lost kids really are a bother, huh?
Isn't that right.
See you later, Yūki-kun.
Geez, he's always disappearing...
Oh, I forgot to tell you but this place is off-limits!
Really?
Then we'll head back in once Yūki's seasickness is over.
Miss, save me!
This man is a spy!
Yūki!
Do you really think you can do that?
What is it, Yūki-kun?
Are you okay?
Excuse us.
We kept playing spies so I guess it got to his head...
That's not it!
This man isn't my father!
Not your father?
Then you stay with him, Conan-kun.
I'll talk to an SDF member about Yūki-kun's situation.
Stop. If you do that...
If I do that...?
I'm fine.
He really isn't your father, is he?
No, he's not!
Save me, Miss!
Enough, Yūki!
Yūki-kun, come here!
Stupid girl.
If you'd minded your own business, you wouldn't have to die!
So you really are a spy.
I am...
But it's too late for you to have regrets.
What?
Yūki-kun, call everybody!
OK.
Brat.
I won't let him go!
Figures.
But...
Target spotted.
He's at the International Freight Section G.
Okay.
You're sure about it?
Yes, it's a 97% match.
I'm counting on you, Hattori.
Hello? This is Megure from the Tōkyō Police.
We spotted Takekawa in Section G.
Okay.
Takekawa's in Section G.
Section G's this way.
Oh, you can't go in there.
Let me go!
Kid, you can't go in there.
Stop!
I told you to let me go!
Yūki-kun!
The spy!
What?!
The spy was there!
With a face like this, he could be anywhere! How am I supposed to find him?
Hey, watch out!
You okay?
Thanks...
Don't be so stupid.
Wanderin' around alone like that's dangerous.
Wait for me here, okay?
I'll be back soon!
Hey, Heiji!
If that's how you're gonna be, I'll show you! I'll find Takekawa before you!
T-Takekawa?!
Wait, Takekawa! Wait! You won't get away!
What is it, Kazuha? Kazuha!
Where did you go?
Don't tell me she went off on her own!
There!
It's him!
This is the police! Stop!
Move!
Stop!
Wait, Nanami-san!
Let's go to the deck.
A spy who had his identity exposed isn't going to wait aboard the ship until we reach the harbour.
You're right.
But you two...
Wait, Conan-kun!
Yūki-kun, go back to where everyone is. Okay?
But that lady...
Wait!
Don't come any closer!
Not one more step!
Give yourself up!
You have nowhere to run!
You sure about that?
Don't do anything stupid!
There's too many obstacles in the way.
It's almost vertical.
I can't shoot my ball at that angle.
There!
Nanami-san!
Can you rotate that cannon anticlockwise?
The cannon?
If you can, do it right now!
Please!
Kazuha!
Die!
Hei... ji...
Get down!
You okay, Hei-chan?!
Stop!
You're not getting away!
Don't move!
Go!
No way!
Suspect arrested!
Give yourself up, Takekawa!
Okay, I'll leave the rest to you.
You okay, Hei-chan?
Hurry up, call an ambulance!
Don't be so dramatic...
Heiji!
I'm fine, it's just a scratch.
Really, Hei-chan?
Yeah.
What is it, Kazuha?
Oh, crap.
Don't cry!
Ouch!
I just got shot there, you know!
Let go! Lemme go!
Ouch!
I was getting a bit nervous there.
But now it's case clos—
Inspector!
Please look at this.
The Kansai Airport Police informed us that they found a pressurised room disguised as a healing capsule among the international freight.
So he planned to escape in that.
Also, after seizing Takekawa at Kansai Airport, they found a suspicious voicemail, so I asked them to send it to us.
Play that voicemail as soon as you can.
It might be a message from Lt. Sasaura.
Got it. I'll set it up.
Yummy!
Say...
What is it?
Are you lost?
Where is the lady who was with you?
You mean Ran?
Now that you mention it, where is Ran-oneesan?
She's still looking for Conan-kun.
The access ID is 'aegis0902'.
The password is '0505informer'.
There's no doubt about it, that's Lt. Sasaura's voice.
Message recorded on April 20th, at 5:30 AM.
That's Sasaura-san's estimated time of death.
This voicemail was on Takekawa's phone.
This is definitive proof that Lt. Sasaura sent the data about the Aegis Destroyers to Takekawa.
We could hear the waves too, right?
So maybe he was somewhere near the sea.
Waves?
And we can hear someone else talking too.
Play it again!
Right.
I saved the Aegis data on the KRY Cloud.
The access ID is 'aegis0902'.
The password is '0505informer'.
What's that metallic sound?
Play the last part again.
Right.
The password is '0505informer'.
It's true, you can hear something.
It's a man's voice.
But we can't understand what he's saying.
I'll send it for analysis.
Thank you.
What's this uneasy feeling I have?
It's like there's something still left unsolved...
Is that you, Shin'ichi?
The TBT we found on Sasaura-san's body isn't from the Aegis Destroyer Hotaka.
But it is boat paint, right?
Yes. After checking the ships arriving and departing from Maizuru Harbour and Wakasa Harbour,
we found out that one of the sightseeing cruises passing by the old naval port
left Maizuru Harbour and passed by Wakasa Shipyard today.
As expected, the paint on that sightseeing cruise matched with the TBT.
Then Sasaura-san's body was dragged along by that sightseeing cruise and moved from Maizuru Harbour to Wakasa Harbour?
Yes, there's no doubt about it.
A sightseeing cruise departing from Maizuru Harbour?
At 5:30 this morning, Sasaura-han was seen waving a Japanese flag on a cliff at Maizuru Harbour.
An employee from a sightseeing cruise witnessed it.
The password is '05—
Message recorded on April 20th, at 5:30 AM.
His watch stopped at 5:30 AM.
And the last call was this morning at 5:30.
5:30 this morning?
That's when his wristwatch stopped.
It's also his estimated time of death.
The time the witness saw Sasaura-san...
The time he left the voicemail...
The time he died...
They were all at the same time!
5:30!
Oh, I see! I made a huge mistake!
After having been arrested at Kansai Airport,
Takekawa was brought to the Ōsaka Police Security Department's Public Safety Division.
We're thinking of bringing X there too once we reach Maizuru Harbour.
You sure the Self-Defence Force doesn't have to be part of the investigation?
There's no distinction between the JMSDF, the Coast Guard, or the Police when it comes to an investigation.
Takekawa and X should be investigated together.
I agree.
Right.
Now the case is closed!
True. Looks like we didn't need your deductions this time, Mouri-kun.
Mouri-san!
Mouri-san?
Umm, that's the captain's seat!
Are you okay?
No problem, I just felt slightly overcome.
Seasickness? In a ship this big?
No, I was overcome by the brilliance of my own deduction.
What are you talking about now, Mouri-kun?
I figured it out.
I know who killed Sasaura-san.
'Who killed Sasaura-san'?
Isn't it X, who we just arrested?
X did infiltrate this boat to steal the data about the Aegis Destroyers.
Yes. And he killed him in order to steal the data card in his phone.
No, the person who stole the data card from his phone was Capt. Fujii.
That's true.
Huh? Then why was Sasaura-san murdered?
Indeed, there was no reason for him to be killed.
In other words, he wasn't killed by X!
What?
Then who...?
Please think back.
Sasaura-san was on a cliff at Maizuru Harbour this morning.
Yes, waving a flag to X.
Yes, and then he fell into the sea and died.
In other words, he never boarded this ship today.
Say what?
But his phone was aboard this Aegis Destroyer!
That's because the killer left it there in a hurry to make us think the victim had boarded this ship.
Think back, Fujii-san.
When and where did you find Sasaura-san's phone?
Now that you mention it...
It was quite some time after we departed.
And nobody noticed it before, despite being in such an obvious location.
Exactly. So why?
It's because it was a fake piece of evidence crafted after our departure.
In other words, the killer is someone who boarded this Aegis Destroyer midway.
Isn't that right, Kurata-san?
Impossible!
I hadn't even heard of Sasaura-san before this case!
He's right, Mouri-kun!
He had no motive to kill Sasaura-san!
Yes, he didn't intend to kill him.
What?!
Conan!
Play the voicemail recorded by Sasaura-san that we found on Takekawa-san's phone.
I saved the Aegis data on the KRY cloud. The access ID is...
Can't you hear a metallic sound?
You're right.
I've heard that sound somewhere before...
What is that sound?
It's the sound made when an expandable baton and a gun secured at your waist bump into each other.
Isn't that right, Kurata-san?
Hold on!
Everybody in the Security Department of the Coast Guard has an expandable baton and a gun!
I see.
But this voicemail was recorded this morning at 5:30.
And his time of death is...
This morning at 5:30!
So he couldn't have boarded this ship while carrying his phone.
Furthermore, you were the one who found the suspicious ship this morning at Maizuru Harbour, Kurata-san!
So at that time, you were patrolling Maizuru Harbour.
Or are you still going to deny it?
Don't move!
To think...
I never thought things would turn out like this!
Who could that be, this early?
How strange...
Hey! What are you doing there?!
Damn...
Hold on!
This is the Coast Guard!
Hey! Stop!
He was obviously suspicious.
Let me go!
He was running away, having just conveyed the information about the Aegis Destroyers to Takekawa.
I didn't know that.
When I rushed to the bottom of the cliff to look for him in the sea, I found that suspicious ship.
After that, I was busy reporting it to HQ and contacting the JMSDF.
Then, at that time, we were informed by the Kyōto Police that Lt. Sasaura's arm had been found aboard this Aegis Destroyer.
I quickly checked the belongings of this man who'd fallen this morning.
And I realised that the man who'd been acting so suspiciously this morning was Lt. Sasaura.
More than the charges for professional negligence, I was afraid of being charged with killing a Self-Defence Force member.
So I asked my boss to let me
take part in this investigation.
Why did you do such a thing?
It's because I knew there was a chance he'd been killed aboard this Aegis Destroyer.
I thought that if he was found to be killed here, I could avoid facing my crime.
So I pretended to be investigating, and put his phone in an obvious location on the deck.
After that, you know the rest.
I sincerely apologise for my selfish behaviour that disturbed the investigation.
Uncle!
Have you seen Ran anywhere?
No.
No matter how much we search, we can't find her!
She probably got lost again.
No!
We looked everywhere!
She disappeared after fighting the spy!
What?!
Inspector?
What is it, Satō-kun?
X made a rather alarming statement.
An alarming statement?
Yes.
It seems his identity was exposed by a young lady just before we caught him.
So he said he pushed her into the sea to keep her silent.
It seems this young lady was of high school age and proficient in karate.
Karate?
Could it be?
R-Ran!
No way!
No way! Ran-san...
No!
Don't tell me...
Ran!
Please hold onto any nearby handrails or tables you can find.
Make sure to hold onto your children.
According to X's statement, Mouri-san fell overboard around here.
We're pretty far away.
Wait!
It's fine!
Anyway, get the patrol helicopter ready!
Roger!
Move!
I made some calculations based on the tides.
She should be in this area.
No way...
It's four times bigger than usual!
Because of the low pressure coming from the southwest, the ocean currents are faster than usual.
The waves are starting to get rougher too.
Considering the stamina of the victim, every second counts...
Patrol helicopter ready!
All right. Depart right away!
Yes, sir!
Let me get in too!
Don't be stupid!
But...
A kid would just be a hindrance!
Damn it...
Considering the stamina of the victim, every second counts.
We have to find her before sunset no matter what!
Roger.
Every second counts?
Ran...
Ran will be okay, won't she?
What happens when somebody falls from that deck?
She should be wearing her lifejacket,
but that's all she would have.
If she fell in the wrong place...
How...
Of course, there's still hope.
Ran-san!
No!
Miss... It's all my fault!
Don't we have any way to guarantee her safety?
All we can do now is leave it to the patrol helicopter.
Damn it, even if we reduce the search field, it's nearly impossible to check the whole area before sunset.
Besides, Ran might still be drifting on the waves...!
Save me... Shin'ichi!
We're on location. We're beginning the search.
I'll call for her through the speaker.
Plug me in.
OK!
Mouri-san!
Ran Mouri-san!
We came to rescue you!
We're going to save you!
Hold on a little bit longer!
Ran!
Ran, where are you?
Hold on just a little!
Miss!
Don't die!
We'll save you soon!
I gotta calm down! There still
has to be a way to find Ran.
The waves are getting even faster.
I think we need to enlarge the search field.
We don't have any time left before sunset.
Limit the search to the Alpha Bravo Fox area and keep on searching!
Roger! Heading for the Alpha Bravo Fox area!
Ran Mouri-san, we came to rescue you.
Hold on just a little bit longer!
It's got a lot darker.
There's less than 15 minutes before sunset.
Sunset...
Sunset?!
Why does that matter?!
Keep on looking! Keep on looking until you find her!
I wish we could...
But in this season, the water temperature drops suddenly just before sunset, at 5 PM.
So even if we find her after 5 PM...
That's enough, Kishi-san!
Oh, no! The water temperature might already be dropping.
I'm sorry, miss. A rescue squad are heading here now, and we would best off leaving the rest of the search to them...
Damn, we don't have time!
Isn't there any way to find her?
Watch?
Oh, yeah, Ran has Mitsuhiko's watch.
Why?!
Why are you going to stop looking for her?
We will find her!
So don't give up!
This ship's supposed to be incredible!
Yes!
Do something!
It's the great detective of the seas, right?
The great detective of the seas?
I see. If we use the radar on this Aegis Destroyer...
At 1700 hours, we will leave the victim rescue to the specialist squad, and head back to Maizuru Harbour.
The radio watch!
Ran has a radio watch!
This Aegis Destroyer should be able to pick up that radio signal, right?
Mitsuhiko! You said the watch was fully waterproof, right?
Right!
The watch sends signals at 5 AM and PM sharp!
Captain, we don't have time!
Hurry up!
Prepare the radio wave radar immediately!
1 minute 40 seconds left until 5 PM. Can we do it?
We have to try!
Alert the bridge and the deck! Quickly!
Start the radio wave radar!
This is not a drill.
I repeat, this is not a drill.
Everyone on deck must evacuate urgently!
I repeat, everyone on deck must evacuate urgently!
Evacuate!
Please, make it in time!
Evacuation done!
Radio wave radar ready!
Start the ES search.
Search started!
It is currently 1659 hours. Only
10 seconds remaining until 5 PM.
9...
8...
7...
6...
5...
4...
3...
2...
1...
Now!
Any response?
No response within the search range...
No way... How?!
Maybe her radio watch has
already sunk deep into the sea...
Ran...
It can't be...
This...
...can't be...
You'll always manage to find me, right?
That's why I said I'd come with you.
But...
Don't go wandering off by yourself again, okay?
Next time, you mightn't be able to find me.
It's fine.
No matter how lost I am, you'll
always manage to find me, right?
You're a great detective, after all!
How can I be a great detective... I can't even find Ran!
Ran...
Ran!
Just now... That was Conan-kun's voice...
Didn't I tell you? I'll always find you, no matter what.
You're late!
Shin'ichi!
Could it be?
It's very weak, but I'm detecting radio waves!
They're getting stronger and stronger!
It's Ran!
Ran is there!
Lead the helicopter there!
Lead the patrol helicopter there!
Roger!
Target coordinates are four kilometres northwest of the destroyer.
Latitude 36°4'.
Longitude 135°.
SH, hurry towards the point.
Roger. Heading towards the point.
We'll be arriving at the search point soon.
We're straight above the search point but visibility is low.
The reflection of the setting sun on the waves is hindering our view.
Finding someone in these conditions will be hard...
Reflection?
Hey, that reflection —
is there a
single spot that's glittering a lot?
Umm...
Well? Please answer.
Yes. Part of the sea is strangely glittering and reflecting light from the helicopter.
There!
Follow those lights!
Ran should be at their source!
Ask the helicopter to head there as the kid said!
Please, Captain!
Follow the bright, floating objects.
We believe the victim is where those objects concentrate.
Roger.
We've reached the location where the floating objects are concentrated.
We're descending now!
There's something directly beneath us!
It's clearly not one of the floating objects.
Found her!
We found the victim!
We can confirm she's alive!
We're starting the rescue!
All right!
We did it, Takagi-kun!
Satō-san...
Good work. You did well. Take her to the hospital as soon as you pick her up.
Roger.
It seems the victim is still conscious.
But we'll take her to the hospital just in case.
Her body temperature appears to be low, but her heartbeat is stable.
Shin'ichi...
Old man...
Thank you!
It's nothing, it's nothing. It just
scratched me. It's really nothing.
Thanks, Hattori.
I told you, Kazuha, I'm fine!
Stop makin' that face!
Crap... Don't cry!
What's he doing now?
Your name was Conan-kun, right?
N-Nanami-san...
Thanks for all your help.
That's what I should say to you.
Thank you.
Bye!
Say, Conan-kun...
Who exactly are you?
Conan Edogawa.
Just an ordinary first-year primary school student.
Movie 18 —
In cinemas April 2014
But before that... Aren't you forgetting something?
Are you sure you want to do this?
I can't help it.
Then let's put an end to it.
In cinemas December 2013