Geez, Dad, the phone's ringing!
I've got it!
Yes, this is Mouri Detective Agency.
Mouri Kogoro, is it?
Yeah, who's this?
I've placed a bomb at a certain location.
What?
A bomb?
It will go off at exactly 3:30 PM.
If you wish to stop the bomb, solve
the code I will relay to you now.
Cut it out!
If you keep joking about that sort of thing...
I'll report you to the police!
What's so funny!?
Take a look outside the window.
Outside the window?
What's outside?
No way...
What the...
I'm high school detective, Kudo Shin'ichi.
While visiting an amusement park with my
childhood friend and classmate, Mouri Ran...
I witnessed a man in black in the midst of a suspicious transaction.
While caught up in watching the deal...
I failed to notice his partner sneaking up behind me.
That man forced me to swallow poison...
And when I came to...
My body had shrunk.
If those guys found out that Kudo Shin'ichi was still alive...
They'd come after me again and put those around me at risk.
At Professor Agasa's suggestion,
I decided to conceal my true identity.
When Ran asked for my name, in that instant...
I became Edogawa Conan.
In order to obtain information on those guys...
I went to live with Ran, whose father is a private detective.
He's so slow, that professor.
He must have misplaced his driver's license again.
He's always like that.
If he doesn't hurry up, we won't be
able to get an autograph from Hide!
We came so far and finally won the drawing!
What's more, it's rare that we get an
opportunity to meet real J-Leaguers!
Ayumi, Genta, Mitsuhiko.
They're my current classmates now that I've shrunk.
The J-League seems to be trending recently.
He's finally out!
Sorry, sorry, I couldn't seem to find my license...
As I thought.
Geez...
Always, Professor...
His name is Agasa Hiroshi.
And this is Haibara Ai.
She's one of the few who know my true identity.
What're you mumbling about alone over there?
It's time to go to Sports Land.
If you don't hurry up, we're gonna leave you behind!
You forgot, you know.
That thing you do every time.
You're right...
Despite shrinking, my mind remains the same.
The unbeaten great detective...
There is only one truth!
Beika Sports Land
J-league...
Sponsored by Nichiuri Television!
The 16th Soccer Class will kickoff right now!
The J-Leaguers!
Endou and Konno!
Narazaki and...
Nakamura are also here!
Well, let's start, shall we?
Yes!
Hey, number 10.
What happened, Conan-kun?
He said to take a rest since they
wanna start with just four.
Excuse me, but aren't you Mouri Kogoro-san?
Yamamori Shinzou ( 51 )
Nichiuri TV Sports News Department Head
I'm the head of the sports news department at Nichiuri TV.
The name's Yamamori.
Yeah...
It's so inspiring to be able to meet the famous detective Mouri-san!
Kouda-chan, get a picture!
Kouda Kaoru ( 27 )
Nichiuri Newspaper Sports & Entertainment Photographer
Yeah, no problem!
She's Nichiuri Newspaper's photographer, Kouda Kaoru-kun.
She used to be in the local news section, but got
transferred to sports entertainment this year.
Yamamori-san, this isn't the place to talk about things like that!
But, they said if you could manage to get some scoops here...
They'd promote you back to local news, didn't they?
Well, yeah...
Well, I wish you good luck.
Me aside, Yamamori-san, I heard that if you
can't increase the soccer broadcast ratings...
You'll be fired from the department head position!
That's true...
You have any good ideas, Mouri-san?
Of all people, he consults Uncle?
I have one!
Really!?
Yeah!
Have me appear alongside Yoko-chan as a guest!
The ratings'll definitely go up!
Yoko-chan, huh...
But her schedule is packed full since she'll perform
at the Shiodome Arena concert this December...
Hey, look at that!
Those kids have gotten really good, haven't they?
You're right!
Just when we weren't looking...
Great!
As expected, progress is fast when you're being taught by a professional.
Come to think of it, Ran, you never seemed this interested in soccer...
That's not true.
I often watch soccer on TV with Conan-kun.
But, you haven't played it before.
You're right.
But there was one time during middle school,
when Shin'ichi kicked the ball out of bounds...
That's right!
That time, he...
What's up, Ran?!
Nothing at all.
Hey, that person...
There's no doubt!
That's the miraculous lone striker, Nakaoka Kazumasa-san!
Nakaoka Kazumasa ( 21 )
Motorbike Shop Part-timer
The miraculous lone striker?
Yeah.
Three years ago, the one who led the Haido High team
to the national championship, that Nakaoka-san.
He was scouted by the Spirits and prospected
as a future ace striker candidate, but...
A month after the championship match,
he caused an accident on his motorbike.
With that, he disappeared from the soccer world.
But, the fact that he's here...
Yeah, he probably still feels an attachment to soccer.
All right, everyone improved!
Change over!
Yes!
Hey, number 10!
Look, he's calling you, Conan-kun.
Well, well, finally my turn!
The brat's good!
Good afternoon, Mouri-senpai.
Sakaki Ryousuke (32)
Sports Gym Instructor
I'm Sakaki Ryousuke.
At Beika University...
You're "Own-goal" Sakaki!
Own-goal?
Yeah!
He scored in his team's own goal during
the college league's final match.
Thanks to that, Beika University lost its only
chance at the championship in five years.
You heard about that, huh?
Of course!
I was watching that match from the stands!
Wait, how many years ago was that?
Ten years ago.
It was a traumatic experience and I still have nightmares sometimes.
Dad!
You didn't have to bring up something from so long ago.
Well, how goes now?
I work as a sports gym instructor and also oversee youth soccer.
Hey, that's not bad.
About that, there's someone I'd really
like to introduce you to, Mouri-senpai.
He's a huge fan of yours.
Would you be willing to spare some time?
Yeah.
Thank you very much!
Right away!
I'll bring him here immediately!
What was that?
I concede defeat, kid.
Wow, amazing!
That was so cool!
As I thought, he's just a soccer kid at heart.
Well done, Conan-kun!
Yeah!
Hey!
Whoa, a hunk!
Awesome, it's the real Higo!
Kudo Shin'ichi...
Do you know him?
Well...
About Shin'ichi...
Do you know about Shin'ichi?
Yeah.
I watched a match of his and called out to him before.
They looked so similar...
His and this kid's kicking form.
I think that's because Shin'ichi-niichan
has been teaching me soccer!
I see.
As I thought, he's teaching you.
Do your best in soccer!
Not fair!
Conan-kun got Higo to stroke your head!
I'm envious!
I guess you'd better not wash your head for a long time!
As you said, huh?
Hey, stop that!
Why not wash it?
I shall stroke your head too!
Me too!
Stop that!
Stop that, you guys!
Sorry for the wait, Mouri-senpai.
Could you spare a moment?
Allow me to introduce...
The manager of a small factory here in Haido City...
As well as the team sponsor head, Motoura Keiichirou-san.
Motoura Keiichirou ( 43 )
Local Factory Manager
I am Motoura.
I've heard so much about you.
I'm flattered!
Motoura-san is a really big fan.
When I told him that you would be here, he insisted on meeting you.
Oh, is that so?
I have some photos that I really must show Mouri-san.
Show me?
Yes, if you would.
Please show Ayumi and everybody too!
Let's take a look!
Geez...
Wait, that guy...
Conan-kun, let's look together!
And this is a photo of—?
This is my son, Tomofumi.
Please look at the other photos as well.
He seems to be enjoying himself.
Is your son here today as well?
About that...
Actually, Tomofumi-kun succumbed to
illness this August and passed away.
He was a fourth-grader.
I see...
Tomofumi has always had a weak constitution...
The doctors forbade him from doing any strenuous exercise.
Then, these photos are...
He insisted on playing soccer, so he pleaded with Coach Sakaki...
And was put on the team.
These photos are the only time he took part in a
match—thanks to the coach—and scored a goal.
So that's the instant the goal was shot?
Awesome!
He was good at soccer, wasn't he?
He's good...
I guess this is the last one?
By the way, why would you want to show me these photos?
Oh, no...
I just wanted you to see moments of
Tomofumi's from when he was alive.
I'm sorry to have disrupted the cheerful ambiance.
Somehow it's become rather gloomy, right?
Yeah.
Gloomy?
That's right!
At a time like this...
Don't tell me...
Could it be...
Let's enjoy a quiz as usual to cheer up!
All right, everyone, join us!
It's said that one characteristic of the cars owned by soccer players is...
"Tightly closed doors," which originated from a soccer term.
Now, which of the following is the term in question?
One: Offside.
Two: Hand.
Three: Corner Kick.
Four: Yellow Card.
This time the difficulty is a little higher, I guess?
Conan-kun, do you know?
Yeah, the answer is...
Two.
I think it's "hand" as in "handling".
If the doors are tightly closed, it means there are no half-closed doors.
No half-closed doors.
handoa nashi
No hand-balling.
handowa nashi
That's correct!
Amazing, Endou!
Not only are you good at soccer, you're also smart!
'Suuup.
Sorry I'm late.
Takahiro, you're too late!
Well, I overslept.
Who's that man?
Sanada.
He's a newcomer just promoted from Youth this year...
And is the sub for the lone striker Higo-san.
You sure have guts to skip the whole first half.
I'm bad with children.
Hey, brats!
I'm not just any substitute.
Sanada Takahiro ( 18 )
J-League Big Osaka Player
I'm a super sub!
Remember that!
Stop that, Sanada.
Hide-san, I've decided that you're my rival.
Let's decide who's the best in the upcoming match!
Before that, you will have to play in the game first.
Of course.
A declaration of war, I see.
Interesting.
That's good.
We'll be airing the season's final match
between the Spirits and Big after all!
We have to get hyped too!
To you guys, I wish you good luck!
Hey, please don't look.
Why's that?
You can't see yet.
Why are you being such a scrooge?
I promise I'll have a word with you once I get this down!
K.K.?
What's that?
Hide, didn't you have to go off earlier?
Oh, man.
Excuse me, Sanada.
We'll continue this in the final match in Tohto Stadium!
Hide looks equally cool when he's running!
I'm bad running...
Me too.
You can't become J-Leaguers then.
That's not true.
There are many players in J-League who are slow runners.
Really?
Even if you're slow, it's alright if you start running before other players.
However, because of that, you need to cultivate other skills,
such as reading the flow of a game and decision-making.
Right.
In short, rather than your running speed,
increase your thinking speed.
To make up for running slow, many people have to
acquire such strengths for themselves so as to flourish.
Even a seemingly minus characteristic
from other people's point of view...
As long as one can find a way to make the most of oneself...
There are many instances that things can be changed to a plus.
I see, words from professionals indeed have depth!
Nah...
Anything else you'd like to ask?
Yes!
Yeah?
Can you teach me the knack to a free kick?
Hey!
You're really impudent for a kid!
Hey, I don't mind at all.
We still have a little time.
Shall I demonstrate for you?
The way to kick is to start in front...
And, rather than just kicking, scoop it up with your feet.
GOAL!
Tohto Stadium
Endou successfully scored the free kick!
Four minutes into the first half, Gamba Osaka takes the lead!
Awesome!
It's just like the free kick I learned!
Hey, Conan-kun!
Which side are you on?
As a Tokyoite, don't you go around cheering on Osaka!
I know...
All right, put that on and cheer for the Spirits.
But, you...
It's all right, I bought a new one.
Big Osaka?
You—I knew it.
Don't misunderstand.
I only liked the color.
Geez, you're not being honest.
No way...
What the hell...
So, shall we proceed?
Take down the code I'm about to tell you.
What?
Blue youth and blue zebra.
Rain from above.
People from below, with their left hand...
As it is, show you the tree on the left.
Wait a second!
The left what?
Their left hand, as it is, show you the tree on the left.
The left picture, as it is—
Not picture, hand!
Hand as in handling.
Their left hand, as it is, show you the tree on the left.
Now, the game begins.
You bastard!
If you lose this game, there will be many casualties.
What's your purpose?
State your purpose!
You'll know soon enough.
Well, I wish you good luck.
Wait!
I can't solve it with just this!
A hint!
Give me a hint!
"Next is Beika."
"Next, Beika."
Wait!
Hello?
Hello!?
Dad...
Damn, they hung up.
"Blue youth and blue zebra...
"Rain from above...
"People from below, with their left hand...
"As it is, show you...
"The tree on the left."
And the hint is...
"Next is Belka.
"Next, Beika."
No matter how many times I read it, I still can't understand.
Inspector Megure, we have identified the explosive.
Plastic bombs were used.
They are designed to be detonated by phone.
I see, so it was just fortunate that there were only minor injuries.
We don't know where the next explosion will be, do we?
Only one hour and five minutes till the time
stated in the advance notice from the culprit.
Before then, we have to solve this code somehow.
I have it!
I know!
The bombs have been set in Haido Park!
Haido Park?
The clue is in the hint:
"Next is Beika. Next, Beika."
What does that mean, Mouri-kun?
This refers to the Tohto loop train line,
the station right before Beika Station.
In other words, it denotes either Haido station or Midoridai station.
Moreover, in Haido Park which is near Haido Station...
There's a huge water fountain.
A fountain?
Is that "rain from above"?
Yes.
And below that, there are statues of a youth and a zebra.
However, what about the meaning of the rest of the code?
For that, we'll know when we get there.
Hooray!
He countered!
Go!
Incredible!
This way!
Move over!
Excuse me!
Please move away!
Here it is.
Indeed, there are statues.
But this...
It isn't a zebra but a donkey?
The culprit mistook it for a zebra!
Also, it isn't blue.
The culprit saw them as blue!
All right, I'll show you!
Mouri-san, what're you...
I'll find the bomb right away!
No, Dad!
Right, we shall close the park immediately.
We have to evacuate everyone in here!
Yes!
"Blue youth and blue zebra...
"Rain from above...
"People from below with their left hand, as it is, show you...
"The tree on the left."
That one!
The bomb is below that tree on the left!
Below that tree...
Good, leave the rest to us.
Mouri-kun and the rest, go out immediately!
Yes!
Now, the Spirits are trailing behind by one point!
Uemura's up for the attack from the left side!
The ball is passed to the center!
A definite course!
Akagi shoots and...
Goal!
Goal, goal!
Goooooal!
Thanks to Akagi and Uemura's combination, the Spirits have caught up!
Just in time, both of you!
As expected, Hide and Naoki's golden combination came out tops!
There wasn't a bomb!?
Unfortunately, it wasn't under the tree on the left.
What about the other one?
The tree on the right?
Just in case, we dug out the area, but...
There was no sign of a bomb.
To be thorough, we are checking under the other trees as well.
It could be that the place the culprit was
referring to in the code wasn't here.
That can't be!
What a crowd!
That's because the vendors congregate during half-time.
If we don't hurry up, the second half is going to start!
It's from Ran...
Sorry, I'm going to the restroom.
Please pick up, Shin'ichi...
Hi, this is Kudo.
I can't come to the phone right now.
Please state the purpose of your call after the beep.
Geez, why is it always like this?
Shin'ichi!
Dad got a warning call about a bomb!
But we can't solve the code and we don't have much time left!
Ran, it's me!
Shin'ichi!
Tell me the code!
Ready?
Here goes.
And the hint is, "Next is Beika. Next, Beika," right?
The bomb's set to go off at 3:30...
There's only 40 minutes left, Shin'ichi!
Got it.
Give me a little time!
"Blue youth and blue zebra...
"Rain from above...
"People from below with their left hand,
as it is, show you the tree on the left."
What is it?
I feel like something's popping out of my head.
Damn, it's on the tip of my tongue, but...
Everyone!
Do you know the mascot characters of the Spirits and Gamba?
For the Spirits, it's "Zebra-kun"!
He's a zebra who's good at kicking!
Well, then do you know Gamba's mascot?
I know!
It's the blue one!
He's called "Gamba Boy"
Fantastic!
You're well-informed indeed!
"Gamba Boy" represents winning after working hard...
Zebra...
The star of Team Gamba!
Gamba Boy...
I see!
That's it!
The blue youth and the blue zebra referred to...
The Gamba and Spirits mascot characters!
Damn, why didn't I notice something so simple!?
Could it be...
The bomb is set up inside this stadium!?
Wait...
There was a hint, I think?
As I thought!
I got it!
Rain from above gives us RAIN [雨] as the top of a kanji.
People from below gives us PERSON [人] as the bottom of a kanji.
Left hand gives us HAND [手] as the left part of a kanji.
Left hand gives us HAND [手] as the left  part of a kanji.
As it is, show you means to simply keep SHOW [示] as it is.
Tree on the left gives us TREE [木] as the left part of a kanji.
If we take those four and make words of them...
While adding SHOW with them...
It becomes ELECTRIC SCOREBOARD!
As evidence of that, the hint "Next is Beika. Next, Beika"...
Refers to what's shown on the electric notice
board for trains on the Tohto loop line.
There's no doubt.
The bomb's been set on the electric scoreboard in this Tohto Stadium!
This is bad, if I don't hurry and confirm it...
At any rate, Conan-kun is slow...
Did he get lost?
Professor!
Professor, lend me the car keys!
Conan-kun!
Where did you go?
The second half is about to begin!
Whatever, Professor, hurry!
There, the kickoff for the second half!
The magnificent feat pulled off by the Spirits during
additional time in the first half that resulted in a tie!
The second half continues with no player changes...
Will they be able to keep the attack up with the current line-up?
On the other hand, Gamba hasn't made any player changes either.
Damn, isn't there somewhere I can climb?
That's it!
Let's go!
There's a child up there!
Reach!
That was close...
Rafinha and Rihara's matchup!
Taking over the ball Rafinha dropped,
Endou kicked it all the way to the side!
And Takei—crossed the ball!
A brutal competition in front of the goal!
Damn, it's not anywhere.
Which means...
Now, facing Akagi's dribble, Endou fiercely checks back!
Akagi passes back for now.
In front of Kihara, Shimura sends it to the front!
Nagata attacks!
A one-two pass of the dropped ball!
Akagi dodges the defense with his dribble!
A look to Nagata, and a pass!
The keeper punches it away!
What?
Don't tell me...
Kudo-kun!
Oh, no!
What's that?
Spirits Eleven, raising a furious protest with the umpire, but still...
Damn, they got a PK!
The other side knocked into him too!
Definitely, right!?
Haibara-san?
Well, the ball is set.
The one kicking is of course the one and only...
Endou Yasuhito!
It's in!
Two to one!
Once more, Gamba is leading!
Nice timing, Haibara.
Kudo-kun, what on earth are you doing at a place like that?
Genta and the rest aren't nearby, are they?
Yeah, it's all right.
A bomb?
Yeah, I haven't confirmed it but...
It's possible that it's been set up on
the electric scoreboard in this stadium.
Sorry, Haibara.
I'll call you back.
Wait, Kudo-kun!
Kudo-kun!
So they are there...
And they're precisely planted on the pillars
that support the electric scoreboard...
Wait...
That means...
The culprit plans to collapse it!?
Hello?
Kudo-kun?
Shin'ichi!
What now!?
The bomb is on the electric scoreboard at Tohto Stadium!?
Tohto Stadium!?
Electric scoreboard?
Yes.
Please evacuate the Spirits supporters
sitting on the home side immediately!
Got it!
These bombs are of a simple design, but
I don't have time to disarm all of them.
What do I do?
Think.
There must be something, something I can still do.
Damn!
If I can't stop all the bombs, I'll just...
Hey, why did you suddenly hang—
Sorry, but listen carefully to what I'm about to say.
As expected, there are bombs.
At 3:30 PM, the culprit intends to drop the scoreboard
on the Spirits supporters sitting on the home side.
No way!
That only leaves 30 minutes!
Yeah, they should start the evacuation of the supporters soon.
You keep watch and make sure that
Genta and the rest don't run wild.
I know.
That aside, Kudo-kun, what about you?
I'll prevent the fall of the electric scoreboard somehow!
The Spirits, trailing one point behind again, attack!
Shimura passes to Nagai!
An attack!
Itazawa to the goalpost!
Kicking the dropped ball up!
Akagi's on it!
Akagi scored a goal!
That was Akagi's second point of the day!
Spirits tied!
Hooray, Mitsuhiko!
Hey, Genta-kun, that hurts...
Wait, something's wrong!
What's the matter?
Look at that!
I wonder what's happening?
The club staffs are explaining something to the referees.
I wonder what's up?
It's right in the middle of the game too...
Haibara-san!
Did you see that properly, Hide's diving headbutt?
Ai-chan?
What's the matter?
Attention everyone in the stadium, we have an emergency situation.
What is this about?
Will spectators sitting on the Spirits side
please evacuate per instructions of the staff.
Could it be that Shin'ichi's involved?
Bombs.
They're attached to the electric scoreboard, according to Kudo-kun.
What now!?
I repeat, supporters seated on the Spirits' side,
please follow the instructions of the officials...
And evacuate in a calm and swift manner.
Something is definitely up.
But, what is it?
I'm worried.
Shall we go and take a look at the situation?
No.
Until Edogawa-kun returns, be obedient and wait here.
He's going to manage this somehow.
Well, only if he is still able to return...
All right.
Not good.
This is taking too much time.
No matter what, I have to defend this pillar at the very least!
Only ten minutes to the time limit!
Damn, will I make it?
Would everyone from this row please evacuate.
There's no need to hurry.
Please keep your distance from the
person in front of you and move forward.
Move with the flow in a safe manner towards the center of the pitch.
No need to hurry.
What's happening?
No idea.
But it doesn't seem to be a small matter.
Will the people from the media please also
move immediately to the center of the pitch!
Immediately? No way!
My equipment is heavy!
It's dangerous, so please leave your belongings behind!
Hey, don't kid around!
There's no way I'd leave my camera behind!
Exactly what's happening?
Like I said—
Hey, please don't do that!
Please come back!
On the net!
Broadcast it on the net right now!
Listen, I'll take all responsibility.
You just have to do as I say!
Got it!?
This will work!
D3 and D4 areas reporting.
Evacuation complete.
E seats, confirmed.
F seats, confirmed.
G seats, evacuation confirmed.
Everyone, quickly, move forward!
Hurry!
Please move forward!
Don't push!
Everyone, please cooperate!
Please keep your eyes on your child!
Only 35 seconds on the clock.
And I have only one left, but is my time up?
Please, hold up!
Incredible!
Kudo-kun...
Yes!
With this, the ratings will skyrocket!
Hey, look at that...
The electric scoreboard blew up!
All right!
I've finally gotten a scoop!
Attention, visitors of Tohto Stadium.
As of now, the stadium staff is working
hard to secure a safe evacuation route.
Please don't push!
It's all right now!
To ensure everyone evacuates safely, please move
in an orderly fashion toward the emergency exits.
The explosion is over!
Please calm down and move according to the officials' instructions.
Has it stopped?
Please, hold it up!
Damn, it's collapsing!
RUN!
What now?
Oh my!
An earthquake?
It's all right, please calm down!
Hey, what exactly is that?
Something's coming down!
What is that?
It's the electric scoreboard!
This is bad!
If they don't hurry and run...
It's no use, they're all unable to move due to panic!
Damn, did we not make it in time?
Shin'ichi...
It's stopped!
Incredible, it's a miracle!
Just a little more, come on!
WORK!
Good afternoon.
November 21st, Monday.
This is Live Information, Miyaneya.
Yesterday, the J-League was home to terrible occurrence.
An explosion occurred during the match, which was
just a step away from becoming a great disaster.
Please look over here.
Yesterday, during the match between
the Tokyo Spirits and Gamba Osaka...
An unthinkable incident involving an explosion
around the electric scoreboard took place.
Fortunately, the incident did not result in casualties, however...
The explosion did involve the famous
detective Mouri Kogoro in some capacity.
We will now conducts live report outside his office.
Tabeta-san!
Yes, we are now outside the Mouri
Detective Agency, Tabeta reporting.
By solving the code given by the culprit with great
brilliance, Detective Mouri saved the J-League.
But prior to that huge explosion, the culprit also
exploded vehicles right in front of this agency...
Thank you, Inspector.
For coming all the way down here.
Right now, whenever I go out, I can't get away from the mass media.
That's because the person who solved
the code somehow became Mouri-san...
Well, as usual, Kudo-kun asked us not to reveal his name.
Uhm, instead of standing around talking, please take a seat.
Thank you.
OK!
Brat!
By the way, Mouri-kun...
I heard you noticed something about the culprit?
Actually, it wasn't me who noticed something...
It was this kid.
Conan-kun did?
This brat here inquired with Ran and me
persistently about the phone call from the culprit.
I thought I would tell Shin'ichi-niichan.
He seemed to be really worried about it.
Incidentally, what was it that you noticed?
It was something the culprit said to Uncle.
Not picture, hand!
Hand as in handling!
I've heard those same words before.
Conan-kun, do you know?
Yeah, the answer is...
Two.
"Hand" as in "handling".
Indeed, it stands out.
Normally, one wouldn't say "hand as in handling".
Right?
The culprit, irritated by Uncle's repetition, said that without thinking!
The expression they remembered hearing.
If that's the case, it's the culprit's mistake.
Then, at that time, who heard those words of that player Endou?
At that time, eliminating-the J-Leaguers who
were there for the match and all of us...
There are four suspects.
Yamamori Shinzou.
Kouda Kaoru.
Sakaki Ryousuke.
Motoura Keiichirou.
Those four suspects surfaced during my investigation.
There was one more person.
At that time, another guy was on a nearby bench.
Nakaoka Kazumasa-san was there.
Isn't Nakaoka Kazumasa the one from that snowy National match?
Takagi-kun, you know him?
Yes.
Three years ago, my nephew invited me to watch that match.
Due to the heavy snow, the 2:05 PM start was severely delayed.
If I recall, the kickoff didn't happen until 3:40 PM.
The match continued until extended time with a score of 0-0.
Just four minutes before the imminent penalty shootout...
Nakaoka scored the winning goal and...
It finally ended at ten minutes before 6:00.
If we include that Nakaoka, there are five suspects.
Well, it's not impossible that they
coincidentally said the same thing, but...
If the culprit's motive was to challenge me...
What I've done recently and the people
I've met are all related to that soccer class.
Understood.
We shall investigate those five people immediately.
Regarding those five pointed out by Conan-kun,
we have conducted the investigation.
Shiratori-kun.
Yes.
First, Yamamori-san.
Thanks to the explosion incident...
The ratings have gone up, and he managed
to avoid getting fired as department head.
So the incident helped him a lot.
Next, Kouda-san.
She, too, was well on her way back to her previous position
at the local news section due to her scoop photos yesterday.
The incident was a lucky break for her too, huh?
Next, Sakaki-san.
At this point, we haven't found any motive that
would cause him to Blow up Tohto Stadium.
However, if we consider the culprit's motive as having
been sparked by Mouri-san's provoking actions...
Sakaki-san's own-goal fiasco during college was
ridiculed by you, or so we heard, Mouri-san.
You're "Own-goal" Sakaki!
I wasn't trying to ridicule him...
And he was laughing, too.
Well, he may be wearing a smile, but inside...
That sort of things happen sometimes.
Next, Motoura-san.
His only son, Tomofumi-kun...
After watching the J-League all-star match that took place at Tohto
Stadium and was broadcast on TV this August, suffered a heart attack.
He was rushed to Tohto Hospital in an ambulance, but...
We found out he passed away in spite of the medical intervention.
Tohto Stadium...
Ambulance, huh...
What's wrong, Mouri-kun?
Nah, it just somehow rang a bell.
Is that true?
Maybe not.
Maybe it did, maybe not.
Well, it's just me I guess!
Geez, don't confuse us like that, Dad...
Making that reaction and throwing us off!
Last but not least, Nakaoka-san.
Three years ago in February, after causing a motorbike
accident, he underwent surgery immediately...
Despite staying in rehab for half a year, his left foot didn't fully
recover its function, and the Spirits rescinded their offer.
The Spirits did?
Yeah.
He quit soccer soon after and departed to South America alone.
A year later, he finally returned here last August.
He went back to his hometown in Gunma, repeatedly
committing motorbike speeding infractions...
And seems to be leading a dissolute life.
In conclusion, Yamamori-san and Kouda-san both
have an apparent motive to blow up Tohto Stadium...
And were in a position where they could have easily set up bombs.
But it's hard to think of it as a put-up job.
It's also hard to think that Sakaki-san,
after being ridiculed about his own-goal...
Would proceed to vent his grudge or challenge onto Mouri-san.
I said I wasn't ridiculing him!
Regardless, what's bugging me is...
The fact that Motoura-san's son suffered an attack right after
watching the J-League match that took place in Tohto Stadium.
Yes, I was intrigued as well.
However, it's far-fetched to consider that a
reason to bear a grudge against J-League.
His son's death had no direct correlation to that.
Now, the question is Nakaoka-san, our last person.
According to testimony from Inspector
Yamamura of Gunma prefecture...
He did speed around like crazy, I'm telling ya!
How should I put it...
Right, as if he were a wounded wolf,
searching or a place to die alone.
Just kidding!
The reason he couldn't become a J-Leaguer was
due to the motorbike accident he had caused.
Regardless, it's highly possible he bore a grudge against
the Tokyo Spirits who rescinded their scouting offer.
Based on these reasons, we have decided to
thoroughly mark Nakaoka-san as our suspect.
Will the motorcyclist please pull over now!
Knock it off, will ya!
Why are you chasing after me!?
We had no intent of chasing after you.
Don't screw with me!
Staking out in front of my shop since this afternoon...
What the hell did I do!?
Now, now, we're only here to ascertain
whether you've done anything or not.
Dirty cops, talking bullshit like that!
Stop fucking with me!
Nakaoka Kazumasa!
On the charges of attempted violence and obstruction of justice...
You're under arrest!
You arrested Nakaoka-san?
Last night when we were staking him out, we
enraged him and he threw a punch at me.
And, we heard his side of the story this
morning after he calmed down, but...
It seems like it wasn't the case that he had a grudge against the Spirits.
What?
What do you mean?
Well, when we questioned him about how
the Spirits rescinded their offer to him...
That's a huge misunderstanding.
I have everything to thank the Spirits for, and no
occasion for bearing even the slightest grudge.
Stop lying!
What do you mean?
This is something even the media's unaware of, but...
The Spirits never rescinded their offer.
The one who declined the offer was me.
I asked them to take it back.
After the motorbike incident...
The Spirits footed my surgery bill and rehab costs.
And, even though my left foot never really recovered,
they said they'd be willing to honor our contract.
Be it only for fifteen minutes, they still wanted
me as a forward and their trump card.
Then, why...
My pride won't allow that!
A person who cannot stand on the pitch for the entire 90 minutes...
Has...
Has no qualification to play soccer!
As a professional J-Leaguer no less!
We confirmed that with the Spirits.
And from the motorbike shop owner he was
working part-time for, we acquired this.
Seems to be a photo he sent from South America.
It's an entirely different ambiance from
what I heard from Inspector Yamamura.
A message on the back.
"Boss, I guess I can't give up soccer after all."
I see.
Can't judge a book by its cover.
He could be a nice guy who loves kids and soccer to our surprise.
But, if Nakaoka-san is not our culprit...
Who on earth is?
Come to think of it, that time...
Suginami Sports Park...
6:00AM, K.K...
Who is this K. K.?
Now, then...
I've come all the way here, but...
Who is K. K.?
That person!
Morning.
You're early, boy.
Good morning!
I see.
K. K. means King Kazu!
It was Miura Kazuyoshi!
Uhm, excuse me.
What is it, boy?
Do you know Kouda Kaoru-san?
From Nichiuri Newspaper.
Kouda Kaoru?
Nichiuri?
Wonder where she got that from.
She knew about how I sometimes train myself here.
And she asked to take a photo of me.
Is that so?
But I refused.
I'm a pro, after all.
Rather than when I'm practicing, I'd like them to take
photos of me sparring in a match, won't you agree?
Especially when I score a goal!
As I thought, this had nothing to do with the case.
Oh, yeah.
Boy, do you like soccer?
Then...
Let's play!
Sure!
Good job, boy.
Thank you!
All right, let's run!
Now, go shoot it!
Golazo!
Nice goal!
That was a good shot, boy.
Thank you very much!
So cold...
Geez, Conan-kun...
Where'd he go now?
What's this doing here so early in the morning?
Don't tell me...
Another advance notice?
Thank goodness, it's just mail for Dad.
This...
Boy...
Yes?
Thank you for this morning.
For being my practice partner.
No, the pleasure's all mine.
As thanks...
I'll give you this.
Wristband!
Thank you very much!
That makes you the second.
The previous child I gave to was a red wristband, I think?
Guess it's been fourteen or fifteen years since.
I was practicing along with a boy just about your age.
That kid also made an amazing shot.
Is that kid in the J-League now?
Who knows...
I didn't ask for his name.
Well, if he still plays soccer, I bet he's become a J-Leaguer now.
Well then, take care and go home.
Yes!
With that, I'll see you later!
Hey!
Watch where you're going—that hurts!
Yamamori-san!
Kaoru-chan!
Sorry, I was in a hurry.
I guess we're both busy now, thanks to that incident.
I'm not as busy as you are, Yamamori-san.
That confident smile of yours must mean you got some scoop, huh?
Well, who knows?
Fine, I wish you good luck.
But, no thunder-stealing, all right?
I know that.
Bye then, I'm in a hurry!
Hey, hey, hey...
What the hell is that woman plotting?
That notebook, I'm sure it was...
"To Detective Mouri.
"Do not consider this over yet.
"Coming up next, more people than last time will watch
the explosions unfold in front of their very eyes...
"And share the horror with everyone else at the same time.
"Detailed instruction will arrive later.
"Well, I wish you good luck."
This morning, an envelope was delivered to our agency mailbox.
When I got it out, I saw that card.
I see.
Uhm...
Are you sure that's from the culprit?
Maybe it was a bad prank...
No, I'm afraid there's no mistake.
Last time, we released information concerning the code,
but the culprit's final words remained classified.
Final words?
Well, I wish you good luck.
I see...
"I wish you good luck."
Right.
And it's the same as the end of this message here.
Damn!
Toying with us like that!
But...
There's no code this time around.
Yeah, but there is a hint for us.
This part of the message...
"More people than last time will watch the explosions
unfold in front of their very eyes," we expect...
It means that next time, at a place where more
people congregate, bombs will be set up.
Last time, the crowd gathering at Tohto Stadium totaled 80,000.
Which means...
Next time, more than 80,000 people will gather at a certain place.
Is there any place like that?
There is!
Where would it be, Chiba-kun?
That!
That poster!
On December 3rd, at the Shiodome Arena...
A performance by popular young singers and groups will take place.
Also known as the "100,000 Concert"!
December 3rd?
What a second!
That concert, isn't Yoko-chan...
Yes, Yoko-chan...
Nah, Okino Yoko-san will also perform.
It's not as lightly as "she'll also perform," is it!?
Well, even with that...
The concert event where Mouri-san's close
acquaintance Okino-san will perform...
Is the target of the next bombing?
That can't just be a coincidence.
In that case...
Perhaps the culprit is indeed someone
bearing a grudge against Mouri-kun.
But, among the five people, I don't see anyone
who would seem to despise Mouri-san.
Uhm...
This has nothing to do with hatred against Mouri-san, but...
The sponsor of that concert event...
Is...
Yamamori-san's workplace—Nichiuri TV station.
In the news show where he serves as the
producer in the evening of the same day...
Part of the footage for the live concert will be broadcast.
I see!
If an explosion should occur during that live broadcast...
Their ratings would shoot up without a doubt.
Yamamori, huh?
Come to think of it, that guy...
Well, I wish you good luck.
To you guys, I wish you good luck!
Damn!
I see.
It's quite possible his pet phrase came out like that without thinking.
Also, regarding Kouda-san...
Maybe more than likely, she holds a personal grudge against Okino-san.
What!?
Against Yoko-chan!?
According to her colleagues...
She's been marking Okino-san for a scoop.
And complained that she couldn't get
anything from her due to her tight guard.
That reminds me, her notebook...
Say, say...
During that soccer class, I happened to take
a peek at Kaoru-san's notebook, and...
It said: "O. Y., December 3rd, Shiodome Arena."
What now?
O. Y. must mean Yoko-chan's initials, right?
Hey!
Why didn't you mention something as important as that earlier!?
Hold on, knock it off, Dad!
Now, now, Mouri-san!
It's not like we've determined that Kouda-san is our culprit or anything!
But, with that...
Those two emerge as our suspects again.
And the remaining suspects are...
That's right, Ran-chan.
About that message card from the culprit...
Do you know when it was put inside your mailbox?
I'm sure it wasn't there when I peeked into
the mailbox yesterday evening, at least.
Then, it was put in there after that.
Which means Nakaoka is not the culprit.
Yeah.
Why?
Oh, because he's still at the detention center.
He'll be released this afternoon, though.
By the way, Ran-kun...
What's this envelope you mentioned that was also in the mail?
Oh, right.
This envelope apparently was delivered early this morning.
It says the sender is...
"Tokyo Spirits Supporters, your fellow friends."
There's a thank-you message for my father and a necktie inside.
Oh, I'm sorry.
That envelope, it seems the glue has seeped out from the edges.
Not a problem.
Thank you.
Not at all.
Good.
Whatever the case, it seems our leads involving grudges
against the J-League and Tokyo Spirits have gone cold.
Once again...
Reopen the investigation into Yamamori Shinzou and Kouda Kaoru!
Apparently something's bothering you.
Yeah.
The concert in question will be held on this date: December 3rd.
The same as the final day of the J-League matches?
See?
Doesn't it bother you?
Plus...
Why did the culprit...
Mention things like this that might help us pinpoint the place?
Security will tighten, in response, and it'll only
deter the culprit from committing a crime.
Now that you mention it, I agree.
Even under tight security...
Does the culprit still have the absolute confidence
of being able to set up and bring in the bombs?
That's true...
Perhaps other than Shiodome Arena, there's another
place where over 80,000 people will convene.
Or, maybe the culprit is just lying?
No.
A prominent characteristic of this type
of crime is that the culprit does not lie.
I can attest to that.
If anything...
If anything?
They may employ a wordplay trick...
To mislead.
Sports and Entertainment News—First, the J-League!
On Saturday, December 3rd, the final
game of the season will be held!
In light of the recent Tohto Stadium bombing,
officials considered a cancellation, but...
During an earlier J-League press conference, Chairman
Oohigashi officially confirmed all will be held as planned!
The J-League final will kick off on December 3rd at 15:30.
Saturday the 3rd has another event at the same time, 15:30!
Power of the Music" in Shiodome Arena!
Otherwise known as the "100,000 Concert", this event...
Shiodome Arena
To our valued audience, may I please have your attention.
As you proceed to the event hall, our
staff will be checking your belongings.
We apologize for the inconvenience, but we ask you to show
your tickets and line up in two rows in front of the check gates.
Thank you very much!
All right, Yoko-chan, see you later.
Do your best on stage.
Excuse us then.
Ready for the live broadcast?
Yes.
Standby preparations should be ready by now.
We don't know what will happen during the live broadcast.
Tell them to never let their guard down.
Yes, sir.
Say, Inspector.
About the explosion, I wonder if it'll
really happen at Shiodome Arena?
Because, see...
What're you blurting out suddenly?
There isn't any other event that would
accumulate 80,000 or more people.
So isn't it obvious it has to be Shiodome Arena?
Geez, this is why I told you to go to the movies with Ran!
And so, Conan-kun?
Is there somethin on your mind?
Today's the last game of the J-League season.
It's the same day as the concert, so don't you find that intriguing?
It's something indeed worth noting.
Just a fluke, a fluke.
Geez, don't go spouting nonsense
and interfere with the investigation!
No.
We also considered that just in case, and
have already requested additional backup.
If I recall correctly, the final's kickoff will take place at 3:30 PM.
It's about to start now.
Now, the Tokyo Spirits will become the champ if they win this match.
The National Stadium
On the other hand, Big Osaka will be relegated to J-2 if they lose.
It's a battle that each of them can't afford to lose.
At precisely 3:30, it's kickoff time!
They're at it, they're at it!
So they've just started!
Say, Sonoko, why did you lie about going to the movies?
Sorry, sorry.
I figured if I said we're, going to watch
soccer, your father would try to stop us.
And today's the last time this year for
me to witness Higo-san's valiant form!
Go!
Do your best, Higo-san!
J-League Meeting Hall
Sheesh, they let Higo score just like that!
I want to eat something too...
I'll allow it if it's just a little.
Then, I'm headed to the store.
What happened to Higo?
Pressing his leg...
He collapsed!
Is he all right?
They're switching Higo out!
Well, an able player is likely to get targeted.
On second thought, not allowed.
Sanada, prepare yourself.
Already done that.
Good, score 'em goals at once.
Understood!
Sorry, Takahiro.
I'm counting on you.
Just leave it to me.
You can go ahead and rest for a year, senpai.
Idiot!
Just go already.
Subbing for Higo, now Sanada has come out.
What?
How goes?
Things on your end.
Anything out of the ordinary?
Nothing.
I don't think we even have 80,000 people gathered here.
And those guys?
But still, it's so awesome to be able to
watch all ten matches at the same time!
Yeah!
To be able to share the excitement with
everyone at the same time, this is amazing!
Well?
Did you hear that?
Edogawa-kun?
Excitement at the same time...
Don't tell me, the culprit's aim is...
Azusa-chan!
Don't worry, she works at the cafe downstairs.
Well, someone in a weird voice called our shop.
What?
Saying they left a message for Mouri-san
in the phone booth in the 2nd District.
What now?
"Warning!
"In the 10 stadiums where the J-1
league is playing, I have set up bombs."
What's that?!
Damn, so it really is that...
"The bombs will explode at the time the game ends.
No additional time is allowed.
"But since leaving you with no chances is not
interesting at all, I shall give you one chance.
"During the second half, if the team aiming for the home
team's goal performs a certain action as instructed...
"They will be able to stop the explosion.
"As proof of the stoppage, the electric scoreboard shall blink twice."
The electric scoreboard again?
"However, the only ones you may pass along this instruction to...
"Are the head coach of each team and their respective ace striker.
"You may not inform any other players.
"During the match, should any suspicious action,
spectator evacuation, or bomb disarming take place...
"I will blow up the bombs in that instant.
"As for the ace strikers, make them wear
a red wristband on their left wrist.
"Now, regarding the only action that will stop the explosion..."
"It has already been shown in this warning message."
What?
"Furthermore, even if the explosion should not occur, you are still
prohibited to disarm the bombs until 35 minutes after the game ends.
"Should you fail to follow these directions,
I cannot guarantee the safety of the spectators.
"Mouri Kogoro! If you wish to stop me, become
the eleventh striker and come to where I am!
"Well, I wish you good luck."
Shit, the same line again!
Messing with us like that!
As I thought, they're misleading us with wordplay tricks.
They got us.
All of today's matches started at the same time.
If we take all the spectators into account,
it will amount to over 80,000 people.
True.
In the warning message, it didn't say
anything about being in one place.
Takagi, when will the games end?
Let's see, I think it's at 5:15...
Only a little more than an hour left!
What's wrong, Sato-kun?
In the beginning of the message, the "Warning!!" part...
It looks like it was written after they stapled the pages together.
Look closely...
The red ink used to write the su
character was left on the staple, right?
す
I see.
But the question is, why did they write
the character after stapling the pages?
The staple...
And the red ink they purposely left on the middle of the staple...
Hey you, what are you doing?
I see, so that's how it is.
Now I know...
The certain play our culprit demands!
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
Did you figure out something?
Say, say...
The rectangular border surrounding this warning message...
Looks like a soccer pitch, doesn't it?
What sort of baloney are you talking about?
If the rectangular border represents the field...
Then the staple must mean the soccer goal.
Because, see, doesn't the shape of a staple look like a soccer goal?
Let me see for a minute.
What's more, the vertical stroke in su
extends towards the "staple" goal, right?
す
Isn't that...
The course of a shoot.
Could it mean to shoot in the middle of the goal?
Hold on a minute, Inspector.
To shoot in a goal means to pass through the goalmouth.
If that were the case, they would've written
the vertical line before stapling the pages...
And it would've gone under the staple.
But in actuality...
They first stapled the pages and then wrote the character.
The vertical line hits the staple and stops there.
I see!
The spot on the staple marked by the red ink...
Represents the middle of the soccer goal's crossbar.
If we think of it that way, the culprit must be
asking us to shoot at the middle of the crossbar!
All right.
Contact each club in the J-League at once!
Roger!
Megure speaking.
This is Shiratori.
We've found out the identity of the
suspect we're almost sure is our culprit!
What?
You found out who the culprit is?
Bombs?
Are you sure?
Yeah.
It seems we've been contacted by the police just now.
How about it, can you do it?
If you can't, you can tell me.
Nobody's going to say anything even if you refuse.
We can find you a replace—
Who else?
Saying you'll find me a replacement,
but who else could you choose?
The culprit ordered an ace striker, didn't they?
With Higo-san out of the game now, ace striker or not...
The only striker we have on our team is me, am I wrong?
Sanada...
Well, I'll manage something.
Plus, if I'm able to stop the bomb, I'll rise to be a big star in one leap!
What'll I do if all the girls start falling for me?
Sanada.
Put this on your left wrist.
No...
I'm shaking in excitement, in excitement!
I'm counting on you, Sanada.
Yes, sir.
The champ team is Tokyo Spirits, right?
Wrong, it's gonna be Kashiwa Reysol!
The players are coming out!
It's the start of the second half!
They've kept me waiting!
The second half is a must-see, too!
Yeah, right.
Hello?
Haibara, listen carefully.
Our culprit's target is indeed the J-League.
Ace strikers with red wristbands...
Roger.
I'll inform you as soon as I see abnormalities.
Do your best.
I'm about to meet the culprit we suspect...
Sorry, I'll call back.
Hold on, Kudo-kun?
Sorry to keep you waiting.
You got the location?
Yes.
Already got on, Mouri-kun?
What's this?
Why are you riding with us?
No choice.
Start driving!
Yes.
What was that!?
Professor, too noisy!
My bad...
So, who are these strikers from those places?
Pay attention to those with red wristbands.
According to Kudo-kun, the announced time of the
explosion will be at 5:15, when the games end.
Don't we have any way to evacuate the speculators?
No way.
If we did that, they'd detonate using remote control.
Looks like we have no choice but to have the
J-League players work hard for us, huh?
Yeah.
They're carrying the fate of all the supporters in the stadium.
The ten strikers, that is.
All right!
Goal!
He hit it.
What?
Sanada just hit the goalpost.
Is that true, Conan-kun?
Yeah.
The live broadcast says so too.
Excellent, the National Stadium is saved!
No, we don't know that yet.
I ordered them to contact our car once they confirm the
signal of deactivation on the scoreboard is present.
So it's not over yet?
What's this?
That didn't work?
Hey, Sanada!
Hurry back to your position!
Damn...
Hey, Sanada!
What the hell was that!?
You clumsy bum!
Sonoko, sit down!
Geez, why did Higo-san have to go and injure himself?
I came all the way here to see him and it's all for nothing!
Sanada, if you miss again, I'm not gonna forgive you!
What the...
All the stadiums are about hitting crossbars!
They didn't score a goal and yet...
Why do they look so happy?
As expected of the elected strikers.
To think they're still able to hit the crossbars
under such extreme circumstances.
Yeah.
Amazing indeed.
Inspector!
We have additionally confirmed the deactivation
of the bombs for teams Cerezo and Jubilo!
Roger that.
All right!
Only four of those left!
We're here!
Mouri-san's here too?
What's the deal with this?
So many of you here...
We don't have much time, so allow me to cut to the chase.
I was intrigued by the fact that the hospital your son
Tomofumi-kun was sent to by an ambulance and died at...
Was in the vicinity of Tohto Stadium where
an explosion happened the other day.
I then did some research.
That day, inside Tohto Stadium, the
J-League all-star match took place.
And, when the ambulance carrying
Tomofumi-kun passed by the stadium...
It was surrounded and blocked by some excited supporters.
The ambulance couldn't move further for a while.
I heard the supporters were having an uproar and pounding
at the ambulance with their hands and megaphones, right?
And the one who incited the supporters was...
I remembered that!
Right...
None other than Mouri-san.
What!?
That's right.
That day I won big time at horse-racing and was ridiculously drunk.
Damn, I had forgotten that all this time.
I see, so the one who was riding in the ambulance...
Was your son, wasn't it?
How long was the ambulance not able to move?
I think it was only about two minutes.
As such, I can't say for sure that was the cause of Tomofumi's death.
However...
However, had he not fooled around like that, it's
possible that Tomofumi might have been saved.
I, too, love the soccer that my son loved.
Of course the J-League too.
But, when it comes to Mouri-san and those troublemakers...
I just can't forgive them no matter what!
Regarding those supporters, which club were they for?
I don't know.
I couldn't see outside.
I only knew we couldn't move due to
Mouri Kogoro and the supporters.
I see.
You didn't know which club the supporters were for, so you
set up bombs in all the stadiums where matches were held.
Motoura-san...
We deciphered the code not long ago,
confirmed with Coach Sakaki, and are certain.
That you're the culprit.
What do you mean by "culprit"?
What kind of shot did Tomofumi-kun perform to score the goal?
It was...
The ball hit the middle of the crossbar
and went into the goal just Iike that.
That was the same as the answer to the culprit's code.
"Hit the middle of the crossbar with the ball," you see.
How about it, Motoura-san?
Like I've been asking you many times before,
what do you mean by "culprit" and "code"?
Motoura-san, regarding the ambulance story
earlier, there's something more to that.
Mouri-san and the others, who stopped the ambulance...
Were in fact trying to save a person.
That's true.
At that time, I dialed 119 in order to try to help an
elderly man who fainted due to hyperthermia.
I was waiting for an ambulance to come
while providing first aid treatment.
So it's finally here!
Everyone, move out of the way!
The ambulance's coming!
Damn, that ambulance is going the wrong way!
Hey, over here!
After that, the ambulance I called finally arrived,
and the elderly man was eventually saved.
Was that so?
Although it was a mistake, I nevertheless stopped
your son's ambulance, and I'm sorry for that.
I won't retort even if you hold a grudge.
But, it's just wrong to drag unrelated people into this!
Motoura-san...
Please stop the bombs at once.
As Mouri-san just said, what you're doing is immoral.
Hold on a minute!
What's the deal with all of this?
Are you saying it wasn't you?
The one who put bombs in the stadiums!
Well?
Something feels out of place, but what?
Inspector, Shiratori, a moment.
We won't make any progress like this.
Don't we have any other decisive evidence?
We have less than ten minutes until our time limit!
I see, this is what didn't make sense.
As I thought, this person is indeed...
Inspector, let's stop this.
I'm fully aware of the reason why you
all came to ask me these questions.
But, I am not involved with that!
I don't think Motoura-san's the culprit, either.
Because, he would've been very anxious
about the time if he were the culprit, right?
Instead, Motoura-san...
Didn't glance at his watch even once.
Even when you weren't watching him, Inspector.
Are you sure, Conan-kun?
I was watching him the entire time.
Geez.
But, the fact that the method to stop the bomb is the same
as Tomofumi-kun's shot should not be a coincidence.
So why is that?
Damn, so close yet back to square one?
Inspector!
Only one place left!
What?
Once they disarm the bomb at the National Stadium where
the Big versus Spirits match is going on, that'll be all.
So they've made it?
Motoura-san, could you please turn on the TV?
Yes.
We have five minutes remaining.
If I recall correctly, Big's striker is Sanada.
It's not Higo?
Damn.
Taking the remaining time into account, we have no
choice but to hope that Sanada-san can stop the bomb.
The only thing I can do at the moment is to
find the real culprit as soon as possible.
This is...
The same photo that was in Motoura-san's cell phone.
Huh?
Tomofumi-kun here...
He's not looking at the camera.
Who's he waving his hand at?
Say, say...
The man in the photo who's holding a video camera...
Is you right, Motoura-san?
Yeah.
I took a video of him, and my wife took
that photo on the opposite side of me.
So you use this video camera, right?
Can I take a look?
Yeah, I don't mind.
Thanks.
If my deduction is correct...
That person should be in it.
Gotta be...
There!
That person...
That's a foul, right?
Yeah.
A perfect position, too.
Motoura-san, please turn up the volume more!
Sure.
Foul.
Sanada's been tackled!
Big Osaka plucks a free kick chance!
Only two minutes on the clock!
Standing on the perfect position...
Sanada!
Pace yourself!
Looks like Sanada is up for the kick.
Deep breath!
Today's Sanada hasn't managed to
fully take advantage of his chances...
But this is the moment of truth!
Can he save Big?
Kick-off!
Big Osaka!
He did it at the eleventh hour!
How was it!?
Did he manage to hit it!?
I can't tell from the TV.
Stop it!
Wait!
On the contrary, the Spirits have been cornered!
The clock's ticking towards 90 minutes!
No way...
Did I not make it?
The announced time of the crime has passed.
Why hasn't it exploded?
Could it be the culprit fumbled?
No.
The reason why it didn't explode is because
the first kick already hit and disarmed it.
I believe the device on the scoreboard has malfunctioned.
Whatever the case, we were lucky.
The remaining question is, who is our culprit?
Haven't I been telling you that it wasn't me?
If that person is our culprit...
Then perhaps that person and this kid are...
Say, mister.
Did anyone else ask you about Tomofumi-kun's death?
Now that you mention it, I heard my wife told someone else about it.
But I can't be sure who that was.
As I thought, that person really is the culprit.
But that person has...
The tag on Tomofumi-kun's papercraft...
The glue came off...
That envelope, it seems the glue has seeped out from the edges.
Not good!
That was reckless!
No doubt about it, that person's the culprit!
Which means...
The timer on the bomb is still ticking!
Geez...
Hello?
Mouri Kogoro, right?
So you're...
Bastard!
Where the hell are you now!?
Looks like you are unable to arrive where I am.
What the hell!?
You're not qualified to be the eleventh striker.
The whistle signaling the end of play has blown!
The winning club for this year is...
Kashiwa Reysol!
This is bad...
I can't make it at this rate!
Hey, everything all right?
Never mind that, why are you here?
We heard everything from the professor!
What are friends for if you're going all by yourself!
Don't you go and try to look good!
You guys...
It's easy to figure out where you are anyway, Conan-kun.
Right, Ai-chan?
Geez.
Professor, to Tohto Stadium!
Hurry!
All right!
Step on it, Professor!
We don't have much time!
I know.
But why Tohto Stadium again?
They're still repairing it, no?
That place is the start of this incident, as well as the final goal.
It's Ran-san and Sonoko-san!
What?
I was just watching the end-of-season ceremony...
And look!
In the spectator stands at the National Stadium!
So Ran-oneesan's party was at the National!
No, that place should be safe.
Rather, I should focus on the culprit now.
You guys, stay here and watch out for anyone suspicious.
I'm going to find the bombs.
Understood!
If you're waiting for Uncle Kogoro, he won't be coming!
I'm the only one who came.
What's more, since I rescued all the
security guards you've knocked out...
I suppose the police will gather here in a short time.
I figured out the trick behind the card in the mailbox.
You placed the card on the same day you
caused the Tohto Stadium explosion.
Before you phoned Uncle Kogoro...
You inserted the card at the back of the mailbox
so that it would cling to the top and bottom, no?
Judging from the structure of the mailbox...
You can't see the card unless you really look into it.
And if there's other mail in the box, you'll be
attracted to those and won't notice the card.
And, on the same day, you sent the mail by
passing off as a supporter of the Spirits, right?
Large enough in size to be inserted into
the mailbox but still bulge out a little...
In addition, the glue would seep out
from both ends of the envelope...
A mail like that.
Of course, the mail carrier...
Would push the envelope to the back of the mailbox
in order to prevent it from falling out accidentally.
By doing so, the glue that seeped out from the
envelope would stick to the card you erected.
If someone pulled out the envelope...
The card would move to the front of the mailbox
and appear as if it were just delivered.
As such, the card would be considered delivered
after checking the mailbox the previous day...
And your alibi would be established.
To put it a different way...
The culprit is the one who had a solid alibi at that time.
Isn't that right?
The one who was caught by the police
and left in the detention center...
The one who had a perfect alibi...
The former ace striker from Haido High school...
Nakaoka Kazumasa-san?
Splendid job, considering you're a brat.
What was your name again?
Edogawa Conan.
A detective.
Nobody passed by.
Yeah.
In that case, wouldn't it be best if
we helped with finding the bombs?
You're right.
This dome looks pretty big.
Maybe it'd be faster if all of us looked.
You can't.
It's dangerous in the dome.
Wait until Edogawa-kun's return...
Hey, you guys!
Hold it right there, you guys!
The Detective Boys, onward!
Yeah!
This is bad, we need to get them back quickly!
Professor, be on standby here!
Leave the children to me!
Idle your engine so that you can chase the
culprit immediately in case they escape!
And?
When did you get to know Tomofumi-kun?
How did you find out about Tomofumi and me?
It was in the video recorded by Motoura-san.
The footage of you exchanging greetings
with Tomofumi-kun, Nakaoka-san.
Perhaps you two met when you were
in the third year of high school, no?
At the field in Haido Park...
When you were self-training, right?
How did you...
Haido High's dorm where you lived, Nakaoka-san,
is just an earshot from Haido Park.
And since I heard you were originally from
Gunma, I figured you stayed in a dorm.
Nakaoka-san, you talked to Tomofumi-kun
while he was watching you practice, right?
Just like how Kazu called out to you in the past.
Boy, do you like soccer?
Yeah.
The first time I met Tomofumi was back in
the spring of my third year of high school.
Like you just said, it was when I was self-training at Haido Park.
Yes!
Tomofumi, although born with a weak body
and unable to go through intensive exercise...
Began to practice with me little by little.
Our practice sessions, with only Tomofumi
and me, lasted until winter the same year.
Meanwhile, I won all the high school soccer tournament matches...
And scored the decisive goal at National
Stadium, so Tomofumi and I had a toast.
Oh, yeah.
Tomofumi, I shall give you this.
May you participate in a match and score a goal.
Thank you!
But, you caused an accident on your
motorbike in the following February...
And cut the relationship between you and Tomofumi-kun short.
Yeah.
My half-year long rehab after my surgery didn't go well.
To seek respite, I departed to South America.
And...
This June, as I was revisiting Haido Park after a long time...
Tomofumi!
Now a fourth-grader, Tomofumi joined the Haido City soccer club.
Due to his weak body, he's been sitting
on the bench cheering for everybody.
But he said his coach might allow him
to play in the next match for a bit.
I made a promise with Tomofumi that, if he can
score a goal in the match, we will have a toast.
And like we'd promised, Tomofumi scored a goal in his match.
After seeing that, I decided I would
resume playing soccer once again.
But then...
And with that, you thought you'd get revenge
on Uncle Kogoro and the supporters, right?
Yeah.
How did you manage to get the bombs?
One of my buddies I made in South America is an expert on that.
And you set up the bombs in nine stadiums.
And, the tenth stadium isn't the National...
But this Tohto Stadium!
The sensor you put in the National was a dummy, wasn't it?
That's why it didn't react to Sanada's shots at all.
The reason you left out National is because
it's a sacred place to you, Nakaoka-san.
On the other hand, you put bombs in this Tohto Stadium where
you vowed to stand on a soccer pitch as a J-League player.
And set them to explode at 5:50.
When Uncle Kogoro solved the code and
came here, you planned to die with him.
The significance of 5:50...
It's the time when Haido High became Japan's
best in the snowy National Stadium, right?
That's why you didn't write out 5:50...
Instead you wrote "at the time the game ends" in the message.
Yeah, that's right.
That championship match was the
end of soccer games, at least to me.
So this place is the start of my last moment.
Nakaoka-san...
I heard you said that someone who cannot stand on the pitch for
the entire 90 minutes has no qualification to play soccer, but...
You're wrong.
What?
To Tomofumi-kun, whose body was weak and
could only stay in a match for a short while...
Would you say he had no right to play soccer?
Even if you could only stand on the pitch for 15 minutes...
Wouldn't it be best if you found a way to make the most of it?
What could a brat like you know anything about me?
You're right.
But a real J-Leaguer would say...
"You don't know the real soccer."
As long as one can find a way to make the most of oneself...
There are many instances that things can be changed to a plus.
What's more, Nakaoka-san...
There's something else you didn't know.
That is...
Everyone did their best!
I wonder what happened to Shiodome Arena?
Nothing happened, huh?
Battery's low...
It's a lie!
There's no way Mouri Kogoro and the
supporters were trying to help someone!
That's just a lie!
It's not a lie!
That's the truth!
Nakaoka-san!
You think you can fool me with that made-up story?
Stop it!
Even if you do that, you'll only sadden Tomofumi-kun!
Sorry, but I can't go back anymore.
Stop it!
This looks bad!
Let's split up and find him!
Genta-kun, Ayumi-chan!
Wait up!
This isn't good, I'll have to evacuate everyone quickly!
With that, there's only one way to stop the bombs.
Did you see the electric scoreboard?
Although it doesn't mean anything now, as a trial for my striker,
my device will cause repeated explosions every minute.
And, if this thing explodes in the end...
It'll induce chain explosions of the bombs
I set up in other places, ending everything.
The manslaughtering detective and the supporters will die.
Uncle and the supporters will die?
Brat, the deduction of yours contains one single huge mistake.
Don't tell me, it wasn't here?
Right.
Regarding the stadiums mentioned in my
threat letter, this place wasn't one of them.
At that point, I hadn't set up any bombs in this Tohto Stadium.
Which means this place isn't the tenth stadium.
It's the eleventh stadium!
So, the tenth stadium is...
The National Stadium!?
That's why...
That's why you prohibited disarming.the bombs
until 35 minutes after the end of the game!
Was your purpose not to allow the
bombs in the National to be found?
Right.
The bombs in the National are linked to
the detonators in the bag right-here.
The explosion will happen four minutes before the end
of the game when I scored that goal at the National.
Precisely since it was the sacred place where I had bet my
entire life, I decided to annihilate it along with myself!
Are you sure there's no mistake, Mouri-kun?
Yes!
The culprit plans to have a showdown with me here!
Roger that.
I'll go check out the camera footage in the security room.
You stay here.
Understood!
Higo-san, you're so cool!
Higo-san!
I love you!
Did you see me?
Who was that?
Damn, why did she shut it off?
I beg you, Ran...
Pick up the phone!
You will now be connected to voice mail.
Why, Ran?
Hurry and flee, brat.
I have nothing against you.
The only one who can stop the bomb is the eleventh striker.
But that guy lost our match and is not here anyway.
Two more minutes and my revenge will conclude.
With this, Tomofumi's grudge will be avenged if only a little.
Cut the nonsense.
Not only did you flee from your broken dreams...
But you used Tomofumi-kun's death as an
excuse to vent your rage at everyone else!
What?
Limiting your potential all on your own...
You're just a coward who'd given up on your dreams!
You brat!
Spitting out crap like that...
The only brat here is you!
Shifting blame to others, deeming everything that
doesn't work your way as lies and trying to destroy them...
That's an outrageous, self-centered brat!
Don't you know that!?
What you're being disrespectful toward is soccer,
which was the very thing Tomofumi-kun loved!
And you're trying to destroy Tomofumi-kun's memory right now!
Haven't you realized that already!?
That's the truth, Big Brother.
Tomofumi...
Why do you have that wristband?
That's the one I gave Tomofumi...
No, it can't be...
It's not possible!
No one's the bad person here.
So please stop this.
Big Brother!
You mean...
You're saying I was wrong, Tomofumi?
I only wanted to avenge you...
And to go to where you are now!
So then, why, Tomofumi...
Why are you denying me as well?
Nakaoka-san?
There's no time.
Tomofumi...
Run away!
Shit!
Stop!
Not a chance!
You think I'll give up that easily!?
It's no use, not with a child's strength!
I'll stop it!
I'll stop the bomb no matter what it takes!
Go!
I've got it!
No way...
That's the only ball I have...
No, even if I had another, with things like this...
What now?
Since the explosion just now was the third one,
that means I have less than two minutes!
What now?
With the debris in the way, I can't aim at the goal post directly!
I don't have a ball with me anymore!
What now?
Conan-kun!
Don't tell me...
Ayumi!
We came to save you!
Hurry up and run!
It's gonna explode!
Conan-kun!
Mitsuhiko!
Genta!
Conan!
You guys, I'm telling you to run away immediately!
Even though I want to stop the bomb, there's not a single ball!
I have a ball right here!
Hide's autographed ball...
I don't know what's going on, but...
If we can stop the bomb using this ball...
Let's go, Mitsuhiko!
Is it really OK to use that ball?
Make sure you catch this!
Here goes!
All right!
Good.
Ayumi-chan, I'm counting on you.
Pass this ball to Conan-kun!
Yes!
Here goes.
On three!
It's here!
Wait for me!
Got it!
You did great, Ayumi!
Hurry and pass it to Conan-kun!
OK!
But what do I do?
Ayumi can't possibly kick that far!
It's fine if you can just kick it over the debris!
Think back to our soccer class training!
You guys...
Here goes, Conan-kun!
No way!
Geez...
I have to babysit you even in the end.
Haibara-san!
All right!
Ai-chan, please!
Pass that ball to Conan-kun!
OK...
Kudo-kun, I'm entrusting you with everyone's thoughts.
Go and receive it!
Well played.
You guys!
What's this?
What's with these brats?
Under these circumstances...
Do they seriously think they can still stop the bomb?
Hurry!
No time!
No use...
There's not even a minute...
I can't aim at the goalpost directly due to the debris, but...
With that type of shot...
Recall...
What I learned from that soccer class, that Endou-san's free kick!
I can do it!
Hit the ball with an in-front kick.
Rather than "kicking" it...
Scoop it up with your feet...
And strike!
GO!
It's useless!
It won't make the curve at that angle!
What!?
Curve around!
How was it?
You did it, Conan-kun!
Conan-kun!
Yay!
You're really something, brat.
So the eleventh striker was actually you, huh?
Edogawa Conan.
But, who would've thought that there were
bombs set up in the stadium we were in!
You're right.
Come to think of it, how did that go?
"That"?
Remember, you said something about how Shin'ichi-kun
missed kicking the ball during middle school and whatnot.
Hide's free kick!
Ran-neechan!
It's white...
How awful, Conan-kun!
Unbelievable!
What a brat.
What's white?
Pervy brat.
Oh, no, it's just...
Conan-kun!
I'm sorry!
Geez, since this is soccer, you should return it by heading!