Emergency!
Patrol car #503 calling headquarters...
Emergency...
Patrol 503, over
We found the criminals! They're in a stolen vehicle,
and are traveling along Sotobari and Gyoki roads.
Roger.
Please State the license plate number of the suspects car, and what both the car and the suspects look like. Over.
It's a black SUV,
with plate number Shinzuku 500, SA 32-55.
And the suspects look like...
Lupin and Fujiko!
Patrol 503, please stop joking around.
I'm not joking...
Patrol car #503 calling headquarters...
Lupin is now turning off Gyoki Road onto Middle Road.
Patrol 503, just cut the crap already...
Over.
I told you, I'm being serious here!
Wait a second, Sato-san.
Please drive a little more carefully...
Shouldn't you still be contacting headquarters?
Ah... Yes!
Patrol #503 calling headquarters...
Suspects are turning right onto Harumi Road.
How dare you wear a lupin mask for a robbery...
I'll never forgive you for that!
Welcome, and good evening to you!
That'll be 1,237 yen.
Pull your car over now!
What's going on?
Awesome!
Pull your car over now!
Let me repeat myself...
There's nowhere for you to run,
so pull your car over now!
You shouldn't have done that...
Now, I'll pay you back with an eye for an eye!
Sato-san, they're getting away!
Hold on to your seat.
Sato-san, what are you doing?
You'll bite your tongue if you keep talking...
Sa-Sato-san!
Just hold on!
Wa-Wait, Sato-san!
Takagi-kun, contact headquarters.
Yes, ma'am!
Honestly...
Sato-san,
Backup and ambulances are on their way.
This bastard has only himself to thank.
How dare he wear the mask of my first love?
F-first love?
Go and have a look at Fujiko.
Okay.
Hang on! The ambulance will be here soon.
Sato-san!
Fujiko just fainted.
The injury isn't very serious.
Really?
But, why did they commit a robbery in such odd masks?
Koumi... Island...
Koumi Island?
Is that why you committed robbery, so that you could take a vacation on that island?
N-no...
No?
What about that island, then?
J-
J-Jolly...
Jolly Roger...
Jolly Roger?
Do you know what that is?
No idea...
Koumi Island
Mama! Hurry, hurry!
Let's go over there!
Wait for me!
Hey, do you know how to use this?
Let me show you.
Sensei, what kind of fish are here?
Good morning! may I have the name you made reservations under?
Mouri Kogoro, the famous detective.
We have two adults, two students, and five children.
Let me look you up.
You know how the "Daily Times" publishes a puzzle to solve each week, right?
They're really hard!
The cash prize keeps accumulating if no one sends in the right answer.
It even reached 300,000 yen!
And do you know who it was that won all that money...?
I have no idea...
Oh, you mean...
Bingo!
After all, I am a famous detective.
Puzzles are a piece of cake for me!
Although, I'm the one who told you the right answer...
If you have 300,000 yen, you can take a vacation in Paris.
The streets of Paris are just my style, but then I'd feel guilty having all the fun myself,
and it's not like we always have opportunities like this,
so I brought them along as well.
I'm just a really kind man, don't you think?
Y-yeah...
What are our room numbers then?
I'm sorry, but I couldn't find your reservation.
Are you serious?!?
Hey, hey...
Wait a minute,
I made this reservation a while ago!
But, I couldn't find your name on the reservation list.
Are we going to have to camp outside?
This island has a tropical climate, so there might be poisonous bugs all over the place.
If only we'd known that it'd end up like this...
Well, we'll think of something.
After all, it's not like we can't talk to people here.
Wow! Haibara-san sounds like an adult.
Well, I'm pretty sure she's not a child...
The front desk said that they'll contact the Tourism Division.
Sorry for all the trouble.
But that man promised me!
He said the reservation was confirmed!
Well, I'm confused too.
Good afternoon, sorry to keep you waiting.
You must be Mouri Kogoro-san, the famous detective...
I apologize...
I'm Iwanaga from the Tourism Division.
Iwanaga Jouji
Koumi Island Tourism Division
The amount of tourists has just skyrocketed this month.
Hotels are all completely booked.
Seems all the happy travelers are causing busyness for us...
But I already made your reservations for you.
You are the famous detective Mouri Kogoro, after all.
Please, follow me. This way.
What a dumbass...
What is he doing?
Who are they?
They're probably treasure hunters.
Treasure Hunters?
Do they repair pipes?
Flushing toilets and stuff like that?
That's not it, Genta-kun.
They look for treasure all over the world.
But how do you know that they're treasure hunters?
Ah, just look at them.
Their skin is nicely tanned,
but only on their hands and heads, and not anywhere else, right?
They must wear wet suits a lot.
Plus the color of their hair has faded from prolonged contact with sea water.
But that only proves that they dive a lot.
That may be true...
But, if you look at that poster,
You'll realize that my deduction is logical.
Treasure!!
Yeah.
They must be dreaming...
...of finding the treasure sleeping under the sea.
I'm high school detective, Kudo Shin'ichi.
Eh? You say I don't look like a high-schooler?
Original Creator Aoyama Gosho
serialized in Shogakukan's weekly Shounen Sunday
While visiting an amusement park with my
childhood friend and classmate, Mouri Ran...
Screenplay Hiroshi Kawashiabara
I went to investigate, and witnessed a man in black in the middle of a suspicious transaction.
Music Katsuo Ohno
Engrossed in watching the deal,
I didn't notice his partner sneaking up behind me.
Character Design Sudou Masatomo
Art Director Shibuya Yukihiro
Color Planning Nishi Kayoko
I was forced to take a poison, and when I woke up...
My body had shrunk!
Director of Photography Nomura Takashi
Sound Director Izawa Motoi
If they found out that Kudo Shin'ichi was still alive,
They would come after me again and endanger the lives of those around me.
Edogawa Conan Takayama Minami
Following Prof. Agasa advice I decided to hide my identity.
When Ran asked me who I was, I blurted out, "Edogawa Conan".
In order to find more information on the men in black,
I moved in with Ran and her father, who is a detective.
Mouri Kogoro Kamiya Akira
Mouri Ran Yamazaki Wakana
Yes, this old man is Ran's Father, the "famous detective", Mouri Kogoro.
People call him "Sleeping Kogoro",
but that's because... that's what's really happening.
Her name is Suzuki Sonoko,
Suzuki Sonoko Matsui Naoko
Professor Agasa Ogata Kenichi
She's Ran classmate.
By looking, you'd never know she comes from a wealthy family, since she's a rather easy-going girl.
This man is professor Agasa
Professor Agasa has invented a lot of interesting and unique gadgets for me since my body has shrunk.
This girl is Haibara Ai.
Haibara Ai Hayashibara Megumi
Her true identity is Miyano Shiho.
She used to be a member of the black Organization, but in order to escape,
She swallowed the same poison that I was given, and her body shrank as well.
Producers
Suwa Michihiko
Yoshioka Masahito
I still don't know the true identities of those men in black,
But I bet on my name as a detective, I'll have it out with them one day.
Director Yamamoto Yasuichiro
Even though I've become small,
My mind is still that of a great detective.
There is only one truth!
Speaking of which...
Why are treasure hunters coming on this island?
Someone found some treasure two weeks ago.
Treasure?
I heard that they found silver in Seabed Palace. Is that true?
I think so.
What's Seabed Palace?
See that deserted island over there?
It's Yorioya Island.
Yorioya Island
200 meters east of the island,
there are ruins in the seabed.
Ten years ago, there was a rumor saying
that there were ruins near Koumi Island.
Many scholars came to do a research on it,
Seabed Palace
but they never concluded whether it's man-made or natural.
Yorioya Island used to be exposed above water.
300 Years ago, earthquakes caused it to sink into the ocean depths.
Due to earthquakes?
Like in a landslide?
Yes, I heard that the seabed nearby contains methane hydrate.
The earthquakes disturbed it and caused a landslide.
That's the most logical explanation so far.
Hey Conan...
What's "meat-tanned-hand-maid?"
Methane hydrate.
Methane Hydrate
In a low temperature, high pressure environment,
Water combines with methane and forms a kind of cage.
It's also called combustible ice.
Combustible Ice?
Water cage?
I don't get it at all.
To put it simply,
you've built a house of cards before, right?
Water builds a house like that,
and each room contains methane.
If the temperature rises or the pressure falls,
it'll become unstable, and the whole thing will collapse, releasing the methane.
I see!
That's why the island, being held up by methane, lost its support and cause a landslide.
Something like that.
I learned that from what they said on TV...
Oh, I see...
Idiot...
Excuse me, Mima-san?
This is Iwanaga from the Tourism Division.
Mima-san, are you here? Mima-san?
It's so different from the hotel.
I know...
I'm sorry. He must not be here right now.
I just tried calling for him.
What's all the noise for?
Oh, Mima-san!
This is Mouri-san and his guests, of whom I told you about over the phone.
Mima Kasuo
Landlord of "Koumi Inn" Lodge
Two rooms and meals for one night, 5000 yen.
Take it or leave it.
Wait a minute, Mima-san!
What a rude guy...
Sorry, he's really a good man,
but he can be a bit weird sometimes.
So Who's participating in the treasure hunt?
We are!
You two young ladies are planning to go diving, right?
Yes.
I can give you a ride if you want to go right now.
We'd like that, please.
What about the two of you?
Treasure hunting is fun.
I want to relax. Don't worry about me.
What about Mouri-san?
Want to go treas-
No thanks.
Just tell me where I can buy drinks and find
beautiful hostesses at the same time.
Mouri Ran-san and Suzuki Sonoko-san, right?
Mabuchi Chika
Owner of "The Grotto" Diving Equipment Shop
Would you like to rent the whole set?
Yep!
Kimiko!
Yamakuchi Kimiko
Diving Instructor
You two...
Will these wets suites work for you?
I think Size M should fit you.
Yes!
Those are perfect.
Great!
To be honest, we don't have a very big selection of wet suits here.
Really? Sorry to trouble you in finding these, then.
These wet suits look so nice!
You think so?
Excuse me!
Hey, clean up after you're done!
We'll be back.
They're treasure hunters, right?
Are they going to be our diving partners?
No, they just came to borrow our air compressor.
There have been a lot of them recently, which causes us a lot of trouble.
Is it because of the silver that was found?
There's a legend saying that Anne escaped from the jail and hid her treasure on this island.
Who's Anne?
That's her.
270 years ago, during the Kyoto Era of the Edo period,
The Seabed Palace was still above ground.
Two rare artifacts were found at Seabed Palace,
a cutlass and a pistol.
According to the initials on the cutlass and the pistol,
These weapons used to belong to two female pirates who were active around 1730,
Whose names were Anne Bonny and Mary Read.
They were led by captain Jack Rickman.
They were female pirates?
That's right.
Anne Bonny and Mary Read were pirates under Captain Jack.
But when they were attacked by the English Navy,
all the crewmen hid below deck while the two women fought bravery back-to-back.
Back-to-back?
Yes... The idea is to let your partner watch your back,
so that you can concentrate on the enemy before you.
If either person lacked trust in the other, it wouldn't work.
Ran, You're...
Ran, You're... You're the only one I trust to watch my back.
S-Sonoko...
Just kidding!
But, you want Shin'ichi-kun to watch your back, don't you?
I don't care about him.
Really?
Yes, really!
Anne escaped from her prison in the Bahamas and moved to the Pacific Ocean.
She continued as a pirate and waited for Mary to escape from prison as well.
Many years later, this story was confirmed,
causing a legend about the two hiding their treasure on Koumi Island.
So, let's go look for Anne and Mary's treasure!
Are these real?
Who knows?
If they are, protecting them must cause a lot of trouble...
Maybe they were made just to publicize this island.
That would cause even more trouble.
Seems like they cause trouble either way.
Sorry, sorry!
Sorry to keep you waiting-
Hey, hey...
Here. This is the map for the treasure hunt.
Starting here, you want to go to each of the five points on the map, solve their riddles, and collect the stamp from each area.
This is the first point.
Take the stamp and stamp it on the blank space here,
then take a hint card for the next point from the treasure chest there.
This game's just a way to keep kids occupied.
Don't say that.
Everyone looks so enthusiastic about it.
10 and 12...
This is the key to finding the treasure.
The clue for the next point is...
even near the end of the sunset,
a pirate still shines
"Even near the end of the sunset, a pirate still shines."
What does that mean?
Well, do your best!
You'll get a present if you find the treasure!
Is the present an all-you-eat-buffet?
You'll know once you solve all the riddles.
Alright, I have to work really hard now!
You don't even know if that's the prize yet...
Hey, Uncle!
Yes, What?
Did you think of these riddles yourself?
Eh? Kind of...
Oh, by the way,
There's a place you can rent bikes next door.
You'll be really tired if you walk, so take a bike.
Okay!
I can see you're enthusiastic about this too, Kudo-kun!
Alright, you're all set!
Just follow Kimiko's instructions and have a safe, fun dive!
Watch out of the area south of Seabed Palace,
it's really deep over there.
Please don't scare us.
Don't worry, I'll be with you.
You're right.
Please take care of us!
That was quick.
Did something happen?
Sharks!
Since the riddle mentioned the sunset,
we came to the west side of the island,
but where's the treasure box with the next hint?
Oh! I got it!
The hint was... "Even near the end of the sunset, a pirate still shines", right?
So that must mean...
It's out there!
Really?
And then what?
You mean the stamp is in the middle of the ocean?
I guess that's not it after all...
Oh, I see...
Look over there!
What is that?
It's a large school of fish.
Are there any eel there?
There wouldn't be any eel here...
Now I understand!
Hey, Conan!
Why is it that you're always saying, "I understand, I understand?"
What did you figure out?
Do you know why fish always swim in groups?
Well...
So they can play together?
Or maybe they get together to eat because they're hungry.
Bingo!
So, what is it that fish eat?
Plankton?
Exactly.
Amazing!
Is there anything down here?
Just look here.
It's bio-luminescent plankton!
I got it!
"Even near the end of the sunset, a pirate still shines."
That must mean this is the place!
Found it.
"A skinny pirate would just laugh."
You can laugh even if you're not thin.
What's wrong, Haibara?
I saw someone in a wet suit, covered in blood, being carried away.
What?
I don't know if it Ran-san or not, though.
Conan-kun!
I have to leave with Edogawa-kun for a while,
so you guys continue on without us.
Why is Haibara-san leaving too?
Don't worry, I'm still here!
We can find the treasure by ourselves.
You're right.
Ran-Ran-neechan!
Conan-kun!
Ai-chan's here too?
Are you okay?
We're fine.
Officer Uehira
Koumi Island Resident Policeman
How is it, Uehira-san?
Kimi-chan!
Were you there too?
I was guiding my clients for a dive nearby.
But I was shocked when I heard that sharks were attacking people.
It's strange how there were three of them, but only one was attacked.
What are you getting at?
Nothing.
But it's so troubling...
It's been a long time since the last accident.
Speaking of which, this is the first time I've seen sharks at that spot.
What is it?
Kimiko-san said there were three of them diving together, but only one was attacked.
You don't think it was an accident?
They should know how to deal with sharks since they're all professionals.
What did you find?
A plastic bag.
Fish blood?
So that's the reason...
Yeah.
Take fish blood, seal it in a plastic bag,
and hide it in the jacket of the swim suit.
Underwater, atmospheric pressure increases by one for every 10 meters,
and sea level is already at one atmospheric pressure.
It become two when you dive 10 meters,
and four when you get to 30 meters.
With such a high water pressure weighing down on it, the plastic bag would eventually burst.
Sharks can hear noises from miles away,
and can smell blood from even farther.
This is a murder case.
Yes, although it's not over yet.
Hey, you brats!
What're you two doing here?
Uncle, a case happened!
What?
Why don't they ever contact me first...
'Cuz I'm the famous detective, Mouri Kogoro.
A shark's mouth sure is big...
The thing is... being bitten by a shark isn't a case, it's an accident.
I don't see anything over there...
Huh? What's this?
How is he, Doctor?
I did everything I could,
but it was too late.
I'm sorry...
Damn!
No way...
How could this accident happen?
It's not an accident.
You're the famous detective...
Mouri Kogoro.
Dad.
Uncle.
Hey, you said that this wasn't an accident. what did you mean by that?
Someone lured the sharks to attack you on purpose.
They hid a bag of fish blood in the lining of this BC jacket.
Note: BC is an acronym for Buoyancy control
Considering you are both treasure hunters,
you are the main suspects here.
Hey, Ran-neechan.
Where are the BC jackets usually kept?
Well...
We don't bring them back to the hotel room.
I think they're usually kept in the diving shop,
and they fill the air tanks there too.
If someone wanted to tamper with the BC
jackets, this would be the easiest place.
Since it'd be risky to do anything after someone's already taken it out.
Wait a second... Kudo-kun!
What is it, Haibara?
Look at this.
They usually wash the instruments here,
so this place is always damp.
Thanks. Could you please take some photos for me?
I have to check on other stuff.
Huh? Since when did I become your assistant?
Not assistant, partner!
You're a smooth talker, aren't you?
So, I'll be back in a bit.
Yeah, yeah...
Hey, Onee-san.
What is it?
Does anyone work here at night?
Are you playing a detective game?
I live behind this shop,
and Kimiko lives in an apartment near the port,
so there isn't anyone here at night.
I see.
And since there aren't any thieves on this island, we usually don't lock the door.
Kimiko, you closed the shop last night, right?
Y-Yeah, but why do you ask?
This little detective here was asking me a few questions.
I see...
You're trying to figure out who could have
done something to the BC, aren't you?
It's true that I closed the shop last night and opened the shop this morning,
But we don't lock the door, so anyone could have snuck in.
Find anything interesting?
No...
Nothing of use yet.
I hope you can find something.
What is it?
What is it?!
What are you doing, Conan?
We're still looking for the pirate's treasure, and can't find it without you!
You need to start using your brains once in a while.
We've tried, but we're completely stumped!
Where are you guys right now?
We're walking towards a hanging bridge.
Hanging bridge?
It's on the map!
The treasure map...
Okay, I see it.
Hurry up and get over here!
Okay, okay...
I have no choice.
Hey Haibara, you coming?
I'll pass.
I knew it.
Hey, hey! What's this?
The road is completely blocked!
Geez...
Are you by yourself?
Your friends are over by the hanging bridge.
I want to go there,
but I can't use this road.
Sorry, sorry,
Last week, an earthquake caused a landslide which blocked the road.
Up ahead, there's a road that turns left.
You can use that road.
Thanks, Iwanaga-san!
Take care!
Okay!
I give up, I don't know the answer.
Once Conan-kun gets here, we'll be able to solve the riddle.
It's okay even if he doesn't come! Can't we still figure it out ourselves?
Huh?
There's a sign posted on the other side of the bridge.
What does it say?
Let's go take a look.
Okay.
I'm starving...
Hey, wait for me!
Wait, please!
Don't move!
W-Why?
This is...
What is it?!?
How much do you weigh, Genta-kun?
39 kilograms!
You're lying!
Wait, I might have put on a little weight recently... maybe 45 kilograms?
That's really bad!
The bridge will break if someone over 40 kilograms crosses it!
A-Are you serious!?
I see, I got it now!
"A skinny pirate would just laugh."
It's telling us to walk across the bridge!
That's right!
"A skinny pirate would just laugh" must mean...
that a fat pirate would cry!
Help me, Mommy!
Found it!
What does "a pirate never cries" mean?
It's already 4 PM. Let's continue tomorrow.
But how do we go back?
Well...
If Genta-kun keeps squatting there,
The bridge will break once as soon as we step on it.
Hey, what are you guys doing over there?
Conan-kun, we found it!
Nice going, you guys!
The next hint is "a pirate never cries".
However, this bridge will break if someone who weighs more than 40 kilograms goes across it! He might fall!
Was that written on that board?
Warning
Not really. What's written on it is "Passage forbidden to anyone who weighs over 40 kilograms!"
I see.
That's why the skinny pirate would laugh.
It's okay, just walk through.
It was just a hint.
The only people who could weigh under 40 kilograms are women and children,
So that was just a code that only they could solve.
Thank you for coming, Inspector!
But did you have to come all the way here?
I found some aspects to be weird.
I-Inspector!
Thank you for coming all the way out here.
I want to know all of the details.
Yes, sir!
You treat us like we're the criminals,
Izu Yamataro
Treasure Hunter
but we're the victims, okay?
If you're the victim, then tell us the truth!
Have you seen these two men?
Nope. Never seen them before.
They robbed a supermarket in Shinbashi last night, taking the cash from the store.
They told us you ordered them to do so,
as an initiation to join your gang.
I don't know anything about that.
Matsumoto Mitsushi
Treasure Hunter
It was probably just a bluff so you incompetent police would let him go.
You bastard!
Do you have any evidence?
Aside from their word?
Now, now,
Calm down, everyone.
Let's have a cold drink.
I'd like to return to my room if you have nothing else to say.
So you have no idea who might want to attack you, Matsumoto-san?
No, none at all.
That's all then, I guess.
Excuse me, do you happen to have a match with you?
I forgot to bring my lighter with me.
Here.
Thanks.
What a waste of time.
Can I have a sip of that?
I'm a little thirsty.
Go ahead. They didn't touch them at all.
I was trying to get their fingerprints.
But even if we had gotten their fingerprints,
it takes more time,
regardless of whether we got someone to come analyze them or sent them back for testing.
By the way, Takagi-kun,
do you smoke?
Sorry.
Do you have UHU glue?
Sorry to interrupt your meal.
Is it time for quiz?
You got it.
Not again...
You want to play it now?
I knew it was coming...
In the fish kingdom on the abandoned ocean floor,
The evil deeds of the previous king were revealed,
and the sea bream fish became the next king.
Of the following choices then, who was the previous king?
1. Squid, 2. Octopus, or 3. Crab?
Ika (Squid)
Tako (Octopus)
Kani (Crab)
So, take a guess, guys.
I know!
It's the third one, the crab!
Why is it the crab?
It uses its pincers to cut off the heads of those it hates.
What? That's so mean!
Wrong, wrong.
That's really far off...
It must be the octopus!
Why?
King Octopus pocketed the kingdom's money.
Just picture how an octopus looks.
In other words, you're saying baldies are usually rich?
That's right.
I don't think so.
Then, it's the first choice, the squid!
Why?
Let me answer that!
I can do it this time.
The King
Osama can be separated into "o" and "sama."
Squid King Squid King
Adding "ika" in front of "sama" gives you "ika-sama."
Ika-sama?
That means he cheated!
That's right!
Something's fishy here...
Hey, Conan-kun!
Osama can be separated
into o and sama
adding ika in front of sama
gives you ika-sama
This is truly...
Ikasama
...Cheating.
Such a beautiful moon.
Yeah.
By the way, I was wondering
why you provide lodging to tourists at your house?
Well, I live by myself and fish for a living.
The Tourism Division asked me to provide lodging so that they could get more tourist to visit.
I see...
I hope that we aren't interfering with your daily life.
It's better to have you stay than the treasure hunters.
Speaking of treasure hunters, is there really treasure here?
Hyenas don't gather at places that don't have treasure,
although it's probably not the type of treasure they are expecting.
I can't find the answer.
Why does a pirate never cry?
Genta-kun, please try to concentrate more.
Hey kids...
Is the hint "a pirate never cries"?
Yeah, that's right.
If it's "pirates cry," I know where it is.
Pirates cry?
Maybe there's a hint there.
Would you like to go take a look?
Going out at this hour?
It's dark outside. Why don't you go tomorrow?
The weather might change tomorrow.
Is it going to rain?
We don't go out to the sea when the south wind starts blowing.
The waves will be very violent, almost like a storm.
Is that called "Life Knowledge"?
Then, let's go together.
It can be an after-dinner walk.
Yay!
What are you trying to do, Takagi-kun?
This is called cyanide methacrylate.
UHU glue contains cyanide methacrylate,
which reacts to the water in secretion.
You can use this to get fingerprints.
Now you just have to wait for the fingerprints to show.
You're really talented to know how to do this!
Actually... I saw this method in a movie one time,
so I asked an officer from the identification bureau how to do it.
Then, I hope this works as smoothly as it did in the movie.
Hey, is this where the "a pirate never cries" hint leads to?
I don't know if this is the right place, but the "cry" place is here.
Cry...
Is it the sound of the wind...?
It kind of sounds like someone crying...
It really does!
Except that I heard the wind on the way here as well.
Well, I knew that already!
The sand here contains a lot of quartz,
and it's fine too.
I see.
Hey, Conan...
What did you find out?
Listen carefully.
The sand is crying!
So that's why it was "a pirate never cries"!
You'll have to figure out the rest yourselves.
Okay.
The hint is "a pirate never cries".
Could it be there?
Come over here! There's no sound here.
So that's the "a pirate never cries" place!
They sure set this up to create the right atmosphere...
A pirate's soul will
go to heaven
The next one is, "A pirate's soul will go to heaven".
Another odd hint again.
The head of the Tourism Division sure is good!
Iwanaga-san, the head of the Tourism Division.
He said that he thought of these riddles himself.
That's his job after all.
Such an impassive person...
What is it?
What is it, Conan-kun?
This is getting interesting.
Conan-kun?
Sorry, I need to go somewhere for a bit.
Why don't you all head back without me?
Wait, Conan-kun!
Not again...
That brat has no team spirit at all.
Conan-kun...
It appeared!
Now we just have to change it into data and send it on to be examined.
Well done Takagi-kun!
It was nothing...
Tell me if you ever want to transfer to the Identification bureau.
I can write you a recommendation letter.
Please don't joke with me.
Anyway, send that back to headquarters.
Right away!
What are you doing here?
I was taking a walk and I got lost.
How do I get back to Koumi Inn?
Go that way.
Thank you. Good night!
How is it, Takagi-kun?
Any news from headquarters yet?
Nope, not yet.
I see.
What's wrong?!
The alarm in the Tourism Division has gone off!
Then, something must have happened in the Tourism Division's office.
No, their alarm often malfunctions.
We better go and take a look just in case.
Where is it?
Next to the police station.
We'll be borrowing your car...
Okay.
Headquarters might send a report back later.
Please take care of it.
G-Got it.
Damn, why are there so many incidents happening lately?
I-It's here!
Let's see...
Th-This is...
Hurry, get in!
Geez, I asked for about pubs with beautiful hostesses.
Damn...
Can't I have a drink in peace?
I hate coming to tourist spots.
I'm getting angry!
Hey, shut up!
Huh? What happened?
Hey, wait a minute!
What are you doing?
There aren't any beautiful hostesses here, Head of the Tourism Division!
What does it matter?
She'll look beautiful when she's in a dark room anyway!
You have to take responsibility!
I'm busy right now!
What?!
Someone broke into the display room at the Tourism Division's office.
What? A thief?
Let me take the bike.
Wait a minute.
Get on! Or I'll go without you!
Please wait for me!
Sit tight, I'm going to go fast!
Wait, you haven't paid your bill yet!
Customer-san!
What's the problem, ma'am?
Uehira-chan, someone ran away and didn't pay his bill.
Please get him for me.
Geez... Not another incident!
They broke the display counter using a small crowbar.
It was a pretty bold move.
Yes, Sato-kun?
Like Conan-kun said, there were gunshots.
There are blood stains at the crime scene.
I see.
Can you maintain the area?
It would be quiet difficult to do so.
That's what I was afraid of.
Take a picture of the crime scene and come back here.
Yes, sir!
The cutlass and the pistol were stolen!
Were they worth a lot?
They were priceless artifacts found inside Seabed Palace,
the cutlass of Anne Bonny and the pistol of Mary Read.
There's no need to worry, cause I'm here!
Mouri-kun, you're red.
No,
I'm just excited to see everyone here.
Mouri Kogoro, you are under arrest!
You didn't pay your bill, stole a bicycle, and were riding it while drunk!
Hey, hey...
Is that true?
Yes.
He didn't pay his bill at the pub,
stole Iwanaga-san's bicycle, and rode away.
That's what the hostess told me.
I didn't steal his bike.
I rode him here while he sat right behind me!
Right? Right?
Yeah...
Oh! I almost forgot, Inspector...
The results from the fingerprints analysis arrived.
Hey, is this true?
Matsumoto Mitsushi.
He has stolen important cultural artifacts from ruins all over the world,
along with committing theft and burglary of works of art, and even murder.
He's a big fish.
So they're international fugitives.
Damn, so they really are trying to steal Anne and Mary's treasure.
What do you mean?
There's more treasure besides the stolen cutlass and pistol?
Yes.
Anne Bonny and Mary Read were pirates.
Before they got caught 300 years ago,
they hid their treasure here in Koumi Island.
Is it true that they hid their treasure here?
Yes, the stolen pistol and cutlass are the best evidence of that.
Hey, Uncle...
I thought you were at a pub with beautiful hostesses.
Not only was she not beautiful,
she was an old hag!
I knew it.
It's that smell.
You've got something on you, Uncle.
What is this?
I see.
How do you get off of this island?
There is only one scheduled ship that leaves here every afternoon,
but you could also leave in a fishing boat.
Alright then, ask everyone to be extra careful,
to avoid having their fishing boats stolen.
Understood!
Hey, what about the cuffs?
Hey!!
Hey, Inspector Megure...
I saw that Matsumoto guy paying on the diving shop owner, Mabuchi-san.
What?
Inspector Megure,
we're back.
Thank you for your hard work.
I need you to check on something.
The diving shop owner has had some contact with Matsumoto.
Both of you immediately go to the diving shop.
We'll go to the hotel where Matsumoto is staying.
Yes, sir!
Inspector Megure, the cuffs on my wrists!
How's the weather?
The wind is strong...
but since the sun is out, there shouldn't be a problem.
I'll zoom in on the picture.
The pattern on the tracks is different from the ones on the tire.
Just like I thought, it's not this bike.
Conan-kun?
Yeah?
Conan-kun, the food is ready!
Be there in a second!
What is it?
I think it's a GPS tracker.
GPS tracker? Why would a bike have one of those?
Geez... What is Conan doing?
He said he was coming, just give him a minute!
Here he comes!
Sorry to keep you waiting!
You are so slow, Conan. I'm starving!
Sorry, sorry.
Huh? Where's Uncle?
He has a meeting with the police, so he went down to the station.
Okay then, everyone's here.
Let's dig in!
I never thought that it'd be nearby!
Yummy! I want another one!
Hey, did you meet Iwanaga-san on the way to the hanging bridge?
Iwanaga-san?
Ah, you mean the head of the Tourism Division?
Yeah.
No, we didn't see him, right?
Yep.
We found that place ourselves.
I see.
Does everyone have enough food?
Yes, we're fine. Thank you very much.
Are you going for a dive today as well?
No, my heart is still fluttering with fear from what happened yesterday.
But there won't be any time left tomorrow,
so we'd like to take a boat ride later.
Better not go out to sea this afternoon,
The waves might get stormy.
Really?
Then, we need to hurry up and find the treasure before that happens.
You're right, we only have one hint left now.
Let's work together, Conan-kun.
I need to go somewhere, so you guys go ahead without me!
Well, I guess we'll leave the anti-social guy here.
Let's find the treasure and split it among ourselves.
Sounds good to me!
I thought so. None of the other bikes have GPS trackers.
Sir, the latest information on the weather.
That's not good... it looks like a small typhoon.
Anyway, go and let the fishing association and the hotel know.
Yes.
What a pain...
Matsumoto and Izuyama haven't gone back to their hotel room yet,
but there's nothing that shows that they left the island either.
So, they must be hiding somewhere.
At least one of them was shot. They're probably looking for a doctor.
I've checked with the clinics, but there's no sign of them.
About the diving shop owner, Mabuchi,
I found out what Conan-kun saw last night.
Matsumoto was asking her to prepare a boat for them to escape in.
First of all...
Let me tell you that I have no idea where Matsumoto is.
It's hard to make a living from just this diving shop,
so I agreed to help Matsumoto.
I never thought that I'd have such bad luck.
I see.
The bullet shells that Takagi-kun found were from old bullets,
Bullets that had been stored and preserved for a very long time.
We're checking with the hunter's association in regards to the rifle.
Please come in.
Sorry to interrupt,
but I just got a report saying that Mineo-san, a member of the hunter's association, is missing his rifle.
Is that so?
Who is Mineo-san?
He's an old man living all by himself.
His niece, Mabuchi Chika-san who runs the diving shop, takes care of him.
Ask Mineo-san for more details,
and please ask Mabuchi-san to come over here as well.
Yes, Sir!
Do your best to find the stolen cutlass and pistol!
I'm begging you!
We'll do our best.
But, why did they wait until now...
Why commit the crime while all of the police are here?
That's true. When Uehira-san was the only officer here,
it would have been much easier to get off of the island.
Most likely, the criminal was worried that his identity might be exposed if this went on.
What about the backup from Tokyo?
Helicopters can't come because of the low air pressure from the storm, and ships would take too long.
We have to depend on ourselves...
Not only in looking for Matsumoto,
but also the person who attempted to kill them.
There it is...
I found it!
Great!
The last hint was really easy!
"A pirate's soul will go to heaven."
The only possibility is the observatory!
The numbers on the stamps are the hint.
Now, go and find our treasure!
"The numbers on the stamps are the hint."
"Now, go find our treasure!"
My boss went to go check on the situation at sea.
Please wait for just a moment.
Okay.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Sorry! I don't think we can go out to sea today.
The waves are really rough out there.
How unlucky...
But nothing can be done.
Let's just go to a beach then.
Good morning, Uehira-san.
Good morning.
Why do you look so serious?
Did something happen?
Chika-chan, please come with me.
Inspector Megure would like to talk to you.
Uncle!
What is it?
Why did the treasure hunters steal the cutlass and pistol from the Tourism Division?
They, should be after The treasure...
But instead stole those items.
Could it be that they need them to get to the real treasure?
That's why I think those men went to where the treasure is hidden.
Uncle, do you know where it is?
Why are you asking me?
Uncle, did you used to be...
...a treasure hunter too?
Even if I were a treasure hunter,
How would I know where the treasure is hidden?
Didn't you say it yesterday?
Speaking of treasure hunters, is there really treasure here?
Hmph, hyenas don't gather at places that don't have treasure,
although it's probably not the type of treasure they are expecting.
"It's probably not the type of treasure they are expecting."
So, you know what the treasure is, right?
Follow me.
Why are some of the numbers red, and some blue?
Give me a pair of scissors.
Okay.
There are two questions:
Why are they separated into two colors?
And what do the numbers mean?
Could the numbers lead to an address on this island?
I know!
Let's ask Uncle!
Uncle!
I wonder what Inspector Megure needs Mabuchi-san for?
Maybe it's related to the case...
There's probably just some kind of misunderstanding.
Hop in, you two.
Okay!
Put these in the car as well.
Wait, you?!
Get back in the car!
You wouldn't want anything to happen to your friend here...
Uncle, did you used to be a treasure hunter?
Yes, when I was young.
I came to this island to look for the treasure of Anne and Mary, and I've been here ever since.
That was when I fell in love with a woman,
married her, and became a fisherman.
This is a map of how this island looked 300 years ago.
And that's how it is...
The numbers are drawn according to this map.
Iwanaga-san, from the Tourism Division...
He wrote those numbers out according to this ancient map.
But, so far, no one's been able to piece the puzzle together.
So, it was created 300 years ago,
by Anne Bonny herself.
Yes.
So we will find the real treasure
If we manage to solve the riddle?
Probably.
There were no addresses here 300 years ago.
The easiest way to solve this code would be to use the alphabet.
So, the number five means...
Five means...
A, B, C, D, E...
It's "E"!
That's right!
Seven is "G"!
12 is...
A,
A, B,
A, B, C,
A, B, C, D,
A, B, C, D, E,
A, B, C, D, E, F,
A, B, C, D, E, F, G,
A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H,
A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I,
A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, J,
A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, J, K,
A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, J, K, um...
The 12th letter is "L".
It's "L"!
These are all the letters.
The red letters are on top,
and the blue letters are on the bottom.
Now, we just have to unscramble them.
Is it a name?
Red could be their last name, and blue could be their first name.
That's possible.
Do you think it's related to the two pirates?
Probably.
Look, look! This looks like a name!
It's... "Jolly"?
"Jolly..."?
Girls, hurry and escape!
Don't move!
Ran!
So, you know karate, miss?
But, if you don't listen to me, your friend's going to die.
This is our boat...
Why is it here?
I asked your boss, the owner, to prepare it for me.
Money talks, doesn't it...?
N-No way...
You're of no use to me anymore.
We don't have enough air tanks.
Kimiko-san!
Don't move!
Bitch, stop moving!
Come on, come on! Get on the boat!
Why do I such at this...
Well, how about this?
How do you read that?
I think it's pronounced "Groe"...
Is it "Jolly Groe"?
No...
It's "Roger".
"Jolly Roger!"
"Jolly Roger?"
Who is that?
Is that a famous pirate or something?
The direct translation would be "Happy Roger", right?
"Jolly Roger"...
It's something that sailors in the 17th century never wanted to see.
The name consist of "Jolly Rouge", which means "Red Flag",
and "Old Roger", which means "Demon".
"Red Flag?"
"Demon?"
Yes,
The "Jolly Roger" the puzzle is referring to...
is the pirate flag on the map.
Amazing, Conan-kun!
Well done.
What's this?
300 years ago, a sailor drew this as they were passing through on a ship bound for Spain.
This island has since sunk into the sea.
I heard it was due to methane hydrate.
Yorioya Island used to be exposed above water.
Three hundred years ago, earthquakes caused it to sink into the ocean depths.
Yorioya Island?
Does that mean there's treasure on that island?
Yeah, most likely.
But there must be something else,
something that gives a better hint.
What is it, Conan?
Did you find something?
This pirate flag drawn on the ancient map...
The skull's teeth...
...don't you think they look like letters?
You're right,
They look like letters from the alphabet!
The top row is D-O-S.
The bottom row is D-I-O-S-A-S.
What does it mean?
It says "Dos Diosas".
Two goddesses
It means "Two goddesses in Spanish".
Amazing!
As expected of you, Haibara-san!
So, is that it?
We should go to the island to take a look.
But, aren't the treasure hunters looking for treasure in the ocean?
So, that must mean the treasure is underwater.
No, there would have been a hint about the ocean
if it was really underwater.
Not to mention, Poseidon is the male god of the sea.
They're probably looking for another way to get in.
The entrance of the two goddesses collapsed because of the landslide,
and no adult can pass through.
So they must have found another entrance somewhere...
That's why even with the police here investigating,
they risked stealing the cutlass and the pistol anyway.
The girl from the diving shop!
What happened?
Where's Mouri-san?
He's not here.
He should be at the police station right now.
Ran-chan and Sonoko-chan have been kidnapped.
They were taken away by boat.
Who? Who kidnapped them?
Matsumoto, the treasure hunter.
They must be going to Yorioya Island!
You guys, hurry and inform Uncle and the police.
Got it.
Be careful.
Yep.
Uncle,
Can you take me out to sea?
I need you to get me to that island.
What?
Not to find the treasure.
I want to save Ran-neechan and her friend.
Shin'ichi!
Conan-kun,
I heard that Ran-kun was kidnapped.
Yeah.
I know you're going to go save her, even if I tried to stop you.
Hold on a second before you go. I want to give you something.
I'll get the boat ready.
Got it.
Take these with you.
These are mini-air tanks.
Just pull, put in your mouth, you'll get 10 min worth of oxygen.
Unfortunately, I only have two of them with me.
So, save them for when you really need one.
Thank you, professor.
The two of you can share one air tank.
You don't need us anymore! why don't you let us go?
There's just one last thing I need from you...
Hurry and get everything ready!
Could it be...
Sonoko!
It's your turn, miss.
What exactly do you want us to do?
Don't worry, your turn's next.
What?
Ran and her friend were really kidnapped by Matsumoto?
Where did they go?
They went to an island, and island!
It's called Yorioya Island.
They figured out where the treasure is, and are going to get it now!
Get ready to head out to the sea.
I'm going to save them!
Yes, sir!
But, why did they take hostages with them?
A hostage would only get in their way of finding the treasure.
They have some other use for them.
Another use?
They were both injured by that rifle shot last night.
The place they're going now is the same
spot that the sharks attacked yesterday.
They're going to be used as bait?!?
Most likely.
There it is!
I knew it.
What should we do! there's not much time left.
Continue on to Yorioya Island.
What?!?
I'm small enough to get through the entrance of the Two goddesses.
Not good...
Impressive.
I can't believe you're still alive.
Take these torches,
or you won't be able to see anything inside the dark cavern.
You'll only die if you stay here.
Keep moving!
Stop pushing me!
This is...
We've already been here a lot of times.
We just have to find Anne Bonny and Mary Read's treasure today.
You two, stay here. And don't you dare think of running away, either...
There's a small temple straight ahead of you on that path.
with statues of two goddesses by it.
The entrance is behind them.
Got it!
You can only stay for 30 minutes,
or the boat will be gone, and you won't be able to get back.
Thanks!
I'll go save Ran-neechan and Sonoko-neechan now!
Anne Bonny and Mary Read, huh?
This is weird...
An adult should be able to fit through this...
Last week, an earthquake caused a landslide which blocked the road.
I see.
The earthquake made the entrance bigger.
Could they have taken Ran and...
No, since they bothered to take them all the way here, I don't think they would kill them.
But, what if...?
What we do know is that Matsumoto was shot by a rifle last night.
If they dive,
the smell of blood would attract sharks.
So, what does that mean?
I means Ran-san and her friend might be used as bait.
Wait a minute, Mouri-san!
What are you doing?
Let go of me! I can't just leave Ran in the hands of some scum-bags!
It's impossible, Mouri-san!
The storm's getting worse!
Shut up! Let me go!
I'm sorry I have to do this, but...
What should we do now?
We have to go back for now.
I have a bad feeling about this, though.
Hurry and come inside. It's really dangerous out here.
But, they're in danger right now,
Conan-kun, Ran-oneesan, and Sonoko-neesan.
Yeah.
That's right.
The water level's gone down some.
The tide is ebbing right now.
Are we going into that cave?
That's right.
It's a shortcut to the treasure.
Okay, bring two air tanks.
So, the legend of the pirates was true...
I guess so...
Put the air tanks down. You're going in first.
But...
Shut up, and get moving!
Bones! Bones! Bones!
Looks like everything's safe this time around.
The gas is gone...
Gas?
This place is full of gas when the wind isn't blowing as hard.
That's why you told us to go first?
Why else would we need you here?
Hurry, and keep going.
What?
This is it!
We finally found it!
What an idiot...
Who asked you to put this in to open it?
That's why you died.
You need to use this.
You, open it!
Me?
Let me do it.
Ran!
Shit, it's not working after all?
Just give it up, already!
So that's what it is.
Do you know how to open it?
Anne and Mary always fought back-to-back.
Which means...
...they should be put this way.
We found it, we found it!
Give me the torch!
It's amazing...
The treasure...
Where's the treasure?!
Be patient!
Ran, what should we do now?
We could run away now,
but we don't have an air tank, so we'd drown
before ever getting to the surface.
You're right.
So, we just have to try and hold them on
until someone comes and saves us.
That's right.
There's wind.
There's an opening around here!
Dammit!
Where is it? Where is this freaking treasure at?
It's the same for me!
I can't find even a single piece of treasure anywhere!
Not even a coin!
I don't know how, but someone must have gotten here before us.
Hey, this is different from what we talked about!
I came all the way here because
you told me there would be treasure!
Shut up!
There's no helping it then.
We better get out of here before air runs out.
Yeah, but first, let's get rid of the dead-weight.
Sorry, but this is how it ends for you.
Don't come any closer!
Ran, I trust you to watch my back.
Be careful, Sonoko!
Bitch!
Damn, this woman sure is a fighter.
Indeed.
But, no matter how good the are, they can't do anything...
...against this!
Always play your trump card last.
Both of you, get down!
Are you okay...
...Ran-neechan, Sonoko-neechan?
What a relief you came, you brave boy!
But, how did you get all the way down here?
There's a tunnel that leads here from Yorioya Island.
So, the pirates' treasure really does exist?
There's no treasure here.
They said that it was taken by someone who found this place before us.
Did you hear that?
Isn't that a shame?
You can stop hiding now.
You were sneaking behind me, and following me all the way down here, weren't you?
Inspector Megure, we can go out to sea now!
The wind is dying down now!
Mouri-san.
The weather forecast said that the storm won't stop until morning.
But... Look...
The storm is really calming down now.
Calm down, Mouri-san.
How can I calm down?
Ran has been kidnapped,
and I have to put my faith in a brat to go save her!
All the while, we adults have to just sit and do nothing!
Mouri-kun,
I understand how you feel, but there's nothing we can do, if we can't go out to sea.
Once the storm calms,
We'll go save Ran at once.
Now, be patient.
Damn it!
You can stop hiding now.
You were sneaking behind me, and following me all the way down here, weren't you?
Iwanaga-san.
Now, now...
Saying that I was "sneaking" is a little too harsh.
Just like you, I wanted to save them.
Then, why are you carrying a rifle with you?
I heard that they were international fugitives.
That's the rifle that belongs to Mineo-san, right?
N-No...
You brought the rifle with you because you were afraid of the treasure being stolen.
This has nothing to do with the treasure!
Iwanaga-san,
you told us you thought of all those hints on the cards yourself, right?
Uh, yeah...
But I saw the exact same numerical hint in Mima-san's house.
It was on a three-hundred year old map,
which I heard was left by Anne Bonny herself.
In other words, you saw that map before, but couldn't figure out its clues.
So, you used the map's clues to invent a game for tourists who came to the island...
so they could help you solve the clues, right?
Oh, yeah!
You even tried to get my dad to join in the treasure hunt game too!
I see!
The probability of a famous detective solving the clues is much higher than a bunch of kids.
In order to track the movements
of the people taking part in the treasure hunt,
you installed GPS trackers on the rental bikes, right?
Th-That's because I was worried that those who participated might run into danger.
If change the numbers on the map into the letters of the alphabet,
they spell out "Jolly Roger", referring to a pirate flag.
If you looked at Yorioya island from above, it looked like a skull.
That's why Anne Bonny left such a hint.
Also, even the pronunciation of Yorioya Island,
came from the pronunciation of the words "Jolly Roger".
I'm sure you already knew about this,
but there's another meaning behind the "Jolly Roger".
What is it?
You know how the real map has the pirate flag, or Jolly Roger, on it?
The teeth of the skull gave the second hint,
"Dos Diosas."
The hint is "Two goddesses".
Conan-kun?
That's right,
you should have seen it when you followed me just now,
the temple with the statues of two goddesses.
That's the entrance.
I see.
How did you know?
Damn it,
was my guess wrong from the very beginning?
The rigged BC jacket,
and the rifle attack on the treasure hunters...
You did all of those, didn't you?
There were tire marks left by your bike...
both behind the cave, and at the place where the bullet shells from the rifle were found.
I made mistakes that even an grade-schooler noticed...
It wasn't a grade-schooler.
Uncle Kogoro told me.
He told me all this,
and he noticed how Iwanaga-san had the smell of gunpowder on him.
It's probably because it's an old rifle which doesn't work as well, so the gunpowder flies all over the place.
I get it now.
I should've known.
As expected of the famous detective, Mouri Kogoro.
E-Earthquake?
It stopped.
This isn't good! We need to get out of here fast!
Yeah, let's bring them out.
Give me a hand, Iwanaga-san!
Okay.
Damn it!
What should we do? The rock blocked the entrance!
It's gas!
Get to the boat!
Hurry!
Damn, if this continues...
Conan-kun, what should we do now?
Bring them to the cabin, just in case.
Hook an air tank up to them so they can get some oxygen,
and don't let them breathe in the gas.
Ran-neechan, you two could use these.
What are these?
They're mini-air tanks that professor Agasa invented.
What about you?
I have another one right here. Don't worry!
Is that so...?
Damn, what do I do now?
If this goes on, the gas will...
Gas?
The gas is probably methane.
It probably rose and accumulated at the top of the cave.
If we can make use of the gas...
Is there anything, anything at all?
That'll work!
Ran-neechan, Sonoko-neechan,
Please, listen to me.
Since the water flowing into this place broke through,
the walls probably aren't very thick.
That's why, I think if we make the gas explode, we can make an opening in the top of the cave so the ship can...
You want us to ride the ship out to escape?
Will we be alright?
I don't know...
But, we'll all drown or be poisoned by the gas if we don't get out soon.
We'll die anyway.
We might as well give it a try.
What are you going to do, Conan-kun?
I'm going to kick that chain fragment
at the rocks at the top of the cave.
It'll create a spark,
Which should be able to make the gas explode.
Ran-neechan, you two go into the cabin
and breathe through the air tanks.
When the gas explodes,
all of the oxygen in the air will be gone in an instant.
What about you?
I'll be fine...
As soon as I kick the chain, I'll jump into the cabin along with you.
Don't worry.
I got it.
Inspector...
Get the ship ready!
We're heading out to sea!
Yes, sir!
Everything's prepared and okay, Conan-kun!
Yes!
This is bad!
Conan-kun...
Conan-kun!
Hang on, Conan-kun!
Ran...
Hurry up, hurry up!
Full speed!
A-A pirate ship?!?
Ran!
Ran, are you alright?
I'm fine!
We're saved!
Everyone, get off the boat!
Watch out!
Jump into the ocean!
Sonoko!
This way!
So, did you find the treasure?
Nope.
There was just this wreck of a pirate ship.
Maybe that ship was the treasure
The map that Anne Bonny left behind...
...wasn't a map leading to treasure.
She was just trying to send a message to Mary Read, who was in jail.
A message?
I'm right here!
I'll always be here waiting for you, Shin'ichi!
Just kidding...
Sonoko!
Who do you think you are, acting like a know-it-all?
No, there's a strong possibility that he's right.
Most likely, Anne built that ship and stored it there for Mary,
in preparation for the day
when they could go back out to sea together.
That's why she built the ship.
However, Mary fell sick in prison,
and passed away before that could happen.
Anne continues to wait for her partner, Mary,
until the day she died as well.
The ship that was left behind,
ended up in a cave at the bottom of the ocean, waiting for the day to come where it could set sail with its builder.
And now, three hundred years later,
it finally had its first and final voyage.
It sent all of you to the surface, then crumbled and vanished, just like the people who built it.
I'm just guessing though.
So, don't take it seriously.
It's been three hundred years, though,
so it's unlikely we'll ever know the truth.
No, I don't doubt that Anne was waiting for Mary, Uncle.
The proof is below the skull of the Jolly Roger...
Anne and Mary's pistol and cutlass.
Hey...
Ran-neechan, I was wondering...
How did you know I didn't have a mini-air tank back there?
Because you're just like that guy.
I think it was when I was in eight grade,
and there was a sudden rainstorm after school...
Why'd this have to happen now...?
Here, take this.
You have to hurry back home, right?
Yeah... thanks.
But what about you?
Stupid, I'm a detective!
I already knew it was going to rain,
so I brought an extra umbrella with me in this.
Really?
Thank goodness. I couldn't be late for my meeting with my mom.
I'll be borrowing this umbrella then!
I'll give it back to you tomorrow!
Okay!
But, I found out later that
Shin'ichi didn't really bring an extra umbrella.
He got drenched walking home, and ended up catching a cold.
That's right,
You reminded me of Shin'ichi at that time.
You're stubborn,
just like that stupid detective freak!
Well, excuse me for being stupid...