Kurokawa Mansion
As Mr. Kurokawa sat at his word processor, having a drink,
Daizo Kurokawa (62)
Kurokawa Hospital Director
someone hit and killed him from behind.
The weapon was undoubtedly the bronze statue lying next to him.
But this is what I don't understand.
While it appears to be a dying message, what does "JUN" mean?
It identifies the culprit, loud and clear.
Say what?!
What's more, the killer is one of those three!
He's on the ball for once!
Mina Kurokawa (32)
Daizo's Second Wife
His wife, Mina Kurokawa-san,
Daisuke Kurokawa (36)
Eldest Son ∙ Physician
his oldest son, Daisuke Kurokawa-san,
Manami Nakazawa (27)
Housekeeper
and his housekeeper, Manami Nakazawa-san. One of these is the killer.
Great, Mouri-kun! So, who is it?!
The person who killed Daizo Kurokawa is...
...you!
H-His wife?!
The letters "JUN" that Mr. Kurokawa left behind
correspond to the English word for the six month of the year: June.
This month can also be called "Minazuki" in Japanese.
In other words, "Mina-san". What's more, you—
So what if I was born in June?! So what if "Mina" is in "Minazuki"?!
You're gonna pin this on me with some lousy pun?!
No, no, this is a logical deduction based on—
Would someone on the verge of death do something so roundabout?
If it was me, I'd just type the killer's name straight out.
Not you, too, Inspector?
That's the extent of his logic? Oh well...
Is making innocent people out to be guilty what detectives do?!
I'll do it like always and use this Tranquilizer Watch Gun
to have the old man sleep again!
Here it comes!
Really?! I've been waiting!
Yes. I was merely joking when I said you were the killer.
Joking?
Inspector Megure. Take a close look at the body.
Mr. Kurokawa's right pinky is the only finger with blood on it.
Indeed it is.
So, which parts of the keyboard have blood on them?
"Ke", "mu", "ro", and the uppercase English key on the left side.
The blood on the "ke", "mu", and "ro" keys came from his pinky
when Mr. Kurokawa typed "JUN" with his index finger,
but no one presses keys on the very left side with their right pinky.
Then where did the blood on that left key come from?
Most likely, Mr. Kurokawa was hit from behind by the stealthy culprit,
upon which he put his right hand to his head.
This is probably where the blood on his pinky came from.
Then, when he looked back, he was hit again,
and he knocked over the keyboard with his pinky as he fell.
In other words, the English uppercase key on the very left
was not pressed of Mr. Kurokawa's will at the time of the crime,
but just happened to be pressed as he fell instead.
Then, after the killer left, Mr. Kurokawa used the last of his strength
to press the keys in front of him...
...thinking he was typing in Japanese kana.
Then what would "JUN" have been in kana?!
"Manami"!
Yes. The housewife, Manami Nakazawa-san...
You did it!
Y-You're joking, right, Detective? There's no proof, after all...
Oh, but there is proof.
You removed your slippers at the time of the crime, did you not?
Because the slippers would have made noise on the wood flooring,
making it impossible for you to sneak up on Mr. Kurokawa unnoticed.
Unbeknownst to you...
...you actually stepped in some of the blood on the ground.
The inexplicably missing bit of blood in Exhibit A proves this.
There should be blood on the bottom of your white sock!
You also said in your statement that you hadn't gotten near the body.
May I ask that we be allowed to examine the blood on your foot?
Kurokawa killed my husband one year ago.
You mean the patient my old man did heart surgery on?!
That's right!
I'm the wife of the patient who died after he operated on him drunk!
The fact no one noticed the simple changes to my hair and name
means the incident wasn't big enough for any of you to remember it.
I tried to get testimonies from the hospital staff so I could accuse him,
but not a single person would help me!
They were all afraid of Kurokawa!
So you decided to avenge your husband...
Today was the anniversary of his death...
I regret nothing!
I managed to get revenge for him!
Let's go.
Wound up giving him all the credit again...
I'm high school detective Shin'ichi Kudo.
I went with old friend and classmate, Ran Mouri, to an amusement park
where I witnessed a suspicious deal with a man dressed in black.
I was so absorbed with watching the deal
that I didn't notice a second man sneak up from behind me!
He forced me to take a poison, and when I woke up...
...my body had shrunk!
If they learned Shin'ichi Kudo was alive, they might go after me again,
putting all the people around me in danger!
Per Dr. Agasa's advice, I decided to conceal my identity.
When Ran asked my name, I quickly answered, "Conan Edogawa."
To get information on the men,
I wound up living with Ran and her detective father.
But the old guy's such a bonehead detective...
Unable to stand by and watch, I took his place
and used my powers of deduction to solve tough case after tough case.
As a result, the old man's now a prominent and famous detective,
while I'm stuck doing grade school all over again.
I even wound up in the "Detective Boys"
with my classmates Ayumi, Genta, and Mitsuhiko.
"Detective Boys"
Now let me introduce the gadgets the doctor has built for me!
First is the Tranquilizer Watch Gun!
Pressing the button while using the aiming device on the cover
will launch an tranquilizing needle that can knock a person out instantly.
Next is the Voice-Altering Bow Tie!
By adjusting the dials on the back,
I can produce all types of voices, from children to adult!
For offensive items, I have the Power Kick Shoes!
They use electricity and magnetic fields
to stimulate my feet muscles and maximize my kick power!
To chase down criminals, I have the Turbo-Engine Skateboard!
But as it's solar-powered, it can only be used when the sun is out.
Whoops, can't forget this one!
The Detective Boys' badges contain miniature transceivers
as well as transmitters!
There are plenty of others,
but my main weapon is undoubtedly this!
Even when I'm small, my mind remains that of a sharp detective!
There is always only one truth!
Dr. Agasa's House
April 28th (Saturday)
"To Yusaku Kudo..." "To Mr. Yusaku Kudo..."
They're all to Dad...
Conan Edogawa
(Shin'ichi Kudo)
Probably all fan letters anyway...
Come to think of it, I hear your father's latest Night Baron book
was a huge best seller in America, too!
Yeah. But he's in Switzerland now.
It's gotta be a pain sending him fan letters
when he's constantly traveling all over the world.
Well, the important thing is that he's getting to do what he wants.
Yeah, yeah.
Incidentally, Doc, what're you making?
A new gadget for me?
Sorry, but it's nothing that paltry.
Humankind studied the birds in the sky to create airplanes!
But no one has yet duplicated the wing-flapping mechanism of insects!
If I can create the very first one and sell it as a toy,
I'll capture the interest of children the world over!
And then I'll get oodles of money and become a billionaire!
And just when is that gonna be reality?
I've been hearing him say that since I was a kid...
Still, the fact I never get fan letters anymore must mean
that society has completely forgotten—
"Shin'ichi Kudo
2-21 Beika Town, Beika City"
It's to me.
"Teiji Moriya"?
The Teiji Moriya?
"Please forgive the suddenness of my letter."
"I've heard much about your exploits as a high school detective
in the newspapers and on television,
and very much wanted the chance to speak with you in person."
"As such, I would like to invite you to the afternoon tea garden party
Hiroshi Agasa (52)
Inventor
I am holding at my home on Tuesday, April 29, at 3:30 PM."
"I do hope that you will attend."
Oh, so it's a party invitation?
Doc. You know who Teiji Moriya is, right?
I most certainly do!
He's an architecture professor at Tohto University,
and one of the best architects in all of Japan!
Why would such a big shot want to invite me?
Architecture is art, so he's probably always looking for inspiration.
Plus, Professor Moriya is a master genius just like me!
Master genius, indeed...
A garden party?
Ran Mouri
Teitan High School Junior
Yeah. I can't make it, seeing as I'm in the middle of this one case...
So you want me to go in your place?
The invitation said companions are welcome too,
so you should go with your dad and that one kid living with you—
What's his name again?
Conan-kun?
Yeah. You three should go. The invitation's in your mailbox now.
Geez! You hardly ever call, and when you do, it's for selfish reasons!
Okay! But on one condition!
Condition?
See an all-night movie with me next Saturday!
Eh?!
Come on! I haven't seen you in a while!
Meet me in the lobby of the Beika Cinema at 10:00 PM!
W-Wait! Next Saturday's no good! Maybe later on when—
No! We have to go during May!
Say, which do you like better, red or blue?
Red or blue? What brought that on?
Just answer!
Well, red, I guess?
Red? I should've guessed! That's what I was going to say, too!
Well, red is your favorite color...
Kogoro Mouri
Private Detective
Hey, where's dinner?
Yes, yes, I'll get right on it.
Alright, Shin'ichi! The night of the 3rd, at 10:00! Don't forget now!
Wait!
Geez.
If I could see a movie, I wouldn't have said I couldn't make a party.
Still, why does it have to be May 3rd?
Did something happen on that day?
May 4th is when Holmes and Moriarty fell into the Reichenbach Falls,
and May 5th is Children's Day...
Hey, Conan-kun!
On your way home?
Inspector! On another case?!
Inspector Megure
Police HQ ∙ Investigation Division
Yes, on a couple...
Oh, let me introduce you. This is my newest assistant, Shiratori-kun.
My name's Shiratori. The Inspector's told me about you.
Detective Shiratori
Police HQ ∙ Investigation Division
I hear you notice interesting things...
No, it's all just coincidence!
Yes. Multiple coincidences are common...
Well, I'll be!
With all these incidents, I won't get to relax during Golden Week.
Bye!
Golden Week?
Oh, yeah!
May 3rd is Constitution Memorial Day!
And that's gotta do with what?
Birthday?
That's right! May 4th is Shin'ichi's birthday!
My plan is to invite him to an all-night movie on May 3rd,
and then surprise him by handing him a red polo shirt for a present
when the clock strikes midnight!
Oh, yeah! May 4th is my birthday!
I totally forgot...
So what movie are you seein'?
"Legend of the Red Thread".
Red thread?
Oh, you never heard of it?
It's a romantic movie based on a story about a man and a woman
whose pinkies were connected by a red thread of destiny since birth!
Ick! That's so girly...
And look! Both Shin'ichi and I have red as our lucky color for May!
So I decided that we gotta see this!
That's nice, but there's no way I can see it with you...
Hold on! Didn't you say this was an all-night movie?!
That's right...
Forget it! I forbid it!
A young man and woman getting all cozy in the dark, late at night—
It's not like that! Don't be creepy!
Shin'ichi always forgets his birthday!
I have to remind him every year!
Otherwise he'd just get older and older!
Though I'm actually smaller now...
Yeah, but... He's still in high school—
Oh, yeah!
Dad! Let's go to Teiji Moriya's garden party!
W-What brought that on?
Shin'ichi was actually the one invited, but he can't make it...
Wanna come too, Conan-kun?
Yeah! I do!
Like we can really go, using an invitation for Shin'ichi!
Teiji Moriya is a famous architect, right?
It'd be a historical meeting between great detective and great architect!
Great detective and great architect, huh?!
He is so easy to manipulate...
Moriya Mansion
April 29th (Tuesday)
Conan-kun! Wait! We need the invitation!
Enjoy yourselves!
Thanks!
Wow!
Truly a building from 17th century England's House of Stewart era!
You know a lot about architecture, Dad!
Yes, I was once known as the Walking Library!
More importantly, look closely at the left and right sides.
Hey, look!
When you stand in the middle, the left and right sides look the same!
The garden and the building!
This is what they call "symmetry"!
Professor Moriya lived in England until high school,
so he is quite fond of English-style architecture. In particular—
In particular, uhh...
His keenness for classical-style symmetry is remarkable!
A cheat sheet...
He even changed how he writes "Teiji" to give his name symmetry!
Almost sounds like a disease...
This is the first time I've seen such a wonderful garden!
I thank you for your kind praise!
Teiji Moriya (47)
Architect
Hello, I am Teiji Moriya.
I-I'm Ran Mouri! This is my father, and Conan Edogawa-kun.
Shin'ichi—I mean, Kudo-kun—couldn't make it today,
so we came in his place!
I see. So Kudo-kun couldn't come...
But this man's a famous detective, too!
Hey! Whadya mean, "too"?!
I'm Kogoro Mouri.
Oh! You're that famous detective! Pleasure to meet you!
Right this way. The party is in the rear garden.
The rear garden is just as wonderful!
Just what I'd expect from a famous architect's party—
musicians, models, corporate execs, critics, and celebrities...
All famous people from TV...
Please, make yourselves at home this afternoon!
How pretty! Are these all homemade?
But of course. It's only proper to serve homemade food at a tea party.
Please, have some.
Thank you!
How does it taste?
These cookies are delicious!
I'm glad to hear it!
Spending all night making them was worth it!
Oh, Professor! You cook?!
I might not look it, but I am single.
All the food here—the scones, sandwiches, cookies—I made it all.
I'm the type who isn't satisfied unless I do everything myself...
I see! That's the mentality that produces all those beautiful buildings?
I do not consider something architecture if it is not beautiful!
Most young architects these days lack artistic sense!
They need to feel much more responsibility for their works!
Incidentally, Mouri-san. Would you mind if I posed a quiz?
A quiz?
Yes. The goal is to deduce the password to a computer
that three men use for their business,
though I'm sure it will take the great Kogoro Mouri-san no time at all.
- He's the famous Kogoro Mouri-san!
- This'll be great!
Certainly!
Go ahead!
Hey, now. You gonna be alright?
Well, then, here is the data on those three people.
The password is a five-character word based on their commonalities.
Would you like to try too, Ran-san?
You have three minutes to solve it. Please think it over, everyone.
Ready, begin!
Their names have no common characters...
Their birthdates and blood types are all different, as are their hobbies.
This is harder than I thought...
What could it be? Do you suppose they have something in common?
I give up. I think I'll wait for the pro's answer.
Same here...
Do you think Dad'll be all right?
Wait, these three people were each born a year apart...
I got it!
It's Momotaro!
M-Momotaro?!
It's their Chinese zodiac signs!
The years of the monkey, the rooster, and the dog...
A monkey, a bird, and a dog were all Momotaro's retainers!
Correct, little boy! Most impressive!
Gotta have embarrassments sometimes too, old man!
Seeing as you've solved the puzzle,
I'll give you a special tour of my gallery, Conan-kun!
You may come too, Ran-san!
Okay!
Please feel free to look around!
Huh? Ran-neechan! Isn't this that one house?
Oh, it is!
It's Kurokawa-san's mansion!
Speaking of which, wasn't Kurokawa-san murdered?
Yes...
I designed this house very shortly after I struck out on my own.
Everything beyond it is from my 30s.
I was still inept in my youth. Please don't pay them much attention...
He's even designed a bridge...
Incidentally, Ran-san. Are you and Kudo-kun very close?
Yes, I suppose!
We grew up together, and we go to the same high school!
Though I haven't seen him at all recently...
But this Sunday, Shin'ichi—
No, he and I have a date to see a movie on his birthday!
Oh, that sounds like fun!
I take it you've already gotten him a present?
No, on Saturday I'm going to—
He and I both like the color red!
And we both have red as our lucky color for May!
So I was thinking of giving him a red polo shirt!
That sounds like a marvelous present! I'm sure Kudo-kun will love it!
Thanks!
Crap! I haven't figured out what to do on my birthday!
Oh? Isn't this the Beika City Building?
That's right.
We're seeing the movie in this building, in Beika Cinema 1!
We're meeting in the lobby at 10:00 on the night of the 3rd!
Is that so? This building is one of my best works...
There's no better place for a young couple to celebrate a birthday at!
W-What am I gonna do?
May 3rd (Saturday)
Well, order something for dinner, okay?
Okay...
Ten hours until 10:00 at night...
I am so screwed...
See you later!
What am I hiding for?
I told you to turn her down earlier!
I couldn't help it!
I couldn't turn Ran down after seeing her check her calendar
so happily everyday!
Doc, build me a fancy Shin'ichi robot!
I'm afraid that's not possible, even for a genius like me!
Didn't think so...
Two days ago, a large amount of explosives,
containing octogen, was stolen from a Toyo Munitions warehouse.
The police have mobilized over 100 officers for the investigation,
but no clues have been found yet.
Talk about scary...
Yeah. Octogen molded together with plastic makes plastic explosives.
—Kurokawa mansion burned down, including several nearby houses.
That's the Kurokawa house from the other day!
Yes, where that murder took place...
There sure have been a lot of arsons lately...
—the police believe the same person is responsible for this fire—
Yes, hello?
Is Shin'ichi Kudo there?
Just a minute.
It's for you, Shin'ichi.
How do they know I'm here?!
Don't be silly! You know all calls to your house get routed here now!
Oh, right! My bad...
But I never get calls anymore, so I completely forgot.
He sounds odd, as if he's using a voice changer too!
Hello?
Shin'ichi Kudo?
Yes.
You catch the news? I stole the explosives from Toyo Munitions!
What?!
Think you could give me your cell phone number?
I have no obligation to give it to you!
Oh, so you don't care if your only contact with me gets cut?
Alright. The number is—
Alright. Now take your phone and come to Green Park on the Teimuzu River.
I have something interesting to show you!
Green Park?!
Better hurry before some kids die!
What?!
Shin'ichi!
I gotta check it out!
You sure it's not just a prank call?
Using a voice changer is too much to be a prank!
Contact Inspector Megure, Doc!
Right! Be careful, now!
Yeah, yeah!
Teimuzu River Green Park
Ayumi
Genta
Mitsuhiko
C'mon, Mitsuhiko! Lemme fly it now!
I want to try, too!
Hold on a minute.
Piloting a remote-control plane is quite tough...
Hey, Mitsuhiko! Where'd you get that plane?!
Conan-kun!
A man with a beard gave it to us!
He said it was a bomber plane!
A bomber plane?!
That thing beneath its fuselage...
...could it be a bomb?!
Gimme that, Mitsuhiko!
What?! It's my turn next!
There's a bomb on that plane!
You idiots!
Oh no!
The antenna broke off!
Conan-kun! The plane!
It's no use! Everyone, run!
You idiots! Not that way!
Conan! Do something!
Damn it!
Not good!
Go!
What blew up?
Fireworks?
It was a plane!
An orange flash! Plastic explosives!
What's the big idea?!
Where's Kudo?
Crap!
Ah, so he's saying a brat like you is enough to handle me...
"Like you"?
Is he watching me from somewhere?!
Alright, listen up!
In exactly one hour, another bomb will explode!
Exactly one hour?!
In the plaza in front of Beika Station!
If Kudo won't come, then you find it!
Wait! I'm just a kid; I can't find it that easy!
Gimme a hint or something!
Hello?
Beneath a tree. But it's not exactly buried beneath one.
You better hurry, or someone might wind up taking it!
Damn it!
Conan-kun!
Hey, Conan! Where are you going?!
Ten to 1:00!
No luck! Can't find anything!
Welcome!
What does "under a tree" mean?!
And what does he mean that someone'll take it?!
"Please, someone take her."
Did someone abandon you? You poor thing...
Don't worry! I'll take care of you!
Roots are beneath a tree...
nekko
A cat?!
neko
Thank you!
Huh?
Wait, old lady!
You idiot! Can't you see the stoplight?!
S-Sorry!
Oh no!
Five minutes to 1:00!
Dammit!
Four minutes to 1:00!
Alright! She's caught in traffic!
What's going on?! The sun is still high up...
Oh, yeah! It must've broken somewhere when it went flying!
I'm borrowin' your bike, kid!
Wait!
Huh? "Kid"? I'm younger than him?!
Oh no! It's starting to move!
Three minutes to 1:00!
Hey, yeah! This road makes a big curve to the left!
A-Are you alright, kid?!
Gimme this case, old lady!
25 seconds left!
Hey, kid! Are you alright?!
Yeah...
Damn!
I can't let it detonate here! What do I do?!
It stopped?! Alright!
I'm pretty sure there's an empty lot past the freeway!
You don't need this?
It's ticking again!
Yeah, this is the one!
Sonoko Suzuki
Teitan High School Junior
- Ooh, how flashy!
- But this color is—
After being injured trying to distance the device from people's homes,
the boy was rushed to the police hospital, where he is being treated.
Conan-kun! You're awake!
Conan! You okay?!
Where am I?
The hospital!
Conan! What the hell were you doing?!
Now, now...
Explain so I can understand!
Your questions can wait! Go get the doctor!
Conan!
I'll get him!
Right.
Nothing to worry about now.
His brain waves were just fine when we checked earlier,
so he can probably leave tomorrow.
Thank you...
Take care.
Take care of yourself.
Sorry to be sudden, Conan-kun, but can you tell us what happened?!
Yeah!
I see...
So you rode the bike to protect others from the explosion?
Yeah...
Oh, Inspector!
The culprit makes contact by calling Shin'ichi-niichan's cell phone!
But you can't use cell phones in hospitals...
Oh, there's no need to worry.
We're isolated from that ward there,
and there are no electronic medical devices here,
so cell phones can be used here!
Dr. Agasa explained the situation, which is why we brought you here!
That's a relief...
Also, I ruined that bicycle...
Could you pay for it later, mister?
Never mind that—why did you do something so reckless?!
You nearly died, you know!
Sorry...
Anyways, where is Shin'ichi?! The guy's trying to call him, right?!
As I said, Shin'ichi-kun is busy with something else,
so he asked Conan-kun to handle this...
What a lowlife! I'll teach him a lesson next time I see him!
Definitely can't tell him I'm Shin'ichi Kudo...
Anyway, Inspector! Did you find out what kind of bombs they were?!
Yes.
Both the plane and the carrying case bombs used plastic explosives.
Just as I thought...
A blue-tinged, orange flash is the telltale sign of a plastic explosive!
They were most likely explosives stolen from Toyo Munitions.
The plane had a concussion bomb with a detonator cap attached,
while the carrying case had a time bomb connected to a timer.
But the fact it temporarily stopped 16 seconds before 1:00 bugs me...
About that...
The only possibilities are that the timer stopped due to a malfunction,
or that the culprit stopped it remotely for whatever reason...
From the fact that the culprit went out of his way to phone Kudo-kun,
he either wanted to challenge the famous high school detective,
or he's someone with a personal grudge against him.
From what I've looked into,
all the criminals from cases solved by Shin'ichi Kudo-kun
are currently serving out their prison sentences.
Meaning it must be a relative or lover...
In any case, we're out looking for the man from the sketch they drew.
He means this, Conan! It looks just like him!
It's a work of art!
We all drew it together!
You really got his main features!
But it doesn't ring any bells...
He used a voice changer to alter his voice!
It could be someone I know!
Inspector. Out of all of Shin'ichi-kun's cases so far,
which one received the most public attention?
That'd be the one involving Mayor Okamoto of West Tama City...
A 25 year old female office worker living in West Tama City died
when she was hit by a car the mayor's son was driving.
The mayor had been in the passenger seat
during what at first seemed to be a regular accident...
...but Kudo-kun was skeptical about it.
Shin'ichi Kudo
Teitan High School Junior
Mayor Okamoto (52)
West Tama City Mayor
Kohei Okamoto (21)
Mayor's Son
This cigarette butt was found lying directly next to the victim.
The son's saliva was found on it.
So you tossed this away?
Y-Yes.
After I hit her, I rushed out of the driver's seat and over to her.
I probably unconsciously threw it away then.
I see.
Judging from its length, it hadn't been lit for very long at all.
Yes, it happened just after I lit it.
With a lighter?
Yes.
What lighter did you use?
The car's cigarette lighter.
Then please get in the driver's seat and try lighting a cigarette!
You need only go through the actions.
But... with your seatbelt on, please.
Okay.
Here...
Use one of these.
They're the same kind as the one found at the scene.
Alright...
Stop!
Yes...
The only way to reach it from the driver's seat is with your left hand.
But that lighter only had fingerprints from your right hand on it.
How do you explain that, Kohei-san?
I must've used my own lighter to—
Nope.
You accidentally left this lighter where you had just been.
And your father doesn't smoke...
You unquestionably used this car's lighter from the passenger seat...
...as your father sat next to you, driving!
All other fingerprints were craftily replaced...
Even the seat positions and mirror angles were perfect...
But it seems you overlooked the cigarette lighter, Mayor Okamoto...
My son, Kohei, volunteered to take my place to save my position...
I was really the one driving!
I'm so very sorry!
Dad...
As a result of that incident, Mayor Okamoto lost his position,
and his plans for a revitalized West Tama City were scrapped.
Inspector. Do you suppose his son holds a grudge for what happened?
Come to think of it, he was an electrical engineering student...
I'll look into it!
Do you remember anything else about the culprit?
Anything at all...
Hmm...
A smell...
There was this sweet smell when he gave Mitsuhiko-kun the plane...
There was? I didn't notice anything!
Me neither...
Could the sweet smell have been from cosmetics or something?
I don't know. But it seemed different from perfume...
A sweet smell?
Alright. If you remember anything, let me know.
We will!
Well, we should probably get going...
Yeah. Conan is all better now...
If anything bad happens, I'll rush straight here!
Y-Yeah, thanks...
He's so lucky...
We should get hospitalized, too!
You certainly are popular with the girls, loverboy!
He has no idea how to read people...
Well, bye!
See ya, Conan!
Thanks!
Still, where could Kudo-kun have gone at such an important time?!
Wait, Conan!
Listen. If it's the bomber, I'll handle him!
Hello?
I'm impressed you found the bombs. Well done.
But children's time is over. Put Kudo on!
Yes, now it's adult time!
Who's this?! Where's Kudo?!
Kudo isn't here! Now you're dealing with me!
The great detective, Kogoro Mouri!
Fine. Now listen close; I'll only say this once!
I've planted five bombs on the Tohto Loop Line!
Five—
—bombs?!
If any trains travel below 60 km/h after 4:00 PM, the bombs'll blow.
They're also set to explode if not dismantled by sundown.
I'll give you just one hint...
The bombs are planted "X the X" on the Tohto Loop Line.
In each "X" goes one word.
Well, good luck, Great Detective Mouri.
H-He's just bluffing! Planting bombs on the Loop...
No, he means business.
He most likely has the detonators set for 4:00 PM,
and if the trains fall below 60 km/h after that... they'll explode.
In any case, I need to contact HQ...
It's Megure...
I agree with Inspector Megure...
But what exactly is the bomber after?! Why do something like this?!
Just made it!
Today's our lucky day!
Tohto Railway Terminal Station
Bombs on the Loop?!
Tohto Railway Traffic Control Room
We just received emergency contact from the police department!
Understood! I'll stop all trains at once and have them inspected!
Traffic Dept. Head
Sakaguchi (52)
Command Chief
Kusunoki (45)
No! We can't stop them!
The bombs'll explode if the trains go below 60 km/h after 4:00 PM!
Say what?!
There's only three minutes until 4:00!
Order all trains on the Loop to travel above 60, no, 70 km/h!
What about the trains stopped at stations?!
Get them moving immediately!
What about trains about to stop?
Send them through!
All we can do is keep all the trains running nonstop
until the bombs are found!
Kusunoki-kun!
U-Understood!
Emergency orders! Emergency orders!
Attention, all trains! Someone has planted bombs!
They'll explode if they're traveling under 60 km/h!
All trains are to stay at 70 km/h!
I repeat, someone has planted bombs!
They'll explode if they're traveling under 60 km/h!
All trains are to stay at 70 km/h!
Hey, doesn't this train seem strange?
How so, Genta-kun?
We're almost to Beika Station, but we're slowly speeding up...
Attention, passengers.
Due to an emergency, this train will pass through Beika Station.
Hey! What does "emergency" mean?
Due to an emergency, the train on Line #1 will be passing through.
I see! Alright!
Apparently, no trains have exploded so far.
I've got it, Inspector Megure!
Got what?
"X the X" means "beneath the seats", or "above the racks"!
That's where the bombs are!
"Under the trains" is also a possibility.
Yes, well...
Say, weren't Ayumi-kun and the others getting on the Loop Line
from Midoridai Station to get back to Beika?
Again, this train will continue to run nonstop for the time being.
Should you find a suspicious item onboard,
please refrain from touching it and let the conductor know.
W-What does "suspicious item" mean?!
He means something out of the ordinary!
I know that! But what's "out of the ordinary"?!
Well, that would be, uhh...
Ayumi-chan, do you read me?!
Conan-kun! I read you!
Where are you right now?!
On the Loop...
I thought so...
Hey, Conan! What in the world's goin' on?
Don't tell us there's something that starts with a "b" on the train?!
Don't worry, it's nothin'!
Look! There's no guarantee the bombs are only inside the trains!
Bombs?!
I knew it!
Does that mean we're gonna die?!
Of course not! I will find where they're hidden!
Conan-kun...
Damn it! We can't leave this all to Conan-kun!
We gotta try hard, too! This calls for the Detective Boys!
Detective...
...Boys?
Y-You're right! The bombs do seem to be inside the trains!
Alright! Let's go, Detective Boys!
Yeah!
W-Wait, you guys!
They cut me off!
They gonna be alright?!
Alright! Got it!
A joint task force has been assembled at HQ.
I'm off to Tohto Railways' command center.
Will you come too?
Yes! I will accompany you!
It's just past 4:30!
Look! All trains on the Tohto Loop Line have continued to run nonstop
for over half an hour!
Both Tohto Railways and the police department have only commented
by saying that there has been an emergency situation!
30 minutes is the most the police can keep it under wraps...
Borrowed this from a nurse! It'd be best to watch from your room.
Rigging them to explode if they go under 60 km/h makes some sense...
...but having them explode if they're not dismantled before sundown?
What's that about?
Why would they blow up when the sun sets?
Does it have something to do with the trains' lights?
Here you are!
Please enjoy!
That outfit's pretty sweet! You look good in red!
Thanks!
Both Shin'ichi and I have red as our lucky color this month!
Come to think of it, I haven't seen Shin'ichi-kun in a while either...
Maybe I should go with you too!
But it's going to be a boring movie, plus he's pretty boring himself...
I'm just kidding! No one's gonna get in your guys' way!
You get serious so easily, Ran! That's why I love teasin' ya!
You're so silly, Sonoko...
But I'm surprised your dad's letting you go to an all-night movie!
He was against it, but I ignored him!
I bet he and Conan-kun are discussing dinner right about now!
So you couldn't find anything suspicious inside the trains?!
That's right...
All 21 trains were thoroughly searched by their conductors,
but all items had owners!
So, how about your end?
Videos taken along the tracks showed no bombs under the train cars.
I see...
Then where could the bombs be?!
Bad news, sir! The passengers are getting unruly!
How long're you gonna keep this thing going?!
Just stop it already!
My child has a stomachache! Please, let us get off!
What is this "suspicious item" anyway?! Don't tell me it's a bomb?!
A-A bomb?!
Screw this! I'm gettin' off! I'm jumpin' out!
Calm down, sir! Stop!
Chief Director! I can't keep this up!
Hang in there a little longer!
Mouri-kun! Have you figured out any way to locate the bombs?!
An hour and a half until sunset...
Still, having them go off when the sun sets...
That's like the exact opposite of my skateboard...
You know, it's solar-powered, so it doesn't work once the sun sets.
The sun?
I got it! I got it, Doc!
Megure here!
Inspector! It's Kudo!
Oh! Kudo-kun! I've been waiting!
Dr. Agasa explained everything!
The bombs are not "below the seats",
"above the racks", or "under the trains"!
They're "between the tracks"!
Between the tracks?!
The bombs are set to detonate after a dozen or so seconds of darkness!
When the trains pass over, the cars block the light for a few seconds!
One car is 20 meters in length; 10 cars are 200 meters long.
60 kilometers per hour is 16.7 meters per second.
In other words, it takes about 12 seconds to travel 200 meters!
The bombs are rigged to explode just barely after that amount of time!
So move the trains onto other lines immediately!
There's no danger in stopping them as long as they're off the Loop!
Understood!
Mr. Sakaguchi. You heard what to do!
Right!
Divert Train #11 onto the Shibahama Station cargo line in 3 minutes!
Get everything ready!
Train #11, Train #11! Track switch in three minutes!
Shibahama Station, circuit confirm interlock on!
Move all cargo trains onto emergency sidetracks!
Train #11, passing through Kawashina Station!
Shibahama Station
Train #10, passing through Shibahama Station!
Switching track!
Reducing speed, now!
68 km/h... 66 km/h...
64... 63 km/h...
62... 61...
60 km/h!
59! 58 km/h!
Everything normal?!
Yes! All normal!
Alright! Keep slowing and stop at the next cargo station!
Roger that!
We did it!
No, we can't rest easy yet! There are still 20 more trains on the Loop!
Train #9! All normal!
Train #20! All normal!
One train left!
This is Train #10! Currently at 55 km/h! All normal here!
We did it!
We did it! We did it! We pulled it off!
A truly excellent display of skill!
Excellent work!
Now it's our turn to handle things!
Whew, we finally managed to get off!
I'm never rushing onto a train last-minute again!
Really?! That's great!
Say, was it you who found the bombs, Conan-kun?!
No, it was Shin'ichi-niichan who found them!
Though the bombs haven't actually been found yet...
The bombs are placed where there wouldn't be shade
from buildings or walls after 4:00 PM!
When searching, always be aware of the sun's location
and be very careful not to cover the bombs with your own shadows!
Bomb located!
Understood!
The five bombs have been safely collected.
Yes!
Alright!
It was all as Kudo-kun deduced...
Fifteen minutes until sunset...
Talk about a close call...
But it's too early to celebrate...
The amount of explosives used so far accounts for only one-fourth
of the stolen quantity...
Meaning that the bomber still has the remaining three-fourths?!
Sorry I'm late.
So, what'd you find out?
Well, about Mayor Okamoto's son Kohei...
I learned that he left early this morning for the Izu area.
Which means he's innocent...
Yes...
Umm, about the bombing incident...
Solved.
All thanks to Kudo-kun...
The issue now is the remaining explosives and the bomber's identity.
About all we know for sure is that the bomber doesn't live near
any of the five spots along the Loop, right?
Right?! If the bombs blew up, entire trains could've been sent flying!
He wouldn't risk that near his own house—
Could that also be why he stopped the timer in the carrying case?!
There was a playground and an apartment building nearby...
That's it! The bomber lives in those apartments!
Alright! Straight to those apartments!
Nothing at all?!
Yes. We checked not just that building, but all other nearby houses...
But they were all in the clear...
Oh...
Say, Inspector. What kind of places were the train bombs planted at?
What kind? Just regular ol' residential areas...
Oh, yes. There was one on a bridge, over the Sumida Canal.
On a bridge?
Isn't this that bridge?
Hold on...
Wasn't there a photo of this in Professor Moriya's gallery?
Say, didn't Professor Moriya design this bridge?
He did?
That's correct.
Teiji Moriya designed it.
The bridge was completed in 1983,
and the fact it was built of stone in an English style instead of iron
was quite the topic at the time.
With this bridge's design, Teiji Moriya won
the Architectural Association of Japan's Newcomer Award!
You certainly are well-informed!
Architecture interests me...
—the recent series of arson incidents. Police believe—
That's enough. It's distracting.
'Kay...
Come to think of it, the Kurokawa mansion that was set on fire
was also designed by Professor Moriya...
Say, I wonder who designed all these houses that were set on fire!
I bet we might find something interesting if we look into it!
Interesting, indeed...
I'll go now.
Okay. Thanks for coming with me today!
Better give me the details later!
Steal at least a kiss from him!
9:00...
In one hour...
Say what?! They were all designed by Mr. Moriya?!
Yes.
The Kurokawa, Mizushima, Yasuda, and Akutsu mansions—
which were all burned down—
were designed by Professor Moriya in his early 30s.
Hard to think it's a coincidence...
Maybe the bombs on the Loop were really meant for that bridge, too!
That bridge?!
It's quite possible.
The bomber could be the arsonist,
who's going after Professor Moriya's designs!
Aha! That's it, Inspector!
The culprit is someone with a grudge against Professor Moriya,
or someone who's jealous of his success!
His challenge to Shin'ichi was just camouflage!
I see. It is highly likely...
I agree.
Homemade igniters were used during each arson!
I now realize they have something in common with the bombings!
Everything being targeted is work from his 30s...
Alright! For now, let's go speak with Professor Moriya!
Mouri-kun! Lead the way!
Right, where was it again?
I remember, mister!
I'll lead the way!
Don't be silly! You're still not—
I'm all better now! Come on!
Hey, wait!
I leave it to you, Shin'ichi...
Mouri-san. Just ahead is where the bomb timer temporarily stopped...
A playground...
Yeesh! We wasted so much time, all because of those crude bombs!
I see. That's indeed too much to be a mere coincidence...
Can you think of anyone who might do something like this?
Hmm, let me think...
That's a photograph from when I was ten, Conan-kun.
With me are my mother and father.
Your father must be a really great person, Professor Moriya!
He was a world-renowned architect.
He was particularly active in England...
I was a big fan of his architecture...
I believe he passed away—
—fifteen years ago, in a fire at his villa.
Together with my mother...
I inherited this mansion after it happened.
And that's when your designs suddenly began to get the spotlight, right, Moriya-san?
Yes, that's right...
Huh?! This smell...
Could it be?!
Moriya-san. Do you have any ideas who could be behind this?
Oh, right...
This is where his works from his 30s begin!
The Kurokawa mansion...
The Mizushima mansion...
The Yasuda mansion and the Akutsu mansion...
And then the bridge...
Wait a minute! This bridge—
No doubt about it!
I was still inept in my youth. Please don't pay them much attention...
No way! Is that even plausible?!
But that smell...
Was this here last time?
"My Visionary New Town, West Tama City"?
Come to think of it...
As a result of that incident, Mayor Okamoto lost his position,
and his plans for a revitalized West Tama City were scrapped.
I get it! It was Professor Moriya who was planning this!
A new town, with perfect symmetry...
It's the same as the lampposts in the playground!
Ah! So that's why—
That person is the culprit, after all!
But there's no proof.
Guess I'll just have to wing it...
Perfect!
Now for some scissors, tape, and a marker...
A lighter?
I see. So you can't think of anyone...
I apologize for not being of use.
Well, if you can think of anything, please let us know.
Where's Conan-kun?
Pardon me...
This is Megure...
Oh! Kudo-kun!
Okay! Got it! I'll gather everyone in the gallery right away!
Moriya-san. I'm sorry to ask, but could we see your gallery?
Very well. But would you mind if I stopped by my study first?
Not at all!
Sorry for the delay. Right this way...
The gallery is on the second floor.
Right in here...
Megure here. Yes, we're in the gallery now.
Inspector Megure. Press the speaker button so that everyone can hear.
Alright...
Actually, I've figured out who's behind these arsons and bombings!
You have?! Who is it?!
Hold it! I've figured it out, too!
The culprit is you, Detective Shiratori!
What?!
As someone with deep respect for Professor Moriya's father,
you were suspicious about his death and began to suspect his son,
who had stepped into the spotlight immediately afterward!
You were suspicious that he had set the fire that killed him!
Certain of this, you set fire to each of Professor Moriya's buildings!
Your respect for the father became desire for revenge against the son!
What's more, you were always absent whenever the bomber called!
H-Hold on, now!
Well, Shin'ichi?! Isn't that what you wanna say, too?!
No!
What?!
These incidents were not perpetrated by someone
with a grudge against Professor Moriya!
The one responsible is the designer of the four mansions set on fire,
as well as the bridge... You, Professor Moriya!
What?!
You idiot! What kind of architect destroys his own work?!
Early on, Professor Moriya inherited his father's architectural talent,
and in his early 30s, he made his unusually young debut into the architectural world.
Hello?
And with his design of the bridge on the Loop,
he won the Architectural Association of Japan's Newcomer Award!
Professor Moriya continued to produce new buildings after that,
when he suddenly—
or maybe not so suddenly—
wanted to get rid of the works he created in his youth.
This can be surmised from the professor's words at the tea party...
Most young architects these days lack artistic sense!
They need to feel much more responsibility for their works!
In short, you put those words into action.
That does sound familiar...
Hold on! You weren't even at his party! How do you—
Now then, everyone.
Hey...
Have a look at the panel photographs.
Look closely at the Kurokawa mansion,
the Mizushima mansion, the Yasuda mansion,
and the Akutsu mansion, as well as the bridge.
They each use classic English-style architecture,
but do you notice anything about them?
They all look like splendid works of architecture to me...
They're not perfectly symmetrical!
Correct! Their left-right symmetries are slightly off.
Most likely, the clients ordered it that way,
or he had to compromise due to building laws or the like.
Professor Moriya, being a perfectionist, couldn't stand that.
Around the same time, a shadow began to creep
into his life as an architect, which had been smooth-sailing until then.
His plan for a revitalized West Tama City,
which he had spent a great deal of time on...
...was suddenly canceled as a result of the mayor's arrest!
Ah! So Professor Moriya designed this, too?!
By challenging me and tarnishing my name as a high school detective,
the professor hoped to exact revenge on me,
while also trying to camouflage his goal—the bridge's destruction—
to look unrelated to the recent string of mansion arsons!
And the reason he stopped the bomb timer in the carrying case...
...was because of the gas lampposts in the playground!
They were a symbol of his new West Tama City!
The professor didn't want to destroy them;
he designed them to resemble the ones from his beloved London!
Am I wrong?!
An interesting theory, Kudo-kun...
But unfortunately, there is no proof.
Oh, but there is... Behind the model case!
This is the bomber's disguise!
Impossible! That's in my safe in the study!
Oh, so the bomber's disguise is actually hidden in your safe?
What?!
These are my glasses!
I painted them black with a marker!
I made the mustache and wig by cutting that helmet's decorative hair
and then taping it together!
These were all Shin'ichi-niichan's ideas!
Professor Moriya. I must ask you to come down to the—
Don't move!
Move, and I'll blow the bombs I set in this mansion!
They won't blow up.
After all, that detonator...
...has no batteries!
Impossible!
W-When did you—
How did you know this was a detonator?!
Well, you don't use lighters!
Plus you used long matches to light your pipe...
...and the sweet smell Ayumi-chan mentioned was your pipe's smell!
Arrest him!
Alright! That solves all the cases!
What a happy ending!
It's hardly happy, Mouri-san! You're horrible, calling people criminals!
Yeah, sorry about that! Even monkeys fall from trees, as they say!
Though in his case, his theories fell instead...
You're gravely mistaken if you think you've resolved everything.
There is one other building I wanted to get rid of!
No! The Beika City Building?!
Don't tell me it doesn't have perfect symmetry too?!
All because of the absurd reason that the building budget was lost
due to the bubble economy's collapse!
It's my grandest and lousiest work of all!
None of you would ever understand my aesthetics!
Well, then. One minute to 10:00...
Ran...
Beika City Building
Beika Cinema 1
Yes, this is Mouri...
Ran-neechan! Get out, quick!
Ran-neechan! Are you okay?! Ran-neechan!
Gimme that!
Hey, Ran! What happened?! Respond! Ran!
Damn it!
What the hell are you doing to my Ran?!
I've only blocked the lobby's entrance and emergency exits so far.
The best is yet to come...
What?!
Hey, Kudo! I assume you're listening from somewhere!
You better hurry before your beloved girlfriend winds up in scraps!
You'll pay for this!
Mouri-kun! No violence!
What're you doing, kid?!
These are—
What the—Bomb blueprints?!
What?!
I'll go give them to Shin'ichi-niichan!
Hold on!
I'll send the bomb disposal unit right away!
I can't wait for the bomb disposal unit!
Wait!
If you see Kudo, tell him this!
"I gave you three minutes! Enjoy it all you can!"
Wait, Conan-kun!
Shiratori-kun! Take care of Professor Moriya!
Right!
Ran!
Where are you, Ran?!
Ran! Ran! Damn it!
Mouri-kun!
Ran!
Inspector! What are the rescue units doing?!
Calm down, Mouri-kun! Calm down!
Hold on, Ran! I'm coming!
It's all right! Help will be here soon!
Hello?
R-Ran?!
S-Shin'ichi?!
Lucky! Looks like the phone lines haven't been cut yet!
Where were you?! You're always gone at the most important times!
You're really always—always—
Do you even know what situation I'm in now?!
Yeah, I know.
I'm right in front of the emergency exit; it's blocked with debris...
I managed to squeeze through the rubble to get here...
...but the shock from the bomb...
...seems to have deformed the door, so there's no way to open it...
Say, is there anything weird in the lobby, like a briefcase or suitcase?
Weird?
What is this? It's really heavy and big!
And there's this digital clock on it...
Be careful! That's a bomb!
A bomb?!
Damn you, Professor! You put the biggest one here!
Ran! What's the timer say?!
Hold on!
42 minutes and 7 seconds...
42 minutes, huh...
Which means it'll explode three minutes after midnight...
Three minutes?
"I gave you three minutes! Enjoy it all you can!"
What is this "three minutes" thing?!
Well?!
It's no use! All stairwells are buried in debris!
It'll take more time to reach the people trapped in the 5th floor lobby!
Ran...
18 minutes left!
There's no time left! We have no choice...
Hey, Ran! Do you got any scissors on you?
I have sewing kit scissors, but what are we going to do with those?
You're going to disarm the bomb!
Now listen, follow my instructions...
Wait! I can't do it while on the phone!
I'll go by you!
Wait!
Alright. There doesn't seem to be a vibration detector on it...
But do it gently!
Alright!
Can you hear me, Shin'ichi?
Yeah, loud and clear!
I'm tearing the bag now.
Be careful!
What is it, Ran? Are you all right?
Y-Yeah... I'm fine...
Okay! I'm ready!
Alright. First, let's remove the outer cover. Pull it up and off.
Gently, now!
R-Right...
It's off, Shin'ichi!
Great! Now we're going to cut the wiring inside...
Mess up the order in the slightest and we're goners!
First, the yellow cord near the bottom...
I'm cutting it!
Okay!
Inspector! Don't tell me Ran is—
Calm down, Mouri-kun! That isn't where Ran-kun is!
Don't worry! Your daughter still has 15 minutes until she's blown up!
Damn you! Talk! How do we stop the bomb?!
It's a special bomb, you see...
Even if it can be disarmed, the last wire will determine her fate!
Several pillars of smoke are rising from the Beika City Building—
It's cut.
Alright... It looks like we'll make it in time!
Once we cut the final black cord, the timer'll stop!
The black cord?
S-Shin'ichi...
I cut the black cord, but the timer isn't stopping...
P-Plus there are still two cords left!
A red one and a blue one!
What?!
The path to the 4th floor stairway is finally open!
Hurry! There's only four minutes until it detonates!
Ran! Ran! I'm coming!
Mouri-san!
Where are you going, Mouri-san?!
Let go of me! I have to save Ran!
Please stop! The rescue team will save—
Ran! Ran!
The hapless love of a father for his daughter...
Architecture has no need for love...
Nor does life!
Wait, Professor! Don't tell me you purposely left out the two wires
to set me up?!
What should I do? Cut them both?
You idiot! One of them's a booby trap!
It'll blow the instant you cut it!
A-Are you serious?!
Damn! Which is it?!
Red or blue?! Which should we cut?!
Midnight... Three minutes left...
Damn it! Which is it?! Which one?!
Shin'ichi?
Yeah?
Happy birthday, Shin'ichi...
After all...
I... might never get to say it again...
Ran...
Cut it...
Cut whichever color you want...
But... what if I get it wrong?
It doesn't matter.
We're goners anyway, once time is up...
So choose your color...
B-But...
Don't worry! I'll be right here with you until you're done cutting!
We'll be together when we die...
Shin'ichi...
Which color do you like better, red or blue?
Red, I guess?
And look! Both Shin'ichi and I have red as our lucky color for May!
So I decided that we gotta see this!
Ran! Ran! You alright?!
Damn! She can't hear me!
Oh, yeah! My cell phone!
It's gone!
Damn, did I drop it earlier?!
T-There's a little boy here!
You're safe now, little boy! Let's go!
W-Wait! There are still people trapped inside!
Alright, wait here!
It's no use! Get the jackhammer!
Right!
Today's my wedding anniversary,
but it doesn't look like I'll be enjoying it much...
"I gave you three minutes! Enjoy it all you can!"
I get it! He was telling me to enjoy three minutes of my birthday!
Wait! Wasn't that when—
Oh, that sounds like fun!
I take it you've already gotten him a present?
No, on Saturday I'm going to—
He and I both like the color red!
And we both have red as our lucky color for May!
Lucky color?
Oh no!
Run, little boy!
- Little boy!
- Ran! The red one's a trap!
Cut the blue one! Don't cut the red one!
Ran, where are you?! Respond!
Ran! Ran! Ran!
Ran!
Goodbye, Shin'ichi...
I-Impossible!
It's so wonderful that Ran-kun is all right, Mouri-kun!
Yes! Thank you!
- I'm with Nichiuri TV!
- Give us your thoughts!
What role did the great detective play?!
These bombings were meant to tarnish my name as a great detective
by leading my daughter Ran into a trap that—
Oh!
Conan-kun! You came because you were worried?
Yeah...
Where'd you get that bandage?
Oh, I just fell...
You need to be careful.
Say, Conan-kun. Have you seen Shin'ichi?
Huh? He was just here a minute ago...
Ugh! After I went and got him a present...
Come to think of it, Shin'ichi-niichan did seem puzzled!
He thought you'd pick the red wire for sure,
so he was wondering why you cut the blue one instead...
I didn't want to cut it.
"Legend of the Red Thread"
After all, Shin'ichi and I...
...might be connected!
T-There's no red thread!
Guess that means I'm outta luck as long as I'm Conan...