- Wow! It's Mt. Fuji!
- It's so pretty!
It's definitely the best mountain in Japan!
What's that?
Oh, those are the new Twin
Tower Buildings in West Tama City.
319 meters and 294 meters in height,
and the tallest twins in Japan!
I wish I could visit!
Doc! Let's stop by on our way
home from camping tomorrow!
Hmm. It's a little out of the way, but sure.
West Tama City...
That's where I exposed
the former mayor's crimes,
and where Moriya Teiji
tried to get the best of me...
Still, these guys sure love camping...
Camp tomorrow! Camp the day after tomorrow!
Camp Grounds
Thank you for the food!
Hold on! You still have rice left!
My mom said it's bad luck to
waste even one grain of rice!
That's correct! Rice farmers
work hard 88 times to make rice!
88 times?
Yes!
If you cut up the character for "rice",
you get "88" out of it, right?
You do?
- Oh, you do!
- You're right!
That's why the age of 88
is called the "rice age".
While we're at it, 77 is
called the "happiness age",
and 99 is the "white age".
Do you know why 77 is the "happiness age"?
Because the character for
"happiness" looks like "77" in cursive.
Right?
The "white age" is 99 because
"white" is "100" with one line missing.
Wow! You two always know so much!
I bet you guys are
actually lying about your ages!
You got that right...
So now I have a riddle for you!
Can you guess what age 44 is called?!
44?
Here's a hint! One kanji
and three katakana characters!
You don't need to add "age" to the end!
"44"
One kanji and three katakana characters...
What could it be?
44... 88... Oh, geez.
Doc, I figured it out, but man, that's stupid.
You think so?
How about you, Ai-kun?
Have you figured it out?
- I don't know, either!
- Me neither!
Likewise!
Then here's the answer! 44 is half of 88, right?
88 is "rice." And since this is
half of that, it's "a half bowl of rice"!
Just as I thought...
What? What's wrong?
A half bowl of rice!
Let's have two each!
Get it?
Restrooms
I peed my pants a little...
Brr!
It looks like I'll be going
to the Twin Tower Building
in West Tama City tomorrow.
He'll be coming too, of course.
Got it, boss! The Twin Tower
Building in West Tama City!
They say that's the closest
place to heaven, as I recall!
Perfect. It's closest to the afterlife.
Let's use it to hold an execution!
I'm high school detective Kudo Shin'ichi.
I went with old friend and classmate,
Mouri Ran, to an amusement park
where I witnessed a suspicious
deal with a man dressed in black!
I was so absorbed with watching the deal
that I didn't notice a second
man sneak up from behind me!
He forced me to take a poison,
and when I woke up...
... my body had shrunk!
If they learned Kudo Shin'ichi was alive,
they might go after me again,
putting all the people around me in danger!
Per Dr. Agasa's advice,
I decided to conceal my identity.
When Ran asked my name,
I quickly answered, "Edogawa Conan."
To get information on the men,
I wound up living with
Ran and her detective father.
Okay!
I'm Agasa Hiroshi, genius inventor!
Let me use this chance to
introduce my masterpieces!
The Stun-Gun Wristwatch!
The Voice-Changing Bowtie!
The Power-Assisted Kick Shoes!
The Turbo-Engine Skateboard!
And the Criminal Locator Glasses!
One of the lenses has another
new gizmo attached, as well!
Infrared Telescopic Vision!
I made these all for the now-little Shin'ichi!
He uses these gadgets to
solve cases using Mouri-kun's voice
and catch bad guys!
Take this!
Oh, yes! I nearly forgot!
I also invented the Detective
Badges and Wristwatch Flashlights
that he and his classmates use
for their Junior Detective League!
Incidentally, besides me,
there are four others who know who he is.
His father and mystery writer, Kudo Yusaku,
his mother and former actress, Kudo Yukiko,
high school detective of
the west, Hattori Heiji-kun,
and his classmate, Haibara Ai-kun.
Her real name is Miyano Shiho.
She used to work with the men in black,
but after they killed her sister,
she tried to flee the organization.
She took the same poison as Shin'ichi
and wound up shrinking.
The men in black are
relentlessly pursuing Haibara!
And now, unbeknownst to me,
something's about to happen!
Even when I'm small, my mind
remains that of a sharp detective!
There is always only one truth!
I feel squished in here...
It's because you're sitting in the back!
You sat in the front last time!
It seemed more fun back here...
Hey, Conan. Scoot over more.
Sheesh. It's because you ate 5 bowls
of rice first thing in the morning!
Sorry, I gotta scoot over, Ayumi-chan.
Mitsuhiko! Let's play a game!
Then let's play the 30-second game!
You count 30 seconds in your head,
and then stop the stopwatch.
Cool! Let's all play!
I'm busy driving.
I'll pass, too.
28. 29. 30!
40 seconds! 10 seconds over!
29. 30!
27 seconds!
So close!
30!
Yikes!
59 seconds?
Are you sure this thing isn't busted?
I think it might be you, Genta-kun!
28! 29! 30!
30 seconds exactly!
- Wow, Ayumi-chan!
- You must be psychic!
It was just luck...
Say, Haibara. Who were
you calling so late last night?
I didn't call anyone. Are you sure
you weren't dreaming, Kojima-kun?
Eh? Was I?
It's so tall!
I can't see the top!
It's like it even goes above the clouds!
Is that you, Conan-kun?!
Huh? Ran-neechan! What's going on?
Hey, you! What're you doing here?!
We came to check out the buildings
on our way home from camping.
What about you?
Tokiwa Mio-kun, the owner
of this Twin Tower Building,
was a junior student of
mine in college, you see,
and she specially invited me
for next week's grand opening!
Oh? I never heard about that.
Right?! He didn't even tell me, either!
He only confessed after I grilled
him about his strange behavior.
Confessed?! I wasn't hiding anything!
I get it! You two came to keep an eye on him!
After all, Tokiwa Mio-san is the rich
daughter of the Tokiwa zaibatsu,
and still single!
And since Ran's parents are
currently separated, she's worried!
Excuse me, but might
you be Mouri Kogoro-sama?
Yes.
I'm Sawaguchi, the president's secretary.
She's with guests at the moment,
so I'll show you the showrooms first.
Building A is entirely for business offices,
and floors 31 and above
are all occupied by Tokiwa.
The showrooms are on the 2nd and 3rd floors.
Hey. What kind of company is Tokiwa?
Mostly computer software,
but they do all sorts of computer-related stuff!
Does that mean they got
video games, too?! I can't wait!
Just look at all these interesting things!
Hello, everyone! Welcome!
This is Hara, our managing
director and programmer!
Nice to meet you!
- What is this?
- Is it an arcade machine?
Wanna try it out?
This uses a computer to predict
what you'll look like in 10 years!
Oh? What you'll look like
in 10 years? That's amazing!
Doc! Let's try it!
Please sit in the seats, then.
I wouldn't wanna see my old
face from 10 years in the future...
Are you ready? Here we go!
Here is how you two will look in 10 years time!
Huh? It's no different at all...
This machine is broken!
No, it's not.
Check out Ayumi-chan's.
So cute!
You're way cuter than this girl!
Kids don't know
anything about grownup charm!
- Anyways, let's try it, too!
- Yeah!
- Eh?!
- Not good...
I totally know high-schoolers like this!
Oh! I think you both look nice!
Really?!
Yes!
You and me are next!
I totally know old ladies like that!
Oh, shut up.
So pretty!
Oh?!
Looks just like Eri when she was young!
- Almost too good for Shin'ichi!
- Eh?!
It makes me mad to think that
jerk's stringing this girl along!
Don't say that, Sonoko!
Come on, now...
What?
- Why are you embarrassed?!
- No, it's not like that...
Next is Conan and Haibara!
Huh?!
Hey! Haibara!
I'm fine.
I'll pass, too.
After all, in 10 years, I'll look like Shin'ichi,
and Haibara'll look like Miyano Shiho.
Come on, you!
I'm gonna see what kind of
punk you look like in 10 years!
You too, Haibara-san!
Hold on!
Oh, crap!
I wonder what you'll look like, Conan-kun!
Error?! That's strange...
Lucky!
It might mean neither of us
will exist 10 years from now...
Yes! Certainly!
Everyone! I'll show you to
the party room on the 75th floor!
Please follow me to the elevators...
- I'm sorry!
- Not at all...
There it is!
She was born in the year of the boar,
so she tends to rush recklessly!
Oh, I see! You do that often?
This elevator goes directly to the 75th floor?
Yes. This elevator is for VIPs,
so it goes directly to the desired floor.
The only place it can be
stopped from the outside
is the concert hall on the 66th floor.
So high up!
What an amazing view!
It's like we're getting closer to heaven!
We're preparing for the grand
opening party, so it's a little crowded.
Mouri-senpai!
Tokiwa-kun! It's been a while!
Thank you for coming all this way!
Yeah, I was planning to come alone, but...
I'm his daughter, Ran!
My mother also sends her regards!
Hey now, Ran!
Let me introduce you!
- My classmate, Suzuki Sonoko!
- Hello!
- Dr. Agasa, the inventor!
And Edogawa Conan-kun,
Haibara Ai-chan, Yoshida Ayumi-chan...
...Tsuburaya Mitsuhiko-kun...
- Hello!
...and Kojima Genta-kun!
- Hi.
It's nice to meet you all! I'm Tokiwa Mio.
Now let me introduce you!
My art instructor and Japanese-style painter,
Kisaragi Hohsui-sensei.
Kisaragi Hohsui? The one
famous for his Mt. Fuji paintings?
I know about you, too!
You're Kogoro the
Catnapping Detective, aren't ya?!
That's "Sleeping Kogoro!"
This guy reeks of booze!
This is Oki Iwamatsu-sensei,
a councilman of West Tama City.
He assisted with the construction
of this building in many ways.
And this is Kazama Hidehiko-san,
the architect of these buildings!
I have a small connection to you, Mouri-san.
I'm actually a pupil of Moriya Teiji.
Moriya Teiji?!
But there's no need to worry.
I won't blow up these buildings like Moriya.
B-Blow up?
Because they're different
heights and unsymmetrical, right?
Oh? You know a lot, little boy.
Hurry! Hurry! You can see it so close up!
- It's so pretty!
- It's huge!
Oh! This is an incredible view!
You can even see Fuji at night here.
Even at night?
What does that mean?
What can you see from the other side?!
- What's that?
- It looks like a dome roof...
Tower B is for commerce.
The lower area is for shops,
and the upper area is a hotel.
There's an indoor pool on the top floor,
and the dome can open and close!
Wow! That's really something!
Say, Mio-kun. Could you let me
stay in the hotel this weekend?
But we still haven't opened...
No, in other words?!
Very well. I'll prepare
a suite on the 67th floor.
I'd like to have dinner
with you too, if possible...
That's a strange brooch.
A present from someone nice?
No, I got it for myself.
Mio-kun! I'll be leaving now!
Oh, I'll accompany you!
You needn't see me off!
He seems angry about something...
Mio-san bought up all of his
paintings and then sold them for a lot.
He wasn't happy about that...
Chocolate!
Oh, you caught me! I'll let you have some, too!
Yay!
- Here you are!
- Thank you!
- Thanks!
He's a brilliant programmer,
but also very childish...
Oh, but that's how he can make fun games!
Oh, yes!
I'm working on a new video game;
could I ask for your opinions?
- For a game?!
- Certainly!
I live in Soho.
We live in Beika!
That's not far, then! Just a quick bus ride!
Want to come by next Sunday?!
Yes! We'll be there!
What's wrong, Ai-chan?
Nothing.
Ran-san.
There's something I'd like
to talk to you about alone.
Could we meet tomorrow?
Sure, that's fine.
I'll let you know the time and place later.
Ran-oneesan.
There's something I
wanna talk to you about alone.
Eh?
It's the hair. That's the problem...
Maybe I'll try a wave, too!
Never thought I'd see a
car like that these days!
- What was it again?
- A Porsche 356A!
What?!
Hold it! That elevator is for VIPs only!
Employees use the general elevators!
- Y-Yes, ma'am!
- Our apologies!
Tell me! Where did you see
that car?! What color was it?!
Oh, it was stopped in front
of this building. It was black.
It's Gin's car!
Wait, Conan-kun...!
Hey! Where are you going?!
Hurry! Hurry!
There it is!
Damn!
But... why'd they come to this building?!
The truth is, I've always liked
Ayumi-chan since kindergarten.
But she seems to like Conan-kun...
Please tell me, Ran-san!
How can we go
from childhood friends to
lovers like you and Shin'ichi-san?
H-Hold on! Shin'ichi and I aren't like that!
And, I've started to notice
Haibara-san lately, too...
Am I a horrible man to be
fond of two girls at once?!
It's not horrible at all!
Liking someone is a very good thing,
and I think you should treasure such feelings!
Then?!
But maybe you should just
be close friends for right now?
With Ayumi-chan and Ai-chan,
and Conan-kun and Genta-kun too, of course!
I understand!
Half off five donuts!
Welcome!
I really like Conan-kun.
But he likes someone else.
Do you mean Ai-chan?
No. You, Ran-oneesan!
Don't be silly!
Conan-kun likes you! I know it!
So I'd like you to tell him
you already have Shin'ichi-san
so he should give up!
U-Uhh...
Otherwise, I'll feel so bad for him...
But we don't know for sure
that Conan-kun likes me...
I do!
How?
My woman's sixth sense!
O-Oh...
Huh? What?!
I'm telling you, I think
Conan-kun has a crush on me!
What?! He does not! Don't be stupid!
Oh? And how do you know that?
No, uhh, childhood love is like the
measles! There's no need to worry!
Come on, now! Think seriously!
In that case, don't make any strange lies,
and be honest with yourself.
Be honest with myself?
If you do that, the answer
should turn up on its own.
See ya! I'll call later!
I'm the one who needs to be honest...
W-What are you doing?!
I've asked you here for but one reason.
The truth is, a man was found stabbed to death
in a suite in the Twin Tower Building.
- Eh?!
- That's!
Oki Iwamatsu, the West Tama City councilman!
I hear you were there when he
asked Tokiwa Mio-san for a room.
- Chiba-kun.
- Yes, sir.
Mr. Oki's estimated time of death
is between 10:00 PM and midnight.
We believe a knife was used,
but it wasn't at the scene.
But there was an "O-choko" cup
by Mr. Oki's hand, split in two.
O-choko?
This.
This O-choko is quite expensive.
There's a good chance Mr. Oki,
fond of sake, brought it with him,
and that it's a dying message
indicating who the killer is.
In other words, the police think the
suspect is one of those five people?
The building still hasn't been
opened to the public, you see.
Oh! I got it! The "O-choko"
refers to "chocolate"!
The killer was the
chocolate-loving Hara Yoshiaki!
- Eh?!
- No way!
It wasn't Hara-san!
He's a nice person!
He shared his chocolate with us!
Yeah!
Hey! Quiet, you!
Hara-san is most likely in the clear.
Of the five people we questioned,
he was the only one with an alibi.
Alibi?
That's not nice, Inspector!
You should've said so at the start!
Could "O-choko" refer
to "ochokochoi"? [clumsy]
If so, then Mouri-san would
be the most suspicious of all.
Hold on, Shiratori!
It's a joke.
Honestly, now...
What about motive?
We're investigating that as we speak.
Although a councilman, Mr. Oki
held more sway than the mayor.
Supposedly, he even forced
the revision of a city ordinance
preventing skyscrapers
from being built in the area.
So that's why Mio-san couldn't say no
when Oki-san asked for a hotel
room before the grand opening.
Come to think of it, the brooch she had on
looked like that broken O-choko.
Just a minute! Mio-kun couldn't have...!
No. It would've been the
easiest for her to commit the crime.
After all, she lives on
the 68th floor of Tower B,
one floor above the room he was staying in.
B-But...
Say. Doesn't that O-choko
look like the small bowl used
when doing Japanese-style paintings?
My daddy does
Japanese-style paintings as a hobby.
It reminds me of a mortar
used to grind the powder!
So the O-choko links to Mr. Kisaragi...
But it doesn't seem to link to
Sawaguchi-san or Kazama-san...
Shiratori-san, is it true
Kazama-san is Moriya Teiji's pupil?
It's true.
But he's more of the technical
type than the artistic Moriya,
so he doesn't have a preferred style.
As for Sawaguchi Chinami-san,
her father was a newspaper reporter,
and he died from overwork when
she was in her 4th year in college.
But we've yet to find a
connection between him and Mr. Oki.
Inspector.
In my opinion, this incident
was meant to disrupt the...
Only the lower part of the
closet has blood splatters...
And it's in a strange shape...
That isn't for a child's eyes.
Sorry...
Still, what were Gin and Vodka
doing at the Twin Tower Building?
Wait!
O-choko cups are for holding alcohol!
Hey, Haibara. Could it have been them?!
It's true that they have alcohol codenames.
But they'd never be foolish enough
to leave such an obvious message.
...as possible. Got it?
Mitsuhiko-kun! Over here!
You two are early!
This is too exciting!
I'm so happy to think we'll
beat Conan to the punch!
Who are you beating to the punch?
How did you know?!
You guys are always so predictable!
You thought I'd stop you from
investigating the case yourselves
because it's too dangerous, right?
B-Bingo!
It's too late this time, but don't
do stuff on your own anymore!
Okay!
Do these guys really understand anything?
So? Who're we seeing today?
Kazama-san and Kisaragi-san!
And tomorrow is Hara-san!
Kazama-san lives in Setagaya,
but he has a workroom in Asahino,
just before West Tama City!
He's staying there until
the building's grand opening!
Kisaragi-san is single
and built a house in Asahino
with a studio three years ago!
Wow. They really did their homework.
It's too bad Haibara-san didn't
come too, since we're all going!
Huh? You invited her, too?
Yes!
But she said she was
busy cleaning house today!
Brother!
I guess this is what traitors get...
Brother! Brother!
I believe Kazama-san's
apartment is right by the station.
And Kisaragi-san's house is...
Yeah! Up on that hill!
Let's go see Kazama-san first!
Wow! This is a CAD system, right?
Blueprints are all done on computer, right?
Oh! You know a lot!
No one uses drafting boards these days.
What's a drafting board?
I see! You've actually never heard of them?
In the old days, you'd put a
piece of paper on a big board
and draw with a pencil and ruler.
Oh? Really?
So, do you kids need something?
C'mon! Hurry and ask!
- M-Me?
- You suggested this!
Fine.
Actually, Kazama-san! We...
...think this is a nice place you have here!
You have fresh air, and you can see Mt. Fuji!
Oh, geez.
We're the Junior Detective League!
Eh?
We're investigating Oki-san's murder!
That's reassuring to hear!
Sure! Ask anything you want, little detectives!
Okay, then. What was your
opinion of the late Oki-san?
Right off the bat, I see.
A rude old man, I suppose.
But I got this job because he
revised the city building ordinance,
so in that sense, I'm thankful to him.
Did you argue with him about
anything during the drafting stage?
Nothing with Oki-san...
You argued with someone else, then?
Eh? No, that's not what I meant...
Oh? That photo...
Oh. He's my son. Cute, isn't he?
I really miss his voice when
I'm working alone at night.
I sometimes call when I know
he's asleep. I'm such a doting father!
C'mon...
Umm, we're the Junior Detective League...
We're investigating Oki-san's...
Children have no place
acting like the authorities!
No, uhh...!
But it would be a shame
to leave empty-handed.
I'll give you something nice as souvenirs.
I appreciate the drawing, but...
We didn't get to ask about the incident.
I guess the police should handle it, huh?
Exactly.
It's 6:00. Let's head home now.
W-What was that sound?!
Oh, just me snoring?
Haibara was on the phone
in the middle of the night?
Remember what Genta-kun
said when we went camping?
I guess she really was on the phone...
But she has no one to call, right?
I trust her.
But there is a small chance
that her fear of the men in black
could've made her join
the organization again...
It's okay, Doc. There's no need to worry. Later!
Hey! You're all early!
Good morning, Conan-kun!
- What took so long?!
- We've been waiting!
Haibara-san wants to visit Hara-san, too!
Eh? Oh.
What's wrong with that?
I'm interested in his video games, too.
Room 407. This is Hara-san's apartment!
Huh? The door's open...
That's careless of him!
Hara-san! We're here!
C-Conan-kun! Hara-san is!
Police and ambulance!
He was shot in the chest!
He died almost instantly!
A knife?!
He was about to have cake?
An O-choko cup!
Which means it was the same killer!
Well, Examiner?
We'll need to do an autopsy to be sure,
but he died between yesterday
afternoon and yesterday evening.
It appears he was about to
have some chocolate cake.
Then, when the killer entered,
he tried to fight with his silver knife...
But what should we think
about this O-choko cup?
Isn't it obvious? It's a serial
murder committed by Mr. Oki's killer.
It's now likely the O-choko cups
are not the victims dying messages,
but rather messages from the killer.
Hey there, kid!
Are you done already, Tome-san?
Yeah. Say, I hear you
were the ones who found him?
Yeah. It was a shock.
Oh, is that the O-choko cup?
That's right.
Huh? There's no blood on it.
Say, Tome-san. Is that all of the cup?
Of course! Nothing escapes Tome the Examiner!
Bye, now!
Now is it clear it's not them?
They'd never leave those behind.
After conducting an autopsy,
we know his approximate time of death.
Yesterday evening, between 5:00 and 6:00.
Also, all of Mr. Hara's
computer data had been erased.
It's possible that was the motive.
Mr. Kisaragi was with
Conan-kun and his friends
between 5:00 and 6:00, so he's in the clear.
On the other hand, Mr. Kazama
could've driven there in time
after Conan-kun and the others left.
What about Mio-kun?
Neither Tokiwa-san nor
Sawaguchi-san has a clear alibi.
I'm sorry, Mouri-kun, but I think the killer is
Tokiwa Mio-san, Kazama Hidehiko,
or Sawaguchi Chinami-san.
And it's very possible that
these incidents will continue.
So Inspector Megure suggested
postponing the party this Saturday,
but she wouldn't listen.
Not only that, she gave me this to give to you.
This is an invitation to the party...
And Conan-kun, the children,
and I are all listed, too!
Eh?! Us too?!
Honestly! What is she thinking?
Boss!
This the place?
The manager confirmed her picture.
To think she holed up in this dump
to hide from the organization...
The rent was paid an entire year in advance,
and nobody ever answers the phone.
The neighbors say messages
get left on it sometimes,
but strangely enough,
when I checked the machine...
...There were no messages recorded.
Eh?! Y-Yes. What's that all about?
Women will be women.
There's a computer in the car. Go get it.
The organization's phone-tracing program.
With this, we can trace calls in 20 seconds.
Gotcha!
Hello, this is Miyano. I'm not home right now.
Please leave your name
and message after the beep.
Sister? It's me.
I'm going to the Twin Tower
Building's opening party...
Unable to trace
Kudo-kun...
So you were calling your sister.
The phone in the apartment
she used when she was alive.
Now I see! You wanted
to talk to your late sister.
I can imagine how you feel,
but it's too dangerous...
No one knows how I feel!
- Hey, Haibara!
- Hold on!
Let her be for now.
Damn! Just a few more
seconds and we would've had it!
Boss!
Hello, this is Miyano. I'm not
home right now. Please leave...
She erased the message!
You don't think she knows we're here, do you?!
No, that's not it. She erased the
message so no one will hear it later.
Never in her dreams would she
think we're sitting next to the phone,
listening in on her.
Think she'll call again?
I doubt it.
But it sounds like the heavens
are offering us their support!
The Twin Tower Building's opening party...
I'll finally get to see it, Sherry.
Your cold, dead face...
I'm sorry about last night.
I knew it was dangerous, too.
I knew I had to stop at some point.
Even so, whenever I would
feel especially alone or afraid,
I would pick up the phone without thinking...
Just to hear those 10 seconds
of my sister's voice...
Don't be stupid. You're not alone.
I figured it was about time
to call it quits, so I'll stop.
Don't worry. I deleted the message.
But lately, I wonder who I am...
I wonder who I am, and where I belong...
I have no place to be.
Eh?! You have no place?!
What're you talking about, Haibara?
You have a seat right there!
This is mine!
This is my place!
And this is mine!
See? I told you you're not alone.
Central Surveillance Room
C'mon! Where's the spoiled rich girl?!
She said she's on her way.
I can't wait for the party!
- I bet there'll be a lot of food!
- I want boxed eel lunches!
I don't think they'll have that.
Say. Do you think Hara-san,
the managing director,
could've been working with the men in black?
It's possible.
They've been bringing in
promising young people from all fields,
including politicians, businessmen,
doctors, scientists, and more.
Even Councilman Oki?
He didn't have much power,
but maybe when he was younger.
In any case, once inside the organization,
whoever tries to leave or betray
it can expect a death sentence.
Just like how they're trying to kill me.
In which case,
if the killer is one of those four...
Yeah.
There's a good chance they're
connected with the organization, too.
Hi! Sorry for the wait!
Sonoko! What happened to your hair?!
It's an image change!
I decided to take after her and try a wave!
Well? Does it look good on me?
Huh?! It looks like you wanna say something!
N-No, I don't!
Oh! Fallen for Sonoko-san, have you?!
Are you serious, Conan?!
I-It's not like that...
Maybe I should try that, too...
Inspector! We should go to the party, too!
No! Seeing as Tokiwa-san said no,
all we can do is wait here!
All we can do now is pray nothing happens...
Wow! Caviar, foie gras, duck!
This is too much!
- I think I'll have some, too!
- No. You'll have Japanese food.
I'll get you some low-calorie dishes.
She acts like a wife...
I'm always starving because of her.
This car's so cool!
It's a Ford Mustang convertible!
But how'd they get something so big in here?
They probably put it together in here.
No, they used a freight elevator.
Freight elevator?
We have one in our apartment building!
It's bigger than normal ones,
so dressers are easy to handle!
Could it hold an elephant too, then?!
I think so...
I don't think anyone has a pet elephant.
It's so pretty!
"If Shin'ichi were here to see
this beautiful view with me,
I'd be in such bliss!"
Right?
Oh, whatever.
I had wanted Mt. Fuji to be
viewable from that building too,
but the constituents wouldn't allow it.
Oh, right. You can't see Mt. Fuji from Tower B.
Thank you all for attending this,
the grand opening party
of the Twin Tower Building!
I would like to start
things off with a little game.
A game that takes after the name
of my late father Tokiwa Kanenari
and the 30 years of the Tokiwa Group!
A 30-second guessing game!
Just like the one you thought up!
Whoever counts 30 seconds
exactly or gets the closest
will receive the Mustang
convertible on display there!
- Awesome!
- A car!
- It's a foreign convertible!
- That's so cool!
However, if there are two winners,
rock-paper-scissors will take place,
and the loser will have to
tolerate a mountain bike and a helmet!
- I'd rather have the mountain bike!
- Me too!
We can't drive cars!
- Alright, Mitsuhiko!
- We have Ayumi-chan with us!
Victory is as good as ours!
Where could Conan-kun be?
I ask those of you playing the game
to let us hold on to your watches.
They'll be returned shortly with
gems that suit them perfectly!
Wow! Gems!
The Tokiwa zaibatsu doesn't mess around...
Here we are!
Take a flag if you put one in!
Here you are!
- Here you are!
- No, I'm okay!
Same here.
I have no watch, nor any desire to play games.
Now, then! Could the children
please come up to the front!
Huh? Conan and Haibara aren't playing?
Now let's begin!
Once you've counted 30 seconds
from her mark, raise your flag!
Bring it on!
Ready... Start!
- 8. 9. 10.
- 15. 16.
21. 22. 23.
- 7. 8. 9.
- 8. 9. 10.
- 6... 7... 8...
24. 25. 26. 27...
Oh no! I lost count!
Here!
- Here!
Uh oh! I'll have to go when someone else does!
Here!
- Done!
- That blue flag there!
Congratulations! You're the grand prize winner!
Dad!
Are you serious?!
It's you, Mouri-senpai! Come right up!
Excuse me!
Everyone! This is the great
detective, Mouri Kogoro-san!
Could you say a little something?
Now I can say goodbye to the rental car life!
Oh, Dad...
- I got it wrong...
- I was still on 25...
I was on 12.
Great. Then I'd be delighted...
Excuse me. Kazama-san, if you would...
Excuse me.
And now, for the works of today's main guest,
our country's master Japanese-style painter,
Kisaragi Hohsui-sensei!
Kisaragi-sensei deeply loves Mt. Fuji,
and has painted its majestic
figure for over 30 years!
And this time, he's donated his
latest work to celebrate the opening
of the Twin Tower Building,
owned by his pupil, Tokiwa Mio!
I present to you, "Mt. Fuji in the Spring Snow"!
Is that...?!
What?!
M-Ma'am!
Damn!
Get her down! Lower Mio-kun down!
And shut the curtains!
Right!
It's too late...
Piano wire in her pearl necklace?!
The piano wire leads up there?!
That's...
...an O-choko cup!
Could it be?! Is this also...?!
Say what?! Tokiwa Mio-san?!
- Let's go!
- Yes, sir!
The picture of Mt. Fuji...
You can even see Fuji at night here.
So this is what she meant?
Basically, this piano wire hook
was attached to Mio-kun's necklace.
The wire went over the catwalk,
so when the painting was lowered,
she was pulled up.
I see. Who else was on the stage then?
Just me and Kisaragi-sensei.
Then please stand where you were.
Chiba-kun, you stand where Tokiwa-san was.
Yes, Sir.
These lights were our markers.
The middle was Mio-san's.
I was over here.
Meanwhile, you were in the
stage wing, Sawaguchi-san?
Yes. I was in charge of lowering
and raising the painting...
And the pearl necklace?
She said it was a present from someone,
but I don't know who...
When was this picture brought here?
Last night. I brought it in here in
the presence of Kisaragi-sensei.
Meaning the piano wire
would've been most easily set by...
I'm afraid I don't know
what you're talking about.
Come to think of it, Kisaragi-san.
I hear you were mad that
Mio-kun bought all your paintings up
and then sold them at high prices.
I hardly think that would be
cause to murder someone!
But, from what you said earlier,
this appears to be a serial murder...
If so, seeing as I have an alibi
for the second murder, it can't be me.
We never showed
Kisaragi-san the last two O-choko cups,
so he couldn't have known to
leave a similar one here to fool us.
Umm...
Just after the lights went out,
I did sense someone approach
Mio-san and say something.
- Really?!
- Was it a man or a woman?!
I did get a quick whiff of perfume...
Yes! I was the one who talked to her!
But I only went to
double-check things with her...
Aha!
Inspector! I know who did it!
Eh?!
The killer is you, Sawaguchi Chinami-san!
N-No! How can you say that?!
Sawaguchi-san.
I'm told your father was a reporter
with a strong sense of justice,
and that he was always chasing
after politicians wrong doings.
After he died, you went to work for Tokiwa,
and became the president's secretary.
However, during the construction
of the Twin Tower Building,
wrongdoings took place.
Mio-kun and Hara-san got together,
handed Councilman Oki money,
and asked him to revise
the city building ordinance.
Having inherited your father's
character, you couldn't forgive that.
So you killed all three of them!
N-No!
But, Mouri-kun.
I thought there weren't
any connections between her
and the O-choko cups left at each crime?
No, Inspector! "O-choko" is
written as "mouth of the boar"!
Sawaguchi-san was born
in the year of the "boar,"
and has "mouth" in her name!
In short, she left the shattered
O-choko cups at the scenes as messages
of the crushing anger she
inherited from her father!
Oh! Brilliant!
It all fits, and you're not even asleep!
That's nothing but a
skillfully-forced interpretation.
Say what?!
After all, this latest O-choko wasn't shattered!
If she wanted to express her crushing anger...
Shut up, you!
Oww!
You seem to be having a hard time.
If you know something, say so!
I don't know.
All I can say is that Mio-san
must've been very drunk at the time.
Eh?
Otherwise, don't you think she
would've noticed when the piano wire
was hooked to her necklace?
A pearl! What's it doing here?!
Wait a minute! Could it be...?!
Kazama-san! I didn't do anything! Right?!
No, it was too dark to see anything...
If that person is the killer, then...
Now I see! This was the motive!
But, if so, then that incident...
Ah! So that's what that meant!
I've figured it all out!
The whole picture of all
three mysterious incidents!
W-What's that?!
- What's this shaking?!
- An earthquake?
What on earth is happening?!
- Explosions?!
- What?!
Where at?!
The B4 electric room and
the 40th floor computer room!
- The computer room?!
- Eh?!
Kazama-san! Tokiwa's main computer is in there!
All our essential data will be destroyed!
A fire has also broken out
from the rear of the 40th floor!
Please evacuate the building immediately!
Right!
Inspector! It sounds like
we should evacuate at once!
If the electric room's blown up,
emergency power's been cut too!
Then the elevators don't work, either?!
No.
Wait! The observation elevator might work!
Really?!
It has a different power source
in case VIPs need to evacuate!
It works!
- What's the maximum occupancy?
- 9 adults.
It'll take too long to get everyone out!
Are there any other escape routes?!
If you take the emergency
stairs down to the 60th floor,
you can cross the bridge to get into Tower B!
Okay! The women, children, and
elderly will take the elevator down!
Everyone else will take the emergency stairs!
What's the situation?!
The electric room exploded, and
the sprinklers and such don't work!
- The fire doors?!
- Closed!
Can we get to that bridge from Tower B?!
There's a direct elevator!
Alright! Teams A and B to the electric room!
Team C and I will cross the
bridge from the other building
and go to the 40th floor!
Yes, sir!
Go on, Conan-kun!
You get on first, Ran-neechan.
Just go!
Over the weight limit!
Conan-kun!
I'll be fine! I'll take the next one!
Please go now!
The remaining women,
Conan-kun, and Kisaragi-san
will take the next elevator down!
I will take the stairs.
But, aren't you?
Don't treat me like a senior citizen!
Right! As you wish!
Alright, Kazama-san. Please go ahead.
Alright, everyone! I'll lead the way!
Please follow me!
Shiratori-kun, you guys go, too.
I'll catch up with you later.
All right!
Doc, I hate to ask, but...
Alright. Got it.
Huh?
I'm sorry!
- Go ahead!
- But...
We'll be fine!
We'll use the bridge on the 60th
floor to go to the next building!
See you at the bottom!
Go on, now!
Thank you, children!
Oh no! It's pitch dark!
I can't tell where anything is!
Hey! Now what? We gave
them our Wristwatch Lights earlier...
Oh! This is bad!
Honestly, now. You should've
thought of that before getting off.
Oh, yeah! You and Conan-kun
didn't participate in the game!
Let's hurry, then!
Hold on. Can't we just
wait for the next elevator?
You're so dumb. The next one will be full, too.
In any case, let's hurry to the 60th floor!
Here we go!
The scale and timing of
these explosions were planned.
Could the men in black
have planted the bombs?!
If so, I can imagine why they
blew up the computer room...
But why the electric room?
Get on, please!
You, too, Chinami-san.
We can talk in detail later.
All right.
To keep the sprinklers from
activating? Or some other purpose?
Good thing this elevator
has its own power source!
Otherwise, we'd have to
go down all those stairs!
C-Could it be?!
Gin!
Rest in peace, Sherry!
Sonoko-neechan! Your panties are showing!
What?! What?! Why are we stopped?!
It's someone else?
The laser point is gone!
Did he realize it's the wrong person?!
It's no use! It won't move!
- Ran-neechan! Lift me on your shoulders!
- Eh?! Right!
There you go!
Conan-kun! Let me do it!
You can do it, Ran-neechan!
Please!
Way to go, Ran!
- What floor is this?
- The 45th.
This floor has a bridge!
Oh no! Smoke!
Let's run across the bridge
to the next building!
It's me. Any luck there?
No, only the men are coming across.
She probably stayed up above
after realizing what we're after,
but she won't get away.
Drop the bridges!
Everyone! We can cross to
the next building from here!
Look! There's the bridge!
Look out, Conan-kun!
- What happened?!
- The bridges just fell!
Mouri-san! The observation elevator is stopped!
What?!
Ran!
Ran! Are you alright?!
We're okay!
What do we do now, Conan-kun?
This is bad! Our escape routes are cut off!
Eh?!
The other side of the fire
door is filled with smoke!
No...
Now what?
The battery ran out.
It's dangerous to move about recklessly.
Let's wait here for help.
Are you all right, Conan-kun?
Ran-neechan! You're not thinking of?!
I don't know if it'll work
like in the movies, but...
Hold on tight, Conan-kun!
Oh! It's Ran-san!
What?! Gimme those!
W-What is she planning to do?!
Ran-neechan, you're not scared?
I'm scared!
But you're with me,
and Shin'ichi told me to wait for him...
I have to live so I can wait for him...
Conan-kun, I'm...
It'll be okay, Ran-neechan!
I know how you feel, so much that it hurts...
Oh no! The hose is on fire!
Are you okay, Conan-kun?!
Y-Yeah! You're awesome, Ran-neechan!
Mouri-san!
Ran!
- Sonoko!
- Thank goodness you're alright!
Geez! Just had to act crazy!
Look out!
Look! The observation elevator!
Doc! Where is that person?!
Eh? Oh, sorry! I lost sight of them!
And I don't see the children, either!
What?!
Ayumi! Genta! Mitsuhiko! Do you read me?!
We read you, Conan-kun!
Where are you?!
Actually, right in front
of the 60th floor bridge...
What?!
They're up there?!
Takagi-kun! Call an emergency helicopter!
Y-Yes, sir!
Mister! I'm borrowing your flashlight!
Little boy! Stop!
What the...?!
- That sound!
- It's his skateboard!
Conan?!
Oww!
You're awesome!
You're so cool!
You're our savior!
Geez! This is no time to be impressed!
What the...?!
Conan-kun's skateboard!
Conan-kun just jumped
across the 60th floor bridge!
What?!
Megure!
Inspector! We're going up to the top!
Have the chopper land on the roof!
"We"?! Where are you?!
Going up 15 floors is tough...
Hang in there, Genta-kun! We're almost there!
Y-Yeah...
You guys go on ahead.
Eh? Where are you going, Conan-kun?
Hey! Where are you going? Hey!
What's the deal?
You know how Conan-kun is!
He must have an idea!
Let's go on up to the roof!
L-Let me think for a second!
Someone's in here!
The person who murdered Oki-san and Mio-san.
He decided to kill Mio-san for a certain reason,
so he gave her a pearl necklace as a present.
He told her to wear the
necklace at the opening party
and show the painting he
gave as a gift to her on stage.
Then the killer is!
Yes. Mio-san's Japanese painting instructor...
...Kisaragi Hohsui-san!
As I recall, you're...
...Edogawa Conan. A detective.
The necklace you gave Mio-san
was made to come undone easily.
And you had prepared another necklace.
During the party, you took that necklace out,
and hooked it to the piano wire hook
hanging from the painting of Mt. Fuji
and hidden along a curtain fold.
Next, using the light on the floor,
you walked up to Mio-san
and undid her necklace.
To the flustered Mio-san,
you said, "It's okay. I'll get it for you."
And then you put the other
necklace around her neck...
...the piano wire necklace.
In other words...
The hook wasn't attached to Mio-san's necklace.
The necklace had a hook on it from the start.
That's why she never noticed it.
This pearl I picked up fell off
when you took the first necklace off.
The O-choko cup on the stage
was purposely left there
to make it look like a serial murder.
Hold on. Kisaragi-san has
an alibi for Hara-san's murder.
Of course he does.
Because someone else murdered Hara-san.
The fire's reached the 70th floor!
Come on! Where's that emergency chopper?!
I'll check, sir!
Conan-kun...
That night, after we left,
you went to Hara-san's apartment to kill him.
But...
... Hara-san was already dead, shot in the chest.
Thinking quickly,
you disguised it as a serial murder,
in order to create an alibi for yourself.
Because with serial murders,
if you have an alibi for one incident,
you're no longer a suspect.
So you broke your O-choko cup there,
just like with Oki-san.
When you did, some of the
fragments fell on the dried blood.
That's why none of the fragments
in Tome-san's bag had blood.
And, in the photo from the scene
of Oki-san's murder in the hotel,
only the lower part of the
closet was covered in blood.
It was probably because a wall scroll
you painted was hanging there.
You gave Oki-san that wall scroll
as a pretense to visit his room
and catch him off guard.
That's quite the interesting theory,
little detective.
But your theory has no...
I do have proof. Right inside that cane.
The first necklace Mio-san was
wearing should be hidden inside!
How did you know I hid it in here?
The sound.
The sound of the cane slightly
differed before and after Mio-san died.
Truly the ears of a detective.
Oh! Here it comes!
But what was his motive?
Because Mio-san bought all his
paintings and sold them for a lot?
No. His motive was most
likely the Twin Tower Building.
As for the reason you killed
Oki-san and tried to kill Hara-san...
At some point, all of your Mt. Fuji paintings
were of the same angle and composition.
You painted them from the same location, yes?
From a small hill I found on
the outskirts of West Tama City.
For decades, I visited
that hill to do my paintings.
But as I grew older, climbing
the hill became more difficult.
So, three years ago, I bought the
entire hill and built a house there
so I could paint Mt. Fuji
for the rest of my life.
I built my workroom in the very best spot.
From that window,
I had a grand view of Mt. Fuji.
And then that woman destroyed it!
Then, does that mean those
broken cups represented Mt. Fuji?
Yeah. They were his messages of anger
that the Twin Tower Building
had split Mt. Fuji in two.
But the cup wasn't broken
when Mio-san was killed!
That was left to make it
look like a serial murder,
and there was no reason
to leave the message there.
Because Mio-san had already
split the painting of Mt. Fuji in two.
Seeing as the necklace
evidence has been discovered,
I won't be able to talk my way out of this.
Sorry. As a detective, I can't allow you to die.
Hey! Down here!
How did you figure out
Kisaragi Hohsui's motive?
It'd been bugging me ever
since we went to his house.
When we arrived at Asahino Station,
I saw the Twin Tower Building
split Mt. Fuji behind Mitsuhiko.
And Kisaragi-san's house was
in the exact opposite direction.
But the large window in his
workroom was covered by curtains.
So he didn't want people to see
his view of Mt. Fuji was obstructed...
- But there's one other thing.
- Hara-san's killer, right?
This is only conjecture,
but he was holding a silver knife.
In Japanese, silver is "gin."
Look.
When "gin" is on a liquor bottle,
it's pronounced differently.
Gin!
Gin most likely had a gun pointed at Hara-san,
who quickly picked up a knife on the table.
Even Gin would've assumed he
was going to use it to put up a fight...
...never realizing it was actually a message.
Hara-san was working with them?
Yeah. He probably broke into
their computers and stole secret data.
That's why they killed him,
deleted all of his computer data,
and blew up the Tokiwa main computer,
where he may have copied it.
So that's what happened...
Oh no! The battery ran out!
I'll go up and get someone
to help carry Kisaragi-san!
You wait here!
- Yay!
- We're saved!
There's no wind! It should be all right now!
Come back, guys! Hurry!
W-Who would do this?!
That should keep the helicopter away.
Even if they wait around
for the fire to stop, it'll still be...
...time up.
I'm pooped...
What's going on with this building?!
We'll just have to wait for
the fire on the roof to stop now.
I don't think we'll have the time for that.
A bomb?!
They're under all the tables. The timer is...
Only four minutes left!
Damn! They're going to
blow up the party room last
so it's not clear who they were after!
Ran...
Hurry!
Captain! They're not reaching!
Damn! It's no good!
Wait a minute! That roof!
Yes! The key's here!
I get it! We're going to use this
car to jump to the next building!
It won't work.
The buildings are 50 meters apart.
60 if we're jumping across.
There's a 20 meter height
difference with the other building.
On Earth, an object can
move horizontally at one speed,
but due to gravity, it will increase
vertical velocity at a specific rate.
The equation for a 20-meter fall
is t equals the square root of 2s over g.
T being the time,
g the acceleration due to gravity,
or 9.80665 m/s per second.
S is the distance fallen: 20 meters.
Plug these numbers in,
and you get 2.02 seconds.
In other words, it would take
about 2 seconds to fall 20 meters.
We have to travel 60 meters
in 2 seconds. Meaning...
...30 meters in 1 second,
or 108 kilometers per hour.
Given this room's size, we can
get up to 50 or 60 kph at most.
We'd plummet before
reaching the other building...
...but what if we did this?
Y-You're not thinking of going with the blast?!
Huh? What?! What're you talking about?!
Conan-kun is thinking of using the blast
from the explosion to fly further out!
What?!
We're gonna die if we wait anyway!
Let's do it!
- Let's do it, Conan-kun!
- Let's do it!
Let's do it super-flashy!
The key to success will be in the timing.
The bombs have to go off just as
the car breaks through the window
or it'll lose speed and plummet straight down.
Yeah. The problem is you
can't see the timer from the car.
My watch's battery ran out, too...
In that case, we have Ayumi-chan!
She might be able to count 30 seconds exactly!
But she got it wrong just a while ago...
Oh.
What do you think, Ayumi-chan? Can you do it?
I-I'm not very confident, but...
if you're with me, Conan-kun...!
Eh?!
I think I can do it, if you're by my side!
Ayumi...
In that case, how about I stay by
the timer and count until 30 seconds
and then get in the car?
There's no time to think! Let's go with that!
What?! There are bombs in the party room?!
Have them open the dome roof right away!
- The roof?!
- Just hurry!
Kazama-san!
Hello?! It's me! Open the dome
roof immediately! Right away!
Pardon me!
What are you doing, Conan-kun?!
Ran-neechan, I'm coming there now.
- Just hurry!
- Hello?! Conan-kun?!
Alright!
55. 54.
53. 52.
51. 50.
49. 48.
47. 46. 45.
44. 43.
42. 41.
40. 39. 38.
37. 36.
35. 34. 33.
32. 31.
30!
29!
28!
Haibara-san!
What's going on?!
It's Haibara-san! She won't stop counting!
What?!
Haibara! What're you doing?! Get over here!
Don't be dumb. This way is more accurate.
Don't tell me she's planning to
stay behind and sacrifice herself?!
21!
20!
What are you doing?!
My mom said it's bad luck to
waste even one grain of rice!
11!
10!
9! 8!
- Here!
- 7!
- 6! 5!
- Here we go!
Haibara-san!
I absolutely won't let go!
Oh no! At this rate
she'll run into those pillars!
I'm borrowing this!
Conan-kun!
Ran-neechan!
We're okay!
Yay!
Say, Conan-kun! Where did you learn to drive?!
My old man taught me in Hawaii...
Boss, there were five kids
and an old man in the car.
It appears she never came to the party.
No matter.
We accomplished our original objective.
Yes. But to think he'd betray us
and sneak into the organization's computers...
Got it, boss!
The Twin Tower Building in
West Tama City's where the hacker is!
It must be Hara's doing after all.
We took care of Hara,
and blew up Tokiwa's main computer.
The organization's
information won't leak outside now.
I had hoped to use that
building as her execution grounds,
but I'll save that fun for another time.
I can't believe
Kisaragi-san was behind it all...
It's a shock...
You think? I suspected him from the very start!
This is probably as far as
the police will investigate.
Yeah. They'll likely never find
out Gin murdered Hara-san, either.
And the truth about the
bombing will remain in the dark...
Thank you for earlier. You saved me.
No, I only did my duty as a man!
You too, Kojima-kun.
So I'm the same as a grain of rice?
Still, Ayumi! How did you
get 30 seconds exactly again?!
Just luck!
The truth is, it's thanks to you, Conan-kun!
When you're by my side, I get excited
and I can count time using my heartbeat!
Come to think of it, the first
time you counted 30 seconds...
28! 29! 30!
So that's why you wanted me with you...
You were so cool, Mitsuhiko-kun!
Oh, uhh...
You too, Genta-kun!
Yeah?!
- Hey! What're you gonna do now?
- What do you mean?!
If you make Yoshida-san cry,
I'll make you regret it!
Hey, now!
Hey, wait! Don't tell me this car is...?!
That's right! The Mustang
convertible you won as a prize!
My dream car...
No, wait! Maybe it could be
usable again if I dry it out!