Damn, got passed again.
If you were going to rent a car, you
might as well have rented a better one.
I agree.
It would've been better if we took the train, wouldn't it?
Yeah.
Shut up!
It was the client who told me to bring you guys with me!
I had to rent a car big enough to hold you all!
Five seconds left...
If you don't turn the steering wheel...
You'll crash into the wall in five seconds.
What!?
It's amazing!
It's like a castle!
Then, maybe a king lives here?
Don't be stupid.
Of course not, it's just a hotel.
Well, it's right in front of Miracle Land.
So if rich people living like kings were to get
together at this hotel, it wouldn't be surprising.
Oh yeah, I've heard this hotel will
welcome its 100,000th guest soon, right?
Doing pretty well, aren't they?
So it seems.
Uhm, excuse me, but...
Are you Detective Mouri?
Oh, yes.
We have been awaiting you.
I am your client's secretary, Takada.
It's a bit sudden, but please come this way.
You, take care of their car.
Yes.
Please, this way.
Awesome!
You can see all of Miracle Land from over there!
Oh, I'm sorry.
Please sit and wait in these seats.
C'mon, be quiet and sit down.
Yeah...
Man...
Well then, please wait a moment.
Wow, I'm so excited.
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
Somehow, this chair doesn't seem to match this room.
Come to think of it, that's true.
Maybe they ran outta money!
There's no way that's true.
It's a high class hotel after all.
Sorry to have kept you waiting.
These are why we asked the children to come along too.
What exactly is this?
These are Miracle Land's Free Pass IDs.
While Mouri-san is working...
We thought it'd be nice to let you kids have fun at Miracle Land.
Could it be that the client is the owner of this place?
No, it's nothing like that.
We're renting this suite on an annual basis.
Wow, that's pretty impressive.
All right, everyone please put them on your wrists.
Tightly, so they don't fall off.
If you lose any of them, we can't issue you another one.
Mouri-san, go ahead.
It's OK, I won't be going to the amusement park.
Don't say that.
If you finish your work early,
you'll be able to have fun with everyone.
I guess so.
These IDs can only be used today...
Until 10:00 PM, Miracle Land's closing time.
All meals and drinks are free.
Please have as much as you'd like.
All right!
Thank you very much.
Let's go, Conan-kun.
We would please like you to stay.
I'm very sorry.
Why?
Is he the 100,000th guest at this hotel or something?
Well, something like that.
Are you serious?
So nice...
Well, let's go ahead and get in line.
I've heard the normal wait for
the Super Snake is around two hours.
That's right.
Then, Conan-kun, we'll see you later.
Hey, I wonder what the 100,000th guest wins.
At least we know it's not an eel rice bowl.
Man, aren't you lucky?
For the 100,000th guest...
There's probably an awesome prize.
We don't want to be interrupted.
Interrupted?
I'm not really the 100,000th guest, am I?
There's confetti already on the ground in front of the hotel.
Oh, really?
Yes.
The 100,000th guest came about an hour ago.
Then, why'd you make him stay?
That's what the client wants.
Hey, what's this?
What's going on?
Thank you for coming.
I am your client.
Please forgive me, but circumstances
do not permit me showing my face.
The reason I called you here today is because
there is a case I would like you to solve.
What kind of case?
Figuring that out is also a part of your job.
I will give you a series of hints.
Use them as a basis for your reasoning and solve the case.
But, why'd you choose me?
You are the fifth detective that I've hired.
Then, what about the other four?
One is investigating.
Two quit.
The last one could not solve the case...
So he remains here.
Ryuu!
You know him?
He's a detective that I've worked with before.
I gave you the investigation report, didn't I?
How long do you plan to keep me locked up in here?
Let me out!
Detective Ryuu, you were unable to solve the case.
What'd you say?
Incompetent detectives have no right to live.
What's this?
That ID is the same as ours.
Yeah.
Damn!
What's with this?
It's all right, it won't hurt a bit.
You'll be at peace in an instant.
You don't mean...
The one that killed Mogi and Souda...
Goodbye, Detective Ryuu.
Hey, wait...
Wait a second...
Damn it...
Composition Four.
In other words, there were plastic explosives built in...
To the Miracle Land ID that Detective Ryuu was wearing.
Hey, Ryuu just said that Mogi and Souda were...
Yes.
Those two detectives were renowned all around the world.
But they were just fools who wasted my valuable time.
The time-limit for you is 10:00 PM tonight.
Find the truth behind this case before then.
If you cannot solve the case by the deadline...
Your IDs will also explode and you'll
follow in Detective Ryuu's footsteps.
What!?
I would stop.
The ID won't come off by just pulling at it.
And if you do manage to remove it
before I deactivate it, it will explode.
Damn you...
Ran...
Right!
What about Ran and the others' IDs!?
The children's IDs are almost the same as yours.
What'd you say!?
Almost?
Their IDs have an additional feature.
This is a rough sketch of Miracle Land.
There are multiple sensors positioned around the premises.
When their IDs enter Miracle Land, the sensors
will detect it and the detonator will activate.
If they pass by the sensors again to exit
Miracle Land, their IDs will detonate.
To follow them each individually would have proven troublesome.
That's why I implemented this.
Ran!
Haibara!
Can you hear me, Haibara!?
Damn it...
Haibara!
What?
Haibara, don't go inside!
What's wrong?
That doesn't matter, just don't!
Stay out of there!
But even if you say so...
I'm already inside.
You're a VIP, right?
We only give those IDs to special guests.
Is that so?
Please have fun.
Thank you very much.
Did something happen?
I'll contact you again later.
Ran?
Damn!
If by 10:00 PM tonight you solve the case...
And uncover the true criminal...
I'll pay you however much you wish.
However...
If you cannot solve the case in time, I'll detonate all of the IDs.
Take me to where that man is, right now!
That's impossible.
Even I don't know where he is.
What'd you say!?
Mouri-san...
All of your actions are being monitored.
There's a GPS built into your ID.
It'll do you no good to run to the police.
You're saying you'll press the detonation switch?
Damn you!
This kind of talk is a waste of time.
The first hint:
I will only say this once so listen carefully.
TAKA 3 - 8.
What's that mean!?
Say it again!
I told you I would only say it once.
There are 12 hours left until the time limit.
So, will you solve this mystery?
For my sake...
And the children's?
Damn...
Mouri-san...
Please take this.
It's a hotline to the client.
Actually, you can't call him directly.
It's only for receiving instructions from him.
If you solve the case...
Call me using the number in this cell phone, and then return here.
And then, we can carefully listen to the truth.
I'm high-school detective, Kudou Shinichi.
While visiting an amusement park with my
childhood friend and classmate, Mouri Ran...
I witnessed a man in black in the midst of a suspicious transaction.
While caught up in watching the deal...
I failed to notice his partner sneaking up behind me.
That man forced me to swallow poison...
And when I came to...
My body had shrunk.
If those guys found out that Kudou Shinichi was still alive...
They'd come after me again and put those around me at risk.
At Professor Agasa's suggestion, I decided to conceal my true identity.
When Ran asked for my name, in that instant...
I became Edogawa Conan.
In order to obtain information on those guys...
I went to live with Ran, whose father is a private detective.
Those who know my true identity are...
Professor Agasa...
My parents...
The High School Detective of the West, Hattori Heiji...
And my classmate, Haibara Ai.
Professor Agasa has crafted many inventions for my reduced self.
Haibara was once a member of the Black Organization, but...
In order to escape them, she took the same drug that shrunk me...
And her body shrunk.
And finally, there's one more...
Kaitou Kid.
Whenever he shows up, things get troublesome.
Even though I've become smaller, my mind remains the same.
The unbeaten great detective...
There's always only one truth!
Damn!
What's with this traffic jam!?
My daughter's life is on the line!
Get out of the way already!
So make sure you don't leave Miracle Land!
If you leave the area, the IDs will explode!
And of course, stay off the Super Snake!
A part of that roller coaster goes out over the ocean!
Hey, are you listening, Haibara!?
Yeah, I understand.
If you don't solve the case by 10:00 PM...
We'll both be blown to bits, right?
It's interesting, don't you think?
"Interesting?"
You...
Hey, Haibara!
What're you doing?
Hurry over here!
Well, I'll put our lives in your hands...
Mr. Detective.
But I don't get it.
What does this ''TAKA 3 - 8'' mean?
Hey, the dash can be read as "3 no 8", right?
Then, ''TAKA" is a district?
Also, 3—8 equals —5.
If we take away the equals sign, it becomes 3—8—5.
Got it!
Takashima Town!
The third district of Takashima Town, huh?
Hey, which way's the third district?
It's not here.
Huh?
There's no third district in Takashima Town.
What're you saying?
Gimme that!
Damn...
I guess we're back at square one...
Maybe not.
This area's been in redevelopment, so
the districts may have changed, right?
Takashima Town, 3—8—5?
Have the districts changed around here due to the redevelopment?
It became Minatomirai.
There was a third district.
Do you have a map?
Yes.
But do you really think this place is somehow related to the case?
We have to believe it is.
Speaking of which...
Why is he having you, an-elementary school student, assist me?
Maybe he thought you weren't good enough by yourself.
It's definitely strange.
Why did he want just me to work with Uncle?
Why in the world...
What's that!?
Who's there!?
You can't live here, it's gonna be torn down next week.
Must be hard for you as well, with a kid and all.
No, nothing like that!
Of course not.
Mister, have you been living here long?
Yeah.
Since this hotel went bankrupt two years ago.
Has anything out of the ordinary happened lately?
Anything at all?
Lemme see...
Oh, that's right!
A big white bird flew by the other day.
A big bird?
It shot right past me in front of the sun!
When was this?
It was my birthday, April 4th.
On that day, a weird car parked outside in the morning.
And then some real estate agent
came and closed off that basement.
What weird car?
It's weird because there are never cars here.
When I left in the morning, there was a
car that looked new parked in the garden.
But when I came back in the evening, it
had turned into an old second-hand car.
At night, that car had its parts taken and turned into a skeleton.
Why did they close off the basement?
Well, it was the machinery room.
I guess he's gonna sell the machinery and make some money.
About what time was that?,
It was in the evening.
What was that!?
Hey, brat, what happened?
So this is where you were.
Geez, don't scare me like that.
This is...
What's that?
I found this.
What is it?
This is...
A ski mask, gloves...
And a Government pistol?
A receipt?
April 4th, Yokohama Bypass.
Uncle, April 4th...
Isn't that when the weird car was parked outside?
Yeah, he said that the car changed.
It changed?
I got it!
This is where a fugitive changed cars!
Some criminal who did something with
a ski mask and Government pistol.
All that's left is to find out what the case from April 4th is.
If we know that, then the rest will be easy.
Who're those guys?
Guns!
They're definitely not just civilians.
You don't think they've come back for this bag, do you?
It's possible...
All right, I've got it!
You jump out and distract them.
In the meantime, I'll get to the car, save you, and we can get away.
I'm telling you it'll be fine!
When they see you're a kid, they won't just start shooting.
What's with you?
Don't you trust me?
Nope.
Whatever, just go!
Wait up!
Hey!
Get in!
Figures.
Damn, at a time like this!
Stupid second-rate car!
You're under arrest!
Arrest!?
You all are...
Officers?
It's the same as that day, the big white bird...
What?
It's him.
The one who flies through the darkness on his white wings...
It's Kaitou Kid!
Kid?
Inspector, I've located Kid!
Right now, he's on the roof of the
Miyama Building, above the devil statue!
All right, I got it.
President Miyama, Kid has appeared.
I see.
Let's have a look.
Well, even the amazing Kid won't be
able to crack my new security system.
Kid!
Damn!
Yokomizo here.
Kid is flying from the Miyama Building towards Landmark Tower.
I repeat, Kid is flying towards Landmark Tower!
Go after him now!
Looks like the police's stakeout was all for nothing, huh?
This security system's perfect.
Inspector Yokomizo!
We have apprehended one of Kid's accomplices.
We're bringing him to the station.
All right, I'm counting on you.
I've been telling you that I'm not Kid's accomplice!
I'm Mouri Kogorou!
This is bad...
At this rate...
All of your actions are being monitored.
There's a GPS built into your ID.
It'll do you no good to run to the police.
ID Number 1...
ID Number 2...
Now approaching Kanagawa Police Headquarters.
Hearing those voices gets you kind of excited, doesn't it?
But I'm already tired of waiting in line.
I wonder how much longer it'll take.
Let me see...
Since we can say three people in line is one meter...
And since the line's about 150 meters, that means 450 people.
Since 22 people can ride the Super Snake each time...
If there are 450 people, that's about 20 rides.
One ride, including the time to get on and off,
takes about ten minutes, so 200 minutes total.
That means it'll take about three and a half hours.
Amazing, Mitsuhiko-kun!
We still have to wait that long?
I'm so hungry...
If the professor were here, he'd give,us
one of his lame quizzes to kill some time.
I know, right?
In that case, I'll come up with a quiz today.
You will?
I can't?
No, go ahead!
Oh well, I guess I'll just have to answer it.
All right, here we go.
Tada!
Miracle Land Quiz!
Everyone wants to ride the Super Snake at least once.
Out of you all. who's most fit for this attraction?
I've got it!
The answer's Ai-chan, isn't it?
Why?
Because Ai-chan seems like one to like snakes.
I actually hate snakes...
Wrong.
Then it's me, right?
Like the Super Snake, people always make me wait.
What's that about?
When I go to get you for school in the
morning, you always make me wait.
That's wrong, too.
And you, Genta-kun?
Maybe it's me.
Because snakes kind of look like eels...
And I really like eel rice bowls!
So close!
What happens to Genta-kun, since he loves eel rice bowls so much?
Even if you ask me what happens...
It seems like he gets hungry.
I see.
Super Snake in Japanese is 'chou hebi'.
chou hebii
That can mean 'super heavy'.
So, Kojima-kun, with his massive weight, is the correct answer.
Bingo!
I thought that Ran-san would be different, but...
In the end, hers are just as lame.
Kanagawa Police Headquarters
Oh, Conan-kun, are you all right?
Inspector Megure!
What happened to Mouri-kun?
I heard they arrested one of Kid's accomplices?
Oh, Nakamori-kun.
Megure, you rascal...
What are you doing here?
It seems like Mouri-kun's been mistakenly arrested.
So when they said Kid's accomplice...
They meant Sleeping Kogorou?
I have a duty to protect the secrets of my clients.
Didn't I tell you that if Kid is your client, you're an accomplice?
But, why were the Kanagawa Police staking out that building?
Because they received a notice from Kid.
That building is the Miyama Corporation's main office.
On the top floor, President Miyama displays all
of the various jewels he's collected, but...
Unlike the last time he came, nothing was taken.
Did he get in before?
Yeah.
On April 4th, a huge diamond was stolen.
I think the security system has been upgraded, so...
President Miyama's pretty pleased with himself.
April 4th?
But, I thought Yokomizo-kun was in the first division.
Isn't Kid assigned to the second division?
There have been some strange people after Kid's life lately.
Since some officers were injured in the middle of
all of this, the first division joined the investigation.
They're after Kid's life.
Looks like somebody's calling.
Excuse me!
Detective Mouri...
Or, is this Kudou-kun?
So it is you...
High school detective, Kudou Shinichi-kun.
The fact that you came with Detective Mouri surprised me.
I really wanted to have you investigate this as well.
But I didn't know how to contact you.
So you couldn't solve the case and went to the police, huh?
No, we didn't come here on our own.
At the hotel ruins, Detective Mouri was
arrested by five policemen on a stakeout.
Honest, aren't you?
This guy...
Did he know?
That the police were there...
No matter.
So, what was at the hotel?
We found a ski mask and gun used to commit some crime.
Good work, Kudou-kun.
Now, here's your second hint:
Go to the café terrace at night.
The café terrace at night?
You'll know where it is...
If it's really you.
I'll definitely solve this case!
So please disengage Ran and the others' IDs!
Hey, are you listening?
Damn...
The one you love...
Do you know how painful it is to lose the one you love?
Work hard so that you won't have to...
Kudou-kun.
Why?
Why does he know my true identity?
This guy...
Who is this guy really?
The line's not moving, and I'm getting more and more hungry.
Right?
Speaking of which, we haven't had lunch yet, have we?
In that case, I'll stand in line while you-guys-go eat.
Is that really OK, Haibara?
But I feel bad for leaving Ai-chan here alone.
I guess...
Then, I'll stay with Haibara-san!
I'll stay, too!
Then, me too...
Don't be stupid, at that point there's no reason to do it.
Then let's do this:
We can take turns every thirty minutes.
How about we start with Ai-chan?
Agreed!
Then, I'll see you in thirty minutes.
All right!
Let's go!
Sorry.
Please go on ahead.
I wonder how long I can keep this up...
Yokohama Osanbashi Pier
If I could analyze one, I might be able to figure something out, but...
There's a chance it'd blow up.
I can't do anything here.
I see.
Oh, that's right!
I gave it a power-up.
Thank you!
Have you figured it out?
Where the "café terrace at night'' is?
Yeah.
Where is it?
Café Terrace at Night...
Was painted in 1888 by Vincent van Gogh.
It depicts a dim gas lamp illuminating a café terrace...
Near a street where horse-drawn carriages frequent.
basha
Gas lamps and carriages...
The first place in Japan to be illuminated by gas lamps...
Was Basha Street.
You overpowered it, Professor...
Haibara-san!
Here.
Thank you.
Sorry to keep you all waiting.
We're still here?
I guess my estimation was off.
We'll switch off with you now.
If you would.
You like this stuff, don't you, Ran?
These places geared towards kids.
Sonoko!
What're you doing here?
Look, the Red Castle Hotel.
Here me a party tonight to celebrate their 100,000th guest.
We're here because that hotel was funded by my dad.
So, here I am at this amusement park killing some time.
Hey, where'd you pick that up?
It's not like that!
This is something from one of my dad's clients.
He must be a VIP, then.
I lost my ID so I thought I might've dropped it.
That's right!
I could get you and the kids an invitation to the party, too.
Or better yet, how about just the two of us go to the Red Castle?
These kids have IDs, so they'll be all right.
Especially this one, she seems to be good at holding her own.
But...
Right now, at the restaurant there, they're hosting a cake buffet.
Also, with this ID, you're free to go in and out of Miracle Land.
What is it that could be here?
Don't move.
Hattori!?
How was it?
Were you scared?
You wish.
You got here at a good time.
Lend me your mind for a sec, Kudou.
What, Kudou?
You, too?
Then, you also...
Yeah, Kazuha's a hostage.
But, she has no idea—she's just having
fun at the amusement park right now.
The number you dialed isn't within our service area or isn't currently on.
As such, we are unable to connect you at this time.
Geez, what's up?
He told me to have fun waitin' as he had somethin' to sort out quickly.
I really feel like Ran-chan, the way she's always waitin' for Kudou-kun.
Huh, Kazuha-chan?
Ran-chan, is that you?
Kazuha-chan, it's been such a long time!
So you came here?
Where's Hattori-kun?
Work, W-O-R-K.
I see.
How boring.
Huh, Kazuha-chan?
Sonoko-chan!
We're going to a cake buffet, wanna come?
I really love cake!
Then, let's go.
C'mon Ran, we're going!
Wait!
Basha Street
I see...
So she's been taken hostage as well.
Yeah.
But not just Ran, the four kids, too.
Also:
The client seems to know...
That I'm Kudou Shinichi, somehow.
He knows your real identity?
Well, I'm not sure, but...
Hey...
Could they've figured out about that poison shrinking you?
Those men in black...
Hey!
What's up?
The ski mask, the gun, and the getaway car...
I see!
It was an attack on that armored car!
Yeah!
Is that what he was talking about?
Probably.
Can-I have a minute?
What is it, boy?
Has that armored car ever been attacked?
Yes, it has.
I think it was April 4th.
Since you have a business here, the police
musta questioned ya about it, right?
Would ya mind telling us the details as well?
I think it was about this time...
Don't move.
Stay still.
It all happened in a flash.
I couldn't tell if I was awake or dreaming.
I guess that means it was skillfully done.
Thank you, ma'am.
Wait a second!
You boys...
Today is the worst day of your lives!
You should go home and rest.
Yeah, we'll do that.
Right after we make it the best day of our lives.
See ya.
Don't go running off on your own, I've been looking for you!
Ow...
Now, now, it's not the time to be fighting.
Whys that dark-skinned Osakan brat here?
The same reason as you.
Mouri-kun...
Give me back the client's cell phone!
Don't you think it's time you told us the truth?
Well, even if you say it that way...
There are limits to what a detective can do alone.
Wouldn't it be better to let us handle it from here?
This is Mouri.
It's Detective Mouri this time?
No matter.
You're on Basha Street now?
Yeah.
It isn't good for you to be working with the police.
Damn!
Are you watching us?
That?
Are you trying to break our agreement, Mouri-san?
Definitely not!
This was unavoidable.
Mouri-kun, who're you talking to?
Morons, morons —
the useless police must perish!
What now?
Morons, morons —
the useless police must perish!
Damn it, what's with that statue?
Morons, morons —
the useless police must perish!
Hey, couldn't that be dangerous?
Watch out, get away from that statue!
It's gonna blow!
What?
Ten seconds to explosion.
Nine...
Eight...
Seven...
Six...
Five...
Four...
Three...
Damn!
Two...
One...
Mom!
Yokomizo-kun!
Send an ambulance!
This is an emergency!
Damn you!
Next time, it will be your kids...
Mouri-san.
What's wrong?
This ID, it started flashing a little while ago.
Mine, too.
You know anything about this, Sonoko?
This is my first time seeing this.
You can ask the guard up ahead.
Geez...
The police nowadays can't even see
bombs that are right in front of them.
What'd you say!?
Isn't it your fault this happened!?
Let me go, you have no evidence of that!
Honestly, it's annoying!
Stop following me around!
What!?
I'm glad I left the police.
I wanna live a long life.
You two, let's go.
Inspector, is this all right?
It's fine.
Ran and the children are being held hostage at Miracle Land.
They're wearing IDs on their wrists that will explode if they leave.
Please protect Ran and the others discreetly—Mouri.
I asked the inspector to look after Ran and the others.
Well, whether this turns out for better or worse...
Depends completely on us now, huh?
So, did you get anything?
Yeah.
On April 4th, an armored car was attacked on this street.
Also, Kaitou Kid stole a diamond from the Miyama
Art Museum on that day, according to the police.
I see.
Well, anyway, I'll go on my own from here.
Don't do anything dangerous.
What do you think?
We're likely finished with the hint regarding Basha Street.
What else can be reasoned from this?
Actually, there is more.
A hint we haven't solved.
What?
The hints I got were:
The café terrace at night and YOU CRY.
'Omae wa naku' in Japanese.
He gave you a different hint?
It looks like it.
YOU CRY...
Using the alphabet, it's...
Y-O-U C-R-Y.
Y-O-U is...
Yeah.
The marine university on the outskirts of Yokohama...
Yokohama Kaiyoudai.
Yokohama Ocean University.
What's left is C-R-Y then.
I'm not sure about that either.
I guess we'll have to head over there.
To Y.O.U.
All right then.
Ran, hurry.
Excuse me.
Yes, what do you need?
Uhm, why is this red light on my ID blinking?
We have a message for a customer.
I'm not sure...
Miss Mouri Ran of Beika...
I've never seen one before.
Is that so?
And her friend, Miss Tooyama Kazuha:
If you are here, please report to the medical station immediately.
What could it be?
Maybe something happened to those kids?
We should go.
Sorry, Sonoko.
Can you go on alone?
I'm fine.
You should hurry, something may have happened to the kids.
I'm sorry.
I'll go mope now...
What is it?
She fainted in the park.
It looks like a light fever.
Is that so?
I'm sorry.
Don't worry, it's all right.
But why did you call Kazuha-chan as well?
This is the first time I've spoken to this girl.
Because...
Isn't it obvious?
Having two people by your side is better than one.
Right, right!
She needs to get some rest.
Will you stay with her?
Of course!
Stay with me, always.
I thought she was just cold child, but she's actually cute.
This acting is so tiring...
Cry, cry, cry...
It could be the abbreviation for some class.
Or a club?
Right.
Aside from that...
Yokohama Hanzai Kenkyuukai...
Crime Research of Yokohama.
I think this club is closest to what you're looking for.
Who're you?
I am Hakuba Saguru.
Someone in the same position as you.
In more ways than one.
The same position?
You're a high are detective and the son of a police chief, right?
Yeah.
But I still can't beat you, elementary school detective.
I see.
We have that in common, as my father is the Osaka Police Chief.
That isn't all.
You too?
Someone precious to me is also at Miracle Land.
Well, we can talk while we walk.
"Wasting time is a cry-ing shame."
Waste too much and we'll end up in tears.
I guess so.
Hey, anyone there?
Hey!
Coming in.
There's a lot here.
Hey, look at these pictures.
They look like snaps of their members.
We should photograph these.
I agree.
The client?
Yeah.
What?
You're doing better than I anticipated, Hattori Heiji-kun.
I can't believe 'YOU CRY' has got you this far.
I'm impressed rare you all.
Ya know...
If ya want us to solve this case...
Why don't ya make the hints easier?
If it were easy to solve, it'd be no fun for me.
After all...
I'm testing your respected detective skills...
To see whether or not you're qualified to solve my case.
What now?
There will be no more hints.
I'm counting on you, my young detectives.
Hey, hold on now!
Damn, he hung up.
No hints...
What do we do now?
Oh, you guys...
Is there something you need?
No, we're just...
Coming to this university next year.
We're just looking around.
Well, if you do come here, be sure to join our club!
Why, of course.
Say, Say, miss!
What are those pictures up there for?
Those are photos of the club presidents in chronological order.
Then, why did you take down the third president's photo?
Because look, there are hooks up there beside the last picture.
And you can see slightly lighter patches on the
wall next to each picture from the third to the end.
This is because you took down the third
president's picture for some reason...
And moved the rest of them over one space, right?
Am I wrong?
The third president, Itou-san, was expelled.
Wasn't that Itou Jirou-san?
No, it was Itou Suehiko-san.
Know him?
Well, kinda.
I think...
This is him, right?
No.
This is him.
Oh, is that so?
What an actor...
Sorry.
I guess it's not the Itou-san I know.
Osaka Police Headquarters
Hei-chan, who's this Itou guy?
I dunno, Ohtaki-han—that's why I'm asking you.
Does the chief know?
No, it's secret.
Secret, Hei-chan?
Well, I'll await your call.
Hey, Hei-chan!
Just goin' out for a smoke...
How about having some food at the school cafeteria?
If my blood sugar drops, then so does my thinking speed.
Idiot, dun have time for that.
We're awaitin' a call here.
They say, Warriors have to pretend to have eaten when they cannot".
But they also say, ''One that is hungry
is unable to win the battle at hand".
Besides, I've already figured out what you're waiting on.
Wouldn't you say the Yokohama Police
Headquarters is closer than Osaka's?
This is an annoyin' guy...
Right, that's right.
Next time you're around, I'll take you out.
So I can count on you, Ao-chan?
Please hurry.
Who was that?
Boss!
Was that your cousin Aoki in the Kanagawa police?
Well, it's just been so long since I heard from him...
No need to hide.
It's something for Heizou's son, isn't it?
He called me as well.
What, he called you, too?
You've been tricked, Ohtaki.
Is there something going on with my son?
Chief!
Come with me, we'll discuss the rest in my office.
It'll be easier if you just tell him everything.
Well, see...
This is becoming troublesome.
Well then, I'm counting on all of you.
Inspector Megure!
I'm going to go say hello.
I'll come with you.
He's taken care of Heiji in the past too.
Then, I'm gonna go ride the Super Snake.
See ya later!
Wait a second!
You shouldn't get out of bed!
Go stop him, please!
Got it!
Inspector Megure?
Ran-kun, and Kazuha-kun!
Why're you two here today?
Is there a case?
Oh, no!
I'm on break, just on break with Shiratori-kun is all.
And you two came to Miracle Land together?
Strange...
Huh, Ran-chan?
It's the kids.
Inspector...
This can't be!
That's what you get for trying to sneak out and ride it.
All right, back to the infirmary.
I'm really sorry.
Please bear with us as we undergo a safety inspection.
I'm going to begin giving out postponement tickets now.
Thief!
That man's a thief!
Ayumi-chan!
Ran-kun!
Inspector Megure...
What's he doing here?
Hey, Takagi-kun?
What're you doing?
Oh, no, see...
You were checking out cute girls during our date, weren't you?
No way, l wouldn't not-not do that...
What was that?
I'm not sure what you meant.
Is that right?
I'll just pretend I didn't see the inspector...
This curry looks great!
I'm so hungry!
Eat up.
Delicious!
What's in this curry?
Disgusting!
It's all wheat flour.
So, who's Itou Suehiko?
On April 4th of this year...
Itou was placed on the most wanted list, after he was
thought to have attacked an armored car on Basha Street.
I see.
So that's why the club took his picture down.
That's not the most interesting thing.
After graduating, he owned and operated an investment advice firm.
That firm, Far East Office, was home to a murder case.
What?
See?
Interesting, isn't it?
All right!
Let's go over there now...
To that Far East Office.
Geez, he finished it...
I'm back.
Welcome back, Sensei.
I'm sorry, Kuriyama-san.
But could you possibly get me something cold?
All right.
Yes, this is Kisaki.
Oh, dear?
What is it?
Weren't you supposed to visit Miracle
Land today with Ran and the others?
Wait a second—"case files"?
What're you doing?
A lot's happened.
I'm in quite a mess.
I understand.
The April 4th armored car robbery, correct?
I'll call you when I have something.
Yeah, that would save me.
Dear?
Hey, Eri...
Do you think I can solve this case?
"Investigating takes legwork."
Isn't that right, former officer?
Yeah, that's right!
I'm counting on you!
Yeah, I got it.
Come!
Come in.
Excuse me.
Oh, didn't you just get a phone call?
Yeah, I did...
From someone I really dislike.
Right, Goro-chan?
Her husband, then.
By saying "prohibited"...
They're begging us to enter...
As detectives.
The murder victim was Nishio Masaharu.
He was the Sales Manager at Far East Office.
He was shot by a rifle.
At university, he was a classmate of the company director, Itou.
That means...
Nishio was also a member of the crime research club?
That's right.
Over here.
"Over here"?
Isn't that my cell phone?
When'd you...
Look at this.
The front row in the picture.
In the middle is the club president, Itou Suehiko.
On his left is the one who was murdered, Nishio.
Hey, who's the woman on the other side of Itou-san?
That woman is Shimizu Reiko.
She's also someone who worked a but...
She committed suicide May 15th.
Suicide?
It was during the time that the police were questioning her.
About Nishio's murder case?
I guess they pushed her too far.
This is where the shooting incident occurred.
Everything's covered in dust, so...
They probably haven't been here since then.
Well, back then, the blinds and window were both open, right?
From that building's restroom, the culprit shot Nishio.
The rifle used was a Charter Arms AR-7...
With scope and silencer attachments.
There were eight empty casings left in that restroom.
It seems the culprit shot all eight in a row.
One of the bullets got Nishio in the back of the head...
Killing him instantly.
Later, they found the plans in Nishio's desk...
That Itou had drawn up about robbing the armored car.
That's why they placed Itou on the most wanted list.
Then, why did they investigate Shimizu Reiko?
That I don't know.
Look, Hattori.
For someone shot in the head, is this enough blood?
True.
Over there, we have a large pool of blood.
What's going on?
The blood on the seat had flowed straight down...
Look at this.
It looks like one of the casters got shot and broke off.
I see.
That's how it happened.
Yeah, it must be.
Hattori here.
It looks like you've made it to the next step, Hattori-kun.
Yeah, somehow.
Do you know what case I want you to solve now?
Nishio Masaharu's murder case?
Hey, could you really be...
Damn...
What the...
A bike?
Whatever it is won't be good, right?
Who're they?
Perhaps they're here to spice up this game?
Like the client said.
Maybe a bit too much.
This won't work, let's split up!
All right!
I got it!
All right, it's just us.
Come and get me.
You're an ugly one.
Offended?
Damn...
Coward!
Not fair to use a gun!
I wonder if Kudou got away...
How unfortunate...
Some paint got on my shirt.
A man wearing a baseball cap and a jumper, right?
But he may have taken them off.
That's possible, too.
What's wrong?
Doesn't he look suspicious?
That man in yellow?
Look, his hair has layered out.
He must have been wearing a hat earlier!
He probably got rid of it along with his jumper and the bag he stole.
As expected of High School Detective
of the East Kudou Shinichi's girlfriend!
I'm really not his girlfriend...
Some cola spilt on the culprit's shoes, right?
Yeah, that was my plan to leave evidence.
That's my bag!
Oops!
Amazing, Genta-kun!
That's not true, Ayumi-chan.
You shouldn't lie, Genta-kun.
Thief!
I saw it all.
Oh, did you really?
There!
It's just an old woman...
Hey, Ayumi!
Is that him, Ayumi?
His left sneaker has cola spilt on it.
He's just lingering around.
Isn't that suspicious?
There's no doubt.
Let's follow him.
This isn't good.
Those guys...
Where are they?
Thief!
Wait!
You won't get away!
Move!
Out of my way!
Move, move!
You're in my way!
We're borrowing this!
Stop now!
Damn...
Surrender.
The security guards will be here soon.
Don't stick your nose where it doesn't belong!
Damn...
Oh, no!
Ayumi-chan!
Ayumi!
Don't move!
If anyone moves, I can't guarantee the safety of this child!
Number 5 is approaching the main gate.
Which is that?
Number 5, Yoshida Ayumi.
I see.
Not another step.
If you come any closer, this kid dies!
You, let her go!
Take me hostage instead!
Don't try me, old man!
Then, take me!
Let me do it.
It's my fault she was captured.
You guys can't!
I mean, we of course can't let civilians become hostages.
Quit talking!
I'm not exchanging hostages!
You there, you better not move until I'm past the gate.
This kid's life is at stake here.
Not good...
If they keep going...
Hey, this is the entrance.
Exit's next door.
Just get out of the way!
You can't order me around.
Follow the rules.
Honestly, someone of your age should be able to follow the rules...
Arrest him!
There's an unlimited supply of hostages here!
Stay back!
If you don't, this woman will...
What're you gonna do?
"What" am I gonna do?
Tell me.
Excuse me, coming through...
Sorry, I finally got the ice cream...
Satou-san...
Inspector Megure!
What are you doing here?
That's what we should be asking you.
Oh, well, actually...
Kudou-kun...
Kudou!
Hey, Kudou!
You're finally awake.
Where are we...
Old Agasa's car.
Professor?
Don't push yourself.
I've put it in a splint for now, but you may have a fractured bone.
Hattori...
You rescued me?
No, Hakuba did.
He called the old guy, and when he turned up...
He was holding you in his arms.
Then, this old guy called me, and here we are.
Hakuba did...
Yeah.
He said he had something else to look into and left before I arrived.
What time is it!?
How long has it been!?
It's been two hours, making it 8:30 at night.
Only an hour and a half left...
For now, we're going back to the Red Castle.
You've figured it out?
The criminal that killed Nishio-san?
No, we're just going back.
There's nowhere else to go, is there?
Oh yeah.
While you were asleep, Ohtaki-han called me back.
He gave me some information.
Something else related to Nishio's murder case.
On the night that Nishio was shot...
A car flipped near the containers at the docks.
The driver was Itou Suehiko.
He was critically wounded and barely survived...
Being stuck in the intensive care unit for a month.
The police looked into the car that was involved in the accident.
They found the hydraulic piping had been tampered with, and also...
Found a rifle with a silencer in the trunk.
Although the fingerprints were wiped...
They confirmed that rifle was the one used to kill Nishio.
So, did they arrest Itou?
No.
About two months after the accident,
the doctors began allowing visitors.
But when the police arrived...
We're coming in.
Itou had disappeared.
Afterwards, Itou couldn't be located...
So they placed him on the most wanted list.
They began suspecting him of attacking the
armored car while he was still in the hospital.
Then, this Itou is the culprit?
Yeah, there's no doubt that Itou shot Nishio.
They found Itou's footprints at the sniper's position...
And found gunpowder on his clothes.
They found eight shells at that location, which is the
maximum amount that could be loaded at once.
And all of the rifle marks match, but...
Mascara?
We found traces of mascara on the rifle's scope.
Look.
That means it came from whoever looked through the scope.
Is that about it?
That's right.
It's a rare type of mascara.
They looked into each of the women working with Itou
and Nishio and found only one that used this mascara.
It was Shimizu Reiko.
The one who committed suicide after that incident?
The Madonna in the Crime Research of Yokohama Club.
She was friends with both the dead Nishio and the missing Itou.
After they graduated, she joined Itou's company
with Nishio as the manager of their library.
The criminals responsible for attacking the
armored car were Nishio and Itou, then?
Itou may have had a motive for killing Nishio, but...
Could Shimizu Reiko have had one as well?
According to her co-workers at the company...
Nishio was interested in her and she was bothered by it.
The police pressed her about the mascara on the scope and the
inconsistencies in her alibi for the night of Nishio's murder, but...
All the way to the end, she never spoke.
And then, on May 15th...
Hey!
She just jumped!
They never found Shimizu Reiko's body, but...
The police determined that she couldn't have
survived due to the fierce ocean currents.
Itou disappeared from the hospital eight days later.
With the two suspects in Nishio's murder
having disappeared, the trail went cold.
Of course, Itou's company went bankrupt without its president...
And who bought it out but the Miyama Corporation.
Are they connected to the Miyama Art Museum,
the place where Kid stole the jewel from!?
Bingo.
The president, Miyama Souchirou, was in the same
criminal research group, and was four years Itou's senior.
It seems Itou followed Miyama quite a bit.
Speaking of Kid, Ohtaki-han found out something interesting.
On April 4th, during a heist, Kid ran into a group of
burglars on the run after robbing an armored car.
There was apparently a bit of a firefight.
A firefight?
Well, since Kid doesn't use guns...
It must have been the robbers shooting at him.
The most likely reason being...
Because Kid saw their faces...
Right?
Yeah.
Apparently, at the scene, they found...
Government and Charter Arms ammunition.
And since then, someone's been trying to
take Kid's life every time he shows himself.
Well?
Isn't it interesting?
Yeah...
But it's not enough to narrow down who shot Nishio-san.
It's true.
We seem to be missing something important.
That reminds me, Mouri-kun called me earlier
to talk about some important witness he found.
Well, the day Nishio-san was shot, one of the janitors heard
several metallic sounds coming from the restroom, and...
After that, he saw Itou-san run out carrying a golf bag.
The metallic sounds were probably the
shell casings falling onto the floor...
And inside that golf bag was a Charter Arms AR-7.
That decides it, old man.
So, where's Uncle?
He said he solved the case already, so he went to go report to the client.
Is Uncle going to...
Implicate the wrong suspect!?
Really?
Step on it, Pops!
Full speed!
Got it!
I knew you'd come, Kaitou Kid.
You set things in place on the roof this afternoon,
and it looks like you finally found your way in here.
I'm not going to let you take the jewels.
I don't steal jewels unless I make an announcement first.
What?
I came here tonight to bid you farewell.
After all, I don't want my life to be endangered any longer.
As expected of Kaitou Kid.
Looks like you found me out.
Yeah, for the most part.
But there's something I didn't get.
The stolen diamond was returned to you...
And yet, you still kept trying to kill me.
I finally figured it out today.
You're very protective of your junior classmates, right?
I couldn't let you go, having witnessed my cute juniors' game.
Even though a guard died, it's still a game?
Accidents happen in every game.
Just like you witnessing it.
When one of my cute juniors asks for
my help, I have to do something, right?
And what kind of spell is this?
Did you seriously think I would come in here...
Without a trick up my sleeve?
Do it!
Kill Kid now!
What is this?
Fear not.
It's just sleeping gas.
You didn't notice?
I've broken in here several times...
Since April 4th.
What?
And the reason I came here to set up
on the roof in broad daylight today...
Was that I wanted to make sure you knew I was coming.
I wanted to ensure you would appear here with your assassins.
Impossible!
I'm sure the police I called for want to hear all about it.
Let's not forget your cute junior who's sleeping behind this curtain.
I guess she's cooler than him, huh?
Well!
I'm sure those two have some interesting information to share.
Especially concerning the stolen items filling this art museum.
It's Kid!
Kid's up there!
It looks like we've reached the goal of your game...
But it's the worst outcome for you—an own goal.
Open up, this is the police!
Open the door!
Hang on, Ran.
Thank you for your work, Detective Mouri.
The client is expecting you.
Come in.
Detective Mouri has arrived.
You must be tired, but there's not much time left.
Proceed with your report.
The cases you asked me to investigate took place on April 4th:
An armored car robbery on Basha Street...
And the related shooting of Nishio Masaharu, a murder case.
I'm going to meet the kids at Miracle Land.
Look after Kazuha for me.
I got it!
The two who held up the armored car were:
ltou Suehiko and Nishio Masaharu.
But, a guard put up a fight, and Nishio accidentally killed him.
And then, four days later, that same Nishio was shot and killed.
The police believed the criminal responsible was Shimizu
Reiko, a co-worker who had been being courted by Nishio.
But I don't think so.
I think their true reason for killing him
was because he meddled in their plans.
Right.
The person who killed Nishio Masaharu was...
Wait a second!
You two!?
You two, Detective Mouri is giving his report...
Oh, no!
Hey...
Hey, what's wrong!?
Are you all right!?
Detective Mouri, hurry and finish.
Like I was saying,
The culprit that shot Nishio-san was...
Sorry about that, Uncle.
Not good!
The monitor shut off!
Damn!
Damn, which button is it?
What's that?
The client could be back there.
What?
Earlier, when we called that Takada,
I heard something in the background.
The same noise I heard while talking to the client.
I see.
We're running out of time.
Let's go.
It's pretty dark in here...
What choice do we have?
Let's go.
Welcome, Kudou Shinichi-kun...
Hattori Heiji-kun.
We meet at last...
Far East Office President...
Itou Suehiko-san.
Well done.
I knew I made the right choice putting you two together.
Just as we thought.
You'll have to pardon my appearance.
It's due to my handicap, you see.
From the accident at the pier, right?
Yeah...
When I found out I wouldn't recover, I shut myself up in here.
I asked one of my friends to invest my hidden assets.
Including toward Miracle Land.
Was that Miyama Souichirou-san?
Outstanding!
You figured out even that little detail?
Wanna hear our report?
We're short on time.
Have you found the truth for me?
Yes.
I don't have much time left.
That's why I needed a detective who could solve this quickly.
A renowned detective who had not
just brains, but the toughness to match.
Now, tell me...
Tell me of this truth you've found.
On April 4th, Nishio Masaharu was killed at Far East Office...
And the shooter in the restroom in the adjacent building was...
Shimizu Reiko.
She made you out to be the culprit in Nishio-san's murder.
She also tried to kill you in an "accident".
It can't be!
I shot Nishio from that restroom!
Are you two as useless as the police!?
Are you!?
It's true that you shot the rifle from that restroom...
But it was after Shimizu Reiko did.
What!?
You actually missed.
With all seven rounds.
Seven rounds?
That rifle's magazine should hold eight.
Well, you panicked and ran out without
collecting the shells from the restroom...
Not noticing how many shots you'd fired.
By that time, Nishio-san had already been murdered.
How is that possible!?
I saw him fall to the floor with one of my shots!
Actually, one of your shots blew a caster off his chair by coincidence.
Then, one of my shots could have "coincidentally" hit Nishio, too!
What's wrong with you?
Why would someone sit around while their room was shot up?
Then, my first shot could have coincidentally...
The blood on the chair that Nishio-san was sitting on...
Had ran downward toward the seat before drying.
That's how we knew...
That Nishio-san was killed by a true sniper with a single shot...
And that there was an amateur who shot around
the room after Nishio-san's blood had dried.
Just from that, we couldn't tell who was the true sniper, but...
When we heard the testimony of Uncle Mouri's witness...
We understood it.
That witness said he heard several
metallic sounds from that restroom...
And then saw you running out with a golf bag.
The metallic sounds were the ejected cartridges hitting the floor.
The fact that there were multiple sounds
proves it was you who caused the damage.
In other words, the sniper was Shimizu Reiko, and...
The one who shot and hit the caster...
Thinking they'd killed him as they saw him fall from his chair, was you.
Inside the golf bag was a Charter Arms AR-7.
Before the crime, that bag was handed to you by Reiko-san.
Isn't that right?
That's true, but...
How can you know Reiko shot him?
The proof was on the rifle scope.
There were traces of Shimizu Reiko's distinctive mascara.
It can't be!
After you got the bag from her and shot from the restroom...
You drove to the pier to dispose of the weapon.
Reiko was likely the one who tampered with your car as well.
Most likely, her motive was to keep the money
from the armored car robbery all to herself.
She was in the car during your heist as well, right?
While fleeing, you encountered Kaitou Kid.
He saw your faces, so you decided to kill him.
But instead, you ended up trapped in a zigzag network of alleys...
And began firing.
They found them in those alleys:
The government and rifle rounds.
No matter how well you can drive...
It'd be impossible for you to hit Kid with a rifle
or handgun while taking such sharp turns.
In other words, there were two more with you.
Who were using the rifle and the Government.
That puts Nishio Masaharu-san and
Shimizu Reiko-san in that car with you.
Actually, most of the evidence was found by the police.
The witness that Uncle Mouri found
was also interviewed by the police.
Armed with such information, they interrogated Reiko.
You see...
Even from the beginning, this case didn't need...
A great officer, nor a great detective.
Well, this mystery is solved.
Please release Ran and the others' IDs.
Lies...
Reiko wouldn't do that...
A lie...
Lies, it's all lies!
It's not a lie.
As we thought, you're alive.
Reiko!
Is that Reiko!?
You weren't exactly reliable...
As my partner.
Nishio-kun wasn't either.
He was always so violent.
If I'd stayed with him any longer...
I would've been in danger.
Itou-kun, you're too petty.
You tried to show off every time we talked.
Being with you wasn't fun at all.
I saw you hiring detectives...
So I let you live, seeing that you were taking all the blame, but...
That ends today.
Don't worry about the assets Miyama-san is handling.
I'll take good care of them.
Miyama-san, too?
Miyama-san met his end as well.
He was caught by Kaitou Kid.
After all of this, the one to survive...
Will be me!
Wait a second!
Kudou, don't move.
That's a Walther PPK.
It holds eight bullets.
When she runs out, I'll go for her.
Six...
Seven...
Eight!
Now!
Hattori!
Sorry, I'm ambidextrous.
Use it, Kudou!
In the air, your leg won't matter!
I see.
Reiko?
Reiko, what happened?
What's wrong, Reiko!?
Reiko!
Please disengage the IDs.
It's all right to release them, right?
Right, send an ambulance now.
What!?
What's wrong?
An error?
She did more than she thought!
Hey Kudou, you got this?
Not everything is fried.
We just have to find the working parts!
I guess this is it for me, Kudou-kun...
Your voice even sounds like a child's...
Hattori, is there still an error?
Yeah, it hasn't changed.
It really is set to a timed explosion!
What the hell!?
At 10:00 exactly...
Damn...
What should I do?
I really wanted to ride the Super Snake...
It's been under maintenance this whole time.
But my dessert is late!
Don't complain, this is all on the inspector.
You're pudgy as ever, Inspector Megure.
As always.
Yep!
Uhm, Inspector Megure?
A Has something happened?
Why do you ask?
Well...
The police officers are all gathering here.
No...
Inspector Megure?
Oh, Shiratori-kun!
Excuse me, Ran-kun.
How is it?
All of the customers and employees in
the restaurant have been evacuated.
Now, it's only the kids...
As well as us police.
I see.
What're you doing, Shinichi?
Damn!
By exchanging secrets...
A man and a woman become closer.
The greatest secret to share...
Is to commit a crime with the woman you love.
You see...
Robbing that armored car was my way
of showing Reiko my feelings for her.
But then, that fool Nishio shot that guard...
Effectively ruining my perfect plan.
Perfection doesn't exist.
There will always be a loose cog somewhere.
If you try to force it anyway...
You'll simply ruin everything.
And even if you reset to the beginning...
Compensating for what you've lost is up to you.
You were just too scared...
To reset.
That may be true...
Please work...
What's this?
If I don't stop the time limit, the IDs won't release either!
Damn!
Are you all right?
Are you still not feeling well?
No, I'm all right.
Well, let me know if you feel sick again.
Yeah, I will.
And still, Conan-kun didn't show...
He must have stayed with Detective Mouri all day.
He ran off without us again!
Conan-kun is the best at sneaking off alone.
Have you heard anything from Mouri-kun?
I see.
When there's one minute left, I'm going in.
I can't leave the children alone in there.
I see.
It's 9:56!
There's no time, Kudou!
That's right!
He uses a wireless connection!
If the wireless connection's not working...
It could work if we connect directly!
A bit more...
All right, it reaches!
OK, it's back up!
We did it!
And now to disable the time limit.
Please enter password.
Hey, what's the password...
Hey, Kudou, this guy...
It's all right, he just fainted.
Probably from the shock.
What is the name of the person you love the most?
That's 59 minutes.
You, please wait out here.
Yes, sir...
Everyone was pretty surprised, huh?
I was completely cool.
So, did you have fun today?
I wish we could have rode the Super Snake.
But that rocket ride sure was fun, huh?
Yeah, I wanna ride it again!
Itou was in love with Shimizu Reiko!
Incorrect password.
What!?
The one he loves isn't Shimizu Reiko!?
Incorrect password.
Entry of another incorrect password will
result in immediate system shutdown.
We're outta time, Kudou!
Who is it!?
Who does Itou love most?
Who!?
You tried to show off every time we talked.
But then, that fool Nishio shot that guard...
Effectively ruining my perfect plan.
I've got it!
What're you typing, Kudou!?
The time limit has been disabled.
That's it...
Yeah, with that, it's over.
Well done, Shinichi.
I was able to remove the time limit, but not the area limit.
So make sure to collect all of them, Professor.
All right, we'll get them now.
Kudou-kun, and Hattori-kun...
You two are the absolute best...
Detectives.
And you are the absolute worst person.
Hey, you two, are you all right!?
All right, take off your ID and place them in here.
We have to give them back?
Well, it's closing time here.
That's too bad...
Handkerchief, handkerchief...
Huh?
I thought I lost mine.
What's this from?
It looks like paint, but...
Where'd that come from?
All right, I'm taking these.
That's...
We apologize for the inconvenience today.
The Super Snake has now reopened.
Even though it's past closing time...
We will run the ride one last time today.
All right!
Are you all right, Hattori?
Nothing to worry about, this's just a scratch.
That's right, do you know why he thought you were Kudou Shinichi?
This.
That?
Your fingerprint?
Do you remember the chairs in that room?
Yeah, only because they didn't match the rest of the room.
The armrest of the chair caught my eye.
Most likely...
There's a sensor on the arm rests that can read fingerprints.
This fingerprint belongs to Kudou Shinichi.
Since that guy's eyes are damaged, he thought I was Kudou Shinichi.
I see now.
Oh no!
It's past ten!
It's gonna blow!
It'll come off now, the ID belt.
Belt!
This, this!
It's true!
Thank goodness!
I'll take that.
Hey, hold on!
Really...
I guess that means this case is closed, right?
By the way, let me down.
You don't want to push it on that leg.
There you go!
The best way to heal is to ride on this girl's back.
Shut up!
That must be cool.
What a kid...
Inspector, I've recovered the IDs.
It's definitely all of them.
Send them to the lab without the kids noticing.
Yes.
All right!
It's time we hit the Super Snake!
Enjoy!
Lucky!
We got it all to ourselves!
Heiji, aren't you glad they sell spare pants?
Fool, I dun need 'em!
All right everyone, hands up!
Talk about going too far.
You don't have to put your hands up if you're scared.
Who's scared here?
When it's time to put my hands up, I'll...
You're too into it now, Heiji!
Hey, you!
Take that off, Genta!
Genta!
What're you doing!?
Hurry up and get rid of that!
The ride goes out over the sea, outside the area limit!
Genta!
What're you doing!?
Move and die!
Yes, ma'am...
Got it!
Kudou!
Back there!
Not good!
Hurry!
You can't!
Stop him!
Don't!
The bars are all linked together, so if you break yours...
Everyone's bar will open!
That was great!
They even had fireworks!
It must have been a bonus!
I didn't get to enjoy it...
Why's that guy here?
He's been with us since the middle of the investigation.
Geez, that Ryuu...
He accepted a bribe to fake his death.
He must've been lying about those other
two detectives he mentioned as well.
Does he need money that much?
Such a disgrace.
Yes, Mouri Detective Agency.
A TV ad?
What kind of ad?
For sleeping pills?
It should be easy since I'm always sleeping?
Geez!
Who do you think this is!?
I don't care how much you're paying!
That much?
I'll do it!
Yes!
I knew it.
That's Sleeping Kogorou for ya...