New York
Next, we present this auction's crown jewel.
The pride of mankind,
and a world-renowned masterpiece.
Once believed lost forever...
Vincent van Gogh's Sunflowers!
What? Sunflowers?
But isn't that the one that burnt up in the war?
Ladies and gentlemen, quiet please.
We'll explain the details now.
It's said that Van Gogh painted seven paintings of Sunflowers when he was in Arles.
The one believed to be
his second sunflowers painting
is the one that we're presenting here today.
It was believed to have been lost to the fires of war in 1945, in Ashiya, Japan,
but last year, a painting with the same composition was found in Arles.
Numerous experts examined the piece,
and confirmed it to be
an original Van Gogh painting.
Now! Let us breathe new life into these sunflowers!
Since this is a legendary work of art
by Vincent Van Gogh,
the second of his Sunflowers series...
The auction will start at ten million dollars!
They're starting at ten million?
And it's going $100,000 higher with each bid.
If I had that kind of money, I'd spend it on a trip to space or something like that.
We have a bid of $20,000,000 via phone,
and a $20,500,000 bid via the Internet.
$50 million!
Hey, that man...
Yeah, isn't he famous for buying up masterpieces?
No wonder.
Is that gonna end it?
$100 million!
Didn't you hear me? $100 million!
I offer $100 million!
Does anyone offer $110 million? Nobody wants to bid $110 million?
Damn it, who's that old man
with the mustache?
What are we going to do?
It's fine, the real battle will start at $200 million.
All right.
$200 million!
It's Mr Suzuki!
Is he serious?
Oh, right, $200 million!
Right... Unless I've misheard,
#705 bids $200 million.
This is the famous... Mr Suzuki!
The online bids will need a moment to catch up.
I'm sorry about this,
but please hold on a minute.
Hey, Uncle, they think
you're out of your mind.
I don't like to waste time
when I'm shopping.
Shopping? Hey...
We don't have to wait for the Internet bids.
$300 million!
I said $300 million!
Going once, going twice...
Sold for $300,000,000!
Before the interview with Mr. Jirokichi Suzuki,
It's starting, Conan-kun!
Coming!
we have a specialist here to explain this Sunflowers,
Hurry, hurry!
which sold for a record price.
What did you make now?
Is this a robot?
Hurry up and start it up, Doc.
Thanks for being here.
My pleasure.
How come such an important painting hasn't been seen before now?
The painting was believed to have been destroyed in a fire during World War II.
Destroyed in a fire?
Then, it's a fake?
No, but that's what was believed for a long time.
Look at this, please.
It's a newspaper from last year.
It mentions how a painting attributed to Van Gogh was discovered in Arles, France.
Now that you mention it, it was supposedly found in the attic of an old house, wasn't it?
Yes, and that is this second painting of Sunflowers.
Come on, let's get started.
- Come on!
- Let's go!
I brought the biggest one.
During his life, Van Gogh
only managed to sell one painting,
others being given away, or even left behind at places he stayed.
I'll just have to press here...
So many people maintain that more paintings could be found at any time.
I hope eel on rice comes out.
I doubt that's even possible.
But isn't there a chance that the painting's fake?
You could say it's even better than eel on rice!
That's one point that specialists took great care in.
- Really?!
- How exciting!
Before the auction, they performed a detailed analysis.
Yeah!
They found that the canvas sheet matched with one used by Van Gogh for another painting from Arles.
Something better than eel on rice...
Like an even bigger portion?
Why would you think that?
Oh, it's out!
Huh?
It's the same watermelon as before.
What? Another failure?
You'll see.
Kamen Yaiba!
Whoa!
Amazing!
It's Kamen Yaiba!
Cool!
How did you do this?
What are you doing, Doc?
You could be making something worthwhile...
So, was the Ashiya Sunflowers a fake?
Well, it can't be ruled out.
Some now suggest that Van Gogh might have even created eight Sunflowers, instead of seven.
And thus, the painting of the Sunflowers that was just sold and the one from Ashiya...
one of them could be a copy of the other, painted by Van Gogh himself.
Did painters really make copies of their own paintings?
Yes, of the seven known paintings of the Sunflowers,
three are copies.
And in fact, all three were painted by Van Gogh.
This is all well and good...
But you could show some more interest in the Doctor's inventions.
Either way, as an authentic piece, it's sure to spur on future research.
It's quite a work of art...
It does seem unusually popular.
Yay.
It seems the press conference's about to start.
Now, we'll go live to the
press conference in New York.
I'd like to ask Jirokichi Suzuki-san,
the winning bidder of the Sunflowers,
to tell us a few words.
Right.
I am happy to have bought
the highest-ever priced painting,
just as I had planned.
You mean, you'd already
planned on spending $300 million?
Exactly.
I did it because I intend to set up a Sunflowers exhibit in Japan.
An exhibit?
We'd like to announce that the Suzuki Financial Group
will be reuniting all of the Sunflowers paintings depicting vases scattered around the world,
to hold an exhibit named The Sunflowers Admired by Japan, at our Lake Rock Museum.
Miss Suzuki, how many paintings do you mean when you say all of the Sunflowers?
Your purchase of this painting was also part of this plan, correct?
Yes. We planned everything in order to announce the exhibit right here and now.
The paintings we'll be showing, including the one from this auction, will be seven in total.
Seven?
Isn't that impossible,
even for a Japanese financial group?
Don't worry. The project is already underway.
We've already been in contact with the owners of the Sunflowers, both museums and individuals worldwide,
and told them that we wish to set up an exhibit
with all of the Sunflowers paintings.
And we have their agreement that after winning the auction today,
they will co-operate with us in full.
And furthermore,
we have seven specialists ready
to take care of the paintings, supervise their transportation and protect them.
Seven specialists?
The Seven Samurai I've gathered for this occasion.
These are the Seven Samurai?
Indeed.
They are top experts who have studied in places with a deep connection to Van Gogh,
such as the Netherlands and France.
Starting from the left is Natsumi Miyadai,
who will be charged with the history and appraisals of the paintings.
A pleasure.
Natsumi Miyadai
Curator for History and Appraisals
Next, we have Koji Azuma,
Koji Azuma
Curator for Restoration and Preservation
another specialist, charged with restoration and preservation.
Next to him is Keiko Anderson,
who's charged with planning the exhibit.
Keiko Anderson
Curator for Planning
I'm Keiko. A pleasure.
Taizo Ishimine
Curator for Transportation and Shipping
Mr Taizo Ishimine will be in charge
of transporting and arranging shipping of the paintings.
I'm Ishimine.
And this is Kumiko Kishi,
who's in charge of the presentation of the Sunflowers exhibit.
Kumiko Kishi
Curator for Exhibit Presentation
I promise the exhibit will be a success.
Charlie
NYPD
And finally, Lt Charlie of the NYPD
will be in charge of security.
I'll protect the Sunflowers.
You mentioned Seven Samurai,
but there are only six here.
The last one will be required to reinforce security once we return to Japan.
His name?
Kogoro Mouri!
He's picking the old man, of all people?
Presumably for the free-gift-with-purchase of the Kid Killer, right?
Yes. Perhaps you may know
him better as Sleeping Kogoro.
Good luck, Kikuchiyo-san.
Wow!
Oh! That great detective, Mr Mouri?!
Sonoko-oneesan's on TV!
Indeed. In all, it's an impeccable team to handle the Sunflowers exhibit.
You're right!
Let's watch it!
Yeah!
Even if you failed to gather the seven paintings,
would you have exhibited the painting you won in the auction?
No, I will only exhibit all seven paintings together.
But then...
Relax.
I've dreamed of setting up
this exhibit for a long time.
And for me, no dream is impossible.
That's...
A Kid card!
Who's that?
He has a gun!
Call security!
Drop the weapon!
Didn't you hear me?
Drop the weapon, immediately!
No way!
What's going on?
I can't see anything!
Something happened!
Kid-sama!
Kid!
Freeze, or I'll shoot!
What's going on?
Freeze!
Freeze, or we'll shoot!
We've cornered Kid
in the east hallway, floor 103.
Kid!
Drop the weapon! Now!
Good. Now slowly raise your hands, and get down on your knees.
Did you hear me?
Raise your hands to where I can see them.
Kid-sama!
Good. Slowly.
Just like that.
Ugh!
Stop, Charlie!
Damn Kaito Kid...
It seems he's escaped.
It was a messy affair, but from what we've been told, there were no injuries.
It's already over?
Kid stole the Sunflowers?
How odd. Usually, Kid only steals jewels.
I was only able to see him for an instant.
But was that really Kid?
It seems you're having trouble.
What are you doing here?
I heard that Kid was going
to try to steal the Sunflowers.
If you'd like,
I'd be happy to help.
I'm Shin'ichi Kudo, a high school detective.
While at an amusement park with my childhood friend and classmate, Ran Mouri,
I witnessed a suspicious deal
involving a man in black.
Since I was so focused on watching the deal, I didn't realize his partner was sneaking up from behind me.
He forced me to consume poison,
and when I came to...
...my body had shrunk!
If those men learnt that
Shin'ichi Kudo was still alive,
they'd come back to finish me off, endangering everyone around me.
At Dr Agasa's suggestion,
I hid my identity,
and when Ran asked my name,
I blurted out Conan Edogawa.
To find out more about those guys, I ended up living with Ran and her detective father.
By the way, the Doc isn't the
only one who knows my identity.
Ai Haibara.
Real name: Shiho Miyano.
She used to be with the men in black,
but to get away from them, she took the same drug that'd been forced on me, and ended up shrinking.
Also, there's Kaito Kid and his assistant.
I still haven't settled things with them.
But on my name as a detective, I swear I'll catch them this time!
My body shrunk, but my mind didn't!
I'm still an undefeated great detective!
There's always only one truth!
We'll be landing at Haneda Airport soon.
For the landing, please store your luggage in the overhead compartments, or under your seats.
This is the dummy we've retrieved.
You seem to be happy about it.
Uncle keeps getting tricked,
so he's just glad he's not the only one.
By the way, is this okay?
You told the crew to keep out unless there's an emergency,
but you're fine letting this kid wander around freely.
Oh, he's a detective representing Japan.
Don't worry about him.
But, what if he's Kid in disguise?
They have a similar body build.
You really are paranoid.
Watch.
See?
What are you doing, old man?
Charlie was suspicious.
And what's an American cop
doing aboard this airplane?
He was only supposed to protect you and the painting until the airport.
He didn't need to come to Japan.
Indeed, the contract only specified protection within the US.
But now that Kid's after the Sunflowers,
I can't leave things be.
I was right to choose you as one of my samurai.
Promise me you'll protect the Sunflowers.
You can count on me.
Now we just need the Kid Killer, and everything will be perfect.
Are you okay, Natsumi-san?
Yeah, just feeling a bit ill.
Maybe you should stretch your legs a bit.
You shouldn't be sitting down for so long.
Thank you.
Where are you going?
The toilet.
Haneda Airport
Oh, geez.
If Kid might be targeting them,
why are they coming in such a gaudy plane?
We tried to tell him to be discreet,
but he told us it wasn't just for transportation, but also for promotion.
And wasn't it your job to stop him,
Inspector Nakamori?
Do you really think that
old geezer would listen to me?
I suppose not.
So this is the plane they're coming back in.
Is the Sunflowers painting coming with them too?
Why do you always
have to show up every single time?
We had to bring him!
Jirokichi-san wanted Conan-kun to come.
Right?
Conan-kun is the Kid Killer, after all.
Geez, talk about nonsense.
Well, don't you go wandering off!
You're only here to accompany us, got it?
Yeah...
Ran! Keep your eyes on this brat.
I always try to, but...
Who could it be? Excuse me.
Ah, Sonoko!
Hey, Ran.
We'll be landing soon,
but I figured I'd call you
to give you the good news.
He wanted it to be a surprise,
and told me not to warn you, but...
Shin'ichi's with you?
But just because Shin'ichi's on the plane, doesn't mean that...
Sonoko-neechan!
Shin'ichi-niichan's there with you?
He was sitting right here until just now...
What's going on?
Sonoko? What's going on? Sonoko!
What's going on, Ran?
I heard screaming, and a loud noise.
What? Inspector Nakamori, come here!
Apparently, something
happened on the airplane.
What? Nobody told us anything.
Could it be Kid?
No luck.
The right aileron and the slats aren't responding.
Never mind that! Turn off engine #4.
We have to put out the fire!
Yes, sir!
Huh? A person?
This is the control tower.
Flight 2501, understood.
I'll free Runway A. Can you make it?
This is Flight 2501.
We'll try. Remove all other nearby planes just to be safe.
Roger.
Inform every nearby plane to leave the area if they have enough fuel!
Hurry, there's no time!
Yes, sir!
Calling all airplanes!
Damn it...
Even if they manage to turn
and head for the the airport,
with that altitude, they'll overrun the runway...
I hope they make it.
Attention, all passengers!
Due to engine trouble,
we're descending to emergency landing altitude.
Recheck your seatbelts and ensure they are properly fastened.
15,000 ft!
Pull up!
Pull up! Pull up! Pull up!
10,000 ft!
Come on!
Huh? Kid-sama?!
What? Kid?
Where is he?
Where's Kid?
Kid?
He showed up?
Hello? Hello?
Big trouble, Inspector Nakamori!
There really was trouble with the airplane!
They're going to perform
an emergency landing on Runway A.
An emergency landing?
Damn it, I can't see anything from here!
Is this Kid's doing?
Conan-kun!
Sonoko, answer me!
Sonoko!
Stop, Uncle!
Wait, Adviser Suzuki!
Moving now is too dangerous!
But if Kid showed up,
he might've stolen the Sunflowers!
We'll be performing the emergency landing now.
As you may know, due to the explosion, we are not in full control of the plane.
The landing will likely be complicated.
Please pray for the landing to be successful.
Let's do this.
Good. Now the next, the next.
Gate #8, quickly!
This is not a drill!
No luck! The plane isn't stabilizing!
Don't give up, try again!
Yes, sir!
Help me, Ran!
Move!
There it is!
It's coming!
It's wavering!
It's no good, they're too high.
This isn't looking good.
Damn it!
Do what you're told!
Reverse it now!
But we could lose control!
Don't worry about that.
Just think about getting this thing stopped!
Yes, sir! Reversing thrusters!
Wha... What?
All passengers in the international terminal...
No! They're going to crash!
Stop, stop, stop, stop!
Please, stop!
That was close...
Shin'ichi! Sonoko!
This is the control tower.
Flight 2501, do you read?
Flight 2501, please respond!
Flight 2501.
This is flight 2501. My apologies.
We didn't follow your instructions, and switched to another runway.
But are you all right?
Yes, we've avoided crashing into the gate.
Everybody's all right.
Please begin extracting the passengers.
Copy.
You okay, kid?
Yeah.
Oh, geez.
That was really close.
Yeah...
The slightest mistake could've caused a huge disaster.
That's right.
But would Kid really do this?
What's that?
Don't tell me it's...
Kid!
Damn it, I won't let you get away!
Where are you going, brat?
Kid's getting away with the Sunflowers!
What, seriously?
Shin'ichi... Sonoko...
Sonoko! Are you okay?
Where are you?
Relax, Ran. I'm fine.
Thank goodness!
By the way, did Kudo-kun call you yet?
Shin'ichi? Not yet.
I see...
What's going on with Shin'ichi?
Isn't he with you?
No, I can't find him anywhere.
Hey, kid! You're not allowed here!
Damn it, where'd he go?
Hey, kid, wait up!
Who's calling me now?
I'm unable to come to the phone right now.
- Please leave a message...
- Oh, no! Shin'ichi!
Please, answer!
Sorry, Ran! I'm chasing Kid!
I'll call you later!
Thank goodness...
CALL ENDED
Shin'ichi...
Where is he? Where is he?
You won't get away!
Go!
Damn it!
But...
When Kid leapt, he didn't have
the Sunflowers with him.
Judging by the amount of time
when I couldn't see him,
he must've hidden the painting
somewhere in that building.
There it is!
These are all the tools
we've been able to find at the airport.
It's fine. For now I just need to check if the painting has any scratches or other imperfections.
Let's get started.
Yes.
Hopefully it's just dirt.
A single scratch would flush the whole exhibition dream down the drain.
Inspector Nakamori, look at this.
Kid was picked up by a rooftop security camera.
He passed by overhead about an hour and fifteen minutes ago.
From what we can tell,
at the time, he still had the painting.
Yeah, but why would he leave it
on top of the building afterwards?
This Sunflowers painting
is surprisingly large.
It might've created too much air resistance to escape on his hang glider.
He might've intended to come back for it later, after everything calmed down,
but the boy spotted it first.
I wasn't the one who found it.
Shin'ichi-niichan saw Kid
hiding it during the chase.
And where is this high-school detective?
He's never around when Kid shows up.
He might just be Kaito Kid.
I don't think so.
That's right.
You have a call from Kudo-kun
from an hour and fifteen minutes ago.
It matches the time of that photo from before.
Oh, geez.
That makes it look like
I really was in the US.
Whatever.
The question is why Kid was
at the airport in the first place.
He wanted to see what happened to the airplane where he'd set a bomb.
Homicidal maniacs often come back
to the scene of the crime.
No way...
Hey! How dare you call
Kid-sama a homicidal maniac?
Open your eyes.
He almost killed you, too.
I don't want to accept that Kid would do something like try and crash a plane...
Excuse me, sorry for the wait.
The painting is pretty dirty from the smoke,
but it doesn't require restoration.
Oh, is that so! Then all is not lost quite yet.
Good work, everyone.
Now let's get to work.
Good thing we found it so quickly.
Yeah. If it'd been left out in the sun, the UV rays and the heat would've destroyed it.
Good work, boy!
You truly are the Kid Killer!
But I told him it wasn't me...
This is the safe we've managed to build thanks to the Suzuki family's economic power:
the Improved Iron Tanuki.
If we leave it here, it'll be safe.
But didn't Kid-sama break
into the Iron Tanuki once?
Don't worry.
We've improved it, right, Lupin?
SETUP COMPLETE
All right. Check that everybody is out.
Yes.
All clear. Nobody's left inside.
Improved Iron Tanuki...
Activate!
ACTIVATE
LOCKING
According to an investigation by the MPD and MLIT,
traces of explosives were found on the outer wall of the plane's cargo hold.
The police is searching for the employee in charge of securing the cargo, who has disappeared.
Apparently, the owners of the other paintings don't want to lend them for the exhibit.
...the terrorist attack and
attempted robbery by Kaito Kid.
You're still here, Dad?
Yeah, there's a big race today.
Oh geez, you're skiving off work for that?
What if they fire you?
That's not something a detective as great as me would have to worry about.
Here's the post.
Who are they from?
Letters, huh... Maybe they're fan mail?!
Conan-kun.
Sonoko invited me to the meeting.
Do you want to come with me?
I'd like to, but...
I already promised my friends I'd go with them to the museum.
I see.
Oh well, it's fine then.
By the way...
Have you heard from Shin'ichi?
No, nothing.
I wish he'd told me he was in the US.
He hasn't called me
since the plane incident.
Ran...
Conan!
We came to pick you up!
Let's go, Conan-kun!
Yeah, I'm coming.
Hurry, hurry!
Doc, Conan was here!
Haibara-san, we can leave now!
Well, see you.
Be careful. Bye!
Ran!
What is it?
Call the police!
It's Kid!
There was a Kid card among the post.
Tonight, I'll take the first copy,
the one which is to the left of La Berceuse.
Damn you, Kid!
Won't you ever give up?
As you know, the owners
of the other Sunflowers paintings
rescinded their agreement to lend us their paintings for the exhibit.
Therefore, to restore their faith in us, I decided to install an anti-Kid security system at Lake Rock.
Last night, as Ms Natsumi suggested,
we camouflaged the security cameras between decorative sunflowers.
If you have any other interesting ideas,
don't hesitate to mention them.
Money is not an issue.
Of course. Our job is to make
this exhibit a success.
We'll pool our ideas together and let you know as soon as possible.
Please do.
Charlie.
You'll cooperate too, right?
Of course.
He may call himself a Phantom Thief,
but he's really just a killer who'll stop at nothing until he reaches his goal.
No, he's a terrorist.
And what do you know?
We can't even be sure if Kid-sama caused the plane incident in the first place!
Then, tell me.
If it wasn't Kid, then who put
a bomb on that plane, and why?
Jirokichi-sama, sorry for interrupting.
What is it?
I'm sorry, but Inspector Nakamori wants to speak to you right away.
Very well, patch him in.
Yes, sir.
It's me, what do you want?
Yes.
Understood. There's no way he'd break into the Iron Tanuki, but I'll check right away.
We're postponing this meeting.
What happened?
Is something wrong?
Don't tell me that Kid-sama...
Apparently, Detective Mouri received a new message at his office.
And what does the message say?
It says: Tonight, I'll take the first copy,
the one which is to the left of La Berceuse.
Nothing more.
Don't tell me...
I'll go and check the painting in the underground safe is secure, just in case.
The painting on the left side of the triptych.
Then, the first copy means...
Please, wait a moment.
Adviser!
According to the message, Kid's objective isn't the Sunflowers you have here.
The one to the left of La Berceuse, the first copy,
is the fifth Sunflowers he painted.
And the fifth Sunflowers painting, as you know, is here in Japan.
Sompo Japan Nipponkoa Head Office Building
At the Sompo Japan Nipponkoa Museum of Art, right?
Museum?
It's a place where you can see art.
It's going to be fun.
Thank you for your visit.
It's the first time I've come to a museum!
Me too!
It's so tall!
It's incredible!
Look, you can see the Bell Tree!
You're right!
But didn't you come to see the Sunflowers?
Oh, right.
Come on, let's go see the Sunflowers!
Hey, don't run!
Do they really want to see the Sunflowers?
Honestly, it's not them who want to see it...
...right, Doctor?
Right,
I have to study them in preparation for the Sunflowers Admired by Japan exhibit.
Suddenly you're into art now?
Though I wasn't expecting
you to come, too.
Didn't you have a meeting?
They already have six samurai there.
Right now, I'm more
interested in what Kid's up to.
It's odd that he'd suddenly be interested in something other than a jewel.
Is that why you came to see the Van Gogh
painting that he wants to steal?
Yeah.
If I can learn something about the painting, I might be able to understand Kid's motives,
and thus might be able
to anticipate his next movement.
Huh? It ends here...
Where's the Sunflowers?
Found it!
Which one is the Sunflowers?
This one, right? The one in the middle.
It's so pretty!
It's incredible!
But what's so great about it?
Guys.
Be quieter, or you'll be kicked out.
Oh, right...
Sorry about the noise.
It's fine.
So this is the fifth Sunflowers painting!
Hey, Doc!
It really is amazing!
Oh, sorry...
Don't worry.
So, that's it, we saw the Sunflowers.
That's it?
Yeah.
Then let's go buy a souvenir!
Yeah, let's go!
Hurry up, Doctor!
I'm coming.
Geez, what did they even come here for?
Young lady, you seem to be interested in something other than the Sunflowers, don't you?
Sorry if I surprised you.
You reminded me of myself when
I was young, so I couldn't help myself.
Do you come here often, Ma'am?
Yes, every day.
I guess you really must like
Van Gogh's Sunflowers.
I guess so.
But not this one.
Here it is.
Looks like it's still fine.
Uncle, what happened?
What are you doing here?
What about you?
Nice timing, kid.
Come with us.
Did Kid...?
Hideo Harada
Director of the Seiji Togo Memorial
Sompo Japan Nipponkoa Museum of Art
The next painting he'll be trying to steal...
Adviser Suzuki, please don't talk about that here.
Right, sorry.
As you can tell, everything is still in order.
Anything further would be
disturbing the customers.
We can talk about the details
in the reception room.
Very well. Let's head there.
Haibara, I'm gonna stay here
with the old man and the rest.
Go home with the others.
Also...
I know.
Don't tell the others anything.
Yeah, thanks.
He trusts you a lot.
We don't have the relationship
you think we have, Ma'am.
No.
You have the same look
I had 70 years ago.
It matches the meaning of a sunflower in the language of flowers:
I only have eyes for you.
But if you merely look on,
then one day, you'll regret it.
Like with me...
People only realize what truly
matters to them once they lose it.
Like that Sunflowers painting.
Haibara, we're heading home.
Huh? Where's Conan-kun?
He went home.
Apparently it was urgent.
Again?
He probably had to use the toilet.
Thanks for your advice.
I'll try to not regret anything.
It's a shame you can't stay any longer, Doctor.
It's fine. This way, I'm even more excited for the Sunflowers Admired by Japan exhibit.
Kiyosuke-san...
Why are you assuming that this warning note is about a potential robbery of our museum's Sunflowers?
La Berceuse is the painting
of the woman rocking a cradle.
It has nothing to do with the Sunflowers.
No, the important part is that it says the first copy, the one to the left...
It must mean the leftmost painting of a triptych.
A triptych?
Yes, a group of three paintings or scrolls.
We know that.
What I don't know is what La Berceuse has to do with the Sunflowers.
That's... what was it?
For goodness's sake...
Aren't you supposed to be a samurai?
How about we ask Koji Azuma-san to explain it to us in detail, since he's the one who deciphered the note?
Oh, right.
Azuma, if you would?
Yes, sir.
Assuming that Detective Mouri's
triptych theory is correct,
let's say La Berceuse would be in the center.
Therefore, the paintings at the sides would be...
Sunflowers!
Exactly.
In a letter he sent
to his younger brother Theo,
he even made a sketch of the triptych, so we can be sure about it.
If we place the paintings according to the sketch with La Berceuse in the center,
to the right you'd have
the 3rd painting and the 7th,
and to the left you'd have
the 4th, 5th, and 6th.
Of the ones in the left,
Original
1st Copy
2nd Copy
the first copy would be the 5th painting,
the one exhibited in this museum.
I see.
Then he does intend to steal this painting.
Then, what should we do?
Kid's notice says he'll come tonight.
We should move the Sunflowers to a secure place immediately.
But we can't do that right away.
It's fine.
I'll explain the situation to the customers, and we'll close early.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Very good.
Slowly. Right, keep it straight.
I wonder if there's anything we can do.
Yeah...
Ishimine, from Cheetah
Transportation, is very effective.
He did all this in just half an hour.
Only one hour left until the sun sets.
Looks like we'll make it in time.
Yes.
That's right, slowly.
Just like that.
Is there anything we can do to help?
Sure.
Can you bring the lid while we pack the painting, please?
All right. Natsumi.
Let's go pick up the lid.
Sure.
Let me help you.
Don't worry, we'll be fine on our own.
Ishimine-san doesn't like it when people outside the team help.
That's right.
Thanks for the offer.
All right.
Ready?
We'll pick it up on three.
The painting's all packed.
Good job.
Here's the lid.
Ah, thanks.
We'll handle the rest.
Shouldn't we inspect the safe?
Yes, we should. Director,
can we step out for a moment?
Charlie-san's right.
If Kid is coming tonight, he'll probably try to steal it from the safe.
Ah, sorry!
It's fine, keep going.
Right.
Wait! There's something
under the lid!
Hey, brat!
We don't have time to waste,
so stop fooling around!
But it looks like a Kid card!
Lift up the lid.
Right.
It's a card! Could it be...
Natsumi-san, let me see...
Right.
It's certainly a Kid card.
I've taken the Sunflowers. —Kaito Kid.
I've taken it? But the painting's right here!
Is that all?
Is that the only thing
written on the card?
Yes.
What do you mean?
Could this mean that the
painting here was already...
Replaced by a fake?
I didn't expect Kid to lie
about the heist's time.
Yeah. The Kid we know wouldn't do that.
No. Something's not right here.
So he completely tricked us.
He's nothing but a petty thief.
He'll stop at nothing to get what he wants.
I'm certain he'd even be willing to kill.
What do you think?
If it's a fake, it's an incredibly accurate one.
I can't confirm its authenticity here.
I see.
Can I take it with me?
I'd be able to check it with far more precision straight away at our studio.
Very well.
If there's a large chance
it was exchanged for a forgery,
our superiors will surely agree.
There's no need, Director.
What do you mean?
You have some nerve!
That's... Kaito Kid!
Of course! This examination was Kid's trap!
That Sunflowers is authentic,
I guarantee you.
Damn you, Kid!
How dare you trick us?
Stop!
Damn!
Azuma-san, Miyadai-san!
Are you all right?
Yeah, but he took the Sunflowers!
Catch Kid!
What?
The Sunflowers?
Wait, Kid!
This is Nakamori.
Kid stole the Sunflowers and escaped.
He is likely headed for the rooftop! Be ready!
Yes, sir!
I found Kid! He's on the highest part of the roof!
Oh, no! He's going to escape!
If only I had my gun...
Kaito Kid just released a number of flying trails.
I lost him.
What? Find him!
Wow! This is crazy!
There he is!
We've been had!
Where is he?
It's too late.
Damn it! He's insane.
He stole it tonight, just as he'd said.
This is the card he slipped
into my breast pocket.
I will sell you the Sunflowers I stole from you for the reasonable amount of 10 billion yen.
We'll meet in two hours in room 1412 of the Tôto Plaza Hotel.
You are to deliver the money
as old-style banknotes,
remove them from the briefcase
and leave them on the bed.
If you don't agree, there's no deal. —Kaito Kid.
Ten billion yen in two hours?
Then Kid's objective from
the beginning was money.
But why did he change so much?
There must be a reason.
Or maybe he's an impostor.
Our museum... can't muster up
10 billion yen in two hours.
There's only one man in Japan who can pull off something of that magnitude.
Fine, I'll get the cash.
Really?
But I have a condition.
If we manage to recover the Sunflowers,
you have to allow us to show it at our exhibit.
Of course!
If we can get the painting back, my superiors are sure to agree.
And can you convince the owners
of the other five paintings
to allow us to show them, too?
Very well, I'll do whatever I can.
Okay.
Okay, we're done then.
We must head to the hotel, immediately.
Yes.
Director, meet us at the hotel
as soon as you're able.
Of course.
Are you coming too, Charlie?
No, I have to get
something important.
Something important?
Yes. Something I need to stop Kid.
Fine, but make sure you're
back in time for the deal.
Don't worry. I won't be late.
By the way, I need a favor from you.
What is it?
I want to invite a certain person
to the legendary Sunflowers exhibit.
Who?
Ever since we started showing that painting,
an elderly lady has come to our museum almost every day.
Oh, she was there today, wasn't she?
Yes, she was.
The painting must be extremely important to her, since she doesn't look at any other.
She just stares at
the Sunflowers with a sad look.
Very well.
Thank you very much.
It's me. I'm going to need that.
Are you sure?
Just carrying one in Japan is a crime, you know.
I don't care. I can't let a terrorist who tried to bomb an airplane go free.
Fine. I'll get you one ASAP.
Thank you, Mark.
Bring it to the parking lot behind Tôto Plaza Hotel in one hour.
Roger.
This is the entrance lobby.
Everything's normal.
At the emergency stairs.
Nothing suspicious here.
Staff entrance here, we need more men.
Damn it! We won't make it at this pace.
Roof team will arrive momentarily.
Sorry for the delay.
Inspector Nakamori,
how is the security?
We have officers
at every entrance and exit.
But if he's already inside the hotel,
it won't be of any use.
Still, we won't fail this time.
We won't let him escape the hotel!
Hurry! There's no time!
Quick, bring in more.
I'll leave these here.
Hurry!
Can we even negotiate in this situation?
It's Kid's instructions.
All we can do is follow them.
From now on, don't speak to me unless it's strictly necessary.
If we're discovered,
everything goes down the drain.
Of course.
But why does he want us
to take all the money out and put it there?
We have no choice.
It's what Kid asked for.
Be quiet, brat!
Okay...
Do you want to see the monitors?
Yeah.
Hold on.
There you go.
Thank you. You're very kind.
I'd just like your help.
I've seen how sharp and
insightful you can be.
I can see why they
call you the Kid Killer.
That was just a coincidence.
Besides, I'm still in primary school.
I'm not prejudiced.
Let me know if you spot anything, okay?
Okay.
For an amount as large as 10 billion yen,
the normal demand would be to deposit it into a foreign account.
But he asked for cash.
There must be a reason.
What?
The press is here? How could that be?
We're supposed to be the only ones who know about this deal!
That's what we thought,
but reporters from every paper and channel are flooding in.
We've already lost control of the car park.
This is the left entrance.
The press started broadcasting!
We're in front of the Tôto Plaza Hotel.
BREAKING NEWS: ANOTHER NOTICE FROM KAITO KID!!
Kid declared that he's only interested in the second and fifth Sunflowers paintings!
Damn Kid! He used
the press to cause a panic!
Inspector Nakamori.
If Kid himself called the press,
then he won't cancel the deal,
no matter how much panic there is.
Either way, we're running out of time.
Give up on taking out all the money.
We have no choice.
There's only two minutes left.
Just open the briefcases and leave them there.
Everybody, get out of there!
Director, we'll be waiting in the room opposite.
But...
Stay where you are.
Hurry!
It's really hot in here.
Can't I open the windows, at least?
Please try and bear it.
There's no guarantee Kid will
come through the door.
Okay.
Everyone has withdrawn from their positions.
Well done. All units, stay where you are until further instructions.
Roger!
Knowing Kid, he must have
an ace up his sleeve.
I have to find it before
the deal happens.
Wait, something seems off.
Something doesn't match.
Oh, no! That's it!
Damn it!
He took the master key.
Damn it, there's no time!
Hurry up!
Kid Killer!
What's going on?
Get in!
Tell me.
The water level in the director's
bottle is higher than before.
It probably means the atmospheric
pressure went up.
Then what's he up to?
I don't know.
But if we don't get that room's
pressure lowered ASAP,
he's holding all the cards.
What the...? What are those two doing?
They're gonna bust the entire operation!
The deal starts in twenty seconds!
Damn it, it won't open!
The difference in air pressure
is blocking the door from inside.
How could they act out like this...!
Never mind them.
There's less than ten seconds left. We have to keep going!
Five seconds,
four, three, two, one...
Zero!
What the...
- What's that?
- Look, something's falling!
Did Kid show up?
All right, it's opening!
Kid!
Damn you, Kid!
It's Kid!
- The tip about the deal with the Suzukis was right!
- Does he have the painting?
He's escaped!
Are you all right?
Yes...
Did Kid bring the Sunflowers?
I don't know.
Charlie-san, look!
The painting above the bed.
You idiots, you sabotaged the operation!
Charlie, where is he? Where's Kid?
He got away.
What about the Sunflowers?
Don't worry, the Sunflowers is fine.
The Sunflowers!
You got it back?
Yes, but the money...
Never mind that.
You did great! Let's hold a press conference immediately!
Adviser Suzuki, please tell us about your victory against Kaito Kid.
There's no reason to fear Kaito Kid.
The owners of the other
paintings can rest assured.
How odd...
Everything's going too well.
Both of Kaito Kid's attempts to steal the masterpieces known as the Sunflowers have been unsuccessful.
Jirokichi Suzuki's planned exhibition of The Sunflowers Admired by Japan is closer than ever to being realized.
Look at that.
I'd love to check out that exhibit.
Ah, the Sunflowers one?
As a result, the rest of
Van Gogh's Sunflowers paintings
are arriving in Japan
from around the world.
As a guest today we have the man behind the exhibit known as The Sunflowers Admired by Japan:
Adviser Jirokichi Suzuki,
from the Suzuki Financial Group,
and his niece, Sonoko Suzuki-san.
Who's that old geezer?
Isn't he the guy who crashed a blimp into the Akashi-Kaikyo bridge?
The exhibit will take place
at the Lake Rock Museum.
That's a name I haven't heard before.
That's because it was created
specifically for this exhibit.
That sounds really interesting!
To provide the most suitable environment for exhibiting these masterpieces,
and to protect them with
the best security system possible,
we had to design it all from scratch.
Let's take a look at some footage of the museum
while Sonoko Suzuki-san
goes into the details.
The Lake Rock Museum
was built upon a cavern owned by our company.
The structure stretches eight floors above ground,
with an exhibit room on each floor.
Each of the Sunflowers
will be shown on a different floor, so visitors can enjoy them all individually.
Then, when the visitors all reach the lowest floor, the underground level,
the paintings on each floor will all be moved using a special lift
to the eighth exhibit room.
While the visitors wait for the lift that will take them back to the roof,
they'll be able to see the complete collection.
I see.
The seven paintings will be exhibited separately first,
so people can appreciate them better once they're all together, right?
Not just that.
The security system is perfect.
A number of sensors will activate at the hint of any problem with the paintings,
immediately storing them in special boxes which are both water and fireproof.
That way, there's no chance of the paintings being damaged in a flood or a fire.
Furthermore, if anybody tries
to steal any of the Sunflowers,
the security system will activate immediately, and seal every exit.
Even if Kaito Kid disguises himself to get in,
he'll have no way to get out.
And the safety measures are flawless too. The lift leading to the rooftop,
the emergency lights, and the security system will keep working no matter what.
Does this mean you have a generator?
Yes, we have it covered in the footage too, so take a look.
Water is drawn from the nearby lake to the tank on the highest level,
so that hydro-electric power can be generated on demand using the height difference.
Main Transformer
Generator
As such, while the visitors return to the rooftop,
the Sunflowers are also transported to a ground level emergency evacuation warehouse using a special rail system.
Incredible! It's perfect!
An impregnable fortress
to protect the Sunflowers.
That's right.
In this incredible setting, you'll be able to see some of the greatest treasures of mankind,
all seven Sunflowers paintings in the same room.
Exclusively at the Sunflowers Admired by Japan exhibit.
We've heard exhibit will last for just one month, and will be limited to a hundred visitors per day.
When will the ticket raffles begin?
Right now.
Really?
You can enter right now on our website.
The raffle starts worldwide at the same time, so the ticket odds will be astronomical.
Make sure you don't miss this chance, everyone!
Oh, I missed out.
YOU LOST!!
I thought we'd have some luck
if we used the Doctor's Internet.
Man, none of us got one.
Doctor, what would show
on the screen if we'd won?
The photo you uploaded initially would be officially registered, and it shows you an ID number and PIN.
You enter those on the application page,
and the ticket arrives some days later.
Doc, you sound really familiar with it.
Could you have...?
Yeah, I won one.
That's some creepy laughter there.
Please, Doctor!
Give it to me, I want to go!
Me too!
And me, too!
Not in a million years.
How immature, Doctor.
Yeah, Doc.
How immature.
Extremely immature of you!
What can I do?
If you want it that much, then I'll do a quiz for it.
It's a multiple choice question, so you only get one shot at it, got it?
Okay!
All right!
That sounds like the Doctor!
Let's begin!
This little sunflower living in a sunflower field loves the Sun,
but what does it dislike?
1: Spiders.
2: Snakes.
3: Scorpions.
In Japanese, they're kumo,
hebi, and sasori.
Oh, so the answer is...
Shh. You two don't get to answer.
I got it!
Me too!
And me!
It's answer three! Scorpions!
That's not the right one, Genta-kun!
But scorpions are venomous, aren't they?
There's venomous snakes and spiders, too!
Seriously?
You lose!
The correct answer is one, spiders.
How come?
- Because spiders are kumo in Japanese.
- Huh?
Geez... Kumo can also mean the clouds.
The sunflower loves the Sun, so it hates the clouds that cover the Sun.
Oh, so the venom had nothing to do with it?
Which means, I'm not giving my ticket to anybody.
And so, we'd like to be able to see the Sunflowers exhibit together.
Any chance?
Please.
I beg you.
Please!
Very well.
All right!
Seriously?
But you'll have to help me more than ever, okay?
Good luck, Kid Killer.
Adviser Suzuki.
We should resume the meeting.
Right.
Come on, kids, I'll take you home.
Okay!
Uncle, don't forget the tickets
for Ran and Shin'ichi-kun.
Right. Ishimine.
Sorry, but please go on ahead.
All right.
Once the vehicle routes and schedules have been determined,
please let me know.
How are you going to transport the paintings to the museum?
Even if the security system
at Lake Rock is perfect,
they're most vulnerable on the way there.
Don't worry.
I have tons of dummy vehicles ready.
I'm the only one who knows what vehicle holds the real cargo.
I see. We can count on you then, Charlie-san. Just one thing...
If you plan to use that,
just remember something.
It's never right to simply take a life, no matter whose it may be.
I'll remember that.
But ideals can't be held to forever either. Reality always betrays them.
Like with Kaito Kid earlier.
Hey, brat!
What are you doing? Let's go!
Everybody's waiting.
Coming.
Looks like I'm not very liked.
Excuse me.
A package just arrived
for you with a message.
Thanks.
Who's it from? It's odd that they'd send it to me here, rather than at the office.
Relax, Lupin.
I've been spoiling you too much.
It can't be... Kid!
Let me see that.
It's certainly a Kid card.
What's that?
It looks like a present, but...
What's wrong, Lupin?
Adviser, please step back.
That's enough, Lupin, get back!
What?
Given the stench and flammability...
Is this phosphine?
It's a flammable liquid.
Everybody, get out of here!
Are you okay, Charlie?
Yes, everything's fine now.
Call Inspector Nakamori immediately.
Yes, sir.
Are you sure? This attack
could have been deadly.
If you contact the police, the exhibit will have to be postponed...
or worst case scenario,
possibly even canceled.
Certainly, Charlie-san may be right, but...
All right. I expect all of you to keep this secret too.
Understood?
Yes, sir.
Very well.
Well done, Lupin. Great job sniffing that out! You saved my life!
Charlie-san, just in case,
we should close off this room.
Right.
Kaito Kid, you've finally
shown your true colors.
I won't show any mercy.
Okay, okay!
Stop!
How many dummy trucks are they going to send?
By the way, what do you think
about what happened earlier?
About what?
Kid's motives.
If the exhibit is suspended,
the second and fifth Sunflowers paintings
will be freed from the Lake Rock Museum.
That would give him another chance to steal them.
Is that all?
If that's the case, he'd just have
to wait a month for the end of the exhibit.
I wonder why Kaito Kid's in such a hurry.
TURPENTINE
Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for coming to the Sunflowers Admired by Japan exhibit.
Now I'll hand the mic over to the man who came up with this exhibit, Jirokichi Suzuki,
to declare the exhibition open.
Well, then... Everyone who came to enjoy the charm of the Sunflowers, here's a question:
Are you ready?
Then let the Sunflowers
Admired by Japan exhibit begin!
Admission is about to begin.
Please have your tickets ready and queue in single file.
Excuse me, my name's Ran Mouri.
Can I see your ticket, please?
It's for six.
Okay, thank you.
This way, please.
We're the first ones in!
So cool!
Ran-oneesan, hurry, hurry!
Are you all together?
Yes.
Okay, please feed the tickets to the ticket gate.
Are admissions going as planned?
Yes. Both the exhibit and security systems are working perfectly.
In that case, everybody should get back to their post, other than Goto.
Yes, sir!
Hold on! Can he really
control everything by himself?
Don't worry, everything's automated.
Besides, we must minimize the amount of people entering and exiting this room.
You have a point.
What's wrong?
Nothing...
Talk about annoying...
That detective brat's here too?
Goto, have you seen
anyone acting suspiciously?
The first group of people took the lift and entered the first Sunflowers exhibit room.
But there's a single person who headed straight to the second Sunflowers exhibit room.
I'll show it on the monitor.
How odd that they'd start
with the second painting.
Can you zoom the image in a bit more?
Goto!
Yes, sir!
What's wrong with her?
Is she crying?
She must've really wanted
to see the second Sunflowers.
Adviser, it's obviously not Kid.
Let's go back to the museum-wide view.
Of course.
Please do.
Yes, sir.
Wow, they look so pretty!
But they look like fakes.
Well, if they were real, they'd wither.
I don't care if they're fake or not, but I wish they'd made them smell better.
How odd. Natsumi-san set this all up,
but she didn't say anything about any smell.
Well, no matter. Let's go see the second Sunflowers painting, which the Suzuki Financial Group owns.
Sounds good!
Let's do it!
Yeah!
Surveillance cameras?
They put them all over the place.
Conan-kun, what are you doing? Let's go!
Coming!
Look, there it is!
You're right!
Awesome!
This is the one I wanted to see.
Ran!
Quick, I just saw Shin'ichi-kun!
Really?
Shin'ichi!
Sonoko, where's Shin'ichi?
I'm sorry, I lost sight of him.
Was he really here?
Now that you mention it...
I didn't get a good look at him, so...
Could it have been someone else?
I hope so.
Since the security at the entrance do thorough bag checks and X-ray everyone,
it wouldn't be possible to get in with a disguise.
So Kid's only way in...
...would be to come as me,
since we happen to look so similar.
What's this note?
A Kid card? So he did come as me!
Is something wrong?
He's not here, either.
Sorry, I might've confused him
with somebody else.
Ran-neechan, Sonoko-neechan!
Conan-kun, don't yell.
Take me to the security center!
A Kid card! He's already
inside Lake Rock!
It's Kaito Kid!
14 = (11 PEOPLE + 1) + 2
15 = (11 PEOPLE + 1) + 2 + 1
What does this mean?
If I was to try and relate it to the Sunflowers...
Some of Van Gogh's paintings
had fifteen sunflowers.
The 4th, 5th, and 6th have fifteen.
Then, is there any painting with fourteen?
Not that I know.
No.
For Sunflowers, some believe fourteen and fifteen sunflowers refer to the same paintings.
In a letter he sent to his brother Theo,
Van Gogh referred to a painting of fifteen sunflowers as having fourteen.
Then let's say this is about
the number of sunflowers.
What does he mean with the other numbers?
If Van Gogh counted there as being fourteen sunflowers,
one theory is that he was referring to Christ's Twelve Apostles,
plus Theo and Gauguin.
Of course! That must be it!
What does that mean?
Look at the card again.
Eleven people plus one
means Christ's Twelve Apostles.
THE TWELVE APOSTLES OF CHRIST
And the plus two means Theo and Gauguin.
THEO GAUGUIN
This adds to fourteen people.
And if they're counted as having fifteen sunflowers,
the theory is that last one represents Van Gogh himself.
VAN GOGH
Let's say your interpretation is correct.
The next question then is,
what does this equation mean?
Why would Kid-sama leave us
such a hard to decipher note?
Besides, is this Kid card
really a warning note?
Well, no matter.
We'll ask Kid himself what his card means once we catch him.
I'll lock Kid inside Lake Rock.
Please help us.
Of course.
Goto, evacuate all the visitors
and museum employees.
Yes, sir.
But...
It hasn't even been an hour since we opened.
There could be a riot
if you do something like that.
Don't worry.
You never know what can
happen during the first day.
That's why I only invited company employees and people Sonoko knows today.
Adviser.
We'll take care of security,
just as planned.
I'm counting on you,
my Seven Samurai.
I see, you have an emergency protocol.
Stick to the plan, and contact
everybody else if you leave your post.
Understood.
Ladies and gentlemen,
a problem has been discovered with the exhibit.
Please, head calmly towards the lift.
Kid! Kid must've showed up!
It's time for the Detective Boys!
No way!
This time, Kid is dangerous.
Don't get away from me,
no matter what!
Okay...
How's the evacuation coming along?
All good.
The only problem could be
the inspections at the exit.
You can skip the X-rays.
Give them back their belongings and let them leave.
But if we do that, Kid will escape.
Don't worry.
He's not the kind to run away when his prey's right in front of him.
You of all people should know.
Well, I'm sure he'll stay inside.
Then let's close all entrance
and exit points and lock him in.
If he's inside Lake Rock, then he can't be in disguise nor have any of his magic trick tools.
Under these circumstances,
we're sure to catch him.
Besides, I have twelve trusted people remaining within the building.
Twelve trusted people...
Of course. He referenced the Twelve Apostles as eleven people plus one, instead of just writing twelve.
What if...
Mr Jirokichi.
The twelve trusted people match the Twelve Apostles of Christ that Kid mentioned in his card, right?
I wondered why Kid didn't
just write twelve people instead.
Could he have singled
one out on purpose?
It might be Judas.
Judas, the traitor?
Then Kid-sama was saying
that there's a traitor among us.
Does that mean somebody else besides Kid wants to steal the Sunflowers?
Adviser Suzuki.
I'd like to check the history
of the Seven Samurai once more.
It could be a ruse to make us mistrust one another,
and throw our security into chaos.
We don't need to tell them that
we're looking into their history.
Then there's no harm in checking at least.
Do it.
Right.
The visitors and employees
have left the building.
Very well. Lock everything down.
Yes, sir. Closing all exits.
Keep moving forward.
Don't stop.
The visitors and museum
employees are all leaving Lake Rock Museum.
What could have happened inside?
Apparently, nobody was
told what's going on.
The only other places with limited surveillance are the server room, and the power room.
But only authorized personnel
know where they are.
Let's give it a go...
This is Charlie. I checked all the security blind spots and found no trace of Kid.
Roger.
There's nobody left in the building. Everyone, get back to your posts.
It's almost time.
Damn! Wait, Kid!
Damn it!
What?
A blackout?
Don't worry.
Turn on the backup generator.
Yes, sir.
Prioritize the Sunflowers monitors.
Got it.
Monitors turning on.
Perfect, the Sunflowers are safe.
Good.
Turn this monitor on, too.
I've received info from Megure.
Okay.
The power's back!
Goto! What's going on?
There's trouble in the power control room.
The lights, the main lift, and the surveillance cameras all stopped working.
I'll dispatch security to the
second and fifth paintings.
Kid really did remain in the building.
No, this may not be Kid's doing at all.
What do you mean?
When we looked over the Seven Samurai's histories, a potential suspect turned up.
What?
Oh, no!
At Arles, where Van Gogh is said to have painted the seven Sunflowers paintings,
this person's twin brother
died six months ago.
Since he had a bullet wound in his chest and traces of gunpowder in his right hand,
the local police deemed it a suicide.
And who was it?
Koichi Azuma.
Azuma?
Yes. The brother of Koji Azuma,
the curator in charge of restoration.
It wasn't suicide.
I killed Koichi.
Over there, on the Sunflowers monitor!
The second monitor!
Azuma!
Why did you kill your brother?
When we found the Ashiya Sunflowers,
which we'd been searching for so long, my brother Koichi changed his mind.
The Ashiya Sunflowers was found?
What do you mean?
That painting was supposedly
destroyed during the war.
That's incorrect.
That day, when Ashiya was bombed, the city burnt as if it was Hell itself.
My grandfather was a carpenter working for a rich businessman in Ashiya,
who'd bought the Sunflowers
and had it securely fastened to the wall
so nobody could steal it.
To save it, my grandfather leapt
into the burning mansion on his own.
Azuma-san!
Ma'am!
Azuma-san, what are you...
Stay back!
No...!
Ma'am! Take the Sunflowers!
No, Azuma-san!
Watch out!
Ma'am, we have to leave!
No!
Azuma-san!
Even if we lose the war...
...we can't let the Sunflowers
be taken from us...
Azuma-san...
Azuma-san!
Ma'am, hurry!
I hope in Japan's future,
we can have a museum like the one Mushanokoji-sensei imagined.
So that the world...
...can see... the Sunflowers.
It was a story our father always used to tell us.
We kept searching for the Ashiya Sunflowers, even after he died.
All we had to go on were the words of the helper the painting was entrusted to.
The words of the helper?
To keep the Allies from confiscating it,
he passed it off as a forgery, and clandestinely introduced it into Europe.
Then the Sunflowers
I bought at the auction...
It's the Ashiya Sunflowers?
So it didn't burn after all.
Indeed. We finally found it.
A VAN GOGH SUNFLOWERS PAINTING FOUND IN FRANCE. IS IT REAL?! IS IT FAKE?!
The Ashiya Sunflowers was hidden in the attic of an old house in Arles.
But after finally finding the painting after so many years of searching,
my brother changed.
He started saying that
the Sunflowers should stay in Arles,
the place that Van Gogh loved so much.
He said that otherwise,
he'd destroy it then and there.
I couldn't forgive him for betraying our grandfather's wishes, as well as our father's.
We started fighting, and in the struggle, the gun we had to protect ourselves went off, killing my brother.
Brother, I...
Run!
Brother!
Get away, hurry!
But...
Hurry!
When I heard there of the Sunflowers Admired by Japan exhibit,
I decided to join the team as a curator.
Thanks to that, I was able
to witness the moment
when the Ashiya Sunflowers
was returned to Japan.
That way, my grandfather's wish was fulfilled.
At the end of the exhibit, I intended to turn myself in to the police.
It's a bit early, but...
Understood.
Megure from the MPD is on his way.
Will you turn yourself in?
Of course.
But I'm not the suspect you're looking for.
What are you saying?
Hey, the Sunflowers is on fire!
Don't try to trick us!
It really is on fire!
Oh no, there's a fire!
We have to put it out, quickly!
Hey, what's going on?
What do the Sunflowers
temperature sensors say?
INTERIOR TEMPERATURE RISING - 868ºC
They're giving abnormal readings.
It seems the fire is for real.
Can't you put it out?
DISASTER PREVENTION SYSTEM DOWN
No.
The disaster prevention system is down.
We have no choice.
Everyone, evacuate!
Goto, open the rooftop door!
Yes, sir!
Let's go! Everybody, with me!
Conan-kun, let's go!
Yeah.
Hurry up, sir! The fire's right there!
I know. Just a bit.
Done. Let's go, kid. Quickly!
Everybody, this way!
Hurry up and get in!
Conan-kun, hurry!
Everybody okay?
Yeah, we're all fine.
Conan-kun, are you okay?
Yeah, but...
What will happen to the Sunflowers?
Don't worry.
The program is working properly.
But the second and fifth paintings...
Don't worry, kid.
No, I know what I saw.
Two paintings are still there.
I have to do something quickly,
or the second and fifth
painting will perish in the flames.
What's going on here?
Just focus on landing.
Yes, sir.
According to Inspector Nakamori,
they'll be bringing Azuma through the back door.
Over here!
Hurry!
Charlie turned over Azuma.
But what on Earth's going on here?
There was a fire.
Sorry, but can you help guide the evacuees from above.
Understood.
We'll help.
Right!
Conan-kun!
Don't tell me, he...
Damn!
I have to hurry,
or I'll burn along with the Sunflowers!
Kid!
You came back?
Never mind that, where's the other painting?
Is the fifth painting okay?
Yeah, the pole blocking it came off easily,
but this one is caught in a weird spot.
We have to get it out ASAP,
or the paint will melt.
Move, Kid.
Wait up, you moron!
This is the Sunflowers!
It's a treasure of mankind!
Did it work?
Hey! You were aiming
for me, weren't you?
There's no time to argue!
It didn't work.
Damn it.
How strong did that old geezer make this?
Conan-kun!
Shin'ichi!
So you really were here?
Hey! Are you listening?
We have to get out of here,
it's dangerous!
- Ran!
- Ran-neechan!
We need your help.
What do you mean?
The painting's stuck.
The only way to get it out is to break the wall.
But that's impossible!
I'm sure you can do it.
I'll try.
Stand back, Shin'ichi.
You too, Conan-kun.
Please!
Ran!
All right!
I did it!
All right! Then let's get out... of here.
Watch out, Ran!
The exit's blocked!
Don't worry, stay put.
Okay...
Jii-chan, can you hear me?
Please keep calm.
Understood.
Ran!
Hang on!
Don't let go!
No way...
What the...
Looks like water's pouring out of the tank.
Do you think it can put out the fire?
Hey! Where's Conan?
He's not here?
Isn't he with you?
Ran's not here, either!
Where'd she go?
Geez, as if I didn't have enough trouble!
Where did they get to?
They were right behind us just now.
She won't answer her phone.
Uncle, they might've come down before us.
I'll see if I can find them.
Okay, thanks.
We're coming, too!
Yeah!
Kudo-kun, don't tell me you...
You okay, Detective?
Don't worry about me,
worry about Ran!
Hang on, Ran!
She's fine.
She just swallowed some
water and passed out.
Look!
The water's getting weaker!
The tanks are running out of water.
Now I'm worried about
the Sunflowers. Let's go!
Did you know about the saboteur's plan?
Yeah. If the sunflowers in the hallways were the fuze to light the fire,
I figured the tube road
could serve as a water pipe.
That means the saboteur
is the person who suggested putting the sunflowers in the tube road.
Yeah. I see you finally figured out who it is.
Come on, let's get out of here.
Hey.
How are you planning on getting out?
We'll go up the tube road to the highest floor where the exit is.
We might be able to climb out through the lift shaft.
What was your plan?
Your escape plan.
There's no way you wouldn't have one.
If I can glide to the exit I made on the other side of the cavern, I can easily escape.
But I don't think I can get there
if I have to carry you and this girl along.
Kid...
By the way, if you knew
the saboteur's plan,
why didn't you stop it?
I knew the saboteur's plan because I copied the computer files about it
but there could've been accomplices.
I tried to prevent the blackout,
but Lt Charlie found and chased me.
So I figured that if
I sent a mysterious card,
a certain somebody would figure it out, and everything would be over quicker.
Well, sorry.
Hold on, I'll get the exit ready.
I'm going to check if we
can get out from the lift hall.
Meanwhile, you catch the saboteur.
Got it.
I don't want them getting away with any more weird stuff.
Right...
I'll leave the rest to you.
Shin'ichi...
Hang on, Ran.
Oh, no...
Since it took so long to put out the fire,
the air pressure inside the cavern
is lower than I expected.
We have to get out of here quickly, the building's gonna collapse.
The door will open momentarily,
please stand back.
All right, the paintings are safe.
One, two, three, four, five, six...
That's odd, there's only six!
What?
It's true! One's missing!
How can that be?
The second painting...
The Ashiya Sunflowers isn't here!
How come that one's missing?
Don't worry!
This voice...
Shin'ichi Kudo?
Yeah. I put the Ashiya Sunflowers inside its water and fireproof case a while ago.
You again?
Sticking your nose into things!
Please just pay attention for now.
In the end, I was able
to protect the fifth painting,
as well as the Ashiya painting,
from the traitorous Judas among you.
So there really is a traitor?
Yeah, but you don't have to worry.
I've figured out who the Judas is.
Koji Azuma has already been arrested.
No, Azuma-san isn't the traitor.
That's right.
Koji Azuma had no motive
to destroy the two paintings.
Besides, when the fire started,
he was talking to you.
That's true, but there can't be
a traitor among the others.
That's right. We all protected
the Sunflowers together.
That's right. Kaito Kid is the one who suggested there might be a traitor.
We can't take the word
of a thief at face value.
That's right.
We should just be happy
that the Sunflowers are safe.
Are you sure, Natsumi Miyadai-san?
After all the effort you went
through to light the fuse.
What are you saying?
Your objective has been to burn the Ashiya Sunflowers, as well as the fifth painting.
You've wanted to destroy these two Sunflowers from the start.
Don't be stupid!
Why would I want to do that?
Very well.
Let's discuss the events one by one.
Kaito Kid caused a giant mess in the auction room, causing security to be reinforced,
which prevented you from getting too close to the Sunflowers.
Because of that, you had to give up on your attempt to destroy
the Sunflowers in the US.
Then, while the painting
was being transported to Japan,
you bribed a worker to place
a bomb on the door of the cargo hold.
But this too was thwarted by Kid.
And you changed your target from the second painting to the fifth.
Kaito Kid figured it out right away,
and sent Detective Mouri a warning note,
so security was increased again.
Kid thwarted your plans twice,
so to get ahead of him,
you planted a fake Kid card
under the lid of the wooden box
used to transport the painting,
and proposed that the painting
should be taken to your studio.
Then Kid was playing the villain
to protect the Sunflowers?
Lies! You're just making this up!
She's right.
Natsumi loves Van Gogh's Sunflowers more than anyone, she'd never do such a thing.
Right. Besides, why would she want to destroy just these two paintings?
Indeed.
I still don't know why she wanted to destroy those two specifically.
What a worthless deduction.
We can ask Natsumi-san
what her motive is later.
Let's get to the point.
Natsumi-san, if my information is correct,
you're the one who suggested decorating the Lake Rock tube road with sunflowers, right?
Yes.
Taking advantage of your position as an appraiser, you obtained turpentine,
which is usually used to restore paintings,
and poured it into the sunflowers' track from the top floor,
turning them into a fuse.
The traitor could've just used my suggestion to their own advantage.
Don't call me a criminal over such weak circumstancial evidence!
I see...
The truth is, I wanted you
to confess on your own.
But if you want concrete
evidence, then fine.
I have files with information on your plan to destroy the two paintings, taken from your PC.
I guess there's no point in hiding it.
You joined my team just to destroy the fifth painting and the Ashiya one?
Yes. But with Kaito Kid's
constant interruptions,
I couldn't manage it.
That's why you decided to set the Lake Rock Museum on fire,
so you could burn the Sunflowers,
since Kid would have trouble getting here.
Yeah, but at first I didn't
plan for it to turn out like this.
I wanted to take advantage of the blackout to destroy the fifth and the Ashiya paintings.
After that, everything would be over.
But Kid wasn't the only one
who got in the way.
I'm sending agents to protect
the second and fifth paintings.
But how did you intend to destroy them?
A single touch would
activate the security system.
Easy.
By covering them in phosphine.
Phosphine?
It's a substance that lights up on fire spontaneously at room temperature.
Which means, you're the one
who tried to kill me, right?
Of course! If the sponsor died, the opening would be postponed,
and the exhibit might even be canceled.
But why?
The fire, the plane explosion...
A single mistake, and you
could've died, too, Natsumi!
I...
That just shows how much
I love the Van Gogh Sunflowers!
I'd rather die than let those two fakes
be exhibited next to the authentic Sunflowers!
There's no truth to that.
The Art Institute of Chicago
and the Van Gogh Museum
already proved that the fifth Sunflowers painting is authentic.
Van Gogh and Gauguin shared a single canvas to paint two paintings.
The evidence is as clear as it gets.
As an appraiser,
you should know that, too.
But...
Besides, you said
you'd rather die,
but you had the bomb explode
just before the plane was to land.
And when you caused this fire,
you made sure you had enough time to escape.
That's...
If you really were willing to die, why didn't you stay at Lake Rock, and stop Kid from putting out the fire?
In the end, you're a selfish person who only thought about herself.
A criminal.
You're no curator.
So it was you all along.
Your hands.
She loved Van Gogh's paintings so much,
that she trusted her own misconceptions over the appraised truth and ended up turning into a criminal.
Well, looks like you're done.
Yeah. What about you?
Think you can climb out?
If I went alone, yeah.
Then what?
Do we ask for help?
We better not. It would
only make things worse.
Watch out!
You okay?
Yeah. How long is this
place going to last?
I'm surprised it still is.
One tiny gap in the ceiling and air will come in from the outside, and everything will crumble.
Kid!
Could you glide out of here
carrying just Ran?
Hey! Don't say...
Can you or can't you?
Yes or no?
Probably yes.
But dodging the falling rocks
with such a low atmospheric
pressure is going to be tough.
Ran!
Kid!
Save Ran!
Damn it! This isn't the time to play hero!
With my child body,
I might still be able to find a way out.
Damn it! At this rate, we're gonna fall!
Where's the exit?
There it is!
Let's go!
I should be able to fit
into the Sunflowers escape shaft.
Damn it!
The Ashiya Sunflowers!
Damn, the water tower!
We have to find them, quickly!
This isn't looking good!
Look!
Oh, no... You're not still in there, are you?
That was close!
I just barely escaped.
Shin'ichi...
You saved me.
Yeah, you'll be okay.
Yeah.
Where are you going, Haibara-san?
Kid and Ran-san just came out gliding!
What?
Seriously? Let's check it out.
Sonoko-oneesan!
Ran-oneesan and Kid are gliding!
- Ran and Kid-sama?
- What? Where?
Kid?
Damn it, this way won't work either.
I'm out of exits.
At this rate, I'll end up dying
with the Ashiya Sunflowers.
Seriously?
Tell me you managed to escape, Detective.
Ran!
Where are you, Ran?
Ah, Ran! Are you okay?
Dad...
Ran! Are you hurt? You okay?
Yeah. Shin'ichi saved me.
You're wrong. It was Kid.
Flying with his hang glider!
Don't you remember?
Oh, of course... I...
Then that wasn't Shin'ichi, but Kid...
And where's the brat, do you know?
Conan-kun's not here?
No, Kid only brought you.
No way!
Then Conan-kun's still...
Seriously?
No way...
Damn it!
At this rate, never mind escaping, I'll drown in less than a minute.
I might be able to move
this with my ball,
but that won't stop everything sinking.
That's it... Underwater!
All this water pouring in means that I'm already below the lake's water level.
So if I use my fireworks ball
to alter how it's collapsing,
and change the pressure, I'll be pushed...
Straight into the lake!
All right, let's do it!
Five, four, three...
Two, one, zero!
Conan-kun!
What are you doing, Conan?
Please, get out of there!
Damn it, what are you doing?
Conan!
Don't worry. I'm sure
Conan-kun can do it.
Please... get out of there!
Conan-kun...
A little further...
Just a little further...
Something's coming out!
The Sunflowers!
Oh, it's safe!
Conan-kun was with me
when I put that painting in the case.
He must be nearby!
Everybody, please find him!
Conan-kun!
Conan-kun, where are you?
Ran...
Something's floating up again!
Yeah, past the painting!
Where?
I'll get him!
- You did it, Conan-kun...
- Are you okay?
Well done, kid!
That's how you do it, Kid Killer!
You okay, brat?
You managed to protect
the Sunflowers. Good job!
As usual, he gets all the glory.
There's something I still don't understand.
Would you tell me?
How did you know who the traitor was all along?
Because I received
an audio message offering me a job.
Steal the second and fifth
Sunflowers paintings.
I see.
You're a disguise expert,
so you can easily recognize
other people's voices, right?
But why did you prevent her plan?
What was in it for you?
I wanted to show
the Ashiya Sunflowers to somebody.
Show them to somebody?
That day, in the inferno
that was the Ashiya bombing,
a carpenter entrusted the Sunflowers to a woman who secretly loved him.
She saw him die before her very eyes.
How do you know that
if it happened so long ago?
A man who saw it happen told me about it.
A man who was once a live-in errand boy in that home when he was young.
The man who saved
his first love from that fire...
He asked me for help.
He told me he wanted
to show her the Ashiya Sunflowers.
I see. That clears up everything.
Aren't you going to arrest me?
I'll let you go this time.
But we both know you wouldn't be able to catch me, anyway.
Let's just say I'll look away this time,
out of respect for the man
who asked for your help,
and his tragic love story.
I was wrong about you, Lt Charlie.
Same to you.
No, no, no!
Where is it?
Where did I put it?
If I can't find it after searching for so long,
somebody must've stolen it!
Who was it? Who stole my ticket?
Aren't you going to tell him
the exhibit was canceled?
He'll see it in the news.
Why are you so cold today?
Apparently, if I even look at you, I'll regret it.
Huh? What's that supposed to mean?
It's a piece of advice I was given.
Let me find it, even one little tick of it!
My ticket!
Kir, Bourbon...
Are you...
Movie 20 coming April 2016.
Production confirmed!