Mom?!
Stay away, Ran!
Just a dream...
Eh? You dreamed I was shot?
Is that why you called me so early in the morning?
Oh, come on, I was worried!
Sometimes even lawyers get people who have grudges against them...
You're just being paranoid, Ran.
It's because of all those crimes you've seen
that you have dreams like that.
But I'm glad you're all right!
Oh, yeah! You were a little younger in my dream, you know!
My! How rude! I'll have you know I'm still young!
Oh, I'm sorry! Please forgive my rudeness!
Very well, then!
Okay, so 7:00 tonight, right?
Dad and Conan-kun can't wait, either!
I wonder... Does she remember?
Conan-kun...
What's goin' on? Why're you up so early?
Oh, no reason. Sorry for waking you up.
Oh, it's tonight! Our dinner date with Ran's mom...
Man, I really don't like dealing with her.
The Fourteenth Target
I'm high school detective Kudo Shinichi.
I went with old friend and classmate,
Mouri Ran, to an amusement park
where I witnessed a suspicious deal with a man dressed in black!
I was so absorbed with watching the deal
that I didn't notice a second man sneak up from behind me!
He forced me to take a poison, and when I woke up...
...my body had shrunk!
If they learned Kudo Shinichi was alive, they might go after me again,
putting all the people around me in danger!
Following Professor Agasa's advice,
I decided to conceal my identity.
When Ran asked my name,
I quickly answered, "Edogawa Conan."
To get information on the men,
I wound up living with Ran and her detective father.
Yes. This guy is Ran's father...
...and the now-incredibly famous detective, Mouri Kogoro.
But he's really a bonehead detective...
...and you all know who's really solving the crimes, right?
The secret behind that is in the two gadgets Professor Agasa made for me!
The first... is this!
The Stun-Gun Wrist-Watch!
Pressing the button while using the aiming device on the cover
will launch a tranquilizer needle that can knock a person out instantly!
Next is the Voice-Changing Bow-Tie!
By adjusting the dials on the back,
I can produce all types of voices, from children to adult!
For offensive items, I have the Power Assisted Kick Shoes!
They use electricity and magnetic fields to stimulate my feet muscles
and maximize my kick power!
To chase down criminals, I have the Turbo-Engine Skateboard!
And an unexpectedly sweet item are these Elasticity Suspenders!
One press of a button, and the rubber will expand or contract!
It's a really unique gadget!
I can't ID the men in black yet, but other cases won't wait for me!
Even when I'm small, my mind remains that of a sharp detective!
There is always only one truth!
BEIKA PRISON
Former Card Dealer
Murakami Jou (35)
Beika Station Shop
Genta-kun! You're gonna eat that one, too?!
Who cares how many I eat?!
This one's a Black Choco Bar!
It's got a grownup taste!
Oh?! Really?!
Yeah, right.
Geez, what's taking him so long?
Look! Look!
You and your boyfriend
are a complete match!
Conan-kun and I are a perfect match!
A-are you sure that game's not broken?!
B-but more importantly, Genta-kun!
Card fortune-telling is obviously a pack of lies!
Now let's check Conan-kun's!
His birthday is...
Hey, now.
Don't be tellin' people's fortunes without their permission.
A sudden closeness to your special someone!
It must be talking about me and Conan-kun!
A chance for an "A"
A chance for an "A".
Note: In Japan, relationship stages are assigned the letters A,
B and C. "A" stands for a kiss, and "C" is going all the way".
"A"?!
"A"? Geez. what year is that game from, anyway?
Hey. What does "A" mean?
The letter A, you see, is the one before the letter B...
So it means fried shrimp!
Note: Ebi-fry = Fried Shrimp, A Followed by B, thus A-B, or Ebi.
Hmm. So it doesn't mean "kiss".
Sorry! Sorry! I overslept!...Huh?
Geez! What took you so long, Doc?!
Sorry...
Touto Aeronautic Memorial Museum
Awesome!
Look at all the planes!
I hear you can even play a helicopter flight simulator here!
That sounds like fun!
Yeah!
Too bad!
Why's that, Conan?
It says here only fifth graders and up can do the flight simulator!
Aww, that's no fun.
Sorry, I played it to death when I got into 5th grade.
In that case, how about I tell you all an interesting story?
Hey. We're in for a long story if we don't stop him now.
Leave it to me.
Note: Pegasus is a beautiful winged horse in Greek mythology.
The "Pegasus" from Greek mythology is-
Tadah! And now for a quiz!
Huh? What're you doing?
Three people who were born on New Year's Day, April Fool's Day,
Note: Children's Day is a national holiday in Japan, celebrated on May 5th.
and Children's Day all got together and formed a club!
So, what was their club's name?
Here's a hint: it's a flying animal, much like the Pegasus!
A flying animal?
Oh? You figured it out, Conan-kun?
Of course! You just need to add their birthdays, right?
Birthdays?
January 1st, April 1st, May 5th... October 7th?
Yep! October 7th!
Note: The kanji, 会 (kai), means club. These kinds of puns are called goroawase.
It's "To-na-kai". Reindeer!
To
na
kai
And they fly while pulling a sled on Christmas, right?
Correct! You're so smart, Conan-kun!
Hey! Isn't that Shishido Eimei?!
Photographer
Shishido Eimei
He's so cool!
Thank you very much.
Next person, please.
Essayist
Nishina Minoru
Alright.
Here you go!
Thank you so much! I'm a big fan of yours, Nishina-san!
Please continue to write lots of delicious books!
That's a unique comment. Thank you.
He's even hotter than he is in pictures!
His type is my favorite!
You're so silly, Sonoko...
What a reckless driver!.
Wait, isn't she...
Model
Osanai Nana
It is Osanai Nana, the model!
I have no interest in women.
Let's get some tea!
What time do you have dinner with your mom?
7:00.
Did you set it up again this time too?
Yeah.
You sure have it rough, too.
What was it, ten years ago when your mom left?
Yeah. When I was seven...
...I remember them having a big argument.
Apparently they split because of personality conflicts.
And then in no time flat...
...your mom began to flourish as a lawyer, right?
In contrast, your dad quit his job as a police detective,
and became a lousy private eye instead.
Wha?
Yeah! Your dad's suddenly all famous and stuff now,
but I bet he would've ruined himself by now had you not been there.
I don't think so, but my mom was really with-it in that regard.
Mouri Detective Agency
I'm back!
Welcome back!
Huh? He's still not ready?
He went to play mahjong during lunch and just got back now!
Geez! Why do I hafta eat dinner with Eri?!
Please quit complaining and get ready already.
I'm here at the house of Asahi Katsuyoshi-san,
owner of Aqua Crystal,
the aquatic recreation center opening today by the Touto Bay!
Aquacrystal Owner
Asahi Katsuyoshi (61)
Conan-kun.
I'll change too!
French Restaurant "LaFleur"
Sorry, Mom! We ran a little late!
That's all right. I'm sure "someone" was busy playing mahjong.
She's as sharp as ever.
I'll have to watch what I say in front of her.
Hello, Conan-kun!
H-hello!
You're so scatterbrained, Tsuji-san!
Oh! Long time, no see, Mouri-san!
Oh! Tsuji-san!
Who's Mouri?
Professional Golfer
Tsuji Hiroki
You know, the detective.
Oh! You mean that famous detective?
Mouri Kogoro?
Yes. I am detective Mouri Kogoro.
Oh, Tsuji-san! Let me introduce my family!
This is my wife Eri, and my daughter Ran.
And that's Conan, the freeloader.
Isn't there any other way to say that?!
Note: Pro-ams are golf tournaments where celebrities play with golf pros, usually for charity.
I'm Tsuji. I played with Mouri-san in a pro-amateur golf tournament.
That reminds me, Tsuji-san.
Doesn't the U.S. Open begin next Thursday?
Yes! I basically practiced an entire year for this one tournament!
This year, I will make it to the top ten for sure!
I look forward to it!
But sometimes it's important to take a breather,
so I thought I might take the girls out for a flight tomorrow.
Tsuji-san here also owns and pilots his own helicopter, you see.
Say! I'm planning to fly the following Thursday, too!
Why don't you come along?
Wow! Really?!
Sounds wonderful!
Yay!
No, uhh, flying isn't really my thing, so maybe some other time.
Oh? That's too bad.
He's no fun.
That man's name is Sawaki-san,
and he's known my mom and dad since they were young.
What's that grape badge for?
That's the symbol of a sommelier.
A sommelier is someone in charge of wines, like him.
Sommelier
Sawaki Kouhei
What's that around his neck?
That's a "tastevin", used to taste the wine
Whoa, you really know your stuff.
I read about it in Nishida-san's books!
For example, red wine is best at room temperature,
and white wine and rose are best chilled!
It's true that many people say that,
but a wine's best temperature is really up to personal preference.
Excellent.
Light red wine is actually quite delicious when chilled.
The key is that a wine's astringency is diminished when cooled.
Really?
Still, I can't believe you're old enough
to be interested in that sort of thing now.
That just means that we've gotten that much older.
That's for sure.
They seem to be getting along well now!
Oh, Conan-kun! Your mouth's all messy!
N-no, that's okay...
Come on, now! Don't move!
A chance for an "A"
A chance for an "A".
Sheesh! Kids are such a pain!
Urgh!
That was delicious.
The wine and food here tastes just like it did back then!
Say. Do you remember?
When we first came to this restaurant 15 years ago,
you gave me a present.
Yeah. Your favorite Zigoba chocolates.
And then we ate them all on a bench at Beika Park on our way home.
Oh, that's right.
Towako-san!
Who's he?!
Isn't that Peter Ford?
Mistress of Club " Towako"
Okano Towako
Newscaster
Peter Ford
The guy who's on TV as a host of several shows.
Dammit! What's she doing with him?!
Who's Towako-san?
She runs a hostess club in Ginza.
She's been extra generous whenever I've-
I should be going now.
Already? I thought we might have some coffee back-
I'm sorry. I still have work to finish.
Thank you for the meal.
Mom!
Dad!
Towako-san disappeared somewhere!
The old guy never learns...
One week later
Midoridai Police Hospital
Come in.
Note: Megure's first name, Juuzou, is the kanji for the number thirteen(Juusan),
but the pronunciation is different when used in the context of a name.
Megure Juusan?
That's read "Juuzou".
Oh!
Oh, Genta-kun!
So Inspector Megure's name is Juuzou, huh?
Oh, Mouri-kun! You came all this way?
And everyone else, too?
We were all just about to go hiking.
Inspector. How is your injury?
Luckily, it missed a vital spot, so there's no danger to his life,
but they say he'll need to stay here for a few days.
Hey, Inspector.
Why do you always have a hat on?
Oh, uh, does it really matter?
I bet his hair is thinning.
Maybe he has a huge bump on his head.
We believe a handgun-type crossbow was used.
We're investigating this from two directions:
whether he was attacked specifically, or just for fun as he passed by.
Hey, old inspector guy!
Didn't you have a gun?!
And you still let him get away?
Of course he wouldn't have a gun on him while jogging!
Plus, even if I had had one, I'm a horrible shot, unlike Mouri-kun here.
Eh?! My dad is good with guns?!
Enough to have been one of the best shots on the entire force!
I guess everyone's good at something...
However, something odd was found where the crossbow was fired.
Here it is.
What is that?
It looks like a western sword.
Huh?! I've seen this somewhere before!
But where?
Good morning!
Good morning! That's a nice brooch!
Note: Sensei can be used as an honorific for certain professionals; in this case, a lawyer.
Here is your schedule for today, Sensei.
And I found this in the mailbox downstairs.
Oh, Zigoba!
Those are your favorite Swiss chocolates, aren't they?
Ah! So he...
But I don't see the sender's name...
It's all right. I know who's responsible for it.
Wow!
Water! Water...
Sensei!
Touto University Hospital
How's my mother?!
Rest easy!
We flushed her stomach immediately, so there's no danger to her life!
Thank goodness...
Was it poison, then?
Yes. We believe it was agrochemical in type.
Mom!
Mom...
Ran...
Eri...
Dear, you came!
Are you okay, Auntie?
Even you, Conan-kun?
Thank you. I'm okay now.
Just to be safe, she should probably stay here for today.
Sounds good to me.
Still, first the inspector, and now Eri...
Is this just coincidence?
Incidentally, I hear she collapsed the moment she ate some chocolate?
Yes. It was apparently in the agency's mailbox.
Zigoba!
A-and... this paper flower!
You don't mean... the same person did this?!
Huh? That flower...
Where?! Where have I seen it?!
Agasa's House
But why would someone so cautious eat poisoned chocolate?
Yeah. The old man got Ran's mom mad at dinner the other night.
Apparently she mistook it as his apology.
I see.
Here you are! Repairs complete!
Who pulled this prank?!
Doc! Don't open it!
Doc!
I'm fine! Go after him, Shin'ichi!
But!
Go, Shin'ichi! Go after him!
Got it!
Which way did he go?!
Ayumi and Genta live down this left street...
Alright!
Oh, Conan-kun!
You say a black offroad bike?
Note: Ofu-roodo is "offroad". but Genta misheard it as "ofuro-ya" or bathouse.
A black bath house bike? What's that?
That's it! That's an offroad bike, Genta-Kun!
C-Conan!
Roger that!
So he did turn left!
Conan-kun! He just turned right, toward Beika Station!
Roger that!
Alright! I gotta beat him there!
Yes! Found ya!
I'm not letting him get away!
There's no way I'm letting him get away!
Note: Obaa-san is used to address an old lady politely.
Are you okay, Obaa-san?
Thank you!
What's this?
That's it! I figured it out!
Beika Central Hospital
Playing cards?
Yeah.
The culprit is doing these crimes to match the pictures on the cards.
Inspector Megure was attacked first, and his name is Juuzou, right?
Megure
Juuzou
You write it as "thirteen", or the King of Spades.
Doesn't the sword that the king is holding
match the one found at the scene?
Next, Ran-neechan's mother's maiden name is Kisaki,
which means "queen" in English.
Kizaki
Thus, the Queen of Spades.
The queen holds the same flower as the one with the chocolate.
He's right! They're the same!
But what about Professor Agasa and the number eleven?
His name is Agasa Hiroshi,
Agasa
Juuzou
Note: The character 土 (shi) means samurai.
and the character for "shi" is a combination of ten and one.
Shi
That's why he's the Jack of Spades.
"Jack" originally refers to soldiers, thus this sword-like object...
They're the same! No doubt about it!
But why playing cards? And why spades?
Spades refer to death.
Similarly, hearts refer to love,
diamonds refer to money, and clubs refer to happiness.
Then is the culprit planning to follow the playing cards in order
and kill people with the numbers 13 to 1 in their names?
More specifically, people connected to you.
But who would do this?
Our only clue was the motorcycle's license plate number,
but it turned out to be stolen.
Inspector!
What are you doing here?
I heard that first Eri-san was attacked, then Professor Agasa too...
But what about your wound?
It's been sewed up! I'm fine!
I heard everything. The culprit is most likely Murakami Joe.
Murakami Joe?!
Who is he?
A maverick gambling dealer.
He committed a murder ten years ago,
and was just released one week ago on parole.
A gambling dealer?
A person who deals out cards to gambling patrons.
This is Murakami Joe, 10 years ago.
Murakami, huh...
It's true that I wouldn't be surprised if he held a grudge against me.
Why's that?
Because I arrested him.
Hold on! It's only natural that policemen arrest criminals!
That's true, but...
Actually, I have heard about that incident.
If I'm not mistaken, after he was taken to the police station...
Shiratori-Kun! We don't need to hear the story!
But why wouldn't Murakami Joe come straight after me?
He could deal with me directly...
Probably to make you suffer.
So as to ruin you slowly but surely.
Say, is there anyone you know with a "ten" in their name?!
They might be the next person to be attacked!
Note: "Juu" and "tou" are two ways to say ten in Japanese.
Ten, huh? Juu... Tou...
Towako-san!
Club Towako
Welcome.
Oh! Mouri-sensei!
Towako-san!
You're all right!
"All right?" Did something happen?
Umm, Shiratori-san. What were you going to say back at the hospital?
You know, about that Murakami guy!
Oh. Well, I guess I'll tell you since you could find out easily enough.
I heard this from a superior officer.
Ten years ago, when Mouri-san was a police detective,
he and Inspector Megure-
Or was he still an assistant inspector back then?
In any case, the two of them arrested Murakami Joe for murder.
While they were interrogating him at the police station,
Murakami said he wanted to use the restroom.
Mouri-san and the inspector ordered an officer to take him there,
then took a smoke break in front of the interrogation room.
Just then, you and your mother arrived to bring a change of clothes.
That's when it happened.
Murakami managed to steal the officer's gun in the restroom.
I remember.
Just then, I...
Get a car ready!
This woman and I have a rendezvous at the ends of Hell!
Mom!
Ran! Stay away!
Mouri-kun.
What's on your mind?
Oh, nothing!
You're saying he shot her?!
I had forgotten until just now!
It must've been something you didn't want to remember.
But... But why would Dad shoot her?!
He must've been really confident about his skill.
Confident he could miss the hostage and hit only the criminal...
But the bullet missed and hit your mother instead.
Apparently, the fact he shot without concern for the hostage
caused quite some trouble for him at the police station, too...
I believe it was soon afterwards that your father left the force.
Hello?
Hey, Ran! Been a while!
Shin'ichi?!
Professor Agasa filled me in on everything.
Sounds like some bad stuff is going down.
It's much more than "bad"!
Where are you?! Come back right away!
Sorry, I'm in the middle of a case here.
I won't be back for a while.
Oh...
Don't get all glum on me!
But the doc and the inspector gave me a summary of what's up,
so if I figure anything out I'll call right away!
Tell me. Would you shoot, Shin'ichi?
I found out why my mom really left my dad.
The Kogoro-san shot your mom, huh...
I don't care how confident he was...
I can't believe what he did.
You would never do anything like that, right, Shin'ichi?!
Good question... I dunno.
But even if it's a fact that your dad shot your mom,
are you sure that equals the truth behind it?
What do you mean?!
That doesn't make sense!
Anyways, that's all I can say.
Cheer up, Ran!
Later!
Wait!
Shin'ichi?! Shin'ichi?!
The truth...
Inspector! I'll watch the emergency exit!
Wait! Mouri-kun!
He gets really fired up when there's a pretty woman involved...
The old guy never came home...
Still, why would Murakami Joe leave clues that point straight to him?
Is he trying to challenge the old guy and the police?
But how did Murakami research his acquaintances from behind bars?
He even knew Ran's mother's favorite brand of chocolate...
Tsuji Hiroki...
Note: The character 辻 (Tsuji) has a radical of ten (＋) within the character.
Tsuji
Hiroko
Tsuji...
Ten
Tsuji Hiroki? The pro golfer?
Yes! Conan-kun noticed it, but Tsuji's name has a "ten" in it!
Tsuji...
She's right! There is one!
I called his home, but he left for the heliport thirty minutes ago!
Got it!
Contact the station and have them send someone to keep watch here.
Yes, sir!
Conan-kun! Let's go, too!
Let's go, Mouri-kun!
Go? To get breakfast?
Dad!
Hey, you! What're you doing here?!
Don't give us that!
We're involved in this too, you know!
I'm your daughter!
So, people connected to Mouri-san are being attacked one by one?
Yes. Counting down from 13.
And since you're number ten, you're in danger now!
Anyways, it'd be wise to cancel your flight for today.
I'll be fine!
If you're that worried, why don't you and Mouri-san come with me?
No, flying isn't really-
Incidentally, where is your flight to today?
Touto Airport. With other places along the way, though.
When did you submit your flight plan?
Hmm... The day before yesterday, at the Aviation Bureau.
Inspector.
There's a chance Murakami is lying in wait at Touto Airport.
Alright! You head for Touto Airport in the car!
Yes, sir!
Mouri-Kun! Just to be safe, we're going to ride the helicopter, too!
Ran-kun! I know how you feel, but this is as far as you go.
But!
Fine.
Inspector! I'd prefer to go with Detective Shiratori in the car!
Are you trying to run away on your own?!
I, uhh, need to use the restroom!
I-Inspector! I don't want to die too!
Get in! If you die, we'll die together!
So we are gonna die!
Well, I'm off.
Conan-kun. We should get going-
Huh? Where are you?!
He couldn't be!
One sheep! Two sheep!
Is that an anti-crashing spell?
Conan-kun!
When did you...?!
I always wanted to try sitting next to a pilot's seat!
Welcome to my cockpit!
We'll be flying over Beika City where you live.
Yay! That's great!
We have no choice.
We can't exactly go back now.
But if you cause any trouble,
I'm tossin' you out!
Nothing seems out of the ordinary...
Whatcha lookin' at?
You're in a helicopter here!
Take a look outside!
Is something the matter?
Not at all.
Say, you applied some eyedrops earlier.
Do you always use them?
Yeah, when I'm driving, or when I'm piloting my helicopter.
We're almost over Beika City.
Huh? You're right!
Mouri-Kun! There's your place, too!
I don't wanna look!
What's wrong?!
It's too bright! I can't open my eyes!
Say what?!
Wait! Were those eyedrops-!
Then that means...!
Oji-san, We are drifting to the left!
Note: Oji-san is used to address a middle aged man politely.
M-Mouri-kun! Do you know how to fly?!
Of course I don't!
We can't stay in the air like this!
I gotta find a place we can land!
Teitan Elementary! Alright!
Huh?!
We'll try to land at the school ground,
so Oji-san, you watch the pedals and the collective.
Note: Collective Pitch is the equal, unified angling of all helicopter
blades. Pilots use Collective Pitch to rise and fall vertically.
You idiot! Cut that out! Are you trying to kill us?
Don't worry.
I practiced lots on flight simulators a lot when I was a kid!
B-but your still are a kid!
Tsuji-san! We're gonna crash if we don't do something now!
Help me out!
Alright! Let's do it!
A-are you serious?!
Altitude 300 feet, speed 40 knots. I'm ready.
H-here goes!
Elevation, 200 feet! Speed, 30 knots!
Press the right pedal 10 degrees!
The schoolyard is dead-ahead!
Distance, 500 feet!
Hey, Genta! Do you read me?! Genta!
Is that you, Conan?
I'm about to emergency land a helicopter!
Get everyone out of there!
Helicopter?
Note: Genta says "ochiru"(堕ちる) which means "to crash", but Conan says "ochiru" (落ちる)
which means "to land". While they have the same pronunciation their meanings are different.
Hey, everyone! Run! A helicopter is crashing down!
Like hell it's gonna crash!
We're spinning left!
Hit the right pedal hard!
Oh no! We're in a downwash!
It really did crash!
Is Conan-kun in there?!
I'm alive!
Conan-kun!
Are you all right, Tsuji-san?!
The fuel is leaking!
What?!
It exploded!
Aren't helicopters expensive?!
The rotors alone cost around 10 million yen.
How many unajuu is that?
Note: Unajuu is grilled eel over rice.
Beika Central Hospital
But I'm just glad everyone's safe.
But Professor, It's so unfair.
He got to pilot a real helicopter all by himself...
That's not the issue here! I thought we were going to die!
About that...
Tsuji-san's vitamin eyedrops had been switched with dilation drops.
Dilation drops?
Medicine used to open up the pupils to treat pseudomyopia and such.
Ah. So that's why the sunlight overwhelmed his eyes...
Except the ones Tsuji-san used are to treat something called "iritis".
Iritis?
How are they different?
Pseudomyopia drops take effect in 5 minutes, and don't last long.
But medicine for iritis takes over twenty minutes,
and it lasts a long time.
A long time?
It varies by patient,
but the pupils will be dilated anywhere from ten days to two weeks.
That long?!
But that means the U.S Open that starts on Thursday...
He probably has no choice but to cancel...
Say, when did the culprit switch the eyedrops?
About that...
This morning, after Tsuji-san took his car out of the garage,
he apparently applied his eyedrops in the car.
Immediately after, he heard glass break,
so he left the eyedrops on the center console and went back inside.
Apparently, a rock had been thrown through a window.
A rock?
That's what happened to Professor Agasa!
However, Tsuji-san figured it was just some kid's prank,
so he had the maids take care of it and left.
There's no question that the culprit threw the rock!
And Tsuji-san's eyedrops were switched while he was in the house!
Yes. Most likely.
Inspector.
There is no doubt that Murakami Joe is responsible.
We found this.
The 10 of Spades...
Mouri-kun! "Nine" is the next one to be attacked!
Do you know anyone with a "nine" in their name?!
I can't think of anyone, but I do know an eight.
Eight?
Yes, Sawaki-san, a sommelier.
Sawaki
Kouhei
Note: The kanji 公 (kou) has a meaning of public.
His name is Kouhei,
Kou
and the top portion of "kou" is the number eight.
Alright! Let's meet this Sawaki fellow!
So this Murakami person is attacking your acquaintances one by one
to get revenge on you, Mouri-san?
Yes.
Still, you certainly do seem calm, Mouri-san...
Well, I'm five, so there are still a few more to go.
Note: The middle character in 小五郎 (Kogoro) means "five".
Wine...
That's called a "wine cooler".
It keeps wine at the proper temperature.
There sure is a lot in it!
Sawaki-san's family runs a fruit orchard in Yamanashi Prefecture,
Note: Yamanashi Prefecture is located just west of Tokyo.
and he has hundreds of bottles of wine stored there!
Isn't that right?
Yes. I thought I'd keep some for whenever I open my own restaurant.
I'm quite fond of wine, may I take a quick look?
Certainly.
Oww!
The wood flooring is scratched up!
Oh, are you all right? I dropped a bottle there the other day.
Conan-kun. You're not wearing slippers, so be careful.
Margaux, Lafite, Haut-Brion...
Such an impressive collection of top-quality wine!
Come to think of it, what was it called, your treasured wine...?
Peto...
You have Château Pétrus, too?!
Château Pétrus?
That's the wine Poirot drank in "Death on the Nile"!
Note: "Death on the Nile" is a book by Agatha Christie.
I did, but I drank it the other day.
Huh?! But I thought it takes years until it's ready to drink?
I just couldn't help myself.
Sawaki-san. We can talk wine another day.
Can you tell us your plans for today?
Do you know Asahi Katsuyoshi-san?
He's a businessman who operates dozens of restaurants in the city.
Oh, I've done a job for Asahi-san in the past!
I hear he's building an entertainment complex
called Aquacrystal on Tokyo Bay.
Yes. He's offered to let me run a restaurant there,
I have an appointment with him at three o'clock.
Asahi Katsuyoshi?
Asahi?
Wait a second.
Nine! There is a number nine in Asahi!
Asahi
Nine
Which means he's the next to be attacked.
But he only hired me to find his pet cat.
We're not really acquaintances...
Murakami might not think so.
In any event, let's protect Sawaki-san and meet with Asahi-san!
Is that all right, Sawaki-san?
Yes. I don't mind.
Then you and Conan-kun-
Are coming.
Conan-Kun and I are coming, too!
I've had enough of this, Ran! This isn't a game!
That's right! Lots of people are being attacked because of you!
I can't just wait for my turn to come!
Ran...
That's Aqua Crystal?
What a...
flashy building!
What a reckless driver!
A little bit off. But not too bad.
Hey! That was dangerous, Neechan!
Note: In this case, Kogoro doesn't mean older sister, but just a younger woman.
What was...?
You know...
Oh, Nana-chan! You too?
Oh, Asahi-san invited you too, Shishido-sensei?!
Note: Ojou-san is a very polite way to call a young lady.
Excuse me, Ojou-san, but who are you people?
Huh? Oji-san, you don't know who I am?
She's Osanai Nana-san, Inspector.
A popular model.
Those three are from left to right-
the essayist Nishina-san,
the photographer Shishido Eimei-san, and...
Peter Ford.
I take it you two are policemen?
And the famous Mouri Kogoro-san?
You're that famous detective?!
I've never seen the real one before!
Shishido-sensei!
Can you take a pricture of us?
Uh... Peace!
Note: "Peace!" is similar to saying "Cheese!" before taking a picture in English.
Oh, geez. Where'd that anger just now go?
This is Sawaki Kouhei-san, a sommelier,
Mouri-san's daughter, Ran-san, and Edogawa Conan-kun.
Oh, you're the "delicious book" girl.
Wow! You remember me?!
Beautiful wine and women always remain in people's hearts.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Have you all been asked here by Asahi-san?
Yes, at three o'clock.
I was also invited at three.
Same here.
Inspector. Has there been some sort of incident?
Yes, as a matter of fact...
Hey, it's almost three. Let's go already.
Oh, right! Let's head to the restaurant for now!
Huh? Come to think of it, all four people called here are-
Is the monorail the only way to get to Aqua Crystal?
Huh? There's no driver!
It looks like you just need to press this button.
This is quite something!
A-are you not good with hanging in the air either, Nishina-san?
No, I just can't stand water, since I'm a kanazuchi
Note: Kanazuchi (かなづち) means hopeless swimmer.
Y-yeah, everyone has their little quirks.
Even if it's a fact that your dad shot your mom,
are you sure that equals the truth behind it?
It's like an aquarium! This totally is an underwater restaurant!
A Ferrari F40! How did they get it in here, I wonder!
I don't seem to see Asahi-san...
That's odd, after he invited guests here...
Don't tell me Murakami already got to him?
What does that mean?! "Murakami already got to him?"
Oh, right! I need to tell you about that...
Inspector. I'll go look around the place.
I'll come too.
Thanks!
Okay, everyone! Just to be safe, please sit with your backs to the wall!
So this is where the emergency exit is...
Wine Cellar
This is the only room that's locked...
I see. So that's what's going on...
Nothing out of the ordinary.
Which means I could be "six".
Why's that?
See how there's a six in the shishi part of my name?
Shishido
Six
So it does!
The other three have numbers in their names, too.
What?
Nana
Look: Nana-san is seven, and Nishina-san is two.
Note: For Nana-san, her name is an homophone of the number seven.
Nishina-san has the radical for the number two in his name.
Seven
Nishina
Ford-san's name sounds like the English number "four".
Ford
Four
I see So if we have a three and a one, we have all the numbers.
There is a three... right in front of your eyes.
Wait, you don't mean-
My name is Shiratori Ninzaburou.
Note: The middle character "zabu" in Ninzaburou is the character for the number three.
Shiratori
Ninzaburou
Nin... zaburou?
But there's definitely no "one" here...
Shin'ichi!
Do you think Shin'ichi could be "one"?
Is Kudo-kun coming here?!
No. But I just got that feeling...
True. If I hadn't been shrunk,
I surely would've been interested in coming along.
Does that mean "one" does refer to me?
Tell me, are any of you connected with Murakami Joe in any way?
Of course I'm not!
Me neither!
I am.
Before I became an essayist, I was a criminal investigative reporter,
and I had done a report on the Murakami incident.
I'm connected, too.
I photographed him for a photo album called "Portraits of Criminals".
Did any trouble occur at the time?
Nothing at all.
What is it, Nana-san?
He got out of prison eight days ago, right?
Yes.
Then it's unrelated.
Oh, you guys! Getting all serious! Let's quit talking about this!
More importantly, aren't you the one
who wrote that lame book, "Restaurants in Paris"?!
All the restaurants you recommended in it sucked!
Do you really know what tastes good?
Excuse me!
Of course I do!
Then let's see some proof.
Proof?
I brought this as a gift for Asahi-san.
but let's see you guess what wine this is!
Blind tasting, huh? All right, then.
This graceful fragrance of violets,
velvety texture, the flavor beloved by Emperor Napoleon, Chambertin.
I've got you!
As if I'd ever buy something that cheap as a gift for someone!
Then what is this?!
You're a sommelier, right?
Yes.
Tell this fraud of an essayist the answer.
This is a Beaujolais Moulin-à-Vent.
Correct!
No way! This is a Beaujolais?!
Even a Beaujolais, when aged in the proper humidity and temperature,
would give a taste and flavor close to a limited Bourgogne.
Note: Bourgogne = Burgundy, a famous wine-producing region of France.
Now do you get it? I suggest you call it quits as a "gourmet essayist"!
Now I feel like having some wine, too!
Let's all have some, then! I'll get the stuff!
I'll have some beer. Where's the kitchen?
That way.
Alright! Lead the way, brat!
Okay!
Who're you callin' a brat?!
Ah! Here we go!
Good news, brat! There's juice here, too!
Really?! I'm so happy!
Enough with the brat stuff!
Here, Ran-neechan!
Thanks!
Oops!
It really is as delicious as you say, Sawaki-san!
Sawaki-san! How about another glass?
Oh, no, thank you.
I'll have some mineral water.
Thanks!
You're not having beer?
Of course not! There's no telling when Murakami could strike!
Here you are, Inspector!
Here, Conan-kun. You can have mine.
T-that's okay! I'll get another one!
Hey! Don't be scampering around, now!
The mineral water is in the bottom drawer of the fridge!
Oh, thanks.
I saw a rare seasoning here, so I gave it a taste.
Is your juice up here, Conan-kun?
What's taking Asahi-san so long?
What could he be up to?!
W-what's going on?! What's wrong?!
Just joking!
Ugh...
Ford-san! Please don't joke around at a time like this!
Incidentally, why are you all here today, anyway?
I got a call from his secretary.
Said Asahi-san was a fan of mine and wanted to meet with me.
Maybe he wants me to help promote this place or something?
I also received a call from his secretary.
I got the same invitation.
I even got a present from him!
Here! This nail polish!
It's made in France and super expensive!
Is that the same reason for you, Nishiya-san?
Yeah, that's right.
What're you doing there, Nana-chan?
I drew on the wine cork with nail polish! Isn't it cute?
What is it? A raccoon dog?!
Oh, you're such a meanie! It's a cat!
Sawaki-san. This is addressed to you.
I found it on the ground.
"Sawaki Kouhei-san..."
"I may be late, so please treat everyone to any bottle of wine you want
from Rack M-18 in the wine cellar."
"The key is in an envelope on the checkout counter."
"Thanks. -Asahi Katsuyoshi"
Was that paper there when I picked up the juice earlier?
Hey! I wanna see the wine cellar!
Me too!
I'd like to see what wine there is, too!
Then let's all go together!
Oh, this is...!
This is grand!
It's a bit cool.
No, it's almost a bit too warm.
A temperature between 10° to 14° C is ideal for preserving wine,
but it's up to 17° C in here.
Just look at these, Inspector!
They're all rare wines!
Romanee-Conti, La Tache, Le Pin, Cote-Rotie, Clos du Mesnil...
Just amazing!
Shelf M-18...
There it is!
Look out!
A booby-trap!
Mister! Inspector!
This is just like the one that hit me in the side!
Inspector!
The crossbow is set up here!
The Eight of Spades!
So it was Murakami who set this up, and wrote that letter!
If so, why would he skip nine and go after Sawaki-san, who's eight?
It couldn't be!
Inspector! Let's evacuate from this building for the time being!
Huh? It's closed.
Was the entrance not here?
No, this is the place.
If we're leaving, can I get my coat first?
Go ahead.
Asahi-san!
The 9 of Spades! It was Murakami!
Inspector! I can't open this door, it has an electronic lock!
What?! Alright, I'll call for help!
No good! We're out of service range!
It's been cut! Damn it!
Inspector! I'm gonna check the emergency exit!
What?!
It's blocked with cement!
This is your fault! We have nothing to do with this!
Yeah! What do you have to say for yourself?!
The fact Murakami didn't go out of numerical order
means you're next, Nana-chan!
Q-quit it!
Why do I have to be targeted by some man I've never even heard of?!
But something bugs you, right?
Earlier, you...
He got out of prison eight days ago, right?
Yes.
I already told you, it was unrelated!
We will determine if it's unrelated or not. Please talk to us.
Three months ago...
Apparently!
We didn't collide, but I got scared and drove off!
Did the person have an off-road motorcycle?!
No, it was a regular motorcycle.
Inspector. Nana-san is right.
It's unrelated to what's happening now.
More importantly, we need to figure a way out of here!
Yeah. We might find an exit if we search the entire building.
Then let's split up and look, too.
Guess there's no other choice.
Listen! Ran and Conan, you stay here!
You remain here too, Nana-san!
Okay...
What's taking everyone so long?
Can't they find an exit?
Don't worry! I'm sure they'll find one and be right back!
I'll just do some searching, too!
You were told to stay here!
Honestly! You're so curious about everything...
But!
A power outage?!
What?! What's going on?!
Why are the lights out?!
Luminescent paint!
Ah! Help me!
Don't move, Nana-san!
Don't tell me this blackout-
What?! What happened?!
What was that scream?!
Inspector!
Mouri-kun, the power room!
Yes!
Nana-san?!
This is it.
Nana-san!
What the-?!
Out of the way!
She's dead!
The 7 of Spades, and a Joker...
It's Murakami! Murakami's here, inside this building!
Damn it!
I'll go check around!
Mouri-san! It's dangerous to go alone! I'll come with you!
Shishido-san.
Please cease your photography.
Why's that?
Since help can't come right away, you'll have to do the autopsy,
but won't you need to photograph the scene of the crime first?
Y-you have a point...
Then I expect you to hand them over to the police later on.
Yes, but of course!
But how did Murakami manage to do this in pitch darkness?
Luminescent paint.
Nana-san's fingernails were glowing.
What?!
I see! Luminescent paint was added to the nail polish she was given!
Her middle nail...
Hey, Inspector!
Nana-san's left fingernail is weird!
The nail polish came off!
Or, wait... did her nail break off?
I think that's a press-on nail that came off.
Press-on?
They're not real fingernails.
They come in various designs, and you glue them to your nails.
Oh? So it came off by chance, then?
Here we are!
It doesn't seem related to her murder...
Oh...
She was grabbed with a left hand!
And pretty forcefully, at that!
Which means... the killer is right-handed!
If I remember right, Murakami... is left-handed!
It wasn't MuraKami who killed Nana-san!
Wait a minute! A while back, the Killer...
Think back! Remember!
He's right-handed!
What the hell?! I've been making a huge mistake this whole time!
Inspector! No luck!
Murakami's nowhere to be found!
Could he have already escaped?
That can't be! There's no way out!
He must be hiding somewhere still!
No... Murakami isn't the killer.
It's someone in here!
Who?! Who killed Nana-san?!
Come to think of it, the killer...
...kicked the can of juice I left on the floor!
The contents have spilled onto the floor.
I'm certain there was about half left in it when I set it down.
So if the killer kicked the can...
...the juice must've flown out and stained the killer's pants!
Nana-san's killer is one of these four men!
Him?! But why?!
I'm sorry, Sawaki-san.
Because of me, Asahi-san was murdered,
and you never got to discuss running his restaurant...
Not at all. I was going to turn him down, anyway.
Actually, I've decided to quit my current job and return to the country.
I'm an only son, so I need to take care of my parents.
In any case, we'd be wise not to act rashly now.
Especially you, Shishido-san.
Yeah, I know. I'm next, right?
I'll be extra careful not to get killed.
Inspector! I refuse to die!
I will get out of here alive!
Wait a minute! Could it be that he...
What're you up to now?!
I thought everyone might be thirsty...
You idiot! Don't be running around on your own!
There's no telling where Murakami might be hiding!
But there's no number in my name, so...
Yeesh!
Here you go!
Here you go, Sawaki-san!
Thank you.
Hey, brat! Gimme some too!
Sure!
Japanese water really is delicious!
That's great!
I was right! No doubt about it!
But there's no proof.
Come to think of it, where is it?!
I found the proof!
What was that?!
There appears to have been an explosion somewhere!
Shiratori-kun! Shishido-san is next! Protect Shishido-san!
Yes, sir!
Shishido-san!
Where are you, Shishido-san?!
Right here.
Put it out!
Do you want to die?!
I'm "two", so I won't get attacked for a long time!
Sawaki-san! Are you hurt?!
N-no. Do you suppose I'll be targeted again?
I-I'm not sure...
Thank you! Emergency lights!
W-what the?!
H-h-help! I can't swi-!
Here, grab on!
Heya, brat! Glad to see you're alive!
Huh?! Ran! Where are you?! Ran!
Don't tell me she's...
Wait, Conan! Where are you going?!
Ran! Where are you?!
Ran!
Ran! Everything's okay now! Calm down!
S-Shinichi?
Conan-kun!
It's no good!
Oh, yeah! My Elasticity Suspenders!
Crap! My leg's stuck!
Dammit! Oh no! Can't breathe!
R-Ran!
Hey! Ran! Ran!
Damn it!
I'm free! I gotta hurry!
Hey! Ran! Ran! Say something!
D-Dad...
Thank Conan.
Thank you, Conan-kun...
No, uhh...
What's wrong?!
I seem to have reopened my wound!
What?!
Look! Over there!
The 6 to 2 of Spades!
Damn it! Is he planning to kill us all at once here?! Screw that!
But, at this rate, it is going to happen.
Because there's no way out!
There is an exit.
What?
You know, the shattered glass!
Yeah! We can go into the sea through them!
N-no! I can't!
Quit bein' a sissy! I'll take you with me!
Then I'll take you, little boy!
I'll be fine by myself!
And I'll take you. Think you got a little bit left in you?!
I'll help you, Inspector.
Thanks.
Then I'll lead the way! Let's go!
Here we go! Deep breath!
Hold on tight and don't let go now!
R-right!
Here! Grab my hand!
Take Ran please!
Yes!
We're saved, aren't we?
Yes. We're safe now!
Nishina! Nishina!
Hey! Say something!
I'll give him CPR!
I'm a certified lifeguard!
Hold it! Detective Shiratori!
You give him CPR!
Huh? No, I didn't say anything-
Do it now, Shiratori!
Understood!
Huh?
Mouri-Kun?
Inspector!
The person behind this string of incidents is not Murakami Joe!
Say what?!
Because the person who shot
Professor Agasa and killed Nana-san
was right-handed!
Right-handed?!
Y-you're all right!
The real culprit most likely met Murakami after he was released,
learned things from him, like how I shot him 10 years ago
and that he was once a gambling dealer nicknamed "Joker",
and decided to use him.
Use?
Yes. The killer realized that he
and the people he wanted to kill
all had numbers in their names.
So he came up with the idea of combining these "name numbers"
with playing cards to pin his crimes on Murakami.
Then the reason Eri-san,
Professor Agasa, and I were attacked
was to act as camouflage to make us think
Murakami was getting revenge against you?!
That's right.
Then who did the culprit really want to kill?!
Asahi-san and Nana-san.
And Tsuji-san.
Given that the method used against him switching his eyedrops-
had a very high probability of being fatal, there's likely no doubt.
Mouri-Kun! Who is the killer, then?!
The killer is among us.
What?!
Come to think of it, didn't Nana-san humiliate you?
N-no! I didn't kill her!
That's right. You were to be killed.
As you can't swim, the killer attempted to drown you
by blowing up the underwater restaurant.
Say, Detective Shiratori.
When you gave CPR to Nishina-san, what was the first thing you did?
What did I do?
You're supposed to tilt the head back, lift the throat up,
and keep the airway open!
Then, what would happen if you hadn't kept the airway open,
and only pretended to give CPR, while shutting the nose and mouth?
That'd kill him, obviously!
Y-you're not saying...
Yes. The person who murdered Asahi-san and Nana-san
and tried to kill Tsuji-san and Nishina-san...
It was you, Sawaki Kouhei-san!
Mouri-san! I was attacked with a crossbow too, you know!
You had set that up beforehand.
After you murdered Asahi-san here last night, that is!
Then the letter that was under the table...
And the secretary that called us all...
Sawaki-san was behind it all.
Including Nana-san's luminescent nail polish, of course!
Motive! What was his motive?!
Something to do with ageusia, most likely.
Ageusia?
That's when you can't taste food and drinks anymore, right?
Yes. He suffers from this ageusia.
Apparently, ageusia is caused by stress or external head injuries.
External head injuries?
Then Sawaki-san was the person
Nana-san got in an accident with?!
H-h-hold on now!
You claim he lost his sense of taste,
but he named Nana-san's wine brand correctly!
He could tell the brand by the wine's color and scent alone.
That's possible?
After it happened, Sawaki-san continued as a sommelier,
relying on vision and smell alone.
But it was an affront to his aesthetic desire to be a perfect sommelier.
That's why he decided to leave his position and return to the country.
But not before getting revenge on Nana-san and everyone else
who had caused him to lose his sense of taste!
It must have been quite hard to accept.
Enough to make him break the bottle of wine he treasured and saved
for the day he would finally open his own restaurant.
Then that mark on his floor was-
But how did you manage to figure all this out?
Yes. It was because he tried to taste some seasoning.
What he tried was chili powder.
People like sommeliers who use their tongues for a living
don't put irritants or stimulants in their mouths, you see.
I was able to confirm that he had lost his sense of taste
when I had Conan give him some mineral water.
Mineral water?
The glass that Conan gave you had salt in it.
And I drank it without realizing it?
It's true that I suffer from ageusia.
But that hardly proves that I murdered Nana-san.
But there is proof. In either your left or right jacket pocket.
That's the cork Nana-san drew on!
Nana-san had that cork on her until just before she was murdered.
So what was it doing in your pocket?
It's because when you stabbed her from behind,
Nana-san spun around and grabbed at you,
at which time the cork slipped inside your pocket!
The press-on nail on the floor likely came off at this time.
How ironic that a wine cork should prove a sommelier's crime.
But there's one more thing!
And it's most likely still asleep in one of your pockets!
The final Ace of Spades that matches those there.
The card for Kudo Shin'ichi!
The Ace of Spades!
Mouri-san. It's all as you say.
Three months ago, on my way home from the restaurant,
I nearly collided with her car, and fell off my motorcycle.
A while after, I suddenly lost all sense of taste.
The doctor said stress might also be the cause.
Having lost all hope, I decided to give up being a sommelier
and enact revenge on the cause of the accident, Osanai Nana,
and the causes of my stress, Asahi, Tsuji, and Nishina.
But what did Asahi-san and the others do to you?!
Asahi caught wind of a "wine boom" and used his vast fortune
to buy up all the rare foreign wine available!
And he couldn't even take care of it right!
Nishina! You pretended to be a gourmet, wrote know-it-all books,
and planted incorrect information about wine in readers' minds!
And Tsuji Hiroki!
He sullied my dignity as a sommelier!
Four months ago, I attended a party he held at his home.
Oh! You're here!
Here's a good sommelier badge for you!
And for your tastevin!
Oh! Lookin' sharp!
You tried to kill Tsuji-san for that?!
"For that"?! You can't possibly understand how I felt then!
I sought dignity, honor, and pride as a sommelier in my work!
And he stomped on all of it with his grimy feet!
Did you kill Murakami Joe?
Yeah.
The day he was released from prison, I just happened to meet him
in front of the Mouri Detective Agency.
That's the day he went to play mahjong!
I thought I might be able to use Murakami,
so I invited him over as an acquaintance of Mouri-san.
Way back when, he did hold a grudge against Mouri-san,
but now he wanted to apologize for everything, so he went to see him.
That's when I came up with the idea of using playing card numbers
to camouflage my crimes.
Killing Murakami while he was wasted was easy.
So you had no grudge against Mouri-san or Inspector Megure, then?!
Exactly.
So you brought me and Shishido-san here...
...because you needed a "four" and a "six"?!
That's right.
I figured three and five Mouri-san and Detective Shiratori
would naturally come if I mentioned Asahi-san invited me here.
I had actually hoped "one" -
Kudo Shin'ichi would come too...
...but unfortunately, my wish didn't come true.
Did you ever stop to consider if innocent people were killed?!
I blew up the underwater restaurant simply to kill Nishina.
I didn't give a damn whether any of the others lived or died.
This place would collapse afterwards, Murakami would go missing,
and it'd all remain an unsolved mystery.
This place would collapse?!
Sawaki-san. There's nowhere to run now. Give yourself up.
Detective Shiratori! Seize Sawaki-san!
What?!
W-what the?!
Oh no!
Come on!
Crap!
Huh? Why does Sawaki-san have Ran?
What are you talking about?!
You just exposed his crimes!
Huh? I did?
Stay where you are! Move and she's dead!
Damn it! Ran's too out of it to use her karate-
That last explosion has caused the building to lose its balance!
Ran! Where are you?!
Up there!
Where is he going?!
He plans to escape in a helicopter!
What?!
He called one here using the secretary's name so he could escape!
That's what he thinks!
Wait! Mouri-kun! Leave the rest to us-
Conan-kun!
The res of you evacuate now!
But I can't swim!
Don't worry! We'll find a plank or something and get you to shore!
Let's go, Shiratori-kun!
Yes!
Which way?
Up the stairs!
The elevator, huh?!
Mouri-kun! This way!
Hurry! Hurry!
Inspector. How good is Detective Shiratori with a gun?
He's as bad as I am.
W-what in the world's going on?!
What are you doing?! Land!
W-who is this guy?!
Why does he have a knife?!
Dammit! Why doesn't that elevator go to the roof?!
Get down here now!
I'm the one who ordered the chopper!
Emergency! Emergency!
A man with a knife has a girl hostage on the Aqua Crystal heliport!
And the building is in danger of collapsing! Send help at once!
Ran!
Stay back!
Any closer and she's dead!
Stop this, Sawaki-san!
Let Ran-san go! Let her go or I'll shoot!
Amusing!
Go ahead and shoot, if you dare!
His hands are shaking!
He'll hit Ran if he shoots!
Shiratori-kun! Don't!
Inspector! Are you all right?!
Escaping in a helicopter won't help you! Let Ran-kun go!
Shut up! I'm gonna take this girl and go kill Tsuji!
Tsuji-san? He can't compete in the U.S. Open anymore.
Isn't that enough?!
Nope! I'm going to kill him, and then I'm going to die!
And she's coming with me!
S-Sawaki-san...
Shinichi... Help me...
Shinichi...
If he runs off with Ran, he'll kill her!
This is bad! If this keeps up, we'll all be goners, not just Ran!
Hand over the gun.
What?!
I'll stab her!
Hey, Shiratori. Gimme the gun.
I said give it to me.
Yeah, right! I can't give it to you!
What're you doing?! Hurry it up!
A-all right!
Boy! You bring it here!
Do you want this girl to die?!
N-no! Don't make a kid do something that dangerous!
Hey!
C'mon! Bring it here!
N-no!
Conan-kun... D-don't give-
Don't give it to him!
'Atta boy! Now bring it here!
Hurry up!
I said bring it here now!
Ah! Now I see! That's why the old guy...
Shi-
Shin'ichi?
Damn it! Hey! Get up! Hey!
Hey! Hey!
I sadly watched the rain
pound on you as you bent over
Ran!
If there was only one umbrella in
this world, I'd find it for you
That was a close one, Ran...
N-now I see! So that's why Mouri-san
shot her back then!
It wasn't to stop the killer,
but to save the hostage!
Yes. A hostage shot in the leg
I can't do anything, but I can't
get drenched in your place, either
is just a burden to a fleeing criminal.
It was to save Mom...
was the truth, then?
I beg of you,
please confess your worries to me
Sawaki Kouhei!
You're under arrest for murder,
bodily harm, kidnapping, and more!
Let go! Let me die!
I'm not letting you die!
I'm gonna make you understand the weight of what you've done!
Talk about a close call!
It looks like you're over your fear of helicopters now, huh?!
Let me off this thing!
Here you go!
He suddenly jumped at me, so I got surprised!
Honestly! It's just a good thing you only grazed Ran-san's leg.
Anywhere else and things could've ended badly.
I'm sorry!
Can't really tell him that my old man often taught me how to shoot
at the shooting range when we visited the lodge in Hawaii!
But now, I've given Ran a painful memory.
Inspector! This is the perfect opportunity to take some time off!
Yeah, I think I will!
The hat can stay on, if you don't mind.
Say, do you think even Shin'ichi would've shot like you did?
Who knows. He might've, if he was as good a shot as me.
I think so, too. Right, Shin'ichi?
What's that?
Shin'ichi's card. The Ace of Spades.
I was holding onto it the whole time.
Who knows, maybe Shin'ichi helped protect me!
You dummy! The person saved by the ace...
A chance for an "A"
...was me...
...you know!
A Few Weeks Later
Eh? You knew why Dad shot you?!
Of course I did! We are married, after all.
Plus it's only natural for a husband to protect his wife.
Then why did you leave him?
That very night, he said my cooking was horrible and didn't eat it.
Huh?
My leg hurt so much, and I worked so hard to thank him with food...
Yet, he...
You idiot! If this is the best you can make, get the hell to bed!
And that's why I moved out.
Just remembering it makes me mad!
That insensitive old clod!
O-oh, I see...
Looks like they won't be making up for a while now...
Come to think of it, Mom's cooking...
...was horrible...