Today, not long after 21:50...
The Tokyo National Institute of Microorganisms in
Nishitama City was attacked by an armed group seven strong.
The armed group restrained two security
guards, took the on-duty researcher captive...
Infiltrated the high-security lab, detonated the plastic explosives
they planted just minutes earlier, and made their escape.
Uno Tadayoshi
Police HQ Senior Superintendent
Odagiri Toshirou
Police HQ Chief Superintendent
At the lab where the explosion occurred...
An extremely dangerous bacteria was being stored inside.
It is speculated the armed group took it into their possession.
Dangerous bacteria?
The mortality rate following infection is gauged at 80%.
To date, no known cure has been found.
Could the bacteria have spread to the vicinity due to the explosion?
That is not a possibility.
Due to the magnitude of the explosion, any traces of
the potential bacteria should have been incinerated.
That's according to testimony from the lab chief himself.
What's the aim of the assailant group?
To be determined.
However, we are exploring the possibility of bioterrorism.
We do have a request for all of you.
To avoid an unnecessary panic...
Only report this as a bombing incident, and...
Refrain from mentioning bacteria or the possibility of bioterrorism.
Does that mean you're exercising media control?
Chief!
The assailant group has posted their manifesto on the internet.
And the name of the terrorist—
The Red Siamese Cats.
"We, the Red Siamese Cats, were the ones responsible for
the raid on the Tokyo National Institute of Microorganisms...
"And have obtained the killer bacteria.
"We will commence with our next move within seven days.
"Await your demise."
It appears they've procured the bacteria after all.
But, weren't the Red Siamese Cats eradicated ten years ago?
Chief!
That means the press control will be lifted, right?
We have no choice.
And now we welcome bacteriologist Ooda Chiaki to the show.
Bacteriologist
University of Beika Medicine
OODA CHIAKI
Should one become infected with this bacteria, rashes
and skin irritation can emerge from any part of the body.
Really, it's becoming a serious case.
They've been reporting the same news since this morning.
The symptoms remain for a number of days,
followed by prostration and possibly even death.
Transmission is primarily done by droplet contact.
Young children are especially susceptible, and often
exhibit rapid symptom development post-transmission.
As she said.
What would you do, having a child's body and all, Conan-kun?
Shut up.
Regardless, Hattori...
It's been bugging me...
About why the assailant group destroyed the lab, right?
If their aim was merely to steal the bacteria, they
would have no reason for blowing up the place.
That's true.
At any rate, you know anything about
this "Red Siamese Cats" organization?
No, I only know they targeted financial
groups through terrorism ten-plus years ago.
Well, we were both kids at that time.
Oh, my apologies.
You're still a kid now, huh?
That's enough.
By the way, Kudo...
You said you're going to be on that airship, right?
The one that's flying from Tokyo to here in Osaka.
Yeah.
That old man that never learns his lesson
issued another challenge notice to Kid.
And that guy also relayed his confirmation a little while ago.
Right now, I bet that old man's...
You damned bunch of red stray cats!
You just robbed me of my front page news about the
largest airship in the world being under my command!
Thanks to you, even my challenge notice to my nemesis
Kaitou Kid has been buried within the back pages!
In that case, Kudo...
Stay at my place after you arrive.
I'll take you to that okonomiyaki restaurant I promised.
Yeah, got it.
Later.
I'm high school detective, Kudo Shin'ichi.
While visiting an amusement park with my
childhood friend and classmate, Mouri Ran...
I witnessed a man in black in the midst of a suspicious transaction.
While caught up in watching the deal...
I failed to notice his partner coming up behind me.
Those men forced me to swallow poison...
And when I came to...
My body had shrunk.
If those guys found out that Kudo Shin'ichi was still alive...
They'd come after me again...
And put those around me at risk.
At Professor Agasa's suggestion, I decided to conceal my true identity.
When Ran asked for my name, in that instant...
I became Edogawa Conan.
In order to obtain information on those guys...
I went to live with Ran, whose father is a private detective.
Suzuki Jirokichi, 72 years old.
Excuse me!
Thank you very much.
He's the cousin of the dad of Suzuki Sonoko, Ran's best friend...
And is an advisor to the Suzuki Financial Group.
This old man obtained all the trophies he yearned for...
And bragged about having fulfilled all his dreams.
Now, he's obsessed with battling Kid.
But...
What has my attention now is them...
The terrorists that decimated the research
facility and stole the dangerous bacteria.
What exactly is their aim?
Even though I've become smaller, my mind remains the same...
The unbeaten great detective...
There's always only one truth!
It's Tropical Land!
The castle looks so small!
Just like an amusement park model!
What a sight, what a sight!
Dad, the view's really great!
Hey, why not come take a look?
Shut up!
I've got a lot on my mind right now!
Geez...
Come to think of it, Mouri-kun is afraid of heights, isn't he?
It's not like that!
Say, do you think Kid-san always enjoys scenery like this?
How I envy him!
But still...
Are you sure Kid will actually come?
Of course he will.
He even sent a reply to Uncle Jirokichi.
Henogo... ndeo... keshimasu?
Hey, you—it won't make sense if you only read the hiragana!
Geez.
Listen!
"I cordially accept your invitation to board your airship.
However, I simply could not bear witnessing a 72-year-old
senior in such a nervous state over a six hour flight.
Instead, I will only take possession of the gem
once the airship begins to near Osaka City.
Please do enjoy your flight until then.
Kaitou Kid.
I wonder if he would come take me into his possession too?
Kid-sama!
I've been considering this for some time, but...
She really does have a unique personality.
Could say that.
Speaking of which, are we the only passengers on board?
I recall a reportage writer named Fujioka-san...
That guy!
Fujioka Takamichi
Reportage Writer
He insisted we allow him to write a report on
the battle between Kid and Uncle Jirokichi...
And offered us his services.
Other than him...
Hello, excuse me!
Would you happen to be Mouri Kogoro-san?
Nice to meet you.
Mizukawa Masaki
Nichiuri TV Director
And also...
I also have one of our reporters, Nishitani Kasumi...
Ishimoto Junpei
Cameraman
Nishitani Kasumi
Reporter
And our cameraman, Ishimoto Junpei.
Pleased to meet you.
Likewise.
This time, with regards to the battle between Mr. Suzuki
and Kid, our station will be offering an exclusive broadcast.
If I'm not mistaken, isn't it supposed
to be a special program this evening?
Yes!
To be honest, we wish we could do a headline presentation
just like when he performed his miraculous mid-air walk, but...
Now is a bad time.
Bad time?
You mean the Red Siamese Cats.
Yeah.
Ever since their manifesto proclaimed they'd
make their next move within seven days...
Our entire station has been on high alert!
If the manifesto proclamation was
genuine, today is the final day.
Thanks to them, I couldn't get a flight permit for the
helicopter I prepared for my autobiographical movie.
What a bunch of pesky stray cats.
Right, Lupin?
Uncle Jirokichi!
Greetings, Advisor Suzuki, greetings!
I'm looking forward to working with you today.
At any rate, what a marvelous airship this is!
To think you're broadcasting from such a marvelous airship...
With a mere staff of three.
I'm sorry.
That incident has all the hands at our station tied.
Come to think of it, what are the
culprits going to do with the bacteria?
Yeah, yeah.
They say you can't be saved once you're infected, right?
I heard it spreads by droplet contact (himatsu kansen).
That's so scary!
So they'll spread it with cold soup noodles (hiyashi tanmen)?
It's by droplet contact (himatsu kansen).
It means it spreads by coughing or sneezing.
They say children are most easily infected, so look out for yourselves.
Don't fret.
I don't care if it's killer bacteria or something else.
I've flown to many places where germs move about like crazy...
And I'm still as healthy as a horse.
We human beings are stronger than germs.
That's right!
Then again...
If it's you little brats, you might just croak and be gone!
Please stop.
Don't say things that will frighten the children.
That's right, you're too inconsiderate!
No harm done!
Don't worry.
Even if the bacteria is being spread elsewhere in Japan...
As long as we're in this airship, we'll be fine.
Rest assured!
That is, if this thing flies forever.
Huh?
Isn't it almost time to prepare the tea?
But before that I'd like to take a puff.
I'll be back soon.
You're still unable to identify the culprits?
Even the former executives of the Red Siamese Cats
now serving sentences insisted they knew nothing.
Our only lead at the moment is that ampule, but...
It didn't originate from any known
manufacturer inside or outside the country
Most likely, it's safe to assume this is a Red Siamese Cats original.
This ampule being dropped in the parking
lot of the research facility suggests...
It's highly probable the culprits brought
with them a number of empty ampules.
And they might've transfered the bacteria housed inside
the facility into the ampules and transported them out.
Then, it seems likely they dropped one of the empty ampules by mistake.
Yeah.
Transferring the bacteria to another vessel is
an exceedingly difficult and hazardous task.
We can assume that the culprits possess
a high degree of scientific intelligence.
But, why didn't they just take them away as-is
instead of risking that dangerous transfer?
In fact, why did they resurface like ghosts after ten years of silence?
What is it they're after?
There are windows over here too!
Those kids are really enjoying themselves.
Yeah.
To think they're able to ride an airship at such a young age...
We really need to thank Sonoko-kun for this.
To those kids...
It must be like riding a piece of a floating cloud in the big sky.
It's nothing.
I just remembered something from my childhood.
When Ran first saw a flying airship, she said...
Shin'ichi, this is big, real big!
There's an UFO!
An UFO is flying around!
UFO?
Well, a balloon resembling a monster was flying leisurely in the sky.
I suppose she must've been really surprised as she said that.
What, bragging about your fairytale princess's anecdotes?
I'm not bragging...
But, she was already such an appealing girl back then.
Even I long to ride this magic ship flying in the sky...
And fly atop the clouds on my way to Dreamland.
I'm joking.
Of course.
Everyone!
Uncle Jirokichi said he's taking us on a tour of the sky deck.
We can see the big jewel!
All right!
Treasure, treasure!
All right, you guys wanna see the treasure?
Yeah!
Then, let's go!
You guys come too, Conan-kun
Well, in order to prevent her from being taken away
by some Peter Pan and flying to Dreamland...
Be sure to keep a tight rein.
What's that supposed to mean?
Professor...
About the UFO story earlier, keep it a secret from Ran.
I know.
Is everybody here?
Yeah!
In that case, allow me, Chief Steward Asano, to treat you to a tour of the sky deck.
Asano Mitsuhiro
Chief Steward
Awesome!
Look, there are glass windows everywhere!
We can see the interior of the airship!
Well then, let us take off.
Everyone, prepare for a surprise.
How exciting, right?
About this Bell Tree 1st...
The total length is 246 meters.
The longest measure of diameter is 42.2 meters.
Compared to the famous Hindenburg...
It's longer by one meter in both length and diameter.
It is indeed the world's largest airship.
Damn...
Why is this place surrounded by glass?
In the cockpit, we have the latest computerized
control system installed and at our disposal.
Hey, there are things that look like balloons floating up there!
Those are called "ballonets" and are filled with helium gas.
They look just like a whale's lungs.
It's true!
They look so alive!
It really feels like we're ascending into the belly of a whale.
How bright!
We can see the sky!
Treasure!
This is the place that Advisor Suzuki is so proud of...
The sky deck!
Part of the roof can be opened and closed.
It's good for sunbathing...
And is more than suitable for stargazing.
Though there are many ways to have fun...
This time, in order to capture that guy, I added a little something.
Show me the treasure!
It's not something you kids need to see!
Shouldn't it be all right?
No!
Hey, you!
You...
Inspector Nakamori!
Oh, Mouri-san.
You're here too.
Allow me to show you.
Wait up!
That's the lapis lazuli I'm using as bait on that guy.
The big jewel, Lady Sky.
Beautiful!
This blue color possesses a certain je ne sais quoi.
The golden grains are sparkling!
Just like the stars!
Look at the largest spot among the golden grains.
Doesn't it look like something?
The largest spot, you mean?
It looks just like a woman's face!
That's correct.
That is the reasoning behind the name "Lady Sky".
Even the ancient Roman natural historian Mulanius
described it as, "A fragment of the starry firmament".
It certainly is most suitable for it to be displayed on this sky deck.
So why are you displaying such an invaluable
treasure in a plain, ordinary glass case?
The glass is bulletproof, able to deflect
bullets even from machine guns...
And won't open without both the input of
my fingerprint and a certain passcode.
Don't you realize this system is as strong as steel?
Something like that won't help us at all.
In fact, the research facility where the bacteria
was stolen from utilized a similar setup.
What'll happen if we press this?
Why don't you press it and find out?
Just like this, what will happen?
Hey!
They didn't have a trap like this in their system, did they?
What the hell were you doing, you stinky brat!
Dad...
I see, there's a sensor.
And you fall into traps too easily.
It's true...
That they didn't have these traps, but...
What would you do if he did this?
If he points a gun at you like this, you'll have no
choice but to open it with your finger, right?
Well, I don't imagine he'd do something like that...
But in that case...
Inspector Nakamori!
In that case, I simply have to do this.
Could it be that he's fallen into the sea?
Something like that won't happen.
Damn, what the hell kind of a trap is this!?
Do you still think it's an ordinary glass case?
If I recall, it was...
I see, so that's how it is.
At any rate, that guy isn't going to appear until dusk.
There's no need for you to monitor here until then, right?
This is my operation, don't go bossing me around!
Let's go!
Roger!
My, what you've demonstrated was of great interest.
Thanks to that, I might just cook up the perfect report.
I'm truly sorry, but...
Please go to the smoking room on B-deck if you wish to smoke.
Mouri-san, how about joining me?
Nah, I think I'm gonna head back to my room for some rest.
I can't even tell left from right.
That's no wonder.
What a relief.
Uncle was really in bad shape, huh?
By the way, those bandages were nicely done, right?
The bandages, the adhesive bandages.
You didn't take a look?
Don't tell me, you did something to them?
Hey, what's this supposed to be?
Like it?
Geez, what are you doing?
This isn't good!
While I was boarding the plane, I gave some
of these to one of the maintenance staff!
Everybody, hurry!
Got you!
It's dangerous to run around here, little miss.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
No problem.
It's bleeding.
Your elbow.
I think I skinned it.
Hang on a second.
Here, please apply these.
Thank you.
What do I do?
If he thinks I did this...
He won't notice!
The writing's small, anyway.
Geez.
I think I'd like to go see the gem again.
With so many people crowding around, I couldn't get a good look.
Oh?
Then, I'm gonna get back to my room.
I've already agreed to send some messages to Makoto-san.
Although I didn't tell him about Kid-sama.
Well, seeya for now.
Who could that be?
Hello.
I'm working as a waiter for this airship.
I took a little break from work to come see
this big jewel everyone is so excited about.
Uh oh...
This is bad.
I really should get going.
Well, please enjoy yourself.
Yes.
Hold on a second!
What is it?
This bandage...
I burned myself a little...
Liar.
It's not a lie...
Then, why don't you take a good look?
At this bandage.
Not good!
How could you possibly have a bandage I gave to someone else?
You're Kid, aren't you?
She's got me.
Tell me the truth!
I'm screwed...
I can't just insist I'm the waiter...
And if I force my way out...
What's so funny?
Hurry up and confess!
What will you do if I confess?
Are you going to keep holding onto me
and deliver me to Inspector Nakamori?
That sounds like an interesting plan.
But, you'll be troubled by it if you do that.
Can't you tell yet?
Who I...
Really am?
Right.
The true identity of Kaitou Kid...
Is me.
Are you all right, Conan-kun?
Caught a cold again?
No, it's not a cold.
What's wrong?
Have you forgotten my face since it's been so long?
Shin'ichi is Kid's true identity?
Don't make me laugh.
You're just playing with your disguising skills...
It's not?
Of course not!
This is my real face.
No, last time "Shin'ichi" also made me forcefully land a plane.
The inspector pinched his face, but the mask didn't come off either.
You just happen to have a face similar to his, no?
Damn, I was being careless!
That guy will definitely come check the surroundings before his crime!
If we leave the jewel alone...
Inspector Nakamori!
You're just unlucky for riding on an airship
where your escape routes are cut off.
Face the consequences!
It's not an airship.
It's an UFO.
I remember you saying something like that when you were little.
I presume that even now you see me as an unidentifiable
alien who just jumped out of an UFO all of a sudden, but...
I dress up as Kaitou Kid in order to
solve cases, not because I want to.
As proof, I always return the jewels back to their owners, right?
But...
Then...
Well, as the great detective Kudo Shin'ichi, I
can't just let that grandiose thief run amok.
And I thought you would understand, but...
Since I'm in your hands, I can only comply.
I'll surrender.
Shin'ichi...
What's wrong?
There a problem?
No...
If you noticed something...
Oh, it's nothing!
I just misunderstood something!
My apologies.
Bye!
What does this mean?
Does that mean Shin'ichi really is Kid?
When he told me he was busy solving cases
was he actually going around stealing things?
Hey, could you get those glasses over there for me?
What's wrong with your arm?
It just feels like a mosquito bit me—it's really itchy.
Geez, who'd have thought we'd have mosquitoes in a place like this.
Here.
Thank you.
Well then.
I...
Still don't believe you.
Then, if you'll excuse me.
Time!
Fujioka-san!
My bad, my bad.
As expected from a Kantou karate champion.
You have such nice muscles!
Hey, look!
An airship!
Awesome!
Just like a whale!
A whale flying in the sky!
Sorry for the wait.
Fabulous!
Miss, one more glass!
Looks like Uncle's back to his old self.
And what's with the "miss"?
Apologies for the wait.
Your dessert cake is here.
Thanks...
I've been waiting for it.
Looks delicious!
Huh?
What's this inside the cream?
It looks like a blackberry!
Hey, Ran.
Ran, hello!
Why are you staring at him with a serious face?
You trying to tell me he's your type?
That's not it at all...
I'm gonna report this to your hubby!
I said that's not it!
As I said...
If we open this door, we can get out from this middle passage.
And if we get out from the door ahead of it...
We'll be there.
That's right.
You guys...
Are you going somewhere?
No, we're...
Just planning to play cards in our room after this!
I see they're up to no good again.
I can't wait!
I hope we can get to Osaka quickly and meet Kid-sama!
And I do hope...
That I can pucker up my lips against his arrogant ones...
No, no!
You absolutely cannot do that!
Kid is a criminal, right?
That's just imprudent!
Why are you so worked up?
No reason.
What now?
Nothing.
You guys, hurry it up!
Roger!
Inspector Nakamori, why don't you take it easy?
I'll have my subordinates watch the treasure.
But while we're taking it easy, Kid could be...
Thanks for the meal!
Then, we'll be playing cards in our room!
Excuse us!
Why are you in such a hurry?
Thank you.
Sorry.
Geez...
Be more careful, will you?
When you're about to sneeze, didn't your
mom tell you to cover your mouth like this?
I'm sorry.
It's all right.
Let's go!
Who could this be?
Hello?
We've released the killer bacteria in the airship's smoking room.
What?
What the hell is this nonsense?
Look under the sofa on the left side of the room.
Hey, wait!
Is something wrong, Uncle?
Oh, not a thing.
Just someone making a prank call.
Inspector...
This is...
There's no mistake about it.
It's the same as the ampule left by the
group that targeted the research facility.
The information regarding the ampule has not been leaked
Which means...
The man who made the call was probably telling the truth.
It's possible the first ampule was purposely
left behind in the parking lot by them...
In order to validate a comparison against
the one now left in the smoking room.
Damn!
At any rate, I'll report this to the higher-ups.
Thanks.
It appears that man was telling the truth.
That's unbelievable!
Now is no longer the time to catch Kid.
Seal off the smoking room immediately!
To be safe, it's best we seal off this bar as well.
No way!
Are you certain?
Could it be a joke?
No, unfortunately, this was confirmed true by headquarters.
At any rate, as I just said, we're sealing off the B-deck smoking room.
Help me...
Rashes?
Don't tell me...
That guy's infected?
Come to think of it, he was in the smoking room!
Help me!
I'm begging you!
I'm not feeling well!
Remain calm!
Please remain calm!
I don't want to die!
Thanks...
It's nothing.
Ran-kun, it's best that you disinfect your hands now.
Come here!
We have alcohol-based sanitizers in the prep room.
Yes!
To think someone's infected in this airship...
Who else entered the smoking room?
Wait, are you all right?
Rashes!
On her right hand and her left arm!
Damn...
Her too?
Is there a place we can quarantine the two of them?
We do have beds for patients in
the back of the examination room.
There aren't any doctors aboard, but we
can lock them in from the outside there.
All right, let's do that immediately.
I'll show you the way.
Hey!
Roger!
As an added precaution, let's seal off this dining room as well.
In that case, everyone move to the lounge!
Dad!
Wake up!
In any case, it's a relief those kids aren't here.
Yeah...
That's right, we need to inform the kids about this too.
You're right.
Sorry.
Not good!
That was fun!
Definitely!
Let's go visit the tail of the whale this time.
Genta-kun...
A whale doesn't have a tail.
It has a caudal fin.
I see.
Genta!
Conan-kun.
Oh, I didn't know this was a restricted access area...
Genta!
Are you feeling all right?
He doesn't have any rashes yet.
Maybe he didn't catch it?
Or, could it just be in a state of latency?
Hey, Conan?
What's wrong?
I know!
Let's all go explore the inside of the airship!
Now's not time for that.
Something terrible has happened.
Something terrible?
At any rate, let's return to the cabin.
Hide!
Stay put right here.
Who is that?
Going there at a time like this...
What on earth...
The sound of a lock...
Could it be that person has the bacteria?
Who is that person?
An accomplice of Kid's?
Geez...
That's not it.
I don't think that was an accomplice of Kid.
More likely, they're with the Red Siamese Cats.
Not good...
This is not good!
Damn!
Those are...
Bombs?
Get to the back.
Climb up the ladder next to the gas shaft!
Hurry, hurry!
Don't move!
Who the hell are you?
Did you find the ampule?
The Red Siamese Cats...
I've planted bombs on this ship.
So long as you control yourselves and hear
me out, I will refrain from detonating them.
Now Lupin, simmer down!
I told you to behave!
How are things going?
Cat-F, cockpit under control.
Cat-D, kitchen under control.
Cat-C, sky deck under control.
The guest rooms are vacant.
Good.
Tell the entire crew to gather in the dining room using the PA system.
Conan-kun...
What should we do?
Attention flight attendants.
Report to the dining room as soon as possible.
I repeat:
All flight attendants should report to
the dining room as soon as possible.
We, the Red Siamese Cats, have hijacked this airship.
Everyone, surrender your cell phones.
Dad, wake up!
I don't have one.
It's me.
The airship's been hijacked.
As I thought.
What are their demands?
Spell out your demands.
Is it money, or do you want your colleague inmates to be released?
We hold a grudge against the Suzuki Financial Group.
Especially against this old man.
It's true that I lent a hand to the police ten years ago...
In order to crush your organization.
That's why you should make me your sole hostage.
Please release the others.
I can't consent to that.
Why not!?
This airship will head to Osaka as planned.
Contact the police.
However, should a single wrong move be made...
I will obliterate this ship.
Relay that!
In addition...
This is that killer bacteria!
Don't make the mistake of assuming you can arrest us.
It won't just be the smoking room—instead, the killer
bacteria will be spread throughout the entire cabin!
What do we do, Conan-kun?
We need to rescue Ai-chan and the others!
Before that, we need to disarm the bombs.
Haibara, there may be accomplices among the hostages.
Be careful.
Roger.
You guys...
Don't tell me you visited the smoking room?
Did you!?
But, we only took a little peep...
Because the smell of the smoke was
so bad, I closed the door right away.
What the hell...
It isn't just sneezing we have to worry
about, but also the smoking room?
It's all right.
We didn't really go inside.
We don't have that redness either.
Besides that, what should we do about the bombs?
There are four bombs in total.
I suspect two of them are near the fuel tank
on the back half of the passage below.
You guys...
Can you go find the bombs?
Of course.
But, don't touch them even if you do find them.
Contact me immediately.
Got it.
And, if you begin to feel even slightly unwell, notify me right away.
All right?
Ayumi and Mitsuhiko should be fine.
But Genta...
Damn it!
I can only hope he isn't infected.
Hey, what about the kids?
No worries, Conan-kun is with them.
As expected...
There's one right behind the smoking room.
If they were to detonate this, the bacteria in the
smoking room would be released throughout the ship.
And if they were to cause a hole in the ship itself
the bacteria could spread to the outside world.
But why did the culprits have to use both bombs and the bacteria?
It's sufficient to just use one of them for hijacking.
Why?
Why are the culprits using both bombs and the bacteria?
As double insurance, perhaps?
In any case, unless they make a clear demand...
We can only wait and see.
Follow the airship from a distance without being discovered.
As for Osaka and the other prefectures in
the path of the airship, I will contact them.
Understood.
Conan-kun!
We found it—the bomb!
And I found one too!
Good.
Only one left.
Get down!
I'll go find the last one.
You guys stay right here.
Open up.
Don't try anything funny.
Unless you'd like to see the hostages killed.
What are you doing, Mizukawa-san?
Mizukawa-san, don't tell me...
It's nothing!
Mizukawa-san!
I said it's nothing!
A rash!
No!
This is just hives!
Come to think of it, he smelled like smoke!
He went into the smoking room!
He must've been infected...
Wrong!
I did go there, but I wasn't infected!
The rest of my body is—
Now's the time...
To take these two down.
Throw him in the smoking room.
Don't tell me I'm also...
Found it!
Say, aren't those children missing?
Children?
Yeah...
If I recall, there were three boys...
And another girl about her age.
Find them.
Blabbermouth.
Edogawa-kun, they've discovered that you're missing.
Edogawa-kun?
Edogawa-kun!
Two men were dispatched to find...
My, how sneaky of you.
You!
What are you doing!?
Are you all right, Ai-chan!?
Shame on you for slapping a child!
If you try something like that again...
I'll kill you.
Good, got them.
You guys did this?
I was the one who did that.
They had nothing to do with it.
Such bravery.
Conan-kun!
Wait.
Shin'ichi...
Damn!
All right!
Kid!
Nice catch!
As expected of Kid-sama!
Great work, even if you are an enemy!
Shin'ichi...
So Kid was here all along.
At least now all the bothersome parties are gone.
Reinstall two of the bombs immediately!
Hard to believe they'd toss you out a window.
What now, Great Detective?
Are you giving up like this?
That's not even an option!
Return to the airship at once!
Don't be ridiculous.
My hang glider doesn't have an engine on it.
Consider yourself lucky to still be alive!
Aichi Prefecture Sakushima
It's headed due west...
So it's really going toward Osaka?
Osaka Prefecture Police HQ
The airship is currently passing above Tsu City, Mie Prefection.
At this rate, it'll arrive at Osaka in about an hour.
There's a Bell Tree Tower symbolizing the Suzuki Group in Nankou.
It's likely the landing port for this test flight.
Blowing up the airship by crashing it into the tower...
Is that the plan of the terrorists that hold
a grudge against the Suzuki Group?
We don't know that for sure.
If that really comes to be...
The killer bacteria will spread around right here in Osaka.
And the lives of seven million Osaka
citizens will be exposed to grave danger.
We need to prevent that from happening at all costs.
But what should we do?
Heiji!
You're late!
Sorry, sorry.
Who's this kid?
Hello there.
Kawaguchi Satoshi-kun.
He's the son of a relative.
They just moved from Yokohama to Nara this spring.
And they happened to be visiting my place, so I brought him along.
Satoshi-kun also said he'd like to meet you.
See, Heiji, your being good friends with
Conan-kun means you love kids, right?
Yeah, well...
Nice to meet you!
Likewise, nice to meet you.
Sorry if I sound rude, but...
Are you two a couple?
Idiot!
What are you talking about!?
Why do I have to be a couple with her?
Heiji is just my childhood friend, and he's only like a little brother!
My lover'd look nothing like that!
Not like that, not like that!
Impossible, impossible!
In that case, may I take Kazuha-oneesan as my future wife?
Go ahead, go ahead.
If you're satisfied with that, I'll even
gift-wrap and hand her over to you.
Thank you very much, Uncle Heiji!
Who're you calling "uncle"?
Now, now, it's just kid's talk.
Satoshi-kun...
I'm glad to hear about your feelings, but...
You have to think hard about that kind of thing.
For starters, in order to get married...
I know.
Boys need to turn eighteen before planning to get married, right?
Then, let's wait until you're eighteen.
If you still haven't changed your mind, I'll consider your proposal.
All right?
Good!
We're done with that topic.
I hope the airship arrives soon!
Before that, there's a battle against Kid.
The stage will be above Osaka City.
I guess we can witness the scene from here.
This is a premiere ringside seat.
I love Kid so much!
We gotta take a photo of him!
I'm so thrilled about this!
Kudo?
Where are you now?
At Mikawa Bay in Sakushima.
What, you're still only there?
It can't be helped.
I got thrown out.
Thrown out?
To be honest, Hattori...
What was that!?
Is that for real?
Yeah.
The airship carrying the bombs, the killer bacteria, and the hijackers...
It's coming toward you.
What a full package.
Just like the yakisoba okonomiyaki deluxe with
pork, squid, and octopus as triple toppings!
We already had two people infected.
Three people.
That director named Mizukawa also had a rash on his right palm.
That's how it was.
I'm just letting you know about this.
And, are you all right?
For now, anyway.
That's a police helicopter.
Are they chasing the airship?
Police HQ...
Sorry, I'll call you back.
Hey, wait!
Damn, he hung up again...
It can't be helped.
You'd run off to a restaurant once you heard about their great food!
Weren't you talking about an okonomiyaki restaurant with someone?
How about it?
What are their identities?
About that, we even extended our search
to the relatives of the former leaders...
But we didn't find anyone that fits the profile.
It's still no use?
Megure here.
Inspector Megure, it's Kudo.
Kudo-kun!
I'm currently in Sakushima, Aichi Prefecture.
But I saw a helicopter from Police HQ chasing that airship.
Yeah, we have Sato-kun and Takagi-kun en route.
In fact, Kudo-kun...
I already know about the hijacking.
And I'd like to make a request, Inspector.
What is it?
Allow me to board that helicopter.
Me, Kudo Shin'ichi.
Hey, where on earth can we find Kudo Shin'ichi?
Given that you are Kudo Shin'ichi.
As-I-said...
I'm asking you to disguise as me!
I have to disguise as you again?
Oh, nothing.
I can lend you a hand, but you can't interfere with my job.
I can't make any promises, but...
I'll see what I can do.
Good.
Cat-E, start the preparations.
Roger.
What?
What are you up to now?
It's been a while, Kudo-kun.
Same here.
But I'm surprised to see Conan-kun here as well.
What were you doing in Sakushima?
I'll explain everything later.
For now, please pursue the airship.
Pursue the airship.
There it is.
It's the airship.
Please approach it.
In order to avoid drawing the criminals'
attention, please elevate adequately.
Roger.
What's the direction of the wind and the speed of the helicopter?
Southeast, 200 kilometers per hour.
Continue straight ahead and once you overtake the airship...
Please maintain the same speed.
Kudo-kun?
Kudo-kun, what on earth...
All right then, please excuse us.
Kid?
The wings, the wings!
The wings!
Fold your wings!
Hurry and fold your wings!
I can't press the switch with you in the way!
Damn...
Hey, where are you touching?
Stop it...
Don't move, I'm trying to press the switch!
Even if you say so, it tickles!
Bear with it!
Hey, that's my...
Look out!
Retreat!
Then, that means, Kudo-kun is...
Actually Kid?
Well then, I bid you good luck.
You're not coming along?
I'll be checking on the situation here for a while.
After all, the gem's already fallen into the leader's hands.
Oh, yeah.
Catch.
What's this?
Old Jirokichi's fingerprint seal.
Thank you.
Although I correctly guessed the glass case would be
protected by a fingerprint authorization system...
I have no use for it anymore, so I'm entrusting it to you.
By the way, about your important girlfriend...
It's best that you keep an eye on her.
That man Fujioka grabbed both her arms earlier.
She did push him away quickly, though.
Since it wasn't via coughing or sneezing, I don't think she's infected.
Just thought I'd let you know.
Nothing...
I thought they would've reinstalled one here for sure...
There isn't one here either.
Could it be that they planted them in different places?
In the end, I only found two.
And they were in the exact same places
where Genta and Mitsuhiko had found them.
Why?
Why didn't they reattach them to the
places that would release the bacteria?
At any rate, I need to disarm them.
Hey, Kudo!
You said you'd call me back, but you totally didn't!
Kudo?
I mean...
Cool down, Conan-kun.
My bad, my bad, I completely forgot.
Geez...
Where the hell are you now?
Inside the airship.
You already went back?
Pretty nimble, aren't ya?
Regardless, what's this about?
I'm a little busy.
The culprits spread the news about the airship on the internet...
All of Osaka's in a state of panic.
What!?
The bullet train station is jam-packed with
people trying to escape Osaka to the west.
Like I said, we're out of seats!
If it's to Tokyo...
Idiot, why can it go to that dangerous place!?
There will be another train coming!
Please don't push!
Why, when there's still space to fit in!?
Please board the next train!
Even the highway and local roads are congested
with cars leaving Osaka bound westward.
Not to mention bank employees and
security guards have all evacuated.
Now'd be a great time to rob a bank, huh?
I think it's best not to do that.
Security systems nowadays are pretty tight.
It's a joke, a joke.
Don't interrupt when adults are talking.
Security...
Hey.
What the...
Don't scare me.
I saw something interesting.
Sorry, I'll call you back.
Hey!
Damn, he did it again.
What's with him?
Say, Kazuha-oneesan?
What?
Who was Uncle Heiji talking to just now?
It's Conan-kun.
Conan-kun?
He's about your age, an elementary school student who's really smart.
He always hit it off well with Heiji.
Then, what did he mean by "when adults are—"
Hey!
Don't go blabbering idle talk!
Fine, fine, it was my bad...
Uncle Heiji!
What is it?
This "something interesting".
Rocket flares?
What's this about?
We'll reach Nara once we pass this mountain.
With the airship smoking like this, people
in Nara will certainly be surprised, huh?
They won't just be surprised!
Panic?
Those guys already posted the news about
the bacteria and the bombs on the internet.
At the moment, everyone's being evacuated, and...
Yeah.
If Nara is like that too...
It'll be a lucky break for thieves.
Idiot.
Even if there's no people, nowadays the security systems...
Security?
Don't tell me...
That's why they chose Nara?
Certainly a possibility.
But...
If that's true, why did they...
Prepare bacteria just for this?
I see.
All right, got it.
You can count on me.
Where are you going, Heiji?
Nara, Nara.
Nara?
If it's Nara, is it related to that airship?
Yeah, and it's dangerous, so don't tag along.
Please take me with you!
Idiot, I just told you not to come along!
I know Nara's roads very well, so I'll be a big help!
I'm going too!
What are you talking about now?
First of all, three people on a bike is illegal...
Don't worry, don't worry!
I just thought of a great plan.
Hold on tight!
Got it!
Satoshi-kun, are you all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
We'll arrive there soon, so please hang on.
Are you sure this is really all right?
It can't be...
Why?
Ran!
Sit down!
Ran...
Rashes...
Help me!
Please!
Let go!
Hey, you get in too!
Don't touch me!
Damn...
What does this mean?
As Kid said, infection won't occur merely by touching one's arms.
Not only did Ran shove him away...
Fujioka-san didn't cough or sneeze.
On the other hand, Genta was sneezed on...
And even breathed in the bacteria in the smoking room, but still wasn't infected.
Why is that?
That director named Mizukawa also had rashes on his right palm.
Could it be...
The airship is after us!
The bacteria!
The bacteria is pouring down!
It's jam-packed with bombs!
Goufuku Temple
Everything's on standby!
Hurry, hurry!
Hurry up and evacuate!
But the Buddhas...
The Buddhas will not be infected by bacteria!
Hurry up and get in the vehicle!
What if they punish us...
We'll come back, don't worry!
Just get in!
Ran...
Ran-oneesan...
Go check it out.
Hey!
You...
Cat-A?
Cat-A, what's wrong?
Respond!
Go check the situation!
Hey!
What's wrong?
He's asleep?
Cat-B!
What's wrong?
Something happen?
Cat-B!
If it's about Cat-B, he's out cold on the roof.
Which is strange...
Since cats shouldn't land on their backs.
It's Conan!
So he did come back!
With Kid-san, right?
Kid-san isn't here.
Damn!
Cat-C, D, E:
Go capture that brat!
No...
Once you find him, open fire.
Roger.
You go guard the dining room.
Cat-F!
Roger.
I'll head there once I've switched to autopilot!
Damn it!
Damn!
The brat's gone up to the sky deck!
One, and...
Seven!
The trap set for Kid came in handy.
And this too.
Wait a minute...
Did he do this on purpose so I could use it?
Don't move!
Throw that away.
Keep your hands in the air.
I saw everything.
You're really something, aren't you?
Now, put your hands on that!
You sure you want that?
Don't defy me.
Yes, sir...
I'm not like the others who...
Can't say I didn't warn you.
Damn you!
Hey, hey...
Are you serious?
What is all this?
The third trap Uncle Jirokichi set up just for you.
Is that so?
If I stole the jewel...
And escaped from that hole by firing my grappling hook...
That was a close one!
He's one hell of an old guy.
And hey, you...
Were you up here this whole time?
Take this!
You're good.
And here's...
A warrior's medal.
Are the rest of you listening?
I've taken out your leader.
Along with the other three.
What?
Don't fool around.
Go, Lupin!
We did it!
Geez.
Don't wave this thing around carelessly!
Edogawa-kun!
We've disabled the two here as well.
Roger that.
What an impressive number of records.
Moreover, within the last two to three hours...
Hey, who'd you call?
And so many times.
If you don't wanna talk...
What do you plan to do with that?
If you don't confess...
I figure I'll pour the contents all over you.
Do what you want.
Put it down for a while.
Slowly...
I see.
This is one neat plan.
The bioterrorist attack on the airship was just a diversion.
Your real intention was to evacuate everyone and steal the
nationally-protected Buddha statues from the empty temple.
Temples usually don't have security systems
so you guys counted on that, didn't you?
Normally, no one would think of stealing Buddha statues.
You have sinned!
What are you talking about?
We just wanted to protect the Buddha statues.
If that's so, share with us the name of one Nara police inspector.
Anyone'll do—give it a try.
That's...
What's this?
You can't even come up with one?
Being a police officer, that's strange.
Hey, there was one.
A police inspector with a name that suits Nara.
They're just a bunch of kids.
Do it.
Hello?
What'd you just say?
They said we're just a bunch of kids.
What's that?
They're idiots, aren't they?
Definitely.
How can there be only three of us...
When we're here to catch a group of thieves?
What!?
Damn!
This is the Nara Prefecture Investigation Third Section Inspector...
Shikatsuno Tsuyoshi
Nara Police Officer
Shikatsuno Tsuyoshi!
Remember my words:
Never belittle the Nara police!
Yo, Kudo.
All the thieves after the Buddha statues have been apprehended.
Of course, all the abbots are safe as well.
Got it.
Thanks, Heiji-niichan.
Geez...
As expected, that boy detective from Osaka pulled some strings.
To say "pulling strings"...
Oh, that's right.
Here's this.
Thank you, lad.
That aside, we have to take Ran to a hospital immediately!
Oh, right.
About that...
I don't want to die...
Ran-neechan?
Conan-kun!
Don't!
Don't come near me, Conan-kun!
It's all right, Ran-neechan.
Because no one was infected at all.
But, the rashes...
Those rashes are merely the result of skin irritation.
Probably just a reaction from contact with lacquer.
Lacquer?
The person who brought Ran-neechan here earlier.
It was the same one who escorted Mizukawa-san as well, right?
Yeah...
I knew it.
Among all the people, he's the only one resistant to lacquer.
Given that his fingernails have turned black...
He's likely a former lacquer craftsman of some sort.
In other words, the culprits didn't steal any bacteria in the first place.
They only blew up the laboratory...
To make this biochemical terrorist act seem real.
This ampule is the evidence.
I acted as if I were going to open this in front of their leader, but...
He didn't even do so much as flinch.
If there was really bacteria inside...
He would've tried his hardest to stop me.
Just like how Ran-neechan asked me to stay away just now.
Conan-kun...
Isn't that right, Uncle?
Yeah...
Are you all right, Ran?
Moreover, look.
Apart from the rashes that appeared initially...
They've also appeared on your hands, arms, and...
The back of your legs, right?
No way!
I'm sure the culprits sprayed lacquer all over this room.
The walls, the sofa, the door handle, and everything.
That's why, for Ran-neechan...
The rashes on your arms were caused by Fujioka-san's
grabbing, who came to smoke and touched lacquer.
The rashes on the rest of your body were only
caused by coming into contact with lacquer in this...
Room...
Hold on!
Then, why was that person...
Hey!
What's wrong?
Conan-kun...
Damn it!
Based on the information from Nara prefecture...
We've uncovered the true identities of the hijacking group.
They appear to be experienced foreign mercenaries.
Mercenaries?
Then, their claim about being the Red Siamese Cats...
It's completely unrelated.
They made use of that terrorist organization's name...
In order to camouflage their true aim of stealing Buddha statues.
And the person who recruited them this time is...
Hold it.
To leave your subordinates behind and escape alone...
Don't you find that a little cowardly?
Boss of hijacking group...
Fujioka Takamichi-san?
Boy...
Well done in figuring out my true identity.
Nah.
I was completely deceived when you
pretended to be the person first infected.
Probably, right after the airship took off...
That female subordinate-oft ours
sprayed lacquer in the smoking room...
And left the ampule there.
Undoubtedly, this was per your instruction.
Afterwards, you entered the smoking room and
came into contact with the lacquer on purpose...
In order to convince us that you were the
first person infected with the bacteria.
On the sky deck, you invited Uncle Kogoro to the smoking room...
Mouri-san, how about it?
And grabbed Ran's arms...
To "infect" all the people who could pose a threat...
And prevent them from getting in your way.
But, it didn't go over very well with Uncle, so...
All you had to do was put sleeping pills in his beer!
Thanks to you, he was sound asleep until now.
For Mizukawa-san and the waitress, the rashes
appeared on their palms and the back of their arms...
Which were likely the result of them
touching something in the smoking room.
Genta, on the other hand...
Didn't get the rashes because he only peeked
inside there without touching anything.
In other words, you were the only person.
Only you had rashes on your neck and face—places
usually unlikely to come into contact with anything.
Moreover, the leader was constantly
talking to someone on his cellphone.
That's how I knew...
That you used the lacquer from the smoking room and
smeared it on yourself in order to induce the rashes.
You made use of the bacteria infection scare...
In order to isolate yourself and give orders to
the terrorist group when no one was looking...
You were the big boss!
That's quite a brilliant deduction, brat.
However, you omitted something of great importance.
What?
I had no intention of escaping alone in the first place.
Unfortunately, all your subordinates have been...
I don't mean them.
Not those that I hired.
I mean my original subordinates.
Don't tell me, there are others!?
Don't move!
Sonoko!
We told you not to move, didn't we?
Edogawa-kun...
There are two more here.
The cameraman and the reporter are with them!
Damn...
Besides, I didn't come here to escape.
It was to lure you out.
What!?
Do you know why we carried out the hijack
for the Buddha statues and not money?
In this information society...
It's only too easy to follow the money trail.
Thus, smuggling the priceless Buddha statues is comparatively safer.
Japanese Buddha statues are extremely popular overseas.
We've already secured a number of buyers.
Now that you've ruined my plan, allow me to return the favor!
We still have plenty of time.
Let's savor this while we can.
Hattori-kun!
You did a great job!
The credit goes to that boy.
That aside, is it possible to catch up with the airship?
I lost contact with him a moment ago.
I have a bad feeling about it.
Understood.
Listen up, Satoshi.
You should go home from here.
But...
I know.
We couldn't have protected the Buddha statues without your help.
Hey, Uncle Heiji!
I think the thieves' target is Goufuku Temple.
There are many national treasures there.
All right!
Got it!
Then, just let me go with...
No way.
It's too dangerous.
Go home with Kazuha-neechan.
Satoshi-kun, let's do that, shall we?
Your mother must be very worried about you.
I know...
But, can I meet that kid called Conan-kun next time?
Uncle Heiji's going to save him, right?
Understood.
It's a promise!
Kazuha, I'll let you handle the rest.
Leave it to me!
Heiji, be careful.
All right!
Let's get going.
To think that you were one of them!
OK on my end.
Hey...
Hurry up and untie us!
My bad, my bad.
I forgot to inform you that there's been a slight change of plans.
A change?
After all, the only loot left for us is this.
So you guys, along with the rest of them...
Can just die.
What!?
Since this is the end, let me share something nice with you.
We'll be making our getaway on a cruiser parked near that bridge.
Immediately afterwards, this airship will explode.
That includes the cabin housing the hostages.
Then, that's why you...
You may have managed to disarm the
bombs planted on the fuel tanks, but...
There are actually two more in the cabin.
Damn!
But before that...
I'll ensure you sink to the greatest depths of the sea!
Damn it
What should I do?
Something...
Isn't there something that can turn the tables?
We've caught up!
It's the airship!
They're flying really low.
Hey...
If they continue on that course...
Yeah...
They'll collide with the Akashi Kaikyou Bridge!
I can see Touto Tower!
And Rokkou's anchor mark too!
Amazing, amazing!
You think you can distract me and make
me knock my head against the bridge?
As if I'd fall for something so childish.
What was that!?
What's happening!?
Damn!
Amazing!
Just like a whale out of water!
Hello?
Hey Kudo, are you all right?
Hattori, just the right person for this.
Please contact the marine patrols.
Contact the marine patrols?
The mastermind, Fujioka, fell into the sea.
The culprit fell into the sea?
Oh, and...
Their cruiser should be parked somewhere near the bridge.
I'll leave their arrests to you.
All right, got it.
Well, I'll see you later.
I'll treat you to okonomiyaki tomorrow.
Look forward to it.
Hey, Hattori-kun.
Was that phone call to Kudo-kun?
Yeah...
I just wanted to ask, but...
Is Kudo-kun...
Actually Kaitou Kid?
Hey, everybody, you all right?
Yes, somehow.
Just a little shocked.
What happened to them?
If you're talking about the two culprits,
I think they fell unconscious over there.
During the sudden climb just now
they probably slammed into the wall.
Serves them right.
So we were saved because we were tied up?
Oh dear, what a surprise!
I wanted to survey the situation in the
hall and the ship suddenly lurched.
Damn you, Kid!
Kid-sama!
Where's Conan-kun?
That boy is all right.
He should be here soon.
Well, please help untie everyone.
Kid-sama, mine too!
Wait, Kid!
Damn you!
Of course, please be so kind as to untie the fine inspector last.
Well, ladies and gentlemen...
As assured, the treasure has now become mine.
Wait!
Don't run, Kid!
Damn you, filthy thief!
It's "phantom thief."
And so are the bombs?
I see, got it.
Well done.
All the hostages are fine.
All the culprits have been apprehended.
And with that, we can close this case.
Yeah.
I'm so hungry!
It's finally time for our long awaited dinner!
I wonder if there'll be eel rice!
But, we seem to have forgotten something...
Now that you mention it...
And now, it's time for your long awaited quiz!
Nobody was waiting for that...
Ayumi-kun, Genta-kun and Mitsuhiko-kun are good children, but!
Who has something that has nothing to do with the airship?
That's... all of it?
Here's a hint if you don't know.
All three have something to do with it, don't they?
If the three of them are good children, that
means they don't misbehave (hikoushinai), right?
Hikou-shinai...
Hikou-sen.
It's an airship (hikousen).
That's it!
I see.
If only that guy were someone as simple as this riddle...
I would've caught him with ease and gotten printed on the front page!
Say, Sonoko-neechan...
Where's Ran-neechan?
Come to think of it, she's slow...
She asked me to come here first so I thought
she must be going to the restroom, but...
She went up by the elevator.
Perhaps she went to see Kid?
What?
Guess there's no way light can go through...
Hey, Shin'ichi.
Damn, I forgot all about that...
Yo, Ran.
It's been a pretty exciting day, huh?
Shin'ichi!
Please turn yourself in, Shin'ichi!
A thief is a thief after all, and it isn't a good thing!
Please, Shin'ichi!
I understand.
Then, you...
If you give me the treasure I long for most...
I'll turn myself in to the police.
But, I don't have anything...
It is, of course...
W-W-W-Wai...
You...
Aren't Shin'ichi, are you?
Conan-kun!
Kid, you bastard!
That's right.
I am not a detective, but a thief.
Stealing is what thieves do best.
Even if it's a person's heart.
Kid-sama!
So cool!
You say that even after he did that to me...
What is "that"?
Lady Sky!
Kid returned it!
Hey, hey!
What did Kid do to you?
Well, it's something Shin'ichi wouldn't do.
Why?
Why is it something that Shin'ichi-niichan wouldn't do?
Why do you think that?
Well, that's because...
Not because I like him!
Don't get me wrong!
About what?
Wait, Ran-neechan!
Hey, hey...
What exactly was "that"?