"The autumn leaves of Mt. Mimuro are scattered everywhere by the fierce gusts of wind..."
Ooka
Wachi
"And now they cover the Tatsuta River like a gorgeous brocade of silk."
Ooka
So you have the same
specialty cards as your master?
This is all thanks to you.
Ooka Momiji...
I'll have to give you my thanks once today's TV recording is over.
Oh?
You're early.
You came already?
Y-You?! What happened?!
D-Don't tell me that...
"...after lying dormant all winter."
"Now the spring has come
and the flowers are blossoming."
"Because I left in a hurry on this journey,
I failed to even bring something to offer at the shrine."
"Please accept the dazzling blanket of autumn leaves over Mt. Tamukeyama as an offering from my heart."
Whoa.
One of the karuta cards
came flying all the way over here?
Oh, please do not
trouble yourself with that.
What? Alright.
I apologize for disturbing you.
She's so cute!
Come on, Dad!
Keep it down!
She looks amazing!
Just like a movie star!
Her kimono suits her well, too!
Wait.
Why are we here,
watching a karuta match again?
Ain't that why Mikiko was sayin'...
"This's before our discussion,
so wait in the waitin' room"?
But then ya go 'n got
lured in by that pretty lady...
And walked
right in to the studio.
Who's this "Mikiko"?
Didn't I just introduce ya?!
That girl with glasses playing
karuta against the pretty lady!
She's the prez of the karuta club
I'm in at our very own Kaiho Academy!
By "I'm in"...
Were ya in the
karuta club, Kazuha?
Yeah!
Ya didn't know?
Anyway, don'tcha think ya two took a little too long in the restroom, Heiji?
Sorry, sorry.
The doors to the
studio were closed 'n all...
And I didn't know whether
or not it was okay to open 'em.
Excuse me.
We're in the middle of rehearsal,
so can we have you be a little quieter?
Y-Yes, sir.
"Though I felt I would
gladly give up my life for you..."
Wow!
Hey, Kudo.
Don'cha think the old man's forgettin' he came to Osaka to have a discussion?
Give him a break.
After all, the kids kept pestering him,
saying that they wanted to sightsee in Osaka...
And he brought them in place of the professor, who had something come up and couldn't come.
In that case,
what 'bout that rich girl?
Oh.
If you mean Sonoko...
She's down with a cold.
But I had no idea you were part of the karuta club, Kazuha-chan!
I do it 'long
side the aikido club!
The karuta club was about to disband 'cause of a lack of new members...
So they asked me
just to add my name.
I participate every now and then to come to Mikiko's practices.
I'm kinda like
a zombie member!
A "zombie member"? That's funny!
You two lively ladies
seem to be enjoying yourselves.
Almost as if you're at a café.
We're sorry!
I'm high school detective, Kudo Shinichi.
While visiting an amusement park with my childhood friend and classmate, Mouri Ran...
I witnessed a man in black in the midst of a suspicious transaction.
While caught up in watching the deal...
I failed to notice his
partner sneaking up behind me.
That man forced me to take poison...
And when I came to...
My body had shrunk.
If those guys found out that
Kudo Shinichi was still alive...
They'd come after me again, and put those around me at risk.
At Professor Agasa's suggestion,
I decided to hide my true identity.
And the moment
Ran asked for my name...
I became Edogawa Conan.
In order to obtain
information on those guys...
I went to live with Ran,
whose father is a private detective.
This is Hattori Heiji,
the High School Detective of the West.
Using the powers of deduction he inherited from his father, the superintendent of the Osaka Police...
He solves countless difficult cases...
And is one of the few
who know my true identity.
Toyama Kazuha.
Classmate and
childhood friend of Hattori.
In Hattori's words,
"she's always getting jealous".
What lies ahead for these two?
And lastly, the future queen,
who's shrouded in mystery.
Who exactly is she?
Even though I've shrunk,
my mind remains the same...
That of an unbeaten great detective.
There's always only one truth!
Man...
We come to a TV studio, and we're stuck in the waiting room?
I wanted to see
the real take, too...
That's not possible.
Because they were
even angry with Mr. Kogoro.
I'm sorry.
This is my fault,
for getting so loud.
Oh, I know!
Once everyone's back, how about we go buy some souvenirs?
What?!
Really?!
Seriously?!
Yes.
If you guys are good and behave until the recording is over, that is.
Of course!
Alright!
Let's all go shopping together!
Speaking of which...
What happened to Conan-kun?
Oh, about Conan-kun...
He's keeping an eye
on Dad in my place.
Hey, boy.
Didn't they tell you to go
wait in the waiting room, too?
But Ran-neechan asked me to come keep an eye on how the recording is going.
Jeez.
All right, clear the way!
Please open a path!
Karuta cards coming through!
Wow! Those're the
Satsuki Cup karuta cards!
They're really playin' up
those karuta cards, aren't they?
What're ya sayin', Kazuha?
In the Satsuki Cup...
Those are the legendary karuta cards used in the final match of the nationals, ain't they?
Oh, yeah...
Playin' a match with those cards was your dream, wasn't it, Mikiko?
Not just mine.
In the 20-year history of the Satsuki Cup...
There ain't no one who hasn't
longed to hold those cards.
Oh, how I'd like to touch those legendary cards in the finals, even just once.
Hey...
Why are those cards
only used in the final?
They've been through many intense matches, so they're badly damaged.
And so, other than when
they're used in the final...
They're put in a case like that, and usually on display in an art museum.
Even so, don'cha think those guards're
makin' too big of a deal about them?
No, they're not!
There was a big panic after last year's Satsuki Cup, when the karuta cards disappeared.
In the end, the cards
were found right away...
But by saying security
aught to be tightened...
It seems the reigning champ, Yajima-san, satisfied Chairman Achiwa.
I see.
By the way...
Who are those two, again?
Are ya an idiot, old man?!
Ain't those the people
you're about to meet with?!
Oh, are they?
Consistent as ever, old man...
The president,
Achiwa Kensuke, is pictured here.
Oh?
He's a bigwig who both established and built up Achiwa Real Estate throughout his lifetime...
And is even called the
Real Estate King of Naniwa.
If that's him, why is a
man like that managing karuta?
It seems it's his only hobby.
Apparently, he's got
considerable skill at it, too.
But it says here that Achiwa-san himself wanted to be a card reader rather than a player.
Whoa!
Who's that beautiful woman?!
That's Satsuki-san, Achiwa-san's wife.
What? She's married?
The Satsuki Cup was originally created by Satsuki-san, when she was the queen...
And Achiwa-san became the
chairman of it as her successor.
Another thing that looks like
it'll come up at the discussion...
Oh, doesn't this
seem kind of interesting?
When Achiwa-san holds his wife Satsuki-san's important matches...
It says he's superstitious about making sure his car's washed the day before.
He's saying that making his car clean is a key to her success and victory.
So, is it okay for me to have a three-person
discussion with this superstitious couple?
No...
His wife, Satsuki-san, passed away due to illness three years ago.
Today's discussion will be
with only Chairman Achiwa.
I-Is that so?
Um...
Who's this really strong-looking guy who's always beside Achiwa-san in the pictures?
Oh, he's Kaieda Tougo-san,
who acted as Achiwa-san's secretary.
Word is that he's a sharp man, having been fully responsible for managing Achiwa Real Estate behind the scenes...
But he quit as the secretary,
and as for where he is now...
Hey, Hattori-kun!
Stop saying such baseless things!
The chairman of the Satsuki Cup ain't got no one "behind the scenes"!
Yeah, Heiji!
Now, now...
That's the rumor. The rumor.
The chairman's entering the studio!
It's Chairman Achiwa!
I've gotta greet him!
It's a pleasure to work
with you today, Mr. Chairman.
Yes, same to you.
It's a pleasure to have you.
Yes, sir.
I hear there's a demonstration with Yajima-kun and Momiji-kun today...
Followed by the match, correct?
Yes.
And when we're on air, we'll show the charm and appeal of karuta to the whole nation...
By featuring the Satsuki Cup's
special karuta collection...
Of which, through Yajima-san's cooperation, we obtained last week!
Oh! So you already have the
Satsuki Cup karuta on display?
Well then,
I'm really counting on you.
Yes, sir.
What incredible dignity.
Yeah. That's the
"Real Estate King of Naniwa" for ya!
Excuse me!
Has anyone been
able to contact Yajima-san?
It's almost time
he's gotta be here...
But we can't get
a hold of him at all.
That's certainly strange.
He said he would come in
an hour before the actual recording.
For the always-punctual
Yajima-kun to be late...
Go tell Sekine-kun to
come in as well, just in case.
In the worst-case scenario,
we'll have him come in as a substitute.
D-Don't tell me he...
Time opened up until filming starts.
Yeah, it did.
So Heiji, where d'ya
wanna go for some okonomiyaki?
Well, ain't that the first place ya think of when ya say okonomiyaki?
Yeah! When ya say
okonomiyaki, it's gotta be...
I'm sorry.
Are you okay?
You're the one who
was playin' karuta earlier...
This is destiny.
Huh?
I thought I'd
never see you again...
What?
My future husband!
Her future...
Husband?!
WHAT...?!
I'm free after filming is done.
If you'd like,
could we talk afterwards?
Whoa...
This girl's boobs are huge!
W-W-Wait, what're you...?!
W-Well, um...
Momiji-san!
I'm sorry, but please return to the waiting room for the time being.
Oh? I had just
gotten to the good part, too.
Actually,
Yajima-san is late in arriving...
Yajima-san?
Well, he is the one
who planned this program...
So I'm sure there's
a lot he's busy with.
Well, I'll see ya later, Heiji-kun.
Yeah, see ya.
Who the hell was that broad?!
That's the pretty
lady from before!
She really is beautiful!
I'm sure he said "Momiji-san"...
Ain't that why I'm
sayin' I don't know her?!
But she knew
your name was "Heiji"!
Ran-oneesan.
So come on 'n spill, already!
Let's wait outside ahead of them.
Ain't ya gettin' angry over nothin'?!
Looks like they're having
some kind of argument, and all.
How so?
Let's go, let's go!
There's no way ya don't know her!
What's she angry about?
She acted so close!
T-That must be 'cause
we've met somewhere before.
There, see?
You do know her!
Haven't I been sayin' I don't?!
If I had seen someone so gorgeous, even once before,
how could I ever forget in the first place?
Someone... so gorgeous?
Well, I can't forget you,
for an entirely different reason.
HUH?!
What's that?!
What d'ya mean by that?!
Hey, hey...
You really don't
know this person, Heiji-niichan?
Ooka... Momiji?
"High school champion of the Satsuki Cup for two consecutive years."
Second-year
student at Senshin High...
"Viewed as certain to
become the future queen."
Ooka Momiji?
The future queen?
Is this the advance
notice you mentioned?
Yes.
It only says,
"I will blow up Nichiuri TV".
What're these
photos of karuta cards?
They're photos that
were attached to the email.
We don't know
what they mean yet.
So?
Does Nichiuri TV know about this?
We've issued them an alert, but...
What do you make of this, Heizo?
Is it a mere prank?
Or a genuine bomb threat?
I cannot judge
based on this email alone...
But if it's not a prank,
this is a very serious matter.
Moments ago, the Osaka Prefectural Police issued us an official emergency evacuation warning.
All all operations and recording have been temporarily suspended...
What's this creepy announcement?
Please vacate the premises via
the nearest emergency staircase.
What's this?
I repeat...
Huh? Now there's
an evacuation drill?!
Moments ago...
The Osaka Prefectural Police issued us an official emergency evacuation warning.
Is something starting?
It's saying "police", isn't it?
Maybe they're
recording something for TV.
All operations and recording
have been temporarily suspended.
Please vacate the premises via
the nearest emergency staircase.
Hey, go look into this!
Y-Yes, sir!
What's going on here?
Kazuha, head for
the fire escape now!
Got it?
W-What about you, Heiji?!
I've gotta find
out what happened!
You go 'n get
outta here ahead of me!
Wait, Heiji!
Oh, come on...
That's dangerous!
Hey, boy!
Where're you trying to go?
I forgot something in the studio.
You idiot!
Couldn't you hear
the announcement just now?!
Aw...
I do apologize.
This is a first for me, as well.
It's my first
evacuation drill in a kimono.
This is serious!
We need to evacuate immediately!
Calm down.
What happened?
I found out there was a
threat to blow this place up!
What?!
Chairman Achiwa...
This may be false...
But until we confirm everyone's safety, we should evacuate for the time being!
Yes, you're right.
Everyone, we're getting out,
just as the announcement said!
Go on, hurry!
Y-Yes, sir!
What are ya doin', Mikiko-kun?
It's dangerous here. Hurry and go!
You too, Achiwa-san!
What're ya doin'?!
Hurry 'n get out!
Everyone, please move in an
calm and orderly fashion.
There is nothing wrong.
Everything's fine.
You guys wait here,
and don't move about, okay?
Now, once everyone has
been confirmed safe...
What?
We gotta wait again?!
It won't connect, after all.
We left Dad behind, but is he okay?
Ran!
Dad! Conan-kun!
What on earth is going on here?
Don't tell me they're having an evacuation drill or something without any advance notice?!
Hey, Conan!
No...
We thought you were
lost or something.
I heard from one of
the TV station staff before.
O-Oh, yeah.
They said this building
received a bomb threat.
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
Oh, man. Really?
By the way, where's
Kazuha-chan and Hattori-kun?
What?
Weren't they with you all?
No...
I'm worried, so I'm
going to go look for...
No, I'll go.
Don't any of you
move from this spot.
Got it?!
Honestly!
How could we be having an evacuation drill when we're so busy?!
This goes way
too far for a joke.
Ah, Heiji!
Mikiko!
Didn't I tell ya to
go ahead and evacuate?!
Yeah, ya did, but
I was worried 'bout ya two...
Sorry, Kazuha.
I can't leave those
karuta cards behind, after all!
If I calculate their position
from their smartphone's GPS...
What?! Hattori's still inside?!
You there!
What're you doing?
Forget those!
Just hurry and evacuate!
Honestly...
Mikiko!
Kazuha!
Hattori-kun!
Do you all know
how dangerous this is?
I'm sorry!
Honestly...
I've taken three
into care in studio three.
Mikiko!
They all seem uninjured.
This is really going too far!
I'm sorry.
Then hurry and get them out of there.
When I thought the
bomb threat might be real...
Roger.
It's like I couldn't stop myself.
We don't know when
the explosion will take place.
We'll instruct everyone to keep their distance and be on alert.
Please do.
He's begun evacuating the
three who were still in the studio.
Is that everyone?
Yes, sir.
All right!
We shall now begin searching
for any suspicious objects.
Begin heading in, men!
Roger!
We were in there!
Is there really a bomb?!
I bet it's a prank, anyhow.
Come on, hurry!
This way!
Seriously?!
Everyone, take cover!
Men, fall back more!
Get away from the building!
Hurry, Mr. Chairman!
Watch out!
Kazuha!
Whoa!
No!
It's dangerous, so stay back!
Damn it!
Where'd they go?!
It can't be...
You didn't get caught
up in this, right, Hattori?!
Kazuha!
You mustn't go!
It's dangerous there.
Okay, let's go.
Ow...
Are you okay? Can you run?
Uh, yes.
All right, then.
Let's go. This way!
We can't make it to the
safe zone anymore, can we?
Indeed.
Someone made it out again!
Is there no one else left?
They said there
are still two inside, so...
What?!
Kazuha, this way!
Damn it!
Heiji!
That was close...
Take cover, take cover!
Everyone get away!
So goin' down is out?
Kazuha, this way!
We're goin' up.
What d'ya mean?
We ain't goin' down?
If we can't get out, we've gotta get somewhere we can breathe first!
Wait, is Hattori...
Going up?!
Damn.
It really ain't connectin'?
Let's go, Kazuha!
Kazuha, this way!
This roof ain't
made of concrete?!
Closer! Get closer!
We can't!
Any closer than this is dangerous!
Sorry, let me through!
Damn!
I can't see anything
through the smoke!
I can't do this alone.
If I was alone, that is!
Kudo!
Sink or swim...
I gotta do this.
Go!
Is that it?!
So you've made
your appearance, at last?
Hattori!
Wait... Heiji,
where're we goin'?
Just come!
This's the only way to get down now!
Get down? But how?
We're gettin' down
from here, Kazuha.
Got it?
Heiji!
Gettin' down from here?
He's gotta be kidding!
Hey!
We're ready, anytime!
Same here.
There's no time.
We'll all go at once.
Right!
Kazuha!
We're really goin' from here?
Hey, I can't see in front...!
Heiji!
Yer kiddin', right?!
Close your eyes, 'n hold on tight!
Wha...?! W-Wai...
Waitta sec!
No!
Ya've gotta be kidding!
Sorry.
We'll be waitin' down there ahead of ya.
Come on, stop!
Sure.
I can't close my eyes!
I'm scared!
Kudo!
Damn it!
Impossible!
Someone's over there!
Will you let go of me?!
Someone really is here!
Stretchers!
Bring stretchers!
Kazuha?!
H-Heiji...?
Damn! That was the
only place to get down, too!
Think.
There has to be another
route out of here, somewhere.
A rescue helicopter!
No, that won't work.
Not with all these flames and smoke.
Far from landing,
it can't even get close!
Wait.
There's a river next to this TV station!
If I can jump over to it...!
Alright!
Will this not work?
The foothold I need to pick up speed on my skateboard here is already gone.
Crap!
Just by taking a quick breath,
my lungs feel like they're on fire!
I have to do something quickly!
If I don't...
Ran!
How could I just give up?!
There has to still be one here!
Somewhere! A foothold to
pick up speed on my skateboard!
That's it!
What're ya doin', Kudo? Hurry!
That's...!
That's Kudo, no doubt.
But what's he...?
I get it!
So that's what yer doin'!
Faster!
Go faster!
I can't breathe!
A little more!
Just a little more!
Oh, no! It's falling!
This is as far as you go?!
Damn!
I didn't pick up enough speed?!
It's no use!
I'll never make it!
I was waitin' for ya!
And... gotcha!
Are ya okay, Kudo?
Yeah... Somehow.
Here.
You dropped these.
Thank you.
Anyway, for ya to have
brought somethin' like that...
Did ya know Nichiuri TV
would be blown up?
You idiot.
Of course not...
I had it, just in case.
Ya sure ya didn't
summon that "just in case"?
Heh.
Seems that way.
Kazuha-chan!
Ran-chan!
Were you okay?
Yeah.
I don't really remember it...
But I only breathed in a bit of smoke.
That's good,
as long as you're fine.
Anyway, thank goodness you're safe.
Yeah.
Ran, it looks like I
dropped the car keys somewhere...
So I'm going to
go look for them a bit.
Okay.
Come to think of it,
where's Conan-kun?
Well, I thought he'd be
at this evacuation area, but...
Hey! It's Conan!
You're right!
Conan-kun!
Where did you go?
We were worried about you!
K-Kazuha!
Hey, Heiji...
Where'd ya go all this time?
Oh, just somewhere.
You too, Conan-kun!
We were really worried about you!
I'm sorry.
More importantly, where's Mikiko?
Well, it seems she injured her arm somehow, and was taken to the hospital.
Her arm...?
It's great that her injury
ain't more serious, but...
I asked what
hospital she was taken to...
So how about
we all go there now?
Yeah! Let's go!
Hei-chan!
Otaki-han!
I'm so glad you're safe!
Sorry, Kazuha, but
you go on ahead of me.
Wha...?!
'Cause I'll be right behind you!
Oh, come on...!
Fine.
Let's go, Ran-chan!
Y-Yeah...
Come on, Conan-kun. We're going.
S-Sure...
No more getting separated now.
Okay.
See ya, Conan-kun!
Did the police really get an advance notice about the bombs?
This is the email
that came to the police.
Karuta cards were attached?
This may have some connection to the recording of the karuta program.
And with Nichiuri TV in that state...
Seems like it'll take quite
some time to inspect the site.
Right.
What in the world is
the bomber aiming for?
Thank you for
taking care of me.
No problem.
Take care of yourself.
Mr. Chairman, how is it?
It's nothing.
Just a mere scratch.
Thank goodness.
To think we could get caught up in something like this right before the tournament...
Yes.
I never could have expected this.
As it is, I may even have to discontinue the Satsuki Cup that's been held for many years.
You mustn't!
I feel that it's in times just like this that we need to emphasize the strength of the Satsuki Cup!
But even the karuta cards used in the Satsuki Cup final were burned up.
If that's all, then
there's no need to worry.
The karuta cards are safe.
What?
What was that?
W-What do you mean?
During evacuation,
Hiramoto-san took them out with her.
M-Mikiko-kun did?!
Far from being burnt,
the karuta were safe, somehow!
Is that true?!
Are the Satsuki Cup
karuta cards really safe?
To check whether
they were damaged or not...
They were taken by the museum staff.
Mr. Chairman,
the karuta cards are fine.
Please rest assured of that.
I thought they were ruined, but that's great.
So Mikiko-kun saved the
Satsuki Cup karuta cards, but how is she?
Though I hear it's
nothing life-threatening...
It seems she's still being examined.
I see.
Mikiko-chan's
taking a while, isn't she?
The doctor said they'd only
be doin' some first aid on her...
Thank you.
Mikiko!
Don't tell me your arm's...
Yeah.
It seems it's broken.
I got what I deserved.
No way...
By going back to get the karuta cards,
I put you and Hattori-kun in danger, Kazuha...
What're ya talkin' about?!
Thank you, Mikiko-kun.
You saved the karuta cards that are also called the face of the Satsuki Cup.
As the representative of the Cup,
I must express my feelings of gratitude.
But, Mr. Chairman!
I can't play in the Satsuki Cup like this!
Indeed.
It is immensely unfortunate for the Satsuki Cup that someone of your caliber is unable to participate.
But for now, I think it's best for you to focus on your injuries healing.
That's right.
Ain't there another
competition next year?
That won't work!
Huh?
If we don't get a good
ranking in this year's Satsuki Cup...
The club will
end up being disbanded.
I just can't let the karuta
club end with my generation...
Mr. Chairman.
The police are waiting.
We should go soon.
Right.
Cheer up, Mikiko.
Yeah, but...
Frankly, it's true that
other than you and me, Mikiko...
There weren't any other members who can play karuta as well.
That's it, Kazuha!
You go out and play!
In my stead, as the
representative of Kaiho Academy!
Asking me out
of the blue like that...
Have you ever appeared
in the tournament, Kazuha-chan?
No, never!
But you always went
with me to my practices, right?
Yeah...
You have tip-top stamina,
and sharp reflexes, Kazuha-chan!
You're strong-willed and competitive,
never giving in, no matter the opponent!
And aren't ya
unusually thick-skinned?
I don't really feel like
I'm bein' complimented...
When's the competition?
It's the day after tomorrow.
What?!
You'll be fine!
Things will work out if we start giving you special training now, Kazuha!
An amateur's entering the
competition and aiming to win?
The game of karuta is based on the "Hyakunin Isshu",
a classic collection of 100 poems, each written by a different poet.
"Iroha Karuta" is a simplified children's version.
Rather than the Hyakunin Isshu-based cards,
should we have them swap in the Iroha Karuta for you?
Don't make fun of her!
I know Kazuha's skills the most, from how she's always practicing!
She doesn't have any
experience in competitions...
But there's no doubt her
skills match that of A-class!
Oh?
Is she now?
Come to think of it,
you were with Heiji-kun...
But what relationship
do you have with him?
We've always been together,
ever since we were little!
Heiji's my...!
My...
You really like him, don't you?
We can tell just by looking.
It's totally obvious!
Keep your mouths shut!
"Though I try to hide it..."
Am I right?
Childhood friends playing lovers...
Honestly, that puts me at ease.
In that case,
how about we do this?
The winner of tomorrow's competition will become the top candidate to be Heiji-kun's wife.
She'll get to confess their
feelings first and win Heiji-kun.
So, how about it?
Hey, what're ya saying?
If you're really serious about him, you're prepared to do that much, aren't you?
Kazuha, don't
accept such a challenge!
I'll say this in advance...
But I'm serious.
Wait!
I accept your challenge!
K-Kazuha-chan!
Seriously?!
It'll be great if you can hold onto that energy until the day of the match.
Same goes for ya!
Ya better not lose
before ya face me!
In that case,
I'll be taking my leave now.
Because I've gotta think of the right words to confess my feelings to Heiji-kun while I'm at the nail salon.
That lady seems scary, doesn't she?
Yes...
We saw sure saw
something amazing, didn't we?
You really are incredible!
To think you could
go against Momiji so fiercely!
What do I do?
Huh?
I made a terrible promise.
I'm very sorry.
No, It's my fault.
Dad!
Did you find the keys?
Well, about that...
I looked all over the place,
but couldn't find them.
What...?!
At this rate, all we
can do is make a spare key.
Oh?
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
It looks like the lady
from before dropped this.
What?
Let me see it.
You're right.
This is Momiji-san's.
Dad, I'm going
to go get this to her!
Hey, do you know her?
This's really
bringin' me down.
What d'ya think I should do?!
"What should you do...?"
She seemed kinda scary...
But she was
really pretty, wasn't she?!
If Heiji-san's confessed to by someone like that, he'll be head over heels...
B-But you're the only
good match for him, Kazuha-san!
Really?!
Really, really!
This's no time to be
grumbling 'bout something like this!
We're havin' all-night
special training tonight!
This's the first time
I've been to a hospital!
It's so big!
I could get lost in here!
Ran-neechan...
There she is, over there!
Momiji-san!
Wait a second!
Wait, Momiji-san!
Aw... She left.
What should we do with this?
We know her name and school...
But wouldn't it be quicker to
look inside for some contact info?
You're right.
Ran-neechan, let me see, too!
Oh, sure...
Let's see...
Oh, it's a photo?
Who is that man?
Oh, there's one more.
Wha...?
It looks like it's a photo
from when she was a child...
That's Momiji-san and...
...Hattori-kun, isn't it?
They're making a
pinky promise, aren't they?
I wonder what promise they made?
A promise to get
married, or something?
When they're just kids?
That couldn't
possibly be it, could it?
No...
He can be
awfully careless, so...
That might be it.
Oh, hey!
That's Heiji-niichan's motorcycle!
Make absolutely sure you
keep that photo a secret, okay?
Especially from Kazuha-chan.
Right.
What's this?
Ya two're here to greet me?
No...
What's up with her?
Ran!
Were you able to give
her what she dropped?
Oh.
Uh, yeah...
Hey.
You sure took a while.
Did you find out anything?
No, the Osaka Prefectural
Police're still in disarray.
Otaki-han's gonna contact
me once he gathers some info.
Mr. Chairman, regarding
that urgent matter I mentioned...
Could we have you answer this call?
Sure, I don't mind.
Honestly!
What's going on with Ran?!
Yes. What is it?!
From the Kyoto Prefectural Police?!
Yes.
And what about Yajima-kun?
What?
He was killed?!
Hattori!
Right.
I understand.
I'll cancel everything
and be right there.
Hey, stop!
Wait, you two!
Thank you for all your work.
Look, you two.
This place is off limits.
We're with Mouri Kogoro.
What idiotic things are you saying?!!
I don't mind you
lettin' those kids through.
O-Oh, right.
It's been quite a while, you two.
Inspector Ayanokouji!
The murder victim
is Yajima Toshiya-san.
He's the son of a
wealthy brewery family.
And seems to have
lived in this mansion alone.
His time of death is presumed to have been around six this morning.
His body was discovered
eight hours later, at 2 PM.
Oh, please watch your step.
There's a great
amount of damage done.
Y-Yeah...
You say this was a robbery?
Based on the state
of the crime scene...
I'd say it's certain
this was a robbery-murder.
Indeed.
We believe that, as well.
Someone breaks in,
seeking money or valuables...
And came across Yajima-san.
So in that instant, the murderer used the Japanese sword they were trying to steal to club him to death...
Took any money,
and fled afterwards.
But why...? Why?
From the look of things, it seems the victim had been playing karuta.
Sure does.
How did you two get in here?
So, Inspector...
We'll look over
the crime scene a bit.
Forensics have already finished their work here, so do as you please.
Wha...? They can?
However, as it is the weapon, we shall be collecting the sword.
Sure.
We don't mind.
Please accompany those
two until they're satisfied.
Yes, sir.
Then, I shall be waiting outside.
Please tell me
if you find out anything.
Sure.
What d'ya think?
I can't say anything for sure yet...
But his right hand...
Yeah.
So ya realized that too, Kudo?
It gives the feeling that someone forcibly removed something that had blood on it.
When you say something
in the room with blood on it...
A karuta card?
The murderer, who
figured out his dying message...
Mixed the card into the other cards that were scattered around.
It'll be impossible to find
that card outta all of these.
In that case, leave it to me.
There's someone who's
good at this kind of analysis.
Oh, what's that?
Seeing how that
remote has blood on it...
It should have been
right next to the victim, but...
Excuse me.
It it okay if we lift that TV up?
Yes, go ahead.
Thanks.
If he was usin' the remote
right before he was killed...
There might be
somethin' on screen.
It's Ooka Momiji.
So Yajima-san was watching this right up until he was attacked?
What's wrong?
It looks to be a past game...
Yeah.
"The 15th to 20th Annual High School Satsuki Cup Competitions."
Why was Yajima-san
watching this video?
Because it is an appropriately high-level match, being the final.
From performance strategy,
to how the cards are lined up...
There is much that can be used as a reference, even just by watching.
It does not have any
relation to this murder.
Oh, but...
Shut up with your "buts"!
Hey!
You're coming, too!
Enough playing detectives!
W-Wait! Oww...
Thanks, everyone.
Sorry for causing you trouble.
What're ya doin'?!
Oww!
Put me down, Uncle!
Not a problem.
We get it!
We get it, so let go of us!
Continuing with the news...
At around 1 PM today...
This news story again?
It sure is worrying.
Oh?
Why did you turn it off, Ai-kun?
You won't remain healthy if you worry every time this news story comes up.
Yes, but...
You got in touch
with the kids, correct?
But I haven't gotten a
call back from Shinichi...
Oh?
See?
Speak of the devil.
Oh! Pass me the
phone after you're done!
Sure.
Um, what in the world were you doing, without even contacting us?!
The professor's
really worried, you know!
Sorry, sorry.
We had all kinds of
problems on our end, too.
So, what do you need?
I sent some photos
to your computer earlier...
But I'd like you to look into
the karuta cards in those photos.
Just when we thought you
got caught up in the bombing...
Now you have
blood-stained karuta cards?
I want you to determine which of those cards the victim had been holding onto.
Aren't you good at persistently
piecing things like that together?
"Persistently", huh?
Oh?
There's a photo of
someone in one of these.
Yeah.
While you're at it,
could you look into him too?
Does this guy also
have a connection to karuta?
Well, I suspect he does.
I'll try, anyhow,
so give me a little time.
Thanks!
I'm relying on you!
Later!
Wait a second!
The professor wants...
That's just dirty...
In that case, it's the main members in the Satsuki Cup that're being targeted.
Right.
Two are certain to be marked.
I'll keep watch over Achiwa-san.
If I recall, we should be
staying at the same hotel.
Then I'll take Ooka Momiji.
Hold it! Hold it!
What do you need?
I'm part of the Satsuki Cup.
Let me through.
Please wait.
We'll confirm that now.
Sekine-kun!
What were you
doing all this time?
Didn't I call you
over and over again?
I'm sorry, Mr. Chairman.
I drank too much last night...
And I fell asleep without realizing my phone's batteries had died.
Good grief.
And when I woke up...
The news was sayin' the
TV station was blown up...
And when I contacted the Cup staff, they said you were looking for me at Yajima-san's place.
Now, when I get here,
there's this big commotion...
And all these cops are gathered here.
Did something happen to Yajima-san?
Yajima-kun... was killed.
What...?!
Apparently, it happened
as part of a robbery...
With the sword he had
hanging in the corridor.
With a sword...?
No way...
Achiwa-san,
who might this be?
Oh, I'm sorry.
My name is Sekine Kouji.
I'm working as the cameraman of the Satsuki Cup.
Sekine-kun was Yajima-kun's rival...
And for the past two years, the Satsuki Cup final was a competition between those two.
Well, I lost two years in a row...
And had thought
this would be my year...
But now I can never
compete against him again, can I?
So are you going to
hold the competition as planned?
Actually, I'm not sure
what I should do about that.
Ya can't give it up, Mr. Chairman.
If the legendary Satsuki Cup was discontinued because of Yajima's death...
Wouldn't that mean
Yajima died in vain?
I mean, wasn't he beaten down?!
Sekine-kun!
Show some discretion in your words!
No, uh...
I'm sorry,
that just slipped out.
I am part of the
Kyoto Prefectural Police.
I have two or three things we would ask you,
but may I have a few moments of your time?
Oh, yeah. Of course.
I'll answer whatever you need.
Then, come this way.
Yes, okay.
Mouri-san...
I need to return to Osaka soon.
Hey, Kudo.
I know who the killer is.
Yes, of course.
So do I.
I'll guide you.
He must be Yajima-san's killer.
But considering that
the Satsuki Cup was targeted...
I still can't understand his crime of blowing up the TV station...
I know.
Ain't it safer to keep watch over Achiwa-san and Momiji like we decided earlier?
Yeah.
I'm first!
I'm second!
No fair, you two!
Wait for me!
Whoa!
What a super spacious room!
Sonoko reserved it for us.
Remember? Wasn't even Sonoko brimming with excitement about coming?
That's apparently why she chose a hotel close to Nichiuri TV for us.
That's the Suzuki Financial Group, for ya!
Oh, is that right?
I hear they're also going to doing special training all night, so prepare dinner for them, too.
Then, please do.
Oh, why did this
have to happen to me?
To see you, cheering on your
friend with everything you have...
Oh, well.
Now, let's start
our special training!
We'll help, too!
Tell us if there's
anything we can do!
We will completely back you up!
You guys!
Really?
Thanks a lot!
It's my phone.
Who's it from?
It's from the professor.
Ayumi wants to talk, too!
Let's all talk to him!
Yes, let's do that!
Good luck with the
special training, ladies.
We'll be over there,
so we won't bother you!
By "completely backing us up"...
This is what they meant?
Oh, it's on! It's on!
You all haven't had anything
else happen since then, have you?
Nope!
We've been fine!
We're already at the hotel!
I see.
That's perfect.
Wha...?
It couldn't be...
Ta-da!
Now for what you've all been waiting for...
"The Professor's Quiz Corner!"
Is that what you called us for?
I'll keep the call short.
The unique style
of competitive karuta...
Is said to resemble that of a
type of traditional Japanese work...
But which of the following is it?
1. Tea leaf harvesting.
2. Kite flying.
3. Mochi pounding.
4. Rice harvesting.
You take cards and pile them up, so maybe it's tea leaf harvesting?
tako
Is it kite flying?
I wanna eat some octopus balls!
ote-tsuki
You can "touch the wrong card"...
mochi-tsuki
So is it "mochi pounding"?
Is that your final answer?
The answer is 4, rice harvesting.
Ai-kun!
Rice plants
become paddy fields...
karukara
And "once you cut" those paddy fields...
Oh!
It's karuta!
I see you may lack
any sense of warmth or fun...
You guys...
Don't stay up too late,
just because you're on a trip!
We won't!
Then, I'm hanging up now.
Okay!
It was this late already?
So much happened today, didn't it?
Dad and the
others sure are late.
I wonder if Heiji's
still with them, too.
If you're that worried,
why not try calling him?
Y-Yeah, you're right...
What's up, Kazuha?
What d'ya mean, "what's up"?
Where're ya wanderin'
about this late at night?
Huh? Kyoto?
What's goin' on?
Sorry.
Some minor business came up,
and I don't think I can see him off today...
So you head home ahead of me.
What's that?
I thought I'd have ya join us for the special karuta training, too!
Special training?
I'm gonna be in the
karuta match in place of Mikiko!
Ya haven't been in a
karuta match before, have ya?
Ain't that why
I'm doin' special training?!
When we were kids,
weren't ya really good at playin' karuta?!
Oh, now that ya mention it...
In grade school, I entered some open-to-all karuta competition, didn't I?
I was so surprised when, outta the blue,
ya won the championship, Heiji!
That was long ago.
Don't remember it anymore.
I remember it very well.
Even when Mikiko asked me
to sign up as a club member...
That was the first thing
that came to mind, too!
Oh?
So, are you done reminiscing?
I'm gonna hang up pretty soon.
What's with that tone of voice?!
Ya wanna get this call
with me over with that quickly?
I ain't sayin' that, now, am I?!
Yeah, yeah...
I'll be fine, even if you're not here, Heiji!
Huh?
What's goin' on?!
Enough!
Heiji, you big idiot!
Sheesh.
What's wrong with you, Heiji?
Jeez.
What's wrong with her?
Oh, well.
Hey, it's me.
There's a small favor I'd like to ask of you.
Yeah, that's it. Please do.
Man, am I tired!
Welcome back, sir!
Thanks.
I never thought we'd get caught up in a case, coming all the way to Osaka.
Dad, where's Conan-kun?
He said he wanted us to head
back together, and got in the car...
But now that
we made it to the hotel...
He ran off, saying he's going
to talk with Achiwa-san or something.
Wha...?
Oh, Conan-kun...
If the person I
thought is behind this...
Then it doesn't seem like
Achiwa-san will be targeted tonight.
What is it, Ran-neechan?
Have you finished
what you needed to do?
Oh, yeah.
Then hurry back
to the room, okay?
We had all that happen,
so I'm just so worried!
Yeah, okay.
I'll be right there!
There.
Now I can track him,
even if he goes outside.
Huh?
Wait, isn't she...?
What is she doing here?
"We promised each other that..."
Whoa!
That's awesome, Miss!
I knew it. I can't be
your practicing partner.
Come on! Don't you
know that was dangerous?!
Just a little closer and I'd be...
I'm back!
Oh! Conan-kun!
A trustworthy
helper came with me!
Oh?
Huh?
Who's that?
What...?
Heiji's mother?!
You see, I heard about
what happened from Heiji...
And rushed right over.
What...? Why?
To help you, Kazuha-chan.
Aren't you doing
special karuta training?
Well, I am, but...
I'll be your opponent.
Though, as a former queen,
I may be inadequate.
Former queen?
This was none
other than Heiji's request.
I shall teach you
everything I know.
However, due to a lack of time,
the training will be particularly intense.
Are you fine with that, regardless?
Yes, I am.
I'll do the best I can.
I knew you'd come,
Inspector Ayanokouji.
It seems we are
thinking the same thing.
Yeah.
Is the little detective not with you?
I'm havin' him keep
watch over Achiwa-san.
I see.
Excellent teamwork.
Yes, but I'm regrettin'
that I chose this end.
Because I never thought
she lived in such a huge house!
Thank you for
all your hard work.
My name is Iori.
I serve Momiji-ojosama.
Why not take a short
break and have some tea?
So he came here, worried about me...
My future husband.
"...incessantly bombarded by the waves, but the color of the dye does not change."
Oh, no!
Somehow, it doesn't
look like he's left the hotel.
"A bit like the waves that
pound the shores of Sumiyoshi..."
You battle on
through difficulty quite well.
To tell you the truth, I did not believe you would make it this far.
How about you rest a while now?
I... I can keep going!
Resting is also a
splendid part of training.
I shall return with some porridge.
Kazuha-chan!
Are you okay?!
Allow her to sleep.
She worked quite hard,
without sleeping even a wink.
What do you
think of Kazuha-chan?
She has much more
talent than I initially thought.
Though the best four
will definitely be hard for her.
To tell you the truth,
lasting until the final will be difficult.
That can't be!
Listen to what someone's saying until they're finished speaking.
I only said it would be difficult.
Never once did I say it would be impossible.
What one needs to
have in competitive karuta...
Is concentration and willpower.
She has those.
If her heart remains unperturbed, and her mind free from obstruction...
Even she has the potential to win.
If I show her this...
Kazuha-chan's heart
will be unsettled, won't it?
My talk will be over quickly.
Please calm down and take a seat.
Honestly!
It's almost the time
we have to get moving, too.
So, what business
do you have with me?
It's about Yajima-san's murder.
Wasn't that done by a burglar?
Was it, now?
Huh?
According to my reasoning,
it was a planned murder in cold blood.
That's absurd!
Yajima-san certainly wasn't
someone of good character.
But was there someone who resented him enough to kill him?
What about you?
Nonsense!
Why would I...
Sekine-san.
You've missed out on winning the Satsuki Cup for two consecutive years.
Because you were defeated by Yajima-san in the final both times.
If Yajima-san were to die, you would...
Stop with the idiocy!
Of course I want to
win the championship!
But wouldn't killing my rival to do so be going a little overboard?
And the police say it was a burglar in the first place, so why are you saying that?
There are several reasons.
First, there are too many peculiarities in the way things were ransacked for this to be a robbery.
In other words, how the murderer didn't lay even a finger on anything related to karuta.
That ain't connected
with killing someone, is it?
I see.
I'm certain that, due to the murderer remembering his attachment to karuta...
Was unable to
handle them roughly.
"Detectives" sure
think of weird things.
But whatever you two
wanna guess, it's all on you.
Anyhow, this don't concern me.
Crap!
Oh, yeah!
Huh? What?
The floor of that
detached hallway creaks.
D'ya remember
the creaking sounds?
What about 'em?
That sound's only there.
If someone had entered from afar, he would have immediately noticed.
However, there was no evidence of a struggle near the body.
I get it.
It sounds like ya wanna say the
intruder was acquainted with Yajima...
But that ain't right!
Even in practicing, karuta requires considerable concentration.
Once concentrating, ya
don't notice even the tiniest sound.
That's why Yajima didn't know someone came in, and got killed.
That's not possible.
Yajima's fatal wound was
right in the center of his head.
If he had continued his karuta, without noticing the intruder...
His wound should be
on the back of his head...
Or on his temporal lobe.
In other words, if Yajima-san and the murderer hadn't been acquainted...
He would not have that wound.
The killer was very
knowledgeable about karuta...
Was an acquaintance of Yajima-san, and lacks an alibi during the time the crime took place.
Furthermore, they were someone who had something to gain from his death.
How strange.
Those all match me perfectly.
But...
Everything ya said
now is just conjecture.
If ya wanna make me out to be the killer, ya gotta have some proof.
Sekine-sama, it's time.
Please come with me.
Sure, I'll be right there.
Too bad. It's already time.
See ya.
Let me ask you
just one more thing.
Ya don't give up, do ya?!
What is it?!
You see, something you
said caught my attention.
I don't know if you
remember it or not, but...
If the legendary Satsuki Cup was discontinued because of Yajima's death...
Wouldn't that mean
Yajima died in vain?
I mean, wasn't he beaten down?!
...is what you said,
if I remember correctly.
Normally, when one hears
that the weapon was a sword...
One would wonder whether
he was slashed or stabbed.
Nevertheless, you
said he was "beaten down".
Only the murderer would know that the sword was rusted, and couldn't be removed from its sheath.
So how did you know
he was beaten to death?
B-Because I saw his
body at the crime scene.
Isn't that enough?!
Just before you came,
a cover was placed over the body.
You didn't have the
chance to see his body directly.
I-I just sort of figured...
From seeing how the blood was splattered,
I just sort of figured he had been beaten down!
Anyway, I've got no
connection to this murder!
Man, how rude!
How will he act,
now that he's shaken up?
All that's left to be cautious for...
Is the match's venue, right?
Yeah. I looked it up earlier, and it looks like it's gonna be pretty bothersome.
This place is huge,
all things considered!
Oh? What's this building
in the middle of the cliff?
That's Satsuki Tower.
"Satsuki"...?
That's right.
It's said that in memory
of his wife, Satsuki-san...
Achiwa-san christened it as
such, once it was completed.
I see.
So it can only
be climbed once a year...
And doing so is reserved for only Achiwa-san and the two finalists, huh?
As for the match particulars...
There's a system that uses cameras and
microphones installed in the venue...
Which can deliver the match to a separate venue reserved for spectators across the river.
That's really complicated.
Through its air conditioning system,
the inside of venue for the match...
Has both its temperature and humidity
always set to, and kept at, a constant...
And the soundproof walls of the building completely shut out any outside noise.
It seems it's made up of
the latest and greatest system.
In other words, it's unarguably the greatest competition venue created solely for karuta.
I'm hungry...
How 'bout we go to the buffet?
I wanna have cake!
Then, we'll be heading out.
Come and enjoy yourselves.
I will.
Ran-oneesan!
Let's hurry and go play!
See you later!
Later.
Take care!
Sorry for the wait.
It's not like all the
souvenirs will be sold out!
Ma'am!
Yeah, you're right.
Okay, let's start training again!
Where should we go first?
Now, wait a minute.
Let's pick through rock-paper-scissors!
If you don't get a little more sleep, you won't have any stamina by the time of the actual match.
I'll be fine!
Kazuha!
D-Don't tell me...
You had Shizuka-san,
the former queen, train you?!
Sure did.
That's incredible!
With that, you might...
You might just actually...!
Okay!
Let's hurry back to the
room, and continue practicing!
If you want to practice so badly...
Shall I be your opponent?
After all, I do not believe this girl can advance to the final round.
What did ya say...?!
Kazuha-chan, you go rest.
Ma'am?
I shall play against you.
Are you dissatisfied with me?
Why is Ikenami Shizuka-san,
the former queen, helping that girl...?
If not, why not
have a fair match?
Since you're saying all of that...
Please do.
Where are Ichiwa-san and Sekine?
Apparently, they're going to Achiwa Hall, the competition venue...
To hold a rehearsal for tomorrow.
We probably don't need to worry, 'cause a police escort is accompanying 'em while they're moving...
But the problem'll be, as we thought, after they enter Achiwa Hall.
What about Momiji-san?
Relax.
She's in Kyoto, too, so
everyone's heading there together.
Oh, sorry. Phone.
I've identified the man in the
photo you asked me to look into.
What? Really?!
Yes.
The contents are a bit shocking.
I've emailed you the details...
So check them later.
Thank you.
Oh, yeah.
How are things
going with the karuta cards?
I just started running them
through some analysis software.
Have to hand it to the professor.
It looks like it can find which card he had been holding in an hour, at the earliest.
Great.
Let me know as soon
as that analysis is complete.
Right.
Sheesh.
"Nagoro Shikao"?
You've made me enjoy this for the first time in a quite a while.
Thank you very much.
Shall we head back now, Iori?
Yes, ma'am.
All things considered,
you really have some guts.
With your skill level, it is surprising to think that you are entering the competition.
Remember this well.
autumn leaf
My name is Momiji.
I'm in an entirely different league from a regular leaf, like you.
A-A leaf?
We already know that much!
I will not hold back, even if my opponent is as much as an amateur as you.
After all, I have let my guard
down for an amateur before...
And suffered an entirely
humiliating loss because of it.
Never once have I had
a more mortifying experience!
And so, I shall move ahead
with all the strength I have!
B-Bring it on!
Now, let's leave
the karuta talk at that.
Is it okay for you to be here?
The chairman is
worried about you, is he not?
Thanks for your concern.
But I am quite all right.
Because whatever happens,
the great detective of the west...
Hattori Heiji-kun,
will be there with me.
What d'ya mean by that?!
Oh?
Have you not heard?
Heiji-kun is my bodyguard.
WHAT...?!
Even last night, he went
without a wink of sleep...
Keeping watch over
me in front of my house.
Well then,
I had better be going.
I look forward to
the match tomorrow.
My, there is more to
Heiji than meets the eye.
Hey, Kazuha. Are ya okay?
HEIJI!
I dunno what kinda
relationship ya have with that broad...
But I'm gonna crush
her in the karuta match!
Just you watch, Heiji!
Yes. Well said.
What's wrong, Hattori?
No, I dunno what it is...
But something cold
just ran down my spine.
Did you catch a
cold or something?
A cold?! This ain't
nothing cute like that!
It's something
much more ominous.
Look, here they come!
Chairman Achiwa...
Ooka Momiji...
And Sekine.
They're all going together.
Don't tell me...
That's Sekine's car!
So what's Sekine-san's condition?
Based on the contact
we've had with the hospital...
It seems he has yet
to regain consciousness.
He, apparently, has a
50-50 chance of being saved.
Ooka-kun got caught up
in the explosion, but was she okay?
She didn't seem to
have sustained any injuries...
But to be safe, we're having her examined at the hospital along with her driver, Iori-san.
Can we have you explain, in further detail, the situation that led to this unfortunate event...
Achiwa-san?
We believe the bombing of Nichiuri TV may also have been targeted at the Satsuki Cup.
Hey, mister.
Who is this "Nagoro Shikao-san"?
W-Where did you
get that photo, boy?!
From that discomposure,
looks like ya got some idea.
If ya know him...
Then won'cha tell us
everything, Achiwa-san?
You see, there was a karuta competition
in Kyoto, called the "Nagoro Cup".
It was based around an elite few...
Meaning less than 20 members, who practiced fiercely every month.
Nagoro Shikao-kun was its leader.
He had considerable skill...
And it was even said that earning the right to challenge a master was only a matter a time.
But he had a strong
fixation on the matches...
And honestly, even watching him from the side, I couldn't call his karuta elegant.
Hey, come on!
I was faster on that one!
Hand over that card!
How can ya say I touched
the wrong card just now?!
Where the heck are ya lookin'?!
So five years ago, Nagoro-kun...
Came to Satsuki, who acted as chairwoman
at the time, and challenged her to a match...
Giving the condition that
she end the Cup if she lost.
What was he doin'?
Challenging the master of a training hall?
But there was no need for Satsuki-san
to agree to his match, was there?
In order to ensure Satsuki
couldn't decline his challenge...
Nagoro-kun leaked
information to the press...
Saying the Satsuki Cup was afraid of the Nagoro Cup, thus avoiding the challenge.
I see.
In other words, he drove her into a position where she had no choice but to attempt his match.
And so, how did
the challenge turn out?
The match could never be held.
Nagoro-kun never showed up, even after the starting time of the match.
In the end, it was
considered a forfeited game...
And Satsuki was declared the victor.
As for Nagoro-kun, the uproar among the press he caused not withstanding...
Forever branded as one who ran on the day of a match,
he became a disgrace to the name of karuta competitions...
And disappeared from center stage.
So what's happening with Nagoro-san and the Nagoro Cup now?
The Nagoro Cup was dissolved due to absence of its chairman...
And the whereabouts of
Nagoro himself remain unknown.
Could these incidents have stemmed from Nagoro's resentment towards the Satsuki Cup?
I do not know.
However, the one who most strongly advocated for the dissolution of the Nagoro Cup at the time...
Was the now-killed Yajima-kun.
What was that?!
As for us at the Satsuki Cup...
We wanted to settle this peacefully,
without aggravating the situation...
But even that
didn't come to pass...
So what about the
disbanded Nagoro Cup members?
We allowed them to join the Satsuki Cup if they desired, of course.
Although only two
of them ended up doing so.
By any chance, were those two...
Indeed.
Ooka-kun and Sekine-kun.
The two who got
caught up in the last bombing?
Yes.
Ooka-kun, in particular, grew skilled by thoroughly training in Nagoro-kun's techniques...
Thus, her numerous
specialty cards are exactly the same.
Furthermore, from the six cards with poems composed in the setting of autumn leaves...
Neither of them
have failed to get one.
She, most certainly,
could be called his greatest pupil.
Why do Nagoro's specialty cards include autumn leaves in their poems?
male deer
I hear it is because
Nagoro-kun's first name is "Shikao".
shika niku
Venison?
Yes.
Venison can also be
pronounced momiji, correct?
I bet Nagoro wasn't too amused by having the girl he favored join and be active in the Satsuki Cup.
Well, yes...
But why now, after all this time?
And what's his reason for taking the time to send an advance notice of the bombing in an email?
I still dunno why he kept
quiet for the past five years...
But couldn't that advance notice email be to call attention to himself and how he was back?
In which case, we would need to investigate these serial incidents in terms of Nagoro Shikao...
Exacting revenge
against the Satsuki Cup.
Excuse me.
What is it?
It seems best to form a joint investigation
team with the Kyoto Prefectural Police.
Yes.
What?!
Superintendent!
Upon inspecting
Sekine-san's smartphone...
They found a strange email
came in just before the bombing.
A strange email?!
The sender is unknown...
And I hear there were only some karuta cards sent as attached files.
What do those karuta cards say?!
Well...
"Because I left in a hurry on this journey,
I failed to even bring something to offer at the shrine."
"Please accept the dazzling blanket of autumn leaves over Mt. Tamukeyama..."
That's one of
Nagoro-kun's specialty cards!
What's wrong, Hei-chan?
I've gotta check right now!
Momiji's in danger!
Is this Iori-san?
From that voice,
this is Hattori-sama, correct?
Yeah.
Hurry 'n check whether Momiji's smartphone has an email from an unknown sender!
An email?
What's going on, Iori?
There is a call
from Hattori-sama.
From Heiji-kun?!
Pass me the phone, Iori!
Momiji?
Hurry and check your email for me!
My email?
What is this, all of a sudden?
More importantly...
I'm so happy
you called, Heiji-kun!
Oh?
What is this email?
There's only
some attached files.
Are they photos of karuta cards?
Wow!
How did you know?
What poem is it?
Read me the cards!
Oh? Sure...
"The autumn leaves of Mt. Mimuro are scattered everywhere by the fierce gusts of wind..."
Momiji!
Listen closely!
Ya absolutely
must not be alone tonight!
Don't even go home!
Come to the Osaka
Prefectural Police Station now!
Got it?!
I cannot listen to that,
even as a request from you, Heiji-kun.
For I must prepare for
the Satsuki Cup tomorrow.
Is this really the
time to sayin' that?!
You might be bein' targeted!
I'll be fine.
Because you'll be
with me, Heiji-kun.
You will protect me, right?
Huh?
I've never forgotten
that promise we made.
Promise?
See you soon.
That idiot hung up on me!
But it seems she
received a karuta email, correct?
Yeah.
Otaki, increase the guards around Ooka Momiji immediately!
Yes, sir!
This means Yajima-san was the only one who didn't have karuta sent to him.
Wasn't a karuta card message also left at the scene of Yajima-san's murder?
In other words...
After the true killer,
Nagoro, murdered Yajima-san...
He left his own
specialty cards and left the scene.
But Sekine came later,
and further hid that handiwork.
I get it.
Through the message left at the crime scene, Sekine was certain that Nagoro had killed him...
And in order to hide
his former master's crime...
Wrecked havoc throughout the house,
camouflaging it as the act of a robber.
Are the police saying that Sekine-kun
was at the scene of the murder first?
Yes.
There's an extremely high likelihood of that.
Actually, we had a certain someone
analyze photos of the crime scene.
From the shape and direction of the bloodstains on the karuta...
All right!
It should have calculated how the cards were arranged at the time of his murder.
Look at the TV!
Because the ones on the
right were laid out on the floor...
Those are the cards that
got Yajima-san's blood on them.
The ones on the
left are clean cards...
And cards that got blood on them from being mixed in with the others later on.
Then, based on the bending and such of the cards with faint blood stains...
The card Yajima-san
had been holding was...
Number 32!
Harumichi-no-Tsuraki!
"A dam on the river cutting through mountain ravines created by the wind is..."
"Upon a closer look, a pile of fallen autumn leaves that cannot be swept down the stream."
As we thought, there was one of Nagoro's specialty cards at Yajima-san's place too!
Look at this. These are the cards that have been used in the crimes so far.
Starting from the left...
There's Nichiuri TV's.
Yajima-san's.
Sekine-san's.
And Momiji-san's,
which we just identified.
These cards all share having the phrase "autumn leaves" in them.
So all of them really
were Nagoro's specialty cards?
Yes.
It seems that Nagoro Shikao is,
undoubtedly, the true killer.
I never thought it possible, but to think that all this was really Nagoro's doing...
My worry is...
The number of cards with poems composed in the setting of autumn leaves, of which he never failed to get...
Come to a total of six.
What do you mean?
He means there are still two left.
What?
If Nagoro really is using karuta cards to call attention to himself and his deeds...
He ain't gonna do something half-baked like leavin' only the two remaining cards, is he?
Don't tell me there are
others besides Ooka-kun...!
The problem is the targets corresponding to those two remaining cards.
If we don't get the specifics soon, it'll prolly be hard to ward off Nagoro's crimes.
Impressive!
It seems you two can stop
Nagoro faster than the police.
Yeah.
But we need
more information to do that.
So, what happened between you and Nagoro-san five years ago?
W-Well...
There had to have been something!
We won't let
you say there wasn't!
Yes, there was.
I couldn't say so before, but
I'm sure it'll be fine with you two.
Come by my hotel room later.
How about I tell you, in detail, about what happened that day?
Now, you guys.
Wait here a minute.
I'm going to go
give this to Momiji-san.
Okay!
We'll wait!
Yep!
Milady.
The police contacted me earlier.
It was regarding wanting to
increase the guards at home.
Yes, I don't mind.
Excuse me.
You're Momiji-san, aren't you?
I'm Mouri, the one who contacted you earlier.
Oh, so it was you?
Thank you so very much for taking the
time to come and return something to me.
Oh, no.
It was no problem.
After all, isn't
this yours, Momiji-san?
Thanks a lot!
This is like my lucky charm!
Without this, I didn't know how tomorrow's match would go...
But now, I'll be able
to make it through, somehow.
To you...
I'll bet it took a lot to extend
a helping hand to your enemy.
No, not at all.
I hope she doesn't practice
so much that her fingers hurt.
What beautiful nails!
These nails are to
protect my fingertips.
In karuta, one's
fingertips are their life.
So, outside of practices,
I always have them done.
Is that right?
Oh, and I wanted to
know your contact info...
So I looked
inside your pass case.
And then I saw the photo...
Oh, do you mean this photo?
Is the one pictured here...
It's Heiji-kun.
I thought so!
This is a photo from when I lost to Heiji-kun
in a karuta competition I entered as a child.
As I cried from losing,
Heiji-kun said to me...
Stop cryin'!
When we next meet as adults,
I'll take ya as my bride.
So wait for me!
R-Really?!
Yeah.
It's a promise.
What...?!
He actually proposed?!
That's why Heiji-kun
is my future husband.
B-But it's a promise
he made as a child, so...
Child or adult,
it makes no difference!
Once a man gives his word,
he mustn't so easily break it!
Am I wrong?
How could I accurately deduce what's in the heart of the girl I love?
No, you're right.
"The rapids rush towards a plummet, and the water is spliced into two streams by a rock."
"Just like those two streams will someday rejoin,
I believe we two will meet again in the future."
I believed our hearts were connected, even if we were apart.
Please tell Leaf-chan this for me.
Leaf-chan?!
I won't let anyone
take a card I'm after.
That's what my master taught me.
Momiji-san...
Ran-chan!
What're ya spacin' out for?
Ran-chan, ya've been kinda weird since ya got back from sightseeing in Osaka.
Sorry!
Anyway, how are you doing?
Well...
Heiji's mom gave me homework sayin',
"You must choose a specialty card to win the match."
But I can't just go,
"This one!" and pick a card.
Do you really to
fret so much about it?
Isn't the Hyakunin Isshu full of love songs?
Don't think about
the matches and such.
I think you just need to pick
a song you like that strikes home.
Love, huh?
If it was me,
I guess I'd go with this one.
"You were gone
before I was able to see..."
Oh, that's by
Murasaki Shikibu.
It's a poem sung about a friend one's managed to reunite with, but who leaves again in the blink of an eye.
Yeah.
Because just when I think I've finally able to see him, he goes somewhere again.
Even though I have so
much I want to tell him!
You're right.
In that case, I'll go with...
"I promised myself that no one would know of my love for you. "
"But I couldn't hide it in my face, and people even inquire of me what has happened.
A love song about love you can't hide,
no matter how hard you try.
That might be perfect
for you, Kazuha-chan!
It was obvious,
even to Momiji-san!
Come to think of it,
I wonder why that woman's so confident.
It's like she's under the
pretense of being Heiji's fiancée.
Don'cha think
so too, Ran-chan?
Y-Yeah.
I couldn't possibly tell her
Heiji-kun proposed to Momiji-san as a child.
What?!
Nagoro came to challenge Satsuki-san the day before the match?!
Is that true?!
Yes, while I was away.
That article states that Nagoro was
afraid of his match against Satsuki and ran...
But he had actually
come the day before.
But why'd he come a day early?!
No idea. We won't know the reason without asking Nagoro himself...
But he may have told Satsuki his goal was to defeat her using the Satsuki Cup's karuta cards.
He used those cards?
But aren't the Satsuki Cup's karuta cards usually kept in a museum?
At the time, there was no fear of them being stolen, so they were kept at my home.
But ya can't hold a match without someone to read the cards, can ya?
You see all the cassette tapes
that are lined up on that shelf?
Long ago, those were
used for karuta practices.
So, how'd the match turn out?
It ended with a
total victory for Satsuki.
It seems Nagoro
couldn't do a thing against her.
Just when I got home...
I remember him leaving through the entryway with a completely pale face, as if he were fleeing.
That was the last I saw of him.
Why didn't ya
tell the police that?!
If I did, there's a chance it could leak to the press or the other members.
And if they knew those historical karuta cards were used for a personal match...
I'm certain there would be backlash and anger among the members.
Well, it's not like I
don't get your point, but...
It's not that I
don't trust the police...
But it seems that Nagoro has
the upper hand against them.
Why does something in
this photo feel out of place?
That's why I can only
trust you two with this.
Is it because Achiwa-san's car is
different from the one he has now?
Make sure there are no further victims!
Stop Nagoro's crimes
as quickly as possible.
Alright.
Leave it to us!
Ran-chan,
two isn't enough.
Could'ya put in
two more of 'em for me?
My brain wants sweets.
O-Okay.
Could she hear
that sound just now?
This girl...
Not good, not good.
I can't use the "covering hand"
or "cross hand" techniques well yet...
So I can't read
the flow of the match.
At this rate...
Heiji'll...
Heiji'll be stolen by that girl!
What's wrong, Kazuha?
Makin' such a scary face...
Heiji?!
Ya get in a fight with
someone or somethin'?
Shut up, ya idiot!
Ain't ya that girl's bodyguard?
So go back to her!
What's with you?
I came to change places with the tuckered-out old lady, and play against you, too.
After all, I've never
lost to ya in karuta, have I?
That was back in grade school!
Ya can't be
my opponent now!
Hey, Hattori-kun.
Don't you remember anything from that
karuta competition you entered in elementary school?
Like a girl who you beat in
the competition, or anything...
Oh, yeah!
That was it, Kazuha!
The karuta competition back then!
The open-to-all one
that you entered and won?
Yeah!
Ya know how there was a girl who was really cryin' from losing the match back then?
That was Ooka Momiji!
Oh, that was her?!
So don't you
remember, Hattori-kun?
About what?
Anything you might have
promised Momiji-san back then...?
Well, I think I only said somethin' like "do your best next time"...
Anyway,
hurry back to her, Heiji!
Ya've gotta
protect her, don'cha?
That's what the police're...
Fine, just go!
If she gets hurt,
or worse, before the competition...
We can't even have our match!
Is that so?
I'll do that, then.
Mom!
I'll leave the rest to you.
Right.
"I promised myself that no one would know of my love for you. "
"But I couldn't hide it in my face..."
"And people even inquire
of me what has happened."
Nagoro-sensei...
Please lend me your
strength this year, as well.
Watch over me...
Satsuki.
"In Naniwa Bay, now the flowers are blossoming after lying dormant all winter."
"Now the spring has come
and the flowers are blossoming."
"The autumn winds blow through
Mt. Yoshino to hail the darkness."
Kazuha-oneesan got it!
We can immediately tell it's her since she looks different from all the other players.
Yeah!
If only Conan had seen her, too!
Isn't that her aikido uniform?
He couldn't help it.
It seems he has somewhere
he wants to go with Heiji-san.
I know!
Let's send Conan-kun the picture of Genta-kun we took at the souvenir shop before!
The one where
they were angry at him?
It sounds like it's started.
Indeed.
Well, even Nagoro shouldn't be able to get in with all this top security.
And not only Nagoro...
Not a single person who was not registered as staff beforehand can enter.
The advance inspection
was completely thorough, too.
We will not allow
Nagoro to do as he pleases.
What's wrong, Hattori?
No, it's nothing.
Who's this?
Oh, it's from Mitsuhiko?
Man, what are
you doing, Genta?
Grabbing a hold of a
thousand sheets together like that.
So that's it!
"The promise you made to me was as beautiful as the dew on the grass..."
I shoulda known.
Momiji's the first to make it out.
What about Kazuha-oneesan?
Not yet, it seems.
Hey!
Isn't that her?!
You're right!
It's Kazuha-oneesan!
All right!
Way to go, Kazuha-chan!
Making it through the
first round is quite a good start.
Oh, Sekine-san? Sekine-san!
Thank you.
To think that girl
made it to the finals!
It's certainly a surprise that there was still someone else with such talent!
Yay!
Awesome!
I wonder if she can win?
Of course she can!
That's Kazuha for ya!
She'll take the cup if she keeps this up!
I wonder if Kazuha realizes?
If she happens to win against Momiji-san, she has to confess her love to Hattori-kun!
Kazuha's sure doing her best.
It's finally down to the
deciding match with Momiji-san.
Yeah.
What?!
Sekine-san regained conciousness?
Oh, so it really
was just as we thought.
Understood.
We'll leave this end to the Kyoto
Prefectural Police and return immediately.
Sekine-san's come to?
Yes.
It seems he did pretty
much just as Hei-chan inferred.
But why was Sekine-san
at Yajima-san's home?
It seems Yajima-san had recently been hunting around for Nagoro here.
Sekine-san discovered that...
And believing he may find information regarding his former master...
He had apparently been
keeping his eye on Yajima-san.
Because of that, he
realized something seemed amiss...
And discovered his body?
Perhaps so.
I believe we'll get the details once we return to Osaka and question Sekine-san directly.
Right.
Then please allow the Kyoto Prefectural Police to handle this area.
Yes, sir.
Oh, please wait!
I'll go with you!
This is the end.
But why do I need
to plant dynamite here...?
What's that smoke?
Is there a fire?
No, if that was it, the fire sprinkler system should have started up!
Don't tell me it's a bomb?!
Come on, don't
even joke about that!
Ain't it kinda noisy out there?
What is in the woods to the west?
Well, there's only an
old storage shed in that area.
What happened on
the surveillance cameras?
That area's outside of the premises,
so there are no cameras!
What?!
Come on.
Don't tell me that smoke is...
Yeah. Let's go!
That's Satsuki Tower,
the place we're heading to.
What's this smell?
Oh, that's because the
elevator was inspected recently.
It must be the smell from the lubricating oil they used at the time.
Does it bother you?
No, it's not that.
I just might be gettin' excited.
It gets your heart pounding.
Is that how you feel?
Well, I didn't think I'd
actually make it this far...
So it is really pounding,
but yours ain't, right?
No, it feels as though my
heart will leap out of my mouth.
I'm just so, so worried about what kind of face Heiji-kun will make when he hears my confession of love.
I can't lose!
I absolutely can't lose!
You cannot come any closer!
What happened here?
Inspector!
Was it bombed?
Yes.
There's one victim.
Due to the body
being severely damaged...
It's not in a state where we can immediately confirm their identity.
I see.
So the question is when and how the bomb was planted here?
Well from looking at the circumstances,
there's a possibility that the victim brought it with him.
What?!
So Nagoro bombed himself by mistake?
Inform the station immediately!
Yes, sir!
Yes?
This is Ayanokouji.
What is it, Kudo?
Hattori, take a look at that.
What is this?
A ring?
Yeah.
Probably the victim's.
What happened, you two?
Look at this ring.
It may be evidence left behind.
An awfully extreme ring, is it not?
Yeah.
Nothin' less from one this huge.
Wait, a large ring?
Kaieda Tougo!
Huh?
By Kaieda, ya mean the guy who was Achiwa-san's secretary?
Yeah!
I'm certain this is the ring
Kaieda-san wore on his thumb!
In that case, is this
"Kaieda" the true killer?
No.
If we hadn't found this ring, the body over there may have taken to be Nagoro.
In other words...
This explosion was camouflage intended to make it look as though Nagoro-san had died.
Wait!
If Nagoro was made out
to have died at this point in time...
Don't that mean the two remaining karuta cards have already been sent to someone?
There are not two cards.
You see, I just
received a call from Otaki-san.
It seems that, after having his secretary check Chairman Achiwa's email history again...
He also received an
email with karuta cards.
That means there's only one card left?
Only one card left...
And only the final match to go...
That's it!
If Achiwa-san has
already received a karuta card...
That only leaves one!
And the person to send that one card to hadn't been chosen yet!
Don't tell me...
Inspector! Look into
Toyama Kazuha's smartphone now!
What?! All right...
But what is this about?
Why was the one, final card left?
It's 'cause they didn't know who would proceed to the final round!
Which means that the target is...
The three gathered in Satsuki Tower!
I'm deeply sorry, you two.
Huh?!
I hope the two of you exhibit the best of your abilities and show me a marvelous match.
We'll do our best, sir.
Ready... now!
Go for it!
Kazuha-chan,
show me your true strength!
What did you find?
Was there an
email with karuta cards?
Yes, sir.
Nagoro's specialty cards
came in about 15 minutes ago.
So it did, just as we thought.
Stop the final match immediately!
Understood?!
This way, Kudo!
Hey, where are we going?
My motorcycle's faster!
What?
Cancel the final match?!
Yes, sir!
Understood!
I'll contact the venue immediately.
Oh?
What's this?
Probably an earthquake.
And if that's all, there's no need to worry.
Oh?
I wonder what happened.
Maybe it broke?
What?!
We had just gotten
to the good part, too!
A power outage?
No, the lights are still on.
Crap!
It's already started!
Yeah, so hang on tight!
Hattori, how do we
make it to Satsuki Tower?
Leave that to me!
I've got an idea!
Come on, don't
tell me you're going to...
"To make a ruby red dye from the fallen leaves that cover the Tatsuta River:"
I knew it.
Leaf-chan didn't even move.
Does that mean she's
throwing my specialty cards away?
"The rumors keep us from meeting..."
What?
Why is it burning so vigorously?
We believe it was set
ablaze with some sort of fuel.
And the fire department
has not come yet?
The roads within the grounds are narrow, and the fire engines can't make it through!
And as I recall, the
fire sprinkler system is also down?
Yes.
So there's nothing more we can do?
Hattori...
Do you still think
Nagoro-san's the killer?
Nah.
Kaieda had already
quit the Satsuki Cup...
And only that man coulda re-registered
him as staff and given him the bomb!
President and Chairman,
Achiwa Kensuke!
As it is, he probably intends to kill himself and take those two along with him!
Like hell I'll let him do such a thing!
It's in the place
that's hardest to reach.
And Momiji-san also knows...
That it's my specialty card!
I bet you want to get this card.
But I won't let ya have it!
I win if I guard this 'til the end!
I'm getting it!
I'm getting it, no matter what!
I've gotta get it!
Shut up!
Shut up! Shut up!
All unnecessary noise,
just get out of my ears!
What's wrong, Kazuha?
Makin' such a scary face...
Ya get in a fight with
someone or somethin'?
Excuse me.
Oh?
That's right.
I can't fight it! I mustn't!
The sound of
the air conditioner...
my kimono rubbing...
The sound of
touching the cards...
The faint breathing...
And the beating in my chest!
They're all my allies!
It's fine for 'em to
come and be within me.
I'm sorry about that.
I'll latch onto the real sound!
"If you tell me that you'll wait for me,
I'll be sure to come back soon."
To make us believe it was Nagoro-san exacting revenge against the Satsuki Cup, this entire series of incidents...
Was a script Achiwa-san drew up!
Five years ago, Nagoro-san had arranged to have a match against Satsuki-san...
But, for some reason, he appeared the night before and had a preliminary match.
Achiwa-san said it resulted in Satsuki-san being declared the victor...
But there's something
peculiar about that.
The photo in the article
we saw at the hotel, right?
Yeah.
The article introducing Achiwa-san...
Stated that he always made his car sparkling clean the day before one of Satsuki-san's matches.
But it was filthy in that photo!
He didn't wash the car the day before one of her important matches...
Because he knew
Nagoro-san wouldn't come!
"Ever since the morning we parted, when the
dull moon hung wanly in the sky and you seemed so cold..."
I get the feeling I was quicker.
Nah.
I'm the one who was faster.
Ain't ya the one who best
knows which one of us was fastest?
I never thought this would
carry on to the brink of destiny...
If Satsuki-san had lost in the preliminary match they had five years ago...
Wouldn't that be the motive?
Yeah.
He silenced Nagoro-san in order to protect the honor of the Satsuki Cup!
And then, upon looking at the karuta pictures left behind as evidence...
Yajima-san became
aware of Achiwa-san's crimes!
But what were those
karuta cards evidence of?
What if he had inadvertently grabbed hold of a deck of karuta with Nagoro-san's blood on it?
I get it!
Fingerprints!
I didn't realize this either,
until I saw a certain photo...
But those karuta probably have Achiwa-san's fingerprints on them!
So that's why Yajima-san applied to have the TV station do a special feature about the Satsuki Cup...
To have the Satsuki Cup's karuta cards, which would become evidence, recorded on video!
Yeah.
That's why the bombing at the TV station and Yajima-san's murder happened at the same time.
Right.
But why?
Where's his reason for continuing his crimes all the way through the final here at Achiwa Hall?
What if Nagoro-san's body were at Satsuki Tower, where the final's being held?
That'd certainly be
the perfect hidin' spot.
So all he had planned all his
crimes from the very beginnin'?!
After all, no matter if he frames Nagoro-san as the murderer with his flawless plan...
It would all be for nothing if the body were found eventually!
I can see it!
Yeah!
"...of knowing where
my love will take me."
"You may have changed your mind..."
A dead card?!
This is bad...
The flames are already that far up!
We've gotta hurry 'n get down there...
But how?
Besides, we have to put those out!
There's no time to hesitate!
Just think of a way
to put out the fire!
You've got to be kidding!
Don't tell me you're going to...!
Here we go, Kudo!
Go!
What was that?!
There!
Now keep inflating!
Hurry!
Make it in time!
What? A fire?!
Stay away! Get inside!
Heiji!
What're ya doin' here?!
Hey!
The direction of the waterfall changed!
It's a miracle!
The fire's going out!
What?
What is happening here?
It looks like we
managed to make it in time.
As I expected of ya, Kudo.
Heiji-kun,
what exactly is going on?
Didn't I tell ya to get
inside 'cause it's dangerous?
What?
Conan-kun's here, too?
What in the world?
What happened, ya two?
Wouldn't it be
quicker to ask Achiwa-san?
What do you mean?
Get back behind me, both of ya.
Why do we need ta get back?
Hey, Achiwa-san.
Wouldn't it be bad for you
if we had these karuta inspected?
Come on, Heiji!
What've ya been on about this entire time?
I think I'll have this old man check my answers 'bout what happened in these incidents.
Huh?!
It all started exactly one year ago, when Momiji won the Cup at this very place.
The stack of cards
Momiji had taken then...
Very much resembled the ones her master,
Nagoro-san, had taken in a certain match.
It's true that because Nagoro-sensei trained me in offensive-style karuta, my specialty cards are the same.
But it would take an
awfully big coincidence to...
Even so, that
"coincidence" happened.
There are black stains on the edges of the Satsuki Cup's karuta cards...
And the late Yajima-san noticed these suddenly appeared five years ago.
And what are those black stains?
They're the fingerprints of the person who held them with hands that had Nagoro-san's blood spurted on them.
Nagoro-sensei's blood
spurted back on them...?
Nagoro-san, who was thought to have disappeared five years ago...
Was actually killed back then.
What?
T-That can't be!
And the one whom
those fingerprints belong to...
Is the true killer
in Nagoro-san's murder.
I lose.
I'll admit to everything.
In return, could you refrain from using the Satsuki Cup's karuta as evidence?
To the Satsuki Cup, those are...
Oh, so that's it.
There was one thing that
I just couldn't figure out...
But with that attitude,
I finally understand.
The fingerprints on these cards aren't yours, are they, Achiwa-san?
No, they're mine!
They're mine, no doubt about it!
It's true...
That ya and Kaieda have been
behind this recent series of incidents.
But ya didn't commit the murder of Nagoro-san, which started it all, five years ago!
It was Satsuki-san, wasn't it?
I understood everything
upon witnessing that sight.
That Nagoro had challenged Satsuki to a match, and that she had been defeated.
They used one of the cassettes I had stored as the card reader.
You know what that means, correct?
Satsuki had heard it countless times.
Of course, it was just
one pattern out of many...
But Satsuki had memorized the order of the cards being read to some extent.
She was in an overwhelmingly
advantageous position!
Nevertheless,
Satsuki had been defeated.
Nagoro's skills had far
surpassed our expectations.
I can only guess how
scared Satsuki must have felt...
For she was certain to suffer a humiliating and crushing defeat in the match the following day.
It was that fear that drove
her into committing the crime.
After that, Satsuki
lost all human emotion.
She even gradually distanced herself from managing the Satsuki Cup.
And then, two years later,
she passed away due to illness.
That is the truth.
Please understand.
Don't!
Stop!
Everything is Nagoro's fault.
If that man had not humiliated Satsuki, none of this would have...
He didn't want to humiliate her!
I believe Nagoro-sensei
went there the day before!
What?
Long ago, I had
asked Nagoro-sensei...
"Why do you bear such a
grudge against the Satsuki Cup?"
A grudge, huh?
So it really does seem that way, when you look at it from the sidelines?
However, if I don't do this,
I can't have a match against her.
I only want to win and be complimented with "you're incredible"...
By my first love.
F-First love?!
That's right.
Apparently, Nagoro-sensei started playing karuta because he was attracted to Satsuki-san.
But his doctor told him he could only play karuta for a year due to an eye disease.
I feel that's why he
played karuta so fiercely.
Because my master didn't have time.
So he wanted to show her his true strength in a match the day before...
Then hand the victory to Satsuki-san in front of everyone else?
To provide justification for having his pupils, myself included...
Of whom he would no longer be able to look after, to be merged into the Satsuki Cup!
In other words, Satsuki-san killed Nagoro-san, not knowing that.
T-That can't be!
What have I done...?!
W-What?!
Kazuha!
Are ya okay?!
Yeah, but it's hard to stand!
You guys!
Hurry and get on the elevator!
Momiji!
Hurry 'n go!
O-Okay...
Hurry 'n get up!
Let's get goin'!
Forget me.
Leave me behind.
Don't be absurd!
I still ain't gonna let ya die!
Momiji-san!
Hurry and get on!
Kazuha!
Climb up here!
Okay!
Hurry!
Damn, just a 'lil farther!
Gotcha!
What the...?!
Please, don't fall yet!
Damn it!
What?!
Like I'll ever let you!
Are you okay?!
We're coming right now!
Hey!
That was close...
Hattori!
This is bad!
It's collapsing!
Pull back!
Huh?
Hey, why are they...?!
Wait, don't go!
Heiji!
Get on, Kazuha!
Hattori...
Kazuha-chan...
Please!
Make it out of there, somehow!
Heiji, is that a...?
Yeah!
What's wrong, Heiji?
Hang on tight!
Don't tell me ya plan on jumpin' all the way to that wall over there?!
Ya really got it!
That's it, exactly!
Ya've gotta be kiddin' me!
What in the world're ya thinkin'?!
It's super far away!
Come on, Heiji!
Ain't it better to just
jump down into the pond?
Not possible.
If we jumped
down from this height...
Even the surface of the water
would be as hard as concrete!
Hold on tight, Kazuha!
If ya let go...
I'll kill ya!
Okay!
We ain't gonna...
Die in a place like this!
What's that?!
Hattori!
There's still somethin' I gotta tell ya!
That motorcycle...
Make it!
Heiji!
Kazuha!
Are ya okay, Kazuha?
Yeah.
I'm startin' to get sick
of these dramatic escapes.
Are they safe?
Man, those two...
I didn't know what
would happen for a minute.
By the way, Heiji...
Yeah?
What's the thing
ya've gotta tell me?
Huh?
What're ya talkin' about?
Ain't that what ya just said?!
That ya wouldn't die
until ya told me somethin'?
Sure ya didn't mishear?
No!
My ears were trained super well during my special karuta training!
If ya got a complaint,
just go ahead 'n say it!
What is it?!
N-No, wait...
What is it?
What's this thing
ya've gotta tell me?
The thing I wanna tell ya...
What is it...?!
Thanks for coming to see us off.
We're the ones
who need to thank ya!
Come to think of it,
what about your karuta club?
About that...
The school acknowledged
that I made it to the finals...
So it looks like it was
settled without gettin' disbanded.
Though I ended up
losin' at the very end.
Kazuha-chan...
Come here a sec!
Oh?
I wonder what happened?
What're they doing?
Telling secrets?
Really?
Yup!
Because I got the
"though I try to hide it" card!
I knew you made that
poem one of your specialty cards!
No, no...
Not just the poem.
It's the name of
the person who wrote it!
Taira-no-Kanemori!
In the Hyakunin Isshu...
He's the only one with Heiji's
"Hei" character in his name!
Oh, I couldn't see
any card but Heiji's!
Afterwards, I sent Heiji a picture of the "though I try to hide it" card!
Saying "this is how I feel".
You sent the "though I try to hide it" card to convey your feelings...
Isn't that against the rules?
Momiji-san!
Could ya hear us just now?!
You aren't the only
one with good ears.
Oh, if it isn't Momiji.
What're ya doin' here?
I came to give you
my confession, just as I promised.
Though Heiji-kun's
already confessed to me.
Huh?
What're ya on about?
Here's the photographic evidence.
They're making a pinky promise.
So they made a
promise to each other?
And if they break that promise,
they have to swallow a thousand needles!
Waitta minute!
What promise did we make?
"When we next meet,
I'll take ya as my bride. So wait for me!"
What?!
Surprisingly, this guy always has someone remember his embarassing moments.
Or do you want to make it like this story from long ago never happened?
Oh, I remember now!
This is what I said back then!
"Stop cryin'!
Can't we just play another match sometime?"
"But when we next meet,
I'll be much stronger."
"So hone yer skills 'n wait for me!"
yome ni toru = take as bride
tsuyome ni toru = become stronger
"I'll..."
"...be much..."
"...stronger"?!
I was goin'
against a girl 'n all...
And figured I
shouldn't hurt her...
So I went easy on her and
took the cards really gently.
Iori?
We're leaving!
Yes, Milady.
So long.
I'll let you go for today.
But I never let someone
let someone take a card I'm after.
Remember that well...
Kazuha-chan.
What?
She wants to play
karuta against Kazuha again?
Sorry, were you sleeping?
Didn't you know a lot
about the Hyakunin Isshu, Sonoko?
Yeah, because I play it
with the family on New Year's.
When I sent Shinichi a photo of the
"you were gone before I was able to see" card...
He replied back with the
"rapids rush towards a plummet" poem...
But I forgot what that means...
"Even if I'm now
separated from the one I love..."
Um, hello?
"We'll definitely
meet again someday."
The poem written by Sutoku-in
with that lovey-dovey meaning?
Hey! Hello, Sonoko?
Sonoko?
Thanks for the treat!
Hey, wait! Sonoko!
How could you have forgotten?
Zero.