Tonight, I've come to Tohto Tower in Minato Ward.
Here at Tohto Tower, the Tanabata Fair is currently underway.
Many visitors have made their way here to...
I know.
Meet at the professor's at 4:00 AM, right?
You too, Genta.
Don't be late.
Later.
Now, I just need a flashlight.
Let's see, I think...
I remember it being in this drawer.
Got it.
Who's there?
Ran-neechan?
Uncle's still out for mahjong, so it can't be him.
Just my imagination?
It's been a while, Kudo Shin'ichi.
No...
Isn't it "Edogawa Conan" now?
I'm surprised you're still alive, and as a kid.
Really...
Hell of a surprise, eh, Partner?
How...
How did they discover my identity!?
Conan-kun?
Conan-kun, what's going on?
I heard some loud noises down there.
Conan-kun?
Keep your eyes peeled.
Bear witness to the destiny of the
people you've become involved with.
Conan-kun!
Everything all right?
Conan-kun?
Where are you?
I'm coming in.
Conan-kun?
RAN!
Shit...
What a nightmare...
I'm high school detective, Kudo Shin'ichi.
While visiting an amusement park with my
childhood friend and classmate, Mouri Ran...
I witnessed a man in black in the
midst of a suspicious transaction.
While caught up in watching the deal...
I failed to notice his partner coming up behind me.
Those men forced me to swallow poison...
And when I came to...
My body had shrunk.
If those guys found out that Kudo Shin'ichi was still alive...
They would come after me again...
And put those around me at risk.
At Professor Agasa's suggestion,
I decided to conceal my true identity.
When Ran asked for my name, in that instant...
I became Edogawa Conan.
In order to obtain information on those guys...
I went to live with Ran, whose father is a private detective.
Enshrouded in mystery, they are the Black Organization.
Gin...
Vodka...
Vermouth...
Chianti...
Korn...
And Sherry.
Her real name is Miyano Shiho.
Her parents, who died when she was young...
Were scientists who worked for the Black Organization.
Under the codename Sherry...
She, too, worked for the organization, and
developed the aforementioned drug...
Apotoxin-4869.
However...
When her only older sister...
Miyano Akemi, was killed by the Organization, she revolted.
She took the drug with the intention of taking her own life...
But instead, her body shrank as well.
As such...
She changed her name to Haibara Ai.
While evading the Organization...
She began living the life of a first grader, just as I had.
Meanwhile...
I clashed with Vermouth, and came away with a vital clue.
I wouldn't do that.
If you attempt to unplug this device...
A signal will be sent out to my partner.
With your boss's...
E-mail address.
"Seven Children"!?
Yeah.
When you dial the boss's address, that's what you hear.
The melody of that song, Seven Children.
Don't tell me you're going to mail that address...
Idiot.
Why would I do that?
Well, I'll send a mail after Detective Takagi
looks into the person behind this for me.
He'll be killed...
Detective Takagi.
It'll happen the very moment he reaches that person.
And their next target...
Will be the one who provided him the mail address...
Which would be you, Kudo-kun.
If you understand, just let it go and forget all about this.
Because that e-mail address...
Is something that should never be opened: Pandora's Box.
Even though I've become smaller, my mind remains the same...
The unbeaten great detective...
There's always only one truth!
Beika Forest
Oh, there you are.
I found one!
A beetle.
All right!
So those beetles do like to gather at high places!
I'll climb up too!
That's impossible, Genta-kun.
I think you'd better not.
I agree.
The only ones who can climb that high would be...
Either Edogawa-kun...
Or monkeys.
Excuse me for being a monkey.
I know, you can use the suspenders.
Suspenders?
Oh...
These things you gave us back at your house?
That's right―I've improved them a bit.
With just a push of that button, they'Il extend up to 100 meters.
Hold the button down, and the belt will elongate.
Once you release it, the belt will immediately retract.
My bad...
Jeez, be more careful.
I found a beetle!
That's great, Genta-kun.
A rhinoceros beetle!
It stopped!
There's two of them!
A male and female!
Huh?
This female beetle...
Her wings have been taped.
Look.
It's true!
How mean!
There are some words on it.
Let's see...
Oh, it says "open".
This kind of tape is found on bento boxes
that they sell in convenience stores.
I saw it on that fried chicken bento I bought yesterday...
Fried chicken?
You've been secretly splurging again, haven't you?
Let me see, I'll get those off.
Here.
Who did this?
What an awful prank.
But, since there's a male and female here...
Could it be...
They're actually lovers?
Then, Ayumi will name them!
Let's see...
The boy will be called Hikoboshi!
And the girl will be Orihime!
That's great!
Now that you mention it, Tanabata is coming up.
Speaking of Tanabata...
All right, got it off.
Time for the quiz you've been waiting for!
No one's been waiting for that.
One year, on the night of Tanabata...
It rained heavily, making it impossible for
Orihime and Hikoboshi to meet with one another.
Troubled, those two thought hard...
And came up with a day called
"The Day to Spend with Your Lover".
Shortened, that would be "Lovers' Day",
and so they met on that day instead.
Now, which of the following is that day?
#1 : New Year's Day on January 1st.
#2 : Setsubun on Februari 2nd.
#3 : Momo-No-Sekku on March 3rd.
#4 : Tango-No-Sekku on May 5th.
I know!
It's number three, Momo-No-Sekku, right?
Because Odairi-sama and Ohina-sama
are lovers in the girl's doll set!
Nope.
It's number four, Tango-No-Sekku.
Lovers like to dance to the passionate music of tango!
I pick number one!
On New Year's Day, you can eat mochi dishes with your lover!
You guys came up with a lot of ideas.
Professor!
What's the answer?
It's number four, May 5th.
But my reasoning is...
May 5th, Boy's Day, is read "Kodomo no Hi."
If you separate the kanji for Kodomo no Hi...
You get "Ko-i-tomo-no-hi."
I see...
That's why you bothered to mention it was shortened
from "The Day to Spend with Your Lover," right?
"Lovers' Day," huh?
I hope that Hikoboshi-san and
Orihime-san can be together forever!
But still...
Do you really think it's suitable to name
two beetles Hikoboshi and Orihime?
Is that so?
I think it's perfectly suitable.
Orihime in English is Vega.
The tape on the female beetle forms the
letter V, which is the initial of Vega, isn't it?
True!
It is suitable, huh?
Well done, Haibara-san!
Say...
How do I get down?
Damn...
What's going on?
Stop!
Shit!
Hey, you!
Are you all right?
Call an ambulance!
Yes!
Tanabata... Kyo...
Hey, hang in there!
An ambulance is on the way!
Hey!
Hey, you!
Hang in there!
Hear me?
I'm making an exception by bringing you here.
You have to behave yourself and wait out here.
Dad, your necktie is crooked.
Mouri-san!
Thanks for coming so early in the morning.
Good morning, Ran-chan.
Conan-kun.
Good morning.
So this is a wide-scale serial murder case?
Right.
Our crime scene was at a turnpike in
Odawara City, the day before yesterday.
We also discovered a mahjong tile there.
We already have several cases that
include a mahjong tile discovery...
Namely in Tokyo, Kanagawa, Shizuoka, and Nagano.
That brings the total number of prefectures involved to five.
I see.
At any rate...
Let's go over the remaining details in the conference.
Yeah.
Please.
Isn't that Mouri-san!?
Long time no see!
Your voice is as loud as ever, Yokomizo...
Yokomizo Juugo
Kanagawa Prefecture Police
Yokomizo Sango
Shizuoka Prefecture Police
I'm Sango.
And this is my brother, Juugo.
I know that.
I've met him many times now.
Sango Juugo?
And, who's this lady with you?
Oh, pardon me.
This is an Inspector Ogino with the Saitama police.
Ogino Ayami
Saitama Prefecture Police
I'm Ogino Ayami.
I've heard much about you.
My, to think there's such a beautiful
inspector working with the Saitama police!
When I worked in Saitama, she was my junior in terms of seniority.
Why the Saitama police?
The victim who was killed in Tokyo
was from Tokorozawa, Saitama.
That's why I was called to this conference.
And you, Mouri-san!
Why are you here?
He was invited to serve as a special advisor
as per Superintendent Matsumoto's request.
To think we have to call upon a private detective for aid...
Such a shame.
Agreed.
You're...
Yamato Kansuke
Nagano Prefecture Police
Inspector Yamato Kansuke from Nagano police.
And you're...
That quack detective with Gunma police!
That's mean, Mouri-san.
Yamamura Misao
Gunma Prefecture Police
I do have a proper name, Yamamura Misao, you know?
Look!
But, didn't the incident happen in Nagano?
Why bring someone in from Gunma?
Because the crime scene lies on the border
of Nagano and Gunma, seeing as how...
The victim's body from the knees down were in Gunma Prefecture!
Right here!
I already know your name.
Inspector!?
You were promoted to inspector?
Oh, you've noticed?
Thanks to everyone's assistance. I've been
honorably promoted to the rank of inspector!
So, you're an inspector...
Is Gunma really gonna make it?
Say...
Did the boy with glasses not come?
Boy with glasses?
You mean Conan?
Right, right!
Edogawa Conan-kun!
When he's around, cases always seem to get solved somehow!
Come to think of it, that's happened to me as well.
It's happened to me also!
You guys too?
Actually, it's also happened to us.
And then...
You'd lose consciousness, and next thing
you knew, the case would be solved, right?
Oops!
Lose consciousness?
Really?
I don't think so.
Nah, nah, nah.
Just me?
Yeah, you were the only one...
The only officer I tranquilized.
How weird...
I'd like to commence the conference now.
Excuse us!
Mouri-san!
Hey, Mouri-san!
Who is he?
That guy who looks so diabolical.
Matsumoto Kiyonaga
Police Headquarters Superintendent
Idiot!
That's Superintendent Matsumoto Kiyonaga!
With that face?
If you keep that up, you're gonna get a beating!
For starters...
The common factor between the
previous five cases but not the sixth...
Was that all of the victims were
stabbed to death with a large knife.
And judging-from the puncture wounds...
The killer raised their right arm and then plunged the knife downward.
Also...
The victims in each of the five cases were
attacked with a stun gun, kidnapped...
And killed and left at the primary crime scenes.
Now, one question surfaces.
Why did our suspect, after disabling the victims...
Take all of the extra time to relocate them...
And only then proceed to kill?
Next, on the bodies in all six cases...
We found mahjong tiles with red circles on the front...
And alphabet letters with black vertical
lines through them on the back.
These appear to be messages left by our killer.
About the red circles...
On the 7-Pin tiles, only the top-right and bottom- left four bottom circles are left unmarked.
The alphabet letters look like two A's, E, H, Z...
Along with an upside-down L.
Also, among the accessories often carried by the six victims...
One of each item was taken away.
A pendant...
A small pouch...
A keepsake...
A motorcycle key holder, a make-up kit...
And then a doll.
Could they have merely been dropped while
they were being kidnapped by the suspect?
No, when it comes to only one of each item missing.
It's natural for us to assume they were taken by the suspect.
Our main question should be what
the messages are supposed to mean.
There is one other message.
Left by our sixth victim, Ryuuzaki-san
were the words: "Tanabata... Kyo."
That was his dying message.
Ryuuzaki-san was probably at the rest house in
Mount Daikan when his brake oil was leaked out...
Which must also be where he saw his eventual murderer.
Everyone...
Aren't you thinking a little too hard about this?
The mahjong tiles represent the game of mahjong itself.
The motive is simple...
It's a dispute gone bad over mahjong.
The 1-Pin and 7-Pin tiles left by the suspect...
Were meant to represent eight people playing Mahjong.
As for the 7-Pin tiles, only two circles remain unmarked in red.
One of them represents the suspect.
While the other...
Represents the final victim.
You mean, the crime is still ongoing?
Yes, I'm afraid so.
But...
If it were meant to represent eight people...
Wouldn't it be better to leave 8-Pin tiles?
There's actually one further meaning to the 1 and 7-Pin tiles.
The suspect was waiting for those
two tiles in order to claim victory.
And with those, the suspect could
have made an epic comeback!
I see!
Another player must've then won with a cheap combo!
And that's when the suspect went crazy, right?
Exactly!
I'm afraid all of his fellow players were
engaging in this narrow-minded style of play!
The suspect couldn't take this lightly.
And that's the motive for you.
Uhm...
What do the alphabet letters mean, then?
Why did the suspect take the extra time to
transport the victims elsewhere for his kills?
Also...
Regarding Ryuuzaki-san's dying message, what does it...
About that...
Well, as for that...
As for that...
We'll find out as we go.
Superintendent.
Let's ponder the significance of
those six locations to the suspect.
Should there be any significance, it could
very well lead us right to our killer.
As for the six victims...
They're-bound to be related to the suspect somehow.
Discovering the common factor among these six...
Will be the fastest way to get to the killer.
It's still possible that the connecting link lies in
a game of mahjong, as Mouri-kun suggested.
Also, the alphabet letters and black
lines on the back of the mahjong tiles...
Along with the dying message "Tanabata...
Kyo," are problems you need to unravel.
Listen up, everyone.
It's extremely likely our suspect will commit another crime.
We have to bet our pride as police and put a stop to this.
At times like this, we must put aside our
territorial imperatives and rivalries...
And promote the free exchange
of information with one another...
In order to capture our suspect as soon as possible.
I urge you to do your best in your investigations.
Yes, sir!
Bathroom, bathroom!
Can't hold it!
Looks like it's over, the meeting.
Looks like it.
Officer Matsumoto!
Long time no see.
Is Sayuri-sensei doing well?
Ah, you're Mouri's...
My daughter's doing just fine.
Well, Mouri...
I'm counting on you.
Your humble Mouri Kogoro...
Now vows to meet your expectations by doing his very best!
Thank you for your work!
Oh?
Detective Chiba, did you lose a little weight?
Oh, you noticed?
I'm on a diet now.
It's popular on that morning TV program, you know?
Speaking of weight...
Shiratori...
Haven't you gained some by comparison?
Let's not joke around, Mouri-san.
I go to the gym twice a week, you know.
How unusual.
Big bro's drinking black coffee?
Yeah.
The doctor put a limit on my sugar intake.
And speaking of which, didn't you hate sweet stuff?
Three murder cases in a row on my desk.
I can't function without glucose!
Uhm, Inspector Yokomizo...
Oh, no...
I mean the elder of you.
Right.
Say...
Is that the boy you've been talking about, Edogawa Conan-kun?
Yeah!
Because he's always listening to Mouri-san's deductions...
Sometimes, he'll say things that turn out to be surprising hints.
And, he often notices little interesting things.
Even things we pros may overlook.
Is that so?
Oh, crow~
Why do you cry~
'Cause in the mountain, the crow~
Hey!
Detective Yamamura, that song...
I see you haven't taken notice yet, but I'm actually...
Why were you just singing that song?
"Inspector" Yamamura.
"Why," you ask?
Well, I just heard it outside the bathroom.
It sounded like push-button dial tones.
When I left the bathroom...
I saw an officer with glasses dialing on his cellphone and...
Wait, Conan-kun...
Don't tell me...
Don't tell me, those guys...
There!
Hey, Conan-kun?
Something wrong?
Damn!
Going to the bathroom!
Conan-kun?
But there's a bathroom right behind me...
That was a Porsche 356A...
Gin's car!
Why?
Why were they in the conference?
Exactly what is their objective?
What now?
They infiltrated the police conference?
You're too loud!
I hope Haibara didn't hear that.
I think she's in the lab downstairs.
Most likely...
The disguised officer would've been Vermouth.
While waiting for the elevator to arrive...
She must have mailed her boss about the meeting.
I see.
And that's what Detective Yamamura overheard...
The push-button tones that sounded like Seven
Children as she input her boss's address.
But why...
My, my...
And here I was wondering what it
was you two were whispering about.
Haibara!
And?
Why did you think it was Vermouth?
The push-button tones alone won't...
Because Gin's Porsche was there too.
The risk would be too high for them to infiltrate the police without a disguise.
When it comes to disguises, Vermouth does it best.
At any rate...
It's now safe to assume that these cases
somehow concern the Black Organization.
And I'd like to investigate these cases as well.
Think you can lend me a hand?
I don't mind, but...
Even if I did tell you to stop...
You wouId never give up, would you?
But, you need to be on high alert.
I'm sure you're already aware, but...
If your identity were to be exposed to them...
Yeah.
I know.
Usui Pass • Lookout Platform
Odawara Atsugi Highway • Ooiso Parking Area
Nerima Ward, West Ooizumi
Ikoi Forest
Yokohama City, Isogo Ward
Horiwari Riverside
Shizuoka Prefecture, Izu City • Mount Sukumo
Old Hakone Turnpike • Hayakawa Toll Station
They didn't play mahjong!?
Right.
According to our investigation...
The six victims never even played mahjong.
Sorry to say, Mouri-kun's deduction was a miss.
Looks like we're stuck.
At a time like this, if only Kudo-kun were here...
By Kudo...
Do you mean the kid that often helped on your cases...
That high school detective, Kudo Shin'ichi-kun?
Well, somewhat...
Now that you mention it...
I hadn't heard anything about him until recently.
I bet he gave up playing detective.
Ah, no, it's not like that.
A while ago, at a Teitan High School festival...
He solved another case.
Takagi-kun!
Sorry, I slipped...
What's this about?
As per his request...
We've been withholding information regarding his involvement.
I see.
Such a humble person.
He's changed, for some reason.
In the past...
He was actually quite a showoff.
Taking two days off from school
didn't net you much progress, huh?
Could say that.
And what about the correlation between the
mahjong tiles and the alphabet letters?
Still haven't worked it out.
The same goes for "Tanabata... Kyo."
Amazing, Mitsuhiko-kun!
So good!
That's a rhinoceros beetle, right?
Yeah.
I'm pretty good at things like this.
But some people are so cruel...
Putting tape on beetles like that.
You mean Orihime-san, right?
I wonder who did it...
It really is...
Say, Genta-kun...
The thing you're making...
Is that a snake?
Can't you tell?
It's an eel!
E-E-L!
Again with the eel?
Genta-kun, you really love eels, don't you?
You even wrote it on your Tanabata wish card.
Come to think of it...
Tanabata is tomorrow.
Tanabata...
Kyo...
What's that supposed to mean?
That's a no-no.
You should've turned it off before the...
Excuse me.
It's me.
And?
What!?
Roger that!
Good news.
I was told that a man suspected to be our
serial killer might show up in Beika City.
What now?
Fukase Minoru, age 27.
His connection to Jinno Shuuhei-san,
the one who was killed on usui pass...
Was that he stabbed and wounded him once with a knife.
He's been wanted since a year ago.
I've had my subordinates monitoring his girlfriend.
I'm told she boarded a train from Nagano to Tokyo...
And just arrived at Beika Station.
Yoshii Risa, age 21.
She works at a snack bar in Nagano.
And?
What was this Fukase guy's motive for stabbing Jinno-san?
While they were lining up at the
Tropical Land amusement park...
Jinno-san warned him not to smoke
which caused him to fly into a rage.
Tropical Land...
Takagi-kun?
What came to mind?
Could it be...
Could it be that...
The victims were all waiting in the same line?
What?
Details, now.
Yes, sir.
There are two variations of the
mahjong tiles found near our victims.
Jinno-san's was 1-Pin, and the others had 7-Pins.
And, if we place them into the circles
as indicated by the red marks...
The victims may have lined up this way, right?
I see.
Then, that Fukase...
All right, Megure.
Get your men and go along with Inspector Yamato.
Damn...
Why'd you have to come along too?
For once, I wanted to ride on the capital highway!
Inspector Yamato, what about you?
Say, say!
All right.
Split up and begin the stakeout, just as we planned.
She's the suspect?
Or, could she be...
Minoru!
Fukase is in sight.
Remain at your posts.
Do not alert the suspect.
Hurry, hurry!
The game shop's on the 7th floor, right?
Yeah.
And let's get some ice cream before we go home.
I'm gonna get a vanilla and chocolate double scoop!
Inspector!
We have children around Fukase!
Remain calm.
Once the children are gone, we'll make our move.
Roger.
Which floor is this?
I think we're close.
Suspect has passed 5th floor.
We're almost to the 7th.
Now, secure him.
Roger.
Roger that!
Wait!
That idiot!
Fukase!
Don't move!
Police!
There's nowhere to run!
Shit!
Stop it, Fukase!
Stay away!
Any closer and I'll kill her!
Damn...
Don't move!
I'll stab her if you dare!
Stop it!
You can't get away with this!
Shut up!
Stay away!
You all, stay away!
I get it, just calm down!
What a waste of our time, punk.
He's unconscious.
But why?
Stay away...
Stay away from Minoru...
Stay away from Minoru.
Don't do something rash, Risa-san.
Please drop the knife.
This won't change anything.
Please, drop the knife.
I won't...
No!
Stay away from Minoru!
All right...
That's enough, Risa-san...
You don't want to commit another crime...
I'm sorry...
Are you all right, Inspector?
No need to worry...
My belly fat has some thickness to it.
I'm sorry...
I'm truly sorry.
I dropped my guard.
What?
I can't let another prefecture's officer
get hurt in my jurisdiction, now can I?
What is it?
That female hostage just then—she's...
Gone?
Is it all right?
To walk away like that.
Isn't there something you want from that guy?
Vermouth.
There's nothing that can be done.
And didn't you want me to leave like that?
Not to mention.
That man likely isn't the killer.
Yeah.
That's true.
Take it easy, lady!
I have a hurt right shoulder...
Your right shoulder's hurt?
Come to think of it, just then, you...
Stay away!
A man who can't even raise his right arm
to use a knife can't be our assailant.
Assuming he didn't hurt it after
committing the crime, that is.
Beyond that...
I'm impressed you managed to figure me out.
Your ankle.
Ankle?
There was a bulge near your right ankle.
You have a gun concealed there, no?
And...
Even after that guy wounded your face with a knife...
I don't see any blood seeping from it.
Jeez...
I guess I'll have to make a blood-seeping mask next time, huh?
I think you purposely made yourself his hostage...
And planned to utilize your gun to turn the tables
on him once you were out of the police's sight.
I doubt you would really put your gun to use, anyway.
And I didn't expect to receive a compliment from you.
Why is your organization following this serial murder case?
My, how straightforward of you.
Spit it out.
NOC.
NOC?
Non-official cover...
A member of yours working undercover
as a civilian became one of the victims?
Right.
That NOC, perhaps seeking some sort of insurance...
Carried a memory card containing our entire NOC list.
The Organization had planned to get rid of them shortly.
However...
That person was killed by someone else first.
Correct.
And now, their killer...
Has made off with the memory card.
Most likely unknowingly.
I see.
It would be bad for you should the police
catch the killer and look into that database.
Wait, the fact that you're here means
the NOC was at the conference...
No, that's not it...
You had one of your partners disguise as an officer.
That's why you infiltrated the conference, was it not?
You wanted to ensure that your
partner's disguise was still airtight!
And if it weren't, you would've
continued your own infiltration.
Who is it!?
Who are they disguised as!?
Is the real officer safe!?
Our conversation has come to an end.
It's on you to solve the rest.
Their codename is... Irish.
Irish...
Right.
Irish whiskey is nicely distilled, with a mild taste.
Excuse me, security guard?
This kid looks lost.
He's lost?
No...
Good luck.
I wish you the best.
Damn!
It's me, Megure.
Superintendent?
We just got a call from a painter named Shindou Sumire
saying she has a clue that may lead to our suspect.
The address is in Hachioji City.
Yes.
Yes, sir.
Understood.
Sato! Takagi!
Head to Hachioji now!
Yes, sir!
Got it.
Shindou Sumire, you say?
Not good, Partner.
If we head this way...
Even if we are ahead of the cops, we'll still
get caught before we finish our target off.
We won't be running into the cops.
It's me.
Great.
We made it safely.
I'll take right.
OK.
I'll aim for the left.
Cute boy.
Nice lady.
What the...
Stay calm!
Slowly pull over!
Right!
We got a flat tire.
And another here.
Takagi-kun, contact Shiratori-kun.
Got it.
Shit...
Somebody got here first.
No use staying, then.
Move out.
What?
No one's there?
And it doesn't look like she just went out for a while?
Right.
The room has been trashed.
It appears the suspect abducted Shindou-san and fled.
Requesting backup ASAP.
Please call for the forensics team.
Roger.
Thanks.
Takagi-kun...
What is it?
Sato-san?
Disguised as an officer?
Yeah.
Their codename is Irish.
Heard it before?
No...
Never.
I see.
If only I had something on Irish...
I could deduce their disguise.
You should stop.
If it's true that this "Irish" has disguised as an officer...
They would've been alerted to your running
after Vermouth following the conference.
Yeah...
But...
Don't you get it!?
The more cases you solve...
The more likely it is that they'll see you're Kudo Shin'ichi!
Ai-kun.
I know what you're worried about.
But...
This isn't something I can leave unsolved.
This now concerns the life of the officer Irish has disguised as.
At any rate...
There's no doubt that Irish already
infiltrated that police conference.
I need to do anything to expose their identity...
Catch the culprit before them...
And get the memory card their NOC was carrying.
That one, single card...
May just be the trump card that crushes them.
But can you trust it?
What Vermouth said.
She's already aware that Haibara is Sherry.
She may even know my identity as well.
But, for whatever reason, she's kept
it quiet from the Organization.
I have no choice but to trust her for now.
In contrast, she'd call you out to
The shrine like she's leery of you.
What she's leery of is Irish.
Let's not meet except for at school until everything dies down.
Only as a precaution, though.
What is it, Gin?
Where have you been for the past two hours?
Seems you've been places where
you had to power off your cell.
Does that bother you?
No matter.
Just do the job you've been assigned.
Speaking of which...
The one who used the drug to dispose of that
high school detective was you, wasn't it?
What's this about?
About Kudo Shin'ichi.
Have you forgotten?
What happened?
Sorry...
I broke Conan-kun's bowl.
It's all right; it's just rare, isn't it?
For Ran-neechan to break things.
Really...
What was I doing?
Ayase City
Kouryou Sports Park
No doubt about it.
Our victim's Shindou Sumire.
Yeah, got it.
3:00, right?
See you then.
Was that from Detective Takagi?
Yeah.
Another conference at 3:00.
Has there been any progress?
That Shindou Sumire's body was found.
Where?
He said it was in Kanagawa Prefecture's Ayase City.
Was there a 7-Pin mahjong tile there?
Yeah.
The red mark this time is on the
top-right of the four bottom circles.
But instead of a letter on the back, there's a triangle.
Hey!
Get to school!
Yes!
It's true...
Really strange, huh?
Morning.
Conan-kun!
It's bad!
Your dolphin's fin is missing!
Fin?
It's true.
These are...
Leather glove impressions.
A mysterious case has occurred!
Don't exaggerate.
I bet someone just knocked it off by
accident while cleaning the room.
But we searched everywhere and couldn't find it!
It's fine.
I'll just make another and put it on.
Don't tell me...
That fin...
Not that.
Don't worry.
There's no doubt.
It was them.
Just looking gives me the chills...
We're lucky not to have gotten into an accident.
Don't you think it's strange?
It's so unlikely that two tires would burst at the same time.
Then, someone could've scattered nails around, right?
A sniper.
Our tires must have been sniped by someone...
From this bridge.
I remember a car being here.
No way!
Say Takagi-kun...
Call it a wild hunch, but...
In this case...
Even outside of our culprit...
There may be people lurking around we aren't aware of.
People we aren't aware of?
At Shindou-san's studio...
Her paint tube was stepped on twice.
The first time, it caused paint to squirt out.
Then, after the paint had dried, someone stepped on it again.
That could mean...
After the culprit abducted Shindou-san...
Yet another person came inside.
Is that so?
Couldn't they have just left after the paint had dried?
The culprit, I mean.
One more.
I feel uneasy about the woman who
disappeared at the mall in Beika City.
Could she have been a partner of those people...
Who purposely got taken hostage?
What for?
Sato-san, you're thinking too much.
You're right.
Maybe I am.
But...
If it were true...
Within our police force...
Must be one of their spies!
And...
The spy would be among the conference attendees.
The dark knight helmet?
It was sabotaged.
People in the drama club were panicking.
The bowl...
I broke Conan-kun's bowl last night.
And now, the dark knight helmet Shin'ichi wore that time...
I have a bad feeling about this.
Aren't you thinking too much?
That brat and Shin'ichi-kun aren't related in any way.
That may be, but...
I need to tell him about it.
The dark knight helmet was...
Oh no...
On that helmet...
Were my fingerprints.
Damn...
If both the dolphin fin and the helmet was their doing...
What now?
If I don't make a move soon...
People like Ran and Uncle will be in danger.
The memory card!
If I could get that memory card...
I would have the upper hand.
I have to hurry and get the culprit.
I bet that's from Shin'ichi-kun.
He says, "I'm involved in a really nasty
case right now, so don't call or text me."
What is this "nasty case"?
At least tell us about it, Shin'ichi...
That should do it.
What gets me is the message "Tanabata... Kyo."
What does that...
Tanabata... Kyo...
Kyoto?
Oh, Kudo!
It's been a while.
What is it you wanna ask me about?
I see!
Who are you talking to?!
Don't scare me like that, moron!
Sorry, sorry.
Jezz...
Thought I was gonna die there.
So, you're talking to someone who
would make you jump like that!
Stupid.
It's just Kudo, Kudo.
Regarding that serial murder case...
He asked me whether "Tanabata Kyoto" rings a bell or not.
Sorry about that, Kudo.
That stupid Kazuha just butted in agajn.
About "Tanabata Kyoto"...
Doesn't he mean the Mitarashi Festival?
The one held in Kitano Tenman Temple.
Also, the Tanabata Festival in Jishu Shrine is famous too!
I know!
Why don't we go there tonight?
If you wanna go, do it alone.
You hear that, Kudo?
Yeah...
But I can't see the connection.
Guess not.
Other things that come to mind are...
Hey, let's go.
There's no need to stay in a hotel since it's just
in Kyoto, and we can be back on the same day!
Idiot.
I wouldn't stay in a hotel even if you said so.
There was a fire there two years ago, did you forget?
Stingy.
Hey, Hattori...
What's this fire about?
There was a huge fire in Kyoto the year before last.
Come to think of it, it was on the night of Tanabata.
Tell me more.
I remember the hotel's name was Vega...
Two guests died as a result.
Hattori...
Do a thorough investigation of that fire for me.
Immediately!
Got it!
Wait, Heiji!
What are you doing?
Class is starting soon.
Inform the teacher for me.
Just say that Hattori-kun went to meet
Orihime-san-Vega-because its Tanabata.
Wait!
Who's this Orihime-san!?
Fire...
Do the red marks and letters on the tiles represent a fire?
The cause was a lit cigarette that
belonged to a guest on the fifth floor.
The emergency staircase was unusable.
Another guest on the sixth floor died from smoke inhalation.
Honjou Nanako...
From Mitaka City, Jindai Ward, huh?
Mizutani-san!
Mizutani-san?
If you're looking for Mizutani-kun, he's out.
Do you know where he went?
So, you're Detective Mouri's assistant?
My name is Sawamura Shun.
I'm a law student at Jounan University.
Nice to meet you.
Thank you.
Ah, but, please don't tell anyone about this.
It's a confidential investigation.
That's why he sent a kid like you...
So, Mizutani Kousuke-san and Honjou Nanako-san were...
Lovers.
They ran away from Chiba and came here because
their parents disapproved of their relationship.
Ran away...
On the day of Tanabata two years ago...
Those two took a trip to Kyoto
and stayed at that business hotel.
But then, he went to visit a friend in the city by himself.
In the meantime, the hotel caught fire.
"If only I hadn't gone out by myself...
"Nana wouldn't have died."
He began crying, after saying that.
What does Mizutani-san do for work?
He was working a part-time job, but...
Once his girlfriend died, he stopped working.
It also looks like he hasn't been home for a while.
Where might Mizutani-san be now?
Who knows...
He may be in Chiba, I think.
Today's the second anniversary of her death.
Then, at a temple?
Maybe.
I think you'll know if you ask her big brother.
One second.
Prior to her death...
Her brother came to my place several times.
He said that, if his sister were ever
in any trouble, to contact him...
Here we are!
Look.
That's her brother's card.
And this is Mizutani-kun.
Can I take note of this number?
Sure.
And, please give me your cellphone number too, Sawamura-san.
All right.
Hello, Hattori?
Oh, Kudo!
This is big, very big!
Crazy big!
The names of the seven victims you sent...
Match the names of the guests
on the sixth floor during the fire.
There were two more guests on'the sixth floor.
Honjou Nanako-san and Mizutani Kousuke-san.
What, you knew that already?
Then, how about this?
That Mizutani guy...
He came here a year ago asking about the same thing I am.
It looks like there's no doubt this case has
everything to do with the fire two years ago.
But what does it all mean, then?
If Mizutani's the culprit, what would his motive be?
Wasn't Honjou-san's death an accident?
Hattori...
In that hotel...
How many elevators are there?
Elevators?
I think there's only one.
What's the capacity?
One sec!
It says the elevator's capacity is limited to seven people.
What's this about, Kudo?
I'll get out, I'll get out!
I see...
I get it, Kudo.
Yeah.
Most likely, on the night of the fire...
Honjou Nanako-san was...
Pushed out of the elevator after boarding it.
Because the eighth person wanted to get in...
She was forced out.
The eighth person would be...
The one with the 1-pin tile, Jinno-san.
The other six would have been standing in the elevator
on the positions suggested by the 7-pin's red circles.
And the last circle would represent Nanako-san's position.
I'm afraid so.
Mahjong tiles do have the shape of an elevator...
And the black lines drawn on the back
of the tiles represent elevator doors.
No doubt about that.
When Jinno-san got on, the buzzer sounded.
That's why he wanted someone out.
The scapegoat turned out to be Nanako-san!
The other six either pretended not to notice or...
Feared that they, themselves, would be forced
out, and decided to cooperate with Jinno-san.
After being unable to ride the elevator, Nanako-san...
Died after being unable to escape.
What's wrong?
There a problem with my deduction?
No...
It's just that I still don't understand
what the letters on the tiles mean.
Yeah.
It is strange that there was a triangle
instead of a letter on the seventh tile.
Well, if the last circle really does represent Nanako-san...
There shouldn't be any more murders.
I hope so.
At any rate...
I'll try to locate Mizutani-san.
Thank you, Hattori.
For real.
Kudo...
Tell you what!
I found an awesome restaurant
that serves Okonomiyaki dishes.
We'll pay it a visit the next time you come over.
You have to come.
I'll be waiting.
Yeah, I know.
Later.
Kudo...
You have to.
What?
On July 7th two years ago?
All victims were in Kyoto on that day?
Yeah.
We've confirmed it through our investigations.
That means...
The "Tanabata... Kyo our witness heard...
Appears to really be "Tanabata Kyoto."
As for that day...
I have people looking into exactly
what happened in Kyoto then.
The question is...
What do these messages the culprit has left
us on the mahjong tiles actually mean?
Only the bottom-left circle hasn't been marked red...
Which means it's probable there will be another murder.
And...
It looks like it's no coincidence that today is July 7th as well.
Then...
Then, the last person will die today?
Where and who?
Could it be that...
Someone here...
I've got it!
The seven locations represent the shape of a certain animal!
A certain animal?
Here, look.
If we connect the lines between all of the crime scenes...
Do you get it now?
This long line is the neck.
And here's the chest.
The front leg.
The back.
And the hind leg.
So, instead of Nessie from Loch Ness...
It's Assie!
From Lake Ashino!
Quack, quack!
Assie?
Is there even such a thing?
Nah, never heard of it.
I don't get it at all.
Well then...
How about this?
If you say so...
I can see it!
It's Assie!
But, why Assie?
It could be Lake Yamanaka's Yassie...
Pay attention to the shape of the lake.
Lake Yamanaka is shaped like a whale.
What about Lake Ashino?
I get it, Mouri-san!
The next crime scene will be at Assie's nose!
Amateur, Inspector Yokomizo!
They wanted us to think that...
But, in fact, it's really here!
I see!
It's the eye!
It's in Gunma Prefecture's Annaka City!
I know Annaka City well!
I'll head over there too!
Lead us!
Yes!
I'll go too!
What're you...
Stop it.
But with only the two of them against a vicious killer...
Two's enough.
That was fun!
Yep.
Would've been nice if Conan-kun had come.
Say, don't you think Conan's been weird lately?
He went home alone again today.
I bet his cold hasn't gone away yet.
Remember, he even took two days off from school?
It's here!
It's a rhinoceros beetle!
This bus must have come from Beika Forest.
I see!
The beetle flew onto that man's
shoulder while in the forest.
And got on with him!
Convenience store tape!
Again?
Looks like they're playing pranks on other beetles too.
How sad.
No use.
The tape's on there really tight.
Let's ask the professor to peel it off again.
And to treat us to something!
Kazuki-san...
There was only one anonymous bouquet this time.
Looks that way.
Hello.
You're Detective-Mouri's assistant?
Is that true?
And, I'm searching for Mizutani-san
as part of an investigation, but...
It seems he didn't come to
the memorial service, huh?
Yeah.
He came here at early dawn...
And hurriedly left a bouquet before leaving.
Just left a bouquet?
Yeah.
My parents still cannot forgive him
for running away with my sister.
That's why...
Then...
The one she said was left anonymously...
Was that Mizutani-san?
She mentioned it was the "only" one today...
Which means there were other anonymous ones before, right?
Yeah, other than his.
When?
And do you know from where?
I do.
Let's see...
Four on the day of the funeral two years ago...
From Matsumoto City, Kawasaki...
Numazu, and Kamakura.
Three on the memorial service day last year...
That time from Tokorozawa, Odawara, and Hachioji.
All seven were from where the victims lived...
Actually, when I met Kousuke-kun this morning...
He said something strange.
Something strange?
"There were eight people I could not forgive."
"Now, only one remains."
This was doneby the same culprit.
The way they taped the V-shape is the same.
I see!
This could be someone's message.
Message?
Now, do you know what the message is?
The answer is "Help," an S.O.S.
Why?
This bug is known as a "beetle" in English.
My Volkswagen has a similar shape
so it's also known as a Beetle.
Also...
After combining the word "beetle" with
the musical term "beat," you get...
The name of the legendary band, The Beatles!
"Beatles," you say?
Their first album was titled, "Please Please Me."
The second, "With the Beatles."
The third, "A Hard Day's Night."
And the fifth, is "Help!"
How's that?
See now?
What is "The Beatles"?
Sounds like a foreign band.
You guys don't know The Beatles?
Not at all.
I remember my sister listening to them occasionally.
She loved the oldies.
"The oldies"?
I wish he had treated us to food instead of quizzes.
"Help!" means someone is asking for our assistance, right?
I see.
I finally understand.
The meaning of "Tanabata Kyoto."
All seven victims checked in?
The victim of the fire was a young girl named Honjou Nanako.
And, her boyfriend by the name of Mizutani Kousuke...
Came here to look into this case a year ago.
Also...
Two hours ago...
That Hattori Heiji-kun came and inquired about the same thing.
Yeah, that's right.
I have a bit of interest in the case.
Right, right, Inspector.
I'll share something juicy with you.
The mahjong tiles represent an elevator.
Elevator?
The number of guests staying on the
hotel's sixth floor amounted to nine.
Not counting the deceased
Nanako-san and Mizutani himself...
All other seven were killed.
Just who is this final person?
Oh, I know.
This is chouzu, isn't it?
Right, you know a lot!
But I don't know what to do with this dipper.
Is that so?
I'll teach you then.
All right.
What?
The location of the stars?
Yeah.
The seven crime scenes...
Represent locations relative to Polaris
and the six stars in the Big Dipper.
Hold on.
It's true.
They're not just similar.
They align perfectly with the actual photo of the stars.
What a perfectionist, our killer.
Just the same...
The mahjong tiles and letters...
All represent Polaris and the Big Dipper.
The 1-Pin and 7-Pins all indicate the
shape of Polaris and the Big Dipper.
And the letters...
Polaris
Dubhe
Merak
Phecda
Megrez
Alioth
Mizar
Alkaid
Really represent stars from
the Ursa constellations...
As Greek letters.
So, Haibara?
The location of the remaining Big Dipper star...
Merak, right?
Right away.
Thanks.
There.
Shiba Park, in Minato Ward.
The person who sent the "Help!" message
should be near that oak tree we visited before.
We need to rescue them!
Yeah!
Detective Boys...
Commence!
If this is about Mizutani-kun and Nanako-san...
A boy with glasses came and asked about
the same thing a couple of hours ago.
Boy with glasses?
Yeah.
He said he was Detective Mouri's assistant.
And these were Mizutani-san's words, correct?
"There were eight people I could not forgive."
Now, only one remains.
Yeah.
What happened?
Did Mizutani-kun...
No, just asking.
What?
You mean our suspect plans to kill another?
Yes, I'm afraid so.
Also, Conan-kun came here earlier as well.
Conan-kun did?
Nah.
How could I ask him to do something like that?
That brat.
Then, who else could it be?
Could it be Kudo-kun?
Superintendent...
Would that not mean Mizutani Kousuke is the culprit?
Yeah.
I think that assumption is valid.
But who is this last person?
Where will the next crime scene be?
Nana...
Kousuke!
Hey, can I try again?
I'm so excited.
This is my first trip with Kousuke!
Kousuke!
Nana! Nana!
Let me go!
Nana's in there!
Nana!
Nana...
Understood.
I'll go look for him as well.
Thanks.
Even Tsuburaya-kun hasn't gone home?
Yeah.
It's already 7:00; where could those three be?
I tried to get them on their Detective
Badges, but they aren't answering.
Say, Professor, could those three have...
Yes?
Sawamura-san?
Mizutani-kun and Nanako-san's hobby?
Could it have been star-gazing?
That's right.
He said he chose to live here because
of its proximity to the observatory.
As I thought.
Of all the stars...
They loved Polaris and the Big Dipper the most.
The beautiful shape of the Big Dipper...
And Polaris shining right above the north pole...
I think they strengthened their love by gazing at those stars.
Well, a kid like you...
You wouldn't understand.
Thanks.
The place here that's nearest the stars would be...
Good evening!
I'm currently at Tohto Tower, where
the Tanabata Fair is being held.
Unfortunately, even though it's cloudy,
tonight is the last night of the fair.
Visitors wearing beautiful
yukatas are gathering all around.
Next is our weather forecast for tonight and tomorrow.
Wearing a yukata on a date, huh?
There is a high chance of rain in the
Tokyo area around 10:00 tonight.
Thunderstorms are expected elsewhere.
Miss!
What is it, boy?
Can you watch this for me?
I can, but...
Are you alone?
When I went to the bathroom...
My daddy and brother left without me.
Meanies, aren't they?
Hitomi-chan, your yukata's beautiful!
Moeri-chan, yours is cute!
Hey, let's take a picture of us four!
Take a lot, a lot!
All right, cheese!
Cheese!
Have we been here before?
Did we take the wrong path?
Let's go home.
No way!
We must find this person ourselves!
That's right.
Don't you want to solve a case without Conan-kun for once?
I do!
But we can't seem to find that oak tree...
Ah, I know!
Let's ask this beetle to show us the way.
Beetles usually fly towards the tree with the same sap.
That way!
Do we have to run?
Through our investigation, we
have identified the suspect...
And have determined that it's highly
probable he will commit another murder.
However...
We still do not know the whereabouts of the
suspect nor the location of his next crime.
Any ideas, anyone?
Damn...
While we wait...
It's possible someone's out there being killed.
We did it!
It's the oak tree!
Huh?
There's another one.
Could it be taped up too?
Just a little more...
It's taped, just like we expected.
It must be there.
Someone needing our help must be in there.
Probably.
But, still...
It's a little creepy.
I feel like something's coming.
Stop talking like that.
As expected at a place like this, the stars are pretty!
That one's Polaris...
And those form the Big Dipper.
Those shapes...
Where have I seen them...
What!?
Polaris and the Big Dipper!?
Then, you're saying the crime scenes
represent Polaris and the Big Dipper?
There's no mistaking it, Inspector!
You're the detective from earlier.
Yeah.
So, Mizutani-san and Honjou-san's hobby was star-gazing?
Thanks.
Superintendent!
The final star from the Big Dipper
matches the location of Shiba Park.
Good work.
Megure, secure an emergency warrant for
Mizutani Kousuke and await further orders here.
The rest of you, head over to Shiba Park.
Hurry!
Yes, sir!
What the...
Don't scare us like that!
What do you mean by that?
You shouldn't be hanging around here at this hour.
We're not hanging around!
We're here to help!
To help the person who used the
beetles to send those S.O.S. messages!
Regardless, go home.
Your parents are worried about...
Not so fast.
They can go home after we answer that message.
Thank you very much.
I'll take it.
Ah, sorry.
If you would.
Hello, this is Takagi's cell.
Agasa-san.
We're a little occupied here.
My apoIogies for disturbing you.
Can I tell you something?
This may sound strange, but...
The Beatles?
Don't tell me...
Understood.
I'll be right there.
Professor, hide with the kids in a safe place for now.
Takagi-kun...
Make a detour to Beika Forest.
But...
Don't worry.
I'll take full responsibility.
Understood.
But, allow me take that responsibility.
Hey, which way?
I dunno!
It's to the left.
Got it.
Conan-kun was on TV?
Yeah.
I saw him enter Tohto Tower by himself.
It was around 8:00, I think.
I see...
Well, no need to worry―he'll come home soon anyway
But...
His cell phone's been turned off...
It's no use, Superintendent.
Takagi and Sato aren't answering.
Leave them be, then.
All right.
Mizutani should be hiding somewhere around here.
Split up, and arrest him when you find him.
Yes, sir!
It's so cloudy that you can't see them.
The stars you and Nanako-san loved most...
Polaris and the Big Dipper.
Boy...
About this visitor...
You saw him?
Yes.
He's visited the tower after-hours often, so I took notice.
Around 7:00, he went up to the viewing platform alone.
So you're the assistant of that Detective Mouri.
But it's too bad, huh?
To have come so close to the sky
and not be able to see the stars.
I can see them.
Whenever, wherever...
Only those stars...
What?
The viewing platform?
Yes, sir!
This lady seems to have witnessed him.
Did you see him leave?
No, I didn't.
All right.
There's no doubt that our suspect
is still on the platform above.
He may be planning to call someone
up there to commit another crime.
We are to ambush and arrest
him while protecting the victim.
The suspect may be armed.
Stay alert and commence.
Please keep the interior lightings as it is.
Roger.
Go!
Yes, sir!
Hey, Mizutani-san.
After drinking that wine...
You're planning to commit suicide, right?
"There are eight people I cannot forgive."
"Now, only one remains."
The one that still remains...
Mizutani-san...
It's you, isn't it?
The shock and the anger you felt when you
learned the details of Nanako-san's death...
I think I understand.
That's why you went to the hotel in Kyoto
and investigated those seven people, right?
Just as you said...
On that fateful day, two years ago...
If I hadn't gone to meet my friend...
Nana wouldn't have died.
When I think of that...
I can't forgive myself.
But you mustn't commit suicide!
That just means you're murdering your―
I know that.
I know that, but...
I can no longer bear to live in a world without Nana...
Not to mention...
I'll get a death sentence anyway.
It won't be a death sentence.
After all, Mizutani-san...
You didn't kill anyone.
Wasn't there someone who asked you, with
your kind heart, to take guilt on yourself...
And commit suicide in exchange for
them killing those seven people?
I don't object to your desire to take
responsibility for Nanako-san's death.
But, listen...
The one that other person really despises and wishes to kill...
Is actually you, Mizutani-san.
And it's because...
You were the one...
Who took away his beloved sister.
Isn't that right...
Nanako-san's elder brother...
Honjou Kazuki-san?
Brother!
Why are you here?
Bastard, you have no right to address me that way!
Brat...
How did you know I did it?
It made no sense, no matter how I looked at it.
If Mizutani-san had been the culprit...
The logic behind choosing the positions of
Polaris and the Big Dipper as the crime scenes...
Wouldn't have made sense.
Because...
That would've defiled his precious stars, no?
As such, I thought this may have been...
A plan someone else had come up with, in order to
make the star-loving Mizutani-san their scapegoat.
When I realized that, everything came together.
Moreover...
The culprit, who accurately adapted the positions
of Polaris and the Big Dipper to the map...
And used them for crime scenes,
was clearly a perfectionist.
But, the sign oh Mizutani-san's apartment door...
Was slightly tilted...
And the handwriting wasn't very tidy either.
By comparison...
The phone number written on your name card...
Was in very neat handwriting.
There was even a faint pencil line,
to ensure the writing was straight.
And inside your organizer...
Even the names and addresses of those
that sent flowers were clearly recorded.
All of this undeniably showcases your
perfectionist personality, doesn't it?
You...
Just who are you, really?
Edogawa Conan.
A detective.
Thanks for coming.
Agasa-san...
Where are the other kids?
Their parents took them home.
I'll show you the way.
Please do.
Ai-kun, go wait in the car.
The one who told Mizutani-san the
whole story of how Nanako-san died...
It was you, wasn't it?
Yeah.
That day...
When I heard from this guy that Shindou Sumire, the
artist, was staying in the same hotel on the same floor...
I went to her personal art exhibition to ask some questions.
At that time, I happened to overhear Sumire and Ryuuzaki talking.
And you passed on the information to Mizutani-san...
While adding in your own lies.
On the first anniversary of Nanako-san's death...
Everyone who had been on the 6th floor brought flowers.
If it was because they felt guilty, only
one or two might have come, but...
All seven came.
The only possible reason for that was
they wanted to express their gratitude.
They wanted to say, "Thank you," for
allowing them to board the elevator.
Then, could it be...
Nanako wasn't chased out...
But instead voluntarily...
Yeah, that's right.
Nanako was that kind of a girl.
But even still!
That doesn't change the fact that it was because
of them boarding that elevator that she died!
Mizutani-san...
Indeed, Nanako-san did die in place of those seven people.
However...
Even though you're also a substitute...
By taking Honjou-san's place and
killing yourself to atone for his sins...
There's a world of difference there!
And that difference...
Is as great as that of a star in the sky
and a stone rolling on the ground.
Nana...
I quit.
What?
I'm sorry.
I won't be committing suicide.
This boy's words brought me to my senses.
Mizutani!
And, I'm sure that Nana in heaven...
Wouldn't want me to commit suicide either.
I'm returning this to you.
I have no need for it now.
Please turn yourself in, Brother.
Damn!
Honjou-san.
Those are the items you took from the seven victims, right?
You handed these to him and assured
him that, if he died with these on him...
He would be presumed the murderer, right?
It's a good thing I came.
When I heard that Detective Mouri was investigating...
I rushed here fearing I would be exposed.
I lied to you because...
I was hoping you would be the one taking revenge on them.
But you didn't have the courage to do so.
That's why I had to do it myself!
That isn't courage!
It's merely self-satisfaction!
Shut up!
Since Detective Mouri isn't here, that must mean you came alone!
Don't belittle me!
Did I make it in time?
I'm Matsumoto from the Police Headquarters.
Police Headquarters?
Are you injured?
Come with me to the station.
Damn it!
Shit!
Like I'd be caught by the likes of you!
As I thought, you...
You're Irish, aren't you?
Police!
Don't move!
As expected!
Superintendent!
Superintendent!?
Please be strong!
Superintendent!
What're you doing here?
The other Superintendent Matsumoto is a fake!
He's been replaced!
The superintendent was from The Beatles generation.
But I never thought it'd really be him...
Hurry and contact Inspector Megure!
Roger!
It's me.
What is it?
We've been exposed.
They know he's a fake.
Got it.
Vermouth...
He really was here?
Yeah.
He left his skateboard in my care...
But since he never retrieved it, I thought it was strange.
Surely he isn't still in there!
That can't be.
It would be disastrous if he were.
He could run into that murderer!
Murderer!?
The police are conducting a search inside right now.
Sonoko, wait here!
Wait, Ran!
Hey, you! Wait!
What have you done with Superintendent Matsumoto?
Don't tell me...
Nah, he's still alive.
I need him to be my scapegoat, you know.
I'm assuming that's the memory card
containing the Organization's NOC list?
Yeah.
Might be.
When did you find out I was a fake?
I had a general idea.
If Vermouth, the master of disguise...
Had sent someone else to infiltrate in her stead...
That could have been made impossible
due to the difference in body stature.
And when I thought along those lines...
You were the first to come to mind.
I see.
As expected...
Of Kudo Shin'ichi.
Before matching the fingerprints, I was skeptical too.
Have you already reported this to your boss?
No, not yet.
I haven't told anyone.
Not even Gin?
Yeah.
About Kudo Shin'ichi.
Have you forgotten?
I've done away with a lot of people.
How could I possibly remember them all?
What is it about this one?
No.
It's nothing.
Regardless, concentrate on your assignment.
Why?
There was a time when...
He shot a fellow member of the
Organization that made a mistake.
He left the body to burn there at Haido City Hotel...
Where it eventually turned to ashes.
That member was someone I respected like a father.
Haido City Hotel...
Pisco!?
You've investigated us thoroughly, haven't you?
To have failed in killing Kudo Shin'ichi...
And then failing to see through to your true identity...
He's made a huge oversight.
I'll be taking you to meet that person...
To have you act as a witness in order to overthrow
that conceited and cold-blooded bastard.
Only this man is sure of my identity as of now...
As long as I can defeat him...
But, with the tranquilizer out of action...
There's only...
Have no fear.
I won't kill you.
I'm just going to knock you unconscious.
Unless I bring you back alive...
I should think you being Kudo
Shin'ichi is something that person...
Would find hard to believe.
This is...
Detective Chiba?
Detective Chiba!
Are you all right?
It seems he's just lost consciousness...
I think the same goes for the rest of them, too...
Conan-kun!
Hey, you!
You, wait up!
Conan-kun!
What happened?
Ran... neechan...
Are you all right?
Are the two of you all right?
Detective Matsumoto!
It's serious!
The other detectives downstairs were...
Attacked by the culprit?
What is it?
No good...
Run...
What?
What happened?
Run...
He's...
You...
You aren't Superintendent Matsumoto, are you?
Don't...
It's all right.
I can't avoid a bullet from a rifle like Kyougoku-san, but...
A pistol...
Say, Ran...
Did you know?
The speed of a rifle bullet is about 1000 meters per second.
Compared to that...
The speed of a pistol's bullet is only a third of that...
Which puts them at roughly 350 meters a second.
What's so funny?
Don't tell me that you think you can dodge a bullet?
That's exactly it.
Interesting.
Let's give it a try.
Amazing...
I have to hand it to you, little lady.
I had forgotten...
That you're a karate expert.
Ran!
You're really wasting my energy here.
Stay down!
Leave the rest to me.
Just stay there!
Damn...
Allow me to enjoy this even more!
Shit!
What a pity.
You were so close there.
What's wrong?
Already out of ideas?
Yeah, that's the way.
Let's end this game of cat-and-mouse, shall we?
How the tables have turned.
Shit...
Now...
Hand over the memory card!
They're here, huh?
"How the tables have turned," was it?
It's me.
How is it?
Have you secured the memory card?
Yeah.
I can't really see you.
Hold it out further.
That's right.
A little more.
Now!
Bingo!
I wanted to shoot.
Partner...
Look below.
That's...
He has no means of escape.
Thanks for your service, Irish.
There's someone else down there!
Hey, pull yourself together!
Wake up, come on!
It's all right!
It didn't hit your vital points!
Once we take care of them...
I'll hurry and get you medical treatment!
I see now...
No wonder Vermouth thought so highly of you...
Don't talk.
After you've recovered...
I'll make you reveal your boss's true identity, so be prepared!
Irish!
Kudo Shin'ichi...
Keep... coming after us...
Irish!
They used Irish as a shield!
It'll be troublesome if we have to land.
Use that!
Roger!
Damn it!
This is bad...
Ran's still downstairs!
There we go.
Continue!
Partner...
What should we do?
Chianti...
Smoke them out.
OK.
Damn it...
What now!?
Tear gas!
There we are.
Force them to the top!
The mouse has been cornered.
Go up.
Attack from above!
There'll be nowhere to hide!
Roger!
Damn...
What do I do...
If this goes on, I'll be a sitting duck!
Damn it!
What do I do?
Now...
Let's see your face.
They just jumped!
Accepting their fate of no escape, huh?
Go!
We've been hit!
Great!
Now what!?
I can't control it anymore!
We have no choice!
Retreat!
Roger!
Who...
Who the hell was that?
As expected of the Silver Bullet.
He has his ways.
Actually, about that...
There was a huge bang and I fainted.
Thank goodness no one was hurt.
I'm sorry!
Well then, Ran-chan.
I'll inquire as to the details another day.
Thanks in advance.
Sure.
I'll arrange for a car to send you home now.
Please wait a while.
Thank you very much.
Are you really all right?
Oh yeah, I'll get you something to drink.
You don't have to...
Don't mention it.
Thanks.
Ran-neechan...
Shin'ichi-niichan said that the case has been solved.
Come to think of it, Shin'ichi...
About that, he said he had another case...
He left abruptly again?
And...
I'm sure he said something like
"Don't tell anyone I was involved."
Oh, right!
He also said it was all right for you to call now...
"All right to call?"
Ah, no...
He might have said, "Please call..."
Well, just hearing his voice is enough, I guess.
Besides...
Voice aside...
There are people who can only meet once a year.
Seems they didn't find any bodies in
the debris of that helicopter crash.
Yeah.
All of them must have escaped before the explosion.
And in the end...
We weren't able to uncover Irish's true identity.
The police didn't come across anything either, did they?
I couldn't possibly tell them, anyway.
Even so...
To be confined in such a place for ten days...
I heard Superintendent Matsumoto didn't see
the face of the person who kidnapped him.
Regardless, it was all thanks to
those kids that he was rescued.
Yeah.
Irish died before he could even reveal the hiding place.
Irish...
Kudo Shin'ichi...
Keep... coming after us...
I'll do just that.
Until the day I destroy you!