Damn...
Where'd he go?
There!
Let's end this game here...
Mr. Sneak-Thief.
We should.
It's growing too dark to continue playing hide-and-seek with you...
Detective-kun.
I'm high school detective, Kudo Shin'ichi.
While visiting an amusement park with my
childhood friend and classmate, Mouri Ran...
I witnessed a man in black in the midst of a suspicious transaction.
While caught up in watching the deal...
I failed to notice his partner coming up behind me.
Those men forced me to swallow poison...
And when I came to...
My body had shrunk.
If those guys found out that Kudo Shin'ichi was still alive...
They'd come after me again...
And put those around me at risk.
At Professor Agasa's suggestion,
I decided to conceal my true identity.
When Ran asked for my name, in that instant...
I became Edogawa Conan.
In order to obtain information on those guys...
I went to live with Ran, whose father is a private detective.
The culprit is...
You!
This guy's name is Mouri Kogoro.
Besides being Ran's father...
He's now a detective so renowned even
crying babies have the respect to stay silent.
The people call him "Sleeping Kogoro".
As for the reason behind that...
I'm sure I don't have to explain that, right?
These two gadgets were both invented by Professor Agasa.
Due to my shrinking, the professor invented
a number of unique gadgets for my use.
Especially this Instant Soccer Ball Belt.
When you push the button on the buckle...
A self-inflating soccer ball comes out—a brilliant innovation.
By the way...
There are others that know my identity other than the professor.
My mother and father...
The high school Detective of the West, Hattori Heiji...
And...
A fellow elementary school classmate...
Haibara Ai.
She, along with her elder sister Miyano Akemi,
was a colleague of the men in black, but...
Miyano Akemi was murdered by the organization.
Upon hearing this, Haibara, in protest...
Attempted to escape...
By taking the same drug I had been forced to, and her body shrank.
One more remains...
Kaitou Kid.
I've yet to put him behind bars.
But, as a detective...
I'll keep up the chase until I get him once and for all!
Even though I've become smaller, my mind remains the same...
The unbeaten great detective...
There's always only one truth!
10 Hours Earlier
I see.
This is the advance notice you received from Kid?
Yes.
This morning, on the balcony of my apartment...
Maki Juri
Actress
This was placed, along with a large bouquet or roses.
He's still as pretentious as ever.
"Romeo, Juliet..."
"Victor, Bravo..."
"In the midst of where 26 letters fly about...
Yaguchi Masayo
Manager
"I shall call upon you and gratefully accept the 'Jewel of Destiny'."
"Kaitou Kid."
Along with a playing card that's been split in half.
Here you are.
Thank you.
Uhm...
What's your opinion, Mouri-sensei?
Let's see here...
This "Jewel of Destiny" would be—?
It would be in reference to this.
How pretty!
This is a star sapphire, then?
Yes.
The three lines that intersect on its surface...
Represent faith, hope, and fate.
Thats is why it is known as the "Jewel of Destiny".
I see...
It sure is magnificent!
It's perfect for Joséphine, whose love for
blue sapphires was no trifling matter...
Which is why we're currently using it in the performance.
Performance?
I've heard of it!
It's a new theater that opened in Shiodome called Sora, where
they're currently putting on a play called Joséphine, right?
Joséphine?
She was Napoleon's first queen.
She was also a well-known rose collector.
I see.
So that's why he sent the bouquet of roses.
That's right, little boy.
You seem to know a lot.
Nah, he's only good for knowing trivial facts!
Romeo, Juliet...
Victor, Bravo...
Juri-san?
Yes?
At the theater where you're currently performing...
Has there ever been a performance of Romeo and Juliet?
I didn't participate in the performance, but...
It was Sora Theater's maiden performance.
Why do you ask?
I've figured it out.
Really?
In this advance notice Kid sent...
We have three Ws and one H.
In short...
Who, when, where, and how...
Are all communicated through its content.
I see!
Hey, hey...
Can he pull this off?
Foremost is "who".
This goes without saying—it's Kid.
Then we have "where".
That'd be where Romeo and Juliet was performed—the Sora stage.
Next: "when".
From the "Bravo" in the letter, we can take this
to mean when the audience is applauding.
Lastly, we have "how".
"Victor" refers to the conqueror.
That is Napoleon, whom Kid intends to disguise as.
Additionally, the playing card in the advance notice...
It was split in half to make the "V" sign for victory.
In other words...
Kaitou Kid will appear on stage during your performance of
Joséphine, and, precisely when the audience applauds...
He will, while disguised as Napoleon, attempt to steal the ring.
Bravo!
Bravo, Mouri-san!
No wonder you're a renowned detective.
No, you flatter me!
Say, Uncle...
What does this "in the midst of where 26 letters fly about" mean?
Idiot!
Count the number of letters in the English words at the top.
Romeo, Juliet, Victor, Bravo.
They add up to 26 letters.
Oh, I see!
By the way, Juri-san...
When will the performance of Joséphine run until?
Today is the last day.
Which means what Kid is aiming for is...
Ah-le-le!
Geez!
What is it this time?
Because, it's strange!
Look, there are only 22 letters.
That can't be.
I counted them as well.
Even if you count the exclamation mark,
there are still three letters missing.
Well, Kid must have counted wrong then...
Hey, hey...
Anyway...
It's certain that Kid will be coming tonight to steal the jewel.
Yes, I understand.
There's another favor I must ask of you.
Of course the police will be contacted as well, but...
Would you also attend tonight's performance?
In order to protect this jewel from Kid.
No problem.
l, Mouri Kogoro...
Have never turned down a request from a beautiful woman.
Thank you so much!
Hey, Masayo-san.
Oh, yes.
These are tickets to tonight's performance.
Please feel free to bring your companions along.
Thank you.
"In the midst of where 26 letters fly about"...
"26 letters" should refer to the English alphabet...
And this playing card...
I can't quite picture it as a V sign...
Shiodome View Tower
Sora Theater
I'm so excited.
Me too.
Actually, I've wanted to see this play all along.
Hey, Conan...
What's with that backpack?
It's getting in the way.
Just because...
"Just because" of what?
Don't tell me...
You brought snacks you weren't gonna share?
No way, I'm not you.
Hey, you guys.
I specially invited you all here...
So be on your best behavior, all right?
Yes!
Thanks for extending the invitation to us as well.
Of course!
Mouri-sensei!
My apologies for having you wait!
Yaguchi-san, hello.
It's Yaguchi.
Are you ready to see Mouri-sensei?
Sure.
Come, please enter.
Pardon our intrusion.
Welcome, Mouri-san.
Hello.
I apologize for my appearance.
Natsuki-chan, this is the famous Mouri Kogoro-san.
You've heard him, right?
Sakai Natsuki
Hair Style & Make-up Artist
I'm Sakai Natsuki.
Hello.
So big!
There are so many flowers!
Awesome!
I apologize.
In accepting your offer, I may have taken too great an advantage
of your generosity by bringing these children along as well.
No, I don't mind.
Juri-san, are you into diving?
Yes, although I only just started.
Would you like to go together sometime?
Sounds good.
Sure!
Never mind that he's never dived before.
Did you say something, Ran?
Nothing!
There are so many cosmetics!
Looks like it.
This is called foundation, right?
Just counting the foundation, there are...
One, two, three, four...
Five types.
Five different types?
Hey, you!
You young ladies...
It's too early for you to be interested in cosmetics!
Kids should be kids...
Right?
Yes, ma'am...
Yes?
Oh, Masa-chan.
Narusawa-san!
I heard Mouri-san was here...
Mouri-san!
You're the renowned detective Mouri Kogoro-san, aren't you?
I am Narusawa.
Narusawa Bunjirou
Actor
I'm a big fan of yours.
A pleasure to meet you.
Your role is that of Napoleon, is it not?
Yes.
You recognize the costume.
Oh, yes!
Let me introduce everyone.
Starting with...
The actress playing the role of Joséphine's best
friend Thérésa Tallien, Tajima Tenko-san.
Tajima Tenko
Actress
Nice to meet you.
The one playing the role of Joséphine's lover
Hippolyte Charles, Shinjou Isao-kun.
Shinjou Isao
Actor
Hello.
And, our stage director on this play who's concurrently
playing the role of Joséphine's patron Paul Barras...
Ban Tooru
Stage Director & Actor
The name's Ban Tooru.
Pleasure to meet you.
The pleasure is mine.
Everybody's gathered here then?
Inspector Nakamori!
Hello, Mouri-san.
Long time no see.
I really have to thank you for last time.
Oh no, I should really thank you.
I wonder if they're all who they appear to be...
You're right...
Kid often disguises himself as someone close to his target.
Perhaps he's already among us...
Oh, yes...
This time I've specially brought along
someone to help with the investigation...
Well, I said there was no need, but that rascal Megure...
Oh, no...
I mean Inspector Megure strongly recommended him.
Get in here.
Hello, I'm Kudo Shin'ichi.
Shin'ichi?
Kudo-kun!
Oh, it's just this guy.
Isn't Kudo Shin'ichi...
That famous high school detective?
Who was he again?
What are you talking about?
He's Ran-oneesan's boyfriend!
He isn't!
Her husband, actually.
Sonoko!
He's Kaitou Kid!
This person is not Shin'ichi-niichan!
It's Kid in disguise!
Kid?
And how would you know that?
Because I'm the real...
The real—what?
Nothing...
I see.
We can't say that possibility doesn't exist...
Ouch!
Please stop, Inspector Nakamori!
Just what is going on here?
I don't know.
Maybe it's because Kid resembles me to begin with, or...
Perhaps...
You're the one that's an impostor.
Hey, hey...
All right!
Ow!
There's no doubt he's the real thing.
Now, I'll go ahead and pinch the faces of everyone else as well.
No, there's no need for that.
I have a feeling that Kid is not among us.
I'm telling you, he is!
And I've already thought of a secret plan to arrest Kid.
Well then, please share this secret plan of yours.
Maki-san, if you don't mind, can we have
everyone else out of the room for a moment?
I don't mind, Inspector.
We've already finished up our preparations.
Excuse me.
I'm going to go do things my own way, so...
What'd you say?
Wonderful!
We've got no use for detective brats like you.
Well then, we shall take our leave.
We look forward to seeing you on stage.
Hey...
You should have called me if you were going to be coming back!
Sorry, sorry.
I just wanted to see that cute face you make when you get surprised.
Cute...?
Starting out rather boldly, aren't you?
Well, I guess I'll go and check the roof.
Ran, would you like to come along?
The top floor is like an observation deck.
You should go, Ran.
I wanna go, too!
You will stay here.
I wanna go, I wanna go!
I wanna go, too!
Now look here, you...
I wanna go, wanna go, wanna go!
All right.
Why don't we all go together?
Yay!
Say, isn't Conan...
He seems to be a completely different person around Ran-san.
It must be because...
He's at that age where he's spoiled.
I see.
What a brat, that guy.
Don't forget you're brats too.
It's not like I'd let her be alone with Kid.
All right, looks like this door's really locked.
How'd it go?
All the doors to the roof are locked.
In other words, if my deduction is correct...
Kid won't kid around with us via the roof!
I guess not...
Because he's already here.
Hey...
I'll watch Conan-kun, so...
Why don't you two go off somewhere?
No, it's fine.
Besides...
He seems different somehow...
Because, he never says things like that.
Like what?
Cute, for example.
That just means he's gotten a little more straightforward.
You should be more frank as well.
If you like him, just tell him.
No way!
I told you, it's not like that, didn't I?
Awesome, awesome, awesome!
Genta-kun, you've only been saying "awesome" this whole time.
What else can I say?
It's awesome.
Oh, look at this—what a superb view!
There's really not much else to say besides "awesome".
See?
It really is impressive, isn't it?
How daring of him...
To disguise as Shin'ichi, of all people.
Yeah.
Maybe it's because it's easier for him
to reach his goal by disguising as me.
At least it saves us time searching for him.
Yeah.
By the way, you guys...
Do you know who Napoleon was?
Yeah, sort of.
At least that he's the French hero who
conquered Europe for a period of time.
All right!
Then, as a warm-up for the performance...
I'll give you a quiz on Napoleon!
Shin'ichi-oniisan's going to?
Just like Professor Agasa.
It's not going to be a lame pun, right?
My question is grounded in history, so it's educational.
You should think on it too, kid!
Shut up.
Ready?
On Napoleon's land...
Two Japanese people built their houses.
Who were those two Japanese people, out of the following choices?
One, Fuyuno-san.
Two, Furuno-san.
Three, Fukano-san.
Fuyuno-san, Furuno-san, Fukano-san...
All the names have "fu" and "no" in them.
I got it!
Don't tell them!
The difference between the three names is
that they have "yu", "ru", and "ka" in the middle...
I got it!
It's Fuyuno-san and Furuno-san!
Only Fukano-san's name has "ka" in the middle, right?
"Ka" in the "middle"
translates to "Chinese"
Therefore Fukano-san is Chinese!
What?
Are you saying that's not the answer?
The answer is correct, but it's the way you solved it.
Guys, do you know Napoleon's famous quote,
"In my dictionary, the word impossible does not exist"?
I've heard of it!
This riddle plays upon that famous quote.
"Land" can also be pronounced "jisho" (dictionary).
"Moji" refers to the characters
posted for the name on a doorplate.
Basically: "On my land, the
characters Fukano do not appear".
I see.
By the way, what Napoleon actually said was...
"Impossible is a word found only in a fool's dictionary".
Or so it seems.
As expected from the amazing Haibara-san!
But, it's still just a lame pun, as we thought.
Besides...
I don't think it was very educational either.
Really?
Joséphine...
Thérésa...
What is it, Citizen Barras?
Sir, allow me to introduce...
Thérésa Tallien, and Joséphine.
This gentleman is...
I know of him.
General Napoleon Bonaparte.
I heard you were a very heroic gentleman.
You flatter me.
General, I wonder if you would dance with me?
With pleasure.
Everything around me makes me miss...
Those glorious days...
Bonaparte...
The Isle of Elba...
The King of the Romans...
Hey, Ran.
Isn't that person next to the Pope your father?
So that's the secret plan to catch Kid?
Haibara, cover for me.
Have fun.
Kid, you all right?
That was pretty dangerous.
Yeah, I'm fine.
Anyway...
Is something the matter?
This kid suddenly came running from around the corner...
He fell down after crashing into me.
Are you all right, little boy?
I'm fine!
But, mister, your baton is really something!
Isn't it longer than the one this man has?
You're right.
It's much longer.
Well, there are many different sorts of batons.
Length: 60 centimeters or below.
Diameter: 3 centimeters or below.
Weight: 320 grams or below.
Those are the regulations on batons mandated by the public safety
commissions in each of Japan's administrative regions, right?
Mister, isn't yours...
Quite a bit too long?
Tell me, why is that?
As for why it's so long...
That's because...
It's not a baton!
I won't let you get away!
Wait!
Damn!
Everything in the world...
Glory.
Victory.
The future is mine!
It is ours!
When the curtains are completely lowered, we strike.
Understood.
Now!
Grab Kid!
He's disguised as Napoleon!
Hey!
What are you...
How careless, Kid.
That underwhelming code you sent...
Yours truly, Mouri Kogoro-sama, deciphered every last bit of it!
No!
I'm not Kid!
Cut the nonsense and show us your true form...
Kaitou Kid!
Ow, ow, ow!
He's real.
Then, where's Kid?
Let's end this game here...
Mr. Sneak-Thief.
We should.
It's growing too dark to continue playing hide-and-seek with you...
Detective-kun.
Enough with the small talk.
Let's bring this to a Kicking end.
Yeah.
After all, your girl is waiting with your prepared supper.
Conan-kun!
Supper's ready!
If you don't hurry, it'll all be gone!
Well, it does seem like the end is near...
Detective-kun.
Yeah.
Seems that way.
Hey, hey...
I see.
A paraglider for a hang glider, huh?
I expected as much from you.
The paraglider just now...
Was it another of Professor Agasa's inventions?
You've got nowhere left to run.
Without flight...
Even Kaitou Kid is just an ordinary sneak-thief.
Then I guess it's time...
I return to being the thief I was.
What's that noise?
No!
Later!
Damn it!
And now for the weather around the airports...
Haneda Airport
Hokkaido...
Tonight in hakodate, there will be rain, at times turning
into thunderstorm, and winds from the southwest.
Thunderstorms in Hakodate, huh?
Such unfortunate weather.
What if the airplane is struck by lightning?
It's all right!
Because planes fly above the clouds.
Oh, but the landing takes place below the clouds, doesn't it?
I got all dressed up for today and it's going to rain...
In that getup, you'll get your belly button taken by the God of Thunder...
My grandmama said so!
Really?
Then, I dare him to try and take it if he can!
You've shown us too much kindness.
Even going as far as inviting us to attend
the post-performance celebration party.
It was thanks to everyone that the gemstone is safe, so it's only proper.
Exactly.
Rather than dwelling on that, let's enjoy Hakodate!
You know, that Juri sure is late...
Yeah.
Sorry about that.
She's having Natsuki-san do her make-up right now.
In the car parked in the parking lot.
Applying make-up?
It sure is tough being a huge star.
The real burden is on Natsuki-chan.
Juri finds her so useful that she's pretty
much her personal assistant nowadays.
I see.
Hi!
Sorry for the wait everyone.
My, as always, you're exceptionally beautiful today!
Thank you, Mouri-san.
It looks like everyone has arrived.
No, Shinjou-kun isn't here yet.
Shinjou-san isn't feeling well.
He called this morning to say he couldn't make it.
Oh, is that so?
Such a pity, isn't it, Juri?
Why's that?
Nothing.
Uhm...
Aren't the other cast members coming?
Of course not!
There's no merit in asking those extras to come along.
What was that just now?
Hakodate Lake Oonuma Shoreside
Juri's Villa
If my instincts are correct, that guy will definitely show up here.
Inspector Nakamori, all personnel are present.
Good.
A-Team, take the front.
B-Team, take the rear.
C-Team, patrol the vicinity.
Yes, sir!
Inspector Nakamori...
What is it?
Inside the villa, the lights...
What?
That's...
Sky Japan Airlines, leaving for Hakodate.
Flight 865 departing at 18:15...
Is now commencing with boarding procedures.
Calling all Flight 865 passengers headed for Hakodate...
Wow, they're so soft and fluffy!
Not bad, right?
I feel like a CEO!
As far as domestic flights, having a First Class second floor...
Is exclusive to Sky Japan Airlines!
Hey, what is it?
What's wrong, Ran?
You've been looking behind you ever since we got on.
It's nothing.
Welcome aboard.
Thank you.
She's here!
Who's here?
Be quiet.
Uhm, the seat next to you...
Oh, go ahead.
Eri!
You!
Auntie?
Ah-le-le!
Mom, don't tell me you're going to Hakodate too?
What a wonderful coincidence!
It's definitely fate that brought you and Dad together again.
What are you talking about?
You were the one who said you were invited by Juri-san to Hakodate
and asked me to accompany you due to your father being busy.
Ran, not this from you again...
Now, now...
Anyway, why don't you two have a seat?
You've got to be kidding!
Why do I have to sit next to him!?
Why do I have to sit next to her!?
Come on, you two...
Dad!
Excuse me, Juri-san...
May I sit next to you?
Sure, go ahead.
Geez...
Wait, Mom!
Excuse me—you're Maki Juri-san, correct?
Yes.
My name is Kisaki Eri.
I want to thank you for inviting me for this occasion.
No problem.
That's right!
If the vulgar man next to you troubles you with his speech or conduct...
Don't hesitate to ask for my consultation.
You're a lawyer.
Well then, I shall be at your service.
Sure.
How did things end up being like this?
"End up being"?
Get used to it.
Hello, everyone!
Sorry to have kept you all waiting.
Shinjou-san!
Didn't you say that you weren't coming because you were feeling ill?
Nah...
I'm feeling much better.
I was just sitting around by myself...
So I figured I would join you guys.
Sorry to keep you waiting, Joséphine-sama.
Why haven't you done as I said?
Relax.
There'll be more than enough time once we get there.
Well, have a safe trip.
Yes, see you again soon!
Flight attendats, please prepare the cabin for daparture.
What are you thinking about?
I bet it has something to do with Kid.
Yeah.
Did he truly intend to steal the jewel last night?
It's growing too dark to continue playing hide-and-seek with you...
Detective-kun.
On top of that, he had an overly long baton stick.
That's too careless a mistake for Kid.
Hey, hey!
My seat number is 4K.
K for Kid, right?
My seat number is 4J.
J for Jumbo, isn't it?
My seat number is 4B.
That means... that means...
So that's it!
The four English words that Kid wrote on his message...
They were a reference to the phonetic alphabet!
Phonetic alphabet?
Yeah.
They're codes used over wireless communication
in order to prevent miscommunication.
"R" becomes "Romeo".
"J" becomes "Juliet".
"V" becomes "Victor".
"B" becomes "Bravo".
Airplanes also use it over radio communications.
SKY-J 865.
Runway 16 Left.
Taxi in.
JULIET 10, ECHO 10, CHARLIE 10.
SKY-J 865.
In essence, the "In the midst of where 26 letters fly about part...
Was an advance notice that he's going to commit the crime aboard
the plane, where those phonetic codes fly about over the airwaves.
Furthermore, it will take place on this flight, from Tokyo to Hakodate.
Why is that?
If it's on plane, the return trip...
The picture of the playing card, right?
Yeah.
That the two of spades card was split in half...
Indicates a number that is not divisible by 2—an odd number.
Flights that depart from Tokyo are, like this flight
numbered 865, given odd number designations.
All flights arriving into Tokyo are designated even numbers.
If we think about it that way, we can
understand what happened last night.
He purposely drew my attention to him...
To lure me into thinking his heist had failed and...
Put everyone off their guard, as he intended.
If that's the case...
Kid is somewhere on this plane.
And even now is aiming to steal that ring.
Is anything wrong?
For some reason, I'm not feeling too well.
You must be getting tired.
This flight is Sky Japan Airline Flight 865, headed for Hakodate Airport.
Here, Juri, put your hand out.
Some vitamin pills.
I am your chief cabin attendant, Shindou.
SKY-J 865. Winds 160 and 10. Clear for takeoff.
SKY-J 865. Clear for takeoff. Runway 16 Left.
Takeoff.
Eighty.
Check.
V1.
VR.
V2.
Positive.
Gear up.
Huh?
My ears feel weird for some reason.
Yeah, me too...
It's because of the change in air pressure.
Just swallow and you'll be fine.
It still feels weird.
Nothing happened.
If that's the case, hold your nose and blow.
However, don't do it too hard.
You might get dizzy.
It worked!
Awesome, look—something came out.
Conan-kun, face forward, all right?
You were right, it worked!
I guess girls will be girls...
The way someone looks when blowing
their nose isn't very attractive, you know?
She wouldn't want someone of the opposite
gender, especially someone she likes, to see that.
Excuse me, Juri-san.
Could you sign this for me as a commemoration?
Sure.
Oh, damn it...
I forgot to bring a pen for you to sign it with.
Maki-san?
Here, use this.
Thank you.
You can see how I could never let her out of my reach.
What's Dad doing?
Don't worry about that superficial man.
How about taking this time to tell me who everyone is?
Sorry 'bout that.
Are you all right?
Yeah.
All done.
Thank you very much!
Western or Japanese snacks—which would you like?
No, I'm fine.
Western or Japanese snacks...
I won't need either.
Nor any drinks.
I'll take beer and a Japanese snack to go with it.
Just a moment, please.
Drinking beer in first class is the...
Hakodate Airport
This rain is horrible, isn't it?
Yeah...
Hopefully everything will be all right.
SKY-J 865, contact Tokyo Control.
118.90.
SKY-J 865.
Tokyo Control, SKY-J 865.
Flight level: 390.
SKY-J 865, Tokyo Control. Roger.
Are you all right, Captain?
I'm fine.
Last night my youngest had a fever, so I didn't really sleep much.
Should I request some coffee for you?
Please, if you would.
The ring's still all right?
Yeah.
But I won't let my guard down.
That was rather quick.
Hey, Masayo-san.
The chocolates...
Service for the cockpit?
Relatively rare on domestic routes.
It's Misawa.
I've brought the coffee.
Please come in.
Sorry for the intrusion.
You can't come in here, Miss!
It's fine, Misawa-kun.
She's your senior.
Long time no see, Captain!
Yeah.
It's been about five years since you resigned, hasn't it?
Seven years now.
It's been that long?
You too, Nakaya-san, long time no see.
Hey.
I saw Joséphine, you know.
Oh, I'm glad!
Yeah, it was truly wonderful.
Really?
Thank you so much.
We will always come in support of you.
Well then, Captain, I'll see you later.
Maki-san?
Here, have a chocolate.
Thank you.
Mouri-sensei, would you like one too?
Oh, thank you.
Yum!
It can't be!
Uncle, there's an almond scent.
Yeah.
Cyanide poisoning, then.
It's the chocolate!
There was poison in the chocolates!
The chocolates?
Dad!
Don't worry.
If there had been poison in the chocolate Uncle ate,
the symptoms would have already manifested.
But then...
How did Juri-san...
The Captain's message was...
In order not to alarm the other passengers...
He'd like for news of this incident to not be
leaked until after we arrive at the airport.
Understood.
But, just how did the culprit manage to poison Juri-san?
Like I said, it must have been in the chocolates.
Since she collapsed right afer eating it.
I'm with him on this one.
No way!
Don't look at me!
I bought this box of chocolates this afternoon
from a shop in Ginza where we always get them!
And I only just now opened them!
Right, Natsuki-san?
Sorry, I wasn't really watching.
Natsuki-san!
But, since you ate one too and nothing happened...
That means that only a portion of the chocolate was poisoned, right?
If that's so, I wonder how Juri-san was made
to choose one of the poisoned chocolates?
As her manager, it's only natural you would
know which chocolate she'd eat first.
I didn't do it!
Besides, she chooses the chocolate randomly every time!
It did look like Juri-san hesitated over which chocolate to choose.
Shut up!
Kids should stay out of this!
At any rate, I will take possession of those chocolates.
Yes, sir.
As for the rest, we can only wait until we arrive
at the airport and let the police deal with it.
Yeah.
In order to preserve the crime scene, would
everyone please move to the seats at the back?
The front lavatory is now off limits as well.
Apart from that chocolate, all that's come into
contact with her mouth since she boarded were...
Those vitamin pills...
Even so...
It wasn't a sure thing that Juri-san
would have wanted to take those pills.
I got it!
I know who the culprit is!
Dad?
Who?
Who? Who?
Who? Who? Who's the culprit?
The deceased Juri-san only consumed two
types of things after boarding this plane.
Those two types of things were...
The chocolates we were just discussing, and...
Tenko-san's vitamin pills.
You?
You understand now, right?
The culprit who killed Maki Juri-san on this plane is...
Tenko-san, it's you!
Don't joke around!
A false accusation is a serious matter!
In the first place, I don't even have a motive!
Is that so, I wonder?
There's no one here who doesn't have a motive to kill Juri-san, is there?
What are you talking about?
You're the hair dresser and make-up artist Sakai Natsuki-san, right?
If you could explain.
I have been with Juri-san for a long time...
So I believe I'm the one most familiar with her relationships with others.
First, Ban-san...
Although he held the title of play director...
In reality, it had been Juri-san, the
chairman, doing all the directing.
Originally, it was he who trained Juri-san to become an actress, but...
It all reversed.
He couldn't even oppose her.
I've seen him getting angrily told off by his
wife, Tenko-san, over this matter many times.
Narusawa-san was asked for a divorce by
Juri-san three years ago and agreed, but...
It seems he still has feelings for her.
No matter how many times he begged
her for reconciliation, he was rejected.
She also seemed to be getting bored with her young lover, Shinjou-san...
And asked me to introduce some other cute guys to her.
Then there's her manager, Masayo-san.
Juri-san has always criticized her as dull and dim-witted...
Often humiliating her in front of everyone.
And then there's myself.
I was always being abused by the selfish Juri-san.
When I wanted to get another job, she interfered.
I pretended nothing was wrong, but I resented her.
See?
That's why it wouldn't be strange at all if any one of us murdered her.
Hey, Genta-kun...
How can you eat at a time like this?
Because it'd all go to waste otherwise.
Delicious!
If the poison had been on her fingers...
The first person to have touched her hand was Shinjou-san.
Could he has placed the poison at that time?
No.
There were other opportunities.
What if the poison was on the signature pen?
Maybe the poison was placed on the switch for the reading light.
No, also...
Poison could have been applied to areas in the
restroom Juri-san would have been likely to touch...
That's right—after Juri-san went into the
lavatory, she came out rather quickly.
Wait a minute, before that!
I see!
So that's how it was!
That's why she...
For some reason, I'm not feeling too well.
I've figured out this trick...
And the culprit who set it up!
Ah-le-le, Uncle!
What do you think that is?
What?
There's nothing there.
All right, and now!
Damn it!
Hey, what are you talking about?
I guess I was just seeing things!
I'm going to the restroom!
What's with him?
No choice...
This will be the first time, though...
Dear, you can stop putting on airs.
Wha—?
Oh, no!
I messed up!
Sonoko?
Me?
That's quite enough.
Let's hear the truth from you.
What?
Well, it's not like this case is of a caliber
that requires Sleeping Kogoro to solve it.
All right, I'll explain the situation.
No way...
All right!
Today it's Auntie's Deduction Show!
We'll begin with the method the culprit used to administer the poison.
From that altogether unsurprising modus operandi...
And that would be ear clearing.
Ear clearing?
Once Juri-san boarded the aircraft...
She would definitely have to clear her ears.
The culprit knew this.
They knew that she would use the method in which she'd pinch
her nose with her thumb and forefinger while she blew...
And that she always used her right hand in doing so.
Perhaps some of those present are aware that this method
of ear clearing is among the first things taught to new divers.
After becoming an advanced diver, it's possible to
clear your ears without pinching your nose, but...
Juri-san was still a beginner.
Nine times out of ten, she would have done it.
Isn't that right, dear?
Yeah...
Hold on!
How'd you know that?
Uhm...
This method of ear clearing...
Similar to how Ayumi-chan felt...
It's somewhat embarrassing for a female to do
so in front someone of the opposite gender...
Not to mention that Juri-san was an
actress and you were sitting next to her.
No matter how much of a blockhead you
are, you are of the opposite gender...
Blockhead!?
That was why Juri-san went to the
lavatory to clear her ears in private.
Then, upon returning to her seat, she used the thumb and
forefinger of her right hand to pick up the chocolate and eat it.
As had happened many times before, she even
licked the cocoa powder that got on her fingers.
She was unaware this habit of hers was being exploited in
order to complete the introduction of poison into her body.
What do you mean?
Where exactly was the poison?
It feels like it's kind of hard to breathe, doesn't it?
Yeah.
Weird, isn't it?
Actually, the poison was already slowly entering Juri-san's body.
Right, the reason she wasn't feeling well...
Was because of the poison that was being absorbed through her skin.
Her skin?
If that's the case, could it be...
Yes.
Inside the car parked in the lot at Haneda Airport...
Having applied the poison and foundation
mixture to both sides of Juri-san's nose...
The culprit responsible for Juri-san's death...
You, Sakai Natsuki-san...
It was you!
That's not possible!
Still, that was a fairly interesting deduction!
Conan-kun mentioned it to me...
That you scolded the children who were playing with the foundation.
It was as a precaution against the one in a million chance...
That they would mess with it on the day you
would use it to commit the murder, wasn't it?
Then, if you're so sure, show me your evidence!
That's right...
If we had examined the thumb and forefinger of Juri-san's right hand...
And actually found poison-laced foundation there,
it would have served as sufficient evidence, but...
Given that Juri-san licked the poison off,
that evidence has vanished, hasn't it?
But, there is other evidence.
The bottle of poisoned foundation and the sponge.
Smart as you are, you wouldn't have brought those two items aboard.
On the other hand, disposing of them in the airport
trash cans would have likewise been dangerous.
Right.
If it were me, I would have sent it...
Addressed back to my own house, via the mail.
Well, if we contact the airport post office and have
them investigate the mail parcel, we'll know for sure.
Well, would you care to tell us?
Your home address.
That woman...
She destroyed my dream.
Your dream?
It had been my dream to become a Hollywood make-up artist.
In order to fulfill my dream, I studied abroad
at a make-up school in Los Angeles...
And even mastered speaking conversational English.
Upon my return to Japan, while helping this
woman with her hairstyling and make-up...
I continued to write to Hollywood seeking employment.
Then, one month ago, when a Hollywood actress came to Japan...
An agent who recognized my make-up skill
approached me asking if I wanted to work with her.
To me, it was the chance of a lifetime.
But...
But that woman...
That woman secretly intervened and destroyed that opportunity.
She really didn't want to let you go.
I could have forgiven her if she had done it because
she needed me because of my make-up skills!
But that wasn't it...
She had only wanted me by her side in order
to use me as a servant to her many whims.
After I found out everything, I realized l
had no choice but to go through with it...
She'd ruined my pride as a make-up artist.
Your pride as a make-up artist?
Don't make me laugh!
If that were the case, why would you use your make-up as a weapon?
At this moment, you have no right to talk about pride.
I...
You're still young.
After you've repaid your debt to society, you can start over.
What is this, this feeling of dread?
It's like the inside of my head is tingling...
This is bad!
Hey!
Tell the captain and co-pilot not to eat the snacks you just gave them!
If you don't hurry, the captain and co-pilot will be in danger!
You're stupid, aren't you?
There's no poison in the snacks.
It's not the snacks!
It's their fingers that could have poison on them!
What!?
What's going on here?
Explain yourself!
Yes, I'll be right there!
Sorry for the intrusion.
As I feared!
Captain!?
Captain, what's wrong!?
Are you all right!?
What's going on?
Nakaya-san!
Are you all right!?
Captain!
No, the auto-pilot's been disengaged!
Captain, please pull yourself together!
Captain!
Hurry, pull him up!
Move the seat out of the way!
Captain!
All right, now for the auto-pilot switch...
Shinjou-san?
Not bad, kid.
Everything's all right now.
Summon a doctor immediately.
Got it!
We are currently experiencing a medical emergency onboard.
If there is a doctor among the passengers, please identify
yourself to the nearest flight attendant immediately.
As suspected, they've been poisoned by a fast-acting poison.
I'll begin administering first-aid if you would
please move them into the passenger cabin.
All right.
Narusawa-san, Ban-san—give us a hand!
Yes, sir!
The medical kit!
Yes, ma'am!
Say, Conan-kun...
Why did the captain and co-pilot also...
Earlier, Juri-san entered the cockpit.
At that time, the captain and co-pilot took Juri-san's hand and kissed it.
I see, so that's when the poison that was on Juri-san's fingers...
How unfortunate, then.
If they had just shaken hands normally, the poison would have
only gotten onto their palms, and they wouldn't have ingested it.
Whoa...
How are they, Doctor?
Fortunately, they only ingested a very small amount
of the poison, so their lives are not in danger.
However...
They remain in a fuzzy state of consciousness
and will be unable to operate the plane.
What'd you say!?
The captain and the co-pilot are unconscious?
Excuse me...
Could I have your name?
I'm a passenger, my name is Shinjou.
Shinjou-san, do you know the current flight situation?
The current altitude is 12000 feet.
Current speed is 280 knots.
Fortunately, the ILS for landing has already been inputted...
And I have some experience operating the flaps and gears, so I can do it.
All I need are instructions with regards to the timing.
Got it.
We will clear all other landings and takeoffs.
We'll also put in an immediate request
for a flight captain to come to the tower.
The current weather around Hakodate is not stable.
Consequently, all incoming and outbound flights
have been suspended until further notice.
We appreciate your patience during this time.
Ladies and gentlemen...
So that's that.
I'll take over the captain's seat.
As for the co-pilot's seat...
Right...
Could I get you to take care of it?
Your judgment with the control yoke earlier was pretty impressive.
Yay!
I've flown planes lots of times in the arcade center!
Hey!
Conan-kun, no fair!
I wanna sit there too!
Me too!
This isn't a game!
Also, I won't need anyone to steer anymore.
It's just that, even with ILS, I'll need to do a
number of things at once during the landing.
That's the only time I'll have him assist.
Even so, why that brat?
At any rate, just leave it to me.
We'll be landing in around 15 minutes or so.
Everyone, please return to the passenger cabin.
Shinjou-kun just said he had some experience, but...
Maybe he's got a license to fly a Cessna or something...
Huh?
Dad, Mom seems to be fast asleep.
What?
Everyone, please hurry back to your
seats and fasten your seatbelts tightly.
Dad, sit next to Mom, all right?
Geez...
Guess it can't be helped.
Hey, wake up!
Hey!
Geez...
You're Kid, right?
What are you talking about?
Don't be stupid, drop the act.
In what world would there exist someone who'd let an
elementary school student take the co-pilot's seat?
You got me there.
As for the real Shinjou, right now...
He's dressed up as a fake Kid and at Juri-san's villa in Hakodate...
Right?
When you got on the plane, Juri-san was angry, you see...
I'm pretty sure he was told by Juri-san to be
a fake Kid as entertainment for the party.
I expected as much from you.
Except...
There's a certain other person who, disbelieving Kid would
give up just like that, had headed to Hakodate as well, so...
That person might be chasing after the fake Kid as we speak.
And?
When is it you plan on taking possession of the "Jewel of Destiny"?
I'm not after it anymore.
You should know about it as well...
A real star sapphire is cold when you touch it with your lips.
That one's a fake.
What he did back then—it was to ascertain that!
It was probably in order to attract playgoers to see Joséphine...
That they tried to publicize that fake as the real thing.
What're you gonna do?
You gonna arrest me?
Detective-kun.
Of course, after this giant metal bird has returned to its nest.
Sky-J Flight 865.
Hakodate Tower will now take over.
Please change the radio frequency to 118.35.
118.35, roger that.
This is Hakodate Tower.
I am the control chief, Uesugi.
I'll hand you over to Captain Shimaoka.
This is Shimaoka.
We'll get right to it—do you see the M.C.P.?
That's the Mode Control Panel.
Yes, I see it.
Then please press the APP button on that panel.
This will enable the plane to lower itself onto the runway automatically.
Roger.
APP...
That one.
It's pressed!
Who are you?
I'm Edogawa Conan, Shinjou-san's assistant!
Assistant?
Do you have a child next to you?
Little boy, do not touch the control yoke or any of the other switches!
Understand?
Now we can relax for the moment.
Can you handle operating the flaps and the landing gear?
Yeah, I got it.
My father taught me how to pilot a Cessna in Hawaii.
I see, guess I didn't pick the wrong person for the job after all.
But, that was all with feet planted firmly on the ground.
I've never flown for real.
It's the worst possible weather, but they
should still somehow be able to land, right?
Yeah.
Really bad rain...
The wind seems pretty strong as well.
Don't fall, airplane!
There's the airport!
Here it comes!
Flight 865: Flaps to 1.
Flaps to 5.
Flaps to 10.
Lower the wheels, flaps to 20.
We're finally about to land.
What the—!?
It's the lightning!
We've been struck by lightning!
This is Flight 865!
We've just been struck by lightning and all the displays have turned off!
Calm down.
Turn the white knob next to the glare shield.
They're back...
Not yet!
The auto-pilot's not engaged!
What'd you say!?
Abort the landing!
Full thrust and pull up on the control yoke!
All right, retract the wheels.
They're retracted!
Good, now contunue to climb!
No!
The wind is blowing it off course!
Turn to the right!
Turn right!
It's going to go right into the terminal building!
Bring up the nose of the airplane!
Not good!
Wow!
Awesome!
How's the airport?
Is the control tower all right?
Flight 865, can you hear me?
I can hear you!
What's the damage assessment?
No injuries at the tower.
But the runways can't be used for the time being.
How's the situation on your side?
We've lost Engine #2.
It's all right.
The remaining three engines are enough to make a landing.
But keep an eye on your balance.
The plane is currently stabilized.
We've just adjusted the rudder, and cut
the throttle down to position three.
Good, what's your current altitude and speed?
3000 feet, 200 knots.
Set the flaps to 5 and level out.
Turn the nose to 180 degrees and ascend to 4500 feet.
Roger that.
All we have to do now is circle around and wait for clearance, then.
Yeah.
As long as the auto-pilot functions are restored,
once the runway becomes operable again...
We can try landing again using the ILS.
This is ridiculous!
Didn't I tell you there aren't enough fire trucks!?
You have to put out the blaze on the runway!
Conan-kun, it's bad!
It's bad!
One of the engines fell off!
We already know, don't worry.
We can still land safely using three engines that are left.
And we still have plenty of...
What's wrong?
We're almost out of fuel!
What?
Out of fuel!?
You said we're out of fuel?
How did that happen!?
Could it be because the engine fell off?
No, usually each of the four engines have their own fuel tank, so...
The cross-feed valve is open!?
Hey, what is that cross-something?
It's a cross-feed valve.
Pressing that switch opens the valves that separate the tanks...
Making it all one big tank.
Damn, just how did that happen?
Whoa...
Geez, that old geezer.
That being the case, we don't have a moment to spare.
Yeah.
There should be maps over there, someone bring them over.
Hakodate Tower, this is Flight 865, mayday, mayday!
Tower, do you copy?
Please respond!
Flight 865... Hakodate Tower... please say again... louder!
Hey...
There's too much static, I can't make them out.
Exactly what's happened?
Professor!
We've lost an engine and the fuel is running low!
What'd you say!?
Map, map, map...
Should be that red one.
Got it!
Damn!
The auto-pilot, the runway, the fuel...
And now even the radio comms are gone as well!
Did you say the auto-pilot is gone!?
Then, you're piloting manually right now!?
Conan-kun!
Here, the map!
Thank you.
There's about 3000 pounds of fuel left.
At 300 Ibs/min, we've only got 10 minutes of flight time left.
We need to find somewhere to land within that time.
What do you mean by "somewhere"?
There's no way the last runway is going to be cleared in 10 minutes.
How about Chitose?
If we go to the New Chitose Airport...
It's very possible we'll run out of fuel before we get there.
What about other airports?
Aren't there any others around this area?
There aren't.
There might be an agricultural takeoff
and landing strip, or a JSDF base, but...
The length of the runway wouldn't be long enough.
If that's so, how about we try landing on a strip of road instead?
Hokkaido has a lot of wide and straight roads...
That's impossible.
The span between the wheels on this plane is 11 meters.
All roads spanning 12 or more meters across are required
to have a central divider as well as traffic signboards.
There would likely be residences and power lines in the vicinity as well.
Then, how about a field?
No way.
The ground would be too soft.
Rather, it'd be better to try a water landing in the sea nearby...
No...
The plane could be tossed by the waves and get turned over...
Where?
There has to be somewhere we can land...
Somewhere long, straight, and clear of obstructions...
Hey...
If we aren't able to land, what'll happen to us?
Well then...
We would crash...
I don't wanna die!
Hey, Conan-kun...
I know a place!
It's long, straight, and clear of obstructions!
A little while ago, they showed that place during
a dolphin and whale watching program on TV...
Dolphin and whale watching...
Muroran, then?
The piers!
Nippon Steel Pier...
Nakau Pier...
Motowanishi Pier...
Muroran Pier...
Nisseki Pier...
Found it!
Sakimori Pier!
Its length...
Approximately 1400 meters...
Its width is probably about 30 meters across!
But the width of this plane is...
Yeah...
Just short of 60 meters.
But, if we let one side of the wings hover
over the ocean, we should be able to.
Impossible.
That isn't enough stopping distance.
This plane should need more than 2000 meters of stopping distance.
The integrity of the ground surface is also a problem...
Luckily, or unluckily, there's not much fuel
left and there aren't many passengers.
The lighter we are, the shorter the stopping distance.
Depending on the wind direction, it may be even shorter.
According to the weather report I saw at Haneda Airport...
They said strong winds from the west will blow throughout the night!
Really, Mitsuhiko?
Yes!
This pier pretty much stretches east to west.
As long as we head into the west wind and land
from the east, we may just be able to land!
It's impossible.
When we collided with the control tower
earlier, I took a strong blow to my left arm...
I've been mostly controlling the plane
using only my right hand ever since...
If we're going to land manually...
I'll need to hold on to the control yoke tightly with both hands.
You—how's your vision?
1.5 in both eyes.
Any chronic diseases?
No...
And your bust, waist, and hip sizes?
Let me see, my bust is...
What!?
Good, you've passed.
Sit here in my place.
What are you saying!?
I don't know anything about flying a plane!
It'll be all right.
I'll be behind you, teaching you how to work it.
All you have to do is hold on to the control yoke.
I can't—there's no way!
The plane!
The plane's falling!
It's gonna crash!
Ran-neechan, hurry and sit!
And now, slowly pull the control yoke towards you.
Steady...
Great, nicely done.
Easy, wasn't it?
Not at all!
What direction to Muroran?
Looking for it right now.
Found it!
It just so happens that the Hakodate to
Sapporo flight path passes near Muroran.
The bearing is 023 degrees.
023, is it?
We'll pass over a mountain.
Our altitude needs to remain over 5000.
Roger.
Excuse me...
Please tell the passengers we're heading to Chitose.
Yes, sir.
Also, please transfer everyone on the second floor downstairs.
If they discover a high school girl is piloting the plane...
They may well panic.
You guys return to the cabin too.
Even if you stayed here, there's nothing else you guys can do.
I'd also like for you guys to keep an eye on the other
children and make sure they don't cause trouble.
This is a very important job.
If you can't do it, I'll ask someone else, but...
How about it?
Can you?
Understood.
We'll do our best!
Leave it to us!
All right!
I owe you guys!
Roger!
I'm staying.
Because if anything happens, Ran won't
have anyone else that can help her.
That'll be fine.
All right, I'll explain the other controls en route...
There's not much time left.
Let's go!
Flight SKY-J 865!
This is Hakodate Tower!
Do you copy?
Please respond!
It's no use, they're not even responding on the emergency line.
Take a look!
Flight 865 is heading away.
Where do you suppose they're going?
So that's the Great Shiratori Bridge, then?
That's quite impressive, Shiratori-kun!
Sorry to disappoint, Inspector, but that's the Hakucho Bridge.
The kanji "白鳥" can be read as either "Hakucho" or "Shiratori"
Coming to Muroran as you suggested on the way back
from our business trip to Sapporo was well worth it.
My, the Great Shiratori Bridge sure is beautiful...
Hakucho Bridge
Someday, I'll bring Miwako-san here...
This is definitely not on my list.
That's an amazing number of patrol cars!
Perhaps they're chasing after a particularly vicious fiend...
All right.
Let's check it out!
Ladies and gentlemen...
I'm scared, Mama!
There has been a small accident on the plane.
It's gonna be fine, right?
We will be diverting to New Chitose Airport.
It should be a smooth flight.
We apologize for the inconvenience and thank you for your understanding.
We're really going to Muroran, right?
We're approaching Muroran.
Descend to 2000 feet.
Yes, sir.
There!
I can see the lights!
That's Muroran Harbor!
Sakimori Pier is more to the left!
On the other side of Hakucho Bridge!
No good!
Hey...
It's dark—I can't see anything.
Wait, is that really where we're going to land?
What now?
We can't turn back now...
Hey...
Can we do this, Conan-kun?
What're you—!?
Looks pretty bad, so I'm bailing.
Good luck.
Hold on!
Hey, wait!
Ran-neechan, lower the nose of the plane!
Wait, what do you think you're doing?
Grab onto something!
What?
What happened?
It's fine.
Don't worry.
Just keep the plane steady.
K-
Kaitou Kid!
Well, young miss...
Let us meet again someday, under the pale moonlight.
Yes.
Bye!
He jumped off!?
That's right!
Shinjou-san was Kid!
I see...
So that's why he pressed the depressurization button.
He got scared because we're going to crash, so he fled!
And I was a fan of his...
That jerk!
Sonoko-neechan, isn't it a bit early to say we're gonna crash?
But, Conan-kun...
What are we going to do now?
Now it's up to us to land the plane, Ran-neechan.
I told you it'll be fine, Ran!
Don't they always say, "Ask three people
and you'll be wiser than a pearl"?
We'll pull through somehow!
Hey, hey, the saying goes...
The saying goes, "Wiser than Mañjuśrī", doesn't it?
Note: Manjusri is the bodhisattva of transcendent wisdom
Was that it?
Anyway, let's circle around the pier and take a closer look!
Help!
Please help me!
I'm not Kid—you've got the wrong guy!
Then why did you run?
Because I once stole a clock...
See, you are Kid!
Inspector Nakamori...
What?
What's that over there?
Isn't it obvious?
That's Kid.
Kid!?
Then, you are...
I told you, you've got the wrong guy!
Sonoko-neechan, how's it look?
Not good at all.
There's some lights here and there, but...
It's mostly pitch-black and I can't really see anything.
Damn!
Are you all right, Ran-neechan?
What's wrong, Ran?
I don't know...
Just that suddenly, I feel...
Conan-kun...
I can't do it after all.
No way!
You can do it, Ran-neechan!
This is bad...
It'll be too dangerous with her like this.
Sonoko-neechan, switch with me for a bit.
I'm going to the restroom.
The restroom?
I'll be right back, but...
Just in case the radio comes back on,
you should both put on your headsets!
Wait!
Geez, going to the restroom at a time like this?
This is why little brats—
Hello?
Hello!?
Ran.
Can you hear me, Ran?
Shin'ichi?
I'm calling from the control tower in Sapporo.
Looks like you guys are in a bit of a mess.
But everything will be all right.
Just stay calm, follow my instructions,
and you'll definitely land in one piece.
I'll protect you at all costs, so don't worry!
Are you listening, Ran?
Ran, answer him!
What is this?
You're acting all confident...
Do you even know?
That the lives of all the passengers are in my hands!?
Don't act so nonchalant about it!
When I really need you, you're never here...
All I get is a phone call!
Even when you finally make it back,
you're gone again in the next instant...
Every time...
Every single time...
No!
I don't want to hear it!
Shin'ichi-niichan said...
Wait for me, Ran.
Don't run away!
I'll be right back!
You always leave me behind, all alone...
He said that he wants you to wait for him until then.
What do you take me for!?
I...
I like you...
Shin'ichi.
Ran...
There's light!
I see light!
There are red lights moving around like an obi!
What?
So that's what's going on...
Damn it, that bastard Kid!
You're not getting away!
Hey!
Kid's headed toward the pier!
Got it.
Kid is now headed toward the pier.
A-Team, B-Team, take opposite sides and wrap around.
Align the patrol cars all along the edges of the pier!
C-Team, follow my lead!
We'll attack Kid from all sides!
Patrol cars coming, Gramps.
Something must have happened, I guess.
Looks like they're coming from this side, too.
Ran!
Begin landing preparations!
Those lights are probably the patrol cars that Kid lured there.
So that's why he jumped off...
It was in order to set up a runway for us
using the lights from the patrol cars!
That's my Kid-sama for you!
I knew it all along!
Ran, turn left once more.
Got it.
Kid!
Find Kid!
He has to be around here somewhere!
Look everywhere!
Is he there?
Negative!
How about over there?
I'll leave the rest to you, Great Detective.
All passengers, this plane will now make an emergency landing.
Please fasten your seat belts tightly and obey
all directions from the flight attendants.
Please remove all pens, eyeglasses, and high heeled
shoes and place them in your seatback pocket.
Lean forward, and place your head in between your legs.
Hey there, Ran.
At last, it's time to land.
What's the altitude and speed now?
Height: 700 feet, 140 knots.
All right, just keep maintaining a 3 degree descent.
Sonoko!
Pull down the gear lever and pull the flap lever!
Gear lever?
Flap?
The gear lever is that one.
And the flap is over there.
Got it.
Pull down the gear lever...
And pull the flap...
What?
What happened?
Shin'ichi, looks like we're out of fuel.
Got it.
There won't be any second chances...
It's one shot, do or die!
Inspector Megure.
It seems that plane...
It looks like it's flying this way, doesn't it?
Why?
Fifty.
Raise the nose, and pull the thrust lever all the way up!
Thirty.
Twenty.
All personnel evacuate!
Ten.
Bring the nose down!
Reverse thrust!
Stop!
Stop, stop!
Shin'ichi, there's a crane!
We're going to crash!
Damn!
The rudder!
Use your right foot to press the rudder!
It stopped!
We stopped!
All right!
Kudo-kun...
I guess it wasn't in your dictionary either, huh?
The word "impossible"...
You did it, Ran-neechan!
Ran-neechan?
Ran!
Hang in there!
Sonoko?
They both just passed out...
Well, it was inevitable...
Since I ended up having you guys take on a monumental task.
Good job, Ran.
Blood pressure and pulse are both normal.
You seem fine to me, but we'll take you to the hospital just to be sure.
Thank you very much.
Uhm...
What about Sonoko?
As for her, she doesn't appear to have any major injuries.
It's likely she just fainted due to shock.
I'm glad...
Then, if I could get your name and address here...
Sure.
And also...
Your bust, hips, and waist sizes as well...
That was a pretty flashy landing!
Well then, until we meet again.
I'll get your three sizes then.
Hello?
Ran, it's me.
Shin'ichi?
Hey...
Say, that call earlier wasn't from you, was it, Shin'ichi?
I knew it, that Shin'ichi earlier was Kid!
Huh?
I thought it was strange...
It was as if you were right there, seeing it all happen!
And then, in the middle of it, I heard Conan-kun go, "U-wa!".
Uh oh...
Huh?
But before that, Sonoko said Kid had already jumped out...
That's—I was really, secretly...
I got it!
The one who jumped was Kid's apprentice!
Oh?
Kid remained inside, disguised as someone on board.
Thank goodness it wasn't you, Shin'ichi.
I'm not thanking anyone.
Safe!
So close, but safe!
Safe from what?
It's a secret that only Kid and I know!
Tell me...
No way.
Why don't you try and deduce it?
You're a detective, aren't you?
How am I supposed to do that!?
Then, why don't you arrest Kid and ask him?
You little...