Hey, gal.
Did I make you wait?
This is a strange place to meet.
Can we talk in Japanese...
So that people around us won't listen?
You can't do that weird behavior of yours if you're attracting attention, right?
That's an awfully terrible way of putting it.
You're practically making it sound
as if I have my eyes set on you.
Am I wrong?
I feel that I've built up a
good relationship with you as a friend...
Cut the unnecessary chitchat.
Just give me your answer
about my proposition.
Yes or no?
Before I answer that...
Allow me to guess
what you just ordered.
Iced tea.
No, that's not it.
Champagne...?
No, wine.
Not red, but white.
A well-chilled Meursault.
Here is your Meursault.
H-How did you know?
I read your mind.
Um, excuse me...
I don't need it!
Ah, wait a second.
What do you want?!
My answer is no.
Thanks for the help.
First floor.
Hey, are you okay...?
W-What?!
Please be calm!
Follow our instructions...
Hey, wait!
What are you doing?
Preserving the scene of the crime.
Otherwise...
This will be trampled over, right?
Sir.
The one I called?
He's already inside.
Thanks.
Sorry to make you wait, Rishi!
Inspector Aidan!
Thank you for calling me.
The incident happened
at the shopping mall ahead.
This case could be a little tricky.
That Leon Lowe first discovered the body.
Oh...
Mr. Lowe!
You were his favorite student, right?
Could you ask him not to interfere too much?
I can't ask him that.
I'll go say hello!
Mr. Lowe!
Rishi! It has been a while.
Yes!
Let's speak in Japanese.
Sure.
I hear you're working
as a private reserve officer now?
You've sure
moved up in the world.
As my instructor, you pounded
criminal behavior psychology into my head...
So this is all thanks
to you, Leon-sensei.
Please stop referring
to me as your instructor.
I'm just a civilian now.
At any rate...
I never would have thought
the killer had planted bombs.
And the car that was bombed...
Belonged to the victim,
Sherilyn Tan-san.
She was an excellent
defense attorney, after all...
So I'm sure there were those
who held a grudge against her.
She could have also been
associating with someone dangerous...
Is the inspector there?!
Excuse me! Make way!
What's going on?
There's something on the elevator wall.
What?!
What is this?
Wha...?!
Absolutely not.
Please, can't you
just do this for me?!
No means no.
I'm begging you!
What's going on, you two?
He says he wants to use that one medicine
to go back to his original form again.
He just went through a terrible
experience during his school trip, too...
Even then, I managed to make it
through what happened one way or another.
So I'll be fine!
Please give me the medicine!
Absolutely not!
And just where
does he plan on going?
Singapore.
It's because of this, Professor!
That one guy's going to
be in this championship!
The one with
no losses in 400 matches!
Oh!
You mean Kyogoku Makoto-kun?
So Sonoko suggested
going to see that match.
And I was invited to go along
with old man Kogoro and Ran...
But I can't leave
the country looking like this.
That's right...
Because your passport is for Shinichi.
So please, Haibara!
Give. It. Up.
Oh, come on...
It might be best
to just give up this time...
Aw...
I really wanted to go.
Don't be so disappointed!
Alright, here's my first shot
at cheering you up!
What...?
You're doing this already?!
Tada!
Here comes the quiz!
What is the single,
most popular event in Singapore?
1. Singing the national anthem.
2. Celebrating the Lunar New Year.
3. Flying the national flag.
4. The fireworks display at Marina Bay.
What's with the getup?
The answer to that is simple.
Isn't it number 3,
"flying the national flag"?
Sin
gapore
After all, there's a "rope" that goes up "a pole".
Wow!
That's correct!
Should've expected
as much from you.
Alright then,
here's one more question!
No, that's enough.
What?
It really is lonesome
when the kids aren't here...
Man...
Damn you, Haibara.
Ran...?
Ah, Ran-neechan.
What are you... doing... here...?
Ran...-neechan...?
I've been waiting forever for you.
H-Huh?
What is this place?!
It's so big!
Is that Ran's voice?
Where in the world am I...?
Am I locked up in something?!
Damn it!
Oh?
There, now I can...
Whoa!
Huh?
What?
The... Merlion...?
What?!
I'm in Singapore?!
I'm high school detective, Kudo Shinichi.
While visiting an amusement park with my childhood friend and classmate, Mouri Ran...
I witnessed a man in black in the midst of a suspicious transaction.
While caught up in watching the deal...
I failed to notice his
partner sneaking up behind me.
That man forced me to take poison...
And when I came to...
My body had shrunk.
If those guys found out that
Kudo Shinichi was still alive...
They'd come after me again, and put those around me at risk.
At Professor Agasa's suggestion,
I decided to hide my true identity.
And the moment
Ran asked for my name...
I became Edogawa Conan.
In order to obtain
information on those guys...
I went to live with Ran,
whose father is a private detective.
As such, one of my
strongest rivals is this man:
Kaito Kid.
He's a phantom thief whose true identity remains unknown, a master of disguise...
And a cunning man who,
somehow, knows who I really am.
One of these days, I'm going
to catch him with my own two hands!
Kid's rival is Kyogoku Makoto.
Despite only being
a high school student...
He's a karate master who
boasts a 400-match win streak.
And for some reason, it seems
he's madly in love with Suzuki Sonoko...
Ran's classmate and daughter
of the Suzuki Financial Group.
What are you looking at?!
Hurry up and say
that thing you always do.
Even though I've shrunk,
my mind remains the same...
That of an unbeaten great detective.
There's always only one truth!
What happened to my hand...?
And I don't have any
of the professor's gadgets!
I know!
I'm sure Ran was here!
Wait for me, Ran-neechan!
Oh, Shinichi!
We're over here!
What?!
Sorry I kept you waiting.
Where did you go?!
We've been looking all over for you.
The old man was saying it's hot,
so I was guiding him over to a shady tree.
Wow, thanks!
Oh... Your dad just
never changes, does he?
Hey, Ran!
Can you go buy me some water?!
Guess I'll have to...
Hey, let's go together!
Come on, hurry!
A-Alright...
My, they've sure got some
good vibes going on between them.
That bastard...
I feel so revived now!
Oh?
What's that dangling
from your neck, Dad?
Huh?
I have my passport inside of this.
That way, I won't lose it
or have it stolen.
Good idea, don't you think?
Oh come on, Dad.
You don't need to do that,
because Singapore is completely safe.
Like hell it is!
Hey.
So you've woken up?
I knew it was you!
Wait, how did you
get out of the suitcase?
With this.
When I jammed it
with the tip of this pen...
It opened surprisingly easily,
even from the inside.
I thought a simple ballpoint pen
wouldn't be a problem...
But with you,
I guess I can't be too careful!
That's what I should
be saying to you, Kaito Kid!
Ah, there it is.
More importantly,
what's the big idea?!
Heh... The answer's
right there in front of you.
W-What?
Isn't that Sonoko's...?
At the end of the 19th century...
A pirate ship sank just off the coast of Singapore,
while thought to have been carrying...
A legendary hidden treasure.
It was the world's
finest quality blue sapphire...
Also known as the
"Fist of Blue Sapphire".
It's a big jewel that
Mr. Zhonhan Chen successfully salvaged last year.
Now that you mention Zhonhan Chen...
He's one of Singapore's most influential people.
That's right.
And this old guy sure loves martial arts.
He embedded the jewel
in the champion belt...
And decided to host
a karate tournament.
And the winner gets
the legendary jewel, huh?
That sure is a pastime for the rich.
Exactly.
So I had thought I could just take the jewel in the bustle of the tournament...
But I couldn't possibly enter
the country as Kid, now could I?
If you're only after the jewel...
You didn't need
to bring me along with you!
This is a bit of a special case.
Well, I'll explain the situation
to you gradually as we go along.
Why, you...!
What's that?!
Oh, Shinichi?
Uh oh.
She's calling for me.
Wait, Kid!
If you do anything to Ran,
I'll make you pay the price for it!
What...?
S-Sorry, but I can't
guarantee you that I won't.
Then I'll expose you for who
you really are right here, right now!
You'd better not do that.
You were only able to enter
the country because of this suitcase.
It's specially equipped so that even the X-rays
in the baggage check can't pass through it.
Inside of it, I put a portable
oxygen generator that lasts 12 hours.
And so your body wouldn't start hurting
even after being in there for so long...
I made sure it's a top-class product packed
with the highest-quality cushioning.
I'm sure you get what I mean.
Don't you, "great detective"?
If you don't have my help...
You won't be able to leave this country, since you don't have a passport.
Meaning you won't
be able to go back to Japan.
There you are, Shinichi!
Sheesh. I look away for a second,
and you've run off somewhere and disappeared...
Oh?
I-Isn't that the twerp?!
How did you get here?
Conan-kun?
Ah, he ran away!
He sure surprises you, doesn't he?
He's apparently
a child from around here.
What?! He is?!
Even so, this kid looks
so much like him...
You two let yourselves
be fooled way too easily!
Little boy...
What's your name?
Wait, do you know Japanese?
Um...
This boy's...
Arthur!
My name is Arthur Hirai!
Arthur Hirai?
My mom is Japanese, so...
I'm Suzuki Sonoko.
I'm Mouri Ran.
And over there is my dad,
Mouri Kogoro.
Nice to meet you.
Y-Yeah...
Nice to meet you, too.
Sorry, Ran.
I have to leave for a little while.
Oh, okay.
Hey, little boy...
Where are your mom and dad?
Uh, um...
They're traveling in Japan.
What?!
And they left you at home
all by yourself, Arthur-kun?
Yeah, but it's okay.
I'm used to it.
I see...
In that case, do you
want to come along with us?
Can I?
Yeah, of course you can.
Oh, right!
I'm going to go look
and see how Dad's doing.
S-Sure.
At any rate, he sure is late.
He could have at least texted me.
And I'm sure we were
supposed to meet up here, too...
Move it!
You're all in the way!
Out of the way!
What the hell're you looking at?!
Who're those guys?
The man in the
center is Nakatomi Reijiro.
Nakatomi...
Oh, the president
of Nakatomi Shipping.
He's known for being
a shrewd, talented man...
But there are some dark rumors
about him that never stop.
Hey, babe.
Did you come to Singapore all alone?
If you'd like, how
about coming with me—
I don't have time
for this right now.
Go away!
Are you really okay
with saying that to me?
If I felt like it, shoving a lone girl
like you into my car would be a cinch.
Sonoko!
Shinichi?!
Don't interfere.
Huh?
Hey!
She's with me.
What business do you have with her?
W-Who the hell are you?!
Makoto-san! You need
to at least check your messages!
I apologize.
I'm not very good with technology...
Oww...!
I'll get you for this!
I won't go so easy on you next time!
Makoto-san!
I was so scared!
I deeply apologize for being so late.
You're so cool, Mister!
I can do that, too!
Hiya! Hiya! Hiya!
Hey, karate boy!
How brave!
Ah!
Hey, come on!
Are you okay, Sonoko?
Oh?
Yeah!
Because Makoto-san protected me!
It's been quite a while, Kyogoku-san.
Yes, it has.
And who might you be?
Nice to meet you.
I'm Kudo Shinichi.
My name is Kyogoku Makoto.
Makoto-san,
is something wrong?
No, I just get the feeling this
isn't the first time I've met Kudo-kun.
N—
No, I'm sure you're
just imagining things!
Now, we've seen the Merlion,
so how about we start heading to the hotel?
Oh, about that...
Huh?
You can't participate
in the tournament anymore?!
We came all this way
to see your match, too...
I do apologize.
I had accepted a certain someone's invitation
and entered into today's tournament...
In other words, a sponsor?
Yes.
Sherilyn Tan, a woman
who works as an attorney...
Asked if I would participate, saying she would cover all my travel and lodging expenses.
But she suddenly passed away.
And today,
someone connected with her...
Told me to act like she had
never talked to me about anything.
No way!
Those who are said to be the strongest martial artists in Singapore will be participating in this tournament.
They are opponents I really wanted
to try fighting against, even just once...
All right!
I'll be your sponsor!
What?!
Just leave it to me!
That's the daughter of the
Suzuki Financial Group for you.
Everything's been taken care of!
Makoto-san, I was able to get you
reentered as an invited competitor!
Really, Sonoko-san?!
Yeah!
And I had them make
Makoto-san's hotel the same as ours.
So it's a double date!
It is, isn't it?
If you've talked and settled everything, how about we head back to the hotel, huh?
I wanna hurry and chug some beers!
Mouri-san!
Would you be Mouri Kogoro-san?
Huh? Yes...
My name is Rishi, a reserve officer.
It's an honor to meet you.
Uh-huh...
Same to you.
Um...
A reserve officer?
That's right!
As a specialist in
criminal behavior psychology...
I've received special permission
to assist with investigations.
Oh, is that so?
Actually...
I had been waiting here for you since
I heard you had entered the country, Mouri-san.
You were waiting for me?
Yes, because most tourists come here.
B-But why me?
There's actually a case I want
your help with, Detective Mouri.
Huh?
No way!
I'm in the middle
of my vacation right now!
Hey, hold up.
I think it'd be better
to go along with him here.
What? Why?
If you get along well
with a reserve officer...
You might be able to have him show you
some really good, cheap places to go.
Maybe even the casinos...
You catch my drift, right?
Uh, well...
You might just be right.
Very well!
I, the great detective Mouri Kogoro,
will make a special exception and assist you!
Oh, brother...
What an honor!
Detective Mouri, you're a hero
to my father's home country of Japan...
And I'm a huge fan of yours, too!
This actually arrived
at the home of a certain businessman.
Wow!
Kaito Kid!
Kaito Kid-sama!
I received a report that the Suzuki Group became the sponsor...
...for Kyogoku.
Can you beat him?
There is no need for concern.
No matter who...
I will put him down in one blow.
Good to know.
Come in.
Excuse me.
Mr. Ramanathan has arrived with someone...
...he'd like to introduce.
He's early.
Please bring him in to the lounge.
Understood.
So, how about Kid?
Apologies. We are still investigating.
Along with Sherilyn Tan...
There are issues with handling information.
I have a hunch who was behind it.
You take care of it, then.
Whoa!
This is incredible!
Settle down, Dad!
Oh! Even this suit of armor...
Is so arm-azing!
Whoa!
What?
Are you okay?
Y-Yeah...
Dad!
Get it together.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry about my dad.
So who exactly is Leon Lowe?
Leon-sensei was originally a noted criminal behavior psychologist...
Who arrested countless heinous killers
by cooperating with the police.
Wow...
So basically, he's the
great detective of Singapore?
He left the police force two years ago...
And is currently having much success
as the president of a security company.
I had also studied criminal behavior
psychology from Leon-sensei.
Oh, I see.
So the advance notice
came to this Leon guy?
No, I'll explain everything in order.
First, please look at this.
Kaito Kid is after a jewel
called the "Fist of Blue Sapphire".
It belongs to Mr. Zhonhan Chen,
a businessman.
Kid's advance notice came to him.
In that case, shouldn't we go
to this Zhonhan-Whatever guy's place...?
The jewel is actually being stored
underground, beneath this estate.
The jewel's here?
Yes.
That is the wish of its owner.
The safes here use an independently developed,
state-of-the-art security system...
Making them even safer
than a bank vault...
State-of-the-art, huh?
Sounds like even that darn Kid
will have a lot of trouble this time around.
You sure are one to talk.
What are you talking about?!
No matter how
state-of-the-art the safe is...
It'll be child's play
when it comes to Kid-sama!
Hey, Sonoko...
Don't you know about Kid-sama's
magnificent stealing techniques, Ran?
He could even steal the hearts
of every woman around the world—
Stop, Sonoko!
Huh?
Ah!
Well...
Except for me and Ran, that is.
Isn't that right, Ran?!
Y-Yes, of course.
You're not gonna
go unscathed if you're careless.
Oh, give me a break...
What a lovely inner garden!
It's okay.
It's a pleasure to meet all of you.
My name is Leon Lowe.
And this man is my bodyguard and head of security, Hezli Jamaluddin.
Please allow him to join us.
Mr. Kyogoku.
I was hoping to see you.
Thank you.
I do karate, too.
I always wanted to have a match with you.
I have my own gym in this match.
Oh!
So you're the famous detective,
Mouri Kogoro-san?
Can we train together tonight?
Oh, why thank you.
Sounds great.
Please let me join you.
I never expected to have so many people
in a foreign country know my name.
It's weird.
I don't feel anything.
What is it?
No way.
And you're the high school
detective, Kudo Shinichi-san.
Nice to meet you.
It seems you're more
of a magician than a detective.
Wha—?!
I can tell by your fingers.
They're slender and supple.
I'm a detective nonetheless,
so rather than physical strength...
I prefer challenges
that get my gears up here turning.
I see.
Oh, and I take it the young woman
over there is Suzuki Sonoko-san?
We can't let our guard
down around this guy.
You can't come in! Please wait!
That's okay. Don't bother.
Oh!
Mouri Kogoro-sensei!
My wife and I are huge fans of yours!
R-Right.
Can I take a photo with you?
A-A "photo"?
Oh, you mean a picture!
Sorry. He came in all of a sudden...
Okay, okay!
I'd be happy to!
It's all right.
I would like to show everyone our safe room.
That's good!
I'd love to come along!
And by all means, I'd love to have you see
the Fist of Blue Sapphire up close.
Beyond this door is the safe room,
my very own pride and joy.
This can only be opened
by a select few individuals.
The surface of the walls
are made of heat-resistant metal alloys...
So absolutely
no one can destroy them.
What?!
Plus, everything is completely
sealed off from the outside.
Sorry, sorry! Nothing!
And it's setup so that each piece of cargo
is periodically moved to a different location.
This safe is specially made,
packed with my own concepts...
Meaning it's the only one of
its kind anywhere in the world.
W-What's going on?!
Everyone, please step back a bit.
This jewel is called the "Fist of Blue Sapphire",
and is said to be the emblem of the king of all pirates.
It's a huge cultural treasure.
Can you see it, Arthur-kun?
Yep! Thanks!
I see.
As long as it's here, I'm sure
even Kid can't meddle with it.
Things won't work out that way.
While the karate tournament
that starts tomorrow is being held...
It's been decided that the belt
will be on display at the stadium.
In other words, during
the time of the tournament...
It will be kept safely
in one room of the stadium.
It will be placed under strict security measures, but they're still lacking in comparison to here.
I see.
But there's also security for the stadium...
Yes. We shall guard it at any cost!
If anything happens to the Fist...
You will be paying a hefty compensation fee.
You said that the security measures
are lacking in comparison to here...
But that means you believe Kid is waiting
until the sapphire is moved to the stadium, correct?
Precisely.
It would be far too risky
for him to come after it here.
It sure would be.
So while I can't do much, please allow me
to assist with guarding the jewel.
Oh, thank you.
This is a breeze!
Whoa!
Thanks for the fingerprints!
Isn't this... too easy?
I've been waiting for you.
You making it all the way in here is just what I had expected from you, Kaito Kid.
You sure are confident in yourself.
I'm sorry, but I cannot afford
to have you take the jewel.
Because I don't want to pay Zhonhan Chen
his compensation fee and such.
Stealing treasures like that is my job.
And the harder something is to steal...
The more I get fired up!
It's over.
I hope you like the taste of Singaporean water.
I never thought
he'd use a Taser on me!
Kid!
Is this seriously happening?!
What the...?!
What happened?
It's Kid!
Don't worry. I'm always...
Those at the top always act
while considering the worst possible outcome!
...one step ahead.
I've gotta get out of here, and quickly!
There he is!
What a punch!
I'd be in deep trouble
if I hadn't flown backwards!
You're trespassing
on private property, aren't you?
Wait, what are you doing here?
I was invited to come here
if I wanted to do some training.
I never would have expected
I could have a match with you here.
No, no, no...
I don't want to have one!
Don't waste your breath!
Brace yourself for this!
A soccer ball...?
Where in the world did it come from?
Thanks, detective!
This thing is awesome!
Now I can fly freely,
even without wind.
I've gotta be thankful for Jii-chan.
But...
Why would he go that far?
You saved me back there!
Looks like I was right
to return your equipment, just in case.
It's not like I wanted
to save you, though.
More importantly,
isn't it about time you told me?!
What's the real reason
you brought me here?!
Whoa!
Leon had been searching
for the Fist of Blue Sapphire for years.
But when he was just
one step away from recovering it...
Zhonhan Chen beat him to it.
Apparently, someone leaked
the location of the sunken ship to him.
The most suspicious one is Sherilyn Tan.
She had worked as a legal advisor
for Leon's firm for some time...
But the relationship
between the two soured.
According to rumor, the reason
she became Kyogoku's sponsor...
To hinder Jamaluddin's victory.
Basically, she wanted to
obstruct Leon from obtaining the jewel.
If that's true...
Then the rumors that the location of the
sunken ship was leaked also have a ring of truth to them.
And then Sherilyn Tan was killed.
If we assume the rumors
about the leak are true...
That would mean Leon
had a motive to kill Sherilyn.
What do the police think?
Unfortunately, Leon was
removed from the suspect list.
Why?
Because there's
a much more likely suspect!
A suspect?!
The police haven't made this public...
But a card was left at
the scene of Sherilyn Tan's murder.
An advance notice from me.
So that's it.
But...
Why do I have to see such amazing scenery with this guy, of all people?!
If I'm going to see it with someone,
I wish it was with...
It's time for you to go back
to being Arthur Hirai.
By the way, I'm sure Arthur is
from Sir Arthur Conan Doyle...
But what's this "Hirai"?
Oh, well...
I got it from Edogawa Ranpo's
real name, Hirai Taro.
Oh, I get it.
But more importantly,
this is clearly a trap!
I know.
That's why I brought
you along, great detective.
Aren't you good
with this kind of thing?
I understand your reasons now,
though I don't like how you went about doing it.
I, Kid-sama...
Can't just keep quiet
about this, now can I?
You sure were slow.
I've been waiting for you all this time.
Sorry, sorry.
Hey, look at this.
This nightscape is so beautiful.
Don't you think it's romantic?
Wha—?
Don't be so bashful.
The two of us are dating, aren't we?
Y-Yeah...
What?! You are?!
Damn it...
Hasn't Ran even
realized he's a fake?!
Oh, but if she did realize that,
I wouldn't be able to go back to Japan...!
When it comes to Singapore,
it's gotta be the Singapore Sling!
Gimme another glass!
Mouri-san?
Huh?
A-And you are...?
Do you mind if I sit here?
N-N-Not at all, not at all.
Let's drink together.
Actually, I...
Oh?
Ah!
Uh-oh...
This is terrible!
What have I done?!
I'm so sorry!
No, no... It's fine.
Don't worry about it.
Mr. Mouri... A call for you.
Huh? "Call"?
It seems there's a
phone call for you, Mouri-san.
For me?
Who could it be?
Mouri-san.
Oh?
There's something I really
want to talk with you about!
Come here tomorrow!
Huh?!
Jeez...
Huh...
What the...?!
They hung up on me!
Time to start drinking again!
Who do you think will win?
Mr. Kyogoku!
Because he's never lost!
Wow, he hasn't?
That's the first I've heard about that.
So his considerable effort done
with proper positioning and direction...
Must really be bearing fruit.
Did you two understand that?
Yep!
Who will get
the Fist of Blue Sapphire?
That was so fast!
This Jamaluddin guy
seems ridiculously strong.
He has both speed and technique combined with heavyweight-class power.
He seems to be
quite a formidable foe.
I expected as much from the
captain of the Teitan High karate club!
You notice things
that most people wouldn't.
Hey...
If the jewel goes to Kyogoku-san...
Doesn't that mean you
won't be able to get to it anymore?
Right.
Because I want to be
around him as little as possible.
Ah, Makoto-san's here!
Come on!
You all cheer him on, too!
Wait, why'd you bring
the twerp here with you?
He's gotten pretty attached
to me, for some reason.
Bow to each other!
Oh?
Begin!
That's just scary...
Way to go!
You're so cool,
Makoto-san!
Oh, how I want to
go see him right now!
Oh?
It's from Dad.
Like I've been telling you,
I am not anyone suspicious!
Dad!
What happened?
Ran!
Please explain to these guys for me!
I've pulled out everything
I have that's made of metal.
But even so...
No entry!
Aren't I fine now?!
No!
Damn it!
I'll never be able to get in at this rate!
Mouri-san,
is everything okay?!
Ah, Rishi-san!
He's a staff member. Please let him in.
Yes, sir.
Thank you, Mr. Rishi!
I'm glad I was able
to meet up with you.
After the belt was unveiled
during the opening ceremony...
It's now being stored
in an underground safe.
If you'd like,
I could show you to it later.
But all things considered,
where have you been up until now?
U-Uh, well...
I was doing some patrolling.
Are you sure you didn't just
oversleep because of a hangover?
The password
changes every ten minutes.
It's controlled by a computer,
which informs us via email.
The only ones who get this
are Inspector Aidan and myself...
As well as Leon-sensei, who manages
the safe, making a total of three.
Wow, this room has nothing in it.
Not at all.
There's weight sensors in the floor,
and security cameras in the ceiling...
And then there's officers stationed
all around the stadium, surrounding it.
Oh! With this, I'm sure even
that phantom thief can't do a thing.
Mouri-san,
smoking is forbidden here.
Ah, sorry about that.
Huh?
I was so hammered,
I completely forgot about this.
She handed me this at the bar last night,
saying she needed to talk about something.
That's the business
card of Leon's secretary.
What?! It is?
To tell you the truth,
I was drunk and don't really remember.
How did you know?
The mark of Leon-san's company is on it.
Oh...
Its mark, huh?
"3 PM."
"Meet me at the back
of National Stadium gate 3."
That's what written here.
Oh...
It also says, "Tell no one."
I see.
So it's at 3 PM, huh?
It's almost 3!
M-Mouri-san!
Making a lady wait
is shameful for a man!
That was truly a fine match.
I'll start looking forward
to tomorrow's semifinals.
Thank you very much.
Your strength is extraordinary.
So how about it?
Do you have any desire
to be my bodyguard?
Please excuse me.
Now, wait a minute.
I was just joking now, of course!
But there actually
is one thing I want to ask you.
So tell me...
For what reason
do you have your fist?
There's something out there
for which you pursue strength.
What is it, exactly,
that spurs you onward?
So you can't answer?
An imperfect fist that
has no purpose is dangerous.
Not only to yourself...
But it will lead the people around you
to misfortune and unhappiness.
The people around me?
Misfortune and unhappiness?
Yes.
Like the person
you love, for example.
Even you have
someone like that, don't you?
Your fist is dangerous,
and it may hurt the person you love.
And what will
you do if that happens?
I'm looking forward
to tomorrow's match.
Do you still need something?
Good job out there.
Sonoko-san.
Oh, you...
You just wouldn't come,
so we came to see you.
I apologize for making you wait.
So let's all go get some lunch!
There's this place
I really want to go...
Sorry, Sonoko.
You two can go eat without me.
What? Why?
I'm really sorry!
But since Shinichi's guarding the jewel,
it doesn't look like he can get away from here.
I see...
Then I guess there's
nothing you can do about that.
How about the
two of us go, Makoto-san?
Okay.
See you later, Ran.
Please excuse us
for leaving ahead of you.
I want you to eat
a lot now, Makoto-san!
Thank you so much.
Now, be alert and look everywhere!
If you see anything unusual, report it.
And act immediately!
And...
Are you okay?
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry, too.
Inspector Aidan!
Sorry, I couldn't help but notice.
I-I'm sorry... What...?
There you go!
Keep up the good work.
Yes, ma'am!
Everything okay with the safe?
Yes, sir. Everything is alright.
Excuse me! I'm so sorry.
What's the matter?
Inspector Aidan is calling you to come quick!
B-But...
I'll look after this place.
O-Okay.
We'll be back soon. Thank you.
Now...
I'll be taking the treasure!
I'll be taking this!
Huh? Did this get
caught on something?
Wha—?
A dead body?!
And even worse...
It's Rachel's?!
This is bad!
I've gotta get out of here, and quick!
Oh?
Are those some type of letters?
Crap!
Stop right there!
Drop the gun, now!
Kid, you're under arrest!
What?
Honestly...
How long is Rachel-san
going to make us wait?
Let's wait ten more minutes—
Huh?
W-What's going on?!
It might be Kid!
Hey, wait!
He's here!
Whoa!
This is really bad!
But I'll have this in the bag
if I can get out of the grounds!
There were this many of them?!
Hey, wait!
Damn!
Go! Arrest him at any cost!
Yes, sir!
Oh, come on...
Is it really okay to let him leave?
There you are, Mouri-san!
I've been looking for you!
Man, this sure turned
into a huge problem.
Who would have thought Kid
would appear in broad daylight like this?
But rest assured.
I, the great detective Mouri Kogoro,
will immediately begin tracking him down—
This isn't the time for that!
Something terrible has happened!
Please come to
the safe room right now!
Huh?
Look!
There's a giant bird in the sky!
Now that I've made it this far...
W-What is this...?!
The victim is Leon-sensei's
secretary, Rachel-san.
Rachel-san?
I see...
Did you check the security cameras?
They were no help.
They were hacked so that a video showing
no one present would be sent over and over.
So, have you marked
someone as the killer?
Of course we have.
And we're currently pursuing him
to the best of our ability.
"Currently pursuing him?"
You don't mean...
Make no mistake.
Kaito Kid is the killer!
In any case, not disabling the alarm system
beforehand was a mistake on your part, Kid.
Hey, you know...
If that was true, then at the time...
Shouldn't Rachel-san have
been coming to the stadium...
For her appointment
with this nice man?
Why was she in the safe room?
Oh?
Come to think of it, that's true.
According to the officers
who were in front of the safe room...
It seems she came to tell them
that Inspector Aidan needed them.
Perhaps it seemed urgent
and they prioritized that?
After all, that big disturbance
happened right afterwards...
But I've never heard
of Kid being a murderer.
Ah, hey!
Don't just barge in!
Jeez.
There he goes again!
Hey, there's these
bloody letters here...
Hey!
Brats have to get out!
Yeah.
Take a look at this.
I see.
You've been completely set up,
haven't you, Kid?
B-Bring it on.
T-This has gotten...
pretty interesting, hasn't it...?
Just as I would expect of something
you selected, Sonoko-san...
Both the chicken rice and
watermelon juice were very delicious.
I know, right?!
Is there something else?
W-Well, now that our stomachs are full...
There is one place
I'd like to go, Makoto-san...
I'll accompany you,
no matter where it is.
This looks bad!
Hey, girl!
What are you going to do about this?
Aren't you the
one who ran into me?!
Huh? I don't know what you mean!
C'mere!
Shit!
He may have
other companions lurking.
Sonoko-san,
please keep close to me.
O-Okay!
Your fist is dangerous,
and it may hurt the person you love.
Sonoko-san!
I found it...
Please help me!
Sonoko-san!
Is he alright?
I'm calling for an ambulance.
Is she a foreigner...?
Sonoko-san!
Sonoko-san.
Sonoko-san! Sonoko-san!
How did they say
her injuries are doing?
He said they're
not life threatening.
She's sleeping now, so they're going to admit her for the night...
And then it seems
they'll examine her tomorrow.
I'm so glad.
But even so,
what a vicious hit and run...
It's my fault.
It's my fault that Sonoko-san...
Sorry to have kept you waiting!
My apologies for being late!
No problem.
Good work out there.
How's the investigation going?
Yes, well...
It took place in a back alley
where not many people pass through...
So there aren't any witnesses.
To be more accurate,
there were people there...
But they were taken by surprise
when the patrol car was stolen, and fainted.
Ah!
I hope I haven't disturbed you.
Leon-sensei?
What are you doing here?
I heard about the accident
and flew over here.
Sonoko's still sleeping...
In that case, could I have
you give her these for me?
Thank you.
It seems my worry
was right on the mark.
The god of fighting is testing you.
He's saying that you do not yet have the
mind, body, and spirit required to wield your fist.
I know.
I'll give you a charm.
It's kind of like
a good luck charm bracelet.
If this breaks...
It's a sign of the god's acknowledgment that
you've come to have the proper mind, body, and spirit.
But if you wield your fist
before this breaks...
You know what
will happen, don't you?
Oww...
You took some
pretty heavy damage.
A scratch like this is nothing.
Jeez...
For them to come shooting
at me without restraint...
I was really outwitted this time.
They're making Rachel-san's
murder out to be your doing.
It's all a trap intended
to frame you for the crimes.
It's almost like magic.
Even though I'm not there...
To the audience watching, I certainly appear to be a murderer who may have been there.
So basically, you can start to see how the trick is done if you change how you look at it?
Yeah...
A magician makes a person think as though there may be something in their clenched fist...
And a detective correctly guesses what's in their fist before it opens, right?
So correctly guess
what it is, great detective...
The contents of the mysterious
clenched fist known as "murder".
Jeez...
Ah...
Haven't you gone home yet, kid?
Hey, can I spend the night
with you tonight?
What...
At my house?
I'd be all by myself,
even if I went home.
And I'm scared from
all the stuff that just happened...
But if I could tell them
I was with you, Rishi-san...
I'm sure my mom and dad
would be relieved, too!
After all, spending two consecutive nights in
the same room as that guy would be the worst.
Oh, wow!
Did you get all of these
from your dad, Rishi-san?
That's right.
You see, my father's an oceanographer.
Sadly, he passed away five years ago...
But over the course of his research,
he found fossils and such that had sank into the ocean.
You're proud
of your dad, aren't you?
Yeah!
Well, I still have
some work left to do...
So you go to sleep
ahead of me, Arthur-kun.
Okay!
Oh...
Hey, Rishi-san.
What are the red marks on this map?
Ah, they show the places
where ships were attacked by pirates.
There are pirates, even nowadays?!
There sure are!
Long ago, there were lots
of them close to Singapore.
But I'm more worried
about this murder case than pirates now.
And then there's
Kaito Kid on top of it all.
I borrowed some materials
from Assistant Inspector Aidan...
But I guess I'll be
pulling an all-nighter tonight.
I feel bad for
doing this to Rishi-san...
But I'll have him get a good nap.
Hey, what's that?
I didn't know you
had something like that.
Sonoko-san!
You came to?!
Actually,
I did quite some time ago.
I'm really so glad.
Hey, is that some
kind of good luck charm?
Yeah...
It's something like that.
No, you can't!
Please take it easy and rest.
I'm not the least bit sleepy.
This is so boring, even after
we came all the way to Singapore.
It'll be bad for your body
if you try to do too much.
So please take things
easy and rest tonight.
You know, I've been wanting
to ask you this for a while...
But why don't you ever take off
the band-aid by your left eyebrow?
What?
N-No...
This is nothing, really.
Huh...?
I thought we were not supposed to meet...
...until everything was done?
You bragged your plan was perfect...
But are you totally sure?
You look tough, but you're actually a coward.
Now, watch your mouth...
I always keep promises.
I do.
If you trick me,
I'll trick you back.
That's how I roll.
We have an announcement to make.
In the second semifinals match...
Makoto Kyogoku has withdrawn...
And Tan Lee will proceed to the finals!
Damn it!
I didn't ask for this!
You withdrew from the tournament?!
Why?
Is it because of me?
There's a chance that the gang who
attacked us could come to attack us again...
So I couldn't possibly
leave your side, Sonoko-san.
So it really is
because of me, isn't it?
Go and be in the tournament!
Isn't there an opponent
you want to fight against?!
Yes.
But since I couldn't even
protect you, Sonoko-san...
It feels like I still lack something.
You sure are
lacking in something.
All you do is hide things
from me, Makoto-san!
Hide things?
You won't tell me about the bracelet or the band-aid, will you?
No...
They're really, um...
Get out.
What?
I don't want to be protected by a man who's full of lies like that!
You know, I was
really worried yesterday.
I could never get in touch with you.
Sorry, sorry.
I just got so absorbed
in chasing after Kid...
But it's just what one would expect
of the magician under the moonlight.
Catching him would be impossible even for me, Kudo Shinichi—
Oh, Arthur-kun.
Hello!
Is your friend,
Sonoko-oneesan, okay?
Yeah!
I just dropped
by the hospital earlier...
And the results of the examination
showed that there's no problems.
It looks like she'll be released from the hospital
and go back to the hotel this afternoon.
Wow, that's great.
Thanks for worrying about her.
Let's head back to the hotel soon.
I'd like to consolidate
our luggage for going home.
Are you okay with leaving
Sonoko-oneesan and her guy friend alone?
Yeah...
I thought I'd just
leave them be for a while.
It looks like those two were
having some sort of disagreement...
And Kyogoku-san even
withdrew from the tournament.
Wait, Shinichi?
So, great detective, were you
able to gather anything last night?
Based on the investigation reports
I saw at Rishi-san's house, it went like this...
According to witness testimony...
Sherilyn-san wasn't stabbed in the
shopping mall where she collapsed...
But may have been
in the elevator of Tower 3.
Why would someone go out of
their way to do it in the elevator?
If things didn't work out,
they'd be no place to run to, would there?
With a store-bought knife
still lodged in her back...
She proceeded to move
to the shopping mall.
And then immediately
after she collapsed...
Her car exploded
in the underground parking garage...
Resulting in a power outage
across the entire hotel.
And so, the video feeds from
all the hotel security cameras were cut?
What bothers me is that Leon
was at the scene of the crime.
He had arranged a room for himself,
and another for Sherilyn-san.
But when she was killed...
A large number of witnesses saw
he had been riding a different elevator.
So because his
alibi had been verified...
He was excluded
from the line of investigation?
Precisely.
Come to think of it,
why did Leon have a suitcase?
Ah, the police examined
the inside of it, of course...
But it was empty.
He had only sent the suitcase to
be repaired, and then came to pick it up.
And it was verified that a store
near the hotel had received his request.
So he has a perfect alibi, huh?
There's one more thing...
This.
Why was this left behind
at the scene of the crime?
Where was the need
to drag me into this?
And it even went as far as to have clotted blood smeared on it.
That being the case...
They're an attempt to place
the crime of killing Rachel-san onto you.
The knife used as the murder weapon was
the same as the one used when killing Sherilyn-san.
Rachel-san had been put inside
the pedestal before I entered the safe room.
But to enter the room...
One has to get past the security officers and countless security systems.
Someone who can slip past the eyes of the security and get in without touching the sensors...
It's not me.
Just as I thought,
Leon Lowe is the most suspicious.
Leon, being the
manager of the safe room...
Would be completely familiar
with the security systems in place.
Furthermore, the belt had been
brought to the stadium yesterday morning.
And Rachel-san has been confirmed
to have been alive up until two nights ago.
In other words, it's very likely that the crime took place that night before the belt was moved.
But for what reason?
Why would he need
to kill his own secretary?
Perhaps that could be his motive.
Rachel-san had been trying
to tell the old man something.
And those bloody letters
are a clue that she left behind.
"She"...
That refers to
another woman, but who?
It's no use.
It feels like something
monumental is going to happen...
But my thoughts just
won't come together.
Even the great detective's
throwing his hands up?
Then let's take a break
for the time being.
Incidentally, there's something
in one of my fists, and—
There's a coconut water in your left fist.
That's correct!
How'd you know?
Weren't you just buying it?
Ah, so you were watching me?
Magic, huh?
A magician makes a person think as though there may be something in their clenched fist...
And a detective correctly guesses what's in their fist before it opens, right?
Ah!
I've got it.
Come to think of it, is Sonoko-ojosama
fighting with that one karate guy?
That's what I heard.
Well, I suppose getting caught in
a scuffle as well as a traffic accident...
Would make one feel
pretty insecure and uneasy.
So that's it.
Huh?
He caused Sonoko to get hurt,
and shook Makoto-san up emotionally.
After all, Makoto-san is the
biggest obstacle to having Jamaluddin win.
I get it.
So you're saying that Leon
arranged to have that accident happen?
And just as he planned,
Makoto-san withdrew from the tournament.
And now Jamaluddin will most
certainly take the champion belt.
In other words, it'll be passed into the hands of his employer, Leon.
Along with the
Fist of Blue Sapphire.
But why is Leon so fixated
on the Fist of Blue Sapphire?
I've obtained something
that seems like it'd be a hint to that.
This is a man Leon
had been meeting at dawn.
Couldn't we determine
this man's identity?
Well, it's not impossible...
Tag, you're it!
Now listen here, you!
You suddenly called the professor and said that on second thought you'd go to Hokkaido, then hung up.
So what are you doing right now?!
Sorry, Haibara.
I've had a bunch of stuff to deal with here, too...
Quiet down a little, you guys!
Okay...
Honestly.
You're probably just wrapped up in a case somewhere, aren't you?
Actually, that's exactly it.
What?!
I just sent you a data file
containing a picture that Kid took.
Kid?!
You just said "Kid"...
No way!
Kaito Kid showed up?!
You're on the phone
with Conan-kun, correct?
Conan-kun said he's
in Hokkaido right now?
What would Kid want to steal there?
A wood carving
of a bear or something?
Maybe it's some Sapporo Ramen?
He wouldn't steal something like that.
Ai-chan!
Please let me talk to him!
Me too—
Sorry.
The kids are over here to play right now...
Ah, okay.
I'll tell you all the
details after I've come back...
But for now, I'd like you to look into
the identity of the man in that picture.
Sure, sure. I got it.
So, are you really alright?
Yeah, somehow.
I'm sure there's
no point in me telling you this...
But don't do anything rash.
Thank you.
We'll be fine now.
So, great detective,
what are you going to do now?
I'm going to watch
and see how things play out.
I'll see what moves Leon makes after
he's gotten his hands on the Fist of Blue Sapphire.
But before that comes the old man.
What...
Hey, wait!
The winner of the Zhonhan Cup is...
Jamaluddin!!!
So, what do you think of my city plan?
We cannot accept your proposal.
Why?
You lose nothing with this plan.
It also benefits the country.
It's too hasty.
If you proceed with this much development...
Some may be forced out of their homes.
We can give them another place!
My plan is perfect!
You are too young.
Learn some more, and come back.
Old fool...
Your era is now at an end.
I will build a new city.
Hands in the air!
O-Okay, okay...
You and I are very much
bound together by fate.
Once this plan has succeeded,
we'll both be partners.
I'm counting on you.
I'm awfully indebted to you.
I was suspected of theft, and it looked like the police were going to take me away...
But it was you saving me
that started it all.
And there's been so
many other times since then.
It's because I knew you
were the Nakatomi Reijiro...
Son of Nakatomi Juzo, who had been called the king of Japan's shipping industry.
Don't mention my dad's name.
Ah...
My apologies.
At any rate,
everything will change tonight.
How about we watch the moment
that happens from nearby?
Come, let's go together...
So we can be witnesses to the start
of what will go down in Singaporean history!
Huh?
Sorry about this, old man!
What?
W-What is this, all of a sudden?!
No, stop it! You perv!
Ah, this is it!
Nakatomi?
"Nakatomi",
as in Nakatomi Shipping?!
Probably.
I'll be borrowing this, old man!
Did that brat
just call me old man?
Why did you suddenly leave Japan?
For a vacation.
A vacation.
You also went to Singapore
five years ago, correct?
Yeah, and I've been there ever since.
What about it?!
Regarding President Nakatomi...
So he's that guy
who was in the Merlion Plaza.
Though he got taken out
by that karate guy.
Oh, Haibara?
Did you find out who that man is?
Yeah...
I managed, somehow.
His name is Eugene Lim.
And shockingly, he's a pirate.
A pirate?!
There are recent eyewitness reports
regarding him in Singapore.
I knew you could do it, Haibara.
I can really count on you.
The fact that you're flattering me...
Must mean you still have
something you want me to look into?
Y-Yeah...
Have you heard the name
Nakatomi Reijiro before?
The one from Nakatomi Shipping.
Yeah, I know it.
I want to know the status of the ships
owned by the Nakatomi Shipping company.
Just the ships in the area
around Singapore is fine.
There are two cargo ships and
one oil tanker in the vicinity of Singapore.
What I'm a little curious about is
that the oil tanker is deviating from its planned route.
That's it!
Send me the data on that oil tanker!
Okay.
I'll call you again.
Yes, please.
What this about a oil tanker?
It's the letters spelling "she"
that Rachel left behind.
The word "she"
can also refer to a ship.
Is what you told me
on the phone true?
How could everything that's happening
now be part of Leon-sensei's plot?
I want you to explain
so that I can understand, too.
It all started with the blue sapphire
that Zhonhan Chen located.
"The Fist of Blue Sapphire."
He embedded that into the
belt for the karate tournament...
And decided to
present it to the champion.
Leon-san forced Jamaluddin-san
to participate so he could obtain the jewel.
However, some unexpected
interference entered the picture.
Kyogoku Makoto, a man who's gone undefeated in 400 karate matches, entered the tournament.
And Sherilyn Tan-san, who was later killed,
was the one who invited him.
Even if that was the motive,
Leon-sensei has an alibi.
He had been riding in a
different elevator when she was stabbed.
Here's what really happened.
After meeting Leon by the pool...
She took the elevator
to go back to her room.
But the room in she had been
staying in was on the 16th floor of Tower 3.
Due to the structure of the hotel...
She couldn't go back without transferring
to a different elevator on the 34th floor.
While she was on her
way back to her room...
She was forcibly taken
to a different room...
By Secretary Rachel.
No way...
Rachel was an accomplice?!
The room Leon reserved that day solely
to enter the poolside restaurant for guests...
Was on the 34th floor.
Leon came down to that room, and
it was there that he stabbed and killed Sherilyn-san...
Then placed her body in his suitcase.
Afterwards, Rachel and Leon
each took separate elevators...
And for their trick, she probably utilized the type of faux penknife often used in magic.
However, the blood
was Sherilyn-san's own.
First floor.
Pretending to have
been stabbed, Rachel collapsed.
And immediately afterwards...
This all went unbeknownst to people in the midst
of the power outage caused by the explosions.
T-That can't be...
Knowing of Leon's true plan...
Rachel came to Detective Mouri out of fear, ready to open up to him about everything.
And Leon realized that.
The Rachel-san who came
to the safe room was Kid in disguise.
Kid was used in Leon-san's plan, too.
The real Rachel-san
had already been killed...
And stuffed inside the pedestal.
Foreseeing that Kid would
come disguised as Rachel-san...
He did this to create an alibi for himself,
as well as make it look as if it were Kid's doing.
But why would he do such a thing...?
Then if it were you, Rishi-san, who would
you think it'd be safe to disguise yourself as?
Uh, well...
No matter how
well I disguised myself...
It'd all be meaningless
if the real person suddenly showed up.
So it'd be fine if you knew the time
and place the person would be at in advance, right?
I get it!
Rachel had been waiting
for Mouri-san at 3 PM...
And so...
That's right.
Kid disguised himself as someone
unlikely to come to the safe room...
And by doing so,
he fell right into Leon-san's trap.
Please tell me.
What is my instructor trying to do?!
It's all for a foolish plan.
Leon having been in contact with
Eugene Lim, the leader of a fleet of pirates...
The word "she" having been left behind
in the pedestal at the scene of Rachel's murder...
And then there's the object Rachel secretly left with Detective Mouri...
One of Nakatomi Shipping's tokens.
All those things point towards a ship.
What does that
have to do with anything...?
Rishi-san.
I had an older detective guy
from Tokyo send me this.
It's an analysis of the routes that ships
owned by Nakatomi in this area are taking.
One oil tanker is deviating
greatly from its planned route.
If it continues along this path,
it'll end up at Marina Bay.
Leon-san plans on using the pirates
to make the oil tanker crash into the city!
First of all, why would my
instructor need to do that?
What reason would he have?!
I don't know what Leon-san will say...
But if it's to destroy
this city and then rebuild it...
Then we at least know for sure that it
involves a vast amount of money moving around.
The reason Leon was so fixated
on the Fist of Blue Sapphire...
Is because he needed it as collateral
to manipulate the pirates into doing as he pleases.
B-But...
The pirates are scattered all over the place
to avoid the eyes of the police.
How did he contact them?
With the Merlion.
Wasn't there an incident where
the Merlion started spewing red water?
News of it was broadcast worldwide,
so I'm sure it also caught the attention of the pirates.
That must have been the signal
to start carrying out the plan.
But right now, we need to...
Right.
If we don't hurry, it'll be too late.
You can say that,
but there's nothing I can do on my own...
And we'll need more proof
to put the police into action.
If we do that,
we won't make it in time!
Isn't there any other way?
I know.
Let's ask Mr. Zhonhan Chen for advice.
He holds a lot of influence
over the military and the police.
I'm sure he'll lend us a hand!
Rishi-san,
there's just one more thing.
What is it?
If the oil tanker crashed into
the city the way he planned...
Where do you think Leon-san
would be at the time?
Well, let's see...
My instructor is a very cautious person...
So he'd probably observe
from somewhere far away.
There's a chance he may
not even be in the country.
Okay, I've got to hurry!
Alright, thanks.
Oh, come on...
Where could Dad be?
The show's going to start.
And Shinichi's still off somewhere...
Man, how did I get
caught up in this case?
Was Leon really the one who left my card
at the scene of Sherilyn-san's murder?
No.
Finding the card that
had been stuck to the elevator...
Happened long after
examination of the scene had begun.
Why do you think that is?
Oh...
It's the latest analysis
of the oil tanker's trajectory.
Huh?!
W-What?!
This is really bad!
At this rate, the oil tanker
will crash right into the hotel!
Ran...
Please pick up the phone!
It's heading this way!
Hey, Ran!
Are you enjoying yourself?
Dad!
Where are you right now?!
Huh?
I dunno what it is,
but I can see some really big ship.
Hey...
Wait a minute, Dad...
Don't tell me you're
at the top of the hotel?!
Hello? Hello?!
Can we make it?
I think so.
Sonoko-san! Sonoko-san!
What?
It seems something
has happened outside.
I thought it might be best
to leave the hotel.
Yes?
Okay, I understand.
Who was that from?
Someone from the police.
He said I may be targeted again
if I carelessly went outside...
So I should standby
and wait in my room.
It looks like someone
is coming to escort me.
B-But...
I'll be fine because I'm here.
I understand.
This is bad...
We can't get close to
the hotel with this crowd of people!
This is do-or-die,
so I guess I'll have to do this!
Whoa, it's Kid!
It's Kid! Kid's here!
With this, it's like
it's reserved just for us!
H-Huh?
W-What's the problem?!
What?
T-The Sleeping Kogoro!
I really don't know, just about him...
It's no good.
It won't go through.
Whoa, crap!
Oh, come on...
Where are you, Dad?!
Look!
This city will be born again!
With my hands!
Why... are you...?
W-Wait!
I'm surprised.
I never thought you'd
be able to make it this far.
Even I couldn't
read this far into you.
Rishi.
But now that it's come to this,
I'll acknowledge your integrity.
That's right.
This is all my plan.
Why don't we talk this over a bit?
So put that
dangerous thing away.
Aren't you the one who's
misunderstanding something, Leon-sensei?
Freeze!
There's no one here...
Let's stop the ship now.
The oil tanker stopped, Kid!
Let's leave this to the police!
Yeah.
The tanker!
What happened...?
I'll do whatever you say...
Just please don't shoot me!
Ah, help me...!
Please don't kill me!
Rishi-kun...
I never thought you'd actually shoot.
Jamaluddin!
Wait!
Jamaluddin, what are you thinking?!
The only reason I worked for you...
Was to fight against Kyogoku.
I have no such reason anymore.
What?!
Leon-sensei...
Pardon my rudeness,
but have your skills gotten a little rusty?
You're not the one
who was putting the world in motion...
I was.
You couldn't possibly have...
W-Wait...
Please wait...
I'll give you this.
There's a jewel inside.
Isn't that a fair deal, Rishi-kun?
Kaito Kid!
W-What is Arthur-kun doing here?!
Let's see...
To get to the roof, I think
I have to transfer at the 34th floor.
34th floor.
Hey!
Wait.
Are they...
Heading towards Marina Bay Sands?!
What are you doing?!
I was trying to catch those two,
who were the masterminds behind this!
Stop with the poor acting,
Rishi Ramanathan.
I know full well
that you are the mastermind.
The first thing that made
me have my doubts about you...
Was Kid's advance notice
that was left at the crime scene.
The police didn't notice
the advance notice...
Until right after you arrived
at the scene, did they, Rishi?
And earlier, when I asked you
where Leon-san would be...
My doubts towards you solidified.
What?!
Someone as conceited
and self-centered as Leon-san...
Would never flee the country
when the success of his plan was close at hand.
I'm certain he would be in a place with the best view, watching it all happen.
And you couldn't possibly
have not been aware of that!
Well, this is surprising.
So you were just
testing me with that, huh?
It all started five years ago...
And your father's accident was
the beginning of your plan, wasn't it?
"Suspect Admits Killing
Oceanographer After Initial Denial."
Unless I'm mistaken...
Nakatomi-san also first came
to Singapore five years ago, correct?
N-No, I...
Leon-san caught the killer...
While Sherilyn-san acted as his attorney
and made him admit to his guilt.
I can't think that's
a mere coincidence.
What do you mean?
It was a trap set in order to obtain
the oil tanker owned by Nakatomi Shipping.
Everything was planned.
And then there was one more trap...
The fact of which you
realized, didn't you?
I also thought
it was an accident at first, but...
As I was sorting through my father's personal effects, I realized...
That as my father was investigating some underwater ruins, he had coincidentally discovered...
A sunken ship where the Fist of Blue Sapphire, the emblem of the king of all pirates, was likely to be resting.
That's why you
started by killing my father!
To prevent him from
recovering the jewel first!
Help!
Someone pushed me in the back!
Help is on the way!
Hurry!
Save him!
Since my father had
a strong sense of justice...
I'm sure you guessed that he
would definitely dive in to save him.
W-What is the
meaning of this, Leon?!
You—
Let go of me!
Rishi-kun,
you're misunderstanding something.
The one who killed your father
was sent to prison—
Having suspected you
of causing my father's death...
I came to this country, became your pupil,
and became a reserve officer.
Then I began
investigating into the accident.
I became acquainted with Sherilyn Tan,
who had been in charge of defending him.
When I approached her, asking if she had any info
about the case on Reijiro that could shake up Leon...
She told me briefly.
And then there was Rachel.
That's right.
Every bit of information on you
was leaked to me through her!
In that case, why did you
post an advance notice from Kid?
How about you tell us?
There's the Fist of Blue Sapphire,
and then a murder case he had nothing to do with.
If I dangled those two things in front of him,
I knew for sure the phantom thief would come.
And then he would get
in the way of your plan for me.
That high school detective
didn't show up like I had planned...
But you played your role well.
Nakatomi-san, it seems Leon-san saved you
right when you were being suspected of theft...
But is that really just a coincidence?
Think things over well.
What if this was all just a part of his...
You bastard!
You really did
your research, Rishi-kun.
Huh?
Where am I?
If I remember right...
Dad!
Huh?
Oh!
A-Ah!
Ran?!
What?!
W-What the...?!
Dad...
Ra—
Fall back!
And regroup! Tell the chopper, too!
Who are you guys?
Now then, Rishi-kun...
Unfortunately for you,
the tables have turned.
Eugene, the plan seems to have failed.
You can take this jewel.
Take care of anyone here.
What are you doing?!
Don't move!
H-Help me!
Now that I have the jewel, I have no need for you.
What?
I have no time for your nonsense.
I am known to break promises.
It's just that there was a more lucrative offer.
Don't tell me you guys are after...
You sure are observant, kid.
That's it exactly.
The daughter of the
Suzuki Financial Group is in this hotel.
And if we kidnap her,
the ransom we can get will be astronomical.
Hasn't the little lady
already taken shelter?
She should still be in her suite.
Because I told her over the phone
to absolutely not leave her room.
W-Wait...
Makoto-san?!
Excuse me for doing this!
Wha—?!
All the elevators have been stopped.
What?!
Let's get out of here.
There! Come on!
Don't shoot! You'll hit her!
M-Makoto-san...
What's going on here?
Look.
Everything will work out
just as I pictured in the end.
This city will be burned
to the ground, and be born again!
But you won't be alive to see it!
What?! They're going to shoot rockets at us?
Whoa...
Damn them!
Take this!
Get them, now!
Makoto-san!
What?!
Wh-Wh-What are you...?!
After them!
Open up!
They're here! They're here!
You brats!
What is going on here?
I don't know.
Most of the pirates are now in the hotel.
Just what is going on inside?
It's dangerous here, too. Please get back.
Are you okay?
Y-Yeah...
If this keeps up,
the city really will be destroyed!
Damn it!
Isn't there any good way to stop this?
If we could use that,
we could pull this off!
Kid!
Wait...
Are you serious?!
Of course I am!
It's the guy again!
Shoot him down!
Boss, we can't hit him!
Pesky little bird!
Hey, we've got to do something about that group of pirates before we can do your plan...
And my playing card gun's
only got one more shot!
Isn't there one way left?
Huh?
A trump card that'll turn
the tables with a single shot!
I get it!
I'm diving in close!
Wait!
Makoto-san...?!
Get them!
Stay back!
He is...
...mine!
Kid...
Oh?
Take me to the bow of the ship!
You don't have to tell me twice!
Whoa!
Ran, stay back!
Ran!
Go!
What in the
world is going on here?!
I heard Shinichi's voice...
Are you okay, Miss?
Arthur-kun...
What are you doing here?
Ah...
I was worried about you, Miss.
Thanks.
Oh, come on!
Where is he?!
I'm glad you're safe.
What?
Thank you!
Makoto-san!
Kid took the jewel.
Can you shoot him down?
OK, boss.
Damn! Stay still...
Take this!
Huh?
Was he on the mark?
It will be fine, Sonoko-san!
Oh, no...
What?
Kid!
You...!
Hi!
Wait!
Help me, man!
I'm falling down!
Makoto-san, you're bleeding!
Sonoko-san,
please excuse me for this!
Huh?!
Wait, what are you doing?
We're out in a
place like this... Makoto-san?!
I'm telling you no!
What?! Ah!
It's a back-carry knot.
Sonoko-san, make absolutely sure
you stay close to me this time!
I couldn't get away from
you like this, even if I wanted to...
Where is he?!
Kyogoku-san!
Hold onto something!
Are you alright?
You can have this back.
Huh?
That...
Wasn't the jewel I'm looking for.
Sonoko-san...
Please sit down here for a while.
I apologize.
It's knotted a little too tightly...
Ah, it came loose.
Ah, no!
No, that's... Um...
That's something...
like a good luck charm.
Did you always have this on you?
Y-Yes...
Though I couldn't come out and tell you,
thinking I'd lose my pride as a man.
So that's it...
I always thought
he was being protected...
But it looks like I was
the one protecting Makoto-san.
So that's it! So that's it!
Please return my band-aid to me!
No way!
Please!
I'm going to treasure it
for the rest of my life!
They're a lovely couple, aren't they?
Who in the world are you?
You're not some ordinary kid, are you?
I'm Edogawa Conan, a detective.
But are you really okay...
With letting that insanely strong
boyfriend of yours go off to the US again?
It's fine! It's fine!
Makoto-san really has to
fight somewhere, doesn't he?
Oh, they came out!
Hey...
What's that?
Come on...
Don't cling to me so tightly.
Doesn't that make it hard to walk?
No way.
I'm never letting go of you again.
Oh, is that right?
I've been waiting all this time...
For this moment.
Huh?
Kid!
We've been waiting for you!
What...
Are you serious?!
I could tell that you
weren't Shinichi right from the start!
You see, Shinichi...
Would never do something
like calling my dad "old man"!
What?!
But he's always...
Come to think of it...
I've never called him
"old man" in front of Ran, have I?
I won't let you off the hook for
pretending to be Shinichi not just once, but twice!
Young lady, please make
absolutely sure you don't let go of his arm!
Restrain him!
Kid!
Catch him!
I'm absolutely not going to let go!
Don't let him get away!
Professor...
He's not here!
Augh!
He got away!
Damn it!
He has to still be nearby!
After him!
Conan-kun!
Welcome home, Ran-neechan.
Good to be back!
You weren't lonely
without me, were you?
You dummy...
We were together the entire time.
Let this reach...
To the distant beyond.