Whoa!
Wow!
It took off in no time!
And it flies awfully high, doesn't it?
Lemme see, too!
Me too!
P-Please wait a second.
These can fly at an height
of 10,000 meters for 30 minutes!
I'm sure that's the world
record for a drone, though...
Even so, how do you
control it at that altitude?
It utilizes satellite communication.
That's why you can even
control it from a great distance.
Oh...
I'm relying on the video
being sent from the aircraft...
As well as the latitude
and longitude data to pilot it...
But between its direction,
speed, and the camera...
I have to operate three things
simultaneously, so it's quite difficult.
But why did you build this drone?
"Why?"
Because it's every man's dream!
With this, you can feel as if you've
climbed Mt. Everest, even if you haven't!
What a creepy way to laugh.
Or rather, this invention
seems like it breaks countless laws.
Up
Next
The Latest Info on the
Tokyo Summit
Coming up after this commercial break...
We'll bring you the latest information
on the upcoming Tokyo Summit!
Latest
Info
Venue of the Tokyo Summit:
"Edge of Ocean"
I'm here at the location of the summit!
On this reclaimed land near Tokyo Bay...
The event will be held next week, at the "Edge of Ocean"
integrated resort's international convention center!
Detailed Guide to "Edge of Ocean"
Opens
Next Month
Scheduled to open
next month, "Edge of Ocean"...
Was designed to take in plenty of water,
which is appropriate for a seaside city...
And is composed of a wide variety of facilities.
Casino Tower, which was
constructed in the motif of a shell...
Also acts as a lighthouse
to keep the ocean safe...
In which you can
look out over "Edge of Ocean".
And in the shopping mall
located close to Casino Tower...
A large waterfall and
an indoor park are in place...
Allowing visitors to have
a moment of peace and tranquility.
And one other concept
it's comprised of is: "Japan".
The interior of the
International Convention Center...
Borrows from the beauty
and form of Japanese gardens...
And also has a classy
restaurant on the first floor.
In addition to all of that,
please take a look at this!
This is a two-layer monorail that
runs around the perimeter of the area.
Through its fusion of traditional culture with future advancement...
It certainly brings about
the feeling of a smart city.
As you can see...
For the Venue of the Tokyo Summit,
Brings You the Latest!
"Edge of Ocean" is
connected by two bridges.
The Metropolitan Police Department, which will be in charge of security for the summit when it is held on May 1...
Announced that they will be placing as many as 22,000 officers on security duty throughout the metropolitan area.
Coming up next, we'll bring you news on the "Swan" unmanned space probe...
I'm high school detective, Kudo Shin'ichi.
While visiting an amusement park with my childhood friend and classmate, Mouri Ran...
I witnessed a man in black in the midst of a suspicious transaction.
While caught up in watching the deal...
I failed to notice his
partner sneaking up behind me.
That man forced me to take poison...
And when I came to...
My body had shrunk.
If those guys found out that
Kudo Shin'ichi was still alive...
They'd come after me again, and put those around me at risk.
At Professor Agasa's suggestion,
I decided to hide my true identity.
And the moment
Ran asked for my name...
I became Edogawa Conan.
In order to obtain
information on those guys...
I went to live with Ran,
whose father is a private detective.
These three are
Genta, Mitsuhiko, and Ayumi.
They're my classmates
now that I've shrunk.
And this is Haibara Ai.
Her real name is Miyano Shiho.
She was originally
part of the men in black...
But in order to take her own life,
she took the same drug as me...
And her body shrank.
Then there's one member of the Black Organization that's shrouded in mystery...
Amuro Tooru,
code name Bourbon.
His true identity is a secret operative for the National Police Agency who directs the MPD's Public Security Bureau...
A policeman known as "Zero".
In order to camouflage that fact...
He acts as Detective Mouri's apprentice...
While working at Café Poirot.
He's a man of many mysteries.
Even though I've shrunk,
my mind remains the same...
That of an unbeaten great detective.
There's always only one truth!
Special
Report
Unmanned Space Probe
"Swan" Returns from Mars
Having finished collecting samples from Mars,
the unmanned space probe, "Swan"...
Will finally return to Earth
on May 1, Japan Standard Time!
During its return, the main body of the probe would burn up in the atmosphere...
So only the return capsule, measuring approximately four meters in diameter...
Will be sent though
the atmosphere for re-entry.
Afterwards, it will
descend via parachute...
Heat Shield Separates
Parachute Opens
And is expected to splash down in the
Pacific Ocean, in the coastal waters of Japan.
Lands in the Pacific Ocean
Special
Report
Unmanned Space Probe
"Swan" Returns from Mars
Lands in the Pacific Ocean
I see.
Diagram of "Swan"
Re-entry Capsule
Precision-Guided GPS
Capsule
A presision-guided system with an attached GPS unit is on board the sample's capsule...
Precision-Guided GPS
So that the place it touches down can be determined to within a 200 meter radius!
Wow...
Whoa?!
Hey, wait!
Hurry and lemme try!
No!
You must not touch it!
I want to try it, too!
Maybe I should divide the controller up into three...
One each for direction, speed, and the camera.
Oh, brother...
We interrupt this program
for some breaking news.
This just in...
Moments ago, a large explosion took
place at the international convention center...
Where the Tokyo Summit
will be held next week.
Here's security camera
footage from when it took place.
What is this...?
Emergency
Explosion Took Place at the
Scheduled Venue of Summit!!
As for the "Edge of Ocean" integrated resort,
which has become the scene of the crime...
Due to the fact that it had
not yet opened to the public...
The grounds were mostly vacant.
Professor!
But reports are coming in regarding
casualties among several police officers...
Who had been performing
security checks for the summit.
I repeat.
Moments ago...
At the "Edge of Ocean"
integrated resort...
This could be a terrorist attack!
But isn't the summit next week?
It might have been an accident.
The number of police
officers who suffered casualties...
And well as whether this was
an accident or an intentional act...
Remains unclear,
due to ongoing investigation.
The police officers suffered casualties?
That sure is worrying.
Professor!
The video disappeared!
Okay!
I'll be right there!
That's right...
Come to think of it, a terrorist attack happening before the summit...
Would only make the
security tighter for the real thing.
What's wrong?
The security camera footage
from right after the explosion...
Was there something in it?
I may have seen wrong, since
it was only there for a moment...
Oh?
But that man was in it.
The one who's working at Poirot.
If I'm not mistaken,
wasn't his name Amuro Tooru?
Amuro-san was in it?!
The forensic investigation...
Ended with no
explosives found at the scene.
There's a traditional Japanese restaurant on the first floor of the international convention center...
And a kitchen area, which became the site of the explosion, is located underground.
A large quantity of
gas was detected there.
Therefore, we believe it's safe to conclude that this was a gas explosion.
Hold it.
Construction on that
building had just been completed.
It's very unlikely that there
would have been a gas leak.
Indeed.
It's true that the gas main
was the latest model available...
And it was also possible to open
and close the gas line via the internet.
In that case,
how did a gas leak occur?
It's possible that the system
was defective to begin with.
Had it not been inspected?
The inspection was
scheduled for today.
What do you mean?
The internet connection for
"Edge of Ocean" had just been set up today.
And after a security inspection by the MPD's Public Security Bureau this morning...
It was also scheduled to be inspected.
In that case, it seems highly
likely that this was an accident.
Because if this was an act of
terrorism aimed at the summit...
It would be meaningless unless it was carried out next week...
On May 1, when important people from
various countries would be gathered there.
Regarding the
venue for the summit...
We've been informed that it will
be changed as a result of this incident.
So it's likely this was an accident...
I have information to report.
State your name and affiliation.
I'm Kazami Yuya, of the
MPD's Public Security Bureau.
Have you located an object that ignited and caused the gas to explode?
Not yet.
The Criminal Investigation Division is looking into the electrical equipment.
The point of ignition may have been a high-voltage power cable.
Don't tell me you found
a fault in its construction?!
No.
However, we did find fingerprints that were burned onto the door of the high voltage cable's storage unit.
In other words, they're fingerprints that were on the door prior to the explosion?
Yes.
The only ones who entered the scene were those involved with its construction...
And members of my own Public Security Bureau, who were there performing a security inspection this morning.
Consequently, when we compared the fingerprints with those of the construction workers...
As well as the fingerprints of police officers in our database...
We found that the former member of the MPD's Criminal Investigation Division One...
Mouri Kogoro's
fingerprints were a perfect match!
What?!
That's ridiculous!
No way!
That can't be!
The international convention center
that's built on reclaimed land?!
I've never even been there!
But your fingerprints were found
at the scene of the crime, Mouri-san.
That's impossible!
Dad...
Maybe you were drunk again, and
broke in without realizing it or something?
Like I said...
I've never even been there!
This is some kind of mix-up!
Search all you want,
but you won't find anything!
Calm down, now.
Pardon me.
Y-Yes, sir.
Is something wrong, Conan-kun?
That police detective's
face is injured. Is he okay?
Oh, you mean Kazami-san?
Apparently, he was at the scene of the explosion when it happened.
I-I've gotta go to the restroom!
Oh, what's up?
Yeah...
What?!
The police suspect your dad?
Yeah...
Though I'm sure
it's some sort of mistake...
Got it.
I'll look into it, too.
It's so hard to use
this alternate phone.
Huh?
Where's my phone?
Hey, Professor?
What?
Oh, Shin'ichi?
What's the trouble?
I have a small favor to ask of you.
How long are these
guys going to be doing this?!
Well...
Come on, Takagi!
Do something!
Send them away, now!
Yes, well...
Oh?
Why is my phone here...?
Whoa!
This thing is fun!
Yeah!
But please make it
go slower, Genta-kun.
Because I'm recording the video!
My bad, my bad...
But this thing is awesome!
To think we can make
it fly from this far away!
You can control it from
up to 30 kilometers away!
Oh, we just made it fly 20 kilometers ahead a little while ago.
Wha...?
And I had it carry a present
to my aunt's house in Saitama!
I bet your aunt was super happy!
W-When did you
learn to do all that?
But you know...
Don't you think this
screen is small and hard to see?
Well...
I didn't originally plan to divide it up for three people, after all.
Hey, Professor...
Put a screen on my controller, too!
Put one on mine, too!
Yes, well...
Okay!
In that case,
it's time for a quiz!
Now, listen...
If you answer this quiz correctly,
I'll attach a monitor on to each of those!
Wha...?
And here's the question!
Out of the following, which row of hiragana has the largest scale?
1. The "a" row.
2. The "ka" row.
3. The "sa" row.
4. The "ta" row.
What's "scale" mean, anyway?
It's asking which one is
the biggest and most vast.
A hiragana that's the
biggest and most vast...?
In basic Japanese syllabary, the
"a" row refers to "a", "i", "u", "e", and "o"...
The "ka" row refers to
"ka", "ki", "ku", "ke", and "ko".
Change the rows into their
syllables and think about it.
So it's "sa", "shi", "su", "se", and "so"...
Then "ta", "chi", "tsu", "te", and "to"...
Oh, I don't get it!
Ah, Ayumi-chan!
Please don't move the camera!
I-I'm sorry!
Then, here's hint number one: "swan".
Swan?
Wait, Ai-kun...
When you say "swan",
you think of a swan on a lake...
Hey!
They live on a huge lake,
so it's the "mi" row!
mizu umi
Wait, there isn't one.
Hint number two:
The "swan" comes back.
The swan comes home?
Oh, so it is a lake, after all!
o-uchi
uchi
So "home"... "pit"... "inside"...
Oh!
I know!
The "Swan" unmanned space probe
is returning from space!
So, what's the correct answer?
It's number 1, the "a" row!
chuukan
The character "u" is in the center
of "a", "i", "u", "e", and "o".
uchuu
Combine those, and you get "space"!
And space is on a
bigger scale than anything!
Yes, you answered correctly.
All right!
Oh, come on, Ai-kun...
You always give too
many hints, each and every time...
Now listen here, Professor!
Isn't it awfully dangerous to give them a quiz while they're controlling the drone?!
Besides...
What they're all filming now isn't all fun and games, unlike your quiz!
You're right. I'm sorry.
We, the Criminal Investigation Division...
Along with the Security Bureau and the Public Security Bureau...
Ended up inspecting the
scene before the summit...
And the Public Security Bureau was in charge at the time of the explosion.
So that's why
Detective Kazami was injured...
He was outside of the building,
so he received only minor injuries...
But as for the people
who were inside the building...
I know...
I saw the news saying about how there were also people who died.
Yes.
I'm sure I shouldn't be saying this...
But the fact that only us police were injured, and not regular civilians...
May have been a
blessing in disguise.
If the explosion had
occurred during the summit...
The whole world would be thrown into an uproar, wouldn't it?
No, the MPD...
And the Public Security Bureau
is receiving the brunt of it.
Though it's only natural, what with an accidental explosion occurring before the summit.
"Accidental?"
Ah, no...
I meant that, based on the conditions at the scene,
it should have been treated as an accident at first.
Were Uncle Kogoro's
fingerprints really at the scene?
Yeah.
Kazami-san found them...
And immediately
brought it up as a criminal act.
Detective Kazami did that...?
Thanks, Detective Takagi!
Bye!
Be careful on your way home!
Ran, what's the matter?
Help me, Shin'ichi!
Dad's going to be arrested!
Damn it!
I told you, I don't know!
But these came from the
computer we seized from you.
The schedule for the summit...
And the floor plans for the now-exploded international convention center.
What?!
That's not true!
My dad never could have saved those documents to his computer!
Yeah, that's right!
He's completely computer-illiterate!
Exactly!
I can't do that!
At any rate, we'll listen to the details down at the police station.
Don't give me that!
Like I care about Public Security's
voluntary questioning!
In that case, I place you under arrest for interfering with the duties of a public servant.
But all I did was
push your hand away!
Wait, hey...!
Hey!
You can't!
This can't be happening!
April 28, 4:56 PM.
Hey!
Let go of me!
Getting riled up only
increases our suspicion of you.
Hey!
Wait!
If Uncle Kogoro is the bomber...
Then what's his motive for
blowing up the venue of the summit?!
Yeah!
What would I do that for?!
We'll ask him that
during our questioning, as well.
Hey!
Come on, stop!
Dad!
Calm down, Ran!
Call Kudo-kun right now, and—
I did!
I did, but...
How could he...
Why won't that guy
come at a time like this?!
This man is a
Public Security officer, isn't he?
Who knows? I sure don't.
And both you and
Detective Kazami are injured.
That means you were at
the scene of the explosion, too.
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
Weren't you doing a preliminary inspection of the venue for the summit?
At the time, I'm sure you sensed the likelihood it was a terrorist attack.
But at this rate, the explosion
will be treated as an accident!
So you invented a false suspect!
Am I wrong?
Amuro-san, if you're
a policeman like he is...
Isn't it possible for you
to tamper with his computer...
And leave his fingerprints
at the scene of the explosion?!
The police...
Don't follow leads
without any sort of proof.
Why are you doing this?!
Because there's something I have to protect, even if it costs me my life.
This time, Amuro-san...
May be my adversary.
Why?!
Why won't you defend Dad?
Don't tell me you
seriously think he blew it up?
That man can't do such a thing.
Then, why?
Attorneys don't defend
those whom they're related to.
Because it's very likely that judges will decide they "lack objectivity."
In other words, if I accepted and acted as that man's defense...
It may backfire and
work to our disadvantage.
No way...
But don't worry!
Because I'll find him a
good attorney in no time!
It's unfortunate.
This turned out just as
you said it would, Furuya-san...
But if we had only
figured it out sooner...
Our fellow comrades in
Public Security wouldn't have died.
Yes...
Who would have thought it
would be bombed before the summit.
We're currently looking into the national extremists on Public Security's list...
As well as international terrorists...
But what about
on your end, Furuya-san?
We're looking into the transmission
that accessed the location's gas line.
It looks like a slightly
peculiar system is being used.
And what would that be?
As soon as the
investigation is complete...
I'll convey that to the
MPD's Public Security Bureau.
Understood.
What's happening
with what we talked about?
Right.
It's programmed so
that you enter "2-2-9-1".
Ah...
Furuya-san?
Got it.
So that means...
I knew it.
But...
In other words...
Traces were found on
Mouri Kogoro's computer...
Showing that it accessed
the scene's gas main?
Yes.
We received a report from the Anti-Cybercrime Division stating so.
That settles it, then.
Mouri Kogoro broke in here...
Opened this door...
And tampered with the
high-voltage power cable.
Hold on a minute!
If that was true, Mouri-kun should
have been shown on the security cameras!
Ah, no...
Internet access at the
location only began yesterday, so...
This can't be!
What is he saying
in the interrogation?
Mouri Kogoro
continues to deny it all.
We can send the case to prosecution
even if he continues to deny it, but...
You intend to prosecute him,
even when you don't know of any motive?!
Sending a case to prosecution
once all evidence has been gathered...
Is the natural thing to do
for a member of the police.
Now, wait a minute!
Something's wrong here!
Something's strange!
"Something's wrong..."
"Something's strange..."
Do you think the investigators
will act, based on just that?
I see...
Yes.
No!
Why won't anyone defend him?
Is it because this
is a major incident?
That's right.
And also because the suspect
they would be defending...
Is the famous "Sleeping Kogoro".
So every single attorney is hesitant.
Come in.
Excuse me.
Inspector Shiratori?
I thought I needed to tell you
this before it winds up on the news...
Tell us what?
Mouri-san's case...
Is being sent to prosecution.
Is there sufficient evidence to
send the case to prosecution?
Mouri-san's fingerprints
were found at the scene.
Its floor plans
were on his computer...
Along with the
schedule for the summit...
And an access log which
leads to the ignitable object.
That's more than
enough to prosecute.
Why... is Dad...?
Mom...
Wait for me, Ran!
I'll definitely get
the old man out of this!
Agasa
Professor!
You said you found it?
Oh, you came?
Here, look.
It certainly...
may look like a bomb...
Remember how we filmed the scattered debris because you asked us to?
We reconstructed this by taking those images and piecing them together like a puzzle.
In order to determine
the specific type of bomb...
Ai-kun is currently comparing it to every image on the internet.
There.
I found an object that matches.
Huh?
What is that?
I'll bring up the details.
An IoT pressure cooker?
It's an extraordinary high pressure vessel made into the shape of a pot.
cooks without
any loss of flavor!
and stewing all in
just this one device!
allow easy-to-use
MultiControl!
It turned out great!
Wasn't that easy, Daddy?!
"Simply by setting the pressure, temperature,
and time from one's smartphone..."
Or so it says.
Prepare meals?!
Besides the pressure cooker...
There was also a frying pan, a kettle, and various kinds of tableware scattered about.
Which means the
location of the explosion...
Was the kitchen area
of the on-site restaurant.
What the...?!
You mean it wasn't a bomb?!
Hey!
Isn't it because you asked us
to find the object that exploded...
That even Ai-kun is
working so hard by doing all of this?
And yet, what was that?
That wasn't like you.
Sorry.
What's wrong?
Did something happen?
Old man Kogoro...
Was sent to prosecution!
Wha...?!
Huh?
Who's that?
Oh?
What did you just say?
As I said...
Please allow me, Tachibana Kyoko,
to defend the Sleeping Kogoro.
Here are the cases I've handled so far.
The Nijo Medical
University extremist case...
METI is the "Ministry of Economy, Trade, and Industry".
The METI spying incident...
You sure have had a lot of
cases related to public security.
Then she's perfect for this case!
So what percentage of
trials have you won or lost, Miss?
Oh?
You sure know some
hard words for a little boy.
I've lost all of them.
Wha...?!
Huh?
Oh, but public
security cases are difficult.
Yes, they are.
As you know, the Prosecutor's Office wins over 90% of cases they've brought to prosecution.
And that number is even
higher for public security cases.
In other words,
I can't possibly win.
But I'm a "mobi-ttorney"...
"Mobi-ttorney"...?
It refers to a freelance attorney without a law office,
who accepts jobs through their mobile phone.
That's why I have to handle
even the most impossible trials.
And she's going to defend Dad...?
You're looking for an
attorney to represent him, correct?
I heard about it
at the legal association.
Please allow me to handle it!
Well...
P-Please give us a minute.
Mom, you can't!
That attorney has no intent to win.
She certainly doesn't.
But because she seems to be
a no-good attorney at first look...
The prosecution
might underestimate her.
She can't win with just that!
Wouldn't it be best to have a court-appointed attorney, after all...?
In that case, I can't interject.
Huh?
But with her, I can chime in.
Even so...
I feel uneasy about this.
What's that cat's name?
Goro-chan!
It sounds like you continued denying everything to the police.
Of course!
Because I didn't do anything!
But we have all this evidence showing that you're the bomber.
That's what I don't
understand, Mr. Prosecutor!
I can only think
that someone set me up!
This bombing case
has been assigned to...
Prosecutor Kusakabe, of the District Public Prosecutor's Office.
Oh, my!
This is bad!
Even I, who's defended clients in only a small number of public security cases...
Knows his name.
Is he that good of a prosecutor?
He's a competent, unbeatable prosecutor
who's on the same level as Kisaki-sensei.
The complete opposite of me.
Oh, I know this case!
The NAZU hacking incident!
Wait, NAZU...?
You mean the famous agency in the United States that's doing space exploration?
Oh...
That's the case where an employee of a game company hacked into it for fun last year.
Kusakabe-san was the
prosecutor at that time, as well.
And in that trial...
I lost, of course.
"Of course...?"
Oh, brother...
This is regarding the
result of today's investigation...
But I'm concerned that Mouri Kogoro has absolutely no motive to carry out a terrorist bombing.
A "motive", huh?
But given that
we have all this evidence...
Shouldn't we just go ahead
and indict him tomorrow?
B-But...
For example, this log considers the gas main of the scene of the explosion to have been accessed...
But there's also a considerable possibility that the suspect's computer was used as a relay point by a third party.
Moreover...
There would be plenty of opportunity to leave the schedule and floor plans on his computer...
In order to frame him for their crime.
Chief Kusakabe, that's...
Just your own personal guess,
one which ignores this evidence.
Prosecutor General Iwai...
I want to have the
police investigate further, and—
You are going to
indict Mouri Kogoro.
That's the decision of Public Security.
Understand?
Is that "Public Security" with us,
the Public Prosecutor's Office?
Or are they with the
National Police Agency?
This discussion is over.
Please leave.
You were requested to
perform an additional investigation?
Yes.
By Prosecutor Kusakabe.
So with that investigation, you can also make it so Dad doesn't get prosecuted?
No.
That additional investigation was Prosecutor Kusakabe's own personal idea...
And it seems that the NPA's
Public Security has decided to prosecute him.
Wait... Why are the police interfering by ordering prosecution?
Law positions the police where they're to be directed by the Public Prosecutor's Office!
And above all, prosecution is at the sole authority of the public prosecutor—
Yes, it's just as you said.
However, that only applies to cases handled by the Prosecution Office's civil affairs, criminal affairs...
Or special investigation departments.
I'm sure you're aware that the circumstances differ slightly in regard to their public security department.
Oh, right.
Just saying "Public Security"
doesn't help much, does it?
The Metropolitan Police Department...
The National Police Agency...
And the Public Prosecutor's Office...
Each have their own
Public Security branch.
The police send the results of what they
investigated to the Public Prosecutor's Office...
But the prosecution receives that and looks into the case again.
Whether or not
they indict the suspect...
Is usually based on the National Police Agency's judgment, taking the prosecution's investigation into account.
But the Public Security Department of
the Public Prosecutor's Office is different.
Frankly, the prosecution's Public Security branch is no match for the police's Public Security.
There's a world of difference in the
amount of investigators and know-how they have.
That's why there are times they also push for
prosecution, out of consideration for public security.
"Out of consideration
for public security...?"
A bombing at the venue
of the summit, in particular...
Is the same as smearing mud in the faces of the MPD's Public Security Bureau.
So I can picture them straight-out placing pressure by saying "you must prosecute him."
Then, Dad's going to be...?
Yes. I'm sure
he'll be prosecuted.
This can't be happening...
It's almost as if this attorney
wants him to be prosecuted!
You're looking into the possibility that someone manipulated Uncle Kogoro's computer, aren't you?
Well, it's true that Prosecutor Kusakabe requested that we do an additional investigation...
Tell me as much as you can.
Shin'ichi-niichan said he wants any information he could use to help Uncle Kogoro.
What's this about Mouri-sensei?
Amuro-kun?
You were listening?
To what?
I was just worried
about Mouri-sensei...
And brought some
refreshments from Poirot for him.
Oh...
Mouri-kun's no longer here.
It's a general rule that when one is sent to prosecution,
they're moved to the Detention House.
You couldn't possibly
not know that, Amuro-san.
Oh, is that so?
You're as knowledgeable as ever, aren't you?
Oh, and then...
You can't bring those kinds
of things to the Detention House.
I understand!
What's he aiming to do...?
"2-2-9-1" was
successfully put in place.
What was that?
What did he say to Amuro-san?
Dammit!
Hey, Mr. Police Detective!
Gimme back the computer
you took from Uncle's place!
'Cause the game I like is on it!
That's a piece of evidence,
so we can't return it just yet.
Give it back!
Come now, Conan-kun!
Stop doing that!
But it's the game that the
Professor made for me, too...!
Oh, Conan-kun!
I called you who knows how many times!
What?
Huh?
The battery's dead.
Can you charge it with that?
Yep! Thanks!
The battery usually
lasts much longer than this...
So what did you call about?
The case documents will
be coming any minute now.
And Ran said she wanted
you to see them too, Conan-kun.
After all, Conan-kun often
realizes interesting things...
And besides...
If there is something,
he might tell Shin'ichi about it for me.
Yeah!
I'll definitely tell
Shin'ichi-niichan about it!
Thank you, Conan-kun.
I'm sorry to have kept you waiting.
Here's the evidence that
the prosecuting side requested.
Wait...
Then, that means...
They decided to prosecute Uncle?
The Prosecutor's Office contacted me, saying they will be indicting him very shortly.
Dad...
Don't worry!
We'll help him out of this, for sure!
Come this way.
Yes, Ma'am.
There's his written affidavit,
an expert appraisal of the scene...
And photos of the scene
taken by the forensics experts.
There's so much...
I've got to find some sort of clue!
Around the Site of the Explosion
Damn it, isn't there something?!
Glass Shards at Site of Explosion
Exploded Pieces of High-Voltage Power Cable
Door of High Voltage Cable's Storage Unit
What is it?
Huh?
Well, I just felt like I've
seen this somewhere before...
Looking at this, you can clearly see the method the bomber used.
Documentation of
the police's investigation...
Is something like a detailed
handbook on a crime, isn't it?
"Handbook"...?
Hello?
This is Tachibana.
The court?
Yes...
Pre-trial organizational procedures?
Prosecutor General Iwai!
Why did you contact the defense and tell them you're going to indict without informing me?
Don't make me
keep repeating myself.
This is the decision of Public Security.
So not just their
decision to prosecute...
You do everything Public Security
says, even down to the timing?
Because of that, the court contacted me, saying they want the prosecution and defense...
To come in first thing tomorrow to do pre-trial organizational procedures.
Why did they contact you,
Prosecutor General Iwai?!
I'm the chief prosecutor in this case!
When you finish
the procedures, let me know.
That huge ice cream isn't here...
No, it's not.
Oh, I'll go ask one of the staff...
So Amuro-san,
please get the flour and eggs.
You seem like you'll be
a good wife someday, Azusa-san.
Avoid doing or
saying such rash things!
Huh?
You're very popular among the
female high schoolers who frequent us, Amuro-san!
Not too long ago, there was even a flood of comments across the internet saying that I'm coming on to you!
These days, you never know where someone could be listening in on us from!
I guess so...
Furuya-san.
Why are you so fixated
on making this into a case?
If this gets processed as an accident, we won't be able to get even a single warrant.
For Public Security, you should even be able to perform an illegal search without a warrant.
It's for that very reason that we need to leave legal means open...
Or we'd be digging our own grave.
"Bear the weight of your
illegal work on your own."
That's how Public Security operates.
But deciding whether to
legally announce the incident...
Or illegally cover it up is also
what we do at Public Security.
Of course it is.
But only after considering which of those two will best protect Japan.
Oh, Amuro-san!
The staff said...
Now, starting with the prosecution...
Please present your evidence, in order to clearly indicate the facts to be proven.
Yes, sir.
I submit to you a
summary of my evidence.
Ran.
Calm down.
But...
The trial still doesn't start today, does it?
That's correct.
These are
"Pretrial organizational procedures".
They simply narrow down the points at issue,
evidence, as well as fix a date for the trial.
Didn't I tell you both that?
You did, but...
Kyoko-sensei!
Prosecutor General Iwai, this is Kusakabe.
The pre-trial organizational procedures have just been completed.
What evidence did
Prosecutor Kusakabe present?
It was the same as
the evidence we received earlier.
This is his summary.
And what about the trial date?
It was set.
That was also just as we expected.
Oh...
I'm sorry, but could
you please read this?
I'm going to use the restroom.
Oh, Kyoko-sensei!
The restroom's in the opposite direction!
Kyoko-sensei!
What's this?
The bug I put on
Detective Kazami yesterday...
So he's nearby?!
I see...
Please continue.
He's close!
How could he be
here in this court?!
Where is he?
Is that...
Kyoko-sensei's ringtone?!
Oh, Kyoko-sensei?
There's something I
wanted to confirm with you.
Oh, I'll be right back.
Why can I hear Kyoko-sensei's voice through the bug on Detective Kazami?
Did she just happen
to be near Detective Kazami?
No...
In order for me
to have heard her voice...
Those two had to have
been close for quite a while!
This was no mere coincidence.
As a result of the investigation that we, the Public Security Bureau, carried out...
It has been discovered that Nor was used to hack into the scene of the explosion.
Nor?
It's a piece of browsing software...
That encrypts one's IP address through
multiple computers so that it can't be traced.
And it isn't possible to
break through Nor's anonymity?
Generally speaking, it's not.
But if the Nor browser
is misconfigured or has a bug...
It appears to be possible
to identify a specific user.
Conversely...
If we create a vulnerability in the perpetrator's Nor browser from here...
The possibility of
tracing them will arise.
We at the Public Security
Bureau are currently searching...
For the possibility that we can trace the server and identify the user.
Excuse me.
They've called a meeting.
I will be leaving my seat temporarily.
Go ahead.
Eavesdropping on
the investigation meeting?
W-Why are you here?
You sure give it your all
when it comes to Mouri Kogoro.
Or is it that you're
doing this for Ran-neechan?
It's not a problem.
Come on out.
Why did you call for me?
Furuya-san?
You sure did well to operate
in Public Security like this.
M-My apologies...
Who in the world...?
Wait!
Were you the one who
put the listening device on me?
No, a child like him
couldn't possibly have...
Amuro-san directs all
Public Safety officers nationwide.
He's the National Police Agency's "Zero"!
Those who can be
in contact with Amuro-san...
Are limited to select police detectives,
even among those in Public Security.
And you were one of them,
Weren't you, Kazami-san?
Who in the world are you?
Edogawa Conan...
A detective.
The man known as
"Amuro" that you speak of...
Is a killer.
Last year, he pushed someone we were examining
at the Detention House into committing suicide.
Suicide...?
Sorry.
That wasn't something I
should have said to a child.
But for some reason, it just feels like I can talk about this with you.
You're a peculiar boy.
And so, as soon as the Public Security Bureau determines the point of access through Nor...
Mouri Kogoro will be—
Pardon my interruption...
But something serious
is happening right now!
Whoa!
Wha...?!
W-What the...
Mom, this is really bad!
I can't believe this!
What?
What's going on?!
Isn't this pretty bad?!
Wow...
What is all of this?
How long are you going
to keep asking me the same thing?!
The Tokyo metropolitan area...
Which is on high alert due to
the Tokyo Summit being held today...
Is experiencing one baffling
phenomenon after another.
The Metropolitan Police Department has
yet to give an official statement on this.
And not just within our nation...
But voices of unease and criticism from the countries participating in the summit...
Continue coming into
the Japanese government.
We've also received reports of computers and electric kettles exploding...
What on earth happened?
I repeat.
Today...
What's the attacker trying
to accomplish by doing this?
Electrical appliances...
allow easy-to-use
MultiControl!
Wasn't that easy, Daddy?!
It turned out great!
"Simply by setting the pressure, temperature,
and time from one's smartphone..."
"One can prepare
soup and other such meals."
So that's it!
This terrorism began with the explosion at the venue of the summit!
What's the situation?
The phone dispatch
headquarters is in a state of panic!
There's currently over 100 locations throughout the city that have been hit!
What in the world is going on?!
Is this an act of terror?
Are you going to
make a statement about this?!
Conan-kun?
I'm sorry, but there's no
time to talk with you right now...
Inspector Megure!
I'm sure that this is all IoT terrorism!
"I-O-T terrorism"?
The terrorist is indiscriminately attacking electrical appliances that can access the internet!
So these attacks can be stopped by disconnecting them from the internet!
IoT terrorism, huh?
What a kid...
The pressure cooker found at the scene of the explosion is also an IoT appliance!
Once the terrorist controlled
the gas main over the internet...
And filled the scene with gas...
They used the IoT
pressure cooker as the ignition...
To blow up the venue of the summit!
T-Then that means...
Yeah.
Uncle Kogoro
couldn't have done it.
Is that true?
Wha...?
T-That's what Shin'ichi-niichan said,
so please look into it, Inspector!
Conan-kun.
Shin'ichi's doing a lot
to help my dad, isn't he?
You silly girl...
I'm not doing
this just for your dad.
So that's it.
If that's true, we may
be able to win this trial.
Yeah!
Because with Uncle being held by the police,
he can't access the internet right now!
No...
If one sets the
time and date in advance...
IoT terrorism is possible, even
after being held in police custody.
Wha...?
If they can trace the
server and find the access point...
Mouri-san's charge will become final.
That can't be!
But isn't tracing a server very hard?
Will they be able to
finish by the time of the trial...?
Public Security is handling the investigation, so it shouldn't be hard at all.
Wait!
How do you know that Public Security is handling the investigation?
What?
Oh, I'm sorry.
You see, little one...
Because Public Security is often the one that handles these types of investigations.
Public Security has many
"collaborators" working with them.
By "collaborators", you mean civilians who assist in the Public Security officer's investigation?
That's right.
Particularly with the
"Act on Wiretapping"...
Those who manage a server that's going to be investigated often cooperate with Public Safety.
If they find someone like
that who'll cooperate with them...
They should also be able to find evidence of Mouri-san's unauthorized access.
Oh...
That's only if any such
evidence exists, of course!
Oh, that thing's fine.
Just leave it.
Do you think we should?
Yes, I do.
Let's ask the manufacturer to help.
I knew it.
What is this uneasy feeling?
There's still something about her...
Regarding the continuing
string of chaotic events...
The Metropolitan Police Department...
Released a statement saying there's a high probability of them being IoT terrorist attacks.
I certainly didn't
think this was IoT terrorism.
I should have expected you to
see through such a elaborate trick.
I'm not the one
who saw through it...
But thanks to this, we succeeded
in having it processed as an crime.
As such, I want to bear the
weight of the illegal work we did.
It's time to release our "cooperator".
Before we do...
Please tell me what
information you've found so far.
Right.
NAZU?!
We'll release this info to
the Anti-Cybercrime Division...
And have the Criminal Investigation Division report it at the investigation meeting.
You're going to give the
Criminal Investigation Division credit?
That should be reported
from our own Public Security.
Heh.
This is a reward.
It's thanks to the Criminal Investigation Division that the terrorist bombings were processed as a crime.
Besides...
The fact that this info came from "Zero"...
Has already been conveyed to the attaché behind the scenes.
You're frightening, Furuya-san.
Kazami.
To me, there are two men
much more frightening than I am.
And one of them...
Is still just a child.
That just brought to mind the same child you're thinking of, Furuya-san.
We've received a report that traces showing Mouri-san's computer had been hacked were found.
It was used as a relay point, after all.
And where do those traces lead?
Because it was accessed from an unknown smartphone connected to public Wi-Fi...
We were unable to determine that.
But at that time...
Mouri-san was being held in the Detention House by the prosecution...
And it was not possible for
him to be near an access point.
Furthermore, the hacking in
the current IoT terrorist attacks...
Also used Nor, the same
method as this previous attack.
So the attacks were
carried out by the same person...
How is the investigation into
identifying the server progressing?
According to a report from
the Anti-Cybercrime Division...
They've found that the
system is located in NAZU.
I'm very sorry I'm late!
Kuriyama-san!
No, I'm sorry you had to
come while you were on vacation.
Not at all.
As your secretary...
I can't be out having fun during this serious matter you're having, ma'am!
You're a real lifesaver.
Let's see here...
Here's the results of the examination
I did on Attorney Tachibana Kyoko.
What?
Huh?
Kudo Shin'ichi-kun requested that I do this.
Shin'ichi did?
What...?
So Shin'ichi-niichan asked
you to do something like that?
Why look into Tachibana-sensei...?
Hey...
Oh?
This is Shin'ichi-niichan we're talking about,
so I'm sure he has a good reason.
For now, why not take a look at it?
I found that one of Tachibana-sensei's
clerks caused an incident last year.
What?
But Tachibana-sensei
is a "mobi-ttorney".
Her law office closed last year.
It was because a man named Haba Fumikazu,
who had been one of her clerks at the time...
Broke into a game company,
committed the act of larceny...
And was arrested.
Worse yet, Haba committed suicide in the Detention House after his case was sent to prosecution.
What?! Suicide?
Suicide...
What do you mean?
We now know that Mouri Kogoro's computer is being controlled and manipulated by someone.
As such, there's a very low chance that he's the one behind these attacks.
And so, that's that.
But what about his fingerprints that were on the door to the ignitable cable?
Oh...
You see, burned-on fingerprints...
Are easy to transfer.
Is that Public Security's conclusion?
Do not indict Mouri Kogoro!
You do everything Public Security says,
even down to deciding not to indict?
You sure are obstinate!
What?!
It happened to Prosecutor Iwai, too?
Yes.
She suffered minor burns, but she's being cared for at the hospital.
Don't tell me that
was IoT terrorism, too?
When we examined her smartphone...
We found that it was accessed from Nor,
just like what has happened so far—
Excuse me.
This is Shiratori.
What?!
Hold on a moment.
They decided not
to prosecute Mouri-san!
Mom!
Isn't that great, Ran-neechan?
It is, thanks.
I've got to tell Shin'ichi
and Sonoko about this, too!
By the way, what
should we do with these?
This is the record on Haba Fumikazu
that the prosecution examined.
Wait...
The person listed is Prosecutor Iwai, the one who was burned by her smartphone catching fire.
So she was the
lead prosecutor last year.
Yes.
But now, she's
the Prosecutor General...
Making her Prosecutor Kusakabe's superior,
though they started the same year.
That's right.
Strangely enough,
that's because Prosecutor Iwai...
Took advantage of the Haba Fumikazu larceny case in order to further her career.
By the way, what is this?
Why are you looking into
me and my former clerks?
Um...
My apologies.
I wanted to know more about you,
so I asked Kuriyama-san to do that for me.
She sure did her research.
It looks like you're
also an excellent clerk.
"You're also"?
It's almost as if you're saying that Haba-san was like that, too...
But wasn't that man a bad clerk...
Who committed larceny and caused your law office to shut down, Kyoko-sensei?
That wasn't Fumikazu's fault!
It was because I was powerless.
So you call him by his first name.
For you to call a clerk who worked at your law office "Fumikazu"...
Did you read that he committed
suicide at the Detention House?
Oh? Yes...
That suicide...
Happened right after he was examined by
Public Security officers at the Detention House.
Last year, he pushed someone we were examining
at the Detention House into committing suicide.
Why was Public Security examining him?
I haven't heard anything about that.
Peculiar things like that had been happening one after another, leading to Fumikazu's suicide.
Excuse me...
But wasn't Haba Fumikazu-san denied an apprenticeship at the institute?
You mean he was
aiming to be a judge?
Yes, that's right.
But after his completion ceremony at the Judicial Research and Training Institute...
He...
Those who will go on from here to become judges or attorneys...
The fact that you met here will be—
Chief! Chief!
I...
I want an explanation about why my application was rejected!
What do you want...?
I want... to hear the reason...
you denied... my judicial apprenticeship!
For no reason...
You stole my goal
of becoming a judge from me!
You stole it!
You'll pay for this!
I'll make you pay!
I'LL MAKE YOU PAY!
Because that behavior was regarded as him running wild due to a self-satisfying sense of justice...
Not only his path
to becoming a judge...
But also to becoming
an attorney vanished...
And his life in law was cut short.
Why did you make
Haba-san your clerk?
You see, there's two
sides of the coin to everyone.
And what you see of
them is a mere one side.
I heard from your daughter outside.
If Mouri-san is no longer
going to be prosecuted...
I guess I'm no longer needed.
Oh?
W-Well, I suppose so...
Then, I still have
some investigating left to do...
You're looking into Nor,
which the attacker's using, aren't you?
Yes.
And we've requested NAZU's cooperation in the investigation.
NAZU?
You mean in the United States?
That's right.
You see, NAZU had a hacking incident last year that also used Nor.
Oh, the one that
Kyoko-sensei defended...
As a result of that...
A system able to trace
Nor users was completed at NAZU.
So first thing tomorrow, we're going to have them analyze this for us.
Since NAZU is pressed for time today with their "Swan" splashdown mission.
Isn't that the unmanned space probe?
Yes.
With that happening, on top of the summit taking place on the same day...
All of us in the MPD
are also pretty hard-strained.
That's right...
The summit also starts today.
Public Security has many
"collaborators" working with them.
Is that...
Kyoko-sensei's ringtone?!
Why can I hear Kyoko-sensei's voice through the bug on Detective Kazami?
Is a killer.
Well, I just felt like I've
seen this somewhere before...
No way.
It can't be.
Midori-san!
"Send the detailed documents about the NAZU hacking incident to my smartphone immediately!"
That's what Shin'ichi-niichan was saying!
Oh, Conan-kun!
We're going to go down to the police station to pick up Dad now...
Oh, come on...
And why won't
Shin'ichi answer his phone?
It looks like
you knew I was coming.
I first realized
something felt off back then.
Pardon me.
Y-Yes, sir.
When I had the Professor look into it, there was a remote control app installed on it.
The type that doesn't place an icon.
What proof do you have
that Public Security installed it?
There wasn't any.
But I expected as much.
Why didn't you remove the app, even though you knew it was there?
Because I'm going to meet
the one behind all of this now.
Don't tell me you
figured out who the terrorist is?!
Yeah, and their motive too.
Their motive is...
All of you guys, Amuro-san!
It all started with the
NAZU hacking incident.
That took place last year—
Haba Fumikazu?
That's right.
Didn't Haba-san commit suicide at the Detention House last year?
Yeah...
It was last year, on this very day.
It happened...
One year ago, today?!
So that's it.
How could this be happening?!
I'm sure the terrorist still hasn't finished taking out their revenge!
IoT terrorism, again?!
Amuro-san!
Go!
"Swan" Returns Tonight
Special Breaking News
The unmanned space probe, "Swan" is returning to Earth at long last!
"Swan" Returns Tonight
Special Breaking News
Good evening, everyone.
I'm here at the National Astronomical Observatory of Japan, in Nagano Prefecture.
Oh, wow...
It's already this late.
I need to send you guys home.
What?!
Even when "Swan"
is coming back soon?
Please let us
watch the TV broadcast!
Yeah!
No, you can't.
Go watch it at home.
How could you, Haibara-san...?
Oh?
What is it?
Oh, the kids are wanting
to watch the broadcast of that.
Wha...?
How much time until
it enters the atmosphere?
Um, I think it was...
Kudo-kun?
Less than an hour left?!
There's no time!
Conan-kun, is the terrorist
doing what I think they are?
Yeah!
They plan on hacking into
NAZU and making it crash!
But where in the world are they?!
Damn.
I never would have thought...
This would come from the sky!
Oh!
He's here!
Sir!
Dad!
H-Hi.
Welcome back!
I'm sure I worried you, Ran.
I'm really so glad.
And you too, Eri.
I'm sorry for all of this.
What are you talking about?
I'm so happy for you, Ran!
Thanks, Sonoko.
Hey, I know!
I'll send this emotional
scene to that mystery geek!
Wait a second, Sonoko!
Then, can I join in, too...?
With this, you should
be able to contact him!
Okay, say cheese!
Huh?
A blackout?
What's going on?
Someone, please
turn on the backup lights!
Inspector!
It seems the emergency
generator has been destroyed!
What?!
What in the world is going on here?!
I have a report from NAZU!
They confirmed that their unmanned space probe has been hacked into!
What did you just say?!
With things as they are...
They said they can't
separate the capsule!
The main body of "Swan"
will burn up in the atmosphere...
But once they found that the landing point of the capsule is off course...
It seems that all of NAZU is in a frenzy!
I'm sending you the latest data on the estimated landing point!
139 degrees, 45 minutes,
8.405 seconds east longitude.
According to NAZU, its
predicted landing point will be...
What?! Isn't this...?
How can this be happening?!
Conan-kun!
I knew it.
The terrorist is targeting...
The Metropolitan Police Department!
The capsule's going to
hit the MPD headquarters?!
What's going on here?!
If a capsule that's over
four meters wide strikes here...
There will be unimaginable damage and harm!
Arrange for large personnel
carriers as quickly as possible!
And order an immediate evacuation within a one kilometer radius from the MPD headquarters!
Yes, sir!
What about an evacuation map?
There's no time for that!
Dad...
Don't worry.
I'm here with you.
And Eri...
Don't you leave my side!
I-I won't...
Way to go.
The capsule that
separated from the probe...
Will only come
crashing down like a meteorite!
In other words, its trajectory can only be controlled
in the short time before it enters the atmosphere!
Within a one kilometer
radius from the MPD headquarters...
There are various government offices, parks, and several hotels.
That's approximately 150,000 evacuees, just as a rough estimate!
In regards to evacuation
shelters for that many people...
I've put together a list of proposed sites within a one kilometer vicinity, along with routes to them.
Prime Minister, sir!
We have received a report from NAZU that they are unable to modify its memory!
What?!
The signal sent from
mission control to the probe...
Is encrypted by a specific code.
But it seems they can't overwrite its memory if that code doesn't match!
So you're saying that the
terrorist changed the code?!
Yeah.
When they hacked into NAZU and changed the probe's trajectory!
We have to have them tell us
what they changed the code to!
I'd like you to be my
cooperator in order to do that...
Along with the professor who
made something as incredible as this!
What're you going to do?!
I'm going to bring
the dead back to life!
For him to come up with a plan like this, he's as impressive as ever.
Well, it'll be great if we
can get the code through this...
Do you think I managed to make it speed up even more than before?!
Professor!
The video's shaky!
The plan won't work out, at this rate!
Well, this is my
first time flying it at night...
Whoa!
A drone at night!
I wanna try it, too!
It's very unfair for only
you and her to do it, Professor!
You guys are here?
Yeah, because
"Swan" isn't on the TV!
I guess you're right.
Then, can I ask for your help?
I feel uneasy with
the Professor's piloting.
Wow!
Alright!
I'm really looking forward to this!
Ow!
That's what you have to say?
Let's let the kids handle this...
While we continue
getting everything ready.
We are...
The drone...
Flying squad!
Go!
Starting now...
Appropriately 30,000
people will take shelter...
At "Edge of Ocean", built on reclaimed land near Tokyo Bay.
Where was that?
I have no idea!
Um...
Is that where they had
planned to hold the summit?
Indeed.
We will be taking
shelter in Casino Tower.
Casino Tower?
Oh!
That's it, over there!
Oh, right.
I've got to let Shin'ichi know.
NAZU is continuing to send the code...
But, just like we thought, it seems they can't access the probe.
Dammit!
We've got to hurry and
have them tell us the code...!
Isn't that the data they can see at NAZU's mission control center...
Mr. Terrorist?
Prosecutor Kusakabe...
I never would have thought it was you.
And who are you two?
I should have realized this sooner...
Back when I saw the
summary of evidence you submitted.
Those glass shards were a
piece of the true point of ignition...
Of which only the one
behind the explosion would know.
But you submitted that as evidence...
When everyone still believed the point of ignition was a high voltage cable!
Nice timing.
These are the documents pertaining to the trial on last year's NAZU hacking incident...
In which you headed the case.
So that's it.
The method used in that incident also involved hacking in using Nor.
You used the same method
as the case you headed...
In order to commit acts
of cyber terrorism, didn't you?
But that's where
you made your error.
NAZU had already completed a system that could trace hackers.
Knowing that, you used a
version of Nor that had a bug...
To access your superior's
smartphone and make it explode...
While having it appear
to be an act of IoT terrorism.
You did so in order to have
the police identify that dummy.
That's why the timing of that
IoT terrorist attack was strange, wasn't it?
Don't touch my belongings!
Stop!
There are traces of having
used Nor on that smartphone!
Seriously!
You're not getting away!
Damn!
It didn't work?!
Not a problem!
Damn you!
Prosecutor Kusakabe...
Was Public Security really your motive for engaging in these acts of terror?!
If the venue of the
summit was blown up...
And the United States'
space probe crashed into Tokyo...
Public Security would lose every scrap of prestige and dignity it has!
Why do you detest Public Security
to the point you'd go that far?!
As long as you all have power...
Our own Public Security Department
can't carry out complete justice!
So you're saying that it's okay for people to die if it's for the sake of justice?!
I didn't intend to kill any civilians.
That's why I blew it up when only the Public Security officers were there...
Chose IoT terrorism, in which fatalities were unlikely to arise...
And even chose that spot over there for the place the capsule will crash!
So the reason you made the
MPD headquarters have a blackout...
Was to have the
civilians inside evacuate?
Yeah.
So that's it.
And you committed IoT terrorist attacks on all the roads leading here...
In order to stop anyone
from entering this area.
Even so, you should know there was a fair chance that someone could fall victim to it!
For the sake of justice,
a few sacrifices are unavoidable!
That's not justice!
Even...
Even the man
who was my cooperator...
Became a victim.
You mean Haba-san?
I knew it.
He was your cooperator.
H-How did you know that...?
It was the PIN number
set for your passcode.
It caught my attention
because it was so unusual.
But the reason you didn't turn off the input sound was so you wouldn't forget...
About Haba Fumikazu.
No!
It was to burn my desire to exact revenge on these guys into my mind!
All cooperators of the
Public Security officers report to Zero...
And are managed by number.
But Public Security officers don't know about each other's cooperators.
And until last year, we knew even less about a Public Security prosecutor having a cooperator!
That's why you so easily discarded the man who was my cooperator back then?!
So that's it.
You had a ulterior motive...
The act of larceny
Haba-san committed last year!
I-It was me who
asked Haba to do that.
In order to investigate
the NAZU hacking incident.
Haba, who knew that access data was at the game company where our suspect had been seen coming and going...
Tried to make off with it.
Those cooperating with Public Security are illegally forced to undergo risky examinations.
It's for that very reason that the relationship
between Public Security and their cooperators...
Is stronger than that of blood relatives.
By no means is it a relationship where they're only connected by money!
They're one in body and soul,
bonded by a common sense of duty.
During the examination, why didn't you tell them you were my cooperator?!
I can't let your status as a Public Security prosecutor be snatched away from you because of my mistake.
Now's the time to think
about your yourself more than me!
I know the pain of having a position of justice taken away better than anyone.
Please!
Think of your own life!
"The lives of the many Japanese people are far more important than my own."
I have the same resolve you had
when you always used to say that.
I told the head prosecutor
over his larceny case everything.
Haba is my cooperator.
And I'm the one who had
him commit an act of larceny.
Even so, we will indict him.
What?!
Don't tell me this is the
Public Security Bureau again?!
Don't worry.
I'll have the trial work out
so that he doesn't utter your name.
That's not what I'm talking about!
The next day, when I was headed to the MPD headquarters to try to negotiate with their Public Security directly...
Yes?
Huh?
Haba was driven to suicide—
No...
Was murdered by Public Security!
Because of that, you came up with this plan to crash the probe into the MPD headquarters...
Yes.
Ever since I found out that "Swan" was
returning to Earth on the anniversary of Haba's death.
And the IoT terrorism?
That wasn't in my plan...
But as a prosecutor, I couldn't allow an innocent man to get indicted.
You committed IoT terrorist attacks just to prove that Mouri Kogoro wasn't the one behind the bombing?
Yes.
But it was on the spur of the moment...
So the number of victims
far surpassed my expectations.
You must not
commit any further crimes!
Tell me what you changed
the code to when you hacked in!
Public Security officers are
professionals at defending justice!
Justice mustn't be lost, like
what happened with with Haba!
Tell us the code!
You can just
go ahead and arrest me!
And in the examination,
I'll remain silent about everything!
Prosecutor Kusakabe!
Kusakabe-san.
That's impossible!
How is Haba...?!
This is a live video from the heliport at the MPD headquarters.
What's going on here?!
The Public Security officer who examined him at the Detention House...
Made it as though he had committed suicide, allowing him to renounce the life he had led to that point.
That was done in order to suppress the fact that he had been the Public Security prosecutor's cooperator.
And also...
In order to make sure Public Security prosecutors could never again have someone be their cooperator.
That fact was hidden, even from you.
"Bear the weight of your
illegal work on your own."
You don't have
the power to do that!
That's what Public Security has decided!
With as much as Haba-san had his heart set on becoming a judge...
He must have had a very
strong sense of justice, didn't he?
That precisely why he,
who had his legal apprenticeship denied...
And had nowhere to go
decided to be your cooperator.
That's right.
Kusakabe-san, you pulled me up
out of the darkest point of my life.
We had only worked
together for a mere two years...
But, Kusakabe-san...
You told me, "It's because of you that I can fight as a Public Security prosecutor."
That's why I can
fight like this, even now.
Kusakabe-san!
Please tell them what
you changed the code to!
If it crashes there, Haba couldn't possibly go uninjured, either!
This is dirty!
So this is how Public
Security officers operate?!
"Swan" will enter the
atmosphere any moment now!
Don't they have the code, yet?!
At this rate, they'll become
unable to access the probe at all!
Furuya-san,
there's no more time!
Hurry up and tell us the code!
Quickly, Prosecutor Kusakabe!
But...
Kusakabe-san.
Is that your form of justice?
The one I believed in?
When I hacked into NAZU...
I changed the code to...
What?!
A communications blackout?!
Yes, for a brief period of five minutes after it re-enters the atmosphere!
So, apparently, because a layer of
plasma forms around it during that time...
They're unable to
maintain contact with it...
And they won't know for sure whether its trajectory was corrected!
Moreover, there's a chance
that its parachute won't open!
No way!
Let me...
Let me get Haba away from there
and find shelter, quickly!
Prosecutor Kusakabe!
Did you hear anything
from Shin'ichi-kun?
No, not yet.
Though I left him a voicemail.
Oh, come on!
What is that guy doing?!
And it looks like
Conan-kun's battery is dead...
This is that twerp we're
talking about, so I'm sure he's fine.
At any rate, this
place is awfully tall, isn't it?
Okay, let's hurry and go.
This way!
Haba!
Where are you?!
What's going on here?
He isn't here.
B-But on your phone,
he definitely was here.
What you were seeing
was a superimposed video.
Wha...?!
Using video
filmed with a drone...
We edited it to make it appear as if he was on the heliport of the MPD headquarters.
He's currently in a safe place.
So that's it.
Amuro-san.
If, by some chance, they
weren't able to correct its trajectory...
Is the place it'll strike really be...
Yes.
The over four meter wide capsule...
Will come crashing down here,
at a speed of over 10 km/s!
Since it's you, Amuro-san...
Are you able to immediately
get your hands on an explosive?
Do you plan on destroying
the heat-resistant capsule?
No...
The explosive just needs to be able to change its trajectory so it lands in the Pacific Ocean.
What a crazy idea!
Well, is there any other way?
Kazami, carry this out immediately.
Yes.
This is the "illegal work"
that Public Security excels at!
Among the explosives that Public Security's forensics experts seized...
This one is the most powerful.
And it's not being tracked?
Because the deadline for
its disposal is approaching...
It'll be fine, as long as we
rewrite the records on it.
Okay, then please do.
That's not a problem.
We'll send the data on the capsule's expected trajectory to your address.
Okay, you guys!
It's takeoff time!
Understood!
Yay! Alright!
"Calculate where we should have it explode" is easier said than done...
Honestly!
They sure know how to use people!
Mitsuhiko-kun... Ayumi-kun...
Genta-kun...
And Ai-kun...
You four must
defend this country!
Huh?
The drone's body is wavering.
Maybe the Professor's
package is too heavy?
Let's just leave it
around there and keep going!
N-No, you mustn't!
That package is my
precious, irreplaceable treasure!
I've narrowed the margin of error
to within a ten meter radius!
I'll send you the video from the drone...
So I'll leave the timing
adjustments to your end.
Right, and I'm counting on you.
But is this really okay?
I mean, for us to film the
capsule from "Swan" up close...
It's fine.
We have permission from the police.
Though it's from the
MPD's Public Security Bureau.
What?!
The parachute won't open?!
It seems the heat shield is locked.
Prime Minister, sir!
Issue an order to shoot it down!
Please wait!
But...
If we intercepted it at this altitude...
There's a possibility that it
would only cause further damage!
It's just crossed an
altitude of 30,000 meters.
Yes.
All right.
Don't be careless about this.
Roger that!
Amuro-san.
Can you get the
timing down with this?
Yeah.
We're approaching the capsule!
Everyone's counting on you guys.
We'll hit it if we
keep going like this.
I-It'll be fine!
That drone is equipped with a system that
automatically dodges when it detects an approaching object!
If you guys don't get close to it,
we won't be able to see the capsule flying!
I want to see it!
Go, Mitsuhiko!
All right!
Kudo-kun...
Don't be reckless with this.
Here it comes!
Go!
The parachute... opened!
What?
Nothing's showing
on the screen anymore.
Don't tell me we hit it?
Doesn't it have a system
that automatically dodges?
What?
Oh, it probably...
Ran out of batteries!
Or rather, it didn't
have any such system, so...
Looks like it all worked out.
You sure surprised me.
Who in the world are you guys?
I guess you could say we're a little detective boy's "cooperators"?
What?
Right.
Copy that.
It was a success.
Thank goodness.
Furuya-san.
We will now arrest him
and turn him over to the police.
Right.
Wait!
Kusakabe-san.
Even now,
we're one in body and soul.
Yeah.
Alright. Let's go.
Fumikazu!
Kyoko!
Fumikazu...
I never imagined you still were alive.
You truly are a
fearsome person, aren't you?
To think you were one
of their cooperators, too...
And with the Public
Security prosecutor, no less!
Kyoko-sensei.
You were also a
cooperator, weren't you?
One of Detective Kazami's, I mean.
Didn't you ask me earlier, little one?
About why I hired Fumikazu.
Because he had his
legal apprenticeship denied...
Public Security had their eyes on him as someone who needed special attention.
And so...
I was ordered to hire him
and report his behavior to them.
But while working with Fumikazu...
For some reason, I began
feeling strongly attracted to him.
I felt the same way.
It's for that very reason...
That I'm really sorry
things turned out like this.
To think you were one of
their cooperators, just like I was.
Everything began with the
NAZU hacking incident, didn't it?
Yes.
Since Public Security had told me to make their suspect be found guilty...
I had been moving
forward with the examination.
That was when...
He was caught at the game company where their suspect had been coming and going.
I didn't know why he
did something like that.
I desperately asked
Public Security to help him.
But he committed suicide.
I resented Public Security!
So I closed my law office...
And aimed for a chance to exact
my revenge as one of their cooperators.
And that's when you were appointed to defend Uncle Kogoro...
So he'd be found not guilty, wasn't it?
Yes.
I didn't know why Public Security wanted him to be found not guilty...
But if that's what they wanted,
I thought I'd make him be found guilty!
So you dragged people into
this who weren't even involved?!
What else could I have done?!
I never would have thought...
That he was alive and
under Public Security's protection.
If I had only known...
I never would have done this.
So right now,
Fumikazu's your cooperator?
What number is he?
"What number?"
Doesn't Public Security refer to us by number behind the scenes?
I'm "2-2-9-1".
So what number is he?!
Tachibana Kyoko.
I release you from being one of Public Security's cooperators.
Isn't that fine, Kazami?
"You must bear the weight
of illegal work on your own."
That was how Public
Security operates, wasn't it?
This is where Haba is.
You're free now.
If you want to see him,
we won't stop you.
Don't act so conceited!
I'm the one who decided
to be your cooperator!
I'm the one
who decided to betray you!
And I'm the one
who decided to love him!
Don't ever think you all were
in control of every part of my life!
Goodbye.
Kyoko...
No matter how much she despises us,
we will protect her until the very end.
That's...
What we do in Public Security.
Thanks to you...
We managed to arrest a terrorist who showed contempt for Japan.
When did you first
believe it was terrorism?
It was all just as you inferred.
While I was inspecting the international convention center that day...
I found that the gas main
could be accessed via the internet.
But right when I considered the possibility
of a terrorist bombing that used that...
And issued orders to
Public Security's forensics experts...
But based on the state
of the scene of the explosion...
It was also possible that it
could be processed as an accident.
And so, you created a suspect.
And why, as quickly as possible, we wanted to transfer that suspect from the police...
To the Public Security prosecutor who would do everything Public Security said.
So that's why you sent Kyoko-sensei in as a defense attorney...
And why you released Uncle Kogoro once any leads to it being an accident were eliminated.
You sure are incredible,
to have seen through all the mysteries.
No, there's still one
mystery I haven't figured out yet.
And that's—
Your phone.
Huh?
It's been lit up for a while now.
Oh, Shin'ichi?
I'm taking shelter in the
Casino Tower at Edge of Ocean right now.
Yes?
Call me when you get this message.
What?!
The capsule's going where?!
Due to an explosion
of unknown origin...
It will strike down on the reclaimed land near Tokyo Bay at this rate!
And on one part
of that reclaimed land...
Stands "Edge of Ocean",
where 30,000 people are taking shelter!
We can no longer intercept it!
Relax!
There's still time!
Please don't panic!
Everyone,
please remain calm!
All of you will be able to board the vehicles,
just like when we came here!
Inspector!
Due to conflicting reports, regular people brought their vehicles to take shelter here!
What?!
And with only two bridges,
traffic is completely congested!
This is really bad.
Everyone's panicking!
Shin'ichi...
Damn!
It won't connect!
I can't get a hold of Ran!!
What should we do?
There's no more time!
Amuro-san, this time I'm going to have you be my cooperator!
There's a traffic jam up ahead.
Aren't they giving
proper evacuation instructions?!
So that's Casino Tower?
Furuya-san!
The parachute came off
the capsule, and it's gaining speed!
And...?!
We've received its estimated
landing point from NAZU!
At this rate, it's going to strike Casino Tower in less than five minutes!
Ran...!
Damn it!
What do we do?! What do we do?!
Amuro-san!
Hold on tight!
What are you doing, Amuro-san?!
It's here!
I thought I was gonna die there.
Still, that was incredible.
So?
What do we do?
O-Oh, hold on a second.
Head towards this building
that's under construction!
Okay!
Don't get separated, you guys.
We won't!
This has turned into quite
a chaotic situation, hasn't it?
Can we make it?
Considering the height of this building
and its distance from Casino Tower...
We should, if we speed up from
here in about one minute.
This is do-or-die!
So please, make it in time!
Ran...!
W-What?
The power of love
sure is great, isn't it?
Huh...?
I've been wanting to
ask you this for a long time...
But do you have
a girlfriend, Amuro-san?
My... lover is...
This country, itself!
Let's go, Amuro-san!
Can we move it by
even just a millimeter?
That's what I'm planning on!
Five, four...
Three, two, one...
Zero!
It's no use,
we're not high enough!
Bring it on!
Go!
Ran!
Dad!
Ran...
I'll handle the rest.
You need to go right now, too!
There's still one thing
I haven't figured out.
Why did you drag
Uncle Kogoro into this?
I can't publicly investigate
things due to my position.
But if he got caught up in the incident,
you would naturally become my cooperator.
And if that happened...
Doesn't that mean I could
borrow some of your true strength?
You really overestimate me.
"Just like a handbook on a crime,
the police's test samples were manipulated."
Having committed this series of terrorist attacks with such an unusual motive, the former public prosecutor...
Kusakabe Makoto will be dealt with by the Metropolitan Police Department as the suspect—
Looks like "Public Security"
vanished from his motive.
I'm sure that was the decision
of the Public Security Bureau.
It safely splashed down in Tokyo Bay...
And inside the capsule that was retrieved from the "Swan" space probe...
Yum!
Was a substance
which originated from Mars.
It was presented among great expectations of it helping to clarify some of the mysteries of the universe.
Wow!
But I wanted to see it with the drone.
If only we hadn't
had the Professor's package...
Those kids aren't thinking a thing about how they contributed to retrieving the capsule.
Yeah...
And they even
helped Japan out of a crisis.
They're truly amazing.
Alright!
Let's use the Professor's
drone to explore Mars, too!
That sounds great!
Yeah, let's do that!
Please make a new one, Professor!
Make us a bigger one!
Oh?
Well, I guess I'll do the best I can...
I'm really looking forward to Mars!
Same here! Same here!
No, that isn't possible.
Let's meet again...
On the ship that
floats above the night sky.