15 years ago, Northern Atlantic Ocean
Kaidou Wataru (41)
Number 1 St. Yashiro, First-Mate
Iceberg, 12 o'clock!
Hard to port!
Captain...
Captain, are you all right?!
Excuse me.
Captain...
Captain!
Please hold on, Captain!
First-mate...
Half a month ago, Nishitama City
Yashiro
Yashiro Hideto (49)
Yashiro Cruiser Designer
It's so beautiful.
I wish I could show Shinichi this beautiful sunset.
I see it.
Wha... What?!
You'll be able to see better from up here.
It's true that I can see better now,
but what an embarrassing position...
We saw that, Conan!
Crap!
Let me down, Ran-neechan!
We saw you, we saw you!
We saw you! You were indulging
with Ran-san again, weren't you?
Idiot, it's nothing like that!
Your face is red, Conan-kun.
What are you talking about?
That's just because of the sunset.
He's turning red!
Stupid! No, I'm not!
What are you talking about?
I'm telling you, it's because of the sunset!
It's the same as that time.
Eh? What is?
It's nothing.
What is it? Tell me!
I'm telling you, it's nothing!
Detective CONAN
Strategy Above The Depths
I'm high school detective Kudou Shinichi.
Original story: Aoyama Gosho
While I went to an amusement park
with my childhood friend Mouri Ran...
I witnessed a suspicious transaction by a man in black.
Script: Furuuichi Issei
Because my attention was focused on the transaction,
I didn't notice another member
approaching me from behind.
Music: Oono Katsuo
He forced me to take some poison.
And when I came to...
My body had shrunk!
Character Design: Sudou Masatomo
If the men in black find out that Kudou Shinichi is still alive,
they'll come after me again and endanger the lives of my friends and family.
Art Director: Shibuya Yukihiro
Construction: Nishi Kayoko
Following Professor Agasa's advice,
I decided to hide my identity.
Director of Photography: Nomura Takashi
Director of Sound: Izawa Ki
When Ran asked my name,
I suddenly blurted out, "Edogawa Conan."
In order to get information about the men in black,
I moved in with Ran and her father, a detective.
I'm from Teitan Elementary Grade 1,
Class B. Kojima Genta.
The same, Tsuburaya Mitsuhiko.
Yoshida Ayumi.
Along with my apprentice, Conan...
And Ai-chan...
We are the Detective Boys!
These sparkling detective badges on our chests
each contain a microscopic transceiver.
They also have homing signals.
It's the very latest technology!
These wristwatch flashlights are waterproof,
so you can even use them in the ocean!
Edogawa Conan: Takayama Minami
These two devices are Professor Agasa's inventions.
The Professor's made other unique
gadgets for the shrunken me.
Most importantly, the Super Bowtie Voice Changer and the Wrist Watch Tranquilizer.
Wrist Watch Tranquilizer
Super Bowtie Voice Changer
Mouri Kogorou: Kamiya Akira
Mouri Ran: Yamazaki Wakana
Thanks to these two devices, the famous detective "Sleeping Kogorou" was born.
You know, Haibara-san's a bit cool.
Or rather mature for her age.
Haibara Ai: Hayashibara Megumi
Dr. Agasa: Ogata Kenichi
Kudou Shinichi: Yamaguchi Kappei
Of course she is.
Haibara Ai's real name is Miyano Shiho.
She was originally a part of the Black Syndicate.
But to get away from the organization, she took the same drug that I'd been forced to take, and her body shrank as well.
And so I, who went from being a high school
detective to an elementary school detective,
have been solving one complex case after another,
As I secretly try to find out
the identities of the men in black.
But Uncle...
Producers:
Suwa Michiko
Yoshioka Masahito
If only his deductions would get a little better...
Even though I'm much smaller,
my intellect remains the same.
The detective with no unsolvable mysteries.
Director: Yamamoto Taiichiro
There's always only one truth!
Wow, it's so big!
It sure is luxurious.
Of course, it is.
Yashiro Group is a pretty big financial group.
This is that 100-million dollar
group's first cruise ship ever built.
It's gotta be this luxurious.
Welcome.
You must be Mouri-sama.
Uh, yes.
We're preparing your seats right now.
Please wait a moment.
Hey Professor. What is that?
This? It's just a regular IC recorder.
I was thinking I could use it to immediately record my thoughts when I get hints or ideas for new inventions.
Oh, speaking of new inventions,
Tada! Cufflink speakers.
It contains a transceiver as well.
That's pretty cool.
These are awesome.
Those are some nice cuff links.
This is great. I'll borrow these for awhile.
But those are...
You idiot. These things are made for dandy men like me.
It's still a bit too early for a kid like you.
But, Dad! Those are...
It's fine, Ran-neechan.
I probably won't need them inside this ship anyways.
Mouri-san?
You're the famous detective,
Mouri Kogorou-san, right?
Yes, that's right...
Cool!
What's with this guy?
I'm a script writer, Kusaka Hironari.
Kusaka Hironari (26)
Script Writer
I'm a big fan of yours, Mouri-san.
Oh, thank you.
Ah, this is...
Akiyoshi Minako-san.
She's a sub-leader of the design team for this ship,
And she gave this ship, the St. Aphrodite, its beautiful name.
Akiyoshi Minako (32)
Yashiro Cruise Designer
I'm Akiyoshi. Nice to meet you.
I'm Mouri...
Wow, she's beautiful.
Yeah...
Excuse me, Mouri-sama.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Your seats have been prepared.
Oh, sorry.
Could you add two more?
It's okay with you, right, Mouri-san?
Yeah...
Then, right this way.
Hey, isn't your dad acting a bit strange?
Why?
Well, because if it were the usual him, then...
"Speaking of Aphrodite, she's the goddess of beauty and love!"
"That name would be better suited
for you rather than for the ship."
That's what he would say, isn't it?
That's probably because
Minako-san resembles my mother.
I see.
Come to think of it, they do look alike.
That means she's the type Uncle
would have a hard time dealing with.
I'm actually writing a drama series
set on a luxury cruise ship.
And I met Minako-san while I was collecting data.
More or less.
I see...
By the way, Mouri-san.
You were invited of course, right?
Or did they hire you to investigate some matters?
Well, how can I say this?
To say it was an invitation...
Actually, that's not it.
It's not?
The ones invited were actually Sonoko's parents.
Her father is the President of Suzuki Financial Group.
But my parent just couldn't make it,
so I came in their place.
And I thought, the more the merrier, so...
She managed to get invitations
for the eight of us as well.
So that's how it was.
Well, you could say that I'm just here as her guardian.
Oh, I see.
I see...
By the way, what kind of story are you writing?
Is it a story where someone goes
around the world on a luxury cruise?
I like that.
Yeah!
Maybe it's a panic story like the Titanic
where the ship sinks in the middle of the ocean.
Hey, Ai-kun...
Speaking of sinking,
There was a case a long time ago
where a Yashiro ship hit an iceberg.
Yes. It was an accident during
the winter about 15 years ago.
I believe that due to the misjudgment of the captain,
One staff member died, and the captain
ended his life along with the ship, too.
Really?
What are we going to do if this ship sinks, too?
I can only swim seven meters.
Don't worry.
The St. Aphrodite has a very good captain.
And there aren't any icebergs
around this part of the ocean.
Although, if the ship sinks, the first ones to be
rescued will probably be those folks over there.
Hey, isn't that Niemi-san, the former captain?
And his company. Also, there's the very talented...
Hey, that's Uruashi Shimai!
No matter how many times I see her, she's still got a nice body.
They were all personally invited by
the President of the Yashiro group.
The Yashiro family has arrived.
Yashiro Takae (51)
Yashiro Cruiser Chief Executive,
Entarou's daughter
Yashiro Entarou (78)
Yashiro Group President
His daughter Takae is married and is
the Chief Executive of Yashiro Cruiser.
Oh, Chief Takae's husband died
in a car accident recently, right?
Really?
Yes. Yashiro Hideto-sensei...
He was my superior and the leader
of this ship's design crew.
I see.
As I recall, he had a heart attack
while he was driving and drove off a cliff.
Hey, it's the captain!
He's so cool!
That's Captain Kaidou Wataru.
Remember the accident 15 years ago
that we talked about earlier?
He was the first-mate of that ship.
What? Something you don't find right?
About Yashiro Hideto-shi's accident?
The fact that his heart attack came while
he was in the middle of descending a hill...
But according to the department's analysis,
there weren't any suspicious points, right?
Yes, but...
Why not? It's not a bad thing to
investigate until you're satisfied.
I'll notify the department.
Thank you, sir.
Satou-san, would you like me to help you?
You still haven't finished your report though, right?
Chiba-kun.
Help me out a bit.
R-right...
Now that the drinks are all set...
Wait. Let me do it, please?
Well, then. To this fun cruise trip,
And to Ran's gold medal at the Kantou competition.
Cheers!
Thank you. Geez, Sonoko...
Hey, Ran-oneesan.
You're amazing, winning first place at the karate tournament.
Kantou Taikai: Is a martial arts tournament, any form of martial arts is allowed, however, only hand to hand combat is allowed.
Not only that, it was the Kantou competition.
That's awesome! Awesome, awesome!
So, did you get some kind of present from Kudou-kun?
Shinichi?
When I told him on the phone
all he said was, "Oh? Good for you".
That's it?
He's probably all caught up
in his investigations on his cases.
That deduction maniac.
That was right after I said
congratulations like mad as Conan...
I'm full!
That was a good steak.
I wish I could eat it every day.
I wonder if dessert is next?
What's wrong?
I think I'm a bit seasick.
Yeah, I'm also a little off...
You just drank too much alcohol.
Ran-chan, so strict...
Geez...
You have a very interesting father.
No, he's just a drunken old man.
I'm sorry. I think I'll leave and rest in my room.
Are you going to be okay?
Yes. I have medicine in my room, so...
Take care...
Hey, Dad! Are you sure you're all right?
Mouri Kogorou is okay!
It's fine, Ran-neechan.
All that's left is to put him in bed, so...
Sorry about this. Then, Conan-kun,
I'll leave Dad to you, okay?
Sure.
I'm sorry, Professor.
It's not a problem.
It's fine, it's fine.
Good night, Ran-chan.
It's open, Professor.
Right.
All right. Us, too.
Yeah.
Well then, Conan-kun.
I'll leave Dad with you, okay?
Eh?
Yo!
We're visiting!
What are you guys doing all together?
We've decided to give something to Ran-san
as a present for winning the competition.
What are these?
They're pretty, huh? We picked them up on that island we visited this afternoon.
We're going to make a gold medal from
these and give it to her as her present.
It's a bit sad that she didn't get
anything from Shinichi-oniisan, right?
Good luck with that.
I'm going to take a bath.
A bath?!
What, you want to join me?
No, that's...
I'll read your schedule for tomorrow.
Your breakfast will be at 7:00 A.M., I will bring you a western-style meal set to your room.
Tsujimoto Natsuho (25)
Purser, Yashiro family's assistant
After that, Chief Takae will be at a squash session with Madam Niemi at 9 A.M.
We've booked a court on the 7th floor.
The President will attend a gathering at 9:30 A.M.
It has been moved to the pool bar on the 3rd floor.
After the squash game, Chief Takae will return to the room around 9:30 A.M.
It feels so good!
Indeed, morning tea is really
something in the salty breeze.
It's really something.
Yeah, it really is something.
It really is something.
Hey, did you see Chief Takae's legs?
They really don't look like they're in their 50's.
Geez, how can you think of such
things so early in the morning?!
Professor, isn't it about that time?
You know, your famous lame quizzes.
If you're going to ask us, then do it fast. It's unsettling.
He's completely being toyed with.
All right, then I'll answer your request
and give the quiz based on this cruise.
It appears that Genta-kun's received some
treatment at the doctor's office on the ship.
Now then, what's happened to Genta-kun?
One.
He ate too much and hurt his stomach.
Two. He twisted his ankle after tripping.
Three. He was out too long in the sun and got heat stroke.
Now then, what's the right answer?
If it's the usual Genta-kun,
then it's choice one, but...
Nope, it's not the first one.
I'll never hurt my stomach no matter how much I eat.
I've got it!
Me, too.
But isn't that riddle a bit hard for kids?
Because you have to use English, and...
Sonoko!
English? English is the hint?
The second hint is "ship".
Ship?
I got it, the answer is "2" where he twisted his ankle.
"Fune" in English is "ship", right?
Genta-kun put a "shippu" on his leg.
Note: a "shippu" is a medicine pack.
That's correct.
Just some extra, "Yuujou" is "Friendship".
"Uwasabanashi" is "Gossip".
Hey, hey. "Gossip" is different.
Well then, I'll see you at 10:00 A.M.
The ship was shippu, huh?
Hey Mitsuhiko, if I was in a fight while I'm
crossing the ocean, then I'll regret it, right?
Note: this is another pun, Goukai means crossing he ocean and Koukai means to regret. So it's a play on the sound of the word.
What the heck is that?
You think you're so good, huh?
Oh yeah. When are we going to give it to her?
We could give it now...
Hey, how about something like this?
Let's go and get the last round of drinks.
All right.
We've gotta bring back tons.
Don't overact about it
We're going to get some drinks too.
Let's go and get some!
What kind of juice should I get?
Right. Let's go!
Wait up!
What are they so excited about?
I know the secret of 15 years ago.
At 10:15 A.M., come to the basement marina.
I see. He really did fall from the road
right outside of his mansion.
Let's go check it out.
What should we do now?
It's still a bit cold to go for a swim.
I have to go and change.
Change?
I got an invitation from Uruashi Shimai.
Apparently, she wants to hear the stories
of the great detective Mouri Kogorou.
Later...
He's a real showoff, huh...
I wonder when he got the invitation.
Let's just leave him.
But what do you all want to do?
I want to play hide and seek.
S-Sounds fun.
Let's do it!
Hide and seek? How nostalgic.
We played it a lot when we were kids.
Yeah. At the park, at my house, and stuff.
I even played it in elementary school once.
Oh, really?
Sorry, but I'll pass.
Let's play, Conan-kun.
You're not being part of the group.
Come to think of it, I think I was
refused by Shinichi at that time, too.
All right! Let's play hide and seek.
Well, I suppose it'll kill some time.
What about you, Professor?
I have a massage reservation I requested.
Like an old man.
Okay, let's decide on the rules.
The time limit is 30 minutes.
The hiding area is from the 1st to the 7th floors.
Cabins and employees-only areas are off-limits.
Same with the bathrooms and the observation room.
How's that?
Agreed.
Well then, everyone. Gather around.
Rock-Paper-Scissors.
Sonoko's the seeker!
Note: in Japanese you would call the seeker "Oni" which in Japanese means monster or demon.
Hold on, impossible! I can't find six people on a ship this big in 30 minutes!
Totally impossible.
Well, let's make another seeker.
Two seekers?
Why not? It's different.
Well then, rock-paper-scissors again.
I look forward to working with you.
M-Me, too...
Heh, he. Quite an unique combination.
Oh. Lend me you detective badge.
Why?
If there are two seekers, then we won't know who's been caught, right?
We're going to communicate with those badges.
Fine. Don't lose it.
Well then, we'll start at 9:50 A.M. So...
if the seekers find everyone by
10:20 A.M. then the seekers win.
Okay, I won't lose!
Too bad, but we'll win because...
We've got Conan-kun.
Even if you say that...
All right, let's go.
Hide and seek... Start!
Yay!
Later.
We'll start in five minutes.
Ran-oneesan didn't notice it.
She'll surely notice it while we're playing.
She'll be so surprised!
All right.
I got it!
I guess this isn't a good place.
When was the movie?
Wasn't it at 10:00 A.M.?
We should get going.
Hurry!
It's gonna start.
That was close.
All right!
Who would have thought that I'd be the seeker?
But, I suppose it's nice to be
on the seeking side for once.
Five minutes have passed.
I'll look from floor five and up.
I'll leave the bottom to you, okay?
S-Sure...
Hey, Kudou-kun.
Hey, Haibara.
You know, I don't think you understand
the meaning of hide and seek.
Got one.
Darn. How did you know?
The ones who eat a lot have always hidden at the cafeteria since the old days.
Whoa! Haibara-san...
I'm guessing you borrowed that from the Professor.
You need to hide where it fits in.
Hey. Come out.
Ah, man. I thought it was a good hiding place.
Nope. You're still ten years too early to beat me.
Hello. This is Akiyoshi.
Hello, Minako-san? It's Kusaka.
Yes.
Well, then. To get right to the point,
Okazaki Nanami, age 20.
An attendant on the luxury cruise St. Sazan Cross.
All right, I'm going to read the story.
Okazaki Nanami loved the ocean ever since she was born.
She loved its vastness more than anything else.
We managed to find these four pretty easily, but...
The hardest one turned out to be the last as suspected.
Ran-san's really good at hiding?
She's like a ninja, a ninja!
Does an ordinary elementary kid
climb on ceilings and dive in ponds?
Ceilings...
Inside ponds...
Wow...
Haha. She's had a lot of
stamina since she was younger.
We still have 12 minutes. Let's find her.
This place isn't it, either.
10:11 A.M.
Geez, there are only nine minutes left.
Sorry to keep you waiting. It's me, Mouri!
I'm taking revenge for my father!
I'm starting the countdown.
5...
4...
3...
2...
1...
Zero!
We win hide and seek!
It's all thanks to ninja Ran-san.
Yeah, yeah.
Ran-oneesan!
I told you we'd win.
Where were you hiding, Ran-neechan?
You were kicking the soccer ball
the entire time, right? I knew it all along.
It doesn't look like Ran-oneesan found it yet.
That's strange.
Maybe she's just slow.
I wonder if she's still looking?
Wha... So cold! What is this?
A box? Am I in an box?
No... Someone... Someone help!
Help! Somebody, help me!
What's wrong, Sonoko-neechan?
Help!
Calm down Sonoko, where are you?
I'm in a box somewhere...
I can't hear you, Sonoko, say that again!
Are the batteries dead?
Shit, back there...
You're cold, Sonoko? It's cold?
She's shivering.
It's the freezer!
Hey! What are you guys doing?
Where's your freezer?
Freezer?
Please, my friend is in trouble!
It's on the second basement floor.
There are so many!
Which one is it?
Let's split up and find her.
Yes.
Sonoko-neechan!
Sonoko-san.
Sonoko! Are you here?
Sonoko-oneesan, where are you?!
It doesn't look like she's here. Let's go outside.
That was cold.
Sonoko, Sonoko! Answer me, Sonoko!
Damn it! Where? Where is she?
Hey, maybe she's already dead...
Don't say such things!
But there isn't any other place that's cold, is there?
Dead...
It's there!
This ship has a place like this?
It's a little bizarre, huh?
It's heavy.
Sonoko!
Sonoko...
Let's get her to the infirmary.
Ha... I'm alive again.
There's no need to worry.
Once she warms her body and relaxes,
she should be able to move soon.
Thank you.
Isn't that great, Sonoko?
But...
Who would pull a prank like this?
Prank? This is no prank.
It's an official murder attempt.
Please call the police immediately.
Y-Yes, sir.
Tell me the story.
Where were you attacked?
At the marina. I went to look for Ran,
then I was suddenly hit on
the shoulder by a stick or something,
And I think I lost consciousness from there.
What about the face of the attacker?
Hmm. I think I saw it, but I don't remember.
What about the time?
Oh, I remember that. It was at 10:11 A.M.
10:11 A.M.
I see. From here, the mortuary is only feet away.
But why was Sonoko-neechan attacked?
This is...
President Yashiro's metallic fan.
Why would it be in a place like this?
No one's here.
Mouri-san! The captain said that the police...
This is President Yashiro's room.
Yeah, I heard from Uruashi Shimai earlier.
Come to think of it, someone came out of this room.
Who?
I didn't see the person's face...
Whoever it was wore a windbreaker and a hood...
What time?
I think it was about 10:15 A.M.
Really, Mouri-san?
That's strange. Neither of them wear a windbreaker,
And at that time, only Chief Takae should have been here.
Hey. Wearing a windbreaker hood in the hallway,
isn't that like the person was
trying to hide his or her face?
Could something have happened to the Chief?
Chief! It's Tsujimoto. Chief!
Hey, you have a master key, right?
But...
Chief, excuse me for intruding.
Chief!
Don't move! Stay here.
That can't be...
Who in the world...
About 30 minutes have passed since she died.
I'll go and tell the captain.
I'll go to the President.
It looks like she was stabbed
when she came out of the bathroom.
The blood on this side has been wiped clean.
But why?
Why only the blood on this side...
What the heck are you doing?
Ouch...
Geez.
Mouri-san!
About President Yashiro.
Niemi-san says he never came back
after he left the billiard room.
What?!
President Yashiro may have gotten
into some trouble as well.
Thanks for coming.
Mouri-san.
Thank you for coming, Chief Inspector.
Have you located President Yashiro?
We still don't know where he is.
The crew split up and searched the entire ship, but...
In the air or on the waters, cases follow
you wherever you go, Mouri-san.
Will it be space next time?
Going to get on some rocket?
Of course not!
What? The President's fingerprints?
Yes, they were focused around the area where traces of blood were discovered at the marina.
Of course, the blood found on the exit door also matched that of President Yashiro.
Thank you. Keep up the good work.
Also, Chief Inspector.
According to the marina employees,
Those doors appeared to have been opened.
Furthermore, they were opened recently.
What?
The fingerprints, the traces of blood, the door's lock.
Chief Inspector, this looks like...
It looks like President Yashiro was
attacked by someone in the marina,
And was thrown into the ocean through the door.
I believe we can safely assume that.
Indeed.
Shiratori-kun, contact the coast guard
and ask for a sweep of the immediate area.
Understood.
Takagi-kun.
Yes.
I want to talk to the Niemi couple as well.
Bring them to me.
Yes, sir.
Now then, Conan-kun.
Yes?
Leave the rest to us.
I want you to return to your room.
Don't go outside unnecessarily.
There's a high chance that the murderer is still on this ship.
Okay.
Wow, there's a cake, too!
It looks delicious.
Roast beef...
I suppose occasionally it's fine...
Not even occasionally.
Oh Professor,
Should we bring Ran-san
and Sonoko-san's meals too?
I'm sure they're hungry, too.
No, we should let the doctors take care of Sonoko-kun.
Ran-oneesan said that she would eat
later so don't worry about it.
I see...
Hey Mitsuhiko,
do you think she found the gold medal?
I don't think Ran-san has had the time
to think about something like that.
I thought so...
Where's Conan-kun?
Come to think of it, he's not here.
Maybe he sneaked out to listen
to the police investigation!
Probably.
It seems he's good at that kind of hide and seek
Thank you for your cooperation.
I probably don't need to say this,
but please catch the culprit as soon as possible.
Yes, sir!
Now, then.
If we assume that Chief Takae was murdered right after she returned to her room from her squash game and took a bath,
I believe we can safely say that the person wearing the windbreaker that Mouri-kun saw leaving her room was the culprit.
If that culprit went down to the basement marina afterwards,
and murdered President Yashiro,
who got called out earlier...
Then it would be just right time-wise as well.
Meaning that these two cases were most likely done by the same individual.
Mouri-kun, what about the culprit's characteristics?
The height was about 170 cm.
And it was a fairly skinny individual.
With just the height, we can't be certain whether it was a male or female.
Come to think of it, the murdered Chief Takae
was about the same height as well.
Tsujimoto-san, is that the...
Yes.
As a complimentary item for being on
this ship, we gave one to each guest.
But if they really wanted to, the crew
could have gotten a hold of one, right?
Shiratori-kun, what about the culprit's motives?
I believe we can say it was a grudge.
The victim's jewelry and wallet were never touched.
There was no trace of the lock being picked.
Either the victim herself invited the culprit in,
or the culprit used a master key of some sort and sneaked in.
Misaki-san, who holds the master keys?
There are quite a few.
I, of course, as a security officer.
The house assistant, Natsuho-kun.
And the chief cabin attendants all have one.
I see...
Chief Inspector, the culprit targeted the victim when she was alone.
If that's the case, then perhaps the culprit knew the victim's schedule.
Tsujimoto-san, you arranged their schedules, is that right?
Yes.
Who else knew about them?
I told the chief purser, Misaki-san,
but never told anyone else.
Meaning,
if you were 10 cm taller,
or if Misaki-san's weight was 10 kg less,
one of you would have become the prime suspect.
Also, one more thing.
Whether Sonoko-kun's case has
anything to do with these two cases.
But to pass by someone who may have been the culprit and not to have seen their face...
I'm very sorry.
Anyhow, Chief Inspector...
This place is a closed room above the ocean.
The murderer is definitely somewhere on this ship.
The crew and the guests, all together,
it's only 600 suspects, right?
Anyway, Takagi-kun,
continue your questioning with
the guests and find a witness.
Yes, sir!
Misaki-san and Tsujimoto-san,
Please tell us thoroughly about
each guest and crew member.
Understood.
It's exactly as Officer Shiratori said.
The culprit knew about the Yashiro family's schedule.
Natsuho-san says she didn't tell anyone.
That's...
I see! If one used that...
Hey, hey! I have something to ask you, Oneesan.
Conan-kun?
Hey! Where did you come from?
Last night, didn't you talk about today's schedule in the President's room?
Yes, after we had dinner and
came back to the suite.
Then, was there any time yesterday
when no one was in the President's room?
Let's see, yesterday, President Yashiro said
he was tired, so he was resting until dinner...
The only time the room was empty was during dinner.
I see...
You little!
You were listening to the conversation, weren't you?
Ouch!
Misaki-san, was there anyone
that didn't show up to dinner?
No, I believe everyone came.
Then the culprit should be one of the crew members.
Sorry, I'm going to leave now and rest in my room.
Hey, have you ever participated
in Kusaka-san's research?
Kusaka Hironari-san? Yes, I have.
Did a master key go missing after that by any chance?
Enough already, of course not!
Actually, about three weeks ago,
we realized that one had gone missing.
What... There is...?
Further more, it was right after I participated in Kusaka-san's research, just as Conan-kun said.
Hold on. Who is this Kusaka-san?
He's a script writer who has come here for research purposes a few times.
I see...
So, Conan-kun. Are there any
suspicious points to that person?
Yeah. Kusaka-san returned to
his room in the middle of dinner.
Saying he got seasick.
But maybe he was hiding in the
President's room and eavesdropping.
Idiot. He's not a kid, so he won't do
some hide and seek stuff like that...
Wire tapping.
Maybe he left a tapping device in the President's room.
I see, how about it, Mouri-kun?
What's Kusaka-san's physical stature?
Now that you mention it,
it does resemble the culprit's.
All right, let's go to see Kusaka-san.
I see, a tapping device.
You're indeed the great detective Mouri Kogorou.
Actually, this time it was thanks to Conan-kun's idea,
And we did a bit of reasoning.
Really?
But that reasoning is wrong.
Around 10:15 A.M.,
I was on the phone with Minako-san in this room.
You mean the designer Minako-san?
Yes, because we're on the ocean,
I couldn't use my cell phone.
So I was using this phone right here.
The exact time you were on the phone?
Let's see, from about 10:00 until 10:30 A.M.
If you check the calling record,
I think you'll get the exact time.
And what was the phone call about?
If you don't mind.
I was done with the script draft,
so I thought of having her listen to it.
The script draft?
Yes, the draft for a drama series
set on an luxury cruise liner.
I've been receiving advise from her about cruise ships.
Cruising Love Story?
I specifically asked for an open room alone,
so that I could finish this without
being disturbed by anyone else.
But why didn't you see her
in person and talk to her about it?
You're both on the same ship.
She's still single, so to go to her room is a little...
And at a cafe or a lounge,
there is a chance someone will hear us.
It happens a lot in my career.
Stealing ideas, I mean.
I see...
From what I can see, Kusaka-san is clear.
We don't know yet, not until we can confirm his alibi.
What's wrong, Mouri-san?
He was probably caught on that lady there.
She was pretty cute, so...
I heard about the case from Misaki-san.
It's true that at precisely 10:00 A.M.,
I received a call from Kusaka-san.
And we talked for about 30 minutes.
He's been asking me to review his work,
So this morning, during tea time,
He said, "The story will be finished soon,
so I want to hear what you think about it".
"I'll call you at 10:00 A.M.,
so please be in your room at that time."
I see. Well, as long as we can confirm that.
Sorry to bother you.
I guess Mr. Kusaka's alibi is confirmed.
Yes, as long as the two aren't working together.
The phone isn't wireless in their rooms.
It's impossible to commit the crime as they talk on the phone.
What's up, Mouri-san?
You were probably thinking about Minako-san, right?
She's pretty good looking, too.
- From the above...
- Tome-san.
Chief Inspector Megure.
How is it?
We've finished going over it once,
But there isn't really anything that jumps out.
I see.
Just that there were traces of a reddish yellow substance that were wiped off on the floor near the body.
A reddish-yellow substance?
Hey, Tome-san, that wasn't blood?
No. It's got the same color,
but it didn't respond like blood.
Then what was it?
Chief Inspector Megure.
I've talked to all the guests and
crew members on the sixth floor,
But still haven't found any witnesses.
I see...
The welcome party starts at 5:00 P.M.
Let's split up and ask the other
guests on the ship as well.
Yes, sir!
Well then, Chief Inspector.
We will be heading back to HQ
with the evidence we've collected.
Thanks for your work.
Oneesan.
I've been looking for you.
Can I ask you one more question?
Sure thing, little detective.
What is it?
What was the phone call
between you and Kusaka-san like?
Well... He was reading his story
and I was just listening.
You were just listening?
Yes. If I interrupt in the middle, he gets angry...
He would tell me, "Stay quiet and listen".
Something like that happened before,
so I decided not to interrupt him.
Then you were just listening silently
until he finished his story?
Yes. He finished reading his story in about
20 minutes and asked me how it was.
So I replied it was good.
Done!
Here.
Oh... Thank you...
How are you feeling, Sonoko?
I'm fine now.
Maybe it would have been better if
we hadn't played hide and seek.
Not at all.
But right before we played hide and seek, you said,
We're going to win this. Because...
What were you going to say after that?
I told you that I played hide and seek once during elementary school, right?
Yeah.
That was during the school field
expansion when I was in first grade.
I invited Shinichi at the time too, but...
Shinichi, are you listening to me?
Come on, Shinichi.
Let's play hide and seek.
It's fun.
Sorry, but I'll pass.
The soccer tournament is coming up.
That spoiled brat.
He's been saying stuff like that since he was a kid?
And we decided to play without Shinichi.
But you remember how the area under the
stage in the gym was used as storage?
Oh, yeah! The folding chairs were stored there, right?
Yeah. And on the side of the stage, under the stairs, there was a small space there as well.
So you hid there...
Yeah. I thought that if I hid there
no one would ever find me.
Then the teacher who came to check things out
put the stairs back and I got stuck inside.
And then...?
No matter how hard everyone looked, they couldn't find me.
And I couldn't get out so I was wondering what to do.
But then, Shinichi found me easily.
On the way home, I asked him how
he knew where I was and he said...
"The Demons of the School."
In that movie, the kids who hid in the school building were all eaten by the demon, right?
That means, the chance of you hiding in any of the school buildings would be zero.
Wait a sec, how did you know I watched that movie?
Every time we passed the video store,
you always looked at that movie poster.
Even though you're afraid of ghosts and demons, you always watch those movies.
That means you were hiding somewhere in the outer school buildings.
You, an animal lover, wouldn't hide in the hen house where you'd scare all the chickens.
At that time, the basketball club's
older students were cleaning,
So you couldn't have hid in the gym storage
and gotten stuck there, either.
The pool is under construction,
so all that's left is the gym.
That's why I thought that would be
the only place you could have been.
Besides, you were looking underneath the stairs
a while ago right before the gym class.
How's that? Are you surprised?
You're always looking after me, Shinichi.
You idiot, it's nothing like that.
Hey, your face is turning red!
What are you talking about?
It's just because of the sunset.
All right, I get it.
The "It's the same as that time" you said yesterday was about this, right?
Then what you were trying to say earlier was...
"We're going to win,"
"Because the only one who can find me is Shinichi," right?
It's nothing like that!
What's this? Your face is a bit red!
What are you talking about?
That's just the sunset.
Uncle, what was he doing at Kusaka's?
Yes?
Oh, it's the boy this time.
I came to play.
I saw this a bit earlier, but this sure is a cool laptop.
Yeah, it's a commercial product, so...
That's not something kids should read.
Okay.
Hey, this is the same as the Professor's!
Huh, I don't hear anything.
Brat...
Get out.
I suppose no one leaves the evidence behind forever.
Aww, our trip turned out to be a disaster.
Don't say things like that, Genta-kun.
This is a serious case.
Right...
But why do people hurt each other?
If only everyone could get along.
That's impossible.
People have emotions.
A troublesome attribute that's not only invisible, but also changes easily.
If it's friendship or love, then that's fine.
But if by some trigger it changes to malice and vengeance,
Then that could bring forth thoughts of murder.
But my Mom and Dad are fighting all the time, but they still get along well.
That's because they love each other.
Just as Ai-kun said, a person can easily
become the giver or the receiver of pain.
In order to keep something like that from happening,
one must always hold good feelings for others.
Good feelings for others...
Professor!
I want to borrow something from you.
The seatbelt's lock.
Chiba-kun, come here a moment.
Sure...
Did you find something?
Look at this.
The seatbelt's lock?
Do you see this unusual burn mark left behind here?
It's as though something was tied there.
I see it. It's roughly the width of a kite string.
A kite string, huh...
Huh? What are you doing, Uncle?
Where have you been all this time?
The party's starting soon.
Oh, Mouri-san. Chief Inspector Megure wants you to come for a second.
The Chief Inspector?
All right.
Me too!
You stay behind and get ready.
I see. So there are suspicions about
Mr. Yashiro Hidetoshi's accident, too.
Yes. From what Satou-san stated, the kite string mark on the seat belt is suspicious.
How about it, Mouri-kun?
Can you think of anything?
Even if you say so... What were the
other items left behind by the deceased?
Right. There was a juice can that was burnt to
a crisp and a few miscellaneous items like that,
But it says here that they've
all been tossed out already.
Hmm, a juice can and kite string, huh...
Maybe if that was used...
Were you all surprised?
You little brat!
I actually thought of shaking a can of soda and making it go psshhhh,
But they weren't selling any soda...
Soda...!!?
I thought my heart was going to stop.
Ahhh! Being surprised by a can could be...
A stun grenade.
Perhaps the culprit used a stun grenade.
That's right.
What's this, Shiratori-kun? A stun...?
Stun grenade. Also known as a flash bomb.
With a bright flash and an explosion,
it stuns the opponent's movement.
It's a type of grenade shaped like a juice can.
For instance, tying a kite string to the stun
grenade which has its pin pulled out already,
And then tying the other end of the kite string to the seat belt's lock,
Just as one pulls on the lock to secure his seat belt...
I see. Even if he didn't have a heart attack,
he would be unable to drive after he lost consciousness,
And the car would run straight off the cliff.
But a stun grenade isn't something so easily...
Then again, we're in an era
where a person can get anything.
Yes, and if he only wanted to shock the victim,
then he didn't even need to use a real one.
Even a large cracker could have done the trick.
Chief Inspector, we've just received a call.
They say that they found a body
that's believed to be President Yashiro.
Captain, I have something that
I wish to talk to you about.
What is it?
It's about the welcome party at 5:00 P.M.,
I want you to cancel it.
If the culprit is planning his next murder,
Then there's a good chance that he'll
try to use the confusion of the party.
But...
Please, Captain.
No, Chief Inspector.
Let's have this party.
All the questions should be answered there.
Mouri-kun, did you...
Did it come, the usual thing?!
But he's not asleep.
Are you sure, Uncle?
All right. I'm gonna party!
I'll make up for the half day I spent resting.
Sonoko...
Hey, why don't you ask Ran-oneesan?
About the you-know-what.
I suppose.
A gold medal made from sea shells?
Although the string became too short
and it turned into a bracelet...
So you didn't notice it after all.
What a pity.
I'm so sorry. I promise I'll look at it later.
But thanks, guys. I appreciate your thoughtfulness.
Everyone, welcome to the St. Aphrodite.
I will be your host for tonight, Tsujimoto Natsuho.
Thank you.
First, let me introduce to you our main staff.
First, our chief purser, Misaki Naoya.
Next is the doctor on board, Doctor Mizu Tsubu.
Our head chef, Chef Shiomi Katsuhiko.
Did you find out who the culprit is?
Yeah. But I still can't find any solid evidence.
Now then, I've kept you all waiting.
Our captain, Kaidou Wataru.
Before I say my greetings, I would like to introduce you
to the beautiful woman who designed this ship.
The designer, Akioshi Minako-san.
Captain, is it true that Chief Takae was murdered?
There's a rumor that President Yashiro is also missing.
That's...
You're the inspector, right?
Did you catch the culprit yet?
Are you sure it's safe for us to participate in this party?
Calm down. Everyone, please calm down.
What in the word is going on?
Well... Mouri-san?
Huh, Mouri-san?!
Everyone, please calm yourselves.
There's no need to worry.
The gruesome serial killer has already been identified by me, Mouri Kogorou!
We've been waiting, great detective!
The culprit who murdered Chief Yashiro Takae, and President Entarou.
That is... Akiyoshi Minako-san, you!
Her motive was revenge for Yashiro Hideto-shi's accident which occurred about half a month ago.
That accident was actually a murder case orchestrated by the Yashiro family.
But why would Akiyoshi-san take revenge upon Yashiro-san's death?
That is most likely because Minako-san and
Hideto-shi had a romantic relationship.
Hold on, Mouri-san.
It's true that I did admire Yashiro-sensei
as an important superior.
But I didn't have any feelings for him.
Also, I was talking to Kusaka-san over the phone
in my room during the time of the crime as an alibi.
But in reality, you let Kusaka-san read the story on his own for about 20 minutes,
That means there's no alibi
for you during those 20 minutes.
Enough already.
If Kusaka-san stopped reading in the middle and asked me something,
He would know that there wasn't anyone on the other end of the phone.
I'm not stupid enough to try
to create such an idiotic alibi.
If you still insist on saying that I'm the culprit,
then show me the evidence right now!
Hey! You have proof, right, Mouri-kun?
Well...
Could Dad... Could he suspect Minako-san just because she looks like Mom?
Well, Mouri-san?
Sorry. I need a little washroom break...
A break?
I found it.
Chief Inspector, we should do something while everyone's still laughing.
But...
No need to worry, Chief Inspector Megure.
I know the true culprit.
Really, Professor Agasa?
This time, it's the Professor's deduction show!
Everyone, do you know the
original meaning of a cruise?
It's an act of piracy.
Apparently the name came from pirates
searching for prey and zigzagging on their voyage.
There is a pirate on this ship as well.
A pirate who steals others' lives instead of their wealth. A pirate by the name of murderer.
Yes. That pirate is...
The script writer, Kusaka Hironari-san, you!
You sure say strange things.
Weren't you listening to Minako-san's words?
During the time of the incident,
I was telling her about my story on the phone.
You mean this story?
Okazaki Nanami loved the ocean...
ever since she was born.
She loved its vastness more than anything else.
It's a simple trick.
You used a tape recording you premade, left it by the phone,
And murdered the two during that time.
That can't be. I know I erased that already!
Erased?
No, you thought you erased it.
Something important such as this, if you don't confirm it properly, then it could be life-threatening.
Forged evidence, right?
That tape... You used his voice and recreated it, right?
Yeah, more or less.
But there's still further solid proof.
But that can't be used as
evidence for the murder, can it?
The evidence is right there.
Look there
What's wrong, Onii-san?
There's a blackish hair mixed with your red ones.
Isn't that... Blood?
Blood?
Kusaka-san...
I get it.
Oniisan, after you did those bad things,
you looked into the mirror,
But since your hair color is very
similar to blood, you didn't notice it.
But your should remember this.
Blood will clot as time goes on,
And the color will change.
Also, could you remove that scarf around your neck?
If my deduction is right,
there still should be marks left over.
From President Yashiro's nail or finger marks
when he fought back so hard against your attack.
Excuse me.
Kusaka-san, may we hear your
story in detail in another room?
Hold on. Geez.
I still have...
One last trick up my sleeve!
Don't move! If you do, I'll detonate the bombs!
Bombs!
If you don't want me to sink this ship,
then listen to what I say!
That's the guy who attacked me!
You finally remembered?
Please calm down.
Why are you doing this?
I'm taking revenge for my father.
Revenge?
15 years ago, the crew member who
died on the St. Yashiro was my father!
I see, that was...!
Two years ago, I heard a strange rumor from one of my father's friends,
who came to visit my father's grave, about the incident.
During the time, Yashiro Cruise's Chief and First-mate Executive Entarou and Takae,
Decided to sink the ship for its insurance.
Furthermore, there was a crew who was after the accomplishments of Captain Okita and his seat,
They brought in their first man, Kaidou First Mate.
You, who got talked into it,
put Captain Okita to sleep with drugged coffee.
Purposefully crashing the ship to the iceberg.
And at the same time, you blew up the bombs you'd set up beforehand.
The locations to put the bombs were most likely organized by the designer Yashiro Hideto-shi.
Are you saying that Sensei...?
How did you kill President Yashiro?
He lunged at me and choked me on the floor,
so I threw him into the ocean as the ship swayed.
And, just as you did, I was planning to blow up this ship,
And kill you in the confusion.
What a bunch of nonsense.
Just a minute! At least remove your finger from that remote button.
Shut up! Don't come any closer!
He's gone!
You're not getting away!
Conan-kun!
Get him!
Damn it.
Wait, Conan-kun!
Wait up.
Hey, you guys...
We're going, too.
We're not letting you take all the credit.
Hey, Haibara...
Well, like they said...
Don't get shaken off.
Shift to the left!
Now right!
We passed him!
Haibara, take the wheel.
Conan-kun!
You did it, Conan!
All right!
The Detective Boys win again!
Hey!
Are you all okay?
Don't you guys ever do that again!
He was a suspect for a murder case!
What if something went wrong?
We're sorry...
Chief Inspector Megure...
H-How many bombs did he set up?
How is it, Izawa-kun?
Captain, a number of holes were opened by the bombs.
What about the chamber locks?
We locked them, but the water is
reaching from the 3rd block to the 4th.
What?!
Captain, please give the order for evacuation.
Captain!
Evacuate all personnel.
All guests, this is your voyage guide, Norizama.
Please take your emergency life vests
and move to the deck on the first floor.
This is not a drill. I repeat, this is not a drill!
Please move calmly.
All crew members are to guide all guests to the designated locations.
It's not here. The gold medal that
those kids were talking about.
Where did it go?
Ran...
Hey, we're leaving. Hurry up!
Ran, let's go.
There's no need to rush, there's still plenty of time.
Please continue moving without pushing.
Dad, where's Conan-kun and everyone else?
They're fine.
According to Chief Inspector Megure,
After they went chasing Kusaka in a motor boat,
they were picked up by a nearby cruiser.
That's good.
Ran, you two leave on this boat.
I'll go on a different one.
But...
Well then, see you later.
Dad!
Don't rush. Follow the person in front of you.
Once you hit the water, get away from the ship as quickly as possible.
If you get sucked down by the ship's whirlpool,
there won't be anything left of you.
Understood.
It's blazing in here.
We're in a crisis, suck it up.
But when it's hot, it's hot!
I remembered now!
What?
I dropped it where I hid for hide and seek.
You mean the gold medal?
I'm lowering the raft. Hold on tightly.
Wait, I'm getting off.
Hey Ran!
I'm going to go and get it so go on ahead.
But...
It's true that it's just a medal made from sea shells.
But to me, it's a precious treasure.
Well, I'll catch you later.
Wait a second, Ran!
This is it!
We sure were lucky,
that this ship was nearby.
I wonder if the people on the ship are okay?
I'm worried.
Don't worry, she's probably on the emergency boat and...
Kusaka said that he was planning to kill Kaidou-san in the confusion.
But aren't there a bit too many bombs for that?
It's as though he really was trying to sink the ship.
And that trick he used for his alibi,
now that I think about it, it's a bit too simple.
If Minako-san said anything
in the middle of the conversation,
then the trick would fall apart right there.
Maybe he tested it a few times already.
He probably thought he could use it to create his alibi,
after he confirmed the fact that she wouldn't interrupt.
She did say...
If I say something in the middle, he gets angry.
Chief Inspector Megure.
I just had a talk with the coast guards.
Apparently, they discovered a fruit knife
stabbed into President Yashiro's back.
What?
What does this mean?
Kusaka didn't say anything about a knife.
It was 10:11 A.M.
It was about 10:15 A.M.
No, it wasn't Kusaka...
Then who...
They really don't look like they're in their 50's.
Hey, Conan...
Where are you going Conan-kun?
Conan-kun.
I wonder what it is.
Something just doesn't feel right.
A feeling that says if I just let it sink like this, I'd be losing something that I'll never be able to get back.
You mean about the case?
Yeah, probably.
Most likely.
Conan-kun...
The case? Are you sure that's all, Kudou-kun?
If my deduction is right, then the real culprit is...
Captain.
The evacuation of the guests is now complete.
I'll take the life raft.
You go ahead on the emergency boat first
once you've gathered all the crew members.
Understood.
Aren't you going down with the ship, Captain?
You! What are you still doing here?
Hurry and evacuate!
You should have some recollection of this.
It was something my father loved.
An origami boat...
Are you...
That's right. I'm the daughter of Captain Okita,
the one you and the Yashiro family murdered.
Sorry to tell you this, but I've
destroyed the remaining life rafts.
H-how could you?
Don't move!
This is a pretty small place.
Let's go somewhere bigger and have a long chat about this as we feel the salty air.
It was half a year ago,
That Kusaka came to see me,
saying it was for his drama research.
But I found it strange that he held more interest in the Yashiro family, which had nothing to do with his research.
That was when I took the chance when he left to go to the washroom...
I saw, "The truth behind the St. Yashiro Number 1 Sinking Case".
And learned that was Kusaka's true goal.
I didn't think it could be true,
But I asked Yashiro Hideto the following day.
Once I gave him a bit of high-proof alcohol, he spilled everything.
The truth about how that sinking case was not an accident, but a planned murder.
Without even knowing that I was Okita's daughter.
I-I didn't know. I was ordered by the Chief, and...
I don't need excuses!
I'll have you chase after the Yashiro family.
For my father who died a depressing death.
Damn it! Let me get there in time!
Please, forgive me!
Goodbye, Captain.
Hold it!
So you were the real culprit, Akiyoshi Minako-san.
Uncle...!
Don't move!
Sorry, but I made sure that gun
couldn't be used anymore.
I found it in your room during my washroom break.
Captain.
I'll have a long talk with you later.
Akiyoshi-san, based on my deductions...
Let's just drop the act.
All three of us are going to die anyways.
A deduction like that on top
of a sinking ship is pointless.
How can I stop?
Revealing the truth is what detectives live for.
Most likely, you learned that Kusaka was planning to murder the four of them.
But there was an impossibility in his plan.
That's why you killed Hideto-shi first as though
he died from an accident caused by a heart attack.
Using a self-made stun grenade.
With Hideto-shi's death, Kusaka changed the four murders to just three.
And decided to use you as an alibi.
Knowing that, you decided to take revenge with your own hands by using his plan.
First, you set up bombs separately from Kusaka's.
This is the ship you designed.
You should know exactly where to hit for it to sink.
Then, this morning at 10:00 A.M., you received the phone call from Kusaka,
and dashed out of your room
just as Kusaka began to read his story.
You knocked out Chief Takae who was taking a bath,
and put on the bath robe and pretended to be the Chief.
Then Kusaka came in and thought you were
Chief Takae since you were wearing a bathrobe,
And you pretended to fight him by trying to take the knife from him,
and stabbed it into your own stomach where you'd already put a blood-like substance.
And after Kusaka left, thinking he
had done what he came for,
you murdered Chief Takae.
After you wiped the reddish substance from the floor and put on the windbreaker, you left the room.
At the time, I thought it was because you didn't want me to see your face that you turned your back to me.
But I realized it later.
Perhaps it was a woman.
Instinctively trying to turn away her chest.
I see...
That's why that time, he...
Afterwards, you went to the basement marina.
When you got there, it was just when the
President sat on top of Kusaka, choking him.
You quickly ran up to the two of them,
then held both feet of the President...
Both feet...?
That's right. You made sure that you didn't touch either of Kusaka's feet,
Right, right... Stabbed him in the back.
Since you hid yourself right afterwards,
Kusaka believed he did it himself.
All according to your plan.
You're indeed the great detective, Mouri Kogorou-san.
I decided to use that man, because I learned that you were coming on this cruise.
In order to fool the eyes of the great detective, I needed a fake culprit.
Furthermore, I needed a culprit who really did think he had done it.
That man called my father, whose fate went down with the ship, the representation of an anachronism on his laptop.
I won't forgive anyone who talks badly about my father.
You're the one who cannot be forgiven.
Not only did you take the lives of those three,
You put a lot of innocent people in danger,
And you even sunk the ship
you created to do such an act...
I've done detailed simulations over and over again.
The number of bombs, the amount of water entering the ship, the time it takes for the evacuation,
And even to the point where I saw that man over there,
Dying a gruesome, lonely, and depressing death upon these giant blue waves.
St. Aphrodite was born from nothing.
Its fate is to return to nothing.
But since you've managed to figure things out up until this point, I guess I have no choice.
I'll turn myself in quietly.
It's not my hobby to fight with a woman.
Isn't that sexist?
Uncle...
What? Still can't change your hobby?
Like I said, fighting a woman isn't my hobby.
All three of us are going to die here anyway.
That's because you got in the way of my revenge!
That kid...
Shinichi?
Huh?
No, nothing...
Shall we end this soon...
Mouri Kogorou-san?
I don't really want to see the great detective looking like this, but...
Mind your own business.
Uncle!
How unlucky,
to have the great detective
suspect me from the very start.
Do I look that much like some woman you hate?
It's just the opposite.
You resemble her too much.
So I thought, as long as the culprit wasn't you, then it would be fine.
As I tried to find evidence to prove your innocence,
it turned out like this...
Uncle!
Are you all right, Uncle?
That was a great deduction, Uncle!
What the heck are you doing here?
First thing first, we have to get out of here.
Run away...?
We can't. All the emergency boats are gone and this woman's destroyed all the life rafts.
Hey, hey...
Captain!
Captain...
We're saved.
What's this feeling?
The case has already been solved.
So what's this stomach turning, unsettling feeling?
It's going to sink soon. Hurry.
Hey, you're next. Move it!
What are you doing? Hurry up and get on!
W-Where's Ran-neechan?
Ran got on an emergency boat a long time ago...
What? You aren't with Ran?
Hey, what are you saying?
She went back to her hiding spot from
playing hide and seek to get her gold medal.
So I thought she was with you...
That's it!
Hey, hold on a minute!
Hey, where's Ran?
Someone!
Is anyone there?!
Hey, Ran. So you were here all along.
Shinichi, you'll find me, right?
Shinichi?
Hey, where's Ran?
Ran-neechan knew that I was kicking
the ball here the entire time.
That means...
the upper deck!
I'll find you.
I promise I'll find you.
So wait for me, Ran!
Hey, where's Ran?!
Calm down. Calm down and think.
You found her easily at that time, too.
Come to think of it...
How did you know where I was?
You were so caught up in kicking your soccer ball.
You were kicking the soccer ball the entire time.
Weren't you, Conan-kun?
I know it all.
That's it. That day and today, both times...
Uncle!
Are there any places where you
can hide under the floor?
I found one!
Damn it. It won't open.
Uncle!
It broke through!
Ran! You there, Ran?!
Dad?
She's all right.
We need to hurry, Uncle.
Damn it!
This is bad... This is bad...
If we don't turn around the boat soon,
Ran and the others will sink!
I'm sorry, but I can't do that.
If we return now, there's a chance that we'll get caught in the whirlpool from the cruiser as it sinks.
Oh, no!
It's the rescue chopper from the coast guard!
Thank goodness!
It's a rescue chopper!
This isn't good.
Let's run to the bow.
Hey, we're over here!
Hey!
Is this everyone?
Yes.
Boy, just hold on a little longer.
I'll save you right now.
OK.
All right. Hold on tightly, son.
We'll pull you up now.
Support the young lady firmly.
I got it.
What happened?
Grab on!
Shit!
Hold on tight, Conan-kun.
Ran, are you all right?
Boy!
Give me your hand.
We're almost there.
Thank you.
Your parents' boats are already nearby.
Then you first figured out that she was the culprit
when you realized Kusaka's alibi plan was too simple?
Yeah. The reason such a simple alibi plan worked,
was because the phone partner,
Minako-san, used that alibi as well.
And the only one who can disguise herself as Chief Takae with her smooth legs,
is Minako-san, who has the same smooth legs.
I see. But I'm impressed you
found out where Ran-kun was.
Oh, that's because...
I was more worried than you, you know!
That time, I was kicking a volley ball,
but Ran-neechan said it was a soccer ball.
That's why I thought she might be somewhere where she could only hear the sound.
But it's really disappointing.
I'm happy that Ran got saved and all, but, I thought the only person that could find Ran was Kudou-kun.
No. The one who was saved was...
Ran-oneesan!
We fixed the gold medal!
We've made it so that you can actually put it on your neck with a longer string.
I'll put it on for you!
Thank you.
It looks nice on you.
I'll treasure it always.
I was saved...
Thanks to those guys' considerate feelings for others.