That's enough.
Step away from the desk
and raise your hands.
We've anticipated your moves.
Furuya-san, are you okay?
Yeah.
That eye...
Don't tell me...
Furuya-san, step aside.
Don't move!
Wait!
W-Wait!
Stop!
Don't you know that's dangerous?!
W-What the...?!
Now, who's this?
Akai?!
Stay out of this, Akai!
She's Public Security's prey!
What?!
You're not getting away!
Shit!
If we let her escape,
there'll be worldwide panic!
No way!
She's going against the traffic?!
Rye!
Interesting.
I'll run you down!
Akai.
You bastard!
It's me.
She got away.
Please take care of the cover-up.
Okay.
I'm high school detective, Kudo Shin'ichi.
While visiting an amusement park with my childhood friend and classmate, Mouri Ran...
I witnessed a man in black in the midst of a suspicious transaction.
While caught up in watching the deal...
I failed to notice his
partner sneaking up behind me.
That man forced me to take poison...
And when I came to...
My body had shrunk.
If those guys found out that
Kudo Shin'ichi was still alive...
They'd come after me again, and put those around me at risk.
At Professor Agasa's suggestion,
I decided to hide my true identity.
And the moment
Ran asked for my name...
I became Edogawa Conan.
In order to obtain
information on those guys...
I went to live with Ran,
whose father is a private detective.
By the way, there are others besides the professor who know my identity.
Haibara Ai.
Her real name is Miyano Shiho.
She was originally working
with the men in black...
But to escape from them,
she attempted to take her own life...
By taking the same poison I was forced
to ingest, causing her body to shrink.
The Black Organization
is enshrouded in mystery.
All we know so far is that the members
are codenamed after alcoholic beverages.
In order to find out more about them...
Some agents voluntarily became members of the Organization as part of an undercover operation.
There's the agent of the
Central Intelligence Agency, or CIA...
Mizunashi Rena, code name Kir.
Then there's the agent from the NPA's Security Planning Division who goes by the nickname Zero...
Amuro Tooru,
code name Bourbon.
Furthermore, secretly chasing after the Organization from a different angle...
There are some agents from
the Federal Bureau of Investigation, or FBI.
James Black.
André Camel.
Jodie Starling.
And finally, Akai Shuuichi.
He's cream of the crop in
the FBI and a shooting expert.
However, it seems a serious incident
once took place between him and Amuro.
Even though I've shrunk,
my mind remains the same...
That of an unbeaten great detective.
There's always only one truth!
Prof, we're out of snacks.
Eh?!
You already ate them all?!
You ate our share, too?
My bad, my bad.
Didn't the professor say
those were for all of us?!
You look pretty serious.
What are you looking at?
We're almost there,
so don't get all riled up.
The cause of yesterday's massive blackout hasn't been announced yet...
You're unbelievable, Genta-kun.
What is the cause of the massive blackout on
the Bayshore Route of the Shuto Expressway?!
Just let it go.
Tohto Aquarium
So I've been watching the news,
thinking that's strange.
Ah!
They're doing a special feature
on the aquarium we're going to!
Really?
Let me see, Conan-kun!
O-Okay.
Let me see it, too!
This is the Tohto Aquarium.
Man, this seatbelt is in the way.
Hey, don't take it off
while the car's moving!
It had been closed for
renovations since last year...
But it's finally re-opening today,
so we now bring you the latest on it.
How boring.
We're almost there,
so please be patient, Genta-kun.
Ah, it's started!
So with the following footage, allow me to introduce the points
that have changed the most since the renovation.
Our Recommendation for Golden Week
is Tohto Aquarium!!
There are three major points
that have changed as part of the renovation.
The first thing we want
to direct your attention to...
Is that all the attractions
and shops have been moved indoors.
Thus, you never have to
worry about the weather...
Allowing you to enjoy all the facilities to your
heart's content from opening until closing time!
The next thing you should pay attention
to is this aquarium's top selling point...
The magnificent dolphin show!
It has long been
a popular attraction...
But everything in the show
has now been revamped!
The dolphins' performance
has been even further refined...
So it's sure to give us
a surprising and exciting time!
The dolphin kissed me!
Bye-bye.
Wow, I'm jealous.
And the last thing we're introducing today is
the biggest selling point after the renovation...
Let me touch one, too.
The world's first-ever
double Ferris wheel.
With a north wheel on one side,
and a south wheel on the other...
You'll be able to feast your eyes on different scenery,
depending on which one you choose to ride.
Also, as the fountains have been
moved closer to the Ferris wheel...
You can enjoy the
special water and light show...
Along with the scenery,
from 100 meters above the ground!
It's so exciting!
Let's go on that Ferris wheel!
Yeah, let's do that!
Weren't we going to the aquarium?
We could go to both, couldn't we?
Yeah!
Yeah, let's go to both!
Professor...
Thanks in advance
for paying for the tickets.
Wow!
Now we can see the huge wheel!
You're right!
Amazing!
We'll be there
in less than five minutes.
We're here.
Let's go!
I'm so excited!
Hold on, Genta-kun!
Hurry, Professor!
Haibara-san and
Conan-kun, please hurry!
So which one did you decide upon? The aquarium or the Ferris wheel?
Eh?!
What are you sayin', Professor?
Of course we're going to both!
Well then,
here's a challenge for you!
If you can answer the quiz I'm
about to give, I'll take you to both.
Well, here it comes!
If you paint many layers of a color
without mixing it with another...
Which one of the following
four colors will change?
1. Red.
2. Blue.
3. Brown.
4. Black.
Without mixing it...
A color that changes
when you paint many layers of it?
Ah, I have no idea!
Professor,
that's very immature.
It might be a little easier to understand
if you use different words to describe the colors.
Hey, Conan-kun,
you can't participate in the quiz!
Use a different word
to describe them?
makka
For example, red becomes "scarlet".
massao
Blue turns into "aquamarine".
Ai-kun, don't tell them th—
I figured it out!
What?!
matcha
So that means brown turns into "deep brown".
Oh, it transformed!
Yeah.
What're you talking about?
Red turns into "scarlet",
blue turns into "aquamarine"...
Brown turns into "deep brown", and black turns into "jet black".
Please try to focus
on brown, Genta-kun.
matcha
Only brown turns into green tea!
You're right!
It turns into matcha green tea!
Wait a minute!
It's unfair for you two to give them hints!
Okay!
Let's go buy the tickets.
Yeah!
Hey, wait!
Let's get on the Ferris wheel first!
matcha
You can't go to both, no... Please, "wait"!
Come over here, guys.
The Ferris wheel
has a really long line.
It'll probably take about an hour.
The Ferris wheel is so big.
I wonder if we can see
our house from up there.
I want to eat ice cream.
What's wrong?
W-Wait!
I'll buy one for you later.
Hey...
Are you all right, Miss?
Huh?
There's something on your face!
Wow, your left and right
eyes have different colors!
Could it be that she doesn't
understand Japanese that well?
I understand... I understand...
What's wrong?
Why are you here all alone?
It doesn't look like you
have any friends here with you...
And worse,
your knee and hand are injured...
It also looks like
your phone's broken.
Here, lemme take a look at it.
Okay.
How long have
you been here, Miss?
Um...
Then, where did you
come from to get here?
I don't know.
What's your name, Miss?
My name...
S-Sorry, I don't know.
Can I take a look at your head?
Y-Yeah.
It's not a big injury,
but it's relatively recent.
She was probably driving a car, and got into an accident in which she injured her head.
If that's the case, this is
retrograde amnesia due to trauma.
Wait...
How do you know
she was driving a car?
This smartphone suffered an impact strong enough to completely destroy it.
And look...
It's a shard from
a car's windshield.
So, that means she hit
her head while driving?
And the car must've
been a very old model...
Because recent models use laminated glass
to avoid having shards of glass flying around.
Besides, you can catch the faint smell
of gasoline coming from her body.
You're right.
Do you have
anything else on you, Miss?
What's this?
Let me see it, Miss.
O-Okay.
What's that?
What is this?
It looks like a ring of vocab flashcards,
but the cards are translucently colored.
What are these cards for?
Hey!
Conan! Haibara!
We bought tickets for both of you, too!
Come on, let's go ride the Ferris wheel!
Crap!
The nuisances are back.
Huh?
Who is this lady?
Wow!
Your left and right eyes
have different colors!
They're so pretty!
Is one of them a fake eye?
That's not it, Genta-kun.
I think she's odd-eyed.
odd-eyed
Oddo Ai?
This lady sure has a funny name.
Ah, no.
That's not her name.
I got it!
Odd-Eyed
Seal's Eyes
"Oddo Ai" can be interpreted as an abbreviation of "Ottosei no me".
You're talking
about a seal's eyes, right?
Seal?
You're talking about eyes,
aren't you, Conan-kun?
Y-Yeah.
Ah, I'm sorry.
We made her laugh.
By the way, what
are you all doing here?
Perfect timing, Professor.
This lady seems to have lost her memories
because she was in an accident.
Is that really true, Shin—
Er, Conan-kun?
Yeah.
It may be related
to last night's accident...
Then we should take her
to the police immediately!
Stop!
Miss...
Is there some reason
why you can't go to the police?
I-I don't know...
But the police have to
take her under their custody.
Come now!
You can't take pictures
of someone out of the blue.
Hey! Conan-kun!
Wait, Miss!
We're not reporting
this to the police.
I needed pictures of you to see if
I can find someone who knows you.
Someone who knows me?
Yeah, let me help you
regain your memory.
Are you serious, Conan?!
Please let us help too!
After all, we're the Detective Boys!
We'll look for your friends
to help you get your memory back!
Please rest assured.
Thank you.
Then, let's start by looking for someone who knows this lady!
Yes.
You guys,
what about the Ferris wheel?
What are you saying, Professor?
This ain't the time to be riding that!
Let's start by asking
that dolphin guy.
No way.
I already bought
the tickets for you, too...
You're in the way, Professor!
Let's go now.
Yeah, let's go!
Let's go look for them!
Come on, hurry!
Hey, you guys...
Don't just play around!
You have to take this seriously!
You couldn't possibly be planning on not taking her to the police, right?
Of course I will!
Last night, a vehicle traveling down
Route 11 of the Shuto Expressway...
Was involved in an accident that ended with it erupting into flames in the warehouse area beneath the overpass.
Miraculously, no casualties
surfaced as a result of this accident...
Dad.
Right, Yoko-chan?
But the driver of the vehicle
appears to have fled from the scene...
And the police are still trying
to determine his or her whereabouts.
A huge accident occurred on the expressway!!
Is it possible that this was also an organized attack?!
There is currently little information...
A huge accident occurred on the expressway!!
Is it possible that this was also an organized attack?!
Sheesh.
Dad!
How long are you going to
slack off in your work and sleep for?!
Pipe down!
Detectives have to give their
brains some rest, you know!
In other words, your head hurts
because you drank too much.
H-How did you—
No, I said no such thing!
Here.
It's from Conan-kun.
They've taken an amnesiac under their care and want us to take her to the police.
I already informed Detective Takagi,
but please help them too, Dad.
W-What a beauty!
Are you even listening?
Where is this
beautiful lady right now?
H-He said she's at Tohto Aquarium.
Okay!
Wait, Dad...
The great detective is on the case!
No, it's not a case...
Oh, come on.
Inspector.
This is the picture
Ran-san sent to me earlier.
I see.
According to the report, there's a chance she's been in a traffic accident.
A traffic accident, huh?
There was a major accident last night...
And if I'm not mistaken,
the driver is still missing.
And although it was
such a massive accident...
We don't have any precise information about it, much less the media.
Do you think this is...?
Seems like we need to investigate it.
Inspector Megure!
Oh?
How did it go?
Division Three didn't have any
particular information on the case, either.
I see.
What is it?
I've heard rumors that someone
infiltrated the National Police Agency last night.
The National Police Agency?!
However, the MPD headquarters has received no such information.
What could be going on?
Some great power might be at work.
Thank you for stopping by
the Tohto Aquarium Shopping Mall.
Please take your time
and enjoy your shopping.
Huh?
There she is.
I found her, Gin.
Where is she?
Tohto Aquarium.
The aquarium?!
Yes.
Rest assured.
I'll bring her back right away.
We thank you for coming today.
Is the dolphin show starting yet?
The special dolphin show
will begin momentarily.
Has she really been here before?
I know...
And with such distinctive hair and eye colors,
it's odd that nobody remembers her.
Now, where do you plan to go next?
We've already covered
most of the grounds.
You can do it, Miss!
That's the last one.
Please aim carefully.
I can't believe those guys.
Wow!
Congratulations!
You've gotten today's highest score!
You too, Miss.
Please hold both of your hands out.
Yay!
I wanna do it, too!
Me three!
Okay.
You did it!
I'm next.
Oh!
You smiled again, Miss!
I thought so.
It's better when you smile, Miss.
Yeah.
Agreed.
You really think so?
It definitely is!
Please choose three
keychains as your prize.
Yay!
We can have three?
I want that one!
This one for me!
And I'll take that one!
Okay, so this one is yours.
Huh?
What about you, Miss?
No, I'm fine.
Don't worry about me.
But...
You're the one
who won these, Miss...
Hey, you guys!
Oh, Conan-kun.
Ai-chan.
You sure seem
to be enjoying yourselves...
But weren't you gonna help
the lady regain her memory?
Well...
We were planning to
start after trying this game.
And then the
lady won these for us!
Aren't they amazing?
Oh, brother...
They're only just getting started?
Then, how about we start gathering
information for real now?
Looks like we should be
the ones covering this area, too.
Yeah, we should!
Hey, you guys!
Over here, over here!
It's everyone's favorite Hiroshi!
Professor!
I'm over here!
What are you doing up there?
The crowd for
the Ferris wheel thinned out!
Now's your chance
if you want to ride it!
Seriously?
Then, why don't we start
after riding the Ferris wheel?
Sounds good.
She might be able to remember something by observing the scenery.
All right!
Let's go ride the Ferris wheel, Miss!
Let's go, let's go!
Jeez.
Well, let's just let them go with
the Ferris wheel-obsessed professor.
So, the professor's the one
who wanted to ride it the most?
You bet.
Excuse me.
Do you remember seeing the lady
who was just playing darts here before?
Do you mean the silver-haired
woman who was just here?
Yeah!
Do you know her, Mister?
No, I don't remember
ever seeing her before.
And there's no way I could forget
a customer with such skill.
All of them were
double bull's-eyes?
You can't pull off
that feat by sheer coincidence.
Thanks, Mister.
Oh, right.
Huh?
Can I have you give this
to your friend who was here earlier?
Oh, what is it?
We had a bunch of prototypes
from before we painted them.
The lady didn't win enough for her to have one,
so I was wondering if this would do.
Since it hasn't been painted yet, tell her
to enjoy painting it whatever color she likes.
Okay.
I'm sure she'll be happy.
Thank you, Mister.
Alright, have fun now.
Let's go, Haibara.
W-What?
W-Where next?
Once we're done gathering info in the remaining areas that are under construction...
Let's rejoin the professor
and the others.
There's the whole thing with the darts just now,
but rather than looking for a trail to follow...
I think it's a better plan
for us to simply go along with her.
DEEP SEA AQUARIUM
I really want a dolphin strap!
I'd like a jellyfish one!
I'm so excited!
I wonder what we'll
see once we're high up.
I'm sure we'll be able to
see the Bell Tree Tower!
What are you doing here?
Oh, you're right!
Let's head back.
Hey, Miss...
You'll get left behind
if you keep spacing out!
Sorry.
I got the feeling
someone was talking to me.
Oh?
Someone you know was here?
No, it seems I was mistaken.
You're all going together, correct?
Yeah!
This way, please.
Change of plan.
We've run into some kind of trouble.
Hurry it up.
We can't let her do as she pleases.
I know.
Wait up, Mom!
In the end, we didn't gather anything
from the areas under construction, either.
Could you contact the
professor for me soon, Haibara?
What?
What's wrong?
You've been spacing out for a while now.
H-Have I now?
Hey, Conan! Haibara!
We're right here!
Up here, above you!
Over here!
Can you see us now?
Didn't we tell you we'd be here?
Genta, step back!
Watch out!
Huh? Why?
Genta-kun!
Genta!
I'm gonna fall.
Save me, Miss!
I can't do anything here.
I-I can't hold on anymore!
Genta-kun!
Huh?
Genta, are you okay?
Genta-kun, are you okay?!
Stay with me!
Huh?
Why are you here, Miss?
I'm glad you're not hurt.
Oh, I remember now.
I fell down from up there.
Are you okay?
Are either of you hurt?
This lady saved me, so I'm fine!
Thank goodness.
Please go to the on-site
medical room, just in case.
What's going on?
Okay, that should do it.
Oh, thank you!
My poor back.
Ouch, it hurts.
Why is the professor
the one in the most pain?
That's pathetic.
Yeah, he's acting really childish.
You guys will understand
when you get older.
The professor seems okay too,
so let's go ride the Ferris wheel!
Thank you, Miss!
Let's go!
And you can go with us!
O-Okay...
But I'm not bothering you, am I?
What are you talking about now?
You saved my life, you know!
That's right!
Then, how about we go ride it?
Wait!
Edogawa-kun, I need to talk to you.
Okay.
We'll go ahead then—
No, don't!
Please wait, Professor.
O-Okay.
I wonder what's wrong.
How boring.
What? What is it?
Okay, are you listening?
While Conan-kun and
Haibara-san are busy talking...
Are you positive
that she's one of them?
I can't say for sure,
but didn't you feel it too?
Her right eye...
Now that I think about it,
it looks almost like a prosthetic.
Like a prosthetic...
You don't mean—
Yeah, the second in command of
what you call the "Black Organization"!
Rum.
Miss... Miss.
What?
If we assume she's Rum...
Then it calls into question
whether she's even truly lost her memory.
If I remember correctly,
Rum's gender and age are unknown, aren't they?
Yeah.
I heard several rumors about them while I was in the Organization.
Some described
a large, strong man...
Others, an effeminate man...
And others described an old man.
Everyone had their own idea.
And...
Because they injured their
eye in some sort of accident...
Either their left
or right eyeball is artificial.
If that woman isn't odd-eyed,
but instead has an artificial eye, then...
I see.
So you think she's just
pretending to have amnesia?
But why would she need to put on
an act like that just to get close to us?
W-Well...
It's true that, judging
from her physical prowess...
She's likely a member of the Organization,
and we should keep our guard up.
But if she really lost her memory,
if we reversed that...
You can't!
You must never help
her regain her memory!
Don't tell me you're thinking...
"After she regains her memory, I can get information about the Organization out of her!"
You couldn't possibly be
considering that, right?!
If you did that, you wouldn't
just be putting us in danger...
But the lives of the kids over there might be in danger as well!
They're gone!
What's the Professor doing?!
How cute!
Professor!
Oh?
Oh no, the doves!
This isn't the time for that, Professor!
Where did the kids go?
Huh? What?
Oh no.
It's Conan-kun.
I wouldn't pick that up, if I were you.
He's just going to
be mad at us, anyway.
You're right.
Oh, look!
The doves are flying our way!
You're right.
Can you see them too, Miss?
Yeah, that's a massive flock.
The number you have called
cannot be reached at the moment.
Damn it, those guys!
They're probably at the Ferris wheel.
Those kids were
really wanting to ride it, after all.
Yeah, let's go.
H-Hey!
Wait for me!
You may have played
some sort of sport, Miss.
Eh?
If you hadn't, you couldn't have saved Genta-kun the way you did.
That just might be it...
Because you have
a good figure, Miss!
Good figure?
You think so?
Yes, you're just like a supermodel!
Whoa!
The fountain's gotten bigger!
It's getting higher and higher!
This is amazing!
Can you see it too, Miss?
Yeah, it's beautiful.
Look down there, you guys!
There's a rainbow!
You too, Miss!
Come to the front!
O-Okay.
Oh?
Are you okay, Miss?
Is something wrong?
I'm fine.
Just a little dizzy.
You must be scared of high places.
Hey, it's about to
reach the highest point!
You're right!
I've been waiting for this!
We're at the
very top of the top!
Yeah!
Wow!
Look at this view!
Are you okay, Miss?
Hey, hang in there!
Does your head hurt?
What do we do?
Wait a second.
I'll call for help right now.
knock
T-The NOCs...
Ayumi, Mitsuhiko!
What should we do?
She was saying something weird.
She might've
remembered something!
knock
T-The NOCs...
Ayumi-chan, please
use this to call Conan-kun.
Okay.
What did the lady say, Genta-kun?
Uh...
Something about
knocking on a door.
A door?
Kir, Bourbon...
Hey, she started
saying something again!
Shh!
Please keep quiet, Genta-kun.
Stout, Aquavit, Riesling...
Please... hurry...
It's ringing!
What's wrong?
It's the phone!
It might just be...
Yeah, I knew it.
Mitsuhiko, what were you thinking?!
Conan-kun, help!
Ayumi?
What's wrong?
Once we got on the Ferris wheel,
the lady started not feeling well.
What?
How's her condition?
W-Well...
She's pressing on her head
and is in extreme pain.
She's also saying something,
but we don't know what it means...
I'm writing it all down.
Mitsuhiko-kun's writing it down.
Got it.
Conan-kun,
please hurry and help us!
Conan-kun.
Where's the woman you mentioned?
She's just being carried away
by the on-site medical team.
Let's go, Takagi-kun.
Right.
Haibara, Professor...
Please take care of the rest.
Let's go, too.
No, you can't!
Absolutely not!
We're coming in.
This way, please.
As per our talk earlier,
we'll take her under police custody.
I don't really mind...
But there are some things I'd like you to tell the
doctor of the police hospital you're transferring her to.
First of all, it's certain that she lost her memory due to suffering a heavy blow to her head.
But more alarmingly, I've also found she has
an extremely rare injury in the fornix of her brain...
Which is this area right here.
The latter injury isn't
from last night's accident?
Correct.
It's likely something she was born with.
Did it have anything to do
with the seizure she just had?
That part of the brain doesn't affect the
activities in one's daily life, so I don't believe it did.
Got it.
I'll let them know.
Now, if you'll—
Ah, please wait.
There's one more thing.
We found this out
when we examined her...
But this was on her right eye.
What's that?
It looks like
a colored contact lens.
Yes.
It's a colored contact lens to
make the pupils in her eyes appear black.
Although I believe it has nothing to do with her memory loss or the seizure...
So that means thinking she's odd-eyed
or has an artificial eye was a mistake on our part?
I wanted to inform you just in case.
Excuse us.
We've finished preparing
her for the transfer.
Then, we'll also take our leave.
Okay.
Thank you.
Huh?
Aren't you going with them, kid?
Nope.
There's just one more thing
I wanted to ask you, Doctor.
What is it?
It's about the colored
contact lens from earlier...
Since it only made
one eye seem black...
That means both of her eyes
were originally blue, right?
Well actually,
her right eye is transparent.
Transparent?!
Perhaps it's more precise
for me to say that it "looks transparent".
It's very rare, actually.
I believe her eye appears transparent because her iris has almost the same color as her sclera.
So that doesn't change the fact that
her left and right pupils have different colors.
That might have been
too hard for you.
To put it more simply...
Doctor.
Thank you for everything
you've done for us today.
Oh?
You're done already?
Yep! Bye!
All right, take care.
Is it this room?!
Huh?
Is this where my client is?
Sir, stop.
Entry to this area is forbidden
except to those with authorization!
And I'm telling you
I have authorization!
Uncle Kogoro!
Huh?
What are you doing here?
Good timing, brat!
Where's my beautiful client?
She isn't here anymore.
She was transferred
to a police hospital earlier.
Besides, she's not a client.
What?!
I'm sure you didn't listen
to what Ran-neechan was telling you.
Do you still have
other business here?
A-Ah, no.
I wonder what happened.
No idea.
I thought she was
behaving strangely.
Turns out she has amnesia.
And where is she now?
She's being taken to a police hospital.
So, the police have
also started moving?
Yes.
And there's one thing
that's bothering me.
What?
It seems she had a seizure
while she was on the Ferris wheel.
A seizure?
Yes.
Got it.
Keep monitoring her.
Roger.
A seizure on a Ferris wheel...
It can't be...
Why does Haibara
hate that lady so much?
You've got a point.
I've never seen
her that angry before.
Do you know why
she was angry, Professor?
Yeah, about that...
When I tried asking her why,
she just said she didn't feel well and left.
It's no use asking him, Ayumi-chan.
Yeah.
She always gets
mad at the professor.
Yeah, you're right.
Oh, right!
Conan-kun asked me
to hold on to this.
Ah!
Isn't that...
One of the figures
you can win at the darts booth?
But why isn't it colored?
Conan-kun said something
about that, but I forgot.
What...?
Forget it.
We'll ask him directly.
Who could this be?
Oh, speak of the devil.
It's Conan-kun.
Hello?
Professor,
are the kids still with you?
Yeah, we just finished
drinking our tea at Poirot.
There's something I want to ask you,
as well as a favor I need your help with.
First off,
is that woman okay?
Yeah, she was transferred
to the police hospital earlier.
She'll be fine now.
I'm glad to hear that!
And what is this favor
you wanted to ask me for?
We have to go visit her.
You're right.
I'd like you to recover the internal data
from the phone she had on her.
I don't mind, but don't expect me to be able to do a full data recovery.
Yeah, I know.
Also, she apparently said something when she was having a seizure on the Ferris wheel.
I want to know what she said.
Oh, I wrote that down in my notepad,
though it was from only partway through.
Let's see...
She said
"Stout, Aquavit, and Riesling".
What could that've meant?
Names of alcoholic beverages?!
Does that make any
sense to you, Conan-kun?
Don't tell me she's—
Professor,
did you say you're at Poirot?
Huh?
Y-Yeah...
Then put Amuro-san on!
Amuro-san?
Come to think of it,
I haven't seen him today.
If you're looking for Amuro-san,
he's taken the day off.
What?
He called this morning, suddenly asked to be excused for the day, then hung up.
I tried calling him back many times after,
but I'm a little worried because I couldn't reach him.
You heard what she said.
I hope nothing's happned to him...
I'm a little worried.
Amuro-san, don't tell me...
Stout here.
I am on the bus.
Await further instructions.
Roger that.
Stout...
I believed in you.
What a shame.
Stout is dead.
Okay.
Come back at once.
Understood.
For 32 years, the CN Tower
was the tallest building in the world.
The EdgeWalk takes you all around
the 116th floor of the tower.
Putting you 356 meters
above the ground!
Now, then, does anybody want—
Look at the helicopter, man!
That helicopter...
It can't be...
He had it coming.
This is a befitting death for a spy.
I eliminated Aquavit.
I expected no less from you.
Come back at once.
I'd do that, even
without you telling me to.
Come on, how long
do you plan on dragging this out?
I know I told you that
you only have one minute.
And I already told you,
I'm no NOC!
Then let's make this black and white.
Shall we, Riesling?
Gin...
Let's make the distinction between our side and your side perfectly clear.
Besides you, spill the names of the other rats that squirmed their way in!
Spill them, already!
You don't want to
suffer a lot of pain, do you?
Don't make me
keep repeating myself!
I'm not a NOC!
It's no use threatening me, Gin!
Threaten?
You think I'd do
something cutesy like that?
Five...
Four...
Three...
Two...
One...
Zero!
Let's go, hurry!
Where to?
Japan.
No way!
Only two are left.
An MI6 agent from
the United Kingdom...
A CSIS agent from Canada,
and a BND agent from Germany.
Intelligence operatives from different countries
were assassinated one after the other.
What?!
You don't mean...
Yes.
The one thing they have in common is
that they all had infiltrated a certain Organization.
So it was those men in black
that finished them off?!
A spy working for the Organization may have stolen data from the National Police Agency.
We received a report
from Akai-san stating as much.
A spy working for the Organization...
Jodie-sensei...
The reason you called me here...
Is because I came in contact with the person believed to be the spy, isn't it?
Yes.
I thought so.
But she has amnesia...
And the smartphone she could
have used as flash memory was broken.
A smartphone?!
She had one with her?
Yeah.
She left it on a bench
unattended, so I held onto it.
In that case, it'd be best to send it to the FBI headquarters for data analysis.
Yeah.
I agree.
Wait.
The professor said he's just
about able to restore the data...
So it'd be faster
to have him keep going at it.
Then I'd like you to let us know
once the data analysis is done.
Unless we grasp just how much information
has been leaked as soon as possible...
The whole world
will plunge into panic.
What sort of data was stolen?
Non-Official Cover.
You don't mean...
Yes, the NOC list.
It's a list of spies from all over the world
that the National Police Agency has.
That means all the spies who infiltrated
the Organization will be eliminated?
Not just them.
If the NOC list was made public...
Intelligence agencies from all
over the world might be brought to ruin.
So you're saying those guys obtained the key to start an intelligence war?
Yes.
Which means the three recent assassinations
may only be the beginning.
We've really made it here.
But is it really okay to have kept this
a secret from Ai-chan and Conan-kun?
It's fine!
If we told them,
they'd just say "Absolutely not!"
For now, let's try going in.
I don't know whether
they'll let us see her, though.
Yeah!
Yes.
Yes, that's right.
It's the Tohto Police Hospital.
If it comes down to it,
do what you have to.
I'm counting on you, Kazami.
Yes, sir.
Bourbon,
what are you doing here?
I'm here to take
her back, of course.
And here I thought you came here to
shut her up before her memory returns.
Why would I do that?
I can't grasp
what you're trying to say.
Then how do you
plan to approach her?
She's strictly guarded
and isn't allowed any visitors.
Or is it that you can meet her
with no trouble at all?
Maybe you have a special
connection to the police or something.
What have you been
implying all this time?
Never mind.
Standing around here talking isn't wise.
Let's go somewhere else.
If that's an order from the Organization, then I have no choice but to oblige.
How'd it go?
It was no good.
Looks like no one
is allowed to visit her.
Seriously?!
Is her condition that bad?
We'll have to look into this.
Oh, but how?
With this!
I see!
That's right!
We have our strong ally!
Professor!
How's the
data restoration going?
If it's just the latest sent data,
it looks like I can manage to recover it.
Okay, please hurry.
I-I will.
How about this?
Genta-kun,
you can't put a piece there.
I can't?
Oops, my mistake.
Oh?
Detective Takagi!
You're right!
He's finally back!
How's the lady?
Does it sound like we can see her?
Keep quiet.
Because it's a secret
that I brought you in here.
Who are you
keeping it secret from?
Oh, sorry.
I said that out of habit,
since that's how it usually is.
Oh, Miss!
I'm so glad you seem okay!
Does your head not hurt anymore?
Yeah.
I'm fine now.
Thank you.
Under normal circumstances,
we must not let anyone see her.
But since she seems to trust you kids,
we thought it might help her regain her memory.
Really?
Yay!
Thank you!
However, you may only be here
until the start of the next investigation.
Okay!
There!
Where should I make my next move?
Let me see.
How about right here?
Okay!
What do you think of that?!
What should we do now?
They got us good.
We did it, Miss!
What can we do?
Yeah, we did.
Oh, right.
Here, this is for you.
What?
But this is...
The man from the darts
booth gave it to us afterwards.
He said you can paint it
with whichever color you like.
Is it really okay
for me to have it?
Yeah!
You saved my life, after all!
Miss.
Now we all have matching ones.
We do.
What color do you
want to paint it, Miss?
Red? Pink?
If it were me,
I'd paint it black like an orca.
But I think white suits
you better than black.
Your hair is white...
And if you go with white,
you can leave it as is...
Which would make it a great deal.
Genta-kun,
what you just said is wrong.
You're making it sound like
a bargain she found during a sale.
That's fine,
don't you think?
Are you okay, Genta-kun?
Yeah, my bad.
Are you all okay?
Yeah.
Oh, man!
I was just winning, too!
Isn't that only
because of the lady?!
What?
You didn't do anything but
follow her instructions, did you?
Yeah, pretty much.
Excuse me.
Huh?
I'm Kazami,
from Public Security.
I heard the person in
charge here is Inspector Megure.
Are you Inspector Megure?
Indeed, I am Megure.
We want you to hand over that woman over there without delay.
Why?
We should also have
authority for investigating.
This woman is suspected of having
infiltrated the National Police Agency.
We need to hear her
motive for that immediately.
If you've grasped the situation...
I'd like you to begin the preparations
to hand her over right away.
You don't have the
authority to deny my request.
Understood.
This way, please.
I have already
prepared the application.
What's going to
happen to you, Miss?
Who knows?
Okay, this is the
end of your visit with her.
Please go home, you guys.
Come, let's get you back
to your hospital room now.
Okay.
Oh, Miss!
You're leaving?
Miss!
Thank you, guys.
I'll cherish this.
Okay.
Let's all ride the Ferris wheel
together again someday.
Yeah!
That's a promise!
We'll all ride with you!
Now, let's go.
Is she going to be okay?
I know...
I'm worried, too.
Yeah.
Oh, Shin'ichi.
The data analysis is done.
And what did you find?
Look.
"The NOCs are
Stout, Aquavit, and Riesling."
"The two whom you doubted..."
"Bourbon and Kir"?!
Damn it!
So it's just like I thought!
Professor, please analyze who that
message was being sent to as soon as possible!
O-Okay.
Give me a call
as soon as you have it!
Haibara...
Don't go...
Please.
I've told you this before.
"Don't run from your fate."
I don't wanna run from mine, either.
Kudo-kun...
Thank you, Detective Takagi.
Sorry for being so unreasonable.
It's okay.
You get home safe, now.
Okay.
Cheer up, Genta-kun.
I'm sure we'll see her again.
But...
Oh, yeah!
Why don't we go ride
the Ferris wheel now?
Yeah!
And the lady
wanted to ride it again, too...
So let's take pictures of
the scenery and send it to her!
If we left now,
it'll be night by the time we get there...
And we might not be able
to ride because of the long line.
Don't worry.
I'm sure the Suzuki Financial Group has invested funds into the Tohto Aquarium...
So here.
Oh, I see!
That's right!
We have one other strong ally!
It seems you
suspect us of being NOCs.
Both of your names were on the
NOC list we received from Curaçao.
Curaçao...
Rum's confidant?
Yes.
She's a specialist
in gathering information.
Seems like you
already know about her.
Her distinguishing characteristic is that
her left and right eyes are different colors...
That is, she's odd-eyed.
Everyone in the Organization's
heard the story about her.
For old times sake, we'll give you
painless deaths if you're honest and confess.
The reason you captured us
rather than assassinating us...
Is because the info you got
from Curaçao was incomplete.
Am I wrong?
You're as shrewd as ever, Bourbon.
Everything went smoothly
up until she stole the NOC list...
But then she was found by the police
and got into an accident as she was trying to get away.
And to make things worse,
she now suffers from amnesia.
Then shouldn't you go recover Curaçao
and get a hold of the NOC list?!
Gin...
It won't be too late if you wait until after
you've confirmed whether or not we're really NOCs!
You're right.
However...
Gin!
Bro?!
You're guilty
until proven innocent.
Because that's how I operate.
Now...
It's time to exact
judgment on you traitors!
Aren't you done yet, Professor?
Don't be impatient.
The data analysis
will be done in 30 seconds.
Okay...
Once you've uncovered the address,
do what I told you earlier!
Right.
I just need to send a message...
And make it appear to have come from this broken smartphone, right?
Yes, and please hurry!
We have no time to waste!
Oh, it's done!
He hung up...
Over here, Cool Kid!
For now, just read this.
I-Is this...?!
Kir!
What's the matter, Kir?
Continue what you were doing!
You want to take
the handcuffs off, don't you?
You'd shoot your own
solely on the grounds of suspicion?!
You're not the ones who
decide whether you're one of us.
I reprieve your judgment
for just one last minute.
I'll pay respect to the one of you
who sells the other out first...
By letting them
watch a rat bite the dust.
Vodka, start counting.
Roger.
60 seconds...
You think you'll get to me
with those threats?!
If I said she's a NOC, that would be the same as acknowledging I am a NOC myself.
You wouldn't let someone
like that get away unpunished.
50 seconds...
Heh.
How about you?
I can be surprisingly kind...
Kir.
40 seconds...
So you two get along well,
and will cover for each other, huh?
I'm not covering for her at all.
I don't know whether she's a NOC.
Same here!
30 seconds.
But I can say this:
I am not a NOC!
That's my line!
Now...
20 seconds!
Which one of you is the rat?
Gin...
Don't tell me
you're actually serious...?
Which one of you
is going to squeal first?
Ten seconds...
Nine...
Eight...
Will it be...
Seven...
Bourbon?
Six...
Or Kir?
Five...
Four...
Three...
Two...
You're going down first...
One...
Zero!
Bourbon!
What?
What happened?
T-The lights!
Kir! Bourbon!
Don't you dare move!
B-Bourbon's gone!
He escaped!
Damn.
How'd he do it?!
After him!
Sorry, Kir.
I couldn't show you
the carcass of a rat.
But there's no need to
worry about being alone.
I'll send Bourbon over to you soon.
Farewell, Kir.
Gin, wait!
You can't shoot!
It's an order from Rum!
So, what are your orders for us?
Okay. Copy that.
It seems he got a
message from Curaçao...
Saying the two of them
were not involved.
She regained her memory?
Looks like this has
cleared us of all suspicion.
So will you get these
handcuffs off of me, already?
You can't!
There's more to Rum's order.
He says, "I need you to confirm whether
the message I received was really sent by Curaçao."
Though it will probably be an awful lot of trouble
to recover her from the police hospital.
That is of no concern.
If my intuition is right,
there will be some movement soon.
Nice timing, Gin.
The dimwits from Public Security
finally started making their move.
Thought so.
They sure are fools to not
even know they've been bugged.
So, where are they headed?
Right where you had expected.
They are just about
to shove her in the car now.
Get the aircraft ready.
You can't be serious!
It's a good chance
for us to test its power.
You're not thinking
of starting a war, are you?
It's an order from Rum.
This mission
absolutely must be a success.
Roger that.
Can't take it, can't take it,
can't take it anymore!
It feels like this intense excitement
is gonna make me climax.
I can't take it, either.
Gin, are you seriously
intending to use that?!
I couldn't find him, Bro.
He got away.
Doesn't matter.
We'll put off eliminating
Bourbon and Kir.
Recovering Curaçao comes first.
But the hospital is swarming with police and Public Security officers.
Curaçao has already left the hospital.
Where to, then?
Our destination is...
Tohto Aquarium.
Gin!
Don't tell me you set that up in advance,
knowing this would happen?
We're going, Vodka.
Bring the car around.
Right!
Yeah, got it.
I need you to head
over there right away.
We'll perform the rescue.
Understood.
It seems that the two of them
got out of their dilemma.
Thank goodness.
Amazing!
Your plan was a
huge success, wasn't it, kid?!
No, it was nothing special.
That message ended
in the middle of a sentence...
So I continued it by adding...
"You can rest assured
that neither of them were involved."
And simply sent that.
Good, then those two
are no longer in danger.
Yeah.
No.
This is nothing more
than a temporary measure.
The enemy has prioritized
the recovery of their spy...
And it seems they're now
headed to the Tohto Aquarium.
Not the police hospital?!
Yes...
She's apparently being lead out and taken to the aquarium by Public Security.
The aquarium...?
Then we should go, too...
No.
Akai-kun is already on his way there.
We'll take care of rescuing the undercover agent
who was left at the warehouse district...
As well as searching for the NOC list.
Yes, sir!
Conan-kun,
you should get out of the car.
There's no telling what
might happen from here on out.
But...
It's okay.
The FBI will definitely settle this.
Okay.
I'll leave it to you guys, then.
Yeah.
We'll contact you once it's over.
Oh, come to think of it...
How much does Akai-san
know about that spy?
Not much, apparently.
He only knows that they're Rum's confidant, and go by the codename Curaçao.
Thanks, and be careful.
So she's not Rum, but Curaçao...
Curaçao is a liqueur
made from orange peels.
Its main varieties are
white curaçao, orange curaçao...
Blue curaçao,
green curaçao, and red curaçao.
Could it be...
I knew it.
There are five colors.
Where have I
seen this color scheme...
Where?
Try to remember!
If this is a key, then—
She has an extremely rare injury
in the fornix of her brain...
She's pressing on her head
and is in extreme pain.
She's also saying something,
but we don't know what it means...
She said
"Stout, Aquavit, and Riesling".
I see.
If my reasoning is right, then the Organization and Public Security's movements make sense.
But that means...
This is bad!
I have to hurry...
Or else the NOC list will fall
into the Organization's hands!
Yes, yes.
We took her into custody,
as per your instructions.
Oh?
You're telling me
to ride the Ferris wheel?
Yes.
It's not a sure-fire method...
But right now,
we can only take a chance on it.
You'll do it, right?
Yes.
That aside,
we should meet up very soon.
No, we don't know where
the Organization might be watching.
I'll head to the Ferris wheel directly.
Bye.
Please wait, Furuya-san—
Jeez.
Why do I have to come to
the aquarium during Golden Week?
And to make things worse,
I'm here with these kids!
Hey, we're here!
We've been waiting for this!
Yay!
Let's go!
Wait, you guys.
Stay right there.
Okay!
What will you do, Dad?
I'm not in the mood
for looking at fish today.
I'll sleep here,
so you go enjoy yourselves.
Thanks.
I'll go make the arrangements.
Right.
The aquarium again?
I thought they'd surely
take her to the scene of the accident.
That woman had seizures
on the Ferris wheel here.
There might be some
secret regarding that there.
For now, let's stay here
and keep an eye on the situation.
Yes, sir.
Sonoko-neechan's not here...
Yeah...
I'm sure she'll be here
any minute now, though.
I need you to let me ride
the Ferris wheel.
I'm sorry, but ticket sales
for today have ended.
Then, please tell this
to the person in charge here.
A Public Security officer
requests your cooperation.
Very well.
Ran!
Please wait here.
Over here!
Oh, she's finally here!
Sonoko.
Sorry to have kept you waiting. The formalities took some time.
Yay!
We knew you could do it,
Sonoko-oneesan!
You all better be grateful.
We are!
Sorry for making you
give me a free ticket, too.
No, don't worry about it.
You didn't add any extra trouble.
Well then,
please look after the kids.
Yes, of course.
Now then, I'll lead the way
to the Ferris wheel...
So please follow me, everyone.
Okay!
Sure thing.
Is it really okay
to have her look after them?
Yeah.
She works as a tour guide here,
so it's totally okay.
That aside, are you sure you don't want to invite Shin'ichi-kun?
Huh?!
What should we do?
Well, the most important thing
is to keep your guard up.
What's wrong?
You know them?
No.
That's not it...
But I get the feeling I've seen that woman who's with the Public Security officers somewhere before.
Those guys are Public Security officers?
Yeah, I wonder
if something has happened.
What's with them?
How irritating.
Let's just go.
Yeah.
Sorry, Sonoko.
I'm really concerned
about those people we just saw.
Just take the opportunity
in front of you and give him a call.
Crap.
If this one's ringing, then it must be...
I thought so.
What's up, Ran?
Oh, Shin'ichi?
There's something
I need to talk with you about.
What is it?
Please keep it short.
You're busy right now?
Tell me, tell me.
What'd he say?
Y-Yeah.
C-Cut it out, Sonoko!
Ran's really blushing!
Jeez.
Stop!
Are you listening, Ran?
Sorry, but
I'm swamped right now.
So I'm hanging up.
Oh!
Wait, Shin'ichi!
Thank you for visiting
the Tohto Aquarium today.
I'll call you back
once things settle down here.
Wait, don't tell me...
Where are you right now?
Hanging up!
That guy...
He said something about him being busy
and hung up again, didn't he?!
Yeah...
Where is he,
and what could he be doing?
About that,
it sounded like he's here.
Huh?
What do you mean?
I heard the intercom announcement here
coming through Shin'ichi's phone...
I see...
So the problem is:
Who is he with?
Huh?
You sure are naive!
Do you really think a guy
would come to a place like this alone?!
Now, let's go catch
that cheater red-handed!
What?!
Hey, Sonoko!
Seems there isn't
just one, single power supply.
So that means the older facility
is on a different line?
Well, nothing I can do about it.
All done.
Now they won't immediately
find you when you show up.
Nice work.
Hurry!
We'll begin taking
action in 15 minutes.
Got it!
Let's get this thing moving!
Thank you for riding the
Tohto Aquarium's Ferris wheel today.
It is almost time for
the special water and light show...
But due to inspections
on the North Wheel...
We ask that those planning
to ride board only the South Wheel side.
We apologize for this inconvenience...
Right this way, please.
But please follow the staff's instructions
and enjoy your stroll through the pleasant sky.
Whoa!
Yay!
A shortcut!
Hold on just a sec, you guys.
Who might they be?
They're the friends of Suzuki-sama.
What?!
Then, this side is reserved
just for these kids?!
Seems like it.
The special light and water show
that you all have been waiting for...
Will begin in 30 minutes.
Damn it!
I'll never be able to
find her in this crowd!
We hope that you enjoy the dazzling lights and dynamic water spectacular.
But no matter what,
I have to stop her before she gets on!
What in the world
is Public Security trying to do?!
Whoa, things are getting pretty wild.
I wonder if something happened?
Are those...?
Where's Kudo-kun?
I knew it!
He's on that Ferris wheel?!
I've brought the
Public Security officers.
Don't tell me
the reservation is for them?
It is, per our demand.
I'm very sorry!
I misunderstood and let some children get on as a guest about ten minutes ago!
What do we do now?
Shall we wait until they come back?
No.
It's fine, if it's only kids.
Anyway, now that we've ascertained
the safety of the Ferris wheel...
We can be sure that they'll only come
after us once we're on the ground again.
So stay sharp and alert.
Yes, sir.
Let's go, then.
I'm sorry.
I got separated from my friends.
Sorry!
Please let me through.
Stop, you can't get on!
Hold it.
This area is off limits.
Damn.
So I just missed them?
Please go to the
back of the line, kid.
Sorry, coming through!
If they were to plant something here...
It'd have to be in this staff area
where they wouldn't attract attention.
I've got to expose their plan to Public Security
and the FBI as quickly as possible!
Is that Akai-san?!
What are all those cords?!
They couldn't be...
But if they are...
This is bad!
I've got to check, and quickly!
There she is!
Just as we expected.
I confirmed
Curaçao is in the gondola.
There's only one
Public Security officer riding with her.
I expect it'll take them
about ten minutes to reach the top.
Ten minutes, huh?
How are we doing, Vodka?
Ready to start whenever you want.
What about the rest
of the Public Security officers?
It seems there are several
of them stationed at each section...
But they should pose
no threat to our plan.
Then, we'll begin
moving on your signal.
Roger that.
Do you really not
remember me, you bitch?
Yes, that's right.
Well, that doesn't matter.
Once your memories return,
we'll torment you to our heart's content.
We'll have you cough up
where you hid the NOC list...
As well as everything you know
about the Organization.
This should make me
the first one to get here.
So you did come?!
I see you managed
to escape just fine.
If you're here,
then just as I thought...
What?
What happened?
T-The lights!
You shot down the ceiling lights...
Thus depriving them of their vision.
Kir! Bourbon!
Don't you dare move!
You then realized I was trapped
inside the warehouse, still unable to move...
After him!
So in order to make it look like
I may have escaped outside...
You fooled them
by kicking the door open.
Sorry, Kir.
I couldn't show you
the carcass of a rat.
Thanks to that, I was
able to hide in the shadows...
But there's no need to
worry about being alone.
And learn about their next move.
I'll send Bourbon over to you soon.
I figured you'd come here
if that was indeed your doing.
But let me ask you this:
What's your motive behind rescuing us?
Even without putting
yourself in such danger...
Couldn't you have still gotten information on them by listening in?
So you came all
the way here just to chitchat?
Yeah.
I came here to tell you
the FBI needs to back out of this.
We, Public Security,
will be the ones to take Curaçao.
And if I refuse?
Then we'll just have to
take her from you by force.
Pull out, Akai Shuuichi!
For all these electrical cords
to be connected to the fire hose box...
There's something strange here,
no matter how I think about it.
I can't just carelessly open this.
But maybe through here...
Is that a detonator?
That means...
These cords that are
strung up around the axle...
Must be connected to explosives.
What do I do?
The fact that this is
a remote-controlled detonator...
Means that if I recklessly cause a
huge panic and attract their attention...
It'll be curtains for everyone!
That's right...
He's here!
And now, the moment
you've all been waiting for...
What's going on?
The special water and light
show will begin momentarily!
No one's riding it.
No, it can't be!
Why are those kids in there?!
I've told you this before, Amuro-kun.
Don't mistake which
prey you should go after.
Yeah.
I'll hunt their
entire organization down...
Right after I neutralize you!
What'll you do if Curaçao
regains her memory...
And they start attacking
while you're doing this?!
What don't you just
come out and say it?
The Japanese police let information get stolen from right under their noses...
And you can't trust them!
Damn it!
Where did Akai-san go?
Please pick up!
Is he over there?!
W-Where is he?!
Cut it out, already.
You're surrendering already?
Now, let's go for round two!
Akai-san!
You're over there, right?
This is really bad!
I need your help!
If they fail in retrieving Curaçao...
They plan on using bombs
to blow up this entire Ferris wheel!
So, please!
If you're over there,
I really need your help!
If we don't disarm the bombs before those guys set them off, it'll be a disaster!
Are you sure, Conan-kun?
Amuro-san?
How'd you get here?!
I'll explain later.
More importantly,
where are the bombs?
A bunch of them are set
in between the axle and the wheel!
They're remote-controlled,
so there's no telling when they'll explode!
We have to disarm them, and quickly!
All right!
I'll be right there with the FBI!
Wow, that was so beautiful!
Y-Yeah...
Cheer up, Ran.
I'll definitely find him for you.
I'm not worried about that.
I'm just afraid we'll get in his way
if he's in the middle of an investigation.
Just how far does your belief
in the goodness of people go?
Do you hear me?!
I'll definitely catch
that cheater red-handed!
Leave it alone already, Sonoko!
I can't!
We still haven't checked
the one best, special place!
The best, special place?
Yeah!
It's right over there.
The aquarium?
That's right!
How's it going, Amuro-san?
I almost got it.
Everything will be fine now.
So they really set a trap.
Yeah.
It was the right choice
to not simply open it.
Akai-san, what'd you find out
about the explosives?
They're C-4, like I thought.
And they're all
extraordinarily well-placed.
If they all exploded simultaneously...
The axle won't be able to
withstand the weight...
Likely causing it
to collapse in a chain reaction.
I see.
Looks like we have
no time to waste stressing.
So this is it?!
So, do you think you can disarm it?
Not a problem.
It's a very common type...
So I know how to disarm it.
Wow...
You're well-versed
in bombs, Amuro-san?
During my days in the police academy, my friend taught me a lot about them.
He later became an
ace in the bomb squad.
Although he ended up dying in an explosion
while trying to disarm a bomb on a Ferris wheel.
While disarming a bomb
planted on a Ferris wheel...
No need to worry.
His technique was flawless.
I'll prove it to you!
Use this.
There's a set of tools in there.
I'll leave the disarming to you.
What about you, Akai-san?!
The fact that there are explosives means they'll definitely attack this Ferris wheel.
And for them to rescue Curaçao
without getting injured by the bombs here...
The only feasible route would be...
From the sky!
Right.
I'll go back to my former position
and buy us some time.
Do whatever it takes
to disarm the bombs!
He makes it sounds so simple.
Amuro-san, use this.
Ah, thank you.
The rest depends on just how much time we'll get to disarm this.
That's true.
We don't know
when the bombs will go off.
No, wait.
The place they
planted the explosives at is...
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
I have to protect the NOC list!
Man, what's with those two?!
This is it!
These spotlights have the same number of colors
as the five colored films Curaçao had on her.
And unlike during the day, they now
have almost the same level of transparency!
If my reasoning is correct...
Curaçao will remember the NOC list when she sees this color scheme with this level of saturation.
In other words, her own brain
acted like flash memory...
And the point in which the
door to that memory will be opened...
Is when the gondola
reaches the very top!
When she sees this color scheme
with the perfect saturation level...
All her memories
will come back this time.
It's just about there.
Gin, this is the final confirmation.
I'll start in three minutes.
Ready?
We're ready whenever you are.
Just start them up.
Chianti.
Switch to noise reduction mode
and standby at point Alpha.
Roger!
I have to disarm this as quickly as possible,
and then meet up with Kazami.
If memory serves me right,
this one is next...
Wow,
that was a close one.
If this light comes on, it's all over.
Impatience is the greatest trap of all.
Right, Matsuda?
What in the world's going on?
We're almost halfway around.
If it wasn't for
those fireworks earlier...
The information I got
from Furuya-san would be wrong.
Hey, what's wrong?
Stop that, and calm down!
What's going on?
Didn't she already
get her memory back?!
Don't tell me the message
Rum received wasn't from...
Calm down and sit!
Hey, stop it!
You brought this on yourself, Curaçao.
That unique brain of yours has memorized a truth
that puts the Organization in a bad position.
Your ability is indeed
quite extraordinary.
But it can pose a huge threat
if used incorrectly.
You understand what I'm saying, right?
This was your fate all along.
Farewell, Curaçao.
Stop.
T-This can't be...
W-What are you doing here?!
Stand down, Vermouth.
You have no "color", Curaçao.
There is only pitch-black
darkness in you.
R-Rum?
If that darkness is torturing you,
simply dye it another color.
You shall use that special brain of yours
for me and me alone.
Both input and output.
And you will become
my right arm, Curaçao.
Hey, are you okay?
Hang in there!
Sheesh...
Hold on a minute.
I'll call an ambulance for you now.
That won't be necessary.
So her memory returned, after all.
Curaçao has entered
the pick up area.
Two minutes until she reaches the top.
Isn't it about time to start?
Vodka, bring out the arm.
Roger!
Opening the hatch.
Judging by the sound of the rotors,
they should already be nearby.
What are they planning
on starting here?!
Could it be...
Who's this?
It's been a while, Vermouth.
Sounds like your memories
have come back, after all.
Yeah.
More importantly,
when is my pick up coming?
It seems the outside is swarming
with Public Security agents.
That's not a problem...
Because Gin is on his way to you.
Gin?!
Yeah.
By the way, when did
your memories come back?
I heard Rum's been
contacted from your phone.
If you weren't the one
who sent the message...
Oh, that message?
I'm the one who sent it, of course.
Is there any problem with it?
I see.
In that case, Kir and Bourbon
are in the clear.
So he ran away because he didn't
want to be needlessly killed?
It's almost time, Cinderella.
Wait right where you are
for your pumpkin carriage to arrive.
Okay.
Five seconds left.
Three...
Two...
One...
Zero!
What?!
Damn it!
They've already started!
The signal from Vermouth
has been confirmed.
The grounds have been
engulfed in darkness.
Okay.
Begin descending at once.
Snatch Curaçao out of there!
Aye aye, sir!
Please calm down!
We have everything under control!
The lights will be restored shortly.
Please remain calm and stay where you are.
It's a little dangerous,
so please don't run around!
We ask for your
cooperation in this.
Hey, look over there!
The aquarium still has its lights on!
Hey, let's go there.
Okay.
Come on!
Let's go, everyone!
No, don't!
It's not safe,
so please don't move!
I have a terrible feeling about this.
I have to get the kids
out of there, and quickly!
What's this?
A blackout in a place like this?
We sure are unlucky.
Just a little longer,
and we would've made it down, too...
How's it going?
It's no good.
It's not going through.
What's Kazami-san doing?
Sato-kun. Takagi-kun.
It seems the Public Security folks
don't fully grasp the situation, either.
I thought so.
What should we do, then?
Let's offer them our assistance.
But those guys are...
This is not the time to argue about the difference in positions.
Understood?
Yes, sir!
Doesn't look like he's here, either.
Yeah...
Sorry, Sonoko.
I may have just been mistaken.
Hey, look outside!
You won't believe what's going on!
Let me through!
Excuse me.
Please let me see, too.
What is this?!
What's going on?
I can't tell the wires
apart in this darkness.
I was just about
to finish disarming it...
But they took away my vision
at the most critical time.
I can go back to the Organization
if I just sit still here, huh?
Don't tell me...
They're using that
to take the gondola?!
Who's that?!
Excellent aircraft control!
20 until our mark.
I'll keep going at this pace!
A Public Security agent...
So the one who jumped out
earlier really was Curaçao!
This is bad!
Wake up, mister!
Mister!
I don't stand a chance
against them with this rifle...
But there has to be
a weak point somewhere.
Damn it!
Is it no use trying
from this distance?
Okay, let's move out.
Aye aye, sir!
At 8 o'clock...
Above the Ferris wheel...
I saw something move.
Public Security
made a run for it, huh?
Inspect the gondola
with the heat sensor!
Roger!
T-That's the outline of a man?!
There's also a a kid riding it, too.
Bro, Curaçao ain't on it!
What?!
Curaçao!
Discard the gondola.
R-Roger.
Oh, come on...
You've gotta be kidding me!
What's that?!
Gin, what's going on?
Curaçao has disappeared.
What?!
Change of plans.
We'll dispose of Curaçao.
Don't be hasty.
You don't know
whether she's betrayed us yet.
She left the gondola.
Can you think of any reason for doing that,
other than her running away?
Find Curaçao at once!
Roger.
Chianti, get us away
from the Ferris wheel.
Aye aye, sir.
Korn, get the IDWS ready.
Understood.
Don't tell me that's—
What?
Are you planning
on taking me back to them?
Them?
You mean the Organization?
So her memories
really did come back.
Could you possibly be...
Sherry, who
betrayed the Organization?
Now, we're running away.
It's not safe here.
What do you mean, "run away"?
If this is some kind of a bad joke,
can you just stop?!
Gin is here.
You should know
very well what that means.
B-But, why did you save me?
I don't know.
I have no idea why I saved you.
Still, I am Curaçao
who can assume any color!
And I prefer the current me
over the old me.
That's all there is to it!
Now let's go, Sherry-chan.
Wait!
The kids are
still aboard the gondola!
We have to hurry and save them!
I don't know
what happened, but now...
All right!
I can distinguish the wires
from the detonator!
Focus.
Be careful, and
don't get ahead of yourself.
But do it fast!
Mister!
Hang in there, Mister!
This isn't good!
Still?
You still can't find Curaçao?!
There are shadows
moving on the Ferris wheel...
Two kids and some adults.
And this one is bad news!
Bro!
There's somebody
close to the detonator!
What?!
Look, right here.
If I remember right,
it's mounted inside this fire hose box.
Public Security found out about it?
These are the last two cords
connected to the detonator.
Now I just need to
cut this, and I'm done.
I did it!
That was a really close one.
Shower them, Korn...
Rain down bullets on them!
Now that's what I'm talking about!
Do it, Korn.
Understood!
W-What is going on?!
Damn it!
I've got to do something!
This isn't good.
I have to hurry.
So even sniping from
above is out of the question?
It's no good.
Looks like it's hard to get through
because everyone else here is calling, too.
I hope those kids are okay.
Hurry, jump!
Run!
Damn it!
I'm targeted the instant I move...
I can't do anything at this rate!
I'm the one they're after.
Don't tell me you're
planning to act as a decoy!
I'll leave the kids to you.
Don't!
You'll get yourself killed!
This movement and form...
Make no mistake.
That's Curaçao!
What?!
Now they're concentrating
their strikes in one area.
They're targeting someone.
Now's my chance to move!
Die, Curaçao!
No way...
All response from
Curaçao has disappeared.
Mission accomplished!
No, not yet.
We still have to finish off the rats.
Aim at the bombs on the axle.
T-The axle?
Yeah.
If Curaçao was still alive...
She would be likely to take advantage of the panic from the Ferris wheel collapsing to get away...
But this is fine for taking care of
the likes of Public Security.
Korn!
Reload the machine gun immediately,
and take down the axle!
Let's put an end to this
before the Air Self-Defense Force arrives.
Understood.
I'll end this.
Haibara-san!
Are you guys all okay?
Y-Yeah...
Ai-chan,
what's going on here?
I'll tell you everything later.
But for now, just stay calm.
Okay.
Sure.
Akai-san!
Amuro-san!
Over here.
Akai-san!
Are you okay, kid?
Yeah.
You have to hide.
I can still hear
the sound of the rotors.
Where's Amuro-san?
No idea.
But since they switched
to attacking directly...
He must have succeeded
in disarming the bomb.
So now it's a matter
of how to deal with them.
Is that rifle just for show?!
Amuro-san!
Don't you have any way
to counterattack, FBI?
There are ways.
But my night-vision scope
has been laid to waste...
And now all I can use is this
regular scope I brought with me as a spare.
And I can't shoot down that
huge steel crow in the dead of night with this.
You'd be able to take them down
if you could see them?
Yes.
But how?
Targeting the couplings
of the rotor should do it.
I couldn't see any couplings!
Direct confrontation
is out of the question.
But if we could somehow throw them off
from their current position...
And then shine a light in the direction
of the rotors for about five seconds...
I think I can shine light on them...
But unless I have some idea of what they look like,
I won't be able to aim at the rotors.
Don't tell me they plan
on making the axle explode?!
They plan on having
the entire Ferris wheel collapse?
This isn't good.
Half of the explosives
are still on the axle!
Shoot, shoot, shoot!
Dammit!
I can tell which direction
they're shooting from...
But I don't know
where the rotors are!
You just need to have a general
idea of what they look like, right?
Here we go...
Don't waste this chance!
I can see it!
Go!
That light...
It's fireworks!
W-What's that?!
Fireworks...?
We're under attack!
B-But where in the world from?!
You're going down!
Did we do it?!
All right!
Shit! Shit!
We'll crash down at this rate!
Korn, move aside!
Damn it!
It'll be a disaster
if the axle gets destroyed!
This thing won't hold up any longer.
Time to bail out!
Run!
Get away from the aquarium!
This is really bad!
If it keeps rolling like that,
it'll hit the aquarium!
Just who in the world
were those guys?
I have no interest in people
standing at death's door.
Everyone!
All guests in the park are to move to the stadium of the dolphin show immediately.
Please move to the stadium
for the dolphin show immediately!
It's not safe here!
The Ferris wheel...
Ran!
We have to get out of here!
Crap!
The hill's making it go faster!
Conan-kun!
Amuro-san!
Can you stop it?!
I don't know...
But I have to try!
Amuro-san!
I'm fine. Just focus!
Here we go!
Okay.
Please make it!
Akai-san!
You have some sort of plan, right?
How about this?!
All right!
No, it's still not working...?
It's no use!
It's not stopping!
Sonoko, hurry up!
Run!
That won't be enough to stop it!
That's okay!
I still have a trick up my sleeve!
Kudo-kun?!
Damn it!
We'll never make it at this rate!
Stop!
Don't rush into things!
Akai-san!
How about this?!
Ran!
Isn't that ball...?
Inflate!
Faster!
Bigger!
Run!
Watch out!
It's no use.
It's not stopping!
You guys...
Stop!
Did it stop?
Alright! It stopped!
Conan-kun
must've stopped it!
Hooray!
What an amazing kid.
He actually managed to
stop that huge Ferris wheel.
That mobile crane...
Who could have been driving it?
You did well, kid.
Y-Yeah...
Please wait.
I want to confirm the body.
Oh, we don't mind...
But the body's in no condition
to be able to distinguish anything.
Okay, good work.
You may go now.
Is that...?
Yeah.
Kid.
Do you mind showing me
what you just picked up?
What is this?
Don't tell me
it's flash memory?!
No.
It's not memory, but a memento.
Although it's been
burned and charred black.
In regards to the explosions
at the Tohto Aquarium last night...
Breaking Special Report
Tohto Aquarium Ferris Wheel Collapses!!
What is the Attacker's Motive?
Man, I was so close.
The National Police Agency announced that they found the remains of the foreigner behind those explosions.
Oh, come on...
You sure suck at this.
Then why don't you give it
a try this time, Genta-kun?
After causing the collapse of the Ferris wheel,
the attacker stole a nearby vehicle.
Fine.
Let me show you!
You know...
Aw... I wish I could
be as good as that lady.
She told me that
she wanted to save us.
Yeah.
The wheel eventually caught up
to the attacker's stolen vehicle...
Come to think of it,
I wonder where that lady went?
If she didn't, she wouldn't have held onto that keychain just before dying.
She must be doing well.
In which they met their end.
Are you talking about the amnesiac you met at the aquarium?
But I still don't get why she did.
Yeah!
We played games in the hospital.
And we even gave her a keychain!
It made her so happy, didn't it?!
Yeah, we all have matching ones.
Here's mine.
And here's mine!
Wow.
But she's not here anymore...
She must have went back to where she
came from after she got her memories back.
We were so close
to becoming her friend, too...
I know...
But, you know...
Aren't you already her friend?
You all are thinking
so much about her, after all.
I see.
Yes, you're right.
Yeah!
We're friends!
It's possible that those guys
are what changed her.
Yeah.
At the very end, her color changed.
So it's "though I try to hide it", huh?