Detective Conan —
Crossroad In The Ancient Capital
I'm high school detective, Kudo Shin'ichi.
Original Story: Aoyama Gosho
When I went to an amusement park
with my childhood friend Mouri Ran,
I witnessed a suspicious
transaction between some men in black.
Script: Furuuichi Issei
Because my attention was focused on the transaction,
I didn't notice another member approach me from behind.
Music: Oono Katsuo
I was given a poison.
When I came to,
my body had shrunk!
Vice Director: Akira Nishimori
If they found out that Kudo Shin'ichi was still alive,
they would come after me again and
endanger the lives of those around me.
Character Design: Sudou Masatomo
Following Professor Agasa's
advice, I decided to hide my identity.
Art Director: Shibuya Yukihiro
Construction: Nishi Kayoko
When Ran asked who I was, I
blurted out "Edogawa Conan".
Books: "Edogawa Ranpo Volume 13, 14, 15" and "Conan Doyle"
Director of Photography: Nomura Takashi
Director of Acoustics: Kobayashi Katsuyoshi
In order to find more information about the men in black,
I moved in with Ran and her father, who is a detective.
I'm the high school detective of Osaka,
Hattori Heiji.
My strong reasoning and kendo skills,
Note: "Kendo" is the Japanese martial art practiced by samurai.
were passed on to me by my father who works
in the Osaka Prefectural Police Headquarters.
and my bravery was inherited from,
my mother.
By the way, I inherited my
dark-colored skin from my grandfather.
They used to say "Hattori of
the West" and "Kudo of the East",
Both of us were equally well-known, but...
Edogawa Conan: Takayama Minami
Kudo really is something.
With the help of Professor Agasa,
an inventor of strange machines,
Mouri Kogoro: Kamiya Akira
Mouri Ran: Yamazaki Wakana
He has solved many cases.
There are people who know Kudo's real identity,
Inspector Megure: Chafurin
Dr. Agasa: Ogata Kenichi
besides Professor Agasa and myself.
Kudo's father and mother,
Kudo Shin'ichi: Yamaguchi Kappei
and a girl who attends the same
elementary school as Kudo, Haibara Ai.
This little girl used to be in the
same organization as the men in black.
But in order to escape,
she drank the same poison that Kudo was given,
and her body shrank as well.
Producers:
Suwa Michiko
Yoshioka Masahito
By the way, I have a childhood
friend who's in the same grade as me.
Her name is Tooyama Kazuha. She's a fussy woman.
Who are you calling fussy!?
Hey! Don't show up so suddenly, idiot!
You're the idiot!
Who were you talking to?
Who?
I'm making it easier to
understand for everybody that's watching!
Right?
Huh?
Is something wrong with your head?
You're the one who's got something wrong.
Even though I've become
small, my mind is still the same.
Director: Kanetsugu Kodama
There is only one truth!
Beika, Beika station, the exit will be...
So you won't be able to come back for a while.
Yeah, I'm pretty busy investigating a case right now.
Oh.
It's been cold these past few
days, so you'd better be careful.
Same to you. Don't sleep with your stomach exposed.
I don't sleep with my stomach exposed! Idiot!
Yoshinoyama!
Note: Yoshinoyama refers to a play written about two characters in
Japanese history, Minamoto Yoshitsune and his concubine, Shizuka Gozen.
They separated when Yoshitsune's brother pressed him to flee to northern Japan.
Treading through the white snow of the mountain,
longing for a trace of life to appear...
It's as if you two were Yoshitsune and Shizuka Gozen.
What!?
Is there something wrong about
worrying for your childhood friend?
I'm going to hang up now because my dad's being noisy.
Ah... Hey!
Really...
Next time I'll call when he's not around.
Yoshitsune and Shizuka Gozen?
After they separated, they never reunited...
Hey, hey.
Tokyo —
Nishikuni Tachi City
Kamei no Rokurou (35)
Note: Everyone here has numbers in their
name, "Rokurou"= 6, "Hachirou"= 8, "Shichirou"= 7
Kataoka no Hachirou (34)
Washinoo no Shichirou (35)
He's so slow, that Benkei.
Yeah, he claimed he had solved the mystery.
He was the most enthusiastic about this thing.
Kataoka!
Osaka —
Late at night
Neyagawashi "Takohei"
Note: "shi"= 4
Bizen no Heishirou (35)
Kyoto —
Early dawn
East Mountain District "Snack Jirou"
Surugano Jirou (32)
Note: "ji"= 2
—Several days later—
Tokyo —
Police headquarters
The results of the investigation show,
five victims in Tokyo, Osaka, and Kyoto.
Note: Genji refers to "Genji Monogatari," which translates to "Genji Tales," written by
Murasaki Shikibu. Genji had a younger brother named "Hotaru" which means "firefly."
It was confirmed that they're
members of the robbery group, Genjibotaru.
Therefore,
this case...
Kyoto Prefectural Police
Ayanokouji Fumimaru
Sato-san,
Inspector Ayanokouji of the Kyoto Prefectural Police,
was in the same class as Inspector Shiratori?
Yes.
He's of noble descent and is called "The Royal Inspector".
Look, in his left pocket.
Eh?
What is that?
His pet chipmunk.
He takes it everywhere.
He's even weirder than Shiratori.
Genjibotaru has been stealing famous Buddhist statues.
Their activities have been centered in,
Tokyo, Osaka, and Kyoto since 1991.
Their major trait is,
their members are named after servants of Yoshitsune,
and hold identical Yoshitsune Chronicles.
Yoshitsune Chronicles
Their leader is Yoshitsune.
Yoshitsune
Benkei
Suruga no Jirou
Ise no Saburou
Bizen no Heishirou
Kamei no Rokurou
Washinoo
no Shichirou
Kataoka
no Hachirou
Following are:
Benkei,
Ise no Saburou,
all totaling to eight members.
This time, all but three have been killed,
and their Yoshitsune Chronicles have been stolen.
Any leads on the suspect?
Osaka Prefectural Police
Inspector Ootaki
All we know is that the suspect is
skilled in swordmanship and archery.
As to Yoshitsune, Benkei, and Ise no Saburou,
we do not know their ages or genders.
At any rate,
the culprit and the remaining
members of the group must be arrested.
We will do our best to continue the investigation.
Hattori Residence
Magazine: "Yoshitsune of the 20th Century, The Head of a Robbery Group"
Yoshitsune of the 20th century,
The head of a robbery group.
Heiji! Are you there?
That's not good. This is important to you, right?
Uh, y-yeah, I should put it away.
Heiji, are you going out?
Yeah, there's something I wanted to check out.
Was there something you wanted?
No.
I just thought you'd like to see
the Sakura blossoms at Tomorogi.
But, that's alright.
Really?
Then I'll be leaving.
Take care!
Yes.
Why do I have to see him off with a smiling face!?
As I thought, Kyoto is the
hometown of all Japanese people!
Alright, I brought you here on a special occasion,
so don't get in my way.
Yes sir.
Conan-kun's so lucky, he went to Kyoto.
There was a request for Mouri
from a temple called Sannou Temple.
We want to go to Kyoto, too!
Hmm...
I could take you there, but...
Really?
I can meet Conan-kun!
Kyoto! Kyoto!
Tomorrow is...
However, that's if you can answer this quiz.
Here we go.
You probably aren't going to take us, right?
Isn't this alright?
Hear him out.
It'll kill some time.
Hey, what should we do?
Let's try.
Alright.
The three of you know who Benkei is, right?
Yes.
He's Yoshitsune's servant.
Hey,
Who's Yoshitsune?
His childhood name is Ushiwakamaru.
And on Kyoto's Gojyouoohashi,
he defeated Benkei, who was
aiming to get his 1000th sword.
Benkei then became his servant.
That is Minamoto Yoshitsune.
At that time,
The Genji clan and Heike clan were fighting,
and Yoshitsune defeated the Heike clan.
But he was hated by his older brother, Yoritomo.
He committed suicide,
at Koromogawa of Hiraizumi,
where today's Iwate prefecture would be.
Wow, you seem to know a lot about him.
Now the question is:
Benkei had a first love named Uzune.
When he found out that she
was going to marry another man,
Benkei...
1. Became Angry
2. Became Happy
3. Cried
So, which one is it?
His first love!?
Of course he will be angry!
There's no reason for him to be happy!
So you say the answer is "Became Angry"?
He cried.
The answer is "Cried".
You got the idea from "Benkei's crying spot", right?
I'm no match for you, Ai-kun.
"Benkei's crying spot"?
Even a guy as strong as Benkei has a
spot that hurts enough to cry if kicked.
That's right here. "Mukouzune" is "Benkei's crying spot".
But...
What does that have to do with the quiz?
Uh,
Well that is...
I get it!
The people getting married are "Muko" and "Uzune".
Note: "Muko" translates to groom.
Muko and Uzune make "Mukouzune".
It's another big pun.
But since we got the right
answer, we can go to Kyoto now!
Uh... No, because Ai got the right answer...
Haibara-san is part of the Detective Boys, too!
Don't leave Haibara-san out!
My mom told me not to become
an adult that goes back on his word.
Thank you very much.
Thanks.
Sannou Temple
Even if you say so, this doesn't leave here.
Ryuen (34)
Monk of Sannou Temple
Oh, Mouri-san!
Thank you for coming to such a far away place.
I am Ryuen, the one who called you.
Please allow me to introduce you to,
Enkai (65)
Chief Priest of Sannou Temple
The Chief Priest, Enkai.
these three are supporters of this temple.
Sakura Shouzou (51)
Antique Arts Dealer
Sakura Shouzou-san.
He manages an antique art
dealership on Teramachi Road.
You're the famous detective Mouri Kogoro?
Ah, really? Am I that famous?
Mizuo Shuntarou (33)
Noh Performer
Next to him is,
Note: Noh theater is a special theatrical performance over 600
years old. It incorporates the Noh masks and a lot of dancing.
The young master of the Mizuo style Noh theater,
Mizuo Shuntarou.
And this is Saijou Taiga-san,
the owner of a used book store.
Saijou Taiga (35)
Used Book Store Owner
Nice to meet you.
Well, they're all more of friends in kendo than supporters.
Oh, everyone is skilled in kendo?
No wonder you are so vigorous at an old age.
Huh...
Kendo friends?
By the way,
There is a wooden Buddha
unveiled every 12 years at this temple.
Yes.
The main statue of this temple, the Healing Buddha.
It will be presented for worship two days after tomorrow.
We are looking forward to it.
Well,
I believe the Healing Buddha will be delighted.
What are you saying!?
The principal object of worship was stolen!?
Yes.
It has been eight years since it happened.
Sunlight bodhisattva
On the right, as one faces it, is the Sunlight bodhisattva.
Moonlight bodhisattva
On the left, as one faces it, is the Moonlight bodhisattva.
The Healing Buddha in the
center was subject to burglary.
I was going to report it to the police immediately,
but the chief priest stopped me.
He said that there may be a
chance that it would return one day.
How easygoing of him.
And,
Eight years from the event,
five days ago,
in the temple's mailbox was this.
Sannou Temple
No stamps,
and no sender.
Solve the puzzle in the picture,
and you will find the whereabouts of the Buddhist statue.
What is this picture?
Thanks, sir.
As I thought, there aren't that many witnesses,
to a crime committed in early dawn.
Thief!
Out of the way!
That hurts!
That was "Benkei's crying spot".
It hurts a lot, that spot.
Here.
It's yours, right?
Thank you.
That was very kind of you.
Well, not at all.
Yamakura Tae (52)
Mistress of a Tea House in Miyagawachou
I manage a tea house in Miyagawachou.
My name is Yamakura Tae.
Take yours out as well.
Chika Suzu (19)
Dancer
Yes.
I am Chika Suzu.
Nice to meet you.
How should we thank you?
I didn't do very much, so it's alright.
Then please come visit next time.
Take care going home.
Thank you.
What is this picture?
On the very top row, the fifth row,
a cicada, Tengu, and goldfish is drawn.
Note: Tengu is a long-nosed demon that often appears in Japanese literature.
And below that, on the fourth row,
are a chicken and a...
Loach?
The yellow loach looks disgusting.
What's this dot-like mark?
It's probably just a stain.
Between the second and third rows,
there's a violet, Tengu, and Mt. Fuji.
Beside them is an acorn.
Father,
will we be able to find it
before the two days after tomorrow?
D-Don't worry,
if it's up to me, this is not a mystery at all.
Hey hey, is that really true?
Let's leave the searching for
the Buddhist statue up to the pros,
and go sightseeing in Kyoto.
Ah, go right ahead.
If you guys are here, you'll only be disturbing me.
Actually, I contacted Kazuha,
and she's going to be guiding us around Kyoto tomorrow.
Hattori-kun has some other plans, so he won't be coming.
A guy whose girlfriend is already
decided doesn't need to be there.
Oh...
That guy isn't coming.
Conan-kun you're coming with us, right?
Uh, I'm alright.
I already promised to go fishing
in the river with the kids nearby.
Wow,
You made friends already?
Then be careful, alright?
Uh, yeah.
The one who stole the
Buddhist statue from Sannou Temple,
must be the Genjibotaru group.
However,
who sent this picture and with what intentions?
Also, what's the connection between the five murders?
Genjibotaru...
Speaking of Yoshitsune and Benkei,
that must be the place.
Gojyou Bridge
There seems to be nothing here
related to this mysterious picture.
On the Gojyou bridge of Kyoto,
the large man Benkei,
raised his long halberd.
Aiming at Ushiwakamaru, he slashed downward.
Ha-Hattori!
The gods have done some
tasteful things for me to meet you here.
Nii-chan, can you give me back my shinai?
Note: A "shinai" is a wooden practice sword used in kendo.
Oh, sorry, sorry!
Thanks.
Let's go.
Make sure you practice hard!
Don't borrow some kid's shinai.
Anyways,
What are you doing in a place like this?
Same to you, what are you doing?
As a matter of fact, the murdered
owner of the takoyaki shop in Osaka,
Note: "Takoyaki" are dumplings with octopus in the middle.
was an acquaintance of mine.
He was supposedly a member of a robbery group.
I went to his shop often while I was in middle school.
I'm indebted to him in a way.
So, I want to find the culprit and avenge his death.
That's why you came to Kyoto.
You're looking for leads to the culprit.
If that's so, then I have something good to show you.
I see.
If you solve the mystery behind the puzzle,
not only do you find the Buddhist statue,
but it might also lead to clues about the murders.
That's why you...
If the Genjibotaru group was the
one who stole the Buddhist statue,
then if we go around the locations
related to Yoshitsune and Benkei,
There might be some leads
as to how to solve the mystery.
I don't understand Kyoto at all.
Then from now on, leave it to me.
I'll guide you.
Gojyouten Shrine
Here is Gojyouten Shrine.
According to the Yoshitsune
Chronicles, it wasn't the Gojyou Bridge,
where they met, but here.
How about it...
Do you see any common features between them?
Hmm, no.
There doesn't seem to be any.
Then let's get going to the next spot.
Something doesn't please me...
Why didn't the monk from
Sannou Temple request for me?
If he were looking for a
Kansai detective, that would be me.
Note: Kansai is the southwestern half of Japan, including Osaka.
Oh, well...
Probably because they didn't want
the police knowing about the incident.
You know, your dad is a
superior in the police department.
Hmm, oh well.
Wait a second.
Now that you mention it...
Here we are. It's right here.
Benkei Stone
Benkei Stone?
It's said Benkei was always sitting on it,
or that he had thrown it from Mt. Hie.
There's various traditions handed down.
This place doesn't have any connections either.
Okay.
Onwards to the next place.
Where's the next place?
Keage Incline.
I am Inspector Ayanokouji of
the Kyoto Prefectural Police.
You seem to be doing some various
investigations on the Genjibotaru group.
This is different than Osaka.
Amateurs should not stick their
noses in other people's business.
It's a chipmunk.
Alright?
There seem to be uncommon inspectors everywhere.
Kiyomizudera Temple
I'm going to take a picture.
Let's take it in front of the Sakura blossoms.
It's so beautiful.
To be able to see such a wonderful sight...
With Makoto-san would make me so happy!
Ran!
I'm just doing what you always do to me.
Kazuha-chan,
Did you get in a fight with Hattori-kun?
Actually, Heiji,
came to Kyoto to investigate a case.
Also in Kyoto,
Is Heiji's first love!
Keage Incline "Canal Park"
Yoshitsune, Perfected Great Sun Buddha
This one's a miss, too?
Why don't we have lunch?
Sure.
Sakura...
When I see Sakura blossoms,
I always recall what happened,
Eight years ago.
I was on an expedition in Kyoto's temples,
and when I jumped on to the temple's latticed window,
the grid broke.
Then I hit my head on the floor,
and I lost consciousness.
I don't know how long I was sleeping.
But when I woke up...
It was like a dream, but it's a true story.
Maybe one day we'll be able to meet again.
Hey.
What are you laughing at?
Sorry, please continue.
When I come to Kyoto, I always take this with me.
It's a crystal ball.
I've seen this shape somewhere before.
Really!?
Does someone have the same thing?
No.
So,
Does she know about this?
She?
Oh, you mean Kazuha?
I haven't told her anything in
detail, but she seems to know about it.
To begin with, she found out about it...
In a magazine interview article?
Right.
In Kansai's really popular information magazine,
Heiji was asked about his first love.
He answered that it was a girl,
a little older than him that he met in third grade.
Moreover, he said that there's an
important artifact that concerns this girl.
They took a picture like this.
What is this?
An ordinary crystal ball.
He probably received it from that girl.
Then Kazuha-chan, about that girl...
Know her? Of course not!
Heiji seems to have only met her that one time.
Whenever he comes to Kyoto, he looks for her.
Ah, so that's why he has the crystal ball in the picture.
Maybe he thinks that girl will read this article,
and might contact him.
See, isn't that unpleasant!?
As a bonus, there's even a
picture of him taken around that time.
Note: The bold letters underneath Heiji's kid picture read "Heiji in third grade"
How cute!
Don't you agree?
Heiji was so cute back then.
Ran-chan...
That isn't the problem.
I don't think you should be concerned about it.
Even if Hattori-kun had a first love,
she's in the past.
Right now, it looks like it's going well with you.
However,
to men, their first love is special.
Sonoko!
Let's stop this boring conversation.
Anyway, why don't we eat some zenzai?
Note: Zenzai is a dessert of sweet beans, kind of like jam.
Ma'am! Three zenzai, please! And hurry!
That is the west gate of Kurama Temple.
Usually we'd go in from the Nioumon,
Note: "Nioumon" is the "second large gate"
but this way is better because it's a shortcut.
Kurama Temple —
Inner Sanctuary 588 meters
Immobile Hall of Soujyougatani
This is the Immobile Hall of Soujyougatani.
Ushiwakamaru met the Tengu
and was instructed in the art of war.
This is definitely a good place to train in swordsmanship.
Nevertheless, this tree is really big.
Hattori, this place is also not...
Get down!
Wait!
Hey, Kudo!
That guy is like Ushiwakamaru!
Damn it.
Here Kudo, we're going!
We got him!
What is he doing!?
Kurama Temple
Kurama Temple Station
Those taking the train, please hurry,
the train will be leaving short...
Well, you don't have to hurry to that extent.
Hey, these are the train tracks.
You're distracting, don't talk to me!
Violation of traffic laws.
You'll get your license suspended at this rate.
What's his plan?
Damn!
We were so close...
As I thought,
That was the culprit,
who murdered the members of the Genjibotaru group.
That's likely.
However, I don't understand why he targeted you.
Hattori-kun?
Why are you here?
Well,
By chance I ran into Kud—
No, this kid.
And I thought we should solve,
the mystery behind the picture together.
And...
Were you able to solve the mystery behind the picture?
Not yet.
It's pretty difficult.
By the way, was uncle able to solve it?
Well...
Bantochou
"Sakura" Tea House
Note: Geisha are professional hostesses who
entertain guests through various performing arts in tea houses.
Ichi Kayo
Geisha
Note: Maiko are apprentice geisha. It usually takes about
five years of training for them to "graduate" to full geisha status.
Chika Suzu (19)
Maiko
Chika Suzu-chan, you're Japan's number one!
Thank you, I hope it has pleased you.
Come now,
And serve Mouri-sensei.
Yes.
Pardon me.
Kogoro-chan may climb to the heavens!
Why don't you keep climbing!?
You guys, why are you...
The chief priest told us.
Is that so,
The chief priest...
Then how about it? Would you like to join us?
Excuse us for interrupting.
Hey,
Aren't you from Miyagawachou?
Yes.
I'm Chika Suzu.
Thank you for the help earlier.
Do you know her?
Yeah, just a little bit.
If I let you out of my sight for just one second...
Ran-san...
Please don't scold your father.
We're the ones who invited him.
That's right,
we thought we could ask the famous detective,
to reason the Genjibotaru case.
Sakura Tea House —
Mistress
Talking about the Genjibotaru,
don't all the members have a
copy of the Yoshitsune Chronicles?
I have one too.
It's a really great book.
Right, used book seller?
Yes.
But I don't like it very much.
Even if they say it's the Yoshitsune
Chronicles, it actually depicts Benkei's activities.
It is the Benkei Chronicles.
I like it.
Especially the "Ataka no Benkei",
it's the best.
Ataka? What is that?
It's one of the programs of the Noh theater.
While escaping from Yoritomo's pursuing party,
Yoshitsune and his servants,
disguise themselves as mountain priests.
They try to get through the Ataka checkpoint, but,
Yoshitsune's disguise is almost seen through.
Benkei used his Kongoubou,
Note: Kongoubou is a special staff that mountain priests carry.
to hit Yoshitsune at once.
Why?
In order to deceive the checkpoint guards.
No one would ever believe that a
servant would hit his master with a staff.
Then,
Yoshitsune and his party were able
to safely pass through the checkpoint.
Later, when Benkei apologized with tears,
Yoshitsune praised him for his quick wits.
You can understand how deep their bond was.
It's a good story.
I'm sorry, but I haven't had much sleep lately.
May I rest in one of the rooms downstairs?
If that's the case,
there are no other guests
tonight, so take the room next to...
No thank you, I can settle down better downstairs.
Do you think,
you can wake me up at nine?
Please enjoy yourselves everybody.
Wow! You can see the river!
That is the Kamogawa.
Note: "Gawa" is suffix for river.
The Sakura blossoms are beautiful.
Yes, they really are.
Ran, come and see.
It's good to see the Sakura blossoms
from the river bed of Kamogawa as a couple.
However, the view from the river
that flows beneath this building,
Misogigawa, is exceptional.
It really is beautiful.
Yeah, it's beautiful.
Your fingers are like a white fish.
I almost want to eat it!
Did you get injured?
Yes, a little bit.
Let Kogoro heal it for you.
Stop it and act properly!
Haha.
This guy will never learn.
Hey,
Look at that!
Inspector Ayanokouji!
What is he doing at a place like that?
You guys,
should see the evening cherry
blossoms from the balcony below.
Tonight the clouds will clear up,
and a good moon will come out.
Let's go.
Yes.
It sounds great.
I'm going to stay here.
Me too.
Why?
Are you anxious about that dancing girl?
Idiot...
Don't ask anything pointless.
Damn!
That guy's engine is full throttle!
He's constantly like that.
Chika Suzu-chan, revenge, revenge.
I'm going to the bathroom as well.
It's alright, I'm not drunk yet.
You stay with Mouri-sensei.
Yes.
Alright, here I go!
Oh,
The moon is coming out.
The moon.
What's wrong?
No,
It just reminded me of when I was
supposed to meet Ran somewhere.
When I remembered our arranged meeting,
it was already two hours past the set time.
That's pretty bad.
I thought that she wouldn't be waiting anymore.
But for the time being, I went to our meeting place.
Who is it?
I'm sorry Ran.
Actually I...
Completely...
I'm so glad,
I thought that something had
happened to you, and I was really worried.
It was then, huh?
When your thoughts changed
about her being just a childhood friend.
Idiot!
It's not like that.
Since a long time ago, I've been...
Even now,
she's still waiting for me.
What's the matter, Ran-chan?
Nothing.
That guy, Heiji,
he really makes me angry.
But...
Kazuha-chan, I envy you.
Eh?
Because,
you can meet him whenever you want to.
Ran-chan.
That's true.
I can't easily meet with Makoto-san either.
A maiden's worries are endless.
Here we go!
Compared to us,
those old guys are energetic.
Tiger, tiger, tiger, tiger.
Sakura-han,
it's nine.
Sakura-han?
Pardon me.
Oh?
Where did he go?
Surely not...
Sakura-han?
Oh?
What? Who screamed?
Someone!
What's the matter?
Sa-Sakura-han is...
Sa-Sakura-han...
No one can go inside.
Ran,
call the police!
Yes.
A sharp edged tool cut his carotid artery.
It's a magnificent slit.
This could have been done by the
same criminal from the series of cases.
You.
I thought I'd seen you from somewhere.
Are you the high school detective, Hattori Heiji?
That's right.
Everyone, until the police come,
can you stay in the rooms you were in?
Don't go outside for any reason.
I understand.
Sakura-san,
was looking for something in
particular in this storage room,
when he was killed.
But what on earth was it?
The button on his coat looks like it was torn off.
Yes.
It seems like it was troublesome to unfasten them,
but the wallet stuffed tightly with cash is safe.
This isn't a robbery.
Don't touch the corpse!
How many times do I have to
tell you until you understand?
That hurts!
Yes.
I am Ayanokouji of the Kyoto Prefectural Police.
Thank you very much for your efforts, please come in.
You, stay outside.
Yes.
Inspector of the Kyoto Prefectural Police.
You are remarkably fast in arriving.
Did you bring your chipmunk today?
I don't always take it with me.
What do you think?
Is it an external offender?
I wouldn't say the possibility is zero.
If the front door was opened, there would be a sound,
and the okami would have noticed it.
Moreover,
the criminal knew that Sakura-san,
would be in the storage room for whatever reason.
In other words...
Sakura-san's acquaintances,
Saijou-san, Ryuen-san,
and Mizuo-san are the suspects.
The three of them,
after Sakura-san and Ran and them left,
have each gotten up once to go to the restroom.
Furthermore,
there is a staircase that leads to the
basement on the way to the restroom.
The three could have pretended to go to the restroom,
and killed Sakura-san,
who was in the storage room.
One thing that concerns me is,
when Mizuo-san went to the restroom,
Chika Suzu-san followed him.
Yes.
All dancers do that.
However,
for Ryuen-san and Saijou-san, she didn't go.
That was because she was playing a game with uncle.
Conversely, the criminal may have aimed,
for that chance and gotten up to go to the restroom.
That means,
Ryuen-san or Saijou-san is the criminal,
and Mizuo-san is innocent.
If Chika Suzu-san is not an accomplice...
That's right.
Then let's go.
Eh?
Don't play dumb.
That's why you searched Sakura-san's coat, right?
Oh.
You mean these?
Sakura-san's shop was,
on Teramachi Avenue, if I'm not mistaken.
Note: "Teramachi" literally means "temple town"
Sakura Antique Art Shop
Yoshitsune Chronicles.
Ise no Saburou!?
Hattori!
What?
Sakura-san was Ise no Saburou!?
What is this?
T-This is...
A copy of the picture!
What is the meaning of this?
If Sakura-san had this picture...
Then he was the one who
delivered that letter to Sannou Temple.
But, for what reason?
What?
Sakura-san was Ise no Saburou?
Yes.
That person was a member of the Genjibotaru group.
Hold on,
Suruga no Jirou
Ise no Saburou
Bizen no
Heishirou
Kamei no
Rokurou
Washinoo no
Shichirou
Kataoka no
Hachirou
so now the murdered victims are...
surely not me, whose name
possess the missing number five?
Note: Mouri is referring to the numbers in the names of the Genjibotaru group.
Suruga no Jirou
Ise no Saburou
Bizen no
Heishirou
Kamei no
Rokurou
Washinoo no
Shichirou
Kataoka no
Hachirou
Mouri Kogoro
Ha?
That happened a long time ago.
Note: This is a reference to The Fourteenth Target, Detective Conan's second movie.
If the picture at Sakura-san's was just a copy,
and Sakura-san held onto the original,
then didn't the criminal take that one?
I see,
the criminal didn't think that
Sakura-san had taken a copy.
Then,
who's the real criminal?
I think that it's either Ryuen-san, Saijou-san,
Mizuo-san or Chika Suzu-san.
But none of them had a weapon.
After you guys slipped out,
we inspected their bodies.
Well, no one's stupid enough,
to keep the weapon with him after he murders someone.
He must have thrown it away or hid it somewhere.
But,
nothing was found inside of the store.
How about from the Misogigawa?
He could have thrown it away,
from the glass window in the corridor of the basement.
Don't you agree!?
I thought so, too.
Eh?
Sonoko says,
that she heard something splash into the Misogigawa.
Really?
There's no mistake.
But,
the police searched the river,
but they didn't find anything.
It's strange...
there must've been an accomplice.
The accomplice was outside and
grabbed the weapon out of the river.
I don't think that's possible.
Why do you think so, Ku—
No, I mean Conan-kun.
Tonight was a full moon, and it was bright outside.
That balcony floor had gaps to be able to see below.
Sakura Tea House
Balcony
Misogigawa
Bank
If there was an accomplice,
Ran-neechan and everybody would have noticed him.
Oh, right.
The real situation was,
that it was an outsider.
Before Ran and everybody came out to the balcony,
he sought entry through the basement's glass window,
and hid in the bathroom.
When Sakura-san came looking for
something in the storage room, he murdered him.
And while still holding the weapon,
he escaped from the glass window.
But we didn't see anything,
and there were no witnesses on the bank.
It's just a coincidence.
The murderer was lucky.
Hmm, I'm not very satisfied with that explanation.
That guy, he's the same one from Kuramayama.
Kazuha, don't let go!
What!?
You stay here, alright!?
Heiji!
Hmph.
You want to have a contest with me?
Alright.
What? There are gaps of opportunity everywhere.
He's wearing kote?
Note: "Kote" are gauntlets worn in kendo.
Are you the one who murdered Sakura-san?
If that's so, then do the same thing and slice me here!
This isn't something that you'd want.
Something's wrong with my eyes.
Detective, over here, over here.
Heiji? Are you alright?
Kazuha...
The detective?
It's a lie.
Where did you learn to do that?
You can be a terrible woman.
Heiji!
Umekouji Hospital
Heiji, are you awake?
Kazuha.
We're glad you're alright.
We were worried, Hei-chan.
Ootaki-san...
And who was that again?
I am Shiratori from police headquarters.
I heard that the murdered Sakura Shouzou,
was a member of the Genjibotaru group.
I rushed from Tokyo.
Does it hurt?
Just a little.
Stolen artifacts were found in Sakura's shop.
Are you awake?
Inspector, the short sword, did you...
We have turned it over to an expert.
Tell me as soon as the results come out.
If there's not enough evidence,
I'll offer this wound as evidence too.
Eh?
Evidence?
Evidence that the short sword
was used to murder Sakura-san.
It really would have been better if
we had something that the criminal,
had touched with his skin.
Ah, the motorcycle!
There was a motorcycle, right?
That was a stolen vehicle.
Evidence that would specify the criminal?
By the way,
do you know what this picture is?
It was held between the pages of
Sakura's Yoshitsune Chronicles.
Are you sure?
Very well.
You should learn by this
experience and be obedient next time.
With this, I must go as well.
Take care, Hei-chan.
I'm going to call my dad.
Then I will ask the doctor...
Yes.
Conan-kun is with me so—
Ran-chan, I'm going out for a while,
so look after Heiji for me.
Are you going to be alright,
not resting?
I'm alright.
Moreover, he was a really unusual guy.
It's the first time I've seen that sort of style.
Perhaps he had metal reinforcements
in his kote and was using it as a shield.
I thought I'd get a comparison
of the weapon from my wound,
so I made him get out his short
sword and wound me on purpose.
But he left that sword behind.
Why would he?
Not only that,
that guy,
While we were fighting,
tried to pick up the pouch I dropped.
There are so many things I don't understand.
You don't think that old man
might have been your first love?
Hahaha!
Right on the mark!
Of course not!
Mizuo Mansion
You were attacked afterwards?
I know it's impolite,
but I came to ask if you had an alibi.
In any case, the criminal,
had on a Noh mask.
A Noh mask?
Because of that, may I ask if Saijou-san,
and Ryuen-san have an alibi?
Us too?
This is unbearable.
Today we came thinking,
about conversing with Chika Suzu,
about who the murderer of Sakura-san is.
Right?
It's alright.
Last night I went straight
home from the tea house and slept.
However, I'm single,
and my room and my mother's room are separated,
so I can't prove that I was home the whole time.
I'm in the same situation.
I live by myself on the second floor of my shop,
on Teramachi Avenue.
I read some Buddhist
scriptures in the main temple building,
before I went to rest in my room.
I don't have any witnesses.
I see.
One more thing,
does everybody do archery?
Archery?
No.
On the autumn-leaf viewing stage,
Note: A bow made of a catalpa branch was a standard
implement used by shamanesses in Northeastern Japan.
I do hold a catalpa bow.
I've used the bow string balance,
to ward off evil spirits, only on mere form.
Then no one,
that was there at the tea house that night,
was skilled in archery?
Which reminds me, Yamakura...
That Yamakura was doing archery?
Yamakura Tae
But she wasn't there at that time.
Uh, no.
Excuse me.
Oh, you came.
Eh?
What's the matter?
Come, come.
Are you Chika Suzu-san?
Yes, that's right.
She surprised me because she looks different,
from her dancing girl appearance.
Come, please enter.
Yes,
Thank you.
Thank you for last night.
Please come again.
It is I who should thank you.
Thank you, goodbye.
Sannouji was on Rokkaku avenue.
This is Ebisu avenue, so...
Marutake Ebisu Ni Oshi Oike.
Ane-san Rokakku.
It'll be the sixth one.
What was the song you just sang called?
Well,
Note: "Temari" is a traditional Japanese handball game.
we just call it a temari song.
It's about Kyoto's roads that run East and West,
and they're sung in the order of North to South.
All the children of Kyoto learn
the names of the roads by this song.
Then does that mean you're from Kyoto as well?
Yes, that's right.
And your age?
Nineteen.
Nineteen?
This is Oike avenue.
Then I will leave from here.
Goodbye.
Do you think she is...
There's no mistake,
she's from Kyoto and she's two years older than me.
But,
all the children in Kyoto have...
Finally I was able to meet her, finally.
Yes. Hello.
Hei-chan, what are you doing?
You can't just jump out the hospital on your own.
Ah, Ootaki-san.
Kyoto Prefectural Police
Well, leaving that,
the test results are in.
It was from the hilt of the short sword.
The same blood type of Sakura-san's was detected,
and the impression on
Sakura-san's wound matched as well.
Is that true?
Hei-chan,
I'll say this just in case,
but don't be rash.
If something ever happened to you,
how will I ever explain it to your father?
Alright, I understand.
Thanks, Ootaki-han.
Now we know that the old masked man that attacked me,
is the same person that murdered Sakura-san.
Then,
the four people that were unable to dispose the weapon,
are not suspects anymore.
Conan-kun! What are you doing?
You guys! Why?
As a reward for answering Professor's quiz,
he took us along.
However, Genta-kun...
He got lost.
Ah!
Well then, use the detective badges.
We've already called him and made contact,
but...
Genta-kun can't read kanji,
so he can't tell where he is right now.
We thought you could find him
by using those glasses of yours.
Okay.
Leave it to me.
Oh!
Hey!
This is interesting. Oh! He's over there!
Jeez...
There seems to be a case over here, too.
Yeah.
I'll tell you the details later.
Hold on...
Ai-kun the drug please.
What's that?
A drug that suppresses growling stomachs.
Professor developed it for
ceremonies and special occasions.
Plus, other drugs for people who are weak with alcohol,
and some others that turn
your face red right after you take it.
Also, I developed drugs for people
who want to take a day off from work,
which gives you the same symptoms as a cold.
I got help from Ai while developing all the drugs.
None of them seem to be of any use to me.
Rokakku Building
Oh, right here, right here.
He's in this Rokakku building.
He's here?
That's good.
Mom...
Ah, there he is!
I'm saved.
We're glad you're okay, Genta-kun!
I thought we'd never meet for a lifetime.
Me too!
Nevertheless, that's pretty convenient.
A badge with a transmitter.
Yes.
The frequency waves that the badge transmits,
synchronizes with these glasses and...
Hattori!
Oh, that's how!
Wh-What!?
Kudo, you don't think...
There's no mistake.
The sound that girl heard was,
the sound of the weapon hitting the water.
Then,
the suspect is among the four people there.
No, among the three.
There's no way that my first love is the murderer, right?
Hey, hey.
There's only one thing that concerns me.
Between the song that we just
heard and the song I remember,
there's one part that's different.
My first love sang,
the part of "Ane-san Rokakku" as "Yome-san Rokakku".
Note: "Yome" means bride. "Ane" means older sister.
I wonder why...
How would I know?
I found it!
The fragment of the mask!
Hmm...
Inspector!
What's the groaning about?
This is...?
The three members who were
murdered in Tokyo wore them.
One wore the hat, another wore the
scarf, and the other wore the gloves.
The color, design and material are all the same.
Don't you think it's strange?
Yes, you're right.
Why? What's strange?
For example,
if Shiratori-kun wore all three items,
It isn't unusual. However,
if Inspector Megure had the hat,
I had the scarf,
and Takagi-kun had on the gloves,
something would be strange, right?
That's for sure.
It seems as though Shiratori-san had died,
and divided his belongings between us.
That's it!
Wh-What?
I'm hungry.
Be patient.
Chika Suzu-san's mother was a
young geisha in Miyagawachou,
and passed away due to illness when she was five.
Her mother was not married.
Chika Suzu-san was taken in and
raised by the mistress of a tea house,
Yamakura Tae.
What does unwed mother mean?
Well that is...
A woman who didn't marry but had a child.
We don't know who her father is.
However, there is an anonymous payment,
sent to the tea house every month.
But,
for some reason, three months ago,
the payment stopped.
It certainly does seem like a worrisome account.
Three months ago?
But Inspector Shiratori,
where did you get such information?
You heard it from the Royal Inspector right?
That's wrong.
Note: Gion is the entertainment district of Kyoto.
Even if it doesn't look it, I am a
known face in the Gion district.
Heh,
Is that a boast?
Generally,
even if they say he is my rival,
don't compare me with someone
who always takes his chipmunk.
A chipmunk?
Yes.
He has it in his pocket.
As one would expect, he left it
when he came to the scene of the crime.
A chipmunk...
Yes, this is Shiratori.
This is Megure.
About Yoshitsune and Benkei,
there may be one possibility...
Distribution of mementos?
If we think about it that way, the mystery can be solved.
In other words,
either Yoshitsune or Benkei has
already died. That's what we reasoned.
I get it!
Mouri-san,
you said you know who
murdered Sakura-san, is this really true?
Yes.
Well then, please allow me to tell you.
The culprit is...
Chika Suzu-san...
It's you!
That's absurd!
Your reasoning is off.
Is he alright?
Anyhow, let's hear him out until the end.
The motive is revenge for the murder of your father,
who is the leader of the robbery group, Yoshitsune.
Yoshitsune was betrayed by his
servants and murdered three months ago.
That's why the payments to the tea house stopped.
I see...
Plus, you had an accomplice.
Benkei.
Benkei?
As to Benkei, who is it?
The Royal Inspector!
It's you!
Chika Suzu-san,
when you came to the tea
house, you secretly brought something.
The short sword and the inspector's chipmunk!
How cute!
That chipmunk was the key to the trick.
Chika Suzu-san,
Note: Zashiki is a Japanese tatami room.
You gave the appearance of going to
the restroom on the way to the zashiki,
and murdered Sakura-san in the storage room.
Then you tied the short sword to the
chipmunk you had hidden in a cupboard,
and let it escape from the basement's glass window.
The chipmunk jumped into
Misogigawa and made for the bank.
That's where the Inspector was waiting to pick them up.
Later, he tried to murder Heiji with the short sword.
I get it!
So the sound I heard was the
chipmunk jumping into the water!
Besides Sakura-san's murder, you
two are involved in the other cases.
Inspector, do you do archery?
Do I look like I've done anything that complicated?
Is that really true?
However, Chika Suzu-san,
I hear that people,
who do archery have an injury
here where the arrowhead scraped.
Certainly,
I injured my "yanomakura" due to archery, but,
I just started.
There's no way I could shoot anyone.
I think so, too.
If you injure that spot, it's proof that you're a beginner.
That's what I heard my
acquaintances from the archery club say.
And if there was murder, the
distribution of the mementos...
Mouri-han!
Do you really think this girl is the culprit!?
Therefore, I...
Enough joking around!
Dancers are busy performing and entertaining guests,
there is no time for them to be murdering people!
Hey, hey.
What is it?
About the chipmunk...
With a small body like that, I don't
think it could carry a short sword.
Shut up!
Then I'll show you the proof!
C'mon, move chipmunk!
I am too shocked to be able to speak.
You're purposefully ignoring me
in order to be free from guilt, huh?
Stop it!
Don't you feel sorry for it!?
It's animal cruelty!
You kids shut up!
Genta-kun, save the chipmunk!
Oh.
Kudo.
Yeah.
Thanks to uncle, I know who the culprit is.
Same here.
Only those who do archery would say that.
What's left is the evidence...
And the location of the Buddhist statue.
Poor chipmunk.
Let's give it something to eat!
I have some acorns...
Note: A Japanese children song about an acorn that falls into a puddle.
It's almost like the song, "Donguri Koro Koro"
Donguri Koro Koro?
Perhaps...
Hey! What's the matter, Kudo?
Perhaps the copied picture concerned the roads of Kyoto.
What?
First are the roads that run East to West.
The fifth row stands for,
Gojyou Avenue
Note: "Gojyou" means fifth.
"Gojyou Avenue".
The fourth row,
Shijyou Avenue
Note: "Shijyou" means fourth.
is "Shijyou Avenue".
And in between the third and second row,
which means between 2nd and 3rd Avenue,
Oike Avenue
Note: "Oike" is literally the "honourable lake."
is "Oike Avenue".
And to prove it,
Donguri Koro Koro?
Next are the roads that run North to South.
Note: Literally "The Spring River". It is also a traditional Japanese
childrens song which tells about a river in the spring that blooms with violets.
The violet, which is present in the song "Haru no Ogawa",
Ogawa Avenue
is part of "Ogawa Avenue".
Note: "Karasuma" is literally "crow circle".
The Tengu or "Crow billed Tengu" is
represented in "Karasuma Avenue".
Karasuma Avenue
Fuji-san → Tomi
And for Mt. Fuji,
Note: "Tominokouji" literally means "wealthy, small road"
the character "fu" is "tomi".
So it is "Tominokouji Avenue".
Tominokouji Avenue
What is the chicken for?
Note: "Yana gawa nabe" is a sort of soup prepared with loach.
The loach has something to do with "Yana gawa nabe",
Yanaginobanba Avenue
Note: Yanaginobanba literally means "Horse willow place".
so it must represent "Yanaginobanba Avenue".
The chicken is...
Nishinotouin Avenue!
Chicken → West
Nishinotouin Avenue
The character for chicken is
similar to the character for west.
Well that's pretty hard.
Then what does this one mean?
For the cicada, there's an "abura semi",
which relates to "Aburanokouji Avenue".
Aburanokouji Avenue
The Tengu represents "Karasuma Avenue".
Karasuma Avenue
And if the goldfish,
Note: "Fu" is literally wheat bran.
has something to do with goldfish food "fu",
Fuyachou Avenue
it represents "Fuyachou Avenue".
Then if you connect the
similarly colored violet and Mt. Fuji,
the chicken and loach, the cicada and goldfish,
and both tengu's together in a line...
"King".
Why is it a king?
It's a dot!
Isn't it like this?
Tama → Gyoku
Tama can also be read as gyoku,
or jewels.
Bukkou Temple
This place is...
Bukkou Temple!
It's the same as if we found the treasure!
What's wrong?
Nothing.
I just feel a little dizzy.
Rokakku Building
Sorry, thanks.
How do you feel now?
Yes.
I feel better.
Hattori.
Eight years ago,
the temple you snuck into was Sannou Temple.
How did you know that!?
Idiot.
While you were admiring the
Sakura blossoms, it came to me.
Also, there was the latticed window you talked about.
That's right.
I picked up this crystal ball under the Sakura tree.
I'm sorry to throw water onto things,
but that crystal ball,
wasn't dropped by your first love.
What?
Actually...
It's from the stolen Buddhist statue.
Note: Byakugou is the crystal ball just between the eyes.
It's Sannou Temple's "crystal ball",
which was inserted in its forehead.
Byakugou
Crystal ball?
Is that the thing that's in the
Buddha's brow which releases light?
Yes.
In Buddhist statues it's
frequently represented as a crystal ball.
It's the same in Noh masks.
My reasoning is this.
Eight years ago, the robbery group Genjibotaru,
snuck into the main hall of Sannou Temple,
and stole the treasured Buddhist statue.
However, while taking it away, the byakugou fell out.
When the leader, Yoshitsune, noticed it later,
he sent one of his servants to Sannou Temple to find it.
It was then that...
I want to eat some zenzai!
Note: Anmitsu is syrup covered bean jam.
I want anmitsu!
Reluctantly, the leader stored the Buddhist statue,
in the storage room of Sakura-san's shop.
And eight years later,
the culprit found out that the
boy from eight years ago was you.
It was that magazine!
Around the same time, there was an
event that occurred in the robbery group.
Perhaps the leader became seriously ill or something.
The leader, who felt his time was near,
hid the stolen Buddhist statue in another location.
He gave each of his servants a
picture that held the location of it,
and left a will saying whoever
was to find the Buddhist statue,
would become the new leader.
Then he died.
The remaining servants,
tried earnestly to solve the mystery, but were unable to.
Around that time...
As Sakura-san was one of the members,
he came to the culprit to join arms.
Sakura-san knew his skill as a swordsman,
and tried to goad him into killing the other members.
Then,
they'd find the location of the
Buddhist statue and its Byakugou,
and split the money made from selling the statue.
Perhaps,
within the robbery group,
Sakura-san, the owner of an antique art shop,
was the only one who had seized the sale
and distribution routes of the black market.
He probably felt he was the only one who was safe.
The culprit acted as if he agreed to Sakura-san's plan,
when his true feelings were to
murder all the members of the group,
and monopolize the treasure.
But in order to do that, he had to
solve the mystery left by the leader.
Bukkou Temple
So the culprit thought...
to ask the famous detective, Mouri
Kogoro to solve the mystery for him.
Bukkou Temple...
It's right here.
But is the Buddhist statue really hidden here?
Yeah, something doesn't seem right.
H-hey!
Hey, what's the matter?
Hey Kudo!
What have you found?
This is...
Stone: "Jewel Dragon Temple Remains"
Jewel Dragon Temple?
The dot on the picture pointed to this?
Yes.
It's Kazuha.
It's me.
I have the girl in my custody.
In an hour,
come alone to the Jewel Dragon Temple in Kuramayama.
If you contact the police,
the girl will die.
Heiji, don't come!
You'll be killed!
Kazuha!
Hattori?
Kazuha was...
Kazuha was kidnapped.
What!?
In an hour I was told to go alone
to Gyokuryu Temple in Kuramayama.
Gyokuryu Temple!
Well, isn't that good?
We can break in there together and...
Hattori!
Return Bridge
"When the child that heard of his father's death from afar, rushed to Kyoto."
"The funeral procession was just going over this bridge."
"In that moment, the father temporarily revived,"
"and the father and child exchanged words."
Hello.
Kuramayama
Gyokuryu Temple
It's the teacher's will.
Put the "Underworld Katana" in Benkei's drawer,
and put the bow in Rokakku's drawer.
Um, Benkei's drawer is...
From the top, one, two, three...
I wonder what those are, the
Benkei and Rokakku drawers...
Bukkou Temple?
I heard them talking about it, but...
Really, where have those two gone?
Even if I call Kazuha's cell phone, she isn't answering.
Gyokuryu Temple?
I'm hungry!
Is that so? Then once we get back...
Excuse me.
This Gyokuryu Temple,
where is it now?
It's back deep in Kuramayama.
But I heard that it was evacuated a long time ago.
Thank you.
Kuramayama?
He's late.
Knowing that it's a trap, no one will come that easily.
Do you really think so?
Maybe the wind of cowardice blew in his direction.
Heiji!
You!
You didn't hurt Kazuha, did you?
I'm alright, Heiji.
What you really wanted,
was this.
In order to get back this crystal ball,
you attacked me yesterday on this mountain.
Looks like you failed, though.
Next, you thought you'd monopolize the treasure,
so you attacked Sakura-san
at the tea house in Hontochou.
It wasn't Giyon or Miyagawachou because,
the tea house in Hontochou has a river flowing behind it.
River?
After you murdered Sakura-san
who was searching the storage room,
you put a terminal that security
companies use for thefts and lost individuals,
along with the weapon in a
plastic bottle and threw it out.
Then later, with a cell phone,
you accessed the security company's website,
to find the location of the
terminal, which you then recovered.
After that,
you waited in ambush with your
motorcycle for me, who was returning to Osaka,
And tried to kill me with the same short sword.
This attempt was thwarted
because of Kazuha's intervention.
But you purposefully dropped the short sword,
in order to be removed from being a suspect.
The culprit wanted to make us believe,
That it was someone who had
escaped with the weapon from the tea house.
Isn't that right?
Saijou Taiga-san.
Or should I say Musashibou Benkei.
As one would expect from the
high school detective from Osaka,
Hattori Heiji.
How did you know it was me?
You tried to hide that you did archery.
When you sat down,
you drew back your right foot halfway before sitting.
Note: "Hansoku wo Hiku" means To pull foot halfway.
That's called "hansoku wo hiku".
People who do archery sometimes do it out of habit.
Also,
when asked if you did any
archery, you thoughtlessly started to say,
"Yamakura".
Which reminds me, Yamakura...
You weren't talking about
Yamakura-san of the tea house,
but of "Ya no makura"
When you draw an arrow, you place the arrow,
on the second joint of the thumb on the left hand.
Perhaps you tried to say it like this.
Which reminds me, Chika
Suzu-san had an injury on her "yamakura".
Only people who do archery would know a term like that.
By the way, Ryuen-san is an amateur in archery.
Note: The character for bow string is "gen" or "tsuru"
Gen = Tsuru
He called the bow string, "gen" instead of "tsuru."
I attended the town's kendo
gym with Ryuen and everybody.
But one day,
I learned that there was an old
technique in Kyoto, a "Yoshitsune style".
I studied the "Yoshitsune-style" by myself,
And two years ago, I stopped attending the kendo gym.
Then personally called myself the
successor of the Yoshitsune style.
Benkei, the successor of the Yoshitsune style.
I... I liked Yoshitsune more
than Benkei from the beginning.
I wanted to become Yoshitsune!
However,
the leader took the title of Yoshitsune,
and I, who stood at the top of the robbery group,
was given the name of Benkei.
The reason you tried to monopolize the Buddhist statue,
was it for money?
That's right, but it wasn't for personal desire.
It was to make a dojo here.
This temple was where the leader was the chief priest.
Even after it was evacuated,
it was supervised by the leader,
and I used it as a place to practice the Yoshitsune style.
But the leader died three months ago,
and the temple was going to be taken down.
I wasn't going to be able to use it as a dojo!
There's one thing I wanted to ask.
You just took advantage of Ryuen-san.
That's right.
I heard him talking about the statue some time ago,
and when I sent that letter to Sannou Temple.
Sure enough, he came to discuss it with me.
So,
I set him up to send a request to Mouri Kogoro.
I killed Sakura-san,
because I could find someone
to purchase the Buddhist statue.
Now there's something convenient called the Internet.
Come.
Chatting time is over.
Hand over the crystal ball!
In exchange for it, let Kazuha go!
That's fine...
If you tell me where the statue's hidden.
What?
Well...
Where is the statue?
It's in this temple.
What are you saying?
Note: This is a Japanese idiom, and it's like... Is it
that you can't see what you already have in front of you?
Is it that you can't see the forest because of the trees?
You're lying!
I've already searched this temple!
There's no...
It's not a lie!
Kazuha! Run!
Heiji!
They're my disciples.
You guys stay out of it!
Heiji!
Stop it!
This person isn't Heiji!
Wh-Who?
Who are you!?
Kudo Shin'ichi.
A detective.
What?
You let him take the medicine?
Kudo-kun called.
He asked if there was a way to
return to Kudo Shin'ichi once more,
Even temporarily.
But,
there isn't any more of the trial antidote to APTX 4869.
And before, even the Paical,
which he drank as a cold
medicine and returned to his original body,
is ineffective as he has created an antibody to it.
Then it occurred to me...
If he took the medicine that
gave you symptoms of a severe cold,
and drank the Paical one more time,
he might be able to return to his original body.
So then...
As I thought, the experiment was a huge success.
Kudo-kun returned to his original body.
However, it's the same as having a severe cold.
His body is shaky.
I can't guarantee his life.
And how is Heiji-kun feeling?
Who knows?
Until he undergoes examination tomorrow, he must rest.
For the time being, I've been
assigned the role to keep guard.
Kudo-kun?
Damn.
You've deceived me.
I thought that somehow I'd be
able to at least let her escape,
But my body won't move the way I want.
This is dangerous, the effect of the Paical is wearing off.
I'm done for!
For a detective, you'd be the best in the world.
But as a samurai,
You're not very good.
Hattori!
Heiji!
I made you wait, Kazuha.
What do you mean, making me wait? You idiot!
What were you doing until now?
Hey Kudo!
You seem to have snatched my clothes.
Also,
I don't know what you painted on your face,
But I'm not this dark-colored.
Really?
That's alright.
I'll take it from here.
You hurry and go!
Hide before you become small.
And when you return to normal, come back.
Wait there!
Your opponent is me!
Kazuha,
Don't tell anyone you met Kudo here,
even to that girl.
Eh? Even to Ran-chan?
Why?
Just because.
They probably won't meet anyways.
It's better she doesn't know.
I won't allow you two to return alive.
This sword is too weak.
After them!
Hey, did you find him?
No, not yet.
Search harder!
What?
Shh, be quiet.
Don't move.
Shin'ichi!
You have the same expression.
Like that time.
What happened?
You're covered in sweat.
And those people...
Who are they?
Where did he go?
It can't be helped, let's go back.
I'm sorry Ran.
Right now, to meet with you, I...
It's been locked, the door won't open.
Do something!
Note: Tatami are Japanese floor coverings, woven out of straw.
The smell of this tatami...
It's the room that I was pushed into.
Bring me the axe, hurry!
Damn!
It's only a matter of time until they break in.
Is there anything that can be used as a weapon...
What is this?
This chest has a large amount of drawers.
Ah!
Put the "Underworld Katana" in Benkei's drawer,
And the bow and arrows in Rokakku's drawer.
Heiji!
The sword is in Benkei's drawer.
What?
In this chest?
But there are so many. How
am I to know which one is his?
I feel like I've seen this before.
The beams of these drawers,
aren't they like the roads of Kyoto?
I get it.
This beam is Karasuma Avenue
and this one Takoyakushi Avenue.
Hold on...
Could it be the names of drawers
are taken from the names of places?
The names of places?
That's it!
Rokakku means Rokakku Hall.
Benkei's drawer means...
Benkei's Stone!
Sanjou Avenue
Going East from Sanjou to Fuyachou.
Fuyachou Avenue
It's the temari song!
Hmm... Marutake Ebisu Ni...
Marutake Ebisu Ni...
What was after that?
Ah, damn!
I can't remember!
Heiji! Sanjyou is two before Tako.
Two above Tako, and the road that runs West to East is...
Temple then... Fuya...
Fuyachou is the third one!
It's right here!
Be prepared!
The equal sides of this unique blade...
It's the demon sword "Muramasa"!
It's just right for cutting monsters,
That have possessed Yoshitsune.
What did you say!?
Get out of the way!
What are you doing!?
Hurry and go after them!
Yes.
Alright, I'm going to delay them.
Meanwhile, you escape.
No!
I want to be with...
Listen to me!
Heiji.
He's here!
Hurry, go!
You guys,
After the girl!
Conan-kun!
Kazuha-neechan,
What about Heiji-niisan?
Over there!
Hattori!
Damn!
I want to inform the police, but my
cell phone doesn't have any reception.
That's it!
Hey, put it out immediately.
Yes.
Alright, now if someone notices this fire...
Hey.
Hey Ran.
Are you awake?
Dad!
Where's Shin'ichi?
What? Are you still half asleep?
Why would he be here?
More importantly, why are you sleeping here?
And you Dad, what are you doing here?
I notified him,
About Kazuha being kidnapped by the Genjibotaru group.
Mouri-san!
It's about time to come to a conclusion.
As you wish!
You aren't going to trick me again.
Then,
How about this?
A short sword!
It's not an ordinary short sword.
There's a deadly poison with
immediate results painted on it.
What did you say?
Just a little scratch and you're dead.
What a coward!
Oh no! Heiji's in danger!
You can't run away anymore.
From below, the arrows are aimed at you.
Something has to be done.
Conan-kun!?
Wait there!
Hey! Over here!
Take this!
Go Hattori!
Heiji!
The Benkei who wanted to become Yoshitsune.
If you were Benkei,
Yoshitsune would have been
killed at the Ataka checkpoint.
The leader's been defeated!
Arrest them all!
Yes.
It turned out good, Conan-kun!
Yes!
Japanese culture: You usually affix -san after
the last name. It's like the "Mr." in Mr. Smith.
But back there, you addressed Heiji as Hattori.
Sorry, I just got caught up in the excitement.
It's Heiji!
Heiji!
This temple...
Now all the mysteries are solved.
It seems like the effect of the drug was only temporary.
Well,
Thanks to you, I was able to collect some valuable data.
Are you alright, Heiji?
Yes, one way or another.
But where is the Buddhist statue?
Ahem.
Hattori-kun, Shin...
Hmm? What?
No, nothing.
Of course, that was only a dream.
Sannou Temple —
Early Morning
I am truly ashamed that I was not able,
to ascertain the location of the Buddhist statue.
No,
this is what Buddha has chosen.
Do not worry about it.
Everyone, please be careful.
Goodbye.
But this is worrisome,
there is only one hour left until the
unveiling of the Buddhist statue.
It's alright,
we'll just proceed as usual.
The... The Healing Buddha!
He has returned!
Gyokuryu Temple —
Early Dawn
It's here, Kudo.
See, it's just as I said.
Well, I never thought that the
shape of the temple would be "tama",
and the position of the dot indicated the bell tower.
Even I didn't notice that...
Note: "tama" means ball and "takara" means treasure.
Note: A "ukanmuri" is the sort of roof style thing that you see in the explanation.
Tama
If you put an "ukanmuri" on the top of "tama",
Takara
it becomes "treasure".
The ukanmuri represented a roof.
I see...
Now it's back to normal.
Yes.
Those two are a good combination.
Almost like Yoshitsune and Benkei.
Do you mean that boy Hattori
and the famous detective Mouri?
You still have some way to go in your training...
Ha ha ha.
Well now...
Alright,
Ayumi-chan you're next.
It's so cute!
Maybe I should take it home!
That's too bad.
It's my number one friend.
Inspector, could it be that you
don't have many human friends?
I'm sorry I called both of you the culprits.
That's alright.
To tell the truth, I knew who my father was.
I told him myself that it was
alright not to send me any more money.
Y-Your father!?
Who is he?
It's a secret.
That dirty priest!
It's not "yome-san", it's "ane-san", idiot.
Where did you learn that song?
From my relatives in Kyoto.
Was it sometime while I was in third grade?
When I went to visit with you, I was taught it.
With me?
What? You don't remember?
Oh yes,
I remember you couldn't wait for my preparations,
so you said you'd be going to Sannou Temple and left.
That time,
I was helped into wearing a kimono.
I also did my hair,
and wore a little bit of makeup.
Then I went to go find you at Sannou Temple but,
you weren't to be found anywhere, so I played with a ball.
Really,
I wish you could have seen it.
The Sakura blossoms fluttered about, it was so beautiful!
So I was finally able to meet her.
Meet her?
You met your first love, Heiji?
Who is it? Is it the dancing girl?
Even if it takes a lifetime, I won't tell you, idiot.
C'mon stingy, you can tell me.
Alright, I'll tell you in another 1500 years.
What does that mean!?
Conan-kun!
What are you doing?
You're covered in sweat!
Shi-Shin'ichi...
By the way, I gave Shin'ichi-niichan a call.
I wanted him to appear as
Heiji-niichan and save Kazuha-neechan, right?
Yes.
But that guy was really weak.
He escaped halfway.
Even after you told me not to tell anyone else...
That's right...
So that really... That really was Shin'ichi.
I was finally able to meet you.
I'd like some ice cream.
Note: 100 yen is roughly 1.00 USD
Alright, it'll be 300 yen.
In the end, I'm the only one who
couldn't meet the person I wanted to.
Sonoko, you'll eventually be
able to meet Kyougoku-san for sure.
But you know,
I'm not that good at waiting for people.
Isn't that true for you as well, Ran?
Really?
I don't mind waiting for people.
Because the longer you wait,
when you do meet...
You have the same expression as that time.
you'll be more happy.
Ah damn.
If only Kudo-kun could have heard those words...