My name's Shin'ichi Kudo.
I'm a famous high school detective
who's solved countless cases!
I solved a roller coaster murder case
with no difficulty at all,
but then a mysterious organization
forced me to take a strange poison.
Things looked really bad!
Ran! What's going to happen to me?!
pany Pre
of the Company Preside
pping of the Company President's D
The Kidnapping of the Company President's Daughter
Are you alright, little boy?!
Little boy?
What're these guys talking about?
I'm a 2nd year high school student!
How did you get that cut on your head?!
Cut?
Oh yeah!
A man dressed in black hit me and—
What the...
We've found an injured boy.
Yes, he's a grade school student.
Who's a grade school student?!
What're they talking about?!
These officers are acting strange!
There may have been an incident;
he's received injuries to his head.
Where did he go?!
Huh?!
We may have a crime on our hands! Try to find him!
Right!
"Mouri Detective Agency"
I'm home!
Oh, you're back, Ran!
Come on, Dad, can't you stop throwing trash all over?
This is why you don't get any jobs!
And why Mom ran out on you!
I choose what jobs I take.
Anyway, where's that so-called detective of yours?
Wasn't he with you?
He was before we left the amusement park.
But then...
Sorry, Ran! You go on ahead!
What could Shin'ichi be doing?
I haven't run that far, so why am I so out of breath?!
I-I've shrunk!
How?!
Wait, it couldn't be—
We'll use this. Our organization's latest poison.
Could it be because I swallowed that pill?!
Hello, this is Shin'ichi Kudo.
I'm away at the moment.
If you're interested in hiring me, please leave your name and number...
That's strange. He's still not home.
He's probably out havin' dinner with his novelist dad or somethin'...
Shin'ichi's parents moved to America three years ago,
so he's living all by himself now!
Oh yeah?
Something must've happened to him afterward!
I'm going to stop by his house!
W-What about my dinner?!
Darn it! Can't I even get into my own house?!
Dr. Agasa!
Who are you?
It's me! Shin'ichi!
A relative of Shin'ichi, are you?
His house is the next one over.
I'm Shin'ichi!
Here, I'll prove it!
Your name is Hiroshi Agasa and you're 52!
You're an eccentric inventor
and claim that you're a genius,
but everything you make is junk!
You also have a mole on your butt
that has a hair sticking out of it!
Only Shin'ichi knows about that!
He's been spreading my secrets around, has he?
No! It's because I'm Shin'ichi!
I was forced to take some weird pill
which made my body shrink!
A pill that shrunk you?
Yeah!
If such a pill exists, I want to see it for myself!
You suspicious little punk!
I'm taking you to the police!
Doc!
You tripped while hurrying on your way back
from the Colombo restaurant, didn't you?!
How do you know that?!
Your clothes, Doc.
The front of your clothes is still wet,
yet the back is completely dry!
That's evidence that you were running in the rain.
What's more, you also have mud on your pants.
The only street in this area where you could get mud on you
is in front of Colombo,
which is under construction!
Plus some of Colombo's special meat sauce is still in your mustache.
W-Who are you?
Elementary, my dear Agasa!
S-Shin'ichi?
I see.
So the uncompleted poison mysteriously caused your body to shrink.
That's the gist of it.
Talk about lame. My clothes from when I was a kid fit perfectly.
I'm begging you, Doc! You are a genius, after all!
Make me some medicine that'll change me back to normal!
Hold on there! I don't even know the ingredients of the pill you took...
Then all we need to do is figure out where those guys are
and get some of those pills!
Well, that would certainly help...
Listen, Shin'ichi!
If they find out you're still alive,
they'll come back to put an end to you for good!
So this must stay a secret
between just the two of us!
You mustn't tell anyone at all!
That means not even Ran-kun!
Shin'ichi! Are you there?!
It's Ran!
Oh no! Hide quickly!
If you're home, then you can at least answer the phone!
Huh? Dr. Agasa? Where's Shin'ichi?
Uh, well, he's...
Dad's glasses...
Disguise time!
He isn't here?
Whoa, these are strong!
Huh? Is there someone there?
You must be really shy!
Come on now, face this way!
He's...
...so cute!
Her chest!
Who is this boy?
He belongs to a distant relative of mine!
What's your name?
M-My name's Shin—
Err...
Conan!
My name's Conan Edogawa!
Conan? That's an odd name.
My dad was a big fan of Conan Doyle, so...
Reminds me of Shin'ichi somehow...
Oh, Ran-kun, I almost forgot!
Do you think you could let him stay
at your house for a little while?
What the heck are you—
His parents are in the hospital
after getting into an accident...
They asked me to look after him,
but I live a bachelor's life, so...
Sure, but I'll have to ask my dad first.
Right! So you're willing to take him in?
Isn't that great news, Conan?
What happens if Ran finds out
who I really am while I'm there?!
The first step to turning you back to normal
is finding the men in black
who used that drug on you!
And Ran-kun's house is a detective agency!
Her dad might run across
information about them!
Exactly!
Say, Conan-kun.
Yeah?
I'll never get used to this name!
Is there anyone you like?
Like a girl at school or someone?
No, none at all.
There's someone I really like, though!
Don't tell me it's that Shin'ichi boy
you were looking for earlier?
That's right!
He's always been kind of a tease since he was a kid,
and he's always been so full of himself
and a big mystery geek,
but he's also courageous, cool, and dependable!
I really like Shin'ichi a lot!
But keep this a secret from him!
Here we are! This is my house!
It's almost like I've gained a cute little brother!
It's like I can talk to you
about anything, Conan-kun!
Ran...
Let me introduce you to my dad! Follow me!
Um, Ran...
I-I'm actually...
I'm really...
I got one! I got one!
Dad!
My first job in 6 months!
Someone kidnapped a rich guy's daughter!
Some guy dressed in black!
A man dressed in black?!
Taxi!
Conan-kun!
This case is calling my name!
Calling for the famous detective known as Kogoro Mouri!
Why are you here?!
Because he got in before I could stop him!
I'm riding in a car! Yay!
So who is he?!
He belongs to a relative of Dr. Agasa!
I don't need you bothering me while I work! Get out!
We can't get out! We're on a freeway!
The person kidnapped was my only daughter.
Akiko Tani. 10 years old.
My butler Asao saw the perpetrator with his own eyes.
Darn, I can't see the picture.
Being so small is such a pain!
What was the surrounding situation like when she was kidnapped?
Who is this boy?
Just an acquaintance...
Ran! Watch him!
Well then, Asao-san, please explain in detail what happened.
It occurred when she went to play outside after returning from school.
A man dressed in black suddenly appeared from a corner of the garden!
Give this message to her father.
If he wants his daughter back, he'll shut down his company for 1 month.
Get the police involved and she's as good as dead!
Upon leaving those words,
the kidnapper scaled a pine tree and escaped outside!
Did this man have any special characteristics?
My eyes aren't what they used to be, so...
That's too bad...
You shouldn't get in the way of my dad's work, Conan-kun...
Did anyone else hear the kidnapper's voice or any sounds out of the ordinary?
No. Other than Asao-san's shouts for help, it was completely quiet.
Which means Asao-san was the only one who saw the perpetrator.
Judging from the demands, the kidnapper is likely someone from a rival company.
Damn it! To think they would want money on top of that demand!
Money?!
There was a phone call just now!
They demanded that I prepare 300 million, all in used bills!
There must be some sort of mistake, sir!
Silence! You will remain quiet!
Which companies stand to gain something if your company shuts down?
There's something not right about this incident.
Why did the perpetrator kidnap her inside her home?
It would've been easier on her way home from school.
And being clearly seen is too careless.
But demanding used bills is oddly cautious...
Oh, you're really good at soccer, Conan-kun!
I guess so.
Shin'ichi would do that whenever he was thinking about something.
He said it would get his mind working.
That Shin'ichi is me!
Conan-kun!
How rare it is for Jumbo to be friendly with a stranger.
The kidnapper climbed this pine tree to break in and to get out.
Which means this dog must have barked at him!
That's it! I've figured this case out!
It sounds like this dog barks at all strangers, doesn't it?
Yes. Jumbo is one of the best guard dogs around, after all.
Wait, the servants said that it was completely quiet
except for when the butler was yelling!
And where are you going, Asao-san?
He realized it!
There's something strange about your story!
The kidnapper snuck in, took the girl,
and escaped using that tree!
Yet the guard dog didn't bark!
T-That's because...
Plus your testimony is too full of ambiguity!
Was there really a man dressed in black, Asao-san?
Or shall I say, Kidnapper!
Asao! How dare you!
My deepest apologies, sir!
What did you do this for?!
Did someone put you up to it?!
No, I did this entirely of my own accord!
So where is the girl now?
A nearby hotel...
Case closed!
With Detective Kogoro Mouri on the job, no case goes unsolved!
No! It's not over yet!
There's still another side to this case!
Sir! There's a phone call!
I'm busy. Tell them to call back later!
B-But...
This is Tani.
Is the 300 million ready?
Who is this?!
I called earlier.
I'm the guy who kidnapped your daughter.
That's impossible! The kidnapper has already—
So you did have help!
No, I did it alone! Please believe me!
This man is telling the truth.
After being kidnapped for the first time,
she was most likely kidnapped again by someone else.
By someone much worse!
Daddy! Help!
Akiko!
I'm an impatient man.
Hurry and get the 300 million ready
or there's no telling what'll happen to your daughter.
Please! I'll get the money somehow!
Just give Akiko back unharmed!
Keep him talking and try to find out his location!
His location?
Who's that?!
Don't tell me it's the police.
No! It isn't...
Daddy! I'm in a storeroom of a school!
I can see a big chimney from the window—
Akiko!
I'll call again in one hour.
Get the money ready by then!
Big-mouthed brat.
A big chimney visible from a school storeroom
isn't enough information to pinpoint which school it is...
At any rate, please buy us some time by preparing the money.
R-Right!
The kidnapper's nervous now that we know his location!
If we don't rescue the little girl soon...
What're you doing, Conan-kun?
It hasn't been very long since she was kidnapped,
so I figured they might be somewhere nearby...
That's right!
There's no way he could have gotten far with a little girl with him!
If we limit it to the nearby area, that leaves only so many schools to check!
Conan-kun, where are you going?!
Ran! After that dog!
Right!
The chimney she sees is probably either a factory or a bathhouse!
There are only 5 schools in the area where you can see chimneys!
No!
Not here either!
Darn it! It wasn't any of them!
There aren't any other schools that have views of chimneys!
They must not be in this area after all!
Wait a second! Just maybe...
This is it!
She saw this building from the side
and mistook it for a chimney!
Schools in this vicinity that have a side view of this building...
Futatsubashi Middle School!
Place the money on the bench in Hyakujii Park.
Once I have it in my hands, I'll return the girl.
Let me hear Akiko's voice one more time!
You'll have plenty of time later to hear it.
We've come to an agreement.
Which means your role is just about over with.
Not so fast!
Who's there?! Where are you?!
Right here!
It's alright now.
Who are you?
Shin'ichi Kudo—
I mean, Conan Edogawa. A detective!
A detective?
Don't be mockin' me, you little brat!
Darn it! I can't put any power into it with my body so small!
How about this?!
No good! My soccer kicks have weakened too!
Even if I do find the criminals,
in my smaller body I can't even capture them or beat them up!
Playtime's over! Say your prayers!
Stop!
It's all over!
Ran!
Talk about strong!
Everything's okay now!
How did you know to come here?
I followed you and then I saw Jumbo jump out from here!
Jumbo!
So you're the one behind this!
Kidnapping case?
Detective Kogoro Mouri is your man!
Gimme a break.
I was the one who came up with the idea to kidnap me!
What?!
Daddy's always too busy with work to care about me...
So I had Asao-san "kidnap" me.
I thought I could get Daddy
to spend time with me
if his company had to take a break!
I see. So the first kidnapping was a fake.
Even if my daughter did ask for your help,
I find it difficult to forgive what you've done!
I assume you realize this, Asao?!
Yes.
As punishment,
you will make arrangements for a
one-week trip that starts tomorrow!
A trip to Australia, where Akiko has always wanted to go!
S-Sir!
She and I will be going there together, of course!
Daddy!
Letting the dog go so he could find my daughter was a stroke of genius.
You truly are a great detective!
No, it's because of all the experience I've had!
Who are you to talk?
I was the one who found him...
I will express my gratitude to you another day.
Right! I'm looking forward to it!
Thanks, Mr. Detective!
Mr. Detective?
No, she means him, not me!
Say, Dad, about this boy...
Dr. Agasa asked if we would take care of him...
You're against it?
Sure thing!
I got a job the instant he showed up,
and then I solved it like an ace!
He just might be a god of good fortune!
Stay with us and become my son!
I just transferred here!
My name's Conan Edogawa!
Nice to meet you!
I have to go back to grade school again?
The one responsible...
...is you!
If Shin'ichi were here, he'd easily solve this case.
Where could that mystery nerd have gone?
Hot!
Mouri-kun! You were right!
I've changed my mind about you,
"Great Detective"!
I could never do that. I could never
be as strong as Yoko-san...
Next Conan:
The Celebrity Locked Room Murder Case
Ice
Next Conan's Hint: Ice
Look forward to the next episode
Will you win against me next time?