My name's Shin'ichi Kudo.
I'm a famous high school detective known throughout the country!
But I was forced to take a pill by some organization...
...and became Conan Edogawa!
Doesn't matter if I'm small!
My mind's that of a brilliant 17-year old detective!
I can solve cases that not even adults can handle!
Created by
Gosho Aoyama
"Detective Conan"
Serialized in Shogakukan's
"Weekly Shonen Sunday"
Planning
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Character Design
Masatomo Sudo
Art Director
Yukihiro Shibutani
Art Design
Hiroyuki Mitsumoto
Directors of Photography
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takashi Nomura
Sound Director
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
Music Producer
Hiroki Horio
(PolyGram)
Music
Katsuo Ono
Opening Theme
"Mune ga doki-doki"
(Kitty Enterprises)
Performed by
Lyrics
Music
Arrangement
THE HIGH-LOWS
Hiroto Komoto/Masatoshi Mashima
Ending Theme
"Step by Step"
(Mercury Music Entertainment)
Performed by
Lyrics
Music
Arrangement
ZIGGY
Juichi Morishige
Editor
Teramitsu Okada
(JAY FILM)
Story Editor
Jun'ichi Iioka
Color Key
Reiko Hirayama
Associate Producer
Satoshi Kojima
Director
Kenji Kodama
Producers
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Kazuhiko Yagiuchi
(Tokyo Movie)
Masahito Yoshioka
"Mouri Detective Agency"
It's been 3 days since I shrunk.
There still hasn't been any information about the men in black.
But nobody would ask a detective like him for help,
much less give him information about those men.
Yoko-chan, you're so cute!
Go, go, let's go!
Let's go! Yoko!
Come on now, you're too old to be acting like that.
Yoko! Yoko! Yay!
You set the example for hopeless men.
"Teitan Elementary School"
2 times 2 is 4.
2 times 3 is 6.
2 times 4 is 8.
I can't take this anymore...
Let's walk home together, Conan-kun!
You must feel kind of lonely since you just transferred here, right?
So we'll be your friends!
No, um, I don't really...
Hey, you!
Are you saying no to Ayumi-chan?!
Violence isn't good, Genta-kun.
Shut up! You got a problem with me, Mitsuhiko?!
Stop it, Genta-kun!
I gotta go, I'm really busy!
Wait, Conan-kun!
Damn it...
I'll never find those men in black if things keep up like this.
Just be patient, Shin'ichi.
Think what would happen if you rushed things
and they found out that you're really Shin'ichi Kudo.
I know, I know.
It would put not just me but all the people around me in real danger.
Oh, yes! Ran-kun came by yesterday.
She did?
Shin'ichi didn't come to school again today.
And it doesn't look like he's been home either...
I think I'll call the police...
Wait!
I'm sure he's just working on another one of his strange cases...
Don't worry. He'll be back home soon enough, I'm sure of it.
I've got her convinced for the time being, but how long can we keep this up?
Ran...
Oh, that's right!
I made something you'll find useful for your cases.
This is a Voice-Altering Bow Tie!
"Voice-Altering"?
Turn the dial on the back and you can make all kinds of voices.
You can sound like an old man, a child, a man, and even a woman...
I'm certain it'll come in handy at some point!
I doubt that a detective agency would have much use for this...
So that's Conan-kun's house!
We have no choice, we're gonna force him to be our friend!
That's...
The Mouri Detective Agency is closed today. If you've got a job for me...
...come back...tomorrow...
Oh my god! It's you!
Yoko Okino!
That's right.
No way! What would a celebrity be doing here?
Actually, I want to hire you...
You appear to be troubled, my dear.
Yes...
Who the heck are you?
What?!
Somebody's spying on you?!
The furniture's been moved whenever I come home,
somebody's been sending me candid photos they took of me,
and I've been getting anonymous phone calls everyday!
How dare they!
If at all possible, we'd like you to look into it quietly.
Who're you?
Oh, I'm Yamagishi, her manager.
Her manager?
Very well. I will investigate as discreetly as possible.
I'll need your address and phone number here.
Okay.
And if you could autograph this too...
Alright...
Don't forget to write "To Kogoro"...
Now that the great detective Kogoro Mouri is on the case,
you have nothing to fear!
Can I come too?
I've always wanted to see a celebrity's home.
Don't you agree, Conan-kun?
Yeah.
Just don't be getting in the way! Got it?!
We won't!
So this is it?!
This is exactly the kind of place I thought Yoko Okino might live!
Hey, not so loud!
Nobody's supposed to know she lives here, it's a secret.
The 25th floor, was it?
Yoko-chan in the flesh... awesome!
We definitely have to make friends with Conan-kun!
Agreed.
It's so pretty!
Come on inside...
What's the matter, Yoko?
You guys!
This is...
Is everyone all right?
Geez...
I see.
So he had already been murdered by the time you got back?
Yes.
And the person with you at the time was...
...was me, Kogoro Mouri, Inspector Megure!
Why him, of all people?
It's just like old times!
Remember all those cases we worked on together?!
Yes. And thanks to you most of them went unsolved!
It certainly is hot in here.
Do you always have the heater on this high?
No.
And I'm sure I turned it off before I left.
That's odd.
That isn't the only thing that's odd, Inspector.
They're very faint, but there are damp spots all around the body.
And this chair is the only thing still standing,
while everything else in the room has been thrown about.
And this heat...
Was it done to disguise the time of death?
Kids shouldn't get in the way!
That means you!
Have you determined the cause of death?
It would seem this knife was the cause.
Does that knife belong to you?
Y-Yes...
You can't honestly suspect Yoko?
Have you seen the victim before?
Um, I'd have to take a closer look...
So have you seen him before?
I'm sorry, I guess we haven't.
Right, Yoko?
Yes...
I'm sure I saw him—
What was that? What did he pick up?
Don't mind me.
A strand of hair?
Why would her manager try to hide this?
Could the murderer have been...
The murder took place while the door was locked.
Which means the murderer was the apartment's resident.
No! I could never kill anyone!
She's telling the truth, Inspector.
Just because she has a key doesn't mean...
Don't people usually have a spare key?
Yeah!
Hey now, stay out of this!
Um, Yamagishi-san has my spare key.
That's it!
Yamagishi! You're the murderer!
Yamagishi!
Yoko gave you the cold shoulder so you took it out on him, didn't you?!
Hey, now. Where's the proof that she didn't do it?
Such a beautiful young woman would never do anything like that!
I see...
Morons.
Yes, I did have her spare key, but I lost it 2 or 3 days ago...
Stop lying!
I'm not!
I was in the dressing room at the TV station.
I can vouch for him, he told me about it!
Well, if that's what Yoko-san says, then...
I get the feeling that we're still lacking something really important
that could explain everything here...
An earring?!
Hey, Inspector, under that sofa—
You kids stay out of this!
Dang it, they all ignore me...
That's it! This thing!
I'll just set it to an adult's voice, and...
Inspector, there's something beneath the sofa.
What's this?
An earring...
That's Yuko-san's...
Yuko-san?
Yuko Ikezawa-san.
She debuted the same time I did.
I heard that she was upset that Yoko got her role in a drama series...
Now I've got it!
The murderer was Yuko Ikezawa!
Arrest her!
Isn't that right, Inspector?
We'll have to go to the station—
No, let's have her come here for questioning!
You heard the inspector! Hurry!
Yes, sir!
Yuko Ikezawa did it!
There's no doubt about it!
Judging from the scene of the crime, the murderer must be Yoko Okino!
The manager's inexplicable action...
And the odd marks left behind in the room...
All the pieces are here.
The question is how to put them together...
You've got to be kidding me!
The murder took place in Yoko's place.
She's the one you should suspect.
Yuko-san...
I've never been here before now. I'm innocent.
Then what was this doing here?!
I thought I lost that somewhere! I'm glad you found it!
It doesn't stop with the earring.
The superintendent also said that he's seen someone who looks like you!
Someone who looks like me? This is ridiculous.
I'm borrowing your bathroom.
Hold it! I'm not done yet!
You never give up, do you?!
You think I'm the murderer just because of an earring?!
I'm really busy, you know!
Not nearly as busy as little Miss Popular Celebrity, though...
But if the media gets wind of this your image'll take a nosedive!
Maybe you'll lose as much work as I have!
How dare you threaten her!
They both look exactly the same from behind...
And how did she know...
Hey, grownups!
Shut up, boy!
What!?
Why you...
Don't get in the way of their investigation, Conan-kun.
But if Shin'ichi were here he'd easily solve this case.
Where could that mystery geek have gone?
Don't worry! He'll be back, I'm sure of it!
I mean, maybe...
What do I have to say for you to understand?!
I already told you I've never been here before!
That's a pretty weird lighter, isn't it?
How did you know this was a lighter if you've never been here before?
Yes. Care to explain how you knew?
I know someone who has one just like it.
And where does this someone live?
Well, um...
Where's the bathroom?
I've never been here before so I don't know where it is.
Eh? It's in the hallway...
Come to think of it, you knew where the bathroom was too!
Which is because you, Yuko Ikezawa, are the murderer!
You killed that man in this apartment to create a big scandal around Yoko-san!
I didn't.
I didn't! I didn't kill him!
All I did was defend myself when he suddenly attacked me!
I'll admit it, I did sneak in here several times
using the spare key I stole from the dressing room.
I wanted to find something, anything, that could cause a scandal!
But when I came in this afternoon, that man suddenly showed up!
I defended myself with all of my strength...
...and then escaped as quickly as I could!
Are you sure you didn't really kill him in the heat of the moment?!
I said I didn't kill him!
Inspector!
We've learned the identity of the victim.
Akiyoshi Fujie, 22 years old.
Upon graduating from Konan High School,
he began working for Kakubeni Corporation.
Konan High School...
Isn't that your old high school, Yoko-san?
It's just a coincidence!
Isn't that right, Yoko?
I... I know him!
No, I didn't just know him, he was my high school boyfriend!
What?!
Yoko!
I'm sorry, Yamagishi-san. I can't hide it.
Don't tell me you did this to break up with your old flame!
No, I didn't!
After all, he was the one who dumped me.
Who is it?
Who's the murderer?!
Yoko Okino?
Yuko Ikezawa?
Yamagishi, the manager?
Damn it...
We're still missing something we need to make any deductions!
What is it? What are we missing?
A dent in the floor?
Wait a second...
Even though the room's in shambles
this chair is the only thing left standing.
And this room's exceptionally high temperature...
The water splotches left around the body...
The hair in the corpse's hand?
A-ha! That's it!
I've finally solved the puzzle!
The murderer...
...is you, Yamagishi!
You saw him as an obstacle
because he was capable of starting a scandal around Yoko-san!
Then you ran into him while he was hiding in here
and proceeded to kill him!
No!
Yamagishi-san isn't the murderer!
What a nice nap...
You're conscious again, Genta-kun!
Where's the bathroom?
That way.
You're the only one left who could be the murderer!
Forgive me, old man!
Fess up! You'll feel better!
Oh no!
In that case...
Now then, I'll just set it to his voice, and...
Which is what I would like to say, but that isn't the case.
Yamagishi-san.
If you really asked me to help you so that I would discover the body,
you would have also prepared something to prove your innocence.
Yoko-san, the same goes for you,
especially since the 1st person to suspect would be the apartment's tenant.
So then the murderer...
is Yuko Ikezawa!
Now wait just a minute!
She didn't do it either.
Even if she did commit the murder in the heat of the moment,
she wouldn't have told us she ran into him.
But what you're saying is...
Yes, these are only educated guesses at most.
They don't hold up as proof that the three of them are innocent.
But there is evidence to support it.
Yamagishi-san.
You pretended to slip and then removed strands of hair from the body.
What?!
I knew it! I knew you were the killer!
You're wrong.
The man was stabbed in the back,
but he was holding the stabber's hair in his hands.
Don't you find that a bit odd?
Now that you mention it...
The one responsible set it all up to look like a murder...
As if he was killed by Yoko-san herself...
"Like a murder"?
You don't mean...
That's right.
The killer is none other than...
...the late Fujie-san himself!
A suicide?!
Nonsense! How could he stab himself in the back with a knife?!
It's a simple trick involving ice.
He set the heater on high, took hairs from Yoko-san's brush,
then stood up on a chair and fell back onto a knife
that was held in place by a block of ice.
You'll find the indentation mark made by the knife's handle
near where the body was.
The ice shattered and later melted because of the high heat.
However, Fujie-san tried too hard to frame her.
The hair?
Yes.
When Yamagishi-san saw it,
he tried to hide it because he thought Yoko-san had indeed killed him.
But why would Fujie-kun do something like this?
I would think that it was because he still loved you.
Didn't you realize that the two of you look exactly the same from behind?
So he mistook Yuko-san for Yoko-san and attacked—
No. He tried to talk to her.
Not realizing he was talking to Yuko-san and not Yoko-san,
he was completely shocked when she resisted him,
and the feelings of his love being driven to the wall turned into despair and hatred.
But he dumped me! Why would he do that?
No, that's not the truth, Yoko...
The truth is, I asked him to break up with you.
How could you?
Inspector!
What is it?
We've found a diary in the late Fujie-san's house.
What?!
The diary was filled with his pain.
How even after they broke up,
he was unable to forget about her, so he went to see her.
He hoped she would end her career as a celebrity and come back to him.
All he wanted to do was clear up the misunderstandings.
The last thing he wrote was that he couldn't live like this any longer.
It would appear this was a tragic story that consisted of lies,
misunderstandings, and coincidence.
Hot!
Mouri-kun! You were right!
I've changed my mind about you,
"Great Detective"!
I'm exhausted...
It was a little scary, but I've never been that excited before!
I think if we make friends with Conan-kun
we'll get to experience lots more thrills and suspense!
Alright then! We've gotta get Conan-kun to be our friend!
Yeah!
She's so strong!
Already back on her feet after all that happened...
I could never do that.
I could never be as strong as Yoko-san...
I can't even sleep at night with Shin'ichi gone...
I'm really hopeless...
It's strange.
Shin'ichi has been missing for a week now...
Something must have happened to him!
But nothing like that would ever happen to Shin'ichi!
Shin'ichi... Come back soon!
Hello, Mouri Detective—
Ran.
It's me.
Shin'ichi?
I figured you might be crying because you're worried about me.
Yeah, right. Why would I be crying?
Where are you right now, Shin'ichi?
I was asked to take a sort of dangerous case...
I'll come back home once I've taken care of it.
So don't worry.
I'm sorry, Ran.
When I return to my normal body, I'll let you hear it...
My real voice...
My real feelings...
NEXT EPISODE
60 seconds until the next episode's hint!
What do you think these drawings could be?
I'll bet it's a treasure map!
It's time for some treasure hunting!
From this day forth we'll be known as the Detective Boys!
I'm gonna use that treasure
to eat the world's best eel dishes!
What about you, Conan-kun?
I'll save it, I guess...
Hey! There it is!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Neon Sign
Next time, can you crack the code?