The famous high school detective Shin'ichi Kudo
was forced to take a strange poison by a certain organization,
causing him to shrink and become Conan Edogawa!
Doesn't matter if I'm small!
My mind's that of a brilliant 17-year old detective!
I'll solve another case today that would have adults shaking in their boots!
Created by
Gosho Aoyama
"Detective Conan"
Serialized in Shogakukan's
"Weekly Shonen Sunday"
Planning
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Character Design
Masatomo Sudo
Art Director
Yukihiro Shibutani
Art Design
Hiroyuki Mitsumoto
Directors of Photography
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takashi Nomura
Sound Director
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
Music Producer
Hiroki Horio
(PolyGram)
Music
Katsuo Ono
Opening Theme
"Mune ga doki-doki"
(Kitty Enterprises)
Performed by
Lyrics
Music
Arrangement
THE HIGH-LOWS
Hiroto Komoto/Masatoshi Mashima
Ending Theme
"Step by Step"
(Mercury Music Entertainment)
Performed by
Lyrics
Music
Arrangement
ZIGGY
Juichi Morishige
Editor
Teramitsu Okada
(JAY FILM)
Story Editor
Jun'ichi Iioka
Color Key
Reiko Hirayama
Associate Producer
Satoshi Kojima
Director
Kenji Kodama
Producers
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Kazuhiko Yagiuchi
(Tokyo Movie)
Masahito Yoshioka
"Secret Treasures of the World Exhibit"
It's so pretty!
Totally awesome!
Amazing!
A map to buried treasure?
That sure was fun!
I really liked that gold mask!
There's still tons of secret treasure all over the world
that hasn't been discovered yet!
For reals?! I wanna try and find some!
What's this?
What is it?
What's with this piece of paper?
It has a bunch of strange symbols on it...
Hey! Maybe it's a treasure map!
A treasure map?
Yeah, right!
What?! Are you sayin' you can't believe what Ayumi says?!
But...
But what?
What are you getting so mad about?
But what?!
Let's go check it out!
I agree!
Yeah!
Ayumi's definitely right about this!
What if it really is a 100% genuine treasure map?!
Exactly! What if it is a real map?!
So let's go check it out!
Definitely!
Alright then! Let's go treasure hunting!
From this day forth we'll be known as the Detective Boys!
Huh? Detective Boys?
That sounds so cool!
I, Genta Kojima, will be club leader!
Any objections?!
Nope!
My head's starting to hurt...
Let's go!
Yeah!
Go where?
Don't ask me...
Let me have a look at that piece of paper...
Look at this very top symbol.
Haven't you seen this somewhere before?
Hurry!
Alright!
Come on!
Dino Cavane, the Italian crime lord who was arrested last night
at an apartment complex near Tohto Tower, has so far refused to say anything.
The police are currently pursuing Cavane's accomplices,
but they have been unable to find any clues leading to their whereabouts.
The location of the 15,000 Maple Leaf gold coins they stole
is also unknown.
"To Tohto Tower"
I thought the Tohto Tower was suspicious from the very beginning!
Now the treasure is as good as ours!
But what do you think these letters mean?
It says "ORO" here, but...
orochi
G-Giant serpent?
I bet it's an abbreviation!
ōkii
The first O stands for "big"!
The R means rich!
o-takara
And the last O stands for "treasure"!
So that means it's a big treasure that will make you rich!
Wow! I didn't know you could read English, Mitsuhiko-kun!
Well, just a little.
I bet it's a huge treasure!
Hey now!
Alright! I'm gonna use that treasure to eat the world's best eel dishes!
I'm gonna go around the world 100 times!
I'm going to buy a space shuttle from NASA and go into space!
What about you, Conan-kun?
I'll save it, I guess...
You don't know how to have fun, do ya?
Well, excuse me.
Alright! Here we are!
All that's left is to decipher the code!
But none of the other symbols look like anything,
except for the one that looks like an umbrella...
That's it! It's the moon!
The treasure must be where the moon and Tohto Tower line up like this!
That can't be it.
The moon's position changes everyday,
and I doubt you could specify exact locations with such simple drawings.
Then where is it?!
Conan-kun, did you figure anything out?
I was wondering if the other symbols are abbreviations for things.
Like this symbol beneath the tower could be a hat.
Beneath that might be underwear.
The umbrella beneath that could be an emblem on a sweater or something.
And the thing that links them all together...
A clothes store!
But this isn't enough to really—
Hurry!
H-Hey!
"Terahara Clothing Shop"
Find it!
There has to be a clue in here somewhere!
Come on! Faster!
Hey, stop it, you three!
Get out!
Stupid little kids!
I never want to see you here again!
Looks like it didn't have to do with clothing stores after all...
Nope...
I sure am hungry...
Wanna go eat something?
Sure.
Hey, why don't we stop by a bookstore?
Stupid! You can't eat anything at a bookstore!
Just for a short while. Okay?
Whoa!
Hey, check this out! It's hilarious!
Yeah, it is!
"English-to-Japanese Dictionary"
O. R. O. ORO?
Was there such a word in English?
No luck, it's not in there...
Which means...
Italian...
I really doubt it...
Here it is!
Oro in Italian means gold!
Which means this code really does show where treasure is!
"Mouri Detective Agency"
The accomplices of the Italian crime lord Dino Cavane,
who was caught yesterday, are currently in Japan.
The whereabouts of the 15,000 Maple Leaf coins they stole
are, as of yet, unknown.
These coins, which total over 600 million in Japanese yen, were—
600 million, huh? These guys must know what they're doing.
You've trashed the place up again?!
Can you get any worse?!
That reminds me, where's the runt?
If you mean Conan-kun, he left early this morning
to go to the art museum with his friends.
Kids sure got it easy.
Come on, Dad! At least help clean up a little!
Fine, fine.
According to Italian authorities,
three of Cavane's accomplices are on the run, and one of them is Japanese.
What's up with Conan-kun?
How should I know? That's all he's been doing since we got here!
Do you think maybe he figured something out?
It's hopeless! I can't figure it out!
What is this code?!
Is it a map? Or is it some kind of message?!
Damn it!
Look!
Could that be it?!
See! That sign! It looks just like the second symbol!
Hey, it does!
Which means...
Could these symbols actually represent...
It has to be! This shop's directly in front of Tohto Tower,
and the next symbol has the shape of this sign!
So if we follow this order of store signs we'll find the treasure!
But which way should we go from here?
Moon View Street!
Could the moon symbol next to the tower actually represent Moon View Street?!
I bet it does! Let's go!
Yeah!
Look! There it is!
An upside-down triangle sign!
You're right! It looks just like the third symbol!
So these symbols really do represent—
An aquarium!
That's it! I figured it out!
This code is a map from Tohto Tower to the Nanbu Aquarium!
They drew the signs and displays of stores along Moon View Street!
And the final destination...
...is a mountain of treasure!
Okay! Let's go!
Yeah!
I didn't see the fifth star-shaped symbol anywhere...
Damn! And we were so close to the treasure!
Huh?
We've made it all the way to the aquarium!
What?!
How can this be?!
We never even found the fifth symbol on Moon View Street
between Tohto Tower and the Nanbu Aquarium!
Or am I assuming something incorrectly?
Wait. Why is "gold" written in Italian?
If the person who wrote this was Italian, then the moon symbol...
Could it be...
That's it! I figured it out!
We need to go back to where we started!
Hey! Conan!
It's hard to think that the person who wrote "gold" in Italian
would use the moon symbol to represent Moon View Street—
which is in Japanese!
The moon represents night—and the things you can only see at night!
Neon signs!
Conan! What did you figure out?
This is a treasure map comprised of the shapes of various neon signs.
The neon sign in the second symbol is over there!
There!
You're right!
Next we go down by the stadium!
We just need to find an umbrella-shaped sign!
I don't see any umbrella-shaped signs anywhere...
Are you sure you've got it right?
I already found it.
"Tomorrow's Weather"
There.
What're you talking about? That's the sun.
That's it! The symbol for rain!
Rain must've been in the forecast for the day after they wrote the code!
Next is a neon sign shaped like a star!
I found it!
This has to be it!
A Ferris Wheel!
There's no doubt about it! It's the fifth symbol!
So we should see the sixth sign from here!
Where is it?!
There it is! The sixth neon sign!
Say, Conan, there's really gonna be treasure here, right?
Yeah. This symbol has "ORO" written next to it, after all.
I've been looking for the last fish-shaped sign for a while,
but I just can't seem to find it.
Of course not.
This is a residential street. There's nothing on it.
The closest fish would probably be in a nearby river or something.
That's it! The river!
It must mean a river with fish in it!
Huh?
Okay! Let's go check out the river!
Hey now!
Come on, Genta-kun! Stop!
That's dangerous, you know!
Quit yer yappin'! The treasure has to be at the bottom of this river!
Cold!
No! This code represents things you can only see at night!
So the fish symbol at the end can't represent the river.
If my guess is correct, then it has to be somewhere nearby!
A fish-shaped neon light...
Conan-kun?
I finally found it.
The glowing fish, that is.
A glowing fish?
Never heard of any.
Just follow me.
Come on already...
Is there really gonna be a glowing fish here?!
Hey! It's so dark I can't see anything, much less any fish!
Take a look outside.
Towards that river.
The river?
See! Over there!
That's the glowing fish!
The lights are reflected on the water and make it look like a fish!
And the fish's eye is the light on the building in front of us!
Does that mean the treasure's in here?!
Yeah.
It's probably located right around...
...here!
A gold coin...
What's that black shadow?!
It looks like it's connected to a rope.
Now I see.
They raised the sacks of gold coins up
by looping the rope around part of the ceiling that sticks out!
It's the treasure!
Thanks for the help, kiddos!
W-Who are you guys?
Weren't they the ones I saw in front of Tohto Tower?
Wait! Maybe they're the...
Give it back! We found those first!
Stop!
BAM! SMASH! CRASH!
Damn it!
Are you alright, Genta-kun?
I see. They still don't know where the coins are.
Who are those people?
Members of that Italian crime ring, most likely!
Crime ring?!
Come to think of it, I heard about them on the news!
That means those coins just now must've been—
That's right.
We swiped these coins from an Italian bank a year ago.
Just like our boss Cavane told us to.
But then he backstabbed us and ran off to Japan.
With the 15,000 Maple Leaf coins in tow, of course.
We tailed him to Japan and paid him a visit!
But he had hidden the coins somewhere!
He wouldn't tell us where he hid 'em, no matter how much we interrogated him.
All we found at his place was this code!
He wouldn't help us out, so we informed the police of his location,
and set out in search of the coins ourselves, relying only on his code.
The wind blew the paper away when we stopped by the art museum.
But we saw you cracking the code little by little,
so we decided to let you keep going.
Never imagined you'd actually find it for us though!
A gun!
Conan-kun!
So tell me! Where are the coins?!
You better speak up!
The fish.
What?
The coins are hidden at the location where the fish symbol
and the night view of the bridge outside match up!
I see.
Conan! What'd you tell him for?!
We're as good as dead once they find the treasure!
They're gonna kill us no matter what!
They're gonna shoot us to death, I bet...
I bet they're gonna stick us in cement and drop us into the ocean...
No, they're going to burn us to death so there's no proof left behind!
Mom...
Dad...
Mommy...
It's too early to give up just yet!
We still have a chance!
If we all work together, that is!
How will that do anything?
We're just children!
Aren't we the Detective Boys?!
Alright! So what do we do?
Get up. But make sure they don't notice.
We only have one shot at this!
The moment that they find the coins and let their guard down!
Now!
Run!
We did it!
Afterward, we went straight to a nearby police station
and explained everything that had happened.
To everyone's delight, the gang was arrested and the case was closed.
It wound up being the Detective Boys' very first accomplishment!
You're amazing! All of you!
I can't believe you cracked that code!
And you even captured some thieves!
It was me! I caught them!
And I used my reasoning to decipher the code!
Don't listen to them!
It was Conan-kun who cracked the code and beat up the gang!
He was so cool!
Conan-kun.
Thank you!
Good for you, Conan-kun! You've made a cute little girlfriend!
N-No, I didn't...
Now he's embarrassed! How cute!
No, really!
Lousy Conan!
NEXT EPISODE
60 seconds until the next episode's hint!
Damn it! There's still something I want to ask you!
Who has the bomb?!
Huh? Where is it? I can't find—
There's only one way to make her believe me!
If I tell her that I'm actually Shin'ichi Kudo!
Who are you really?
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Cell Phone
Next time's gonna keep you on the edge of your seat. Be sure to watch!