My name's Shin'ichi Kudo!
Until just recently, I was a famous high school detective
known throughout the entire country!
But a mysterious organization forced me to take a pill,
turning me into Conan Edogawa!
Doesn't matter if I'm small!
My mind is that of a former great detective,
and no matter what sort of incident takes place,
- there is always only one truth!
You know Shin'ichi Kudo, Ran-oneechan?!
Eh? Well, yeah...
Awesome!
I can't believe you know the super-famous high school detective!
He wouldn't happen to be your boyfriend, would he?
- No! Nothing of the sort!
Why are you reacting the same way?
No, it's just that—
He's your boyfriend, isn't he?!
Oh, well, you see...
I can't really answer that!
We're home!
Come to think of it, what could Shin'ichi be doing?
It's been a while since I last heard anything from him...
The case he's working on has probably hit a hard spot!
But normally he solves all of his cases
without any problems at all...
Do you think that maybe he's...
...gotten worse at being a detective?
Coming!
What's going on?
I'm so sorry, little boy!
Are you all right?
Yeah...
My name is Ogawa.
Since about 2 years ago,
someone has been sending me toys and money every month.
It's kind of creepy
because the sender's name and address are always made-up.
Toys and money, huh?
Do you have any children?
Yes. A 5-year old son named Yuta.
Exactly how much money have they been sending?
1 million yen each month.
It will total 25 million this month!
- 25 million?!
Yuta loves the fact that new toys come every month,
but being sent money is too creepy for me so I haven't touched any of it.
If that's the case, I wouldn't mind holding on to the money for you!
Dad!
I was just kidding!
Do you have any ideas who it could be?
No.
Are you sure it isn't one of your patients?
Patients?
You're a surgeon, aren't you?
I am...
Then it wouldn't be strange for one of the patients you saved
to send all this to you in appreciation for your help, would it?
No...
Huh? I don't remember mentioning that I was a surgeon...
How did you know that, Conan-kun?!
It was his index fingers.
My fingers?
You have diagonal marks on your fingers, right?
When performing operations,
surgeons use both index fingers to sew tight sutures.
Over time, it causes diagonal marks to appear on their index fingers!
Is he right?!
Yes...
In fact, I performed a surgery just this very morning.
Excellent work, my lad!
This kid knows all sorts of weird stuff...
But that was amazing, Conan-kun!
That was almost like—
Almost like...
You're in a gymnastics club, aren't you?
Only people who train on the horizontal bar ever get this many blisters.
Almost like Shin'ichi...
H-He couldn't be...
He couldn't be.
This came today.
There doesn't seem to be anything strange besides the money...
No! Normally it's a much larger package with both toys and money in it!
This is the first time it's been like this...
A letter.
"I have finished paying the 25 million yen.
I will be coming to get what is mine."
What exactly does this mean?
Your guess is as good as mine.
Hey, why don't these have those line patterns on them?
Line patterns?
There's one on that.
Oh, you mean a barcode.
That is strange.
There aren't any on any of these things!
They don't sell these toys in stores anymore...
And it looks like some have been damaged...
Come to think of it, ever since the toys started coming in,
some of them were worn out, and others were completely broken.
In other words, they've either been sending used toys
or toys that they had purchased quite a while ago.
Along with the large sums of money!
But why?!
Most likely...
...it's just an ordinary prank!
A prank?
Yup, no doubt about it.
No, it's too complicated for a simple prank.
And sending all that money for no reason would be pointless...
And then there's that letter...
You have such excellent powers of deduction, Mouri-san!
That was nothing at all.
No! Dad didn't figure any of those things out!
It was all because of Conan-kun!
He couldn't be...
He couldn't be!
So this letter is the only clue as to who the sender is...
Say, do you think the sender could be trying to buy something
from Ogawa-san?
Depending on how you interpret it,
it could mean something like that.
Now that you mention it...
There is a painting in the hospital that my grandfather left me.
I'm pretty sure they said that it was worth about 20 million yen...
That's it!
The sender must want to buy that painting from you!
Let's all go to the hospital
and have a look at the painting!
We may find more details!
OK! Let's go!
"Beika Hospital"
This certainly is a large hospital!
I, too, was surprised when
I first came here 3 years ago.
I was transferred here from a small, rural hospital, you see...
Ogawa-sensei. Another one of these.
Another one this year, huh?
Morning glories? With the weather as cold as it is?
I can only assume that the person has been growing them in a greenhouse.
Wait, they've been sending these too?
Yes, the same person has been sending these as well.
But the flowers only come once a year.
On today, February 19th.
Sending flowers must mean the sender is female...
The phrase associated with morning glories is "a short-lived love".
Don't tell me you did something with another woman 2 years ago...
Nothing of the sort!
Then could it be your son's birthday or something?
Yuta's birthday is in December.
If it's OK with him,
why don't we have a look at Ogawa-sensei's medical records?
There might be a patient who has something to do with February 19th!
That's right.
May we have a look?
I'm not allowed to show the records to other people...
Can't we bend the rules just this once?
Very well. I suppose I have no other choice.
Sorry to bother you like this!
Well, here are all of my patients' records for the past 3 years.
And there's nobody in here who might want that painting?
No.
Say, would you like to see the painting for yourself?
Sure.
It's hanging in the patients' waiting room.
You're not coming, Conan-kun?
I'll wait here!
OK. Then be a good boy and behave yourself!
OK!
The painting is quite popular among many of the patients too!
Conan-kun! Something's not right!
He's acting too strangely for an ordinary grade school student!
Yeah! Back then, too!
So this dog barks at all strangers then?
And that other time too!
How did you know this was a lighter if you've never been here before?
It was almost like Shin'ichi was giving suggestions!
Yeah!
The day Shin'ichi disappeared...
...Conan-kun showed up, in his place, almost...
Could he actually be Shin'ichi?!
I'll have to make sure!
Here goes!
What're you doing?!
You shouldn't be reading people's records without permission!
R-Ran-neechan!
Did you find anything?
Yeah, sort of.
He said earlier that the flowers are sent to the hospital once a year, right?
That makes me think that it was a former patient here.
It was 2 years ago when he started receiving the toys and the money,
so that narrows it down to patients who were here
during Ogawa-san's first year at this hospital.
Among them, there are 8 people
who have something to do with February 19th.
People whose surgeries were successful on that day,
or people who were released or checked in on that day.
Sending flowers most likely means the person is grateful to him,
but they bother me...
The morning glories grown with care in a greenhouse, and that letter...
It's amazing that you could figure that much out!
Great work, Shin'ichi!
It was nothing—
I knew it!
You are Shin'ichi!
W-What are you talking about, Ran-neechan?
My name's Conan! Conan!
Stop playing around!
Not good! She's found me out!
If word gets out that I'm actually Shin'ichi Kudo,
they'll come back to kill me!
And if that happens,
they might go after Ran and the others as well!
I have to fool her somehow!
Wow! A Game Man! And Yaiba's Great Adventure!
Go Yaiba! Beat up Onimaru!
This is fun!
I think he's faking! It's too suspicious!
Conan-kun must really be Shin'ichi...
But this sort of thing doesn't happen;
this isn't a science fiction movie, after all...
Wait a minute!
If he really is, then...
Say, Conan-kun.
Is there anyone you like?
I have someone I really like!
Don't tell me it's that Shin'ichi boy you were looking for earlier?
That's right!
He's always been kind of a tease since he was a kid,
and he's always been so full of himself and a big mystery geek,
but he's also courageous, cool, and dependable!
I really like Shin'ichi a lot!
Oh no! Game over!
Hey, you wanna try, Ran-neechan?
You like this sort of thing, don't you?
L-Like...
I do not! Don't get the wrong idea!
You don't? I'll keep playing then...
Tomoya Ogino?
Huh? Ogawa-san said his son was named Yuta...
Normally you enter your own name
or the name of a character you like...
Wait. Tomoya Ogino.
Where have I seen this name before?
That's it!
Here it is!
Tomoya Ogino, 5 years old.
He died after Ogawa-san operated on him.
Three years ago, on February 19th!
"I have finished paying the 25 million yen.
I will be coming to get what is mine."
The letter couldn't mean what I think it does!
Ran! Bring Mr. Ogawa here right away!
Hurry! There's no time!
It has to be!
That tone, his mannerisms, his deductions...
They're all exactly like Shin'ichi's!
No question about it!
Did you really find out who the sender is?!
I think it might be the parents of
Tomoya Ogino-kun here!
Tomoya Ogino?
The one who died of appendicitis three years ago!
People can die from appendicitis?
Yes. If it's not detected early enough...
It was already too late for him when they brought him in to the hospital...
The boy's father absolutely would not listen to me, however...
But why would he send you presents if the operation wasn't successful?
They're neither presents nor used goods!
They're the belongings of the late
Tomoya Ogino, who died 3 years ago!
In other words, he's been sending
all of his son's keepsakes!
Sending them out of hatred!
The flowers are delivered to the hospital every February 19th
because it's the anniversary of his son's death!
And that letter means that he's going
to take the life of Ogawa-san's son
on the exact same day!
What?!
Where's your son right now?!
My wife should be on her way
to pick him up at school!
Contact her at once!
Someone already picked him up?!
They told me his father had
already picked him up!
It wasn't you?!
T-This can't be happening...
This is bad!
If we don't find them soon, Yuta-kun's a goner!
Where's the school?!
It isn't very far from here...
Then they're still nearby!
Conan-kun!
Look, little boy.
I have a present for you!
Yay!
Thank you, Mister!
Hey, are you really gonna take me to a fun place after this?
Sure. I'll take you there soon.
To where Tomoya is.
Where?! Where are they?!
Tomoya!
It must have been lonely all by yourself!
I'll bring you a friend soon!
Right now, in fact!
That's Yuta!
What?!
Not good!
Here goes! Try this on for size!
Go!
Did Conan-kun do that just now?!
Yuta!
Daddy!
Stop right there!
Move and you know what'll happen!
Ogino-san! So it was you!
That's right! It was me!
I'm the father of Tomoya Ogino,
who you killed 3 years ago when you messed up his operation!
It wasn't my fault!
It was already too late when they carried him—
Shut up! As if you would understand
the feelings of a father
whose son was murdered just after he turned 5!
All I had left were his remains and the 25 million in insurance money!
So that's why you sent all that money...
That's right.
The money, his toys, and the morning glories that he loved so much!
It was with my hatred that I sent them all to you!
Now it's your turn to feel what it's like to lose your own son!
Please! Don't hurt my son!
Kill me instead!
Just let my son go!
Oh! So you were the one who sent the toys!
Thank you, Mister!
I always take good care of them all!
T-Tomoya!
Tomoya...
What's wrong, Mister?
Did Daddy and the others say something bad to you?
No, little boy.
I was the bad one.
I knew.
I knew from the very start that it wasn't his fault.
But I had to fool myself into thinking it was, or else I...
I'm sorry, little boy! I'm so sorry!
Ran. Call the police.
Wait! Please don't get the police involved!
But he just tried to kill your son.
It's all right.
I see...
Ogino-san. I know exactly how you feel.
After all, I am a father before I'm a doctor.
How lucky it was that it didn't turn into a serious incident.
But why did he send the money and toys for 2 whole years?
He was probably waiting for Yuta-kun to turn 5 first.
The same age that Tomoya-kun was when he died 3 years ago...
I see!
Excellent deduction skills you have there.
But I'm just a kid so I don't really know for sure!
I just remembered something I have to do!
Go on home without me!
What's with him?
I'm home!
Huh? Where's your dad?
He went drinking.
You must be hungry. I'll make you something.
OK!
Oh, yeah!
I hear our shop teacher Kishida-sensei is getting married!
That gorilla?
How do you know about my high school teacher?
No, uh, you're always talking
about how he's a gorilla!
Liar!
I couldn't believe it at first,
but I guess you really are Shin'ichi!
No, I'm—
Just confess already! Shin'ichi!
T-The phone...
Let it ring!
B-But...
Alright! I'll pick it up!
Yeah, this is the Mouri Detective—
Hey, Ran!
It's been a while!
S-Shin'ichi?
No way! You're right h—
Hey, now. Have you already forgotten the sound of my voice?
How cruel!
Darn that Shin'ichi!
Please, Dr. Agasa! I think Ran's on to me!
Call her using my voice!
He shouldn't have made her worry so much like that!
Hey, Ran.
Are you there, Ran?
I'm so stupid! I think I misunderstood things!
No, it's nothing.
Say, Shin'ichi. Have you started using words that old men use?
Have I?
You're a life-saver.
NEXT EPISODE
60 seconds until the next episode's hint!
There are so many beautiful paintings!
I'm so glad we came!
Look at this! The colors are lovely!
What's with that expression?!
What's on the card that he's so shocked about?!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Ball Pen Observation
If you miss next week's episode,
you'll be left behind!