My name's Conan Edogawa!
High school student Shin'ichi was forced to take a pill that shrunk him!
Doesn't matter if I'm small!
My mind is that of a former great detective!
Today's case takes place at an art museum!
Behind the scenes is a grisly, red death!
No matter the incident,
there is always only one truth!
"Medieval Art Exhibit"
Patrolling an art museum at night is the last thing I wanted to do!
You'll never make a good watchman with an attitude like that.
Did you just hear something?
P-Please don't tease me like that, sir!
I-It came from this room...
Who's there?!
Is there someone in here?
A medieval suit of armor? All by itself?
Two watchmen saw it!
Everyone's talking about it!
What do you say we all go there right now? It sounds interesting!
The museum obviously cooked that story up to bring in more visitors!
Yeah, Ran-neechan! Only kids would fall for that!
And you're not a kid all of a sudden?
Well, time to get to work.
Guess I'll do my homework.
Not so fast!
Coming?
Yes!
Ran always gets like that when she gets mad.
Shouldn't have let her learn karate.
"Medieval Art Exhibit"
Look at all these beautiful paintings!
I'm so glad we came!
Look at this! The colors are so lovely!
I take it you like that painting, Miss?
I, too, enjoy this painting very much.
No, I love all of the paintings here!
Almost as if they were my own children.
Who might you be?
Oh, where are my manners?
My name is Ochiai. I run this art gallery.
Oh! I should have known!
Please enjoy your visit here.
Kubota! What are you doing?!
How many times have I said to wear gloves when handling exhibits?!
I-I'm sorry!
You can go.
Iijima-kun. Please take over for him.
Yes, sir.
As empty and quiet as ever, I see.
Mr. Manaka...
Ten days left until this place shuts down.
Take care of all this moldy, old junk for me until then!
OK, architect. Bring the blueprints.
Yes, sir.
This art gallery is going to close for good?
Yes. The previous owner's company went bankrupt
so he sold this place to that Mr. Manaka.
He sold it under the agreement that Mr. Manaka would keep it running!
But then the instant he bought it,
he said he was going to turn it into a hotel!
He's carelessly handling another exhibit again...
I take it you're Kubota-kun?
I've heard about you.
I suggest you hurry and scrape whatever money you can get together!
Damn it!
Again?!
Please enjoy your visit.
Why didn't he get angry again just now?
Earth Gallery
Sky Gallery
Sea Gallery
Huh?
No entry.
That's strange. There's supposed to be another room up ahead.
Just forget about it. Let's hurry and get through this place.
So tired!
Let's go home, Ran-neechan.
I'm starving!
Talk about pathetic! Getting exhausted so easily like this!
Huh?
The no entrance sign is gone.
Hey! Since we're here,
why don't we go see the last room?
You can go home if you want,
but you'll have to cook dinner yourselves.
- That's not fair!
Hell Gallery
This room sure is dark...
Well, it is the Hell Gallery.
What a huge picture!
It literally is a picture from Hell...
The title is "Divine Punishment".
It says it's a picture of a knight of justice sealing away a demon.
It's Mr. Manaka, the owner!
You again?!
Yes, sir!
I assure you, I haven't allowed anyone to touch the corpse, Inspector!
So, did anyone see who did it?
No. I've checked with everyone, but no one saw a thing...
That security camera might have caught the person on tape!
Okay, here we go.
What a stupid murderer. Being caught on tape without knowing it...
Oh? It's the owner!
Time to come out, killer!
Let us have a good look at your face—
Wait a second!
I've seen this scene somewhere before!
It's exactly like in that painting!
What painting?
The picture on display directly across from the victim.
The title was "Divine Punishment".
The murderer must have killed him in this manner
to make it look exactly like that painting.
What a daring murderer, though.
It would be all over if someone saw them wearing that around.
Now that you mention it, there was a no-entry sign in front of the room.
What now?
Ran. That was around 4 o'clock, wasn't it?
But when we passed by just after 5:00, the sign was gone.
The murder took place at approximately 4:30.
It would seem it was the murderer who put the sign up.
After doing that to keep people away,
the murderer put the armor on and hid in the room.
And then killed Mr. Manaka.
Which means the killer was someone well acquainted with the museum.
In other words...
...the killer is one of you.
Hey, look! The owner's doing something!
Hey, you! Don't be messing with the tape without permission!
Look! He's doing something before the killer jumped out...
He realized something and took that card!
And then the pen on top of the desk!
He's writing something!
He threw the pen away!
What about the card?!
Crumpled up in his hands!
Does that card say what I think it might?
It might still be in his hand!
I found this piece of paper in the victim's hand.
What's this?!
K-Kubota!
W-What's my name doing on that?!
It seems you wore the armor to conceal your identity from the camera,
but it also seems that the victim wasn't so easily fooled!
N-No! It wasn't me!
In that case, give us your alibi. Where were you at 4:30?
I was alone in the office, doing work that Mr. Ochiai asked me to do...
Yes, I did ask him to do some work.
Then that means nobody saw you, doesn't it?
Hold on! What motive would I have for killing the owner?!
There's no point in trying to talk your way out of this, Kubota-san!
The owner threatened to sue you for damages
because you were secretly selling this museum's exhibits!
Well, you see...
Is this the truth?
But that had nothing to do with this!
I wasn't the one who killed him!
If you say so.
The truth will come to light once my men find the suit of armor.
Inspector Megure! There's a ballpoint pen over here!
What?
Excellent work, my boy.
This is quite a nice pen!
That pen was created this year
In celebration of Beika Art Museum's 50th anniversary.
Everyone who works here has one.
So someone accidentally left it here, then?
Both colors and widths are exactly the same.
This is probably the one the victim used.
That's strange.
Kubota-san should have known about the security camera,
so why did he choose this room,
especially if it meant wearing armor to conceal his identity?
To make it look like that painting?
No, he doesn't seem to have much interest in art.
Would such a person actually do something like this?
Oh, man!
It's straight out of a horror movie!
Hey there!
Hey, little boy! You can't just barge in here!
Inspector Megure says he wants you to help with something else.
He must've figured out we really wanted to watch the tape.
Well, let's get going.
Right.
This is where it starts!
What's with that expression?
What's on the card that he's so shocked about?!
Why did he throw the pen away when he finished writing?
The killer would have realized he was there if he made any sounds...
Wait! When I found the pen...
...the tip was retracted!
Something's not right!
It's unnatural for someone who's about to be killed
to retract the pen tip of a twist-style ballpoint pen!
Then maybe that means...
Take care of the rest.
Yes, sir.
Now, then—
Hey!
There's a mark on the paper!
So I was right.
Now I have this trick figured out!
Hey, you!
What do you think you're doing?!
Inspector! We found it!
We found the armor in Kubota-san's locker!
You found it?!
This is crazy! I don't know anything about this!
We have two major pieces of evidence that point to you!
This blood-smeared suit of armor, and the victim's dying message!
No! That isn't a dying message at all!
It's a trick the killer used to put the blame on Kubota-san!
That was one bloody attack.
It's a shame that this work of art was ruined.
Actually, that's a replica used for decoration purposes.
I believe it was the same one Kubota-san was moving this afternoon.
Oh, that one?
Ah, so it was a replica.
That's why the museum manager didn't say anything
when he handled the armor so violently.
The replica was used in the attack, so the real one wasn't ruined.
It seems none of the other exhibits have been touched, either.
Come to think of it, the wall where he was killed...
...had cards, but no paintings!
The killer removed them in advance.
To protect them from the blood during the attack.
The killer really was one of the staff members!
Wait a second!
This is a trick that doesn't work without nulling Kubota-san's alibi.
Which means the one behind it...
...must be the museum manager!
If my conclusions are correct,
there's a possibility the murderer might still have it...
Well, Kubota-san.
For now, you'll have to come down to the station.
T-This can't be happening!
I have to go bad!
Bathroom! Bathroom!
Mister! Where's the bathroom?!
The restroom? Go out this room,
go down the stairs on your right,
and then—
That's too complicated for me!
Draw it on this!
Hurry up!
As I said, you go out this room...
What's the matter, Mister?
Why aren't you writing anything?
Oh! You knew before writing anything that that pen doesn't work!
But that's strange. Why did you have a pen that you knew didn't work?
A ballpoint pen that doesn't work?!
Hold on.
If Mr. Manaka was also using a pen that doesn't work,
then this dying message should be...
...blank!
Look! There's a strange mark left behind!
It looks like someone scribbled over the letters with a pen that didn't work!
What if that mark was left behind
because someone tried to cross out the letters beneath it,
but the pen didn't work?
Who is this boy?!
Aha! This wasn't written by Mr. Manaka at all!
It was written beforehand by none other than the killer!
But then why did he take the card in the first place?!
Simple.
The killer told the owner the following:
"Look at the card behind you!
The name of your murderer is on it!"
But the card had Kubota's name on it,
not the name of the killer!
Shocked, he tried to cross out the name
and replace it with the real one
using the ballpoint pen on the table.
But he couldn't.
That pen had been placed there in advance by the killer,
and it didn't work!
So that's why he threw the pen away and tried to crumple up the paper!
In short, this was all a trick to fool us,
perpetrated by the killer
using a pen without ink
and a video tape without sound!
But the pen we found does work.
Wasn't the tip of that pen retracted when we found it?
Yes, now that you mention it...
Strange for someone who's about to be killed
to go through all the trouble of retracting a pen's tip...
So the killer switched this pen
with the other one after the murder,
but carelessly forgot to put the pen tip out?
Which means whoever's currently in possession of a pen that doesn't work
is the one responsible!
In other words...
...it was you, Mr. Ochiai!
Let us hear your alibi.
Where were you at 4:30 when the murder took place?
Mr. Ochiai...
I was waiting to meet someone at 4:30.
Waiting for that black-hearted demon...
...while inside that suit of armor!
Everything that happened afterward
is exactly as you said, Detective.
Good thing everything was caught on tape!
That was no accident.
Having Mr. Manaka stand where he did, the timing,
the location of the card, the location of the pen...
They were all done according to my plan.
I practiced here on several occasions, you see.
Then the rumor about the security guards
seeing the suit of armor walking late at night was real?!
I felt it was a foolish thing to do,
but I did it for the purpose
of getting rid of Mr. Manaka,
the demon who was going to
shut down this divine museum
and take away from me all of these exhibits that are like my own children.
And then there was Kubota-kun,
who went and sold some of my exhibits.
I wanted to punish you as well.
It appears to be different from the picture. Mr. Ochiai.
It seems you've been struck down
by divine punishment as well.
No, it is exactly like the painting.
Although the knight of justice has slain the demon,
he has also been covered in its evil blood
which will soak into him
and make him wicked in turn.
No matter how you look at it, I am a murderer.
I, too, have become a demon.
The fact that I was unable to deceive the small knight of justice
is proof enough of this!
The small knight of justice?
Say, little boy. Do you not need to go to the restroom anymore?
Eh? The art museum's not going to close after all?
Nope. The citizens all got together after they heard what happened.
That's good. We don't have many cultural spots around here, after all.
I'm getting sick of this.
Sick of what, Genta-kun?
It's always Conan and that old man Kogoro!
We never get to help out at all!
Uh, that's because—
Oh yeah!
Have you heard the story at school
about the biology room skeleton coming to life at midnight?
Yeah, I've heard about that!
One of the teachers saw it!
But the heart was still...
OK! This is a case that calls for the Detective Boys!
Let's break into school later tonight!
Hey, now...
Conan! You better come too!
Give me a break!
NEXT EPISODE
60 seconds until the next episode's hint!
There's no doubt about it! He's the murderer!
But what's with that big smile?!
Just what sort of alibi does he have in that camera?!
Look! I took this!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Disposable Camera
You'll be stunned by the next episode's surprising trick!