My name's Conan Edogawa!
High school student Shin'ichi was forced to take a pill that shrunk him!
My mind is still that of a great detective, though!
Using my keen powers of deduction,
I solve every kind of case there is!
Today's case takes place during a spring festival!
Even if it's hidden behind the lens of a camera,
there is always only one truth!
We now go live to Saitama Prefecture's
Tenkaichi Night Festival.
The Tenkaichi Night Festival is famous for the bonfires
that spell out the word "Tenkaichi" on three separate mountains.
The lighting of the letters is about to begin!
Hey! Can't you look for it more quietly?!
Geez. Just when I thought you went to the festival,
you're already back here lookin' for your wallet or something...
Can't even take a nice, relaxin' bath.
You haven't forgotten about your promise for tonight, have you?!
Promise?
Come on! I came along because you said you'd celebrate with me—
What's with that get-up?
And what happened in here?
Sorry, but tonight's plans are cancelled.
After all, the person we would be honoring tonight...
Saitama prefecture's Tenkaichi Night Festival is now underway!
Look! The character for "Ten" has just been lit up on the mountain!
...is dead!
Nothing personal, Imatake.
Um, it sounded like there was a gunshot...
Hey!
Look! The last character, "Ichi", is lit up!
Did you know, Conan-kun?
At this festival, the characters for "Tenkaichi"
are lit up on three mountains in the hopes of a good harvest this year!
Almost entirely a copy of Kyoto's Daimonji festival...
Staying at an inn and going to a festival sure is nice!
It sure is! Don't you agree, Conan-kun?
Yeah.
If I didn't have that, that is.
I hate having her treat me like a kid!
Excuse me.
Could you take a picture for me?
Certainly!
Here's the camera...
Could you take it with that "Ichi" character behind me?
Ready? Here goes!
Go ahead!
A balloon got into the shot...
That's fine. Thanks.
I'm writing about the various festivals in this region.
That's what these pictures are for.
You're a writer?
You're so tan that I thought you might play sports or something...
I got this from work. I often go overseas, you see.
Oh, yes.
You can have this.
Are you sure?
Norikazu Sasai...
I used to write novels under
the penname of Tomokazu Imai.
I've heard of him!
I read a lot of his stuff in junior high!
That's strange.
I thought that Satoru Imatake used that name for his debut...
Imatake and I are old friends.
We used to write things together.
With the Satoru Imatake?!
We both came here today.
Thought we'd drink the night away
in celebration of his winning the Naomoto Award.
Sure is hot.
Take off your jacket if you're hot.
This would make a good picture!
Could you take a couple more shots for me?
Sure!
Norikazu Sasai-san?
Yes...
I'm Detective Yokomizo from the Saitama Police Department.
I'd like to ask you about Satoru Imatake-san.
Has something happened to him?
He's been murdered.
In the hotel room you were both staying in.
The murder weapon was a pistol.
The murder took place just 2 or 3 minutes after 8 PM.
The murderer was a young man.
He fled the room immediately afterward.
You're completely sure about all of this?
Yes. The TV coverage of the festival had just started...
Shot cleanly through the head...
Hey, what are you doing?!
I'm a detective...
Wait, aren't you the famous detective Kogoro Mouri-san?!
Yes, that would be me...
I read about those difficult cases that you solve all the time!
I'm glad to hear it...
I was the one who solved them all.
Please look around as you wish!
I'd be honored if you assisted me!
I see.
Huh?
What's this?
Toothpaste.
A toothbrush! Was the victim killed while brushing his teeth?
You're always getting in the way!
What do you think, Detective Mouri?
This smells greatly of a robbery.
A robbery?
Only the money has been removed from the victim's wallet.
Plus the perpetrator ransacked the room.
This was an ordinary crime done for monetary gain.
Judging from the fact that the victim fell near the front door,
most likely someone had knocked on the door
and shot him the instant he opened it.
But Detective Mouri!
What do you think about this?
The robbery was just a disguise;
the real killer was the room's other occupant!
Hey now, you can't be serious!
The murder took place around 8, right?
In which case, I have an alibi!
I was at the Tenkaichi Night Festival when it happened.
That's where I met Mouri-san and the others.
Isn't that right?
Yes.
But I believe it was during the last half of the festival that we met.
Come on! I was there from the very start!
If you think I'm lying...
...then have this developed.
It should prove that my alibi is real!
OK! Get this developed right away!
Yes, sir!
Detective Yokomizo is right.
This was no robbery!
The victim and the killer knew each other.
It's almost certainly him.
But what's with that big smile?!
Just what sort of alibi does
he have in that camera?!
Seven pictures in all.
But what do these have to do with his alibi?
I took this one!
See! It has Conan-kun's balloon in it!
That's right. We met Sasai-san
when the "Ichi" character was lit.
But it's past 8:40 when "Ichi" is lit.
The murder took place at 8:02 or 8:03.
I think you could make it to the festival grounds in 40 minutes
if you rushed by car.
Detective Yokomizo.
After the first character, "Ten", is lit at 8:00,
about how long does it continue to burn?
Usually until about 8:25 or so.
Have a look at this picture!
This proves that he was at the festival grounds before 8:25, at the latest.
The murder was at 8:00.
No matter how fast you drive,
it's impossible to go from here to the festival grounds in 25 minutes!
Congratulations. Your alibi is airtight.
Of course it is!
How can this be? How can that picture be there?!
Is photographic alteration out of the question?
Multiple exposures or something?
Someone good with cameras could easily—
Hey, now. I handed the camera directly over to you
and asked you to develop the film.
And besides, it was a disposable camera.
I could have done no such thing.
You were the one who developed the film, right?
Yes, sir!
There were no signs of the camera or film being tampered with!
See?
Come on, Detective Yokomizo.
You already knew he was at the festival.
Yes. I heard from the hotel's front desk
that Sasai-san left around 7:30.
They remembered because he was constantly asking the time.
That was because I wanted to make it in time for the "Ten" character.
As you can see, I forgot my watch today.
Something bugs me about everything you did!
It's almost as if you were trying to make an alibi...
Come on, now.
I would appreciate it if you would stop wasting time like this
and get to the real task at hand,
like finding out who killed my friend.
Imatake-sensei!
Sensei!
Where did he go?
If you're looking for Imatake-san's body,
he was taken down to the station.
Who might you be, anyway?
My name is Yamada, from the monthly magazine Literature Era.
I rushed here as soon as the police called me, but I guess he really is...
Literature Era? Didn't Imatake-san—
Yes, it published his "Heroic Sword Legend" series.
Wait, are you Sasai-sensei?!
Come to think of it,
Imatake did mention that his deadline was coming up soon
but he still wasn't done.
That's right! His deadline was tomorrow!
Oh no!
Even if I ask someone else to write something, there isn't enough time,
and nothing would ever be as good as his!
I guess I have no other choice.
Here.
What's this?
Something I wrote a while back.
Imatake kept bugging me to show it to him,
so I just happened to bring it with me today.
I doubt it compares with Imatake's series, though...
No, seeing as you used to worked with him,
I'm sure the editors will all be delighted!
Are you sure?
That's only the prologue to an especially long story.
We would be very grateful
if you would continue to write for Literature Era...
I don't know, I'm busy enough as it is already...
Can't I persuade you somehow?
Very well! I shall write for the late Imatake's sake!
Thank you! I have to be going now!
Hey, Detective.
You heard that, right?
It would seem I must hurry back home and get to work.
For Imatake, who was killed by some idiot who just wanted his money.
There's no question about it—he's the killer!
But he has an alibi.
How? How was he able to take that picture?!
What's more, the camera was untampered, and he had Ran use it.
A picture at 8:50 wouldn't serve as an alibi.
Darn it! There has to be something!
Something that will bring his alibi crumbling down!
Think back to when you met him!
Sorry, but I need to get going.
Not so fast!
That's right!
Sure is hot.
He didn't take his jacket off...
Or maybe he couldn't take it off!
Why not?!
Could you take a picture for me?
Here's the camera...
Could you take it with that "Ichi" character behind me?
Wait! I still want to talk to you!
You just never give up!
Keep harassing me and I'll sue!
Aha, so that's it!
Now I've got this trick figured out!
Just as I thought, he is the killer!
What's more, this was a premeditated murder!
I've got the trick behind his alibi photo completely figured out!
I better let the detective know before it's too late!
Whatever. I'm leaving now.
Not so fast!
I have to do something!
OK! Time for my secret weapon!
Now to set his pose...
...arrange the photographs on the desk...
...and then use this Voice-Altering Bow Tie to mimic his voice!
Yikes!
How many times do I have to tell you?!
I have photographic proof it wasn't me!
Please, Detective. Could you tell him how incompetent he is?
Incompetent he is.
You really disappoint me, Detective Yokomizo!
Mouri-san!
I kept quiet so you could have all of the credit,
yet you were still fooled by the trick
used to make that alibi photograph!
So then he is—
Yes.
The one who killed Mr. Satoru Imatake is none other than...
...the one standing next to you—Norikazu Sasai!
Wait just a minute!
Weren't you the one who said this was a robbery?!
I said that so you would lower your guard.
I knew from the very instant I saw the victim
that the murderer was an acquaintance of his.
Based on what?
The toothpaste foam in the victim's mouth.
His toothbrush was also lying on the ground near him.
In other words, the victim was brushing his teeth
before he was shot!
So? Everyone brushes their teeth.
Yes.
But it's not very common for people to open the front door for strangers
while still brushing their teeth, now is it?
One more thing—this room's condition.
The murderer fled immediately after the gunshot.
Do you think it would be possible to ransack this entire room
in such a short amount of time?
Most likely it was done purposely before the murder
to make it look like an ordinary robbery.
I see.
All of the evidence at the scene of the crime seems to point to me.
But I have an alibi.
How do you explain that photograph?
This is most likely a picture that you took
when you came to a previous festival.
You then held on to the camera until today's festival,
where you ran into Ran and had her continue taking more pictures.
Although it was an extremely simple trick,
the fact that you were wearing the exact same clothes
made it easy to mistake it
for a picture you took today!
That's right!
The reason you endured the heat
and kept your jacket on
was because you didn't want to look any different than in the 1st photo!
Am I wrong?
What a splendid sense of imagination, Detective Mouri!
But do you have any proof that I took
that picture at a previous festival?!
Why, yes, I do!
What?!
Look! It's right here in this picture! Your-
Hey, you!
Don't be bothering Dad!
Dad?
Oh no!
I leave the rest to you, Detective Yokomizo.
Right.
His wrist?
As you can see, I forgot my watch today.
What are you doing?!
How do you explain this?
Your wrist is perfectly tan in your alibi photograph!
Yet your wrist is white now!
The truth is that you took this picture one year ago!
Isn't that right, Sasai-san?!
I concede defeat, Detective.
I decided to get rid of Imatake one year ago!
I wanted to take his place at the top of the literary world!
Yes. One year ago, it was decided that my work
would be published as a series in Literature Era.
But right before the deadline,
the editors switched to Imatake instead!
Simply because he had a better reputation than I.
I saw that series as my last
chance to make it as a writer.
But then he had to go and snatch it away,
almost as if he was ridiculing me!
So then you killed him?
Yes. I killed him.
Miss.
About Imatake's work that won the Naomoto Award...
We both thought up the story for it
back when Imatake and I used to write together.
Though I suppose nobody would believe me now.
Excellent detective work, Detective Mouri!
It was all thanks to you
that we were able to solve the case
and arrest Sasai!
Case? Arrest? Sasai?
Oh, stop pretending!
Uh oh!
I always knew Sasai was the killer...
...I just wasted time to make filler!
Get it?!
Keep laughing!
NEXT EPISODE
60 seconds until the next episode's hint!
Why aren't you going in?
You have business in there, don't you?
You went out with Shin'ichi?!
,The lock has marks on it from being tampered with...
It's a kidnapping, isn't it?
I've finally found you, Shin'ichi...
Shin'ichi! Come out this instant!
I know you're in there!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Video Game
Even next time, there is always one truth!