My name's Conan Edogawa!
High school student Shin'ichi was forced
to take a drug that shrunk him.
Although smaller, my mind
remains that of a sharp detective!
Today's case is a code!
A deep meaning behind regular numbers!
I'll have to change
my way of looking at things!
There's always only one truth!
Created by
Gosho Aoyama
"Detective Conan"
Serialized in Shogakukan's
"Weekly Shonen Sunday"
Planning
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Character Design
Masatomo Sudo
Art Director
Yukihiro Shibutani
Art Design
Hiroyuki Mitsumoto
Directors of Photography
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Ogawa
Sound Director
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
Music Producer
Hiroki Horio
(PolyGram)
Music
Katsuo Ono
Opening Theme
"Mune ga doki-doki"
(Kitty Enterprises)
Performed by
Lyrics
Music
Arrangement
THE HIGH-LOWS
Hiroto Komoto/Masatoshi Mashima
Ending Theme
"Step by Step"
(Mercury Music Entertainment)
Performed by
Lyrics
Music
Arrangement
ZIGGY
Juichi Morishige
Editor
Teramitsu Okada
(JAY FILM)
Story Editor
Jun'ichi Iioka
Color Key
Reiko Hirayama
Associate Producer
Satoshi Kojima
Planning Support
Toyohiko Okuyama
Mitome Asai
Director
Kenji Kodama
Producers
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Kazuhiko Yagiuchi
(Tokyo Movie)
Masahito Yoshioka
There's some! Now!
Got 'em!
They got away again...
We sure caught a lot!
Yeah...
Genta-kun was right—
this is a good spot for fishing!
I'm hungry. What time is it?
It's exactly 1:00.
What do you say we have lunch?
Hey, what's that?
Looks like a remote-controlled boat.
Where's it being controlled from?
A rifle!
Up there! There are people
on the building across the river!
Come on, Conan! Let me see!
There's nobody up there...
Did this guy really shoot it with a rifle?!
Dang! He shot the balloon from way up here?!
He's really good if he did!
Maybe he was doing target practice?
That, or he was being tested...
Tested?
Against his own will.
Against his own will?!
Two other guys were pointing handguns at him!
You serious?!
What are you doing?
Looking for any sort of evidence...
What's with those numbers?
I'm guessing it's a message
the rifle shooter left for me.
Message?
Yes. He seemed to notice me when
I saw him through the binoculars.
But what in the world could
these numbers mean?
At any rate, we need to tell
Inspector Megure about this!
Are you certain that he hit it from here?
Yeah. I didn't see him shoot,
but I saw him holding the rifle.
And then you found that calculator left behind?
Say, Inspector.
Do you think that maybe he was
kidnapped and then brought here?
It did look like he was forced
to shoot against his own will...
We haven't received any such reports...
And I don't see any signs
of them being here, either...
What? Then look harder!
Like across the river, or in it!
The bullet has to be there somewhere!
Yeah! That radio-controlled boat might be—
Unfortunately, this is Golden Week.
Most of our investigators
are out on holiday leave!
But I'll tell you what. I'll at least
check out that calculator. How's that?
Well, I'll see you later.
Give Mouri-kun my regards!
He doesn't believe us one bit!
"Romantic dream trip aboard
the Heisei Expressway"?!
All they did was steal an old photo!
It's hopeless! I can't figure this out!
Of course you can't. There is no message.
Someone just forgot their calculator, that's all.
I can't believe you called Inspector Megure
out there during Golden Week!
Dad!
Say, if that person really was
forced to do target practice
and then left you a message,
all I can think of is...
The time or place where
the real shooting will take place,
or the victim's name...
Or a hint about where he's being held.
People play code games on their
pagers all the time! Number games!
So since 3135134 can also be read
as a couple of Japanese names,
that means the victims are
going to be 31-san and 51-san?
Sure, whatever.
Say, 162 might be an apartment
or hotel room number!
Or maybe a road?
Like Route 162, you know?!
So then what's the 3135134 stand for?
Maybe it was to camouflage the 162
in case the bad guys found the calculator.
I see. Come to think of it,
the river was shaped like a road...
And the flow of the river
resembles a flow of cars.
Route 162...
Kyoto!
Too far. It would at least
have to be in the Tokyo region.
It would have to be a
primary municipal highway.
Here it is! Saitama Prefectural Route 162!
You found it, Conan-kun!
Here it is, Dad!
You can take us tomorrow!
Take you? What now?!
Why did I have to rent a car
and drive you around again?!
Because we don't have licenses!
Hey, he's a detective, right?
So why doesn't he have a car of his own?
He can't afford one!
It sounds like he doesn't usually drive much.
We'd better put our seatbelts on!
Hey, you! I'll have you know—
Keep your eyes on the road!
The curves are shaped differently.
This isn't the place!
This isn't it!
This isn't it either!
Doesn't look like this is it either...
This isn't it.
Why don't you give up already?
You're crazy if you think the shape
of the river will match a street.
What? You were the one who said
the river flowed like a flow of cars!
Did I now?
No more curves to check, I take it?
I'll just turn around up here and—
Under construction...
Stop the car!
Conan-kun?
Aha!
This building's on Route 162 too!
This is the place!
You're right!
It's definitely it!
Way to go, Conan!
What? You found it?!
Conan-kun wants you to
tell Inspector Megure.
Why me?
Because you have a good track record,
plus he trusts you!
A good track record? You sure know
about hard-to-understand things!
Oh well, guess I'll give him a ring!
Megure here—
Oh, Mouri-kun! Perfect timing!
Come to the police headquarters right away!
And bring Conan-kun with you!
There is only one reason why
I've asked you to come here.
We've learned that one of our officers
on vacation and his girlfriend
have gone missing.
This man.
This is the guy, Inspector!
I thought so.
The fingerprints on the calculator
matched his when we checked.
His name is Koichi Yamabe.
He used to be an Olympic marksman.
A marksman?!
The kidnappers probably took
Yamabe and his girlfriend, Eri-san,
and are threatening to kill her
if he doesn't shoot someone for them.
So what Conan-kun and the others saw
was target practice for that?
Looks like your deductions hit the mark!
But our hands are still tied since we
don't know the most important facts:
when and where it will happen...
We know where!
Come again?!
Yes, it's very similar, indeed.
It looks like this is the place.
Excellent work!
Um, don't forget that I was
the one who drove them here!
But we still don't know
when the attack will be...
Yes, that's too bad...
It was around 1 PM when the balloon burst, right?
Is that so? Then 1:00 must
be the time of the attack!
But on what day?
They're keeping two people captive!
They don't have time to waste!
The sniper attack will probably be tomorrow!
Good thinking, Mouri-kun!
Let's make preparations at once!
What's the matter, Conan-kun?
Oh, nothing...
Does this 162 really refer to Route 162?
If it were me, I would make sure to put
the place and time in the message...
Which means...
No...
No matter how I look at it,
the 3135134 still makes no sense!
Alright now. Don't make a move
until I give the order.
Roger that!
Understood!
We have police snipers and a
helicopter on standby at the river.
All preparations are complete.
If the sniper's going to strike at 1:00,
then the criminals should
appear by 12:00 at the latest.
One hour left...
But would you mind explaining why—
They insisted on coming along!
You guys aren't to leave this van!
Well?!
We know!
M-My ears...
Thirty minutes left...
Something's not right!
Why aren't they showing up?!
Maybe Conan-kun is wrong?
What?!
Of course he isn't!
No, that has to be it!
It was a mistake to listen to some stupid kid!
Dad!
Let's see...
It was 3135134162, right?
3, 1, 3, 5, 1, 3, 4...
Mitsuhiko! Let me see that!
Okay...
That's it! Now I see!
You have it upside-down, Conan-kun...
Oh, wow!
You can read the numbers even
when you flip the calculator over! Cool!
What nonsense is this now?
See! 162 becomes 291!
And the rest looks like English letters!
Let me see that.
291, Heisei E...
They are readable...
Heisei E? Wait, I could swear
I've seen that somewhere before...
It was in the magazine
you were looking at yesterday!
The Heisei Express!
Wait, then that means this message
was meant to be read upside-down!
Meaning that the 162 actually
means the 29th at 1:00!
What?!
Yamabe-san must have realized
this upside-down trick
where he was being held
and tried to leave us this message
when he got the chance!
Inspector! Hurry! The helicopter!
Oh, right!
Heisei Express will be departing
from Platform 2 shortly.
Thank you!
Excuse me!
Yes?
Sit down before the train starts, Daddy!
OK, I will...
It's going just as we planned.
He's sitting in the very front of the first car!
It's time.
Huh? Where's Conan-kun?!
Eh?! Don't tell me he's—
What? When did you get in here?!
It doesn't matter! We won't
make it in time if we don't hurry!
Fine, whatever. Put this on!
Too big!
There's the Kanetsu Line!
OK! Follow the tracks north!
Three minutes left...
We still haven't found a curve
that looks like the river!
Here it comes.
Try any funny business and the girl's dead.
One minute left!
Inspector! There!
There they are! Get us lower!
W-What the...
Who cares! Just shoot it down!
Bastard!
Stop or she's dead!
Don't shoot! You might hit Yamabe!
Yes, sir!
There's no wind! The helicopter's speed
is 5 meters per second!
Medium setting should do the trick!
Distance: 30 meters!
Go!
Got 'im!
What're you doing?! That's dangerous!
Damn it!
Damn you!
It's all over! Give yourself up!
Koichi-san!
Eri!
What a stroke of luck that this
helmet just happened to hit him!
Here you are. Don't drop it
on the way back, now!
I won't!
Man, was that close...
You're OK! That's great!
Hey, Conan! That wasn't fair,
you get all the fun!
It isn't nice to hog all the glory!
Conan-kun!
Sorry!
Huh?
Conan! No more sneaking off
without permission!
He got you that time!
Why, you little...
The men we arrested were former members
of the Oni Tora crime ring.
Last year, the leader and various
high-ranking officials in the ring
were all put behind bars
by a skilled public prosecutor.
The remaining members were forced to disband.
So it was that prosecutor they were after?
He was on his way home
from a trip with his family.
Revenge was their motive.
But you did a spectacular job, Mouri-kun!
I don't think I did—
—that bad, myself!
They're acting like he
solved it all by himself.
But I'm sure he'll take us on
vacation somewhere now!
Where would you want to go, Conan-kun?
That's easy! An amusement park!
Boy, it sure is hard to
constantly act like a kid!
NEXT EPISODE
Next episode's hint right after this!
It's a dead body!
It's gone! The corpse is gone!
It's disappeared!
That's impossible!
Let's go, everyone.
Wait, Inspector! We really saw—
I was a fool to believe you!
No, the body is here!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Answering Machine Phone
Don't let the next episode's trick knock you off your feet!