My name's Conan Edogawa!
High school student Shin'ichi was
forced to take a drug that shrunk him!
Although smaller, my mind remains
that of a sharp detective!
Today's is a ransom case!
Money won't buy love!
Even if the evidence is underwater,
there's always only one truth!
It's almost time. Don't push it, now.
The hostage's safety is the most important.
I can hardly believe this is Mr. Takei's daughter...
Hello?!
Do you have the money?
I do!
Let Naoko go!
Hold on. I'll let you see her.
The kidnapper's showed up
in a minivan, Inspector!
It stopped nearby!
Naoko!
I'll bring the money now.
Wait. There are policemen hiding here.
The deal is off.
Wait!
They're running away!
Let's go!
The car never braked
and flew right into the water.
So you were classmates
with the kidnapped Naoko Takei?
Yes.
Naoko Takei...
She always looked so lonely...
But there's no way she could've survived this...
Inspector!
We couldn't find her body at the river bottom either.
The river runs fast in this area,
so she may have been taken downstream...
Oh no!
What do you mean, her body?!
I left everything up to you because
I thought I could trust the police!
And then you screwed everything up!
Give her back! Give Naoko back!
If the minivan fell front-first,
then why is only the side window broken?
A hammer!
Conan! Not again!
Sorry!
You lousy kid!
I can no longer trust the police!
So I would like you to catch the one responsible.
Understood.
My secretary Hanai-kun will give you the details.
I'm Akiko Hanai.
Could you explain the circumstances
under which she was kidnapped?
Circumstances?
Naoko-chan and I were supposed to see a movie that day,
so I went to meet her.
But hours passed and she never showed up.
So you grew worried and contacted the police?
No. I realized it was a kidnapping
when the kidnapper called my cell phone.
The kidnapper warned you
not to tell the police, I assume?
I immediately told Mr. Takei...
It was all my fault. If only I hadn't suggested seeing a movie!
Ran.
Do you have any ideas about who the kidnapper may be?
I wouldn't have hired you if I did!
Then let me put it another way.
Do you know anyone who may hold a grudge against you?
Pardon my rudeness, but you are an infamous corporate raider.
Are you sure you haven't made a lot of enemies in your time?
The old man's finally getting better at this!
I don't remember every single thing!
Listen! Business is war!
The losers are the ones at fault!
Got that?!
Ugh! He backs down too easy!
Akiko-san's room was on the second floor, right?
Well? How's Akiko-san?
Dad...
Naoko really thought of Akiko-san as an older sister.
She said that she was also like a mother to her,
since her real mother had died when she was young.
Akiko-san.
Akiko-san!
Hey...
Oh, it's you two...
Are you alright? We called out to you a couple times...
I'm sorry. I damaged my hearing a bit...
Huh? She's—
Have you given up on Naoko-chan too?
She's alive! I just know it!
But they've looked this hard
and still haven't found her...
She's probably—
That poor woman...
That's it!
Ran-neechan! Let's take a look over there!
What for?
Somebody might've seen it!
That day?
Did anything out of the ordinary happen?
You can say that. The police asked us to help with their investigation.
All the ships in this area helped 'em.
All of them?
Yeah. It's the sailors' code to work together when something happens.
Not that guy with the speedboat, though...
Speedboat?
Yeah, it almost ran straight into my boat, here...
Probably some rich guy who goes around sailing with other rich guys.
What kind of speedboat was it?!
Is this the speedboat he was talking about?
Conan-kun! Don't get on without permission!
Diving equipment?
Both the kidnapper and
Naoko Takei may still be alive!
That was no accident—
the kidnapper drove off on purpose.
As a means of escape!
The kidnapper broke the side window with a hammer
that was placed in the car in advance,
swam underwater to the opposite shore,
and got into a waiting speedboat!
The culprit then escaped
while the police were focusing their attention on the minivan.
Why would they do that?
Probably to confuse the police into thinking
that both kidnapper and the hostage had died.
There could be other reasons, too...
The only thing I don't understand is about the hostage, Naoko Takei.
Her body hasn't turned up.
We only found enough scuba diving equipment for one person.
How did the kidnapper get her out of the sunken car?
Or was she never in it at all?
No, she was seen inside it!
Conan-kun!
Ran-neechan! Did you find anything out?
According to the manager here,
the boat's owner simply abandoned it
and it hasn't been used since.
Maybe that man mistook it for another boat...
That can't be!
But how do I prove this!
The investigation is canceled?!
What for? What's going on?!
Don't look at me. He was the one who decided to cancel it!
I'd like to know why, myself!
Rich people are stingy, after all.
He probably regrets wasting money
on his dead daughter now.
No! She's not dead at all!
And how do you know that?
Um, well...
I think so too!
I don't want to believe that Naoko's dead!
Ugh. Kids can be so pampered sometimes.
Listen. It's obvious once you think about it with a cool head.
Given the circumstances,
neither the hostage nor the kidnapper can possibly be alive.
But!
But you know,
by doing this, he's basically insulting your reputation as a great detective.
You have a point there!
Alright, then!
Leave!
My daughter—Naoko—is dead!
There's no bringing her back now!
But!
This is what you want, isn't it?!
Your cancellation fee.
Take it and get out!
I don't want your lousy money! You can keep it!
Ran! Let's go!
Damn it! That old fogy really knows how to piss me off!
Oh, I just remembered...
What?
I promised to meet my friends...
See ya!
Bah. That spoiled little kid has it easy.
His attitude changed too quickly!
Leave!
There's no mistake about it!
The kidnapper must've contacted him!
Are you just going to let Naoko-chan die?!
Mr. Takei!
If you don't really gather all the money this time,
she might be killed!
But we don't even know if she's alive or not—
Mr. Takei! Have a look for yourself!
Even in the picture the kidnapper sent us,
the newspaper has yesterday's date!
I thought so.
Naoko-chan believes with all her heart that you'll save her!
Mr. Takei!
If I gather the 500 million now and then lose it in another stupid mistake,
my latest business deal will go up in smoke!
Don't you see?!
Money or Naoko-chan? Which is more important?!
Naoko, of course!
But if this deal falls through, my company will go—
—bankrupt. There's no question about that.
Who cares about the company?
It won't replace Naoko-chan's life!
But I built this company with my own two hands!
Yeah, by sucking the lifeblood out of other people!
Shut up!
Corporate raiding is a perfectly legitimate business!
Weak people lose! And the losers have no one to blame but themselves!
That damn old man!
Who's there?!
Why, you little!
Conan-kun!
I was looking for the bathroom—
This is private property, boy!
Please don't tell anyone about this, Conan-kun.
If the police found out, Naoko-chan would be killed for sure this time!
Okay.
We can't afford to let him leave here for a while!
Lock him in your room or something!
Sorry about this, Conan-kun.
Try to endure it for a short while.
Once the deal is over, I promise we'll let you out.
Say, what did the kidnapper tell you guys?
The same as before.
"Prepare 500 million yen by tomorrow."
Are you going to pay?
You saw what kind of person Mr. Takei is...
He'll get the money if Naoko-san is important to him, right?
Money is the only thing important to him!
What's wrong?
I had a younger brother named Masahito.
"Had"?
Yes. He died, four years ago.
No, he was murdered.
He was still about your age.
I'm sorry. Let me hold you for a while.
I'll bring some dinner later.
Do you think you can fool the kidnapper
with these wads of cash made out of newspaper?
Quiet. This is the only choice left!
Conan-kun!
What are you doing?! Let's go!
Now that I think about it,
nobody's actually seen Naoko Takei's face!
Her mouth was taped and she had a blindfold on...
...there was no way to see her face clearly!
The kidnapper was the only person
ever inside the minivan!
Yes! One person played the role of two!
Nobody once doubted that it was Naoko.
It's not unreasonable—she was far away,
and everyone just assumed it was her.
Wait. There are policemen hiding here.
The deal is off.
The kidnapper was completely aware
of what the police were up to!
It's only natural!
The kidnapper was always right by Takei-san, after all!
The diving watch mark on her arm...
Her tan line from wearing a wetsuit...
And then what she did that one time!
An ear-unplugging technique
that every diver knows about!
She must've injured her ears
when she suddenly entered the water!
What's going on?! It's long past our agreed time!
The kidnapper is here. Has been for a while.
What are you doing, you idiot?!
You made me sprain my ankle!
That's nothing.
Compared to the pain
you gave my family, anyway.
Come again?!
You don't remember this place?
These are the remains of a company that you took hostile control over.
What?! You don't mean that you're—
That's right!
I'm the daughter of the former company director here.
My father killed himself, and he took his wife and son with him...
Leaving only me behind...
I was a college student at the time.
I was taken in by some relatives, changed my last name,
and then joined your company.
To wait for a chance to get revenge, of course.
If you had loved Naoko-chan enough to simply get the money ready,
I had intended to let you live!
What are you planning to do?!
Have you die.
Gasoline?!
This is bad!
Wait, I apologize! I'll pay as much as you want!
Just don't do it!
Take your money with you to hell.
Farewell.
No! Don't do it!
Conan-kun!
There's no value in killing that man!
There's no value in letting him live!
It's my duty to rid the world of him!
Do you want Naoko-san to think the same way about you?!
That man is her only family!
You should know more than anyone else
the pain of having your entire family die!
Even if you did get revenge, I don't think your brother would be happy.
Conan-kun...
Masahito...
Naoko Takei was being held in the basement of the old factory.
She was rescued safely.
Apparently, she was somewhat aware of the situation
when she was first confined.
Naoko! You're safe!
Akiko-san!
I'm so sorry I got you involved, Naoko-chan.
Thank you!
We still can't say anything for sure.
If he really attacked for no reason as she says,
then he'll probably have to be put to sleep.
Please come back, Shin'ichi...
You're the only one who can save John!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Conditioned reflex
Conditioned reflex
Next time...
John, dinnertime! Stay...