My name's Conan Edogawa!
High school student Shin'ichi was
forced to take a drug that shrunk him!
Although smaller, my mind remains
that of a sharp detective!
Today's case is about John the dog!
He's a shepherd dog known
throughout the neighborhood!
Dogs may not speak,
but there's always only one truth!
John!
Hey, John!
Come here, John!
Here he comes!
John's so cute!
I wonder how old he is now?
He was still just a puppy when I was a kid,
so I'd say around 8 or so...
What're you talking about, Conan?
Never mind!
That was close!
John. I'm not high school student Shin'ichi Kudo anymore,
I'm grade school student Conan Edogawa now.
Oh, it's you!
Hello!
We're back!
I don't mind at all!
Come on in!
OK!
It's been so long since we ate out!
That restaurant was pretty good!
Hey, this is the place!
The house where John the dog lives!
I know this house!
When we were in grade school,
Shin'ichi used to stop by here
on his way home from school.
He would save some bread from lunch
and then give it to the dog!
Masayoshi Sakaguchi?
I've heard that name somewhere before...
He says he's a lawyer.
Oh, that's right.
He's a famous lawyer who specializes in cases involving minors.
Hey, Dad.
Wasn't this the house where that middle school student killed himself
when I was in third grade?
What was that?!
Hey! What's going on?!
What happened?!
The dog!
What happened to John?!
He jumped at Takeshi!
Conan-kun!
Hey, you!
You're in the way! Get out of here!
John! It's me!
That tickles, John!
Hello? What's going on, Takeshi-kun?!
Hello?!
It's me, Conan!
Eh? Conan-kun?!
Where are you now?!
I'm in Izu on business.
I just heard Takeshi-kun scream—what happened?!
Come home right away!
John's done something terrible!
The victim was Takeshi Maehara-san,
22 years old.
He's a college student who lives
in the apartment complex next door,
and Sakaguchi-san asked him
to watch the place while he was gone?
That's right...
And Takeshi-san invited you,
Sanae Sugita-san, over.
Now then, could you give us the details
about what exactly happened?
Okay...
It was around 8:00 when I came over.
I've never been in such a huge living room!
Aren't you glad you came?
Super glad!
Oh no!
It was just getting fun!
Sakaguchi residence.
Oh, Sakaguchi-san.
Yes, everything's fine.
Eh? John?
He's at the top of the stairs, behaving himself.
Eh? You want to talk to John?
Sure!
John! Hey, John!
Alright, whatever.
Here, your master wants to talk to you.
And then we showed up...
But why would the dog suddenly attack?
I don't know!
I can only think that he attacked Takeshi for no reason at all!
No way! John would never attack anyone for no reason!
But Takeshi didn't do anything!
What's going to happen to the dog, Inspector?
I can't say anything for sure yet,
but if he really attacked for no reason as she says,
then he'll probably have to be put to sleep.
Put to sleep? You're going to kill him?!
At any rate, we first need to talk to Sakaguchi-san...
"First year middle school student kills himself."
"Was bullying the cause?"
"...a classmate that bullied Masato-kun—"
It doesn't give the bully's name!
John's been well trained,
and he'd never attack anyone for no reason at all.
Wait a minute!
John attacked the victim immediately
after the phone was put to his ear.
What if Sakaguchi-san ordered
John to attack over the phone?!
But Sakaguchi-san always seems so nice;
he'd never do such a thing!
Where's John, Inspector?!
You didn't put him to sleep already, did you?!
Don't worry!
He's been taken to the police station for now;
it hasn't been decided that he's to be put to sleep yet.
So, Inspector. What did Sakaguchi-san say?
He says he can't believe that John would attack anyone.
Neither can I! There must be a reason why—
You keep quiet!
Please continue, Inspector.
I asked Mr. Sakaguchi about his phone conversation...
To start off, what exactly did you say to the victim over the phone?
I asked him if everything was alright,
how John was doing,
and then I asked him to put John on the line.
Why did you do that?
I always say good night to him,
so I thought I'd say it tonight too.
So you told John good night?
Before that, I think I asked,
"How are you doing, John?"
Then suddenly I heard John bark
and Takeshi-kun scream...
Sakaguchi-san didn't say anything else?
There's no mistake about it.
The girl who was there confirmed his story.
You mentioned it last night,
didn't you, Ran-neechan?
That Sakaguchi-san's son committed suicide a long time ago.
Oh. Yeah...
I asked him about that at the station too.
He said a bully drove him to do it...
Maybe his son's bully was Takeshi Maehara-kun?!
But it's still just a "maybe."
I thought so.
I heard this directly from Mr. Sakaguchi himself.
His son Masato-kun and Takeshi Maehara-kun
were classmates in middle school.
Masato-kun apparently wrote about Takeshi-kun in his diary
shortly before hanging himself in his room.
I hear that Mr. Sakaguchi loathed Takeshi-kun after reading the diary.
Since his wife had died early on,
Masato-kun was all he had left.
But when he saw Takeshi-kun crying and apologizing at the funeral,
he decided to forgive him.
Takeshi-kun was the only one
who bullied Masato-kun?
It would seem so.
Shortly after, Takeshi-kun moved to Kansai
because of his father's job.
Then, two years ago, he moved back to attend a university in Tokyo.
It was this spring that he moved into an apartment complex
right next to the Sakaguchi residence.
It truly was an act of fate.
Apparently Mr. Sakaguchi was surprised by the unexpected reunion, too.
But he no longer bore any
ill feelings toward Takeshi-kun.
I'm even told that he sometimes invited him over for dinner.
But if he really does still have
a grudge against Takeshi-kun...
What are you trying to say?
Mr. Sakaguchi secretly trained John to attack people
when a specific phrase is said to him!
And then last night, he said that phrase to John over the phone!
How are you doing, John?
In this way, Mr. Sakaguchi accomplished his revenge!
Wrong.
How come?
Have you forgotten?
When I questioned him last night,
he repeated what he said on the phone,
right in front of John.
John didn't react one bit when he heard him.
Gah! I thought I sounded so authoritative too!
Don't feel so down in the dumps, Mouri-kun!
Masato...
Thanks for coming, Conan-kun!
I thought you might be lonely without John to keep you company!
Thanks!
Say, does John always sleep at the top of the stairs?
Yeah, he does.
Why doesn't he sleep downstairs?
See that door there?
Yeah.
That was my son's room.
He absolutely loved John.
But his late mother said
he couldn't let the dog in his room,
so John always slept in front of his door.
John's still waiting for him to open the door
and say good morning to him!
Even though it's been eight years
since my son died...
That's a big phone over there.
The receiver's connected to it by a cord...
Say, wasn't there a cordless phone there last night?
Yes. I sometimes switch it with the phone in my study.
Why do you ask?
No reason!
This guy really did—
Wait a minute!
The clock must've struck 9:00 just before it happened!
That's it!
Now I see how Sakaguchi-san ordered John to attack!
The phone was different?
Yeah.
The receiver on the big phone
is connected by a cord.
But last night he had a cordless phone there, he said.
I wonder why?
Why? There's probably no real reason—
No, there is a reason.
Sakaguchi-san absolutely needed it to be a cordless phone!
What do you mean?
Listen. It would be impossible to carry a regular phone up a staircase!
So Sakaguchi-san purposely placed a portable cordless phone
in the living room!
So you still think that Sakaguchi-san
used John to commit a murder?
I'm absolutely certain of it now!
But I don't know the most important thing—
how he ordered the attack!
Hey, our clock doesn't chime, does it?
The clock in Sakaguchi-san's living room
chimes real loud every hour.
His clock?!
Come to think of it,
it was precisely 9:00 when John attacked Takeshi-kun!
I've figured it out!
The great detective, Kogoro Mouri, has just solved the mystery!
"Beika Police Station"
What in the world are you going to do?!
Just a little test.
When I give the word,
repeat what you said to John last night on the phone!
Okay...
Okay, Sakaguchi-san!
Right.
How are you doing, John?
Louder!
How are you doing, John?!
This can't be!
Were my deductions all wrong?!
I was so certain of it!
You overanalyzed things, Dad.
He would never use the dog
that his son loved to get revenge...
I can't say anything for certain,
but what we found out from our investigation afterwards
was that Sakaguchi-san supposedly took John somewhere in his car
every Sunday for the last three months.
According to him, he took John
to the outskirts of town
and let him get a lot of exercise in the empty fields.
Inspector! He obviously trained John during those times!
But there's no proof.
And I'm sorry to have to say this,
but it's been decided that John is to be put to sleep tomorrow evening.
What?!
Orders from above.
Mr. Sakaguchi understands as well.
Shin'ichi...
Where are you?!
John, the dog you liked so much,
is going to be killed if we don't do something!
Please come back, Shin'ichi!
You're the only one who can save John!
So they're going to kill John this evening?!
That's horrible!
Can't we do something?!
I was up all night thinking about it too, you know!
But...
Alright! Next!
On your mark!
Get set!
That's it!
I've finally figured it out!
What do you think he figured out?
No idea...
What now?!
I'd like to have another test.
On your mark...
Hello?
Get set!
Now say the words, if you would!
You got me!
So you admit you trained John
to attack Takeshi Maehara-kun?!
He didn't remember anything!
He didn't remember me, or Masato!
Yes!
He had completely forgotten about
the very person he drove to suicide!
And then he unwittingly moved into
the apartment complex next to you...
I'm a lawyer who specializes
in crimes committed by minors!
I took this job so that I could help
young people who lost their way!
So when I saw him crying and apologizing at the funeral 8 years ago,
I decided to forgive him!
He was still just a 1st-year middle school student,
and I felt that Masato's death wouldn't be in vain
if he truly regretted it with all his heart!
But when I met him again 8 years later,
he didn't remember a single thing about the incident!
Not only that, he was no different than he was eight years ago!
Give me my wallet back!
I'm just borrowing it!
Stop worrying! I'll pay you back one of these days, when I feel like it!
Who knows when that'll be, though...
When I saw that, I could feel my blood boil!
What was Masato's death for?!
Why did I ever forgive him?!
So then you used John—
That's right!
I decided that if the law couldn't deal with him,
then I would take justice into my own hands!
And I'm sure that John was happy that he avenged Masato too!
That's horrible!
You weren't the only one who was sad when Masato-kun died!
Do you have any idea how sad John was?!
You said so yourself!
Even now, John still waits for Masato-kun in front of his door!
Do you honestly think that Masato-kun would be happy
that you used his loyal dog to kill someone?!
Sakaguchi-san. Bullying is definitely wrong.
And I actually do understand your ill will toward Takeshi Maehara-kun.
But did you ever once think about the feelings of the dog
you stupidly used as a murder tool to get revenge?
John's feelings?
Here you go, John.
Oh, John!
Sakaguchi-san.
John is saying that he still cares for you, even now.
Please try to understand that feeling.
John!
Forgive me, John!
So they didn't kill John?!
That's right!
He was taken in by one of Sakaguchi-san's relatives!
That's great!
And it's all thanks to Kogoro Mouri, the great detective!
But John doesn't live at that house anymore, huh?
That's too bad. We really liked him a lot...
You can always make friends with another dog!
See? Look at that one!
It looks just like John!
It does! Let's go!
Yeah!
You appear to have quite an exceptional dog, Miss.
Actually, I'm a dog-lover myself...
What do you say we talk about dogs at that coffee shop over there?!
No, thanks...
Don't say that!
Come on!
Sic 'im, boy!
Go get him!
Go start a relationship with a dog instead.
You two took a bath together?!
Yeah!
That sure was fun, scrubbing each other's back!
A nosebleed? The bath must've rushed the blood to your head.
I'm dead if she finds out who I really am!
No question about it!
When you commit suicide,
you raise the gun like this and—
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: A gun
Next time too, will you know the culprit from just Part 1?