My name's Conan Edogawa!
High school student Shin'ichi was
forced to take a drug that shrunk him!
Although smaller, my mind remains
that of a sharp detective!
Today's case is the continuation
of a reunion murder case!
Let's listen to "Mune ga doki-doki"
as we review the last episode!
The old man's college buddies had a reunion at the hot spring resort, "Benkei".
The attendees were the club manager, Yumi Horikoshi,
the model shop owner, Jun Omura,
the high school gym instructor, Yukio Ayashiro,
his wife, Noriko Ayashiro,
the Chiba Prefectural police detective, Kazushi Nakamichi,
and then me, Ran, and the old man.
We went to wake up Yumi Horikoshi,
who was still in her room after the fireworks show ended,
only to find that she had committed suicide
by shooting herself in the head!
A makeshift autopsy showed that she had died seven hours earlier—
at around 3:00 PM, when everyone was playing ping-pong
before leaving for the fireworks show!
Kogoro's Reunion Murder Case
(Part 2)
Come to think of it, she did say something...
I really wish I were dead...
She must've been serious!
Say, how did Yumi-san shoot herself in the head?
What are you talking about, Conan-kun?!
Don't ask strange questions!
How?!
Isn't it obvious?
She put the gun up to her head like so and—
Wait! Mouri! What is it?!
Mouri!
Tell me, Nakamichi.
Normally when someone commits suicide with a gun,
they stick the barrel against their head, right?
Yes...
Then her bullet wound is missing something vital.
You're right! Burn marks!
Yes.
When you shoot a gun,
a stream of hot air accompanies the bullet!
If you shoot with the gun against your head,
it would have to leave burn marks behind!
The fact that there are none here means...
...that someone else shot her?!
Yes.
Someone shot her and then tried to make it look like a suicide!
Someone in this inn...
You don't think one of us did it, do you?!
Now, now. Don't get ahead of yourself.
I just said the murder took place at approximately 3:00.
That was right after she went off on her own.
We were all in the ping-pong room from 3:00 to 6:00,
so none of us could have done it.
The only time someone left
was when Omura went to the restroom.
But that was well past 5:00,
and he came back in less than a minute.
He couldn't have done it either.
So then it was an outside job?
Yes, perhaps.
As you can see,
the killer could have gone anywhere along the roof,
plus the door wasn't locked.
It's very conceivable that someone entered from outside.
At any rate, let's hear what the employees have to say.
Someone might've seen a suspicious character.
Anybody suspicious?
We were all out to lunch at three o'clock,
and even after we came back, there was no one that suspicious—
Oh! Actually, there was such a person!
What were they like?!
A young lass with a child.
She seemed very distraught and rushed straight upstairs!
Can you describe this girl?!
Oh, she's right there behind you.
It was those two young'uns.
I believe that was around 6:30, just when the fireworks started...
She's talking about when we came to wake Yumi-san up
so she wouldn't miss the fireworks!
Oh...
We went to her room and were about to go in, but...
...I stopped them.
She gets grumpy when people wake her up,
so I figured it best that they didn't.
Nakamichi? You were still here?
Yeah. I had worked up a sweat playing ping-pong
so I took a quick dip in the public bath.
I felt bad for making you and Omura go on ahead and save our spot,
but you two were taking a bath too, correct?
Yeah. We were in the open-air bath, though...
If only we had gone to wake her up, she might still be—
What are you talking about?
Yumi died while we were playin' ping-pong!
We would've been too late no matter what...
Say. Can I ask you something?
Alright, Omura.
You're hiding something, aren't you?
You've been acting strange since this evening!
Come clean! What're you hiding?!
Nothing!
Don't tell me you did this?!
I saw her!
When I left to go to the bathroom!
You saw the killer?!
No! I saw Yumi!
What are you talking about?!
It was after 5:00 when you went to the bathroom!
Yumi was already dead by then!
That's just it!
I saw her even though she was dead!
She was glaring at the ping-pong room from an upstairs window!
That can't be! Yumi was already dead!
Don't be stupid! That's impossible!
What if what I actually saw was her... her...
Get serious! There's no such thing as ghosts!
Your mind was just confused because you were tired!
You were just imagining things!
Yeah, maybe...
Did something happen at our inn?
What's all this about ghosts and dying?
My friend was shot.
Then they need medical treatment right away!
It's too late for that.
The police are on their way as we speak.
Wait a minute! That's strange!
Why did that person say that at that time?!
Don't tell me the murderer is one of you?!
Of course not!
The murderer was someone else! Don't worry!
Wait! Where are you—
Nakamichi! You're in charge!
I gotta use the restroom!
Hey! Mouri!
Say, isn't it too early to tell that this was an outside job?
After all, the way Yumi-san was killed was—
Hey, are you even listening?
Quiet! I don't need any of your babbling!
This was no outside job!
Would someone who snuck in from outside
kill somebody and make it look like a suicide?!
This was an inside job!
In other words, it was one of my best friends!
I don't know why or how they did it,
but I won't let them get away with this!
I'll expose them for what they are! This I swear!
Old man...
He's right.
One of those four is the murderer.
No, l have a good idea who it is.
lt's most likely the person who said that one odd thing.
But that person has a perfect alibi—
they were in the ping-pong room with everyone else!
"Ping-Pong Room"
l checked Yumi-san's estimated time of death for myself,
so that can't be wrong.
ln which case, how did that person kill her?
What bothers me
is the fact that Yumi-san's finger wasn't on the trigger
of the gun placed in her hand.
You would expect the killer to put her finger on it
to fake her suicide...
lt also bothers me that she didn't have any undergarments on
and that she had changed into a large yukata...
Did the killer change her clothes?!
What for?
Benkei...
Come to think of it, that's the name of this inn, too...
The fact all these arrows are stuck in him
must mean this is from when Benkei died standing up.
Died standing up?
That's it! Benkei!
The killer used this!
I've finally figured out the trick the killer used!
Here goes!
I'll just put the old man to sleep like always
with my Anesthetic Watch Gun...
This was an inside job!
In other words, it was one of my best friends!
I won't let them get away with this!
I'll expose them for what they are! This I swear!
Understood, old man.
But why did the killer shoot her?
Perhaps the killer came to steal her things
but shot her when she spotted him.
But isn't it strange?
Why didn't we hear the shot when we were playing ping-pong?
Why?
The killer has to be in here, so why do they all have alibis?!
Judging from the state of her rigor mortis,
Yumi's estimated time of death was around 3:00 PM
Which means she was murdered immediately after she left us
and returned to her room.
The rest of us were in the ping-pong room from 3:00 to 6:00.
Nobody had the chance to kill her.
What bothers me is what Omura said...
That's just it!
I saw her even though she was dead!
She was glaring at the ping-pong room from an upstairs window!
Omura went to the bathroom just after 5:00.
Yumi couldn't have been alive.
So why did Omura say that?
Say...
Let's play ping-pong! Come on!
Hey!
Conan-kun! What are you saying at a time like this?!
I can't play?
My shakehand grip is pretty good, you know!
That reminds me, Yumi-san used the shakehand grip too, huh?
Remember? She was holding a racket with a shakehand-style in that picture.
Yeah, but you can't play right now! Okay?
You're right.
I'd have to change clothes if I got all sweaty.
Sweat? Change clothes?
Shakehand grip?
Come to think of it, Yumi had changed into a large yukata...
And had nothing on underneath!
And her right index finger stuck out stiffly
instead of being on the trigger!
With the shakehand grip,
you hold the racket with your index finger out.
Could Yumi have been playing ping-pong with the murderer
before she was killed?!
That's ridiculous. What purpose would that serve?
Wait a minute!
I could swear they mentioned something at the police academy—
Say, didn't Benkei die while standing up?
That's right.
Benkei fought hordes of enemies off all by himself
and then died on his feet when they showered him with arrows!
Oh! That's it!
Hey, Mouri. What's the shouting about?
I've finally figured out who killed Yumi!
What?!
Who is it, Dad?!
You were the one who killed Yumi!
What? Nakamichi killed her?!
Hey, stop joking around...
I was in the ping-pong room with everyone else
at her estimated time of death!
Yes, your alibi is perfect.
Assuming she really was killed at 3:00 PM!
What are you talking about? We checked her time of death together!
Yumi's toes were indeed beginning to stiffen,
so I estimated that she had died over seven hours prior.
But there are exceptions:
sudden deaths during intense physical exertion.
In such situations, intramuscular proteins harden more easily,
causing rigor mortis to take effect much more quickly.
Yes. Just like the heroic Musashibo Benkei!
So Benkei's death while standing up—
Yes. It's been medically proven
that it's possible to die while standing up.
Come on, now. The body was in Yumi's own room!
What kind of exercise are you saying I made her do?
No, she wasn't forced to exert herself in her room—
it was in the ping-pong room!
You made her play ping-pong right up until you killed her!
You were most likely supposed to meet her all alone
in the ping-pong room.
But then you invited us all into the room!
Oh yeah! What do you say we play some ping-pong now?
Sounds great!
I'll pass.
Naturally, Yumi grew angry and returned to her room.
After 6:00, when everyone had left,
Yumi went by herself to the ping-pong room, where you were waiting.
It must've been quite the secret rendezvous.
You then invited her to a game of ping-pong.
After making her exert herself for a while,
you got her to return to her room...
...at which point you shot her in the head.
All to skew the estimated time of death and create the perfect alibi!
You likely used Yumi's short temper to your advantage
to get her to return to her room.
As proof of this,
Yumi rushed back to her room still holding the racket.
That's why her right hand which held the gun
had stiffened in the shakehand grip!
So the Yumi I saw right after 5:00 was—
Was the real Yumi, in the flesh.
She was still alive then.
She was watching the ping-pong room
from the 2nd floor and waiting for Nakamichi to be all alone!
Yumi was probably really murdered at 6:30,
when the fireworks show started!
The gunshot would seem inconspicuous with all the fireworks exploding about!
But Nakamichi still had the job
of wiping off the body's sweat and changing the clothes—
there was a chance the trick could be discovered
if we learned that she had been sweating.
He had no choice but to remove her undergarments,
but he did change her yukata...
...with a spare one.
But in the middle of his work, an unforeseen obstacle appeared:
Ran and Conan, who came to wake Yumi up.
You stopped your work halfway through,
exited onto the roof through the window,
and stopped Ran from entering the room.
You then went with everyone to see the fireworks,
pretended to get separated,
and finished the rest of your work.
That's when you put the gun in her hand to make it look like a suicide.
Though it would seem that her hand
had already stiffened into that peculiar grip,
making it impossible to put her finger on the trigger.
Your theory is indeed interesting.
But do you have any proof that I did it?
Don't be a fool!
The only person besides me who could've pulled that off
was you, a police detective!
See! You could've done it as well!
And besides, anybody could learn that from a book.
Why, you!
You sure are dumb, old man.
This great policeman couldn't possibly be the killer.
Great policeman?
Don't you think?
He knew that Yumi-san was dead just by seeing her covered in blood!
You said the following without ever touching Yumi...
Yumi!
Don't touch her!
Nobody but me and Mouri are to come in here, since we're detectives!
For some reason you called not for an ambulance,
but for the police!
You knew that it was too late!
Because you killed her!
How could you?!
Shut up!
I didn't want to kill her!
We went out for 18 years, you know!
Eighteen years?!
That's right!
Until I met someone half a year ago!
You did this because she would hinder your marriage?!
Why? Why didn't you marry her?!
Let go!
I proposed to her many times!
But her answer was always no!
For 18 long years!
Just when I was about to marry someone else,
Yumi told me this:
I won't allow it.
I won't allow you to be happy.
That's when her threatening letters and phone calls
to my fiancée started.
Finally she said she was going to send photos of just the two of us!
I told her that if she brought the photos to the reunion
I would buy them all off of her.
That was the day you caught the bank robber.
I had just met with Yumi.
I was struggling over what to do about her...
...when the robber's gun fell nearby.
It was then that I thought up this plan.
The deal was to take place in the ping-pong room,
but then I told her this:
"The photos have been removed from your things."
I see.
So that's why Yumi rushed back to her room,
racket still in hand!
And you followed behind and shot her!
That's right!
I shot the demon who screwed up my life!
Which one was the demon?
Shut up!
What the hell would you know?!
I'll never know...
...how a murderer feels...
...no matter what the reason!
I don't want to know!
Dad!
Seems you're still as strong as ever...
Don't be stupid. You've just gotten weaker.
Both your mind and your body.
Yeah...
He's been pretty glum lately...
You can't blame him; those were his friends...
That reminds me, if he's that strong,
why didn't he ever win any matches?
Apparently, in actual matches he gets so tense
that he can't concentrate his strength.
So he had a knack for being outdone...
I'll go try to cheer him up...
Wait.
Let's leave him alone for a while.
He'll be back to normal eventually.
This time it's pink!
NEXT EPISODE
Next episode's hint right after this!
Oh, Inspector Megure! Good morning!
Mr. Okida's dead?!
It's damp!
For someone who died while sweating, there's too much here!
lf his heart attack was intentionally caused,
then Tokito-san is the prime suspect!
But how exactly could he have done it?!
Next Conan:
The Computer Murder Case
Next Conan's Hint: Cat
Look forward to the next episode
Next time, it's a fight with a computer!