My name's Conan Edogawa!
High school student Shin'ichi was
forced to take a drug that shrunk him!
Although smaller, my mind remains
that of a sharp detective!
Today's "MuneDoki" is the last one!
The alibi's just too strong!
Let your heart beat to the case!
There's always only one truth!
The Alibi Testimony Murder Case
Wow! Look how fancy it is!
Now I see why it's a five-star hotel!
This is going to be great, Conan-kun!
Yeah...
You kids are way too spoiled...
You're only here because the restaurant's on the way, got that!
Yes, we know!
Say, isn't that the lawyer who wants to hire you?
Yep, that's him! Mr. Tatsumi!
Sohei Tatsumi (48)
—Attorney—
Your great detective work is highly admired,
even within our judicial circles!
No, my work doesn't begin to compare to yours...
All of my groups know about you too! It's true!
Having your office in this posh hotel is really impressive!
Tricks like this are necessary when dealing with corporations.
So he's a popular lawyer who advises a number of large corporations...
Wow!
What would you like to drink?
I'll have coffee.
These two don't need anything; I'll kick them out soon.
There's no need to hurry.
Take your time and relax.
Hello? Room service, please.
If there's no reason to hurry,
then why's he so fixated on the time?
Excuse me while I use the restroom.
Sorry, but could someone answer that for me?
It automatically records calls!
Hello?
Oh? You're not my husband...
Um, who may I ask is calling?
Who do you think? Mrs. Tatsumi, of course.
Oops.
What is that?
Little boy?
Could you put my husband on?
Yes, just a minute—
Mr. Lawyer, it's your wife...
She never learns...
It's me. I have guests right now.
We can talk later.
Sorry. Now, about my job.
Before that... Ran, Conan.
Right!
Let's go, Conan-kun.
There's a tea lounge in the lobby.
Tell them my room number
and order whatever you'd like.
Thank you!
I'd like you to investigate possible infidelity.
Of my wife, Kazumi.
It's almost been an hour...
Here he comes.
Dad!
Oh, there you are.
That took long. Is it a hard job?
No, not exactly...
Is something the matter?
He just wouldn't stop babbling
about how he'd like
to trust his wife again,
so it took longer than I expected.
So he's investigating the wife's infidelity...
Anyway, I took the case.
So let's go eat at this restaurant of yours.
Hurray!
Which is what I'd like to say,
but this is the underground parking garage!
The restaurant is up there!
Whoops...
Were you even being serious about going?!
Mr. Tatsumi...
Conan! Let's go!
Coming!
I think I drank too much...
A police car. I wonder what for?
What a huge mansion!
So this is Mr. Tatsumi's house...
TATSUMI
Lawyers must really make a lot...
Inspector Megure. I brought Detective Mouri.
Oh! Thanks for coming, Mouri-kun!
What's the deal, Inspector?
Well, come have a look.
You two wait there.
Isn't that's Mr. Tatsumi's wife?
Yes. Kazumi-san. 27 years old.
Tatsumi Kazumi (27)
—Wife of Mr. Tatsumi—
The cause of death was suffocation by strangulation.
There's no question this was a murder.
A staple!
What's this doing here?
Alright, you!
What do you think you're doin'?!
Now, now, Mouri-kun.
All three of your testimonies are needed this time.
Testimonies?
Yes, it's true that my wife and I didn't get along.
That's why I hired Mouri-san to check up on her...
Inspector. What was the estimated time of death?
We won't know the details until the autopsy,
but judging from the state of rigor mortis,
I'd say between 2:00 and 3:00 PM.
That's when we were—
Yeah, that's when we were at the hotel.
Now I get it.
So they called us here to confirm his alibi...
I parted with Mouri-san and left the hotel.
I finished researching my next case,
and then when I came home, my wife was—
—as you saw...
Mouri-kun. You're certain you were with Tatsumi-kun
between 2:00 and 3:00?
Yes. I'm certain.
He only disappeared from my sight once,
and that was for only a minute.
Oh yes, the phone rang then...
Yeah! Conan-kun answered it!
Yeah! They said, "I'm Mrs. Tatsumi, of course!"
Which means she was still alive at that time?
The tape of that conversation should still be in the phone at the hotel!
Really?! May we borrow this tape?
Of course. That's fine with me.
At any rate, Tatsumi-sensei was with me
between 2:00 and 3:00—his alibi is airtight.
And besides, the hotel is 10 kilometers from his home.
"Lawyer's Wife Murdered"
"Lawyer's wife murdered.
The focus of the investigation is on the victim's associate?"
She was having an affair.
Mr. Tatsumi's wife was killed by her other lover?!
Judging from the scene of the crime,
it wasn't a robbery.
Our testimonies cleared Tatsumi-sensei of all suspicion.
Which narrows it down.
Damn it! I lost that case thanks to whoever killed her!
That makes me mad!
Something's not right.
There are too many things about this case that bother me!
Why was it necessary to put the body in the bathtub?
What was that staple for?
The way Mr. Tatsumi stalled the old man for an hour...
Why was he so fixated on the time?
Was it mere coincidence that he had someone else pick up the phone?
What did he put in the car trunk?
I guess all the questions start from the hotel!
Was that Conan-kun?
Conan-kun! Where are you going?
I'll be back in time!
This is Mr. Tatsumi's office.
The guest elevator is down there.
Similarly, the employee elevator is over there.
The emergency exit is far, too.
What's that?
It's a laundry chute...
The staple!
That's it!
As always,
I've prepared the room next to my office,
so please make yourselves at home.
The room next to his office? As always?
This is—
Where is it coming from?!
From here.
So that's what this is...
They have a music box instead of an alarm clock buzzer!
Are you staying here, little boy?
No, I'm exploring!
Or are you getting into trouble?
That reminds me—
—the music box stopped during the phone call!
What a rare alarm clock!
Do any other rooms have one?
Of course. All the rooms do.
They each have a real music box
hooked up to a timer.
I've finally found it!
Definitive proof that Mr. Tatsumi killed her!
You're late!
Look how late you are!
You knew we were going somewhere!
Where were you?!
Where's the old man?
He already left!
You did this! You killed Kazumi!
I'm with the police. What's going on here?
Who are you?
Shunzo Hirose (30)
Design Engineer
Hirose. I'm a design engineer.
I'm the man you're looking for.
I had an affair with Kazumi, the victim.
What?!
But I didn't kill her! Why would I?!
She was about to divorce this guy
and marry me!
Oh, that's news to me.
Don't play dumb!
You knew!
He knew?
Assuming I had known, why would I kill her?
As a lawyer, I've heard about scores of cases
in which affairs led to murder.
Why, you!
And besides, I have an alibi.
I couldn't possibly have killed her.
Isn't that right, Mouri-san?
Yes, I can vouch for him.
Hirose-kun, was it?
So how about yourself?
What's your alibi?
Where were you between 2:00 and 3:00 PM
on the day she was killed?!
I was—
Where were you?
I was tricked!
Tricked?!
I came here because of Kazumi's letter...
Here.
"I'll be waiting for you at home at 2:30.
Signed, Kazumi."
But she wasn't home.
I rang the doorbell,
but nobody answered, so I left!
This is really hard to believe,
since you were at the scene when it happened.
Anyone can easily make something like this!
You're a sore loser!
It's clear that you're the killer!
Inspector. Take him in.
He ruined my case!
Ruined?
You got it all wrong!
He always does!
Hirose-san. I'd like you
to come down to the station.
Sorry, old man!
Are you all right?
I'm fine, thanks.
No! It wasn't me!
He's right.
The real sore loser isn't Hirose-san—
it's you, Tatsumi-sensei!
What do you mean, Mouri-kun?
Are you saying Mr. Tatsumi is the killer?
Precisely.
Really now, this is absurd.
This will tarnish your name
as a great detective, Mouri-san!
I could say the exact same thing to you, Mr. Tatsumi.
It truly was an impressive trick of utilizing blind spots.
You had me completely fooled.
The place a body is found doesn't necessarily equate
to the location of the murder.
In other words, the murder didn't take place here at your home,
but at the hotel!
No way!
What are you talking about?!
Mouri-kun!
The voice on the tape of the phone call with Conan-kun
was professionally analyzed and determined to be the victim's!
Yes, of course it was her.
Because she called from the room next to Tatsumi-sensei's office,
which he had rented.
Come again?!
The room next door?!
On that day, Tatsumi-sensei
made his wife wait in the guest room
that he always uses for clients.
He then had her call the hotel at a predetermined time
with a cell phone.
He made someone else answer the unconnected call.
Hello?
Because nobody would ever suspect that the caller was in the very next room.
Immediately after his business with me ended,
he went next door and killed his wife.
He put the body in a laundry basket
and dropped it down a nearby laundry chute.
That was the hotel employees' break time
so there wasn't a soul to be found,
was there, Tatsumi-sensei?
However, the bag with the body was stapled.
Stapled with a cleaning tag.
That was the staple found in the bathroom, Inspector Megure.
Now that you mention it...
But why was the body in the bathtub?
His plan probably started when he realized
that the trunk and the bathtub are about the same size.
The body would stiffen,
so he couldn't just toss it in the house.
Then he pointed the finger at Hirose-san,
who was lured here by the fake letter,
and then he escaped suspicion
by having me vouch for him.
It really was quite impressive.
You disappoint me. You're a lousy detective.
Where is your proof that I killed her?
No court of law could make me stand trial like this.
He's right, Mouri-kun!
I do have proof.
Inspector. There's something I'd like you to get right away.
The tape of the phone call...
Is that all you need, Mouri-kun?
The tape of my wife on the phone?
What do you want with that?!
Play it, if you would.
Hello?
Oh? You're not my husband...
Um, who may I ask is calling?
Who do you think? Mrs. Tatsumi, of course.
What's this?!
A music box?
Shh! Quiet!
Oops.
Little boy?
Could you put my husband on?
Yes, just a minute—
That's enough.
Now do you see?
That hotel uses this music box in place of alarm clock buzzers.
In other words, your wife had set the alarm
but forgot to turn it off when making the call.
Sorry, but music boxes like this can be found anywhere.
It doesn't prove a thing.
Inspector.
Any music boxes where the body was found?
No, none at all.
The killer could have run off with it for whatever reason.
Unlikely.
And why's that?
Conan. The tape.
Right!
Here!
This is a recording of the music box in the room next to Mr. Tatsumi's office!
Give it a listen.
That can't be!
It's missing a note!
That's right. The music box in the next room over
is probably missing either a cylinder pin or a tooth!
In other words, it's the only music box like it in the world, Tatsumi-sensei!
Now then, let's hear the phone recording one more time.
It would be a waste of time.
To think a lawyer would be blackmailed by his own wife...
Blackmailed? By your wife?
She demanded 200 million.
Two hundred million?!
It took skill to get where I am today.
But because of my position, I'm often privy to corporate secrets and the like.
I never made any demands,
but a lot of extra money was added to my counsel fees.
Some of it was illegal, to be more precise.
Kazumi found out about this.
I'll keep quiet if you give me 200 million—
a year's worth of this dirty money—
in the form of divorce compensation.
It's not that much when you consider you can keep your reputation.
But then she got involved with that designer...
I couldn't let her get away with it.
"I'll do what you want, but on one condition.
Call me at the specified time
or else I won't pay the 200 million!"
She agreed without a single question.
She would get 200 million and her man!
It was only natural.
But you shouldn't have made her call.
You had the call recorded automatically,
but you should've listened to it again
before giving it to the police.
Your trick to pull off the perfect crime
actually wound up proving your guilt.
I gambled with myself.
No matter how good the lawyer,
the moment of truth is always a gamble.
Until now, I'd never once lost that bet.
You may be a good lawyer,
but you were a poor criminal.
That's how it is, sir.
Inspector!
Good work, Mouri-kun.
Despite being tricked and taken advantage of.
Hope to work with you again.
Oh, uh, same here...
Tricked? Who? By who?
Oh, well!
Gimme a break.
Now his reputation keeps getting better and better...
NEXT EPISODE
Next episode's hint right after this!
It was definitely Matsuo-san who did this!
But how did he go from the studio
and back in four minutes?!
Aha! I've finally found the secret path!
I wouldn't want the criminal to leave
when the logic show's just about to begin...
...Takashi Matsuo-san!
Next Conan:
The TV Station Murder Case
Next Conan's Hint: Window
Look forward to the next episode
A new opening theme starts next time!
Really, really? I'm looking forward to it, super-very-good!