As times change,
difficult cases increase in number!
Today's case is a manhunt!
Don't put out the flames of love!
He sees the truth in people's hearts,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Created by
Gosho Aoyama
"Detective Conan"
Serialized in Shogakukan's
"Weekly Shonen Sunday"
Planning
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Character Design
Masatomo Sudo
Art Director
Yukihiro Shibutani
Art Design
Hiroyuki Mitsumoto
Directors of Photography
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Ogawa
Sound Director
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
Music Producer
Hiroki Horio
(PolyGram)
Music
Katsuo Ono
Opening Theme
Performed by
Lyrics
Music
Arrangement
Miki Muroi
Tomohisa Kawazoe
Koichi Kaminaga/Tomohisa Kawazoe/Ryujin Inoue
(Polydor)
Editor
Teramitsu Okada
(JAY FILM)
Story Editor
Jun'ichi Iioka
Color Key
Reiko Hirayama
Associate Producer
Satoshi Yokoyama
Planning Support
Toyohiko Okuyama
Mitome Asai
Director
Kenji Kodama
Producers
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Masahito Yoshioka
(Tokyo Movie)
My name is Noriko Okaya.
I was hoping you could find the address
of a man named Tsuyoshi Kitagawa-san.
Pardon my asking, but how are you two related?
I met him in early June, during a trip to Shinshu...
I didn't think much of him at the time,
but lately I've wanted to see him again.
Oh, I get it! You've fallen in love with him!
Yes... Well...
That's so sweet!
Just a simple search. No need for me here.
Here's some tea!
Thank you.
Why's she so nervous?
Do you have any clues or leads?
Yes. His license plate number
and a quick sketch of him.
Oh! He's quite the unique individual!
Alright, just leave it to me.
This sketch...
Thank you for your help.
This'll be a cinch! I can use his license plate number
to get his address from the transportation office!
Are you sure she really likes him?
What're you trying to say?
They say that when you draw someone's picture,
your feelings for that person go into it.
Her drawing doesn't look very—
Enough of your lip!
Go do your homework
and mind your own business!
I'll be back.
See you later!
Conan-kun. You shouldn't get in the way of—
Noriko Okaya-san, lives at—
Stay out of his work!
Alright!
I already saw what I needed!
A handkerchief. Is it hers?
I'll be back later!
Conan-kun! Ugh!
Let's see. 3-9-8... Sumire Lodge...
Bingo!
Thanks for bringing me my handkerchief!
Conan-kun. Want some cocoa?
Sure!
Just a minute, then!
You have a nice apartment!
Thank you!
Say, what's your job?
Who, me?
I used to work at a business firm,
but now I'm taking a break.
Eh? How come?
I got sick. I'm recuperating now.
Kerosene?
That's strange.
I don't see any gas heaters...
A can of mace.
Huh? What's that picture?
It's dated May 19th...
Now, now. Is a girl's apartment that rare for you?
How embarrassing...
This was my boyfriend,
until he dumped me a while ago...
So now I'm looking for a new boyfriend.
That man in the sketch sure seems different, though.
I'm thinking things might go smoother with a different type of person!
That's enough about me. Tell me about yourself.
I bet you have a girlfriend!
No...
I didn't learn much about her...
Oh, well. I guess I'll wait around for the old man.
But will he really find him that easily?
One Week Later
I haven't been to the aquarium in forever!
Me neither! I hope I can pet the dolphins!
Too bad about the weather.
It probably won't rain, though.
The old man's working again today?
This Kitagawa guy moved
without giving his new address to the transportation office.
This is gonna take awhile...
I thought it was strange she hired a detective
when she already had his license plate number...
So that's what this really is...
It's Noriko-san!
But why does she look so sad?
Sorry! I just remembered I hafta do something!
Wait, Conan!
Conan-kun!
Flowers and mourning clothes...
She's visiting a grave?
I wonder whose grave it is. It still looks new.
Oh, Noriko-san.
Saeki-san.
Hard to believe it's been six months already...
Yes...
How are you?
Much better.
Thank you for everything you did.
No, all I did was help with your rehabilitation.
You did all the hard work.
What do you say we have coffee somewhere?
I'm sorry, I need to hurry home.
Oh. Then let me drive you.
That's okay. Thanks, though.
Noriko-san...
Hello!
Oh, hello.
Whose grave is that?
My friend's.
I figured it was that lady's boyfriend's grave.
It is. He was both my friend and her fiancé.
Her fiancé? When did he die?
"Yamaguchi Family Grave"
Early June.
June?!
No doubt about it! It was the guy in the picture!
This was my boyfriend,
until he dumped me a while ago...
Noriko-san lied about being dumped
when her boyfriend was actually dead...
Why?
Say, how did he die?
A car accident.
The two were driving through scenic Shinshu
when they drove into a cliff.
Pardon my asking, but how are you two related?
I met him in early June, during a trip to Shinshu...
What does it mean?!
Did she meet him when her fiancé caused the accident?!
Have you ever heard the name
Tsuyoshi Kitagawa?
Eh?
He drives a red sports car.
A red sports car?!
What is it?
No, nothing...
Tell me! It has to do with that lady!
With Noriko-san?! Who exactly are you?
I'm Conan Edogawa. A detective!
A detective?
What a surprise.
To think that the famous Detective Mouri
would have an assistant like you.
It was the only way to get you to talk.
So what are you investigating?
I can't give any details, but could you start
by giving me the name of Noriko-san's fiancé?
His name was Tatsuo Yamaguchi.
He worked at the same company as she did.
Earlier, you seemed surprised when I mentioned a red sports car.
I heard her talking to the police
after the accident...
A red sports car?
Yes. There was a young couple in it, chasing us.
We tried to lose them, but then—
We did find two sets of tire tracks,
but why would they do that?
They were just harassing us.
At first they kept honking their horn from behind,
and when we let them go ahead
they swerved right in front of us.
Tatsuo-san tried to avoid them, but—
Noriko-san...
Alright. We're looking into the incident,
but even if we do catch them, they'll probably get off easy.
How come?!
Things might've been different had you actually collided,
but as they are now, this would be deemed Yamaguchi-san's fault.
He was speeding, after all.
Do you remember the car's model
or license plate number?
Okaya-san?
Then she answered clearly with
"I don't remember."
She said she didn't remember?!
Yeah. It was really hard on her.
She couldn't describe the couple very well either,
and with no other leads, the police investigation ended after only a month.
So those clues...
Yes. His license plate number
and a quick sketch of him.
Oh! He's quite the unique individual!
Noriko-san remembered
his plate number and his face!
Does the fact that she didn't tell the police
mean that she's going
to take matters into her own hands?!
Saeki-san! What was the rehabilitation you and Noriko-san talked about?!
I was the doctor in charge of her rehabilitation.
How did she seem at the time?
She worked extremely hard.
What normally takes half a year,
she did in three months.
It was amazing...
No doubt about it!
Her lust for revenge inspired her
to get better quickly!
Saeki-san! Let's go see Noriko-san right now!
Come on! Hurry!
Conan-kun!
I have to somehow change Noriko-san's feelings
before the old man finds this Kitagawa guy!
But how—
Ouch!
Oh, sorry! That's a Shakoba Cactus needle!
It must've gotten there when I recently
took one to a friend's house.
A Shakoba Cactus? Was it Yamaguchi-san's?!
He had raised cactuses since he was a kid.
I took all of them in after the accident,
but someone asked for one, so...
I'd like to share them with Noriko-san,
but that would only remind her of him...
So she doesn't know I have them.
Wait! Shakoba Cactuses are also known as Christmas Cactuses!
What if—!
Say, is your house far from here?!
No, it's on the way to Noriko-san's place.
Then let's stop by there first!
Eh?
Looks like she's not home yet.
Nope.
That's odd. There's no telling when the old man will contact her,
so she should be at home!
Don't tell me he's already found the address?!
Mouri Detective Agency.
Oh, you're home?
Did you find out the guy's address already?
Yep, sure did! Wasn't easy, either!
I wore the bottoms off of my shoes!
Who is it? Conan-kun?
I just got off the phone with her.
Dammit!
But the guy's already living with some chick,
so I guess she's out of luck—
Give me the address, too!
What for?!
Hurry, before that couple gets killed!
What?!
katamuite-yuku hizashi ga nagai sakamichi terashite-iru
The last rays of sunlight flow down the long hill
kimi wa hitori de hashiru kawaita nodo osaete
You run up it alone, despite your parched throat
motsuresou ni naru ashimoto akirame ga mada osoikakaru
Feeling about to stumble anytime, the desire to give up floods back
yosoku dekinai happening kidou hazureta yume
Events you could never expect have thrown your dream off course
kokoro kowareteku itami no naka
But when your heart's falling apart from the pain
Losers!
wasurenaide-hoshii koko ni iru-kara
Never forget that I'm always here for you
Damn!
Tatsuo-san!
Noriko-san probably went to the transportation office
on her own to find Kitagawa's address.
Unable to find his new address, she hired the old man!
If she was that intent on rehabilitation,
then there's probably no stopping her
from wanting vengeance!
How is she planning to get revenge, anyway?!
Say, did Yamaguchi-san die instantly?
No. He was still alive after he smashed into the cliff.
He burned to death.
Burned?!
The car's gasoline ignited before he could be pulled out...
Aha! That wasn't kerosene at all!
It was probably gasoline!
It's you!
It sounds like you remember me.
What do you want?!
That accident wasn't our fault!
I don't need your excuses; you're both going to die now.
What?!
What was that for?!
You two are human scum! Get ready to die!
You're going to suffer exactly like my boyfriend did!
You're the crazy one!
Conan-kun!
The roof!
This is probably the only way to calm her feelings!
Stop! What are you doin'?!
Stop right there!
Noriko-san! Stop this foolishness!
Stay back! Please!
Doing this won't bring Yamaguchi-san back!
I know that! But this is all I can do!
Don't do it! Light it on fire and you'll be injured too!
I don't care!
I have no future now that Tatsuo-san is gone!
The least I can do is make these people pay...
Whew, I'm pooped...
Conan-kun...
This Shakoba Cactus sure is pretty!
They bloom in the winter, so in some countries
they're given as Christmas presents
and even referred to as Christmas Cactuses!
Is that Tatsuo-san's Shakoba Cactus?
Yes. I took in all of his cactuses as mementos.
Noriko-san.
Yamaguchi-san may have died,
but he lives on in each one of these flowers.
Tatsuo-san!
You should've come!
The aquarium was awesome!
All three of us fed the dolphins!
But Genta-kun slipped and fell!
The aquarium guy took a picture
at that exact moment!
See!
Wow! Looks like fun!
Boy, am I glad I didn't go!
Abe took out an insurance policy on Negishi-san
worth 500 million yen!
And he had me vouch for his alibi!
No way!
You?!
I'll smash in that rotten head of yours!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Left handed
Next time is a bit difficult!
I read the original.