As times change,
difficult cases increase in number!
Today is alibi destruction.
Use someone and you'll pay!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Hey, Dr. Agasa...
When are we going to find any clues
about those men in black?
You said that if I made old man Mouri famous
he'd get more clients and then maybe we'd find out about them...
He got more clients, didn't he?
Yeah, but we haven't heard anything about those guys...
Just be patient.
Act hastily and they might find out about you.
If that happens—
I know.
It might put Ran and the old man in danger!
Wait quietly for now.
A detective needs patience too, you know.
Say, what kind of experiment is that?
Oh, this? It's a—
Now do you know what kind?
Yeah. A dangerous one.
What a lousy situation.
Huh?
It's old man Mouri. What's he doing?
Excellent choice, sir.
Could I have your address, sir?
Hey!
What are you up to?
Shh! I'm working!
Oh, are you following that guy around?
Hey, now! What if he notices me?!
Get outta here, kid!
Go tell Ran I won't be home for dinner!
Don't mind me!
Gimme a break.
Gunma Prefecture Akaoni Village Fire Festival
Sunday, November 10th
Talk about an easy job!
Half a million yen just for watching someone for three days!
Some jobs really rake in the dough!
That's because everyone admires your great detective work!
Even I'm amazed at how I've solved one case after another!
I solved them all.
Come to think of it, your job's been going well
ever since Conan-kun came!
Maybe he brought some good luck with him!
That's silly...
Ran. How long are we gonna take care of this twerp?
Are his parents still in the hospital?!
Actually, when I visited Dr. Agasa yesterday...
They did get out of the hospital,
but then they suddenly got transferred overseas...
They left yesterday!
Eh? They just left Conan-kun behind?!
They said they'll send for him once they settle in.
So we're taking care of him again?
What was I supposed to say?
He has nowhere else to go...
So basically, you've been abandoned.
Whatever.
If I ever talk to his parents, I'll have to charge them for his upbringing...
Hey, now.
At 8:00 PM today, a man's body was found
under the burning tower of the Akaoni Fire Festival.
According to his personal effects,
the body was that of
42-year-old Masaki Negishi-san.
What?!
—are investigating this as a possible murder—
This is the guy!
What is it, Dad? Did you know him?!
Not just that...
I was with him for three whole days!
Three days?!
You can't mean—
That's right. He's the guy I followed around until yesterday...
...Masaki Negishi-san!
Dad sure is taking a long time
to give his statement.
It's to be expected—
he was with the guy up until yesterday.
The police don't get many witnesses like him!
What kind of case is it?
Come on, old man! I can't wait to find out!
Right. Got it.
Half a billion yen?!
Yes. The late Negishi-san had a life insurance policy
worth half a billion yen.
Doesn't it seem strange?!
Why would he give all that insurance money
to an ordinary friend like you, Yutaka Abe-san?!
And you're the one who hired me to trail him!
Why would he give you the insurance money?!
It was a game.
What?!
We had been friends since college.
When we went drinking one day, he—
We're not young anymore...
Wanna bet on who lives the longest?
Sounds interesting!
How does half a billion yen sound?
...and I accepted his invitation.
So you both took out 500-million yen policies.
I had no idea the bet would last only three months...
Then why did you have Mouri-kun trail him?
No big reason, really.
He recently told me
that he thought someone was out to kill him.
Out to kill him?!
I thought he was joking at first,
but he wasn't acting quite normal,
so I had Mouri-san watch him for a few days.
Isn't that right?
Well, I have work to do.
I run a small business, so I'm actually quite busy.
Please find Negishi-san's killer as quickly as possible.
I'll contact you the instant we do!
I look forward to it, Detective.
He's the only one I can see as the killer,
but he has an alibi.
An airtight one, at that.
Something's fishy! He's definitely the killer!
Half a million yen!
Just to follow a guy for three days!
That's way too much!
And his confident attitude!
I'm not too fond of that, either!
Then why can't they arrest him?
His alibi is perfect!
And I was the one who verified it for him!
The body was found on Sunday night,
during the Fire Festival.
I was on his tail the entire time
until the night before.
In other words, the crime took place
between late Saturday night and Sunday evening,
when the flame tower was lit.
Then the person you suspect must've done it during then...
Nope.
He was on a company trip to Kyushu
from Saturday morning until this afternoon!
Then why are you so fixated on him?
My detective's intuition...
Oh...
His alibi, huh?
One Week Later
Damn it!
What's wrong, Dad?
That damn Abe got Negishi-san's insurance money!
He got the half-billion yen just like that!
I'm going to destroy his alibi, no matter what!
What are those?
The schedule and pictures of his Kyushu trip.
I asked Inspector Megure to let me borrow them.
There has to be a clue in one of these photos.
Just you watch! I, the great Kogoro Mouri-sama,
will expose his trick!
Dad's on fire!
Let's just hope he doesn't burn out.
But Dad, couldn't he have come back on short notice on a domestic flight?
Yes, it's very possible. But his alibi has no holes.
Especially during the time the murder occurred.
He played mahjong with his employees all Saturday night.
Sunday afternoon, he toured the city on bus.
He has pictures to prove it, too.
These photos!
The only time he was alone was when he took a 2-hour nap Sunday afternoon.
It would be impossible to go to Gunma and back in that amount of time.
What's so funny?
These photos are weird!
Weird?
See, look!
He's by a clock in every one!
Now that you mention it...
He must really like clocks!
That's not normal.
It's almost like he took these to prove his alibi.
And the kid's right—
Wait a minute.
It seems like whenever I'm stuck on something,
he'll say something that gives me a hint...
What's in this envelope?
Oh, those are—
—from when I followed the guy—
Uh oh! They're mixed up!
—who got killed!
Dad!
Are you alright, Conan-kun?
Did he give you a boo-boo?
Gimme a break.
Guess he is just a stupid kid.
Say, are you sure this is the guy who was killed?
His body was all burned up...
Yeah, it was definitely him.
His driver's license was lying right next
to the flame tower at the fire festival.
The teeth even matched his dental records.
That's strange.
Criminals normally hide their crimes;
it's far too intentional for the body
to be hidden under the fire
and an easily-understood clue to be lying nearby!
Only one person stood to gain from the body's discovery:
Abe, who would get the insurance money.
The old man's right—
he's the only possible person!
But he has an airtight alibi!
No, there has to be something that will destroy his story!
T-This is it!
This photograph!
That's strange. The Negishi-san I saw...
...was right-handed!
Could it be?!
Conan-kun?
Just as I thought!
These are from Thursday and Friday.
And these are from Saturday!
Thursday
The old man followed Negishi-san
Friday
from Thursday to Saturday.
Saturday
His body was found on Sunday night,
Sunday
so the murder took place between Saturday night and Sunday evening.
But Yutaka Abe was in Kyushu
from Saturday morning until Monday afternoon.
His alibi is flawless!
But if my theory is correct, then it's actually—
Mind your own business, twerp!
Look away for a second and he causes trouble!
Don't hit Conan-kun just because you can't solve the case!
Yutaka Abe is clearly responsible for this!
He even has a motive!
Motive?
His business was 300 million yen in debt.
He used the insurance money to pay it off
and plans to escape overseas with the rest of it!
Overseas?!
He left someone in charge of the company, saying that he was going on a trip.
And his plane leaves at 9:00 tonight!
9:00?! That leaves us only three hours!
We can't let him leave the country!
My only chance now is to corner him
and make him confess!
There's no time! First, I need to get them to the airport!
Alright! I'll use that method!
Eh? You destroyed Abe's alibi, Inspector?!
Yes. I'm on my way to the airport.
I'd like you to come too!
Excellent! I'll see you there!
Alright, now to use the old man's voice...
Hello, Inspector Megure! This is Kogoro Mouri!
New Tokyo International Airport
Listen! Don't get in my way!
We won't!
You come every single time!
It sure is crowded.
Just finding the Inspector is going to be tough...
Which flight is Abe's?
I think it was—
Oh no! They're about to start boarding!
It's dangerous, but I'll have to lure him out!
Paging Yutaka Abe-sama, bound for Seattle
on Flight Number 99...
...Masaki Negishi-sama is waiting for you in the main parking lot.
Again, Yutaka Abe-sama, bound for Seattle
on Flight Number 99—
What's going on, Dad?!
Hey!
Inspector Megure!
Sorry I'm late!
Never mind that! How did you destroy Abe's alibi?!
You said you found out how.
Huh? Where did Conan-kun go?
That was clever of you, Mister.
Who's there?!
Negishi-san actually died Friday night, didn't he?
That's right. The day before you left on your trip.
Then you had Detective Mouri follow a fake Negishi-san around the following day...
Where are you?!
...to make us think he was alive until Saturday.
You checked the date of the festival in advance, and just as you planned,
his body was found on Sunday night.
With his precise time of death indeterminable,
Detective Mouri's statement put it
between Saturday night and Sunday evening.
Damn you!
Then you returned Monday afternoon, as if nothing had happened.
Thus, your alibi was created.
Well? Am I right?
A kid?!
I heard the policemen talking about the case
and I tried applying my own kind of logic!
Your mistake was the substitute you chose for Negishi-san!
You might've fooled the detective,
but there's no fooling the camera!
Your actor was left-handed, unlike Negishi-san!
Give yourself up. This place is crawling with police.
Well done, my boy!
I, Yutaka Abe, was indeed Negishi Masaki's killer.
But I won't be turning myself in. I'm going to live it up overseas!
Eh? But I'll tell everyone that you confessed.
Nobody'll believe you, kid.
But they might believe you!
I, Yutaka Abe, was indeed Negishi Masaki's killer.
You little brat!
You have no idea what it's like
to have your business
on the verge of bankruptcy!
He got what he deserved!
He was stupid enough to take out
such a huge insurance policy!
He had no idea I'd kill him!
And you were stupid enough
to let me kill you, too.
You're the stupid one!
I was gonna let you off easy if you turned yourself in!
But now you've gone too far!
I'll smash in that rotten head of yours!
What the heck?!
I, Yutaka Abe, was indeed Masaki Negishi's killer.
Who on earth did this?!
Geez!
He's one lousy bastard to use me like that!
I'm glad they found the fake Negishi-san too!
Yeah. Apparently Abe asked him
to wander around all day
for no specific reason.
What bothers me is what Abe said afterwards...
It was the kid! He did this!
The only kid around then was—
Oh yeah, right!
It ain't easy being a kid.
So, Ran's all by herself?!
Water?
Ran!
Looks like these might be random murders...
Next Conan:
Next... Next Conan's Hint: Power failure
Next time, finally, a two-parter!
Ran-chan's in danger!