As times change,
difficult cases increase in number!
Let's review the double-murder during the intro song!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
We were invited to Yotsui Reika's birthday party.
Reika Yotsui (24)
Daughter of Yotsui Group President
Someone punctured everyone's tires,
forcing us all to wait in the lodge until morning.
That night, while searching for the missing Reika,
Nikaido was drowned in the fountain.
Ran was similarly attacked, but managed to survive.
Judging from the killer's power outage trick,
it was definitely someone in the mansion!
Just then, Reika was found drowned to death
in a bathtub!
Nanao Yone (64)
Yotsui Family Housekeeper
How did this happen to her?!
She was drowned.
I can't say anything without examining
Yotsui Reika (24)
Daughter of Yotsui Group President
the water she swallowed,
but her head was probably held underwater.
Which means that Nikaido-san's drowning,
Ran's near-drowning in the kitchen sink,
and this murder were
all done the exact same way.
Then that means!
Rokuda Masashi (40)
Yotsui Product Director
Mifune Takuya (26)
President of Mifune Electronics
These really are—
—random murders!
Most likely. And the killer is rather cruel, too.
Look. Even her skirt and socks are sopping wet—
evidence that she put up quite a struggle.
Poor woman...
There are also rope marks on her wrists
and a tape mark over her mouth.
It would seem she was kept somewhere
prior to being killed.
Who would do something this terrible?
Say, you three went to the bathroom just now, right?
Yeah...
Did you see or hear anything out of the ordinary?
No...
They waited outside while I was in the bathroom,
but there wasn't anything strange.
Before he went in last,
Gojo Osamu (24)
General Manager of Gojo Commerce
Ichieda Takashi (26)
City Bank Fund Raising Department
Ichieda-san told us to make coffee,
so I don't know about after that...
I see.
That's how you got your chance to kill her.
Mifune!
It takes at least 5 to 6 minutes to make coffee.
That's all the time you'd need to take her
to the bath and kill her.
No! I didn't do it!
Ichieda-san isn't the killer.
She's been dead for at least an hour or two.
Meaning she was killed between 5:00 and 6:00.
He didn't do it just now.
The same goes for Gojo-san and Yone-san;
the three of them were with me
between 4:00 and 7:00.
This narrows down the list of suspects
to Mifune-san and Rokuda-san, who were in their rooms!
Then it's simple. Rokuda's the killer
since I didn't do it.
Don't be a fool. I saw you.
At around 6:00 AM, you left
your room and went somewhere.
Did you, Mifune?!
Yeah.
I got sleepy, so I went upstairs to wash my face.
A likely story.
The upstairs washroom is right next to the stairs.
You could've killed her on your way there.
What?!
Yes, I could have. There's no one to vouch for me.
But the same goes for you, too!
I never saw you while I was up there!
At any rate, the murder was between 5:00 and 6:00 AM.
Only you two could've done it.
If you could kindly tell me what you were doing then...
The old man's right.
She definitely died between 5:00 and 6:00 AM.
Which means those two are the most suspicious.
But it's strange.
Why are her clothes so wet?
Even if she did fight back, this is too—
Tape marks...
The killer used both rope and tape?!
Rokuda-san. You didn't leave your room at all?
That's right.
And you only left the one time to wash your face?
Yeah.
Um...
Where exactly was the young lady being held?
Doesn't it seem strange?
We searched the whole place!
We searched for her at 10:00.
There wasn't anything in here.
And the bathtub was empty.
Was she outside? Maybe in the forest?!
No.
There's a better place than outside—
inside the trunk of one of your cars.
And you two were the only ones who had
any time to haul her out from one.
Looks like one of you is the lunatic
who's enjoying these random murders.
Are these really random, though?
Ran was attacked for no reason—
it's only natural to think so.
But why?
Why did the culprit wait to kill Reika-san
and let us find her only now?!
And it bothers me that she was killed in here.
Why didn't the culprit kill her at the fountain
instead of locking her in the trunk?
It would be safer and easier than filling a bathtub.
What're you doing?!
Yikes!
The shower's on! Huh?
The shower?
Aha! So that's it!
This is a time-based trick!
In which case, her unnecessarily wet clothes,
the tape marks, the reason Ran was attacked,
and the reason Reika-san's discovery was delayed
all share a common thread!
Which means he's the killer!
He's the bastard who attacked Ran!
But there's no proof that he's the killer!
Darn it, isn't there anything?!
Idiot! You wanna get wet that badly?!
Get wet?!
That's it! Just maybe—
For now, let's all move to the living room
and wait until the cars arrive.
I'm concerned about Ran, too.
Not so fast!
Now what?!
That wasn't me...
Here we go again...
What is it, Detective?
I've figured out who the killer is.
What?!
The killer?!
Please remove your coats and toss them this way.
That will clear all of this up.
Stop wasting our time!
Calm down. Let's just do what he says.
He says it'll help determine who the killer is.
There! Now get checking!
Now you can figure out who it is, right?!
So you are the one responsible
for all three incidents at this lodge!
Yes.
The one who drowned Nikaido-san in the fountain,
drugged and attempted to drown Ran in the kitchen,
and drowned Reika-san in here
was you, Ichieda-san!
Ichieda. Did you really—
Stop kidding around, Detective...
Do I look like an insane killer?
Before Nikaido-san was murdered in the first incident,
we went into the forest to look for Reika-san.
The two of you were with him, correct?
Yes...
In the forest, you decided to split up and look for her.
Ichieda-san followed Nikaido-san
and lured him over to the fountain.
He probably said he saw Reika-san by it.
Then he attacked Nikaido-san from behind
and drowned him!
That's just conjecture!
Rokuda-san could've done the same thing!
Besides, why would I attack Ran-san?
This is the first time I've met her!
And I was with you when the killer cut the lights
to attack her!
How could I have shut the power off?
Don't tell me I had an accomplice...
No, you can shut it off easily enough
by using the air conditioners and microwave ovens!
It's easy.
You set the timers on all the air conditioners to the same time,
and set the microwaves to high.
When the time comes, there's a power overload,
which sets off the circuit breakers.
All the timers are still set to 12:30,
and Conan heard something odd after the power failure.
Isn't that right?
Yeah! I heard a bell!
The microwaves here use dials,
so they still moved without power.
The microwave was warm when I touched it later,
so he has to be right!
Hey, wait!
You then broke the window to make it
look like the killer ran outside
and then urged us to make chase.
You then carried Ran into the kitchen
and tried to drown her.
You had drugged her coffee so she wouldn't fight back.
Shortly before the power went out,
you were in the kitchen with me,
looking for Reika-san.
You could have easily turned the microwaves on
after I left!
Hold on.
Have you forgotten that I have an alibi?
I was with you when the young lady was killed!
If I'm supposedly behind all three incidents,
then please explain how I killed her.
He's right.
Reika-sama died between 5:00 and 6:00.
He was with us the entire time from 4:00 to 7:00.
And the sleeping pills in Ran-san's drink...
Yone-san brought us that coffee!
We all chose our own cups!
Could he really have planned it in advance?
What if he wound up with the drugged coffee?
It's simple.
All he had to do was not drink it.
But Ran-san chose her own cup, too.
How could he have predicted that?
He didn't need to.
Anybody would have done!
So we might've been attacked too?!
If you were unlucky enough to drink that coffee.
Had the drug paralyzed you,
you would've wound up just like Ran.
So you were killing at random?
Stop treating me like a murderer...
Besides, wouldn't I have killed her
when the power went out?
No, you never intended to kill Ran.
That's right. It wasn't someone's life you wanted then...
...it was testimony!
You wanted someone to say that their head
was held underwater!
That would make it seem like the killer
drowned the people in all three incidents!
So then—
She didn't drown to death?
No, she drowned.
Her head just wasn't held underwater.
Doesn't it seem strange?
Reika-san disappeared at 10:00 PM.
But she was killed between 5:00 and 6:00 AM.
For some reason, the culprit waited 7 or 8 hours
to kill her.
And her clothes wouldn't get that wet,
no matter how much she fought back.
And for some reason, the killer used tape
in addition to the rope.
The key to all these mysteries...
...is that shower.
The shower?
Normally, you fill a bathtub using the faucet.
But when Conan just tried to use it,
water came out of the shower instead.
Why was that?
It was because the killer used the shower
to quietly fill the tub.
He taped her to the tub
so she would eventually drown.
Ichieda-san probably drugged Reika-san
when she came down at 10:00,
carried her in here, and used said trick.
He adjusted the shower so that she would drown
between 5:00 and 6:00 AM.
He stayed with us between 5:00 and 6:00,
then pretended to use the bathroom at 7:00
to pull her body out of the tub.
This crude trick would've seemed obvious
had he not dropped a hint.
A hint?
Yes. The attack on Ran was meant to make it
look like Reika-san's head was held underwater too.
But there was a chance that she might be discovered
inside the bathtub.
He burned out the light bulbs here in advance
to keep people away, but it'd be all over
if someone checked the tub.
But he overcame this problem by checking the tub himself.
She's not in here.
Only you could've done this, Ichieda-san!
Yes, I would be the most suspicious
if that trick really was used.
I'll grant you that.
But did you see me do it?
You make some big claims, yet you have no proof...
That's why I had you remove your coats.
Then check already!
You won't find anything, though.
It wasn't your coat that I wanted to see—
it was the water blotches on your shirt!
The blotches on Gojo-san's sleeves
are from when he washed his hands.
The ones on Mifune-san's collar
are from when he washed his face.
So what are those blotches on your arms?
These are the same as theirs—
You got them washing your hands? I think not.
Washing your face? Nope.
You can't get blotches there with your coat on!
Yes. You took your coat off
to keep it from getting wet when you pulled
the sopping wet body out!
Your elbows are wet because you rolled your sleeves up.
Isn't that right, Ichieda-san?
But why would he—
From the fact that these were all drownings,
it may have to do with Yaeko-san,
who drowned in the accident two years ago...
Yaeko didn't die in an accident.
She was murdered...
...by Nikaido and the young lady!
The day of the storm,
Yaeko took a lifeboat to the island to rescue the young lady.
She had one life vest on, and one life vest for the young lady.
But she was shocked when she arrived—
Nikaido was there too.
There were only two life vests.
Are you saying—
They didn't!
They did! They took Yaeko's vest
and left her to die!
I thought it was strange that Yaeko
wasn't wearing a vest when we found her body
and that they both said they hadn't seen her.
But how do we know that's really what happened?
They fessed up right before I killed them.
They confessed to killing my beloved Yaeko!
The two of them deserved to die!
That's enough!
Yone-san!
No one deserves to die.
That doesn't mean I forgive her,
but one person's death is another person's sadness.
My own sadness is enough as it is...
He attacked you too?
Yeah...
I don't remember much because of the sleeping pills,
but I think Shin'ichi came to save me...
Eh?!
Uh oh!
But he wasn't there, was he?!
No. It was actually Conan-kun who saved me...
You were just—
But it couldn't have been that mystery geek!
Yeah! That jerk would never be that thoughtful!
Alright. That's enough, already.
This could be a good game!
Hey, now...
The championship flag was shredded up?!
This was an inside job.
Here we go again...
No! You're not the real culprit!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Diagonal Slash
Next time, a high school is the stage!
That pitcher is so cool!