As we move into a new year,
difficult cases get more complicated!
Today marks the second year of Conan!
He gets into big trouble fast!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Created by
Gosho Aoyama
"Detective Conan"
Serialized in Shogakukan's
"Weekly Shonen Sunday"
Planning
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Character Design
Masatomo Sudo
Art Director
Yukihiro Shibutani
Art Design
Hiroyuki Mitsumoto
Directors of Photography
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Ogawa
Sound Director
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
Music Producer
Hiroki Horio
(PolyGram)
Music
Katsuo Ono
Opening Theme
Performed by
Lyrics
Music
Arrangement
Miki Muroi
Tomohisa Kawazoe
Koichi Kaminaga/Tomohisa Kawazoe/Ryujin Inoue
(Polydor)
Editor
Teramitsu Okada
(JAY FILM)
Story Editor
Jun'ichi Iioka
Color Key
Reiko Hirayama
Associate Producer
Satoshi Yokoyama
Planning Support
Toyohiko Okuyama
Mitome Asai
Director
Kenji Kodama
Producers
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Masahito Yoshioka
(Tokyo Movie)
Conan-kun! Are you listening to me?!
Eh?
Don't "eh" me!
It's been a long time since
your parents transferred overseas
and left you here!
Don't you miss them?
Not really.
Geez, some parents! They don't show up once, or even call!
Oh, man... my lie's getting busted.
Though they really are overseas right now, so it's not really a lie...
Wasn't Dr. Agasa the one who brought him here?
Yeah.
Then shouldn't we at least ask him
how to contact his parents?
Y-You can't do that!
Coming!
Why not? Is there something wrong with contacting them?
Oh, man! I gotta act quick or my identity as Shin'ichi Kudo will be out of the bag!
She's here, Conan-kun!
Your mom!
Eh?
I'm so sorry, Conan-chan!
You must've been lonely all by yourself!
But it's all right now!
Now let's go home!
W-Who the hell are you?!
Eh?! She's not your mom?!
Dear me! He's just being sulky,
after being left alone all this time...
My name's Fumiyo Edogawa.
I'm Conan Edogawa's mother.
N-No! Conan Edogawa's an alias I invented!
"Conan" can't possibly have parents!
I appreciate everything!
I'll give you my thanks another day!
Right! I look forward to it!
Goodbye!
Bye, Conan-kun! Send us
a letter when you get there!
Miss! Don't forget your thanks!
Bye-bye, Conan-kun...
Who are you, lady?!
I told you. I'm your mother!
Nope! My mom's...
Yukiko Kudo.
Yes. Your mother was a beautiful
Japanese actress who enchanted men
all over the world and won all
the major awards at the young age of 19.
But she fell in love with
the young novelist Yusaku Kudo,
married at 20, and then simply retired.
She later had a son, but left him
behind to travel the world
with Yusaku Kudo, now an
internationally-renowned mystery writer.
Isn't that right,
Shin'ichi Kudo-kun, their only son?
Is she with those men in black
who shrunk me with their drug?!
Hold it right there.
Stay still, and I'll take you to
a nice place... A more fun place...
You moron, what're you doing?! Move!
What do you think you're...
Someone catch that kid!
How? How did they find out who I am?!
Was it because I used
the name "Shin'ichi Kudo"
during the karaoke murder case?!
And then they heard from somewhere
that I'd survived the drug...
Damn it! I told the inspector
not to mention my name!
I'm so stupid! It's all my fault!
What now, Shin'ichi Kudo?
Should I go back and tell Ran everything?
No, they'd be in danger
if I go back now...
Dammit! What do I do?!
What?! He got away?!
Yes, I was careless. But it seems
the boy really is Shin'ichi Kudo...
I see. To think he really did shrink...
OK. Look for him. It'll be
a pain if he goes to the cops.
But where?
Don't worry. His next destination
will be probably be there...
Dr. Agasa's House
Guess I got no choice but to talk to Dr. Agasa,
since he knows the situation...
But what's taking him so long?
Where is he wandering around now?!
He's back!
Doc!
Sweet dreams, kid.
Where am I?! Seems to be a kitchen, but...
Damn it, my head's still dizzy...
I'm on the first floor!?
I see. I was carried into this
old house while I was unconscious.
What? You still haven't killed him?!
Don't yell at me!
Those were the orders from above...
It's that woman. And is
that a man in front of her?
The organization wants him,
as an example of the drug's side-effects!
Ah! So that's why she didn't kill me!
Still, that man...
W-What?!
Who is that masked man?!
Oh, crap! He's coming!
Is he awake?!
No, he's still drugged.
Still, is that really the high school
detective Shin'ichi Kudo?
I still can't believe it myself.
But the day Shin'ichi Kudo
went missing coincides
with the day that boy
appeared at that agency,
and all the crimes that happened
around him were solved easily.
The only thing I can think of is that the organization's drug really did shrink him...
Then shall I try it, too?
Try?
I too have some of the organization's latest poison.
If I make someone take it, we can
find out if it really shrinks people.
But who do we give it to?
The man we're dealing with tomorrow.
As soon as the deal is done,
we're supposed to get rid of him.
It's the perfect chance to test the drug.
What if we do find out it shrinks people?
For now, we'll just kill the man
we're dealing with, and then...
...get rid of the kid.
I just told you!
Our orders are to take the kid back
so the organization can investigate the drug's side-effects!
We can't let people know the organization's secrets!
But...
Enough!
We're doing things my way.
Don't give me another corpse to carry!
Understood...
Anyway, did you tell the man
where tomorrow's deal is going down?
Yes, using the usual method.
The deal is at 1:00 PM.
Get sleep until then.
Alright. They're both fast asleep...
Yikes! He's sleeping with the mask on!? Talk about creepy!
Anyway, I need to get these
ropes off and get out of here!
A wine bottle!
Alright! Wrap it in this mat and...
Crap! Did they hear that?!
Looks like I'm in the clear.
Okay! Now to use a shard...
I somehow managed to get the rope off...
...but how do I get
out of this first-floor room?
Even with the snow,
it'd be too dangerous to jump out...
Guess my only choice is
to hide in that fridge...
What's that sound?
Oh! That wine must be
dripping somewhere...
W-What's this?!
What? The kid's gone?!
Yeah! He was gone when I got up!
He must've gone out the window!
Damn him!
He used the snow as a cushion to
get down! He's not getting away!
What're you doing?!
Let's go find him!
No, wait. He's still here...
Say what?
He pretended to escape,
and is waiting for us to leave.
There you are...
Die!
Oh, my. Your hunch was wrong.
Well, he has no place to go anyway.
After today's deal is over,
we'll find and eliminate him.
I was sure I was done...
Thank goodness I found this
storage area beneath the mat then...
Alright! Guess I'll look for that drug
while I have the chance!
Damn, can't find it...
Dr. Agasa said we could
find a way to make me normal again
if we could figure out the drug's composition...
I guess he took it all
for today's deal...
What's with this newspaper?
It has holes all over it...
They must've cut out letters
to make a message
for the guy they're dealing with...
That's right! They said they're
going to kill that guy! This is bad!
I've got to find out where the deal is,
stop the murder, and get the drug!
Guessing the missing letters
gives me i-te-ho-be-ru-ka.
Rearranging them gives me "Beika Hotel..."
The Beika Hotel!
But it doesn't specify where in the hotel.
Are any other letters missing?
No luck, none have been cut out...
Cutter marks!
Ah! It was the August page
above it that was cut!
Which means the August day
above September 27th is... 30!
"Beika Hotel 30!" That's where
their deal's taking place!
Beika Hotel
But what does "Beika Hotel 30" mean?
This hotel only has 19 floors,
and there's no Room #30...
#19? One moment, please.
That's it! It could be
a baggage number! All right!
Excuse me!
Yes?
My daddy lost his number tag. It's #30...
#30?
That's strange.
We only have up to #26...
Huh? Kid?
Damn! Where is it?!
Crap! It's already past noon!
And the deal is at 1:00!
Oh no! I forgot my wallet in the car!
Hey, hey...
Where did we park again?
#42. Here's the key.
Sorry! I'll be right back!
T-The parking lot?
This is the car parked on #30...
Could the deal be happening in here?!
But there's no one inside...
Hey! What're you doing?!
What're you doing to our car?!
Daddy! He must be a thief!
No, it's not like that! I just
thought it was a cool car!
These people seem
completely unrelated...
Guess it's not here, either...
Whoa, a huge man!
What's he looking at?
The parking space number?
There's a small "1" written
in chalk next to the "30"!
Ah! "301" must be
a room number at this hotel!
And he's probably the guy
they're dealing with!
The masked man!
So this is where
they're making the deal!
It's that woman!
Oh, crap! I'm trapped!
That masked man will kill me
for sure if he catches me again!
What do I do?! What do I do?!
What do I do?!
OK, Masao. The door locks by itself,
so you just need to close it!
Well, be good while I'm gone!
Have fun, Mommy!
You're late.
B-Burglar!
Shh! I'm not a bad guy!
I'm Space Detective Conan,
I'm here to catch evil aliens
from Planet Rampo!
Liar! You're just a kid!
I'm simply borrowing this
child's form to deceive my foes!
Then show me your normal form!
No, that's not...
You are a burglar!
Hold on!
Just you wait! I'm gonna
call the cops on you!
Stop that, Masao! Knock it off!
T-That's my mommy's voice!
I'm an alien from Planet Rampo!
I can use any voice at all!
Wow! That's awesome!
You really are a space detective!
Looks like I managed to fool him
with this voice changer...
Hey! Is there any way I can help?!
There sure is! For now,
I'd like to use your phone,
and do you have any chewing gum?
Yeah! I do! But what for?
What?
I've brought your food and wine!
Eh? We didn't order any.
Eh? But we got a call earlier...
That's odd.
It's fine. I am feeling hungry.
Have it brought in.
But...
Silence! Bring it in!
All right. Bring it in.
Right...
C'mon, pick up the pace!
Now get lost!
Gum in the lock?
Well, let's start with a toast!
Let me first introduce
our other guest...
Other guest?! Don't tell me
that kid's under here!
What? He's not here...
The cart's a decoy. He's really...
inside this closet!
Crap!
Out.
But when did he get in there?!
While we were talking
with the bellboy,
he put gum in the door to
defeat the automatic lock.
He then snuck in while we
were focused on the cart.
Did you think I'd fall
for such a trick?
Damn! My only choice is
my Anesthetic Watch Gun...
It won't work!
I had that interesting watch of yours
disabled after we caught you.
What?!
You'll regret the day
you underestimated me...
...high school detective Shin'ichi Kudo!
A toy?
You still can't tell? It's me!
The world-famous mystery writer,
Yusaku Kudo!
D-Dad? Then don't
tell me that lady is...
I'm sorry, Shin-chan!
Mom!
But the fact you couldn't tell means
I still have the skills as an actress!
Which means that big guy is...
Me!
Dr. Agasa!
Don't be so mad!
We were worried too, you know!
Yeah, Shin-chan! We stopped
by the house and you were gone!
And then Dr. Agasa told you
about how I shrank,
and then you cooked up this scheme?
I tested your detective skills!
And you successfully followed
all of our clues to make it this far!
Everything was just as I had calculated,
until you were shot.
So then you knew I was hiding
in that kitchen's storage area?!
Of course! Well, you just
barely passed as a detective,
but it's your own fault for
not realizing I was dressed as
the Night Baron character
from my novels!
You jerk! That was no time for that!
I thought I was about to die!
Oh, is that so? Well, what do you say
we leave this dangerous country
and live together leisurely overseas?
Eh?
That's right, Shin-chan!
We did this so you would
realize the situation you're in!
That's why I helped out
with their act, Shin'ichi-kun!
I have friends in the Interpol.
I'll have 'em look into this organization.
They'll get the drug at some point,
and you can be returned to normal.
So let's put an end to this
dangerous detective game you're—
Forget it!
This is my case! I'll solve it!
You guys stay out of this!
Shin-chan...
Plus, I can't afford
to leave Japan yet.
Shin'ichi!
It's all right.
Let's humor him for a while.
Honey...
But the instant things get dangerous,
we're taking you overseas.
As it seems you have other reasons
for not wanting to leave...
You're leaving your son with us again?!
Yes, he insists on staying here...
Still, Miss...
Here is his upbringing expense.
Use however much of it you like.
10 million yen!
Of course! I'd be delighted
to take care of your adorable
and well-behaved son!
Oh, and Ran-san.
Yes?
Please take care of him for me.
It seems he likes you.
Oh! Really, Conan-kun?
Yeah...
Why, you...
That sure was fun!
Dropping my manuscripts and
escaping to Japan was worth it!
But will Shin-chan be all right?
Don't worry.
He'll admit defeat sooner or later.
Hey! What do you say to a trip
around the world?!
Oh, that sounds great!
There he is!
It's the foreign magazine editors!
How'd they find me?!
We got a call from your son!
Now finish the last 308 pages!
Screw that! I'm first!
He stopped our presses!
He got us good.
Why, that little...
W-What was that?!
Looks like we can assume dynamite was planted in this room.
An act of tears?
T-This knife! Ryoji was behind this!
You're the killer!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Fertilizer
Next time, there's a surprising culprit!
Hope to see you at our movie this year!