As times change,
difficult cases increase in number!
Today's case involves three siblings!
Mysteries upon mysteries!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Ugh! And I came all this way because he said it was a big incident...
You should've just taken the case!
Yeah, right! I'm not gonna search for some lousy missing iguana!
Sounds perfect for you...
What seems to be the matter?
My car broke down on me. Could I ask for a lift to my villa up ahead?
I'll compensate you, of course.
I'd be glad to give you a lift!
Thank you. My name is Hotta.
It's nice to meet you!
Kosaku Hotta, Pres. Of Hotta Industries
H-Hotta Industries!
Hotta Industries —
President
Kosaku Hotta (58)
You run that huge corporation?!
Hey, Yamauchi.
S-Sir!
What happened?!
My car broke down. These folks gave me a ride.
Villa Caretaker
Masahiro Yamauchi (55)
Is that so? I'm Yamauchi, the caretaker of this villa.
Thank you for helping him.
It's nothing! I'm sure he would've done the same!
Are Koichi and the others already here?
Yes. Everyone is worried because you're late.
I wonder. I bet they hope I died in an accident...
Say, Mouri-san. Tonight is my birthday party.
I'd like to invite you, as thanks...
Oh, but...
You don't mind, do you?
Don't mind if I do!
You didn't arrive on time, Father, so we were worried
Eldest Son
Koichi Hotta (39)
you had gotten in an accident along the way.
Yes! Hotta Industries is nothing without you, Father!
Koichi's Wife
Harumi Hotta (36)
Second Son
Ryoji Hotta (28)
For sure! The company needs you to stay well for a long time to come!
Chateau Petrus, 1979. From Koichi-sama.
Hey. Is that expensive wine?
Yes. Eye-poppingly expensive.
It's the king of red wine!
Now then, let us toast to Father's 58th birthday.
Hold it!
Why don't you drink first, big brother?
What is that supposed to mean?!
Just figured it wouldn't be funny if there was poison in it...
How rude, Ryoji-san!
I've heard the rumors.
The overseas branch has taken big hits because of your poor forecasts.
And I hear you're going to be dismissed and sent to a subsidiary.
You're suggesting I'm planning to kill Father over that?!
I hear you've racked up some heavy-duty gambling debts lately!
M-Mind your own business!
Enough!
My dinner...
I've had just about enough of this!
I see my brothers are as close as ever.
Sis!
Eldest Daughter
Fumiko Hotta (30)
Fumiko!
Why are you here?
What a harsh hello, after sending an invitation yourself.
We severed all ties five years ago! I'd never send you an invitation!
I don't want to see your face! Get out!
You're the one who called me here to tell me something!
I have nothing to say to you!
Tonight was supposed to be a feast, too...
Oh, Dad.
Say, what happened between Hotta-san and Fumiko-san?
Good question. I've only been their caretaker for two years,
so I don't know what happened long ago.
Whiskey, huh? Whose present is this?
W-W-What the—
S-Sir!
A bomb...
W-What the—
Call the police!
R-Right!
Looks like I can assume a bomb was planted in here.
That's absurd!
Stay out! Please wait outside until the police arrive!
And just who are you?!
The world's greatest detective, Kogoro Mouri!
Kogoro Mouri?!
The famous detective?!
This was dynamite...
Doesn't smell like dynamite to me.
Trying to butt in again, huh?!
He has wood and glass fragments in him!
Stupid kid! Oww!
This is a whiskey display box!
Ah! The glass stuck in him is from a bottle!
What's that?
The bomb was inside the whiskey box!
That's why there are fragments all over Hotta-san's body!
I see—
I don't need you to tell me! I realized that long before you!
Yeesh...
Dirt? What's it doing in here?
Dad!
Where's Yamauchi-san?
He says the phone is out...
Say what?!
If anyone here holds a grudge against Father... it's you, Fumiko!
Yeah! You hadn't spoken in five years!
Suddenly showing up now without an invitation is undeniably strange!
Yes. I did hate him. Enough to want to kill him!
But I didn't do it. Though I do thank whoever did.
I assume you all feel the same.
What horrible siblings...
How are the phone lines?!
They've been cut by a knife or something...
A knife?!
What should we do, Mouri-san?
What's this?
The bomb was planted inside a whiskey box.
Eh? T-This display box was—
You recognize it?!
Well...
Out with it!
I believe it was a present Ryoji-sama gave to him...
I remember because I took it to his room.
R-Ryoji did it?!
Say, where is Ryoji-san?!
He ran off...
That can't be!
A knife!
This is Ryoji-sama's car.
He hasn't gotten far, if he left his car behind...
Eh? Does that mean he's still lurking about?!
What's this?! It's been slashed!
Mouri-san. What do we do now?
It's probably best to leave in our cars.
Not an option.
What?!
All four of these cars have slashed tires.
What?! Does that mean we can't leave this villa?!
Ryoji did this. There's rubber stuck on his knife!
How did you get here?
We can't drive, so we took a limo...
Are there any other cars?
There's my car. But it's broken and hardly in a usable state...
Say, if Ryoji-san is the killer, why would he slash his own tires?
Isn't it obvious? If his tires were the only ones not slashed,
the police would suspect him right off the bat.
That's strange. He would still be suspected right off the bat
if his whiskey exploded and he disappeared right after!
Ryoji-san didn't do this.
But if the killer's goal was actually to trap everyone inside this villa...
...something else might happen!
In any event, Ryoji-san is still lurking around here.
Make sure to stay together and not go off alone!
Screw that! I'm going back to my room!
Geez, right after I warn her...
Let us all go back inside.
Right...
Mouri-san. I'll try to fix my car...
Be extremely careful.
Hey, kid! Let's go!
Okay!
Fumiko-san's pendant...
Fumiko-san.
Quiet! I'm busy right now!
Are you looking for this?
Eh?
Give that back!
Thanks, little boy. This is the most important thing to me.
Is that your lover?
He died, five years ago. Suicide—
no, it was more like murder.
By Hotta Kosaku, my father!
That's why I left. I couldn't forgive my father...
Oh, I'm sorry. I guess there's no point in telling this to a little kid...
Fumiko-san held a grudge against Hotta-san.
But did she have a chance to plant the bomb in the whiskey box?
What's this?!
Chemical Fertilizer
Chemical fertilizer! Could that bomb have been...
Just as I thought!
Sulfur
Sulfur and chemicals! And that chemical fertilizer!
No doubt about it! That person is the killer!
This person is—!
Is it fixed?
Eh? Oh, Conan-kun...
That car sure is old!
It's the first one I ever designed.
You were a car designer?
Yes, until five years ago.
I quit after something happened...
I've never seen a car like this before!
Huh? It's an old-style car, but it has an airbag...
Uhh, Conan-kun, could you go get Fumiko-san?
What for?
To get the police. Everyone feels uneasy with just Mouri-san, right?
What about you?
I'm the caretaker. I have a responsibility to stay here.
Okay!
Ah, time for food!
Where's Conan-kun?
Probably off playing somewhere.
What a lost cause. I'll go find him.
My food...
There's no need to be shocked. This photograph was in your room.
You went into my room without permission?!
I found something interesting in there...
Sulfur and other chemicals, hidden inside a cabinet.
The explosive wasn't dynamite. It was a homemade bomb
made of chemical fertilizer, sulfur, and other chemicals!
You can make a bomb out of that?!
Indeed, you can.
If mixed properly, it can produce an explosive as powerful as dynamite.
Ridiculous! Why would I want to kill the master of the house?!
This incident was entirely to avenge the person in that photograph.
Hotta-san drove him to suicide five years ago.
Eh?
And he was your son, Yamauchi-san.
- Eh?!
You were the one who took Ryoji-san's whiskey
and delivered it to Hotta-san's room.
That's when you placed the homemade explosive inside the box,
an igniter under the lid,
and easily-ignited phosphorus in the bomb.
It was basically like striking a match.
But it wasn't meant to be a perfect crime.
Because you needed to distance yourself from suspicion
until your next crime.
His next crime?
Fumiko-san?
Well done, Mouri-san. It is just as you say.
My son Kentaro was an extraordinary pianist with a bright future.
He had dated a girl for a long time, but because of his paltry income,
he was unable to propose to her.
But five years ago, he won a competition and finally earned appraisal.
And then Kentaro proposed to her. But...
...the woman's father—Hotta-san—was against it.
S-So that woman was Fumiko-san?!
Kentaro met with Hotta to get permission to marry her.
But Hotta not only refused, but he ruined Kentaro's fingers as well!
The piano was Kentaro's life!
And he had it stolen away forever!
What's more, the woman ran off, leaving him behind devastated!
So the poor boy...
Upon learning all of this after his funeral, I was shocked to realize
that as a company man, I had known nothing about my own son...
And that's why you decided to get revenge...
Yes. After quitting the company, I investigated Hotta
and became his caretaker to find a chance to exact revenge.
But Fumiko had left the family, and it took me two years to locate her.
Then you chose Hotta-san's birthday party as the stage for revenge
and sent Fumiko-san an invitation.
Yes. Now I will have no regrets in life.
But Fumiko-san is safe and sound in the car—
The moment I got her to step into that car, my revenge succeeded.
There's a trap in the car, you see.
The airbag is set to go off when she steps hard on the brakes.
As we speak, she's probably...
You really don't know anything, do you?
Eh?
Why do you think Fumiko-san is still single, after all this time?
Because even now, she continues to love Kentaro-san!
Absurd! A rude woman disowned by her father would never do that!
She wasn't disowned! She left on her own!
She couldn't forgive her father for what he did to Kentaro-san!
That's a lie! It's nonsense!
She abandoned Kentaro!
What's this?
That's Fumiko-san's treasure.
A treasure chest filled with her memories with Kentaro-san,
and her feelings for him.
Fumiko-san always wears it at all times.
Even now, Kentaro-san is the dearest person to her, Yamauchi-san!
W-What have I done?!
I've killed the person who loved my son that much!
Fumiko-san! Didn't the airbag deploy?!
No. Mouri-san had Conan-kun tell me to come back right away...
Fumiko-san... I'm...
I hated my father, too. Enough to want to kill him.
But I can't forgive Kentaro-san, either.
He left me all alone... And drove his own father to do this...
He really is sinful...
Ryoji-san had been locked up in the basement.
Oww!
Huh?
Huh?! Where did everyone go?!
Man, I'm hungry. Oh, that's right! We're about to have breakfast!
Yamauchi-san! Breakfast, please!
I'm so hungry I could die! Anything'll do, just please hurry!
Yamauchi-san!
Dad!
It's strange! Something isn't right!
That's weird.
Eh?
You're supposed to wash makeup off before applying a face pack!
T-That's it! That person really is the killer!
Next Conan:
N-N-N-N-N-N-Next Conan's Hint: Lipstick
Next time is an amazingly unique case!
Am I pretty?