As times change,
difficult cases grow in number!
Today's case is in a mountain lodge in a blizzard!
The murder victim doesn't stay quiet, either!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Yahoo!
Eh? You're not going to ski, Dad?
Don't be stupid!
I'm taking in this nice, cloudless sky first...
Along with the grandeur of this snowy white landscape!
Damn. I knew I shouldn't have come...
Eh?! You lost the key to the rental cabin?!
Geez! It's all thanks to you two!
Guess all we can do is call the manager to bring a duplicate key.
There aren't any phone booths around here,
that cabin is still under construction,
and the ski bus already left...
The only thing nearby is that one lodge up there...
Me, ask help from some upstart with a lodge there? Forget it!
No choice! We'll open it by force!
- No, don't!
- Stop, Dad!
Say! Are you...
Oh! It is Kogoro Mouri-san, the detective!
Masashi Oyama (53)
Toto University Medical Professor
I always read about your brilliant work in the newspaper!
Wow, what a magnificent lodge!
Such an elegant color and design!
Who was talking about rich upstarts just a minute ago?
Come to think of it, I haven't heard your names yet.
Are you Mouri-san's daughter?
Yes! I'm Ran!
This is Conan Edogawa-kun.
We're watching him for a friend of ours.
Oh!
This lion-shaped door decoration is superb, too!
I was hoping for a horse,
but I guess that was asking too much...
A horse?
T-That's true. Horses would be better than lions...
No, no, that's not what I mean...
Dr. Oyama!
Oh! Nakahara-kun!
Kaori Nakahara (30)
Toto University Medical Assistant
What took you so long?!
Everyone's been waiting!
Who are these folks?
Oh, some friends I ran into just now.
Oh? You're all doctors at the same university?
Yep! We're all assistants for Dr. Oyama!
Doctors are very factional, you see.
Tomoyasu Kanazawa (48)
Toto University Medical Assistant
I've been studying under the doctor for dozens of years now.
I transferred here three years ago from some future-less professor.
Ginji Tobita (31)
Toto University Medical Assistant
I'm really glad to be where I am now.
Kaho Ezumi (30)
Toto University Medical Assistant
The essay he presented the other day was wonderful!
Oh, "Gene Therapy as Treatment for Cancer of the Large Intestine"?
The whole medical school is praising his essay right now!
Come now, with my brains, it was a piece of cake!
Thank you for the meal!
Oh no! I forgot to buy snacks to go with our drinks!
I'll go pick some up at the shop at the bottom of the mountain.
Could you get some chips?
Dried cuttlefish for me!
I'll have a salad!
Yes, yes. Here, write it all down so I know what to buy.
Yes, ma'am.
The convenience store closes before 10:00, so hurry!
Yeah, I know.
Hey! What time is it?!
8:58...
Uh oh!
What's going on?
A TV show.
He's addicted to a melodrama that gets 30% ratings!
Oh, I watch that show, too!
Huh? Where are you off to, Dr. Tobita?
Night skiing. I haven't gotten my fix yet.
I should be back by around 11:00.
Well, I guess I'll take a nice,
relaxing bath until the snacks arrive.
Say, did you call the cabin manager about our key?
I completely forgot!
That's all right! You can stay the night here!
Your father can't exactly leave in his state...
I'm going to throw out the trash.
Okay!
Wait! Tsutomu-san! Don't leave me!
I have to, Mitsue-san. We can never be together.
So, please! Forget about me!
Why?! Why can't we be together?!
I'm back!
Welcome back, Kaori!
It must've been rough with the sudden blizzard!
Dr. Tobita!
Man, can't possibly night ski with that blizzard out there!
That warms me up!
Oh, are we drinking?
How was your bath?
Just wonderful!
Oh? I had asked for a salad...
Sorry, they were sold out.
And there was no ice cream.
Who asked for ice cream in this weather?
Maybe it was Dr. Oyama? He does love ice cream...
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
His TV drama ended at 10:00,
so where could he be?
Dr. Oyama always tapes the show
and replays the best scenes afterwards.
Damn you... This was your original intent all along...
But you won't get away with this!
The great detective, Kogoro Mouri, is here!
I'm sure that he, if anyone, will get this message!
Eh? Kogoro Mouri?
The guy always in the newspaper?
Yes! My dad's a detective!
It's past 11:00 now.
I think he's taking a bit too long...
I'll go see what's up.
Huh? He's that famous detective?
Looks sure can be deceiving...
K-Kaori!
Hey! What happened?!
Dr. Oyama!
It's too late. He's dead.
This can't be!
For now, let's untie his ropes...
Stop right there!
I'd appreciate it if you don't mess up the murder scene!
Dad! They can't get police cars
or an ambulance here in this blizzard!
That so? Then I have no choice.
Looks like I, the great Kogoro Mouri, will have to take charge here!
You're still so drunk!
I'll ask just to be safe—
no one's touched anything in the room, right?
No, nothing aside from Dr. Oyama's body.
You found him first, Nakahara-san.
I assume the same goes for you?
That's right. I saw him covered in blood
and fell down in the doorway.
Was there anything of value in this room?
He does have a safe in the cabinet to the right of the TV.
Here?
It's all scratched up!
Do you know what's inside this safe?
Cash, I assume.
He always carried large sums of money with him.
So I guess they were after money...
What's with this blood trail?
It's almost as if he crawled to the wall...
And why is he sitting formally?
The blood on the table stops cleanly...
Ah. The tablecloth slipped off...
Marks from the bloodied rope!
Could this be a dying message from Dr. Oyama?!
So they used tape on the window to muffle the sound, then snuck in...
They were even nice enough to leave footprints outside the window!
I think I've got this figured out!
Hmmm...
No "hmmms"! Get outta here!
I hate to ask, but could you examine him for me?
As doctors, you're more qualified than I am.
Right.
Man, this is bad!
Even his beloved gold watch is covered in blood!
Quit joking around at a time like this!
I estimate his time of death to be between 9:30 and 10:00 pm.
I see. So it was during his TV drama?
Yes.
There are countless cuts all over his body,
but it appears he died of suffocation
after having both lungs punctured.
Suffocation?
Basically, with holes in his lungs,
he couldn't hold air to breathe.
He probably suffered terribly for 10 or 15 minutes...
That's horrible!
Who on earth would do this?!
This was most likely done for monetary gain.
After breaking in through the window,
the killer attacked and tied up
Dr. Oyama, who was watching TV,
then demanded the safe combination, but didn't get it.
Enraged, the culprit stabbed Oyama-san and fled back out the window.
Ugh, talk about dense...
Oh! This man has a cool watch! It's all sparkly!
Conan-kun!
Say, he was tied up, right?
Then he was super lucky the killer didn't take his gold watch!
How odd for someone after money to overlook a watch like that...
Then that means...
...that the killer must be pretty stupid!
But don't you think the killer must've been gutsy?
See? Look at the footprints outside!
They come straight to this room!
So what?
If it was me, I'd be afraid someone else was in the room
and would sneak around and peek in before going inside!
Dad! Does that mean...
Scratching the safe and tying Oyama-san up was camouflage,
meant to make it look like this was about money...
The killer knew Oyama-san would be watching TV alone then...
In other words, one of you four is the killer!
What?!
What the hell?!
Then let's hear each of your alibis between 9:30 and 10:00.
Kaori Nakahara (30)
Toto University Medical Assistant
I was at the convenience store.
I left at 9:00 and returned at around 9:50.
The only snacks that were sold out were salad and ice cream.
But you could've finished sooner if you rushed in your car.
It takes over 40 minutes round-trip!
If you think I'm lying, you can try it with my car!
Ginji Tobita (31)
Toto University Medical Assistant
I went night skiing, a ski slope also 40 minutes round-trip.
Do you have proof of this?
Sure do.
This lift ticket has today's date.
See, it even has the time.
Kaho Ezumi (30)
Toto University Medical Assistant
I cleaned up and washed things with Ran-chan and Conan-kun.
That's true, Dad.
She only left for 2 or 3 minutes to throw out the trash.
Tomoyasu Kanazawa (48)
Toto University Medical Assistant
I was taking a bath from 9:30 until shortly after 10:00.
There's one other person besides Kanazawa-san with a flimsy alibi.
B-Blood stains?!
Huh? But why isn't there any blood on the sofa?
Did someone put it here after the blood dried?!
Wait a minute. The blood-smeared tablecloth... Could it be?!
It matches perfectly! This lighter was sitting here!
Could this be...
Come to think of it, this afternoon, Oyama-san said...
I was hoping for a horse, but I guess that was asking too much...
That was when he asked me and Ran our names...
That's it! A horse! That's what he meant!
This really is Oyama-san's dying message!
It explains his formal way of sitting,
and the bloody lighter on the sofa!
And just as his dying message says,
the killer was that person!
Hey, mister. There's something weird on the sofa—
Knock it off, you damn kid!
What's wrong, Dad?!
I think he's drunk.
Don't be stupid! I ain't drunk!
I figured it all out!
Eh?! What, now?! What did you figure out?!
The killer. I just now figured out
who stabbed Oyama-san!
First is Tobita-san, who went night skiing.
He wouldn't have made up a fake story
that could be easily verified.
Next is you, Ezumi-san.
You only left Ran and Conan for 2 or 3 minutes.
Not enough time to have killed Oyama-san.
Which only leaves Kanazawa-san and Nakahara-san without alibis.
Hold on! I bought the snacks that everyone asked—
Then how much did it all cost?
I forget!
No, you didn't forget. You don't know.
Because you bought large amounts of all kinds of snacks in advance.
You bought them this afternoon when you bought the food for dinner.
Before the murder, you took everyone's orders,
and then pretended to leave in your car.
You then stopped somewhere
and pulled out the snacks they ordered.
Now that you had an alibi,
you went and murdered Oyama-san.
Don't be stupid; you have no proof!
No, you know yourself that there's proof
in this room that you did it.
Have a look at the table.
The blood ends cleanly.
Doesn't it seem like something was on it?
The tablecloth!
Please put it on the table so that it matches with the blood stains.
That is Oyama-san's dying message.
How is this a message?
Think back. Oyama-san died while sitting formally.
Masashi Oyama
Tomoyasu Kanazawa
Ginji Tobita
Kaho Ezumi
Kaori Nakahara
It should start to become clear.
Each of your names includes characters used in shogi (Japanese chess).
Masashi Oyama
Tomoyasu Kanazawa
Ginji Tobita
Kaho Ezumi
Kaori Nakahara
S-Shogi?
Say, Dr. Oyama always said how a horse would make the full set.
Yes. You make up all the pieces but a knight.
Ran. Take the lighter on the sofa and put it on the tablecloth.
Right.
There's only one place the blood on the lighter matches the tablecloth.
Here.
"Kaori"
This is a lance!
Yes. That is a lance's starting position.
This is a dying message that gives your name, Kaori Nakahara-san!
But how did you know that before putting the tablecloth on the table?
Look closely.
That square is the only one with long blood trails.
In other words, it was on the very edge of the table.
I see!
It just coincidentally turned out that way!
Then why did you move it?
It was you who tossed the tablecloth aside, yes?
No! It must've happened when
the killer and Dr. Oyama struggled!
No. The blood on the table ends cleanly,
and the sofa the bloody lighter was on has no blood at all.
This is proof that someone moved it after the blood dried.
In other words, the killer must've returned to the scene,
noticed the message, and tossed it aside!
Am I wrong, Kaori Nakahara-san?!
Kaori...
Your undoing was that you noticed the message after you screamed.
And one other thing—
you said they were out of salad and ice cream,
but setting aside the salad, selling out of ice cream is—
That's enough!
That's right! I killed him!
Why would you do that to him, Kaori?!
You got along so well!
Yes, he was like a father to me.
That's why I couldn't forgive him...
I couldn't believe he'd steal my paper from me!
Paper? You don't mean...
"Gene Therapy as Treatment for Cancer of the Large Intestine"?!
That's right! He stole it from me!
After I had spent six whole years pouring my life into that essay!
Yes, the paper I wrote for my late father's sake...
My father died of large intestinal cancer when I was very young.
The reason I became a doctor devoted to large intestinal cancer
was to prevent any more cases like my father's!
Yet, after he stole the paper I had finally completed, that man...
There's no point.
Nobody'll listen to you if you said you wrote it.
But society will pay attention if a famous professor makes it public!
I'm sure your father would be happier that way!
It was then that I devised this plan.
I decided to kill the man who stomped on my feelings for my father
by puncturing his lungs,
one of the worst ways to die...
But I never once imagined
he would leave a dying message
during those 10 to 15 minutes of agony!
But great detective.
There was one mistake in your theory.
I had predicted the ice cream and salad.
They were sold out of salad, but I did buy ice cream.
Then why?
It melted inside the car.
I had everyone's snacks ready,
and told myself, "OK, time to kill him."
And then I suddenly thought back to my father.
After spacing out for a while, the car's heater had melted it...
To think his ice cream would trip me up...
It's ridiculous!
Dying messages. Sometimes, they're expressed in unusual ways.
Got your angel!
Your silver general is going to waste!
Alright! Now it's finished!
Sometimes, when you change your perspective of something ordinary...
Look from above!
"Idiot"
Idiot?!
Why, you!
Dead in the pool?!
He drowned to death.
Just because you've been in water before
doesn't make you an expert!
Don't tell me you painted what you saw from here?!
This is! Ah, now I get it! That person was the killer!
Yes, this was a murder made to look like an accident!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Cap
Next time, it's an "in" sports club!
Hey, Genta! Run it one more time!
I can't do any more.