As times change,
difficult cases will increase in number!
Today's stage is a sports club!
Let's train both our minds and bodies!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
After winning a raffle, we were invited to a sports gym
the day before its grand re-opening.
I-I can't go on...
I'm exhausted... I can't move...
How pathetic.
Your booze and lack of exercise has gotten to you!
Don't be stupid!
Detectives fight from the neck up!
More like from the neck down in your case...
These renovations have been the earnest wish of our sports club!
Sports Club Owner
Reiko Saeki
As a former high-diver,
I really understand the greatness of sports!
So it was my hope to help others get in shape and better their health...
Hey, Conan-kun.
Let's ditch my dad and check out the pool!
Yeah!
The glass exterior is so wonderful!
They're doing high-diving up there!
That's a high-diver from this club;
I think his name is Saijo-san!
High-Dive Competitor
Naoya Saijo
You're up, Naruse! Don't mess up now!
What was that?!
And you wanna be team captain, Naruse?!
High-Dive Competitor
Kei'ichi Naruse
I haven't gotten enough practice with all the preparations lately.
That the only reason you haven't practiced enough?
What's that supposed to mean?!
In any case, diving like that,
it's clear how the tournament'll turn out.
W-What did you say?!
Stop it, you two!
There are people here! And the media!
You sure you should be acting all big, Kijima?
I-I'm not trying to act big...
Competitive Swimmer
Hisashi Kijima
With that lame earring...
Are you really fit to boss people around?
Hey, Naruse! Get back to practice!
I think that's Kijima-san, Saijo-san's former rival...
Saijo-san took his place as team captain,
so he switched to competitive swimming...
Here we have our prized competitive swimming and high-diving pool.
They're in the middle of high-dive practice as we speak!
Look out!
I know the tournament's soon, but don't go overboard, Saijo-kun!
You're our ace, you know!
I wonder.
Your look says, "What a pity he survived."
Oh, you're such a kidder, Saijo-kun!
Nothing compared to you, though.
You're low!
I know that you want to say
the re-opening will fail if even a rumor
hits the media or tax office!
Tax office?
Conan-kun.
What're you doing here?
Oh, uhh...
Saijo-kun.
We're having a job-well-done party in my office at 8:00!
Don't forget!
Well, guess I'll get a little more practice in.
A hidden camera photo?
The man is that Naruse guy...
Hey, you dropped something!
Hey, you dropped this!
Oh, sorry. I always wear earplugs during practice, you see.
Thanks.
This is my pay dirt.
Pay dirt?
And another!
That smarts...
You brought it on yourself!
You should work out instead of smoking and drinking!
Yeah, that's about the only thing you have going for you...
But that club sure was great!
We should join, Conan-kun!
Yeah!
Right, Dad?
Eh?
Oh! I have a call on my answering machine!
Come on, Dad!
Let's see, is it about work?
Ugh...
Mouri-kun. It's me, Megure.
The Inspector?
I hate to ask, but could you come
to the Saeki Sports Club right away?
Along with Ran-kun and Conan-kun.
One of the instructors, Naoya Saijo-san,
was found dead in the pool!
What?!
Inspector!
Oh! You came, Mouri-kun!
Sorry I'm late. So, what do we have?
It's just as it looks.
We'll need to wait for an autopsy,
but the estimated time of death
is between 8:00 and 9:00 PM.
It appears that—
He drowned.
Just because you've been in water before
doesn't make you an expert!
He's absolutely correct.
After all, the body's condition points entirely to a drowning.
See the foam coming from his nose and mouth?
And the slight bit of blood from his ears.
The water in his mouth and nose
produced pressure on the inner ears.
They're both characteristics of a drowning, right?
T-That's right, but how did you know that?
Eh? Oh, I think it was on a suspense TV show the other day...
But he was a professional swimmer.
It's hard to see him drowning...
Huh? Did he hit his forehead on something?
See? There's a mark on his cap!
Exactly. It seems he messed up during his high-diving practice.
I hear it's quite dangerous practice indeed...
I asked you here because you saw him practicing this afternoon,
and I wanted your testimonies.
It was a very close call then;
I guess he wasn't so lucky this time...
Say, was there nobody else here?
Was Saijo-san practicing alone?
Hey, you! Shut up for a minute!
So?
I'm certain of it.
Everyone else had finished preparing for tomorrow
and were in the back office
at 8:00 for a job-well-done party.
A tournament is coming up,
so Saijo-san practiced whenever he could.
Probably tonight, too...
We also have a witness. There's no question about it.
A witness?
Yes. An old man on the second floor of those apartments
says he saw someone doing high-dive practice all alone.
But he didn't see the accident itself, right?
W-Well, no, but...
Shut up!
Say, I think Saijo-san always wore earplugs when practicing.
Yes, the examiners removed them earlier...
Here they are.
He had different ones this afternoon.
Probably switched 'em.
There's nothing unusual about that!
Then what about his cap?
What about his cap, Conan-kun?
High-divers don't usually wear caps, you know?
So? People can do different things sometimes!
Quit looking at every little thing!
Conan-kun!
Let him go.
Say, was Saijo-san's locker locked?
Huh? No, it was unlocked... But who're you, little boy?
You know, he's the kid staying with Detective Mouri.
Oh yeah?
What's this smell?
This is chloroform!
No question about it! This was a murder!
A couple details are a bit fuzzy,
but it appears this was an accident.
What?! You gotta be kidding me!
This was clearly a murder!
Thanks for coming, Mouri-kun.
No, I'm glad I could help, Inspector!
Hold on, now!
Are we just gonna leave like this?!
Umm, this won't affect our re-opening tomorrow, will it?
Hmm, well, the police will be finished tonight,
so it should be all right.
Hear that, everyone?
What happened to Saijo-kun was terrible,
but it was an accident!
We'll re-open tomorrow as scheduled!
Just to be on the safe side, do your final checks—
Damn! I have to hurry!
The incident occurred after we left.
It would be hard for an outsider to get inside.
Therefore, it's highly likely that the killer was someone on the inside!
Hey, you guys!
What is it, little boy?
The job-well-done party was here, right?
Did anyone leave during it?
I dunno...
If so, I didn't notice.
It was a pretty lively party.
Thank you!
In other words, it wouldn't have been impossible to sneak out.
Those three who opposed Saijo-san...
Reiko Saeki, blackmailed over tax evasion...
Hisashi Kijima, who had his leadership position stolen...
Kei'ichi Naruse, blackmailed with adultery photos...
The killer is definitely one of them!
The problem is that old man's testimony...
It greatly hinders my theory...
Guess I'll have to go there myself!
Yes, little boy?
Hello! My name is Conan Edogawa!
A detective told me to come hear your story.
My story?
You're a painter!
It's just an old man's hobby.
Did you paint this based on what you saw from here?!
That's right.
Painting at a set time everyday is an old man's excitement!
A set time?!
Yes. I drew that picture tonight, too...
Saijo-kun, was his name?
What a pity...
Turning off the lights,
practicing intensely... He brought it on himself.
He turned off the lights?!
Yes. His diving form made a silhouette with the full moon behind him.
So you didn't actually see Saijo-san's face tonight, then?!
That's right. It was very beautiful...
It sparkled so beautifully...
The image came right to me so I painted it right away.
I call it, "Diving Against the Moonlight."
Beautiful? If he hit his head,
he would've lost his balance and fallen!
This is—! Ah, now I get it!
That person was the killer!
Hey, you! Where were you?!
You had us worried, Conan-kun!
Uh oh!
You're in trouble now! Get over here!
No!
Stop! Get back here!
Get back here!
Give yourself up!
Sorry, old man!
It's my butt today...
Uh oh!
Are you all right?! Dad! Conan-kun!
Ran! Gather everyone here on the double!
Eh?!
What's this about, Mouri-kun?
I know who's responsible for this incident.
Responsible?
You mean it wasn't an accident?!
That's right. This was a murder made to look like an accident!
What?!
Those earplugs were my first suspicion.
That was the killer's oversight.
After knocking Saijo-san out with a chloroform-soaked rag,
the killer plugged his ears
with earplugs different from his own.
As for the cap...
Inspector.
Was there any blood, hair, or signs
of a strike on the diving platform?
No, nothing of the sort.
Wait, was the cap meant to fool us about that?!
Precisely.
It was meant to make the poolside murder look like a diving accident.
M-My word!
The killer then threw the removed clothes into Saijo-san's locker
and left... without locking it!
But that's nothing more than circumstantial evidence, Mouri-kun!
Besides, what about the witness?!
Actually, if that witness were to always look out the balcony
at a set time every day, that changes things substantially.
What?! The balcony, at a set time?!
What do you mean?!
In short, the witness didn't coincidentally see it;
he was made to see it!
W-What?! Made to see his death?!
Don't tell me this was suicide?!
If so, there'd be no need to turn off the lights and create a silhouette.
He turned the lights off?
What for?
He didn't want his face to be seen...
That's it! He saw someone completely different!
Yes. And it was that person who killed Saijo-san!
Hisashi Kijima-san.
You used to be a diver,
but switched to swimming.
Might you have hated Saijo-san
for taking your role as team captain?
Competitive swimmers never swim without caps, correct?
Putting a cap on to avoid suspicion, even if no marks were left...
That's something only a competitive swimmer would think of!
So it was him?
That's right.
He killed Saijo-san and
made it look like an accident!
H-Hold on!
You're going to accuse me based on some guess?!
What proof do you have?!
Inspector.
At the bottom of the platform stairs is a painting the witness made.
Unwrap it and have a look.
T-This painting!
Saijo-kun...
That was done while watching tonight's diving practice.
Meaning... this is the killer?!
Look closely.
Never mind that he cut the lights to show off his diving,
there was other definitive evidence that shone in the moonlight...
The old man painted that faithfully to what he saw...
Faithfully...
An earring!
T-That can't be!
One other thing—
if the killer was an insider, he hasn't left yet!
Which means the murder weapon must be in this building somewhere.
But why would he murder him over the role as team captain?
It probably wasn't about skill.
He blackmailed you, didn't he?
T-That's right...
Half a year ago, I caused a motorcycle accident
and severely injured my girlfriend who was sitting behind me.
I dunno how he found out,
but he threatened to tell the owner and the tournament committee!
So I used my health as a reason to give him my place as captain!
But I couldn't forgive him!
He was no sportsman!
He had to pay...
It seems your mistake was making too perfect of a dive.
It was a once-in-a-lifetime performance for me.
I knew I should have,
but I just couldn't lose my balance during it!
My pride wouldn't let me...
A concrete block was later found in an office trash can.
Upon examination, it matched with Saijo-san's forehead injury,
and Kijima's fingerprints were found on it.
Dad! Earth to Dad!
Oh, crap! I forgot about him!
Dad! We should get going now!
What a nice nap! Upsy-daisy!
W-What am I doing up here?!
Oh no!
Oh, you're the son of Heizo Hattori-san,
Osaka's chief of police!
That's it! I figured out the locked room trick! And—
Conan-kun! Conan-kun, what's wrong?!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Needle, Thread and Keyholder
Next time is the first appearance of Conan's rival!
His name is Genta Kojima!
Yeah, no.