As times change,
difficult cases will increase in number!
Today's stage is a golf range!
A nice shot, full of bloodlust!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
The Golf Range Murder Case
.
BEIKA
GOLF
GARDEN
Off it goes!
I don't think he and golf mix well...
Yeah, he says he's not good at any sports that use equipment.
Then he should've said no...
The reason he picked up golf
was a phone call from Nichiuri TV three days ago.
Huh? Pro-amateur charity golf tournament?
I'm sorry, but golf's not really my—
What?! Yoko Okino recommended me?!
Yoko-chan's entering?!
I'll do it! I may not look like it,
but I'm actually a golf master!
Still...
...just because early morning is cheaper,
6:30 is too early!
Especially when you're dragging us along!
Itsui Electronics
Director of Product Development
Eisuke Tachibana (56)
Well, then! Let's work up another good sweat today!
Itsui Electronics
Product Development Manager
Minoru Yasui (44)
Yes, it's perfect exercise just before work!
Itsui Electronics
Product Development Chief
Tatsuya Okubo (35)
Thanks to you, my health's gotten much better!
Itsui Electronics
Product Development Employee
Tomofumi Minami (28)
Oh? I bet so!
.
RESERVED
What? Your stomach hurts?! What a wet blanket!
Just go to the bathroom already!
Strike three, you're out!
When is one gonna make it to the stands?
I'm gonna go watch the other people!
Don't bother them, now.
I won't!
Sir. You can have mine.
Oh, thanks.
What a brown-noser...
Little boy. You should stay away, it's dangerous here.
This is far enough away, isn't it?
Hey.
Be sure to write off his driver repair as a section expense!
Yes, I know.
See? I told you it was dangerous...
No kidding...
Nice shot!
That one really flew!
You have Sunday's farewell contest in the bag!
Yes!
That guy's done already?
He hit them at a pretty quick pace...
Plus he gave some of his golf balls to his boss.
What an obvious suck-up.
Nice shot!
Here's your driver.
Damn you!
C'mon!
Another miss?
Yep. 20 in a row...
What happened?!
Sir!
Stop! Don't touch him!
He's dead...
Ran! Call Inspector Megure!
Right!
What on earth happened?!
It was most likely a bomb that exploded.
A bomb?!
This unique acrid smell... Black powder!
Chief!
Call the police!
No, there's a hospital just down the street!
Oh! You're injured, too!
I'm fine! But we gotta get him to the hospital!
Understood!
The deceased is Director Tachibana of Itsui Electronics...
And who are you?
I'm Yasui, the section manager,
and this is Okubo and Minami.
We all work under Director Tachibana in Product Development.
Do you come here often?
Yes, as it's close to the office.
But today was the director's last day.
His last day?
He was going to be promoted to head of the New York branch.
Inspector. It appears it was black powder that was used.
And please come over here.
This is a fragment of the driver head.
And these are all ball fragments...
...but look at this.
What's this?
It appears to be a fuse.
In other words...
...the bomb was inside the ball,
and set to explode when he hit it.
Precisely.
Tell me, do all the golf balls here have red lines on them?
No, blue lines.
Blue lines?
There are some there.
I see. They have single blue lines.
Which means the red, crossed lines mark the bomb ball.
The question is, was this meant specifically for Director Tachibana,
or was it a random act of terrorism...
I think it was meant for him specifically.
Oh? Why is that?
Because all three of us here hated him enough to kill him.
Come again?!
W-What are you talking about, Minami?!
That's true.
We both had plenty of reason to kill him.
He had already taken credit for three of my product ideas,
and he always ignored you, no matter how many good ideas you had.
N-Not me! I had no problems with the director!
Drop the act.
We all know he stole your girlfriend a long time ago!
N-No! She didn't get stolen! She dumped me!
That's it! I know who killed Director Tachibana, Inspector!
You do, Mouri-kun?!
Yes! First is the M.O...
The killer mixed the bomb ball with other balls in the machine,
so that the victim would hit it!
The question then is,
who got the golf balls for Director Tachibana?
That was this Okubo person.
Meanwhile, Minami-san was in the restroom,
and the Yasui guy was at his own machine.
So it was you!
The kid's right, neither me nor Minami
touched the director's basket!
No one else could've put the bomb ball in there but you!
But that's not necessarily the case.
There's no question that Minami-san
was far away from the victim.
But not you, Yasui-san.
I hear you shared some of your golf bolls with the victim.
T-That was...
In other words,
you could have put the bomb ball in there.
W-Wait! If I did put it in there,
I could've died in the explosion too!
The machines use a queue system;
the last balls in are the last ones out.
And you finished hitting before Tachibana-san.
Could that've been so you would finish
before he hit the bomb ball?
No! I just have a habit of hitting quickly!
Isn't that right, Okubo?! Minami?!
Then one other thing...
Where were you during the explosion?
At this point, Okubo-san can also be removed as a suspect.
The reason being that he was caught in the blast, as was Minami-san.
But I believe you were by the entrance.
T-That was...
Was it because you saw the red-lined ball come up and took cover?
No! I went to order coffee!
Coffee?
Yes! The director liked to drink coffee after he finished hitting!
So I always went and ordered it 10 minutes before he finished!
He's telling the truth.
We brew our coffee from beans,
so he always asks ahead of time.
But it seems a bit too convenient that you were gone when it blew up.
In other words,
you think Yasui-san did it?
That's right!
There's no question about it!
You can't be serious!
I'm not the killer! Honest!
Yasui-san. Just to be sure, may we check your things?
Y-Yes, that's fine...
The old man's logic so far has been unusually consistent.
But if Yasui-san really was the killer...
Inspector! I found this in his bag!
This is—!
T-That's impossible!
This is immutable proof!
You had a backup ready in case of a dud!
No! I didn't put that there!
Boy, what an incredibly simple case this was!
For the great Kogoro Mouri,
it was truly a piece of cake!
This is way too simple.
Did Yasui-san not care if he got caught for killing Director Tachibana?
No... There's something we're overlooking!
Something not even I noticed!
Huh? There's a ball on the tee...
Guess the old man missed it again!
Wait! I'm pretty sure I—
I just assumed the old man hit the ball into a metal post.
But he didn't...
Then what was that sound?
Smells like explosives.
Which means this was the ball Director Tachibana hit,
and that metallic sound was when it hit a post.
Then what were those bomb ball fragments?
That's it!
This is a trick the killer set!
The real culprit is someone else!
We can talk down at the station.
Oh no! I have to hurry!
Alright! The usual method!
Inspector! Please believe me!
I'm not the killer, honest!
That's right, you're not the killer, Yasui-san.
Dad?!
Assuming the explosion happened when the victim hit a bomb ball
was a mistake from the very start!
What are you saying, Mouri-kun?!
We found a ball fragment with a fuse at the scene!
Yes, we did. But Inspector, take a look at this.
I found that ball by a metal post at the far end net.
It's not much, but it should smell of explosives.
Yes, indeed.
When the bomb went off,
Tachibana-san had hit not the red ball,
but that one with a blue stripe.
H-Hold on, now!
I don't get what you're saying!
The killer didn't place the bomb ball in Tachibana-san's machine—
he planted it inside the driver head beforehand!
Eh?!
This is where the killer was crafty.
If there were fragments left over after the explosion,
everyone would simply assume it was the ball that blew up.
Yes! After the explosion,
the killer set down a pre-prepared fragment
when given the opportunity!
B-But that would mean the killer...
Yasui-san. I believe you mentioned the director's driver repair fees?
Yes. The shaft had a crack in it, so I had Minami send it for repairs.
Minami! You—!
Minami-san.
Where did you have the driver repaired?
Oh, with us.
We also do club repair here.
In what way did you repair it?
I felt it best to turn it into a carbon shaft club.
That club was given to the director by the current CEO 15 years ago.
So the director was very attached to it...
So it was an old-fashioned wood head?
So, when did you return the repaired club to Minami-san?
I returned it to him two nights ago.
Two nights ago?!
But you gave it to the director this morning!
Meaning the driver was in your possession for an entire day and night.
Let us look back at your actions today.
Immediately after arriving here...
What? Your stomach hurts?! What a wet blanket!
Just go to the bathroom already!
That was just one of the steps of his plan.
Did you perhaps usually have Minami-san get your golf balls
and have him put ten or so in Director Tachibana's own machine?
T-That's right...
This time, he purposely said his stomach hurt and fled to the restroom
to pass that role onto you.
Moreover, he planned to narrow down the suspects to just you,
by having you be away from the scene the instant of the explosion.
He managed this by giving him the driver
just as you left for coffee.
On top of that,
to completely clear himself of suspicion,
he stood nearby so that he would get caught in the explosion.
Inspector.
Think about where Minami-san was injured.
Okubo-san received injuries to almost his entire body,
yet he only received injuries outside his left elbow and leg.
Why his left side?
Why outside, and not inside?
It's because moments before the explosion,
he quickly covered his eyes
with his left arm and hid behind a pillar.
Minami-san.
Today was the last chance you had to kill Director Tachibana,
as he was about to move to New York.
But wasn't using the driver only you could've had in the last two days
as the murder weapon a bit careless on your part?
I've always hated the director.
The director who would never acknowledge my skill,
and Manager Yasui, who never did anything but suck up to him...
So I plotted to kill the director and have him take the fall.
And you didn't care if anyone else died in the explosion?!
Had this golf range been crowded, even more people would've—
I don't give a damn about that.
Alright, let's go.
Do you think he really meant that?
Conan-kun!
After all, he...
Little boy. You should stay away, it's dangerous here.
I think he said that so I wouldn't get caught in the explosion!
Yeah.
Who knows, he might've actually been a nice person who lost his way.
Conan-kun!
W-We're late for school!
"1st Annual Nichiuri TV Pro-Amateur Charity Golf Tournament"
Yoko-chan! Nice shot!
The following Sunday,
the old man entered the golf tournament
on the condition that he be on Yoko Okino's team.
Yoko-chan was a bit unsteady, but it was a nice shot!
Next up is the famous detective, Kogoro Mouri-san!
Mouri-san! You can do it!
Leave it to me!
Is Dad gonna be alright?
Of course not.
Yikes...
Gimme a break!