As long as people are involved in modern-day crimes,
there are no unsolvable mysteries!
Today's case is about a mysterious murder weapon!
Let's use our heads to figure it out!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Created by
Gosho Aoyama
"Detective Conan"
Serialized in Shogakukan's
"Weekly Shonen Sunday"
Planning
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Character Design
Masatomo Sudo
Art Director
Yukihiro Shibutani
Art Design
Hiroyuki Mitsumoto
Director of Photography
Takahisa Ogawa
Sound Director
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
Music Producer
Hiroki Horio
(PolyGram)
Music
Katsuo Ono
Opening Theme
"Nazo"
(Zain Records)
Performed by
Lyrics
Music
Miho Komatsu
Editor
Teramitsu Okada
Story Editor
Jun'ichi Iioka
Color Key
Reiko Hirayama
Associate Producer
Takeo Izumi
Planning Support
Toyohiko Okuyama
Mitome Asai
Director
Kenji Kodama
Producers
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Masahito Yoshioka
(Tokyo Movie)
It's nice to take a leisurely walk together once in a while!
Yeah!
What's so fun about walking with that runt?!
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
What is it, Conan-kun?
A little bird...
Is it dead?
No. It looks okay.
It's still alive.
It doesn't seem to be hurt...
It flew off...
What a weird bird.
Maybe it had an anemic attack?
It's coming from that apartment building!
Whoops...
There are only two apartments occupied here!
Can I help you?
We just heard a woman scream from this building!
Are you sure? I didn't hear anything...
Welcome back. You're back early.
Is something the matter?
Well, these folks here—
Are you all right?!
It's horrible! My husband!
My husband was murdered on our balcony!
I'm Detective Mouri.
I take it you're the one who screamed?
Which room is yours?
Room 715.
Say, I looked at the mail board earlier.
Hardly anybody lives here, huh?
This place is going to be demolished this month.
So the only ones living here now
are Imoto-san, who runs his own business, and Terasawa-san here.
Allow me.
High heels and two pairs of men's shoes...
Real Estate Agent
Ryusuke Imoto (39)
He's been hit in the back of the head.
The murder weapon appears to have been a flower pot or the like.
Who are you?
My name is Dobashi.
Did you kill him?!
No!
So the cause of death was brain damage...
The killer most likely lifted up a flower pot from behind him
and brought it down as hard as possible.
Hey, Inspector.
There's a mark here,
maybe it has something to do with the murder—
Alright, you!
Will you ever learn to stop butting in during our investigations?!
Interesting.
There definitely is a mark here.
It seems extremely new compared to all the other marks.
The victim was Mr. Ryusuke Imoto, 39 years old
and president of NEED, a real estate agency.
It was his wife, Takako-san, who found him. Correct?
Ryusuke's Wife
Takako Imoto (37)
Yes.
And the person found standing in front of the body
when Mouri-kun and the others came rushing in...
Import Company Manager
Tetsuo Dobashi (55)
My name is Dobashi.
I manage an import company.
I'm Imoto-kun's former boss and the one who introduced him to his wife.
I came to see him today about a business matter.
His matchmaker, eh...
And you are?
Terasawa. I live on the 5th floor of this building.
Former Fishing Goods Store Owner
Norio Terasawa (43)
I used to run a fishing goods store.
"Used to"?
Imoto took control of my store!
He used some dirty legal loophole to do it!
He was a terrible man!
My guess is he did the same sort of things to these people too!
Well, you two?
Yes.
As their matchmaker, I shouldn't be saying this,
but he and his wife were
in the middle of getting divorced
and there was trouble about the compensation.
But that wouldn't matter if he died—
she'd get his inheritance instead!
What are you talking about?!
I heard my husband constantly refused your requests for a loan
because your company was on the verge of going out of business!
So you couldn't handle it and killed him!
What?!
Now, now. Calm down, ma'am.
By the way, Apartment Manager.
Is that main door the only way in and out of this building?
Yes.
And the only ones who entered besides the victim...
...were his wife, Dobashi-san, and Terasawa-san.
Moreover, each of you had a decent enough motive to kill the victim.
In other words, one of you three murdered him.
You can't be serious!
First you, ma'am.
Please explain the situation when you found the body.
It was a little after 5:00 when I arrived here.
More precisely, it was just after 5:05.
I record when everyone enters or leaves the building.
That'll be very handy for us!
Please continue.
The reason I came here today
was to discuss the compensation with my husband one more time,
just as Dobashi-san mentioned earlier.
He and I have been living apart for quite a while now.
When I came in,
my husband was practicing
Tai Chi on the balcony by himself.
Tai Chi?
Yes.
My husband did it every morning and evening for his health.
He didn't notice when I entered the room,
and I didn't call out to him.
When I looked out the balcony again
after using the bathroom...
...my husband was dead!
So basically, your husband died while you were in the bathroom?
Yes.
Pardon my asking, but how long were you in the bathroom for?
Only about two minutes, I think...
Which means your husband died at approximately 5:08.
While you were in the bathroom,
did you hear any sounds or people talking?
No.
Say, when you entered the apartment,
were there any shoes by the door?
Yes, just a pair of my husband's shoes.
Thank you.
Now you, Dobashi-san.
Around what time did you first arrive?
A little before 5:00, I believe.
I was to meet with Imoto-kun at 5 o'clock, you see.
More precisely, 4:58.
Just as his wife said, the reason I came here
was to ask for a loan one last time.
But...
It's pointless, no matter how hard you try!
I have no desire or reason to help you out!
Now please leave.
After that, I went to the roof.
To commit suicide.
Suicide?!
But I couldn't do it.
I stood there for a while, in a daze.
It was then that I heard her scream from the other side of the roof!
Then, when I rushed into the room...
...Imoto-san was dead on the balcony, correct?
Yes.
How about you, Terasawa-san?
What do I have to do with it?
I wasn't in the building.
We just need to make sure.
Around what time did you leave the building?
I believe it was a little before 5:00...
4:50, to be precise.
And he didn't return until just after 5:12.
But...
"But"?
He came back from his golf practice rather earlier than usual...
I changed my mind on the way there.
I've always been a bit spur-of-the-moment!
What do you think, Mouri-kun?
First, Terasawa-san.
You weren't in the building when Imoto-san was killed,
so you're not the killer.
The issue here is with his wife and Dobashi-san.
First you, ma'am!
You said you found your husband's body
after you left the bathroom,
but there's the possibility that you never went to the bathroom,
and that you killed your husband,
pretended to find him,
and then screamed!
What?!
And you, Dobashi-san!
You said you went up to the roof
after Imoto-san refused to lend you money,
but there's a possibility
you were actually in his office
or with him on the balcony!
All you can see from here
is a small part of the balcony.
It's also possible that when his wife came in,
you were on the balcony or in his office,
killed the victim while she was in the bathroom,
and then went up to the roof.
You got it all wrong!
I was already on the roof
by the time she came in here!
She even said that only Imoto-kun's shoes were by the door!
It's also possible that she didn't remember correctly!
Or do you have proof that you were on the roof the whole time?!
Proof?
No, there was no one on the roof, so...
That's right! I heard a sound!
A sound?!
Yes. It was a loud, metallic sound.
It came from the area around this balcony.
You heard a sound?
Yes. A metallic one.
Hey, could that sound have been something hitting the handrail?
See, there's a fresh mark on it!
It appears something hit it from below...
That's it! That's the sound!
The marks look similar...
But the other mark was made coming up...
Yes.
But there's no question that someone hit it.
Did you hear the sound, ma'am?
No.
I probably didn't hear it because I was in the bathroom.
That's odd...
Why would someone put a mark
in a place like that?
It makes no sense...
This handrail seems suspicious,
but in my opinion none of them
seem to be lying, either.
But Inspector!
Just because Dobashi heard a sound from the handrail
that isn't proof that he was on the roof!
He or the victim might've made the sound
while he was on the balcony!
Besides, if the killer was someone else,
that means they flew in like a bird to kill the victim,
then flew off the exact same way they came!
Which would never, ever happen!
You do have a point...
A bird? A bird?!
Come to think of it, the spot where the bird fell—
-was over there!
Directly in front of the mark on this handrail!
The location where the victim collapsed...
The location where the bird fell...
The mark on the handrail!
An abandoned building across the street?
Now I see!
This is the killer's trick!
The murder weapon wasn't a flower pot!
The killer was that person!
My deductions can't possibly be wrong.
She's his wife, who lives separately from him.
He's the president of an import company.
And he's the former owner of a fishing goods store.
Which means the killer is...
Say, Inspector.
I'll be returning to my apartment now...
Oh, right.
You can go for today...
I can't let that happen!
I have to make the old man realize it somehow!
Found it!
Have you figured anything out, Mouri-kun?
No, nothing at all...
In that case, you may leave, Terasawa-san.
Alright.
What's going to happen to me?
And me?
This is fun!
Stupid kid...
Come on, realize it!
Mouri-kun!
This is the spot where the victim collapsed.
And this is the mark on the handrail.
What are you doing?
Conan, that bird fell down there, right?
Yeah, that's right!
That's it!
The victim, the mark, that bird, and that abandoned building!
They're all directly lined up!
I know who did it, Inspector!
Really? Who?!
Don't get too ahead of yourself.
I'll explain everything atop that abandoned building!
Come again?
Come on, Mouri-kun.
What are you checking for in a place like this?
I don't see what this has to do with the murder...
Everyone gather around here, please!
First, allow me to ask.
Ma'am, Dobashi-san, Terasawa-san...
Have any of you ever been here before?
Of course not.
Me neither.
Nor have I.
Then allow me to explain.
You can see the victim's balcony from here, can't you?
Yes, but what does that have to do with anything?
Have you ever heard of surf casting, Inspector?
Surf casting?
It's a type of fishing that uses a so-called "spinning reel"
to allow the fisher to cast the line
some dozens of meters out.
The killer used this technique from here
to hit the victim's head with a weight as he stood on the balcony!
What?!
That's insane!
This footprint is the proof.
The left foot is in front and with a lot of weight on it.
This was made when the killer flung the pole in an overhand fashion.
Like this!
When he was killed,
the victim was performing Tai Chi,
which is known for its slow movements.
Using this fact,
the killer swung the fishing pole
when he turned away!
And as it was reeled in—
—the weight hit the handrail.
So that's the sound I heard?
Correct.
The killer didn't realize the weight had left a mark when it happened.
And there was one other miscalculation on the killer's part.
As the weight was being reeled in,
it hit a bird in mid-air.
The bird you picked up had probably received a concussion.
But Mouri-kun, it's over 30 meters to that balcony.
Could someone really cast a weight that far with such precision?
With enough practice, yes.
Especially for someone who's good at surf casting.
Isn't that right, Terasawa-san?
Terasawa-san.
Those shoes you're wearing right now
should undoubtedly match these footprints.
And if we look hard enough around this abandoned building,
we'll probably—
Hey! There's something on the ground here!
What's that?
I know what this is! It's a pole grip!
A pole grip?
Yeah!
Sometimes after fishermen connect fishing rods together,
they won't come undone.
So to prevent their hands from slipping,
they place rubber tubes or rubber bands
near where the rods connect,
and then pull the rods apart while twisting them in opposite directions!
You're pretty smart to know that...
I just happened to see it on a TV fishing show yesterday.
Come to think of it, they had their gloves off when they used these.
Because they would slip!
Which means the killer's fingerprints should be on it!
Terasawa-san. Your fingerprints!
I can't help but laugh.
He took over my store
and said he was going to build a fashion building in its place!
I said I'd give up ownership if he'd just spare the store, but...
There's no point in keeping this dinky store around.
What's so fun about catching fish, anyway?
What a joke!
What do you losers see in it at all?
My precious fishing rod!
He destroyed it before my very eyes!
I absolutely couldn't let him get away with it!
Your detective work last night was amazing, Dad!
My opinion of you keeps getting better!
Cases like that are a piece of cake for me!
Did he actually make that fishing rod toy
to make me realize it?!
I got something!
Got you!
Dad!
Old man!
Who am I kidding?
Get back here, Shin'ichi!
This guy's one of the men in black!
I finally found you!
Let me go before the bomber gets away!
Ah! So that's how it was!
In the eyes of the killer,
this was an unexpected murder!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Cloakroom Tag
Next time, the men in black suits will appear.
Conan, I'm gonna go back to being an adult too.