As long as modern-day crimes involve people,
there are no unsolvable mysteries!
The stage today is a first-class hotel!
I found the mysterious organization!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Beika Hotel
Your dad supervised a game?
"Mantendo Product Show"
That's right!
It's titled, "Detective Kogoro Mouri's House of Reasoning!"
The player encounters a dead body
in a mysterious mansion,
and gets hints from Detective Mouri
who just happens to be there
to solve the case!
That's practically the pattern with me every time...
But is it okay for their guest to be like that?
This is what you get for drinking so much last night
for your "pre-celebration"!
I only had 5 or 6 drinks...
Gin, vodka, bourbon...
Gin and Vodka...
Those are the codenames for the men in black
who shrunk me!
What long lines!
Of course they are!
Almost everyone in the gaming industry is here!
Mouri-san!
"Mantendo"
Game Development
Hideaki Nakajima (27)
It's me! Nakajima from Mantendo!
I planned "Detective Kogoro Mouri's House of Reasoning!"
Thanks to you, we've produced an amazing game!
You definitely excel at your work, Nakajima.
Assuming you really did plan that game.
Ueda!
"Mantendo"
Game Development
Koji Ueda (27)
I shouldn't have told you that the game would do well
if we used Detective Mouri.
Three days later, your proposal just happened to highlight that idea,
and voila, here you are.
You're a genius at stealing people's things!
Work, women...
Isn't that right, Takeshita?
"Mantendo"
Game Development
Hironobu Takeshita (27)
Yeah...
But that was back in college. It's in the past.
Well, I'll overlook it this time.
After all, you seem to be in trouble with the debt-collectors and all.
Here's the number tag for your luggage!
96.
Hey, we're really late!
What?!
We need to hurry to the show floor and get things ready!
Check this in first!
Mine too!
Hey, don't cut in line!
You should hurry too, you know!
The president will yell at you if you're late!
You have a point...
Please try not to mix ours up.
All three of you have the same briefcase!
Yes. And it's not just our briefcases—
our necktie pins and wristwatches too.
It was the company president's idea
to give ordinary people an impression of our company.
But in actuality, the briefcases are way too big and heavy.
We brought them today,
but almost everyone in the company has left them here.
The president's probably the only guy lugging one around!
Well, excuse me.
Sir!
Get to your posts!
Yes! Right away!
Despicable...
Here's your number tag!
Thanks!
How lucky!
Look, Conan-kun! Our tag number is 100 exactly!
Maybe today's our lucky day!
She's easily excited...
Ahh! Stop!
How do you like this?!
I did it! I came from behind to win!
Great job, Ran-chan!
Very few people can pull that move off!
Eh? Really?!
She might be lucky, after all...
So close! It really lights up if you get over 250...
Hey, Nakajima!
Will you come give this a try?
Sure.
It looks like Nakajima-san's going to try!
Wow! Have you ever practiced anything?
A little boxing during my college days.
Why don't you give it a shot, Ran-san?
No, that's okay...
It's a good stress-reliever!
Stress?
Get back here now, Shin'ichi!
Want to try, Conan-kun?
I need to use the bathroom!
Then let's go together, little boy.
I believe the restrooms are—
He's huge!
Does he work at the game company too?
I don't know. I've never seen him before.
All three of you were in the same boxing club during college?
Yeah.
Until he quit halfway through, anyway.
Ueda...
But to think we would all wind up in the same company...
Number 98.
That's the logo for Nakajima-san's company.
Thank you!
But that's strange.
He should have the company's necktie pin if he's an employee...
Anyway, I should buy the old man
some tomato juice for his hangover...
It's me, Tequila. The deal's done.
Don't worry, Vodka.
Pass the word on to Gin.
This guy's one of the men in black!
Just a kid. He dropped some change.
I finally found you!
Hey, Mister! Could you move your leg?
I can't get my 10-yen coin...
Don't touch me, boy!
Alright!
I stuck a hidden microphone and transmitter onto his shoe sole!
He'll lead me to the others!
To Gin and Vodka!
Huh? It won't open...
A door?
Is this empty?
A restroom stall?
Wait! Little boy!
That big man was wearing this shoe!
He was in the explosion!
Little boy! It's dangerous here!
Hurry outside!
I had finally found a clue leading to them!
Why did this have to happen?!
A terrorist attack?
My guess is that the explosives were attached
to the toilet or something else.
A random murder...
There was one victim.
Any idea who it was?
All that's left are shreds...
Did any of you see anybody suspicious?
No...
Not really...
I did!
I saw the guy who died!
You did, Conan-kun?!
He was a really big man!
He might have been from Kansai...
You saw him too, Nakajima-san!
The big man in black clothes we bumped into in the lobby!
Oh, him...
How do you know he was from Kansai?
I heard his accent in the bathroom right before he died:
"Huh? It won't open. Is this empty?"
He must've been talking about a restroom stall!
In that case, the explosives must have been set near the stall door.
Excuse me...
Company president!
President?
Yes. I'm Mantendo's president, Ishikawa.
I actually received a strange letter three days ago.
A strange letter...
"Cancel the show or else."
This is a threat letter!
Why didn't you contact the police the minute you received this?!
I apologize. I thought it was an ordinary harassment letter.
Inspector. We found this in the debris.
The key makes sense, but what's this round thing?
That's my company's emblem.
Come to think of it, that big man had one of those briefcases.
But why did he have it?
He took it from the baggage counter, but...
What tremendous power! It bent this piece of iron!
What?!
There's something strange about that emblem!
Why is it bent away from the briefcase?!
If the explosion happened outside the case,
it should be bent inward!
This was no terrorist attack! It was a murder!
Somebody wanted that man dead!
Yes. The bomber is the one who gave him the briefcase!
The deal probably took place there—
—the best place to make an exchange without arousing suspicion
by switching number tags!
The baggage counter!
No, nobody else has claimed their things except for that large man...
Which means that the other person hasn't come to claim the other bag!
Great!
There still might be clues leading to Gin and Vodka!
Where do you think you're going?
I need to see the Inspector!
No way. He's busy right now.
Let me go before the bomber gets away!
If that happens, then their—
Ran-neechan...
Where were you?!
You're hurt...
What on earth happened?
100 and 96...
Those are the number tags for our things at the baggage counter.
100 is mine, and 96 is Dad's.
He's still not doing well, so I'm holding his for him.
If I remember right, that man's tag number was—
Number 98.
Which means the other person in the deal
cut in between the old man and Ran!
It was those three!
That big man exchanged tags,
and completed the deal.
And then the instant he opened the briefcase to check its contents...
Wait.
If the goal was to kill him from the very start,
why did they choose this place to make the deal?
If an incident happens at your own trade show,
you could make yourself suspect if you're not careful.
Yet they knew for a fact that he would check the briefcase...
And the fact that the key doesn't match the briefcase bothers me.
Wait! Could I have made a really big mistake!
Number 38.
Number 56.
Looks like nobody knew who that large man was...
Nope. And nobody saw anybody suspicious, either.
Number 99, right?
Yes!
Number 97.
Here.
Number 124.
What?
No, nothing.
Hey, you guys should check your briefcases.
They all look the same, after all.
No, that's alright.
There's nothing important inside, anyway.
Wait a minute! Could this be... Now I see! So that's how it was!
In the eyes of the killer,
this was an unexpected murder!
Alright, folks.
You can go home for today,
but if anyone recalls seeing someone
who might have been the bomber,
please contact me at the police headquarters!
This is bad!
If they let everyone leave now, we'll never know who did it!
Damn it!
I have an idea who the bomber might be,
but I'm still not sure!
I have no choice.
I'll have to use the old man's voice and body
to lay a trap!
It hit Ran in the butt!
Are you alright, Dad?
Hey. Do you still got my number tag?
Why isn't Ran getting sleepy?
Don't worry, I have it here in my pocket.
Oh, it hit the tag...
But I only have one sleeping dart!
Let's get our stuff and go home already...
Alright.
Pervert!
Don't tell me that was you...
It was lint! There was some lint on your bottom, so—
You really should put your leg down now...
Dad!
Are you alright?!
I'm fine, Ran.
You just helped me realize something.
Realize something?
Inspector Megure.
You can't let the people leave just yet.
You can't be serious!
We're dealing with a random bomber!
There could be more bombs!
A random bomber?
There were never any bombs planted in this hotel.
That bomb was planted in that man's belongings
in order to specifically kill him.
Do you wish to let them go,
even though the bomber is among them?
What? You know who did it?!
If we check the contents of something,
the person responsible will admit to doing it.
The contents of what?
That would be—
Nakajima-san.
The contents of that briefcase you've been holding so importantly!
Let us see what's inside.
No, you can't!
You idiot! Do you want to look like the murderer?!
Show them!
Let go!
Stop!
Takeshita!
Now there's no doubt about it.
Takeshita-san. You're the bomber.
How so, Mouri-kun?!
Because he thought the bomb he put in the briefcase would explode.
A bomb inside the briefcase?!
Indeed.
The briefcase emblem found at the scene of the explosion
was bent away from the case.
In other words, it received a shock from the inside.
Meaning that the bomb was inside the briefcase.
Wait. Then when he said,
"Huh? It won't open. Is this empty?" he meant—
That's right.
The key wouldn't open the briefcase.
And it was the briefcase's cover that was empty.
So he gave that briefcase bomb to that large man?
No.
The person the victim was making a deal with gave him the briefcase...
...you, Nakajima-san!
The deal was done by having everyone temporarily check their bags in
and then exchanging number tags afterward.
As proof of this,
I got #96 and my daughter Ran got #100.
But Ueda-san, Nakajima-san, and Takeshita-san
cut in between us.
Naturally, their tag numbers would have been 97, 98, and 99.
But for some reason,
when Nakajima-san went to claim his briefcase,
his tag was—
Number 124.
And then the tag of the large man Conan overheard was—
Number 98.
The tags were probably exchanged
when Nakajima-san and Conan
bumped into the man.
The man then took Nakajima-san's briefcase from the baggage counter.
The instant he checked the contents while inside the restroom—
But why didn't the key fit?
Of course it wouldn't fit.
Takeshita-san had switched that briefcase in advance.
Yes.
Because Takeshita-san had meant for that briefcase bomb
to kill Nakajima-san!
What?!
Your number tags were probably switched
when you had Nakajima-san play that punching game.
But when Takeshita-san checked the briefcase bomb in,
a dangerous problem arose.
My baggage tag number was 96.
Nakajima-san was close behind me,
so it was certain that he would be in the 90's too.
But Takeshita-san hadn't gotten in line yet,
so he would be in the 100's.
There was a good chance Nakajima-san might notice later
if he switched their two numbers.
That's why Takeshita-san cut in between me and Ran...
To ensure his tag number would be in the 90's,
the same as Nakajima-san's!
But is there any proof?
Yes...
The briefcase Takeshita-san has right now
is the one Nakajima-san was supposed to give the large man.
The key found at the scene of the explosion
should fit it perfectly.
And it was a Mantendo original briefcase that exploded.
It should be obvious once you inspect all the briefcases
belonging to Mantendo employees here today
that Takeshita-san's is the only one missing.
Because his briefcase was blown to pieces.
To think that explosion was from a bomb I set...
I even wrote a threatening letter
to make it look like an act of terrorism.
Boy, is my face red!
Takeshita!
That's right! You were supposed to die!
You murdered Yoshimi!
Yoshimi?
The manager of our boxing team
during our college days.
She committed suicide after Nakajima dumped her.
Suicide?
Yoshimi had been very close friends with Takeshita
ever since middle school.
So he must have been—
- Let me go! I'm innocent! He did it!
- That Takeshita.
You narrowly avoided being murdered, Nakajima-san.
But what do you say we move on to the real issue here?
The man in black you were making a deal with...
Who exactly was he?!
Um...
You've ruined the deal—
their organization is going to come after you, no matter what.
Organization?!
I think your wisest choice would be to tell us everything
and seek police shelter...
I really don't know anything!
Just that the place I met them at was always the same.
A bar named "Cocktail," on the top floor of the Daikoku Building...
"Cocktail," at the Daikoku Building!
Hey, Mouri-kun! What organization are you talking about?!
Hey!
Daikoku Building
So this is the place!
I made it!
I finally found them!
I finally made it here!
What?!
Damn it!
Stay out of there, little boy!
Let go! I'm not a little boy!
I'm... I'm...
Let go!
According to police investigation afterward,
the amount of explosives used was incredible,
and the bar was completely obliterated.
There was no way to tell
if anybody had been inside.
All that I found out this time
was that the men in black were attempting to purchase
a list of the world's top programmers
that Nakajima-san had smuggled out of the company.
Are Gin and Vodka dead?
Or did they disappear on their own?
Everything remains a mystery.
Just as the black smoke covers the sky...
...so too is the case buried in darkness.
Hey, Mister! Your button's about to fall off!
This was neither an accident nor a suicide!
It was a homicide! A murder!
Why, you...
You're in the way! Go outside!
That's it! Now I understand Dr. Date's train trick!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Snack Cart Sales
Next time, it's serious deductions once again!
How 'bout a bento, some tea and a sandwich?