A racing second hand, a shooting comet,
a pop-up doll, and broken ceramic!
Mystery-solving logic is helpful against people's dry hearts!
Heiji Hattori looks poised to discover Conan's real identity today!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and there's no outwitting his logic!
His name? Detective Conan!
The old man, Ran, and I went on a trip for Sherlock Holmes fans.
However, the car of Kanaya-san,
this trip's director and owner of the Mycroft Lodge,
fell over a cliff and exploded!
Moreover, having been isolated from the outside world,
we shut ourselves in the lodge to prevent any further casualties,
but Ayako-san, who claimed to know the identity of the killer,
died in an explosion in the garage!
Was the owner responsible?
Or was it one of the five other guests
excluding us three and Heiji Hattori?
Suddenly, Fujisawa-san was attacked by someone with an ice pick!
Who would do such a thing?!
It was the owner.
He faked his death during the first incident,
hid somewhere inside this lodge,
burned Ayako-san to death in the garage,
then attacked Fujisawa-san with an ice pick
and escaped out that window!
Damn it! Why would the owner want to kill me?!
I even helped him with the book he published!
Book?
A Holmes book he published last year with his own money.
I believe the title was
"The Disparagement of Irene Adler."
Irene Adler?
Alright, Ran! We're going after the owner!
Right!
Forget about it. There's no point.
You'd never find the killer by looking out there!
What do you know?!
Take a closer look at this chair.
See how it's unnaturally placed at the narrow end?
It's proof that the killer quickly pushed it under
after breaking the window.
He's right! There are pieces of glass stuck in it!
The killer must have used this chair!
But that only proves the killer used the chair to—
You idiot! Who would bother putting a chair back
after smashing a window to escape through it?
The killer probably held the chair with bare hands
when they broke the window!
It was too dark to remove the fingerprints,
so the killer put the chair back under the table—
so we wouldn't notice and so they could wipe the fingerprints off
when no one was looking.
After the lights came back on?
Wait, we were the only ones in the room then...
That's right.
Now do you see that the owner didn't do it,
and that the killer is in this very room?!
Maid. You said a fuse had blown
when the lights went out, correct?
Yes! When I tried to plug in the coffee maker,
it suddenly sparked!
It was this outlet!
There was a thin wire wrapped around the plug
so that it would cause a short if someone were to plug it in.
But where did the killer get this wire?
I bet it was this!
The wire attached to the top of this coffee pack!
The width and length do match perfectly...
Who opened the packs?
Kawatsu-san and Togano-san...
Now it's clear.
You're the killer, Kawatsu-san!
Hold on, now!
There were three other people in the kitchen besides me—
You moron!
All three of those people have alibis for the first incident!
You most likely took a wire off a pack when no one was looking,
wrapped it around the plug, and then returned to the living room
to wait for the lights to go out!
Then, in the darkness,
you attacked Fujisawa-san with an ice pick
that you carried in here with some ice—
using the flame from his lighter to find him!
However, some unexpected obstacles caused you to fail.
Isn't that right?
Yeah, but something's not quite right.
Right, boy?
Yeah.
The third incident in which Fujisawa-san was attacked
is different than the first two
in that the culprit plainly left evidence behind.
Perhaps this third incident wasn't part of the killer's plan?
Conan-kun...
But I'm just a kid, so what would I know?
Don't pay any attention to him!
He just loves to play detective!
Come over here.
There's something really strange about this kid!
He isn't playing detective! He's really analyzing!
His voice and body are different, but he's almost just like Kudo!
Kudo?!
Yeah! When Kudo showed up during that previous incident,
that kid disappeared somewhere!
And then when Kudo disappeared, he just popped up again...
Could he really be?!
But isn't it strange, Detective?
If Kawatsu-san really is the killer,
how did he set the garage on fire during the second incident?
And during the first incident,
the owner's car sped up before it went over the cliff!
That's right!
Yeah.
I've got almost all of the second incident solved,
but the first incident makes no sense...
Eh? You know how they set the garage on fire?!
Well, yeah...
At any rate, what I don't understand about the first incident
are the following four points.
Why we didn't see the owner for almost an entire day...
Why the car suddenly sped up...
The odd sound coming from inside the car
and the blanket on the dashboard...
And then one more mystery appeared when we came here.
The owner was holding the steering wheel tightly.
The car was on a bumpy road, but his body never slumped.
That means by the time he was placed in the car,
he was long dead and rigor mortis had set in!
Rigor mortis?!
A body usually begins to stiffen 30 minutes to 2 hours after death,
and 9 to 12 hours later, the body becomes completely stiff.
Thirty hours after that, under the best circumstances,
the body loosens up again and approximately 70 hours later
it's back to normal.
If we assume the owner was completely stiff
when he was placed in the car at 3:30 AM,
then he was killed between 3:30 and 6:30 PM the previous day.
In other words, sometime before dinner,
but what I don't understand
is why they had to put him in the car so early...
Maybe to make it look like a suicide?
My guess is that they killed the owner before dinner,
put him in the car, had him sit with his hands on the wheel,
waited for him to stiffen, then went to the garage after dinner
and sent the car on its way.
In other words,
the killer was one of you who left after dinner!
Then why did the car speed up?
A dead person couldn't possibly have done that...
A dead person?!
Could the killer's trick be—
If so, then only that person could've done it,
but there's still no proof!
Wait a minute!
She did say that Ayako-san was loitering in the hall in the afternoon...
If she had actually seen something in that person's room...
That's it!
Now I see!
I know the killer's identity!
Yes, the killer is you!
Fortune-teller Maria Toda-san!
I beg your pardon?!
You must have used hypnosis to make the owner drive the car!
Give me a break.
I can't wait to use a sleeping dart on him...
But it's all over if he catches me during my explanation.
Say! What would happen to the rigor mortis
if the temperature went up?
Would it start sooner?
If so, then you know who did it, huh?
I haven't the slightest idea. I'm pretty dumb, you see.
Damn it!
He knows all right, he's just trying to make me explain it!
Alright, in that case!
I'll just be going to the bathroom now...
Oh. Then I will, too...
Huh? Where'd he go?
Will you get serious?!
I'm a fortune-teller, not a magician!
That's enough of this farce, old man.
What?
I just figured out who the killer is, too!
You did?
That's right.
The person behind all three incidents at this lodge... was you!
The person behind all three incidents at this lodge...
...was you!
Eh? Me?!
No!
The man in a cold sweat behind you...
...you, Togano-san!
Wait!
I was here in the living room hours before the car even took off!
And when Ayako was killed, I was with everyone else!
He's right, you moron!
Oh, man! I hope he didn't wake up!
Stop that, Dad!
Don't you mock me with your fancy Kansai dialect!
And besides, you were with us too when the car started moving!
How could Togano-san possibly have started the car?!
You're right, it certainly appears impossible.
But if he were to utilize the rigor mortis
and a certain function of the car, it would become possible.
The trick goes like this.
The culprit killed the owner almost exactly one day ago,
sat him in the car seat, and stuck his foot on the brake.
Rigor mortis would occur half a day later,
and the brakes would have kept the car motionless
even if the engine was running and in drive.
Before dinner last night, the killer opened the garage
and then waited in the living room for the foot on the brake to loosen up
and cause the car to start moving...
You fool!
Rigor mortis doesn't go away
until at least 40 hours after death!
You even said so yourself—
What if the outside temperature increases?
If the temperature around the body was about 35°C,
the rigor mortis and rate of loosening up would speed up,
so it would start to go away after only 24 to 30 hours.
It was after 10:00 PM two nights ago that the owner disappeared.
If he had been killed shortly afterward...
The car started moving approximately 29 hours later
—before 3:30 this morning—
which was just about the right time.
The hissing sound we heard inside the car
wasn't the air conditioner—it was the heater!
Had it been the AC,
water drops would have fallen by the front tires.
So that's why you were checking around the tire tracks?
That's right.
Naturally, there were no water marks to be found.
But that trick would be easy to see through
by checking the body...
That's why the killer sent the owner over the cliff in the car!
To make the body unrecoverable
so we couldn't check the state of rigor mortis!
So why did the car speed up?
That was probably because his foot slipped off the brake pedal
as the car bumped around.
And the blanket on the dashboard
was there to conceal the heater indicator
from people who got near the car!
I see!
So by witnessing the car with someone else in the room...
...they would have an airtight alibi!
So the reason Togano-san kept Ayako-san in the living room
was because he wanted someone who would witness the car with him?
Precisely.
And the only person who could have done such a thing
was Togano-san!
Interesting.
Your theory almost sounds like it's straight out of a novel.
It's too bad you have no evidence to prove it.
And as I've said before, when the fire erupted in the garage,
I was in here with everyone else.
No matter how you look at it, there's no way
I could have set the fire exactly when Ayako happened to go in there.
No, but it would still be easy enough...
All you had to do was tell her
that the first-edition Holmes book was hidden beneath the back seat
of the car in the garage!
The first-edition book? What's that have to do with anything?
Have you forgotten?
At that time, the car in the garage was drained of its gasoline
and its battery removed!
She wanted to look for the book, but with the car lights unusable
the back seat would have been pitch black.
What would you have done?
If it were pitch dark, I'd have to use a lighter or something...
That's it! A lighter!
Ayako-san used a lighter to look for the book!
The flame ignited the gasoline that had leaked from the car!
So she was the one who started the fire?!
But she was an important witness from the first incident!
There were four other witnesses besides her!
There was no need to keep her alive...
But aren't Ayako-san and Togano-san lovers?
Why would he do that?
Because she figured out his rigor mortis trick
and found evidence that he was the one responsible!
You all remember.
Ayako-san declared she knew who the killer was.
Hearing that, Togano-san grew flustered
and pretended to follow her to the bathroom.
He then told her about the first-edition book
and lured her into the trap in the garage!
Now that you mention it,
Togano-san was the only one alone with her...
So that's why she changed her attitude after leaving the bathroom!
But he certainly was clever to come up with that garage trick...
No. That trap had been prepared in advance for a certain person...
The killer lucked out because Ayako-san had a lighter,
just as that other person would have had!
Yes. The trap in the garage was really meant to kill Fujisawa-san!
What?!
That card that was stuck in your door...
The killer intended to lure you into the garage and murder you!
But things didn't go according to plan
and the garage trap wound up killing Ayako-san.
He quickly devised a plan to cause a blackout
by fiddling with the outlet
and then attacked Fujisawa-san with an ice pick!
I see. So that's why there was so much evidence
after the third incident...
Togano-san was in the kitchen at the time—
he could've very easily fiddled with it!
In other words, the only person
who could've pulled off all three incidents...
...was Togano-san!
Then show us your proof!
If you're going to make such accusations, then surely you have proof?
Oh? You mean you didn't know?
Ayako-san saw a certain something in your room
yesterday afternoon!
It doesn't matter what she saw! She can't talk now—
Question #1.
"Which hand does Holmes write with?"
Question #2.
"What is the name of Dr. Watson's wife?"
What is this?!
Oh, my. Have you forgotten?
Didn't you take the Holmes Cult Test of 1000 Questions too?
Question #241.
"What did Holmes' letter written in the 'Dancing Men' code
say to the killer?"
Oh, I remember that question very well...
The answer is, "Come here at once!"
That question wasn't on the test...
There was only that one question about "The Dancing Men"!
"Write down the entire 'Dancing Men' code as it appeared!"
That's right.
That question was so hard it would be impossible to forget.
Isn't it a little strange that you don't remember it?
I was just—
The reason Ayako-san went to your room
was to copy your test answers!
But you weren't in your room.
You had probably gone to the garage
to check the state of the owner's rigor mortis!
So what Ayako-san saw was—
Yes. A completely blank test with no answers written at all!
The reason he didn't write anything down
was because there would be no point.
In other words,
you knew that the owner wouldn't be grading the tests
because he was no longer alive!
If you're going to claim this is all nonsense,
then would you kindly show us your test?
Right now!
D-Damn it!
Why, you...
Speak up! Why did you want me and the owner dead?!
"The Disparagement of Irene Adler."
His motive was most likely the book you helped the owner write.
What?!
Irene? The actress who outwitted Holmes in one of the stories?
Yes. But the owner's book was mostly about
Holmes' failure as a detective.
Now I see.
Togano-san felt that the book insulted Holmes, so he—
Just the opposite.
Irene was the only woman Sherlock admired.
I couldn't possibly see such a woman ridiculing him.
I couldn't allow it...
I absolutely couldn't!
That was incredible, Hattori-kun!
Just what I'd expect from the great western detective!
Uh oh!
But of course!
A case like this is like a walk in the park for me!
Looks like I made it through this without having my cover blown...
Conan-kun!
I'm right here, Ran-neechan!
Hey.
You're Kudo, aren't you?
What are you talking about? I'm just a kid!
Your fake Kansai dialect was pathetic!
Oh! So this is the gizmo you used to imitate my voice!
I saw you using it in the corner of my eye!
At what point?
"It would become possible."
You talk a little strangely,
but from your tone and the way you set up your theories
you're definitely Shin'ichi Kudo!
What do you mean? Look at me! I'm just a kid!
Fine, have it your way.
Hey, check this out! You'll never guess!
The truth is—
Hold on!
So their drug shrunk you
and now you're living with your girlfriend
to find out about their organization?
She's not my girlfriend. She's a pain in the ass.
You two sure are getting along well!
Yeah!
Hey, wanna hear what Kudo once said about you?
He said you're so annoying he can't stand you!
Annoying?!
Jerk!
That's what you get for putting me to sleep!
What the...
Someone cut this!
Someone tried to kill Hiroshi-kun in fake accidents!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Traffic Mirror
Next time, it's a super-popular series!
A big role for the Detective Boys!
Not again...