A racing second hand, a shooting comet!
Conan's logic will moisten hearts
dried by modern society!
Today's proof is quite unique!
Let's change our way of thinking!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
I'm done with my bath, Ran-neechan!
Are you busy tomorrow, Conan-kun?
No, I have no plans. Why?
One of Dad's friends just called
and invited us over for a barbecue tomorrow afternoon!
He's a friend of yours?
His name's Teraoka-san.
He really watched over me when I was a police detective.
Now he's chief inspector of Investigation Section #4.
That's the group in charge of handling gangs! I'll come!
Real police detectives have lots of interesting stories!
I can't wait!
You'd always say my logic was wrong,
but then you'd wind up being wrong yourself!
He's still like that.
Now you're a famous detective! To be honest, it's hard to believe!
Please give me some credit...
Here, have some—Huh?
You haven't had a drop to drink!
That's not like you!
I'm off duty, but there's no telling what might come up.
This is an awesome car! It must be expensive!
Cars are my only hobby,
so I spend my money on them.
Say, Ran-chan. Did you have something to do today?
Nothing at all!
I'm sorry for calling out of the blue!
He suddenly decided last night and all...
At 9:00, he left his room and said, "I'm bringing Mouri over tomorrow!"
He normally plans things out well in advance...
I just thought it would be nice...
Hello?
Maybe something happened?
What?!
Where are you?!
Alright! I'll be right there!
I won't tell anyone! I'll come alone! Alright?!
I'll be waiting!
Sorry. I'll be back soon.
Did something happen?
That was Matsuyama, a gang leader.
Apparently, he accidentally killed someone last night.
What?!
He's wanted to change his ways, and I've been giving him advice.
I'm going to convince him to turn himself in.
All by yourself? That's not a good idea.
If he were to run away, you'd be held responsible!
And it's dangerous! You should contact HQ and—
I can't! I promised I would go alone and tell no one!
But you're off duty, and without a gun—
I don't need a gun! He called me out of trust!
I can't betray that!
Then I'm coming with you!
What?!
Otherwise, I'll call Inspector Megure!
Why, you...
Alright, fine. But only I'll meet him! Got that?!
Yes. So where is he?
Kowan Wharf, Warehouse 13.
I'll get my jacket. Wait by the car.
I'll get your jacket!
No! You just stay here!
What's taking him so long?
Sorry. It took a while to find the key.
What was that sound?
What was that sound? Could it have been?!
Will Dad be all right after having all that alcohol?!
Ran-neechan! Let's go to Kowan Wharf too!
You're worried about him, aren't you?! I'll get a taxi!
Conan-kun!
Dad...
Kowan Wharf
What are you doing here?!
Sorry! We were worried about you!
Where's Teraoka-san?
Back there.
He told me to wait here.
Let's check it out, too!
What are you saying?! That would put him in—
Dad!
He doesn't have a gun!
Meaning the other guy does!
Wait, Conan!
Sempai...
So when you tried to get him to turn himself in,
he pulled out a gun and demanded your money and credit cards?
Yes. It seems he planned to skip the country...
I told him he'd never get away, and that we should talk it over.
I put my hands up and walked slowly toward him.
I jumped at him and tried to snatch the gun away—
—when it went off.
It was just an unfortunate accident,
Inspector Megure!
Who exactly did Matsuyama kill?
I don't know his name,
but he said he was a gambling client.
And your relation with Matsuyama?
They had talked about him getting out of a life of crime!
That's why he came alone to meet him!
That was another mistake. I take full responsibility.
My judgment was too weak!
Sempai...
If my theory is correct, this was no accident. It was a murder!
Teraoka-san is the killer!
But there's no proof of it!
Here you are.
Thank you.
You've probably already seen on TV or in the papers,
but Matsuyama's victim was indeed a gambling client.
The murder happened around 8:00, two nights ago,
and the weapon was a knife, not a gun...
That's right. We still don't know why he didn't use a gun,
but it looks like a gambling debt
was at the root of it all.
What about Teraoka-sempai's involvement?
A formal decision is forthcoming,
but he did go alone
and allowed Matsuyama to die, accident or not...
He'll probably lose a few months' pay.
I see...
Which means nobody doubts Teraoka-san's testimony...
Oh, there is one thing we've kept from the media—
we found three sets of fingerprints on the gun.
Three sets?!
One is Matsuyama's, and another is Inspector Teraoka's.
We've determined that his prints got there during the struggle,
but we don't know who the others belong to.
Maybe from someone in Matsuyama's gang?
No. We got all their prints, but none matched up.
Maybe an unrelated arms dealer?
We've considered that too, but we don't have any leads.
Who does the third set belong to?
If that gun's owner is who I suspect it is...
Inspector! You told Teraoka-san about those fingerprints, right?!
How did he look at the time?!
Now that you mention it,
he seemed extremely shocked.
No doubt about it!
Matsuyama was shot by Teraoka-san!
The third set of prints is the proof!
Teraoka residence.
Oh, Inspector Megure!
I'd like to discuss yesterday's incident.
That was weird for Inspector Megure to ask me
to come to Teraoka-sempai's house at this hour!
And me and Conan-kun!
I wonder if something happened...
And I called the inspector using the old man's voice!
Everything's all set!
I didn't know the inspector had called you here too...
Please have a seat.
To be honest, I don't know why he called us here, either.
Say, Miss.
There's a show I wanna see...
There's a TV you can watch in the spare room upstairs.
Yaiba Punch!
This room is for when we have guests over.
You and Ran-chan should come spend the night sometime.
Yeah!
So this is Teraoka-san's room.
There's only one missing...
It's in the trash?!
A felt rag?
Smells of oil. Did he use the inside of this to—
So what did you have to say, Mouri-kun?
You're the one who had something to say...
What?! You called me and said you had something to say!
But the one who called me was—
Here we go again...
Very well. Let us forget the details and get down to business.
But first, please have a seat, madam. You too, Ran.
Teraoka-sempai. You killed Matsuyama, didn't you?
I never expected you to say that!
I see you haven't changed one bit!
When you met Matsuyama,
you hit him with a knockout blow,
put the gun in his hand, aimed it at his chest, and pulled the trigger.
Am I wrong?
Ridiculous! What kind of joke is this, Mouri?
First, when you invited us to the barbecue yesterday,
you didn't take even a single sip of beer.
I already told you—
Yes. Just as you said, even off-duty officers don't know
when they might be called in.
So you refrained from drinking. I thought so, too.
However, you were very intent on checking the time.
Perhaps because you knew when Matsuyama would call you?
That's why you left your phone on your belt and didn't drink.
I always have my phone on me! In case I get an emergency call!
Do you have it now?
It's in my room now, but normally it's—
Next, when you spoke with Matsuyama on the phone,
you whispered at first but then started to shout!
What?!
Where are you?! Alright! I'll be right there!
Almost as if to let us hear what was being discussed.
Then, even though you were in a hurry,
when I asked you about it,
you purposely stopped and explained the call in great detail.
That was Matsuyama, a gang leader.
Apparently, he accidentally killed someone last night.
But half of what you said was a lie.
I think he really called you
about his murder the night before.
You then made arrangements with him.
One was to call you at 12:00 the following day.
So the person he talked to was...
Actually him, during the whispering.
He acted the rest out by himself.
The caller had probably hung up by then.
Then, anticipating I would suggest going together,
he said he would meet Matsuyama alone.
What for?
So that I would vouch that you met him unarmed.
That's why you needed me near you when he called.
He suddenly decided last night and all...
At 9:00, he left his room and said, "I'm bringing Mouri over tomorrow!"
In other words, I was used as part of your plan.
But Mouri-kun! He didn't have the gun
when he got out of the car at Kowan Wharf, right?
It seemed that way to me, at least.
He purposely didn't wear his jacket to make it seem that way,
despite having gone through the trouble of getting it before leaving.
So where was the gun?
Attached to his right ankle.
He had hidden the gun in his room.
That's why he ardently refused
when his wife offered to get his jacket.
No! You just stay here!
Well? Am I wrong?
This is all speculation; you have no proof.
It won't hold up in court.
No, there is proof. The third set of fingerprints on the gun.
The third set of fingerprints?
As we waited for you to come back out yesterday,
your wife looked uneasily up at the upstairs room.
At the time, I thought she was just worried
because you were going to meet Matsuyama without a gun.
But I was wrong.
She was worried because you were going to meet him with a gun.
In other words, she knew you had a gun hidden in your room!
Most likely, she found your gun by accident
and picked it up without thinking.
Then she quickly put it back.
She probably wanted to ask about it but was too afraid to
and continued to live in constant uneasiness.
Clueless about this, you took the gun and killed Matsuyama
in a fake accident.
The third set of fingerprints belonged to her.
Is this true?
Mouri-san is exactly right!
Misako!
Would you care to explain your motive for killing Matsuyama?
Don't tell me he was—
—paying me off. I leaked police info to him in exchange for money.
Come again?!
It was just pocket change and unimportant info at first!
I grew more and more numb to it all, and before I realized it,
I had gone beyond the point of no return.
Then I got a call from him
at around 8:00 two nights ago!
He had killed someone. He wanted money to skip the country.
He said if he got caught, I would go down too!
I decided to kill him then.
I told him I'd have the money
the next day and to call me at 12:00.
I had secretly kept the gun should any such situation come up.
The rest was all as Mouri said.
I apologize for my treachery.
People sure do change. Like Teraoka-sempai...
But you heard what he said...
You really have become a great detective!
He looked kind of happy!
I see...
I guess he's really—
You know how Teraoka-san hid the gun in a video case?
You don't have any dangerous stuff hidden, do you?
Huh?
That's—
There's something else inside it...
Wait, Ran!
Dad!
Blame them, not me!
This is all your fault!
Dad!
Don't hide those there!
Was this man's kid abducted?!
Dad! You have a clue about the kidnapper?!
Keita-kun is by lots of crabs and a bubble-spouting whale!
This license plate is fake?!
Oh no! Once the kidnapper gets the money, Keita-kun is—
That's it! The crabs and the whale!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Chairs and Tables
The next episode title's a bit odd.
Can you "crab" me the time? It's "whale" late!