A racing second hand, a shooting comet!
Conan's logic works wonders on
hearts exhausted by modern society!
Today's hints are crabs and a whale!
Unexpected things look like them!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Cheers!
Tastes great! Can't have summer without beer!
Dad! You shouldn't just drink! You need to eat a little!
Yeah, yeah. Don't be so naggy.
I was all excited when he said it was a fancy hotel dinner,
but it's nothing but light snacks!
Who takes kids to beer gardens to eat?
Dentist
Keigo Endo (33)
That man's at a beer garden but hasn't even had a sip...
Are you drunk already?!
No...
Where are you going?
Bathroom.
The bathrooms aren't that way! Really, now...
This way!
Alright...
This is Endo...
Yes. Yes. I'm alone.
What?!
Why is the deal off?! I got the money and didn't tell the police!
Wait! Let me hear Keita again! Hello?!
Did this man—
Old man! Ran-neechan!
Let's get out of here!
What's the matter, Conan-kun?
I can't say it out loud,
but I think there was a kidnapping!
What?!
Just as you said, there's a good chance they're holding him for ransom.
Yeah. It sounds like he hasn't contacted the police.
Driver. Try not to lose the taxi in front of us.
Right.
"Endo Dental Clinic"
"Closed for today."
A dentist, huh...
What now, Dad?
We need to talk with him first...
But we don't know where the kidnapper is looking from,
and it could be a neighbor behind this.
We'll need to be careful.
I have a good idea! I'll be a patient!
Patient?
Alright, start.
My tooth hurts! It hurts!
Hold on! Dad's going to talk to the dentist!
No, I can't hold on! It hurts!
Yes?
I'm sorry to bother you on your day off.
My kid's tooth hurts and he won't shut up about it.
Could you look at it?
I can't stand it!
Understood. Please come inside.
It hurts! It hurts!
Please come in.
I apologize...
Ouch—
Ouch!
Knock it off! That's enough!
Please come into the examination room...
Pardon my late introduction. I am Detective Kogoro Mouri.
Kogoro Mouri? That famous detective?!
I see. So Conan-kun heard my phone conversation—
Endo-san. Could you tell me about it?
If the kid's right, then I can help you.
Alright. This may be some sort of fate.
Just as you said, my son was kidnapped.
His name is Keita.
I let him play by himself in the front yard this afternoon, but...
Keita! Let's go to the park!
Keita?
"Took the kid. Call the police and he's dead. Wait for a call."
It's written on ordinary copy paper.
So what did the kidnapper tell you?
It was a young man's voice on the phone.
He told me to put 30 million yen in used bills in a briefcase
and to be at Starlight Hotel's beer garden at 6:00.
But a little after 6:00, he called me
and canceled the exchange.
Did he explain why?
No. All he said was that he would call again tomorrow morning.
Maybe the kidnapper was suspicious?
He probably never intended to get the money tonight.
He likely watched Endo-san from somewhere in the beer garden
to make sure he hadn't contacted the police.
When you got the first call,
did you hear Keita-kun's voice?
Yes. I asked the kidnapper to put him on the phone.
How did Keita-kun seem?
He sounded unexpectedly cheerful; he didn't seem afraid at all.
That is odd. You would expect him
to at least miss his mother.
He doesn't have one.
She died of a disease last year.
Perhaps that's why Keita grew fond of his kindergarten teacher
and the women in the neighborhood.
I see. Now I get it.
The kidnapper is likely working with a woman good with children,
and she's taking care of Keita-kun.
The old man might be right.
Meaning we can't rest easy,
but it's unlikely they'll hurt Keita-kun.
Endo-san. I think you probably should call the police now...
I can't do that!
Maybe the kidnappers will be caught if the police intervene!
But what guarantee do I have
Keita will return unharmed?!
Yes, but...
Mouri-san!
Yes?
You are my only hope now!
Please! Help bring Keita back unharmed!
I beg you!
Very well! I was the one who came to you!
Let's work together to somehow solve this!
Thank you!
But we can't stay here too long.
We'll leave for tonight and talk on the phone from now on.
Right!
I'll need to borrow this photo.
Yes, go right ahead.
You have nothing to worry about. I will return Keita-kun safely!
Right! I appreciate your help!
I attached the transmitter.
Now we just wait for the kidnappers to call!
Mouri Detective Agency...
They called?!
What did they say?!
They demanded 20 million more, and gave me two hours to get it!
Two hours?
Did you hear Keita-kun's voice?
Yes. I had them put him on just like you said.
Then he said something odd...
Something odd?
Keita! Is that you?!
Daddy!
Keita! Are you okay?!
Yeah! There's lots of crabs here, Daddy!
Crabs?
What're you talking about?
Listen! Call the cops and—
A whale! A whale is spouting bubbles!
Loudmouthed brat! I'll contact you again!
Keita!
Hello?! Hello?!
Loudmouthed? The kidnapper said that?
Yes.
Understood. You get the money ready.
With any luck, I'll have Keita-kun back within two hours!
Really?! Please do your best!
Dad! You have a clue about the kidnappers?!
Yeah! Keita-kun is by lots of crabs and a bubble-spouting whale!
Crabs and a whale?
Don't tell me it's the ocean...
Don't be dumb! Whales only spout air deep underwater!
It wasn't a real whale that Keita-kun saw.
It was probably a model.
A model?
And that would be at the aquarium!
Southern Aquarium
You don't have any whale models?
No. We do have various kinds of
crabs, but no whale models...
Damn! Must be a different aquarium!
We have no time! Let's go!
Say... Are you sure the crabs have to be real?
What?
When Keita-kun said there were lots of crabs,
the kidnapper said,
"What are you talking about?"
Doesn't that mean the kidnapper couldn't see any?
That is true...
So they didn't call from the aquarium?
Look at that, Dad! It's a whale!
"Nichiuri TV"
Oh, yeah! Nichiuri TV's mascot is a whale this year!
Could that be what Keita-kun saw?!
If so, then he was where that blimp was visible...
Got it! The blimp was above Beika Park
when the kidnappers called!
Beika Park?
Yesterday's deal was at a hotel in Beika Town!
Let's go back and look for a place in Beika Town with lots of crabs!
Keita-kun has to be somewhere near there!
Any luck?!
Nope.
Me neither.
Damn! Our time's up!
The kidnappers might've called.
Understood!
They called two minutes ago.
They told him to stand at the end of Platform 1 in Karajuku Station.
Karajuku Station?
Yeah. You keep looking for the crabs, Conan.
Got that?
Yeah!
Even if they did lose to the kidnappers, my transmitter's on the case!
I will find them!
Karajuku Station
Do you think they'll be on a train?
I doubt it.
They'll probably exchange the money elsewhere.
Hey!
Throw the money here!
Don't you care about the kid?!
Damn it! Ran!
Right!
He got away?!
Yes. But Mouri-san got the license plate number on film.
We'll know his identity soon!
Got it!
It's staying in the same spot. Their hideout should be nearby!
Almost there! Just around that corner!
Damn it! They must've changed briefcases here!
But the old man got the license plate number, so we can still—
Was this the kidnapper's?! Was that license plate a fake?!
Oh no! Now that they have the money,
they might kill Keita-kun!
Damn it!
Find it!
Find where there's lots of crabs and where the whale blimp was visible!
Didn't he say the whale was spouting air bubbles?
That blimp wasn't spouting anything!
What does it mean? Was it not the blimp he saw?! Or maybe—
Could it be?!
Can't see it from here.
That's it!
It might be visible from that Starlight Hotel!
Beika Park. And then that.
Keita-kun saw the smoke from that waste incineration facility...
It would look like that only where the park and the tower line up...
That's right around here!
But this is too low. It needs to be the same altitude as the blimp
to make it look like it's spouting air.
Could they be in this hotel?!
That was close!
The tables and chairs...
Could the crabs actually be—
There they are! The crabs!
The tables and chairs look like crabs from above!
No doubt about it! Keita-kun is in some room in this hotel!
Lady!
Do you know which room this boy is staying in?
Oh, he's in a room one floor down. But he just left with his parents.
Thank you!
Alright! I found you! Keita-kun is still unharmed!
Yaiba Punch!
Let's go, Joker! Hiyaaah!
Yaiba Kick!
Hey, are we really going to kill him?
Quit asking and stop worrying about him!
Let's go!
Keita-kun!
Those two are kidnappers! Stop them!
Damn! Nobody move!
Move and he's dead!
Get over there! Now!
Is there anything to kick?!
The bike's right out front!
Run like hell once we're out the door!
Ready?
Take this!
And that's that!
Keita! I'm so glad you're all right! Keita!
Daddy, that hurts!
How did you know they were here?
It was just dumb luck!
I was looking for the crabs when I found Keita-kun!
When I shouted that it was a kidnapping,
they rushed to get away
and wound up like that.
Brought it upon themselves, huh?
Mouri-kun!
Oh, Inspector Megure-dono!
Conan-kun explained everything.
Why didn't you contact us when you learned it was a kidnapping?
Can't trust me, huh?
It's not that at all!
For the next hour, Inspector Megure gave the old man a good scolding.
Not that that's a bad thing!
What was that?
This is a homicide!
It wouldn't be possible to leave from here.
Why is there a bloodstain here?
Ikuta-san was standing here in the dark.
Could it be?!
Next Conan:
N-N-N-N-Next Conan's Hint: Cigarettes
Next time, it's another surprising, well-executed trick!
Can you see crows in the dark of night?