A racing second hand, a shooting comet!
Conan's logic heals hearts dried by modern society!
Today's case is the darkness of night.
Dark mysteries need the light of logic!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Wasn't that delicious, Conan-kun?
Yeah!
Ugh! You ordered nothing but expensive food!
Oh! If it isn't Mouri!
Omura! Long time, no see!
Mouri's Old Friend ∙ Model Shop Owner
Jun Omura (37)
You seem as lively as ever.
Do you remember Omura-san?
Yeah! He's his college friend that we met at the hot springs!
This is perfect timing, Mouri.
I need to talk to you...
What about?
There's this strange sound outside my apartment every night.
A strange sound?
It's a thump, as if something's hitting the outside wall.
Probably just some kids up to no good.
I thought so too, but there was nobody outside when I checked,
and it's been going on for a whole week now.
A whole week, huh...
Why not look into it for him?
Please, Mouri.
Alright! Just leave it to the great Kogoro Mouri!
Thank you!
Delicious!
Nothing beats drinking beer with old friends!
I thought you were here to investigate the weird sound.
Oh, looks like we're out of beer.
I'll go buy some.
No, I'll do that!
Thank you!
You're disturbing the neighbors!
We're back!
Been waiting for this!
What was that?
What happened here?
Hey, Ikuta. What's wrong?
Ikuta! Come on, already! Ikuta!
Quit playin' around!
Ikuta! Ikuta!
He's dead!
What?!
Ran! Get the police!
Right!
A blow to the head with a blunt object...
So many cigarette butts...
2nd-year Student, Beika University
Yoshiro Ikuta (20)
The victim is Yoshiro Ikuta-san, 20 years old.
A 2nd-year student at Beika University.
And you are?
2nd-year Student, Beika University
Masami Kusaka (20)
Kusaka. I'm a college friend of Ikuta's.
Could you explain the situation as you found it?
Yes.
Ikuta and I agreed to meet up here at 10:00 PM.
But just as I called out to him,
he suddenly collapsed...
Did you notice anyone else?
No.
But it was really too dark to see much...
With that light broken,
I could barely even see Ikuta...
You sure you didn't kill him?
I didn't do it!
Please let me through!
Hey! Wait!
Shimizu!
Kusaka! Why did he die?!
Pardon me, but who are you?
2nd-year Student, Beika University
Yoichi Shimizu (20)
My name's Shimizu.
I was just drinking with Ikuta in our friend's apartment.
Where would that be?
There, on the fifth floor.
Eh?!
Ikuta was murdered?!
Whose apartment is this?
2nd-year Student, Beika University
Koji Takeno (20)
It's mine.
My name's Takeno. I'm a 2nd-year student at Beika University along with Ikuta.
And you are?
2nd-year Student, Beika University
Hidenori Nakamura (21)
Nakamura. We're all members of the mountain climbing club.
Ikuta-san drank with you all here?
Yes, I invited everyone over. We've been here since 7:00...
Around what time did Ikuta-san step outside?
A little before 10:00. Kusaka had called at 9:00.
Hold on! I never called anyone!
That can't be. Right, Takeno?
Yeah. Ikuta wasn't here, so I answered for him.
Where was he?
Takeno had asked him to buy snacks at the convenience store.
You're certain it was Kusaka-san's voice on the phone?
Yes. There's no mistake.
I didn't call!
Then how did you decide where to meet?
Ikuta asked me there. He put a note in my locker.
Why did he ask you there?
Um, well...
Didn't you say Ikuta took your money?
What is he talking about?
Ikuta took the tuition money I took to school...
Do you still have that note of his?
No, I threw it out.
Or maybe there never was a note?!
Ikuta-san stole your tuition money
and refused to give it back.
So you phoned him out of anger
and beat him to death!
No! Besides, I'm not the only one who hated him!
Nakamura and Takeno did too!
Why did I?!
You owed him lots of money!
I was in here the whole time! Right, Shimizu?
Yeah. But you did step out for some fresh air.
Around what time was this?
Around 10:00, when Ikuta had left.
The same time the incident occurred...
But it was only for a few minutes!
And why did you have a grudge against Ikuta-san?
Ikuta and Keiko Togawa got stranded in the mountains six months ago.
Ikuta abandoned the injured Keiko and left by himself.
She had already frozen to death when we found her.
She and Takeno had been lovers!
Is this true?!
Inspector.
In mountain accidents, sometimes you have to abandon your friends.
I feel bad about Keiko,
but I don't blame Ikuta at all!
Besides, I never took a single step out of this apartment!
That's true; he was inside the whole time.
At 10:00, he went to the next room
to finish a report for class.
How long was he alone?
20 or 30 minutes...
But you can't get outside without going through this room,
so I can't see how he could've done it.
But a mountain climber could easily
climb down a rope from the window.
Not from that window. See for yourself.
See?
That's as far as it goes?
No way anyone could leave through here.
Say, why did you have the lights off
if you were writing a report?
I saw on the way back from the store.
The lights weren't on in this room then.
Um, well—
Who cares about that?!
As there's no way through that window,
Takeno-san is innocent!
A slingshot?
The only phone is in this room?
A red thread...
Those are the same cigarettes...
Ikuta-san must've been a heavy smoker.
Alright...
Conan-kun!
Omura-san's apartment is directly below Takeno-san's!
Come to think of it, why did the window break then?!
Omura's Apartment
Odd. Whatever broke the window isn't in here.
Blood!
Is it the victim's?! But what's it doing here?!
Isn't this a bloodstain?
What?!
No question about it!
Alright! I'll inform Inspector Megure!
What's a bloodstain doing here?!
Ikuta-san was standing here in the dark.
Could it be?!
That bloodstain, the place he was standing,
and Omura-san's broken window all line up!
Which means...
...at the top of this building, there's—
A bloodstain!
And there's Takeno-san's apartment!
Now I know who killed him and how!
Conan-kun! Where did you go?!
Just looking around.
I'm getting dizzy...
Could I ask you to come down to the station?
Not so fast, Inspector Megure.
I will now shed light on the truth of this incident.
What?!
The key to this incident is the location of the murder weapon.
Yes. It was absent from the scene of the crime.
A bloodstain was left behind on the nearby abandoned building,
but there's one other place with a bloodstain.
What?! Where?!
I was in Omura's apartment at the time,
but something odd happened.
Something odd?
Immediately after the murder, Omura's window shattered.
Does that have to do with this?
There was blood on the pieces of glass.
What does that entail?
Before I explain, I'd like you to check something.
The roof of the abandoned building.
If I'm correct, there should be blood on the railing
directly above the bloodstain on the wall.
What?!
Detective Takagi! Go check it out!
Yes, sir!
Give him a two-way radio.
A radio?
I'd like him to help with something later on.
What the...
Inspector! There's blood on the railing here!
What?! Blood on the railing?!
Just as I suspected.
What does this mean?
Corpse
Omura
Takeno
The wall, the railing, the glass shards in Omura-san's apartment...
Omura
Why is there blood at these three spots?!
The weapon that killed Ikuta-san passed by those three spots.
In other words, the killer accomplished his murder from afar.
Yes. The killer had been in this very room...
It was you, Takeno-san!
What?!
No way!
Are you serious, Mouri-san?!
I couldn't possibly kill him from here!
Does anyone have fishing line?
Fishing line?
I do.
I use it to hang up plastic models.
Bring some here.
Okay.
Ran. Put some rocks in that plastic bag you got earlier.
Here you go, Mouri.
What're you going to do with this?
Now then, Inspector.
Tie two strands of fishing line to a rock.
Alright...
Here, Inspector.
Once you're done, use Takeno-san's slingshot
to shoot the rock onto the other building's roof.
It's only a dozen meters away; the length of a few taxicabs.
Anyone can shoot it that far.
Inspector.
Have Detective Takagi untie the lines,
pass them through the railing, and then tie them together.
Next, the rope on that shelf.
Rope? Oh, that?
Tie one of the lines to one end of it.
Like so?
Now pull the other fishing line in.
Mouri-kun. What do I do with this rope?
Ran. Tie the bag to the other end of the rope.
Right.
Tie it tight so nothing comes out.
All done, Dad!
Mouri-kun! Don't tell me this is the—
Sounds like you've figured it out, too.
Inspector! I'm at the spot!
Good! Now we'll start!
Eh? Start what?
Well, Detective Takagi?!
The bag passed directly above the chalk lines and hit the wall!
It's right next to the bloodstain!
Takeno-san murdered Ikuta-san thusly,
and then pulled the rope in
to recover the weapon.
This would leave no weapon at the murder scene.
Inspector! The bag just hit below Omura-san's broken window!
Mouri! Could that be the thump I heard every night?
Yes. Takeno-san had been practicing.
But something unexpected happened tonight:
the weapon hit the window.
So that's what broke it...
Takeno.
Mouri-san!
Ikuta went down there because Kusaka asked him to on the phone!
Had he not called, I couldn't have set that trick up!
Kusaka-san never called anyone. It was all an act.
But we did hear the phone ring!
He could make it "ring" at any time
by recording the sound and setting a timer on it.
All he had left to do was pick up the phone
and pretend like he was talking to Kusaka-san.
It was also Takeno-san who put the note in Kusaka-san's locker.
All to frame him for Ikuta-san's murder!
But how did he know where Ikuta-san was standing?
It was pitch-black with the streetlight broken...
Takeno-san broke it in advance to make us think that way.
Wouldn't that make it harder to know where he'd be?!
No, he knew where Ikuta-san was,
even in the dark.
That's ridiculous. I'm not a bat.
Ran.
What was Ikuta-san doing
on your way back from the store?
Well, he was standing beneath the broken streetlight...
Oh yeah, and he was smoking!
As a heavy smoker, Ikuta-san dropped lots of cigarette butts.
Takeno-san. You aimed at the light from the cigarette
and dropped the weapon on him.
You had the lights off to prevent anyone from seeing the weapon!
Which means there's a plastic bag
full of rocks still in here!
Then check the apartment! I have no plastic bags!
Takeno-san.
Those are some thick socks for this time of year.
Those are mountain-climbing socks.
You turned them inside-out and filled them with rocks.
Later, you put the rocks in the fish tank and fixed your socks.
As proof, there's a thread in the water plant!
One that's the same color as your socks.
These are sturdy enough to be used as the weapon and not rip...
There should be blood on the inside of those socks.
Ikuta-san's blood!
Mind if I have a look, Takeno-san?
There's no need.
Takeno!
Did you do it because of Keiko Togawa-san's death?
Yes.
As I said, sometimes you have to abandon friends in mountain accidents.
I constantly told myself I couldn't blame Ikuta.
But when I think about never seeing her again,
I feel as if I've been left all alone in this world,
I was so lonely that I felt I was going crazy.
Then, when I entered a pub one day...
Yeah, that's right!
Keiko dumped me so I left her to die!
That's horrible!
He had to pay for letting my precious Keiko die for no reason!
And so did Kusaka, who laughed at the story!
The rest was just as Mouri-san said!
Nothing beats beer after solving a crime! It's the greatest!
It's getting late; we should call it quits for—
Don't say that! Let's get this party goin'!
But I'm exhausted...
I feel great, like I just had a nap!
Maybe because you did just have a nap!
What's the matter, Ran-neechan?
Tonight was the Tanabata, the one day a year that lovers can meet.
I wonder how Shin'ichi is doing...
Ran...
I'm sure Shin'ichi-niichan's looking up at the same starry sky!
Yeah...
Are you Heihachiro Shiota-san?!
Heihachiro Shiota?!
This geezer is that legendary detective?!
This was a murder!
Everyone stay where you are!
Damn it! Right before my very eyes!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Vinyl Tape
Next time, it's a weird old detective!
You mean, like the guy Kogoro learned from?