A racing second hand, a shooting comet!
Let's heal hearts dried by modern society with Conan's logic!
Today's case is the world of acting!
Bloodlust behind the glitter!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
The Stage Actress Murder Case
"Mouri Detective Agency"
You're Dad's teacher?
He wasn't too bright.
He always needed my help,
even when he worked for the police.
Are you Heihachiro Shiota-san?!
Heihachiro Shiota
Legendary Detective
I'm known as the Japanese Holmes.
Heihachiro Shiota?!
This old man is that legendary detective?!
I hear he's done a lot lately, so I came to observe.
I'm so sorry! He's out on a case right now!
Some famous acting troupe was threatened...
Threatened?!
Lead the way, young lady!
Okay...
This is great! I get to see the famous detective in action!
"Beika Art Theater"
"Cancel the show or it will become a terrible tragedy."
Any ideas who sent it?
Of course not.
Hey! Where's Shoko?!
When can we start rehearsal?!
She's still not ready.
Kazuo Motoki
Director
Dammit. Thinks she's so great after some TV work.
Anyway, it's probably just a prank,
but everyone's scared,
so look into it.
Just don't get in the way.
Geez...
Ah, so this is it...
What're you doing here?!
Heihachiro Shiota-san asked to come.
What?! That old man?!
Where is he?!
He disappeared when we got here...
Disappeared?!
Make way!
Hei-san! What are you doing here?!
He touched my butt!
Forgive me! I'm not long for this world!
Old crackpot...
What happened, Shoko-san? Is there a problem?!
Hitomi Sasaki
Manager
I'm sick of it all!
Shoko Oide
Leading Actress
And why's that pathetic director
telling me how to act?!
And having my ex as the leading man sucks!
Move!
Shoko-san!
Eiko Nakayama
Actress
Thinks she's so big!
What's the big idea of showing up
and obstructing my work?!
That actress still needs practice.
Rears are the essence of life.
One touch will tell you how a person lives.
What're you doing?!
Dad!
So vivacious!
Are you really a legendary detective?
What are they doing there?
That's called "marking".
It lets actors know where to stand.
It's important to choose specific spots for the lighting.
Plays sure are complicated!
What's your problem?!
Quit complaining, amateur!
I'm not complaining! I'm asking!
The lights almost fell on Shoko last week!
You saying I did it on purpose?!
So this is what it's like above the stage!
Jun'ichi Tateoka
Props
Go ahead and check!
Get real.
Thanks, little boy!
Is someone after Shoko-san?
Maybe.
You shouldn't be up here! It's dangerous!
Is Shoko Oide-san the culprit's target?
I will never leave you, even if I go to hell.
I'll follow you wherever you go!
Surely, our love will become a star in the heavens!
How boring. They should do some of the classics instead.
Yuichi Uda
Leading Man
So you'll die with me?
I'm not afraid to, if it's with you.
What lame acting!
Marvelous, Shoko! That was absolutely realistic!
Yeah! You really outshone me!
Hey, Shoko!
Shoko...
What's wrong?
Come on, Shoko! That's enough!
She's dead!
Everyone stay where you are!
Damn it! Right before my very eyes!
Dark pink skin and strange spots...
This is clearly—
—a case of cyanide poisoning.
Hei-san! What are you doing here?!
I heard stories about you and Mouri
so I came to see how much you've improved.
Anyway, you're retired! Please don't get in the way!
Listen to the big man talk!
Who saved your job when you let that serial murderer get away?
Um, well...
There's also the time I solved that locked-room murder for you.
Don't worry, Inspector. I know who did it.
I hope so. I'll never hear the end of it if he beats me again.
I suppose I'll just sit here and watch...
The killer was the one who poisoned the water! You, Uda-san!
Ridiculous. I had no reason to kill Shoko.
Not true. You two used to be an item.
I bet she cheated on you once she got popular!
You two used to argue nearly every day about her acting!
I just wanted the play to be good.
Convenient way to put it!
Swallowing cyanide means a near-instant death!
She drank the water just fine after swallowing the prop poison.
There was no poison in that packet.
Watch. I'll prove if there's poison or not.
Wait! Don't!
Ahh! What are you?
See?
Mouri-kun!
How did they slip her the poison?
The rehearsal went for 40 minutes straight.
A capsule before the rehearsal would've dissolved in 15 minutes.
Plus they're not airtight,
so they're not suitable for cyanide.
In which case...
Thinks she's so big!
She brought the water and glasses out.
She's not here!
What are you doing?
You haven't improved one bit!
You know who did it?!
It's elementary. The woman did it.
The woman?!
She was the one who carried the pitcher and glasses out.
That's it! She put poison in the pitcher!
What're you doing there?!
Nothing! Just cleaning up!
What are you trying to hide?!
What are you doing?!
What did I do?!
I said to stay where you were until we're done investigating!
This is—
This writing pad was used to write the threat letter!
What?! Why, you! Getting in the way again?!
There's no way to know that so easily!
But there are pen imprints left!
There are...
The case is closed, all thanks to him.
How could you tell she was suspicious?
As the saying goes,
"There's a woman in every crime."
You're kidding, right?
Inspector.
Well, Takagi-kun?
There's no cyanide to be found...
See! I'll admit to writing the letter, but I didn't kill that woman!
You sure?
You were pretty pissed when Shoko got the leading role.
Of course I was! But you said you wanted her to die, too!
I'll lose the most if this play flops!
Calm down, now...
Inspector.
We found cyanide in the water left in her glass.
The pitcher was clean.
So it was you!
No it wasn't, you lousy detective!
Didn't someone give you the glasses backstage?
Yeah! That's right!
Tateoka-san got them ready for me!
That's true, but I didn't poison anyone!
She did tell me to fire you... What was that about?
Manager Sasaki Hitomi-san. Have you heard anything?
Tateoka-san peeked as
she was changing clothes...
She must've resented it, so you—
He didn't do it.
How's that?
Because he's not a woman?
You're a smart one.
Elementary? Yeah, right.
Elementary?!
Things wouldn't fit if Tateoka-san was after Shoko-san!
The two glasses were exactly the same.
Which glass Shoko-san got depended on Eiko-san.
He couldn't accurately target her!
Spill it already!
It's the truth! I didn't poison anything!
I just thought I'd injure her by rigging the curtain...
Rigging the curtain?
Dad!
I'm staying here!
Come, now. What do you think I'm here for?
A teacher assists his useless pupils.
Take it easy and recuperate.
I will solve this case.
Oh, no, you won't! You always—
Ouch!
Get him to the hospital!
How did the killer slip Shoko-san the cyanide?
They didn't put it on the glass, or in the water.
It was definitely added moments before she drank the water.
That's the look, boy.
You look much more detective-like than Mouri ever could!
Say, how do you think the killer poisoned Shoko-san?
Good question. The answer is,
"Only the gods know."
It's nothing to make light of.
Do you know of the novel, "The Spider's Thread"?
Yeah! The one Ryunosuke Akutagawa wrote?
Yes. He says that Buddha knows all things, good and bad.
Have a look at that ugly scene.
Tateoka! Were you tryin' to ruin my play?!
This is your fault for using that broad!
You blaming me?!
When fools fight, they don't realize
they expose their ugliness.
Just like the fools who cut the spider thread
that Buddha extended to them.
This is no time for spider thread talk. We need to—
Spider thread?!
Why is that star pulled up?!
This is it!
It's directly above the table!
Torn fishing line...
It was wrapped around the star's cord!
Spider thread? Now I get it!
Using this method, anyone could've put the cyanide in her glass!
Was it Tateoka-san's job to give the water to Eiko Nakayama-san?
No. Anybody around does it.
Aha, so it was this person!
Now what? The old man's gone just when I need him.
Oh yeah! I know someone who's perfect for the role!
I'm counting on you, Legendary Detective!
Naptime already?
Okay, Tateoka-san! You can explain it all down at the station!
All the players are here,
so let us get this show on the road...
...and reveal the leading actor and director of this drama.
You're saying someone else did it?!
Indeed, I am.
The killer was waiting for a specific moment.
Yes. The climax, in which all eyes were on the two main characters.
But wouldn't everyone have seen the killer add the poison?!
This situation was a little different...
The spotlight only illuminated them;
the surroundings were dark.
The killer waited for that moment of blindness.
Dark as it was, nobody could've approached the table unnoticed.
There was no reason to.
What's with your voice?
Nothing.
When people concentrate on one spot,
they become careless of others.
Especially of what's overhead.
Someone dripped the cyanide from above?
It's possible, but unlikely.
It would've made a sound
if it was dripped from above.
Plus nobody could accurately get it into the cup from up there!
For a director, you have no imagination.
Do you know Ryunosuke Akutagawa's story, "The Spider's Thread"?
The one where Buddha tries to save thieves in hell by lowering a—
A thread!
Yes. See the star higher up than the others on the ceiling?
Wrapped around it is the fishing line used in the murder.
At the end of it is a weight. Check it and you should find cyanide.
The killer lowered the poisoned weight past the star,
put it inside the glass, then pulled it back up.
Unaware, she drank the water.
So I'm in the clear, since I wasn't up there then!
No.
One could pull this off without being up above.
But how?!
Isn't the location of the victim's glass predetermined?
I believe it's called "marking."
One could do this from backstage by extending the line below.
However, the line caught on the star's cord when pulled in.
The raised star on the ceiling!
So who did it, then?!
We will find out by examining their hands!
Hands?
What's the deal, old man?
Bah. You gonna read our palms to find the killer?
The guilty party will be unable to show their hands!
That's what this is?
Alright! Everyone put their hands out!
Geez...
Good. Now inspect their hands.
Hitomi Sasaki-san. What's wrong? Please show us your hands.
Those marks are—
Yes. They're from forcefully pulling the fishing line.
She was probably nervous.
After the incident,
Mouri ordered everyone to stay put.
The fishing line you used should still be in your pocket.
Why would the manager do this?
Is it because I dumped you for Shoko?
No.
I accepted the fact that you chose her over me.
But then...
I broke up with Uda.
He's as dumb and boring as I thought.
You can have him back. Why not make up with him?
She never cared about the play.
She just wanted to steal you from me!
Hitomi...
Great work, Hei-san!
I heard the rumors, but that
"Sleeping Kogoro logic"
could only have come from Kogoro Mouri-san's teacher!
It was Mouri who copied me!
And you're even as shameless as he is!
Pull yourself together. Are you alright?
Huh?
What?!
"Heihachiro Shiota Detective Agency"
What's the meaning of this?!
Just how it looks.
You're still unreliable, so I'll watch you for a while. Don't worry.
Alright, you!
Honey!
You come to Tokyo to sightsee but don't come back!
You cheated on me again, didn't you?!
Cheating?!
Please believe me! You're the only one I love!
Yeah, sure! Now let's go!
Come on!
Guess he gets his women skills from his teacher, too.
NEXT EPISODE
My father hasn't revealed the Night Baron's identity yet,
but whoever's using his name is in here...
My father's a detective!
Looks like Dad's famous!
The Night Baron!
Next Conan:
The Night Baron Murder Case
(The Case)
Next Conan's Hint: Computer Virus
Look forward to the next episode!
Finally, a super-extra-large case next time!
Super-extra-large eel?
What?