A racing second hand, a shooting comet!
Conan's logic can heal the dried hearts of modern society!
The stage this time is a resort hotel!
This case is a huge three-parter!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
The Night Baron Murder Case
(The Case)
I hate this...
Izu Princess Hotel - Private Beach
Why am I in such a hot place
at such a hot time of the year?
This is all because of
the doc's phone call...
Eh? Izu?
Yes! Three days and two
nights at a hotel in Izu!
And for free, too!
Let's go!
Free sounds good to me.
What am I doing in a place like this?
I should be out looking for
those men in black who shrunk me.
But the occasional break is nice...
What's wrong?
You should come swim, too, Conan-kun!
Come on, quick.
Eh, why not?
Only half has been paid?!
Yes. A reservation for three in the name of Agasa, right? There's no mistake.
That's impossible! Check again!
What's the matter, Dad?
Okay, you! Only half of
the hotel's cost has been paid!
What's wrong with paying half then?
I didn't bring that
much money with me!
Come to think of it, the doc did say...
Is it really free?!
In your case, Shin'ichi-kun, it's as good as free.
In my case? What do you mean?
Just listen.
My scientist friends and I like
to communicate via PC lately.
One of them found an interesting
tour on an online forum
and invited me to apply for it.
It's called the "Izu Mystery Tour".
Mystery tour?
Luckily, my friend, his granddaughter,
and I all were chosen!
But his granddaughter caught a cold,
so now I'm offering you our spots.
Six parties will attend—
ten people in all, including you.
Everyone gets a 50% hotel discount.
But the tour organizer is one
of the other seven people,
and whoever figures out who
that is gets to stay for free
and wins floppy disks
containing a certain program.
Though you wouldn't have a use for the program...
So how do I look for this
mysterious organizer?
Don't worry.
We received the names and room
numbers of all the attendees.
And the organizer's supposed
to play a certain character
and cause an incident during the tour.
A certain character?
Yes, a character you know
very well from novels.
His name is...
...the Night Baron.
You're him, aren't you?
3.04 seconds.
That's how long you took
to respond to my question.
This was most informative.
I'm Shiro Kon'no, Room 2002.
Shiro Kon'no (28)
Bank Employee
Pleased to make your acquaintance.
You'll never find the Baron's identity that way.
You're the one who
answered in 2.86 seconds...
Tokio Ebara (32)
Computer Programmer
Ebara-san, Room 2101.
Do you ever shut up?!
Gen'ichiro Kaneshiro (74)
Computer Company Owner
Exposing oneself when caught off-guard
is the way of man.
Isn't that right, Shizue-san?
Shizue Hayashi (56)
Kaneshiro's Butler
Yes, sir.
Kaneshiro-san, Room 2001...
It took you 6.29 seconds to respond.
My eyes are bad, as you can see.
I never expected you
would question me...
That's all right. I'll know the
truth once I process this data.
But that data's incomplete.
You're still missing
someone's information.
Hideko Kamijo (29)
Software Company CEO
Isn't that right, Mr. Night Baron?
W-What was that,
Kamijo-san of Room 2102?!
0.97 seconds.
Add it in after my
1.48 seconds, Kon'no-san.
Um...
Yes?
What is this Baron thingy?
You mean you don't know?!
Yeah, right.
He's just playin' innocent.
Hey, he shows up in lots of
Shin'ichi's dad's novels!
Yes.
The Night Baron is an elusive
villain created by my father, Yusaku Kudo!
He's a thief of the darkness
and sometimes a crazed murderer!
My father, Yusaku, hasn't revealed
the Night Baron's identity yet,
but either way, whoever's using his
name is one these people...
This makes no sense.
I'm going to our room.
Dad! What about the money for the hotel?!
Hold on. There were
supposed to be ten people.
With me, Ran, the old man and the other five, we're just eight.
We're missing two.
What do you think you're doing?!
Come on, it's just your butt...
It's no big deal.
Why don'tcha come with me and fill my drinks...
Why, you...
Knock it off!
What're you doing?!
That's my line!
Satoru Maeda (30)
Jonan University Electrical Engineering Assistant
What?!
Are you Satoru Maeda-san?!
Yes.
Ran-neechan. Do you know him?
Know? He was Japan's karate champ six years ago!
He's the reason I started
practicing karate!
I'm Ran Mouri! I won
the recent city championship!
A karate champ and a city champion!
I never expected to meet
you here! I'm super-lucky!
Who's super-lucky?
Who's she?
Akiko!
Akiko Sayama (24)
High School Math Teacher
Let me introduce you.
This is my fiancée, Akiko Sayama-san.
You're getting married?!
Hey!
Don't take it personally.
Akiko gets jealous pretty easily...
You're the Night Baron, aren't you?
Room 1901, Maeda-san... 0.75 seconds.
Sayama-san...
He's still at it.
But it's strange. You're supposed to be
two doctors and a little girl.
They couldn't come,
so we came in their place.
That was my father, and he's
a detective, not a doctor.
A detective?!
Yes. His name is Kogoro Mouri.
Kogoro Mouri?
I've seen him in the newspapers.
Yeah, they say he's a great detective...
How dirty of him to send
a detective instead.
Oh, come now. We have
fewer possible Barons now.
But with Kogoro Mouri here,
we cannot afford to show our faults.
Sounds like Dad's famous!
All thanks to me, of course.
Who's there?!
Conan-kun.
Conan-kun!
Let's go back to our room.
Okay...
Oh, that's the deal?
So that's why they were shocked
when I said Dad was a detective...
Yeah...
So it's basically like this...
If I find which of those
seven is the Night Baron,
we get to enjoy
the Izu Beach for free.
I see. So that's why Dr. Agasa told Conan-kun it was free!
Could be...
But of course! Because there's no mystery that I, Kogoro Mouri, can't solve!
Gimme a break.
You were just ranting about going
home 'cause you have no money.
Okay, then! I better go do
my preliminary questioning!
Dad's in such high spirits!
What do you say we look around the hotel?
Okay...
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
Let's move on!
I'm going to stay here
a little longer.
Oh? Well, I'll be in the
gift shop downstairs.
Okay! I'll be there in a bit!
Why?
Why were they all so shocked
at the mention of a detective?
It's just a game, right?
All you get is to stay
for free, so why?
And that murderous glare!
And then there's what
the doc said...
...and wins floppy disks
containing a certain program.
Though you wouldn't have a use for the program...
Somehow...
I've got a bad feeling about this...
Guess I can just call him after
dinner and get all the details...
The Night Baron!
What the?!
A pool!
Are you all right, kid?!
Damn him!
He's gone!
He must've changed in the toilet
and then taken the stairs.
But who dressed up as
the Night Baron?!
Without counting me, Ran or the old man, there's seven people on this tour.
The purpose of the tour is to find
its organizer among the attendees.
The organizer who would cause
an incident as the Night Baron!
But it's just a simple
game to stay for free.
Who'd push someone off
just for that?!
Oh, that program?
Agasa Residence
What exactly is it?!
No idea. All the ad said was that
it was the "ultimate program".
Oh, that reminds me.
My doctor friend mentioned
something or other about a virus...
A virus?!
It's odd, though. He shouldn't
know any more about it than I do.
Hey, doc! Don't tell me that virus is...
Conan-kun?
Ran-neechan...
What're you doing?! I've been waiting
at the gift shop this whole time!
What happened?! You're dripping wet!
I, uh, slipped and fell into the pool!
That's nothing to laugh about!
What's wrong with you?!
But you don't seem hurt.
Go change and then we'll have dinner.
Okay!
It's crowded.
What should we do?
Hey! Ran!
Ran! Over here!
Dad! And Maeda-san and Sayama-san!
What are you three doing together?
Your father just finished
interrogating us...
"You're the Night Baron, aren't you?!" and such.
Geez, Dad...
Akiko-san! That's a lovely dress!
T-Thank you.
But be careful. Some perverted wolf might be on the prowl.
That old perv just doesn't learn...
Akiko-san signed you up
for this mystery tour?
Yeah, Akiko's a huge fan
of Yusaku Kudo's novels.
Especially the Night Baron ones.
Nobody knows more about
the Night Baron than I!
Even my hairstyle
is the same as his!
You're not the only expert
on the Night Baron...
...young lady.
I hope that's food for thought.
Now if you'll excuse me...
What an outfit...
That's why Mom ran out on you!
Quit ogling her, Satoru!
That is one great outfit...
Please stop, sir!
Huh? The old perv didn't
even glance at her!
Maybe she's not his type?
That's Kaneshiro-san, Room 2001...
Looks like Shizue Hayashi-san isn't with him.
Okay! Time to do some investigating!
Where are you going, Conan-kun?
Just the toilet...
Dad! You've had too much!
Say, mister, are you after the
computer virus too?
I'm Conan Edogawa from Room 1902.
Do you remember me?
From whom did you hear about that?
The people on the tour keep
talking about a virus.
But I don't know why
they're talking about it.
All they should know is that
it's the "ultimate program..."
It's the name.
There was once a mysterious
computer virus that infected
computers at large corporations
and ravaged all the data.
Naturally, it is an unstoppable
and undetectable "perfect program."
In fact, it was so elusive
that the people named it...
"The Night Baron!"
The Night Baron?!
Everyone who knows
computers knows its name.
I see. And the tour organizer
is also named the Night Baron!
So that gives some idea as to
the contents of the program!
Hearing that name
brings back memories.
Of my son who
died four years ago...
Son?
What's the matter, boy?
Nothing! Bye, mister!
Be careful, Shizue-san.
That lad is one sharp rascal.
Yes, sir.
That's Kon'no-san from Room 2002.
Looks like he's on the phone.
Wonder what he's talking about?
So it was Tokio Ebara...
Tokio Ebara? The old perv?
So he was the hacker?
A hacker?! A person who
steals computer data?!
Yes. And then?
I want one of these someday!
Don't touch Satomi!
S-Satomi?
It's the name of my mother
who died last year!
Are you alright, Satomi?!
Whew, you're okay!
This guy's named his PC
after his dead mother!
Oh? The old perv's gone!
Hey, Miss! Do you know where the person who was sitting here went?
He went back to his room
to do something.
Oh, boy, if you know him,
could you return this to him?
Come to think of it, he had this necktie wrapped around his head...
Huh?
Conan-kun!
Ah, Ran-neechan...
Don't you "Ah, Ran-neechan" me! Always sneaking around like that...
Oh? Where are the others?
Dad, Maeda-san and Akiko-san all went to their rooms long ago.
Oh? Looks like Dad's not back yet...
Come on, Akiko!
Let me in already!
Yeah right, you flirt!
Come on, you've had
too much to drink!
Did something happen?
She says I was eyeing the waitress...
You were!
Geez...
Guess I'll go up to the top
lounge until she cools off...
Why don't you come too, Ran-san?
Just forget about her!
Well, let's go!
Okay...
Seriously?
Observation Lounge
The starry sky looks so pretty!
Yes, but not nearly as pretty as you.
Just teasing!
Oh, excuse me.
Wow, the ocean's pitch black.
Oceans sure are creepy at night!
Conan-kun...
So, Maeda-san, when did you first meet Akiko-san?
When I was a kid. I was best
friends with her older brother.
He died three years ago, though...
Akiko-san's brother passed away?
Sounds like everyone else here...
Ran-neechan. Where did the old man go anyway?
I saw him earlier with a woman.
Kamijo-san from Room 2102, I believe.
I see...
Forgot about the other old pervert...
Princess Hotel 2F Pub Emerald
Sorry...
I see, so you were married...
Yes. I divorced three years ago, though.
Why would anyone divorce
such a beautiful woman?!
Anyway, could you tell me now?
You know who the Night
Baron is by now, right?
I can't tell you! The hotel fee's at stake here!
Oh, come on! At least a hint!
Please, Mr. Great Detective!
She's got great boobs...
You're so stubborn!
This could be one fun night!
Well, guess I should
get back to my room.
Yeah, get lost already!
Akiko should have cooled off by now.
Plus I'd get bitten if
I stay with you any longer...
...by your little bodyguard.
Later.
Um, do you know what the virus is?
Virus? Like a cold?
Nevermind...
What kind of weird question was that?
The perfect computer virus, "Night Baron".
With it, one could threaten banks or corporations
out of large sums of money.
I'm sure lots of people would like to get it.
But what is the tour organizer trying to do by gathering such people?!
Is it just a game?! Or maybe—
What's that?
Hey, look!
What is it?
NEXT EPISODE
It's disturbing that the immortal Night Baron would perish...
But why did the Night Baron fall?
It was just an accident.
An accident?
Hey, this knot is strange...
The Night Baron!
Next Conan:
The Night Baron Murder Case
(The Suspicion)
N-N-N-N-Next Conan's Hint: Karate
Look forward to the next episode!
Ran-neechan plays a big part next time!
Ran-chan and the old man togeth—
Hi-yah!