A racing second hand, a shooting comet!
Conan's logic works great on hearts
tired by modern society!
Today's case is a stalker!
Let's think about what bothers people!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
The air's so fresh!
It sure is nice in the early morning!
Yeah! Today is perfect walking weather!
It was still dark when you woke me up.
I didn't get enough sleep!
Guts-Man!
Hold on a sec.
Are you going to drink something?
I'm so sleepy I can't keep up...
Two came out! I'm so lucky!
Are you sure there wasn't one already there?
I wouldn't drink it if I were you...
But there are no signs of it being opened,
and nothing looks out of the ordinary.
Doesn't smell strange, either.
Someone probably just forgot it
after buying a bunch of 'em.
Over there!
Ran! Get an ambulance!
Right!
Come on! Hang in there!
Hey!
Guts-Man!
Hey! Did you drink that?!
Could it have been poisoned?!
The deceased is Tatsuya Nagai-san, 26.
He lived on 3rd Street in Midori-dai.
Two train stops from here.
What's the matter?
I just thought I saw him somewhere before...
There's paint on his shoulder...
Inspector.
The poison in the Guts-Man might be an organic phosphate compound.
Organic phosphate?
Yes. Small amounts cause nausea or drooling,
while large amounts result in respiratory failure.
Inspector Megure. This was an indiscriminate murder.
What?!
Follow me!
Where are you going, Mouri-kun?!
Now, then.
The killer placed the poisoned Guts-Man in the corner like so.
Then Nagai-san stopped by and bought a Guts-Man.
But it was the poisoned one he took,
not the one he purchased.
Then, after drinking it, the poison took effect and he collapsed.
But is there proof the killer put the poisoned Guts-Man in there?
Yes.
This.
I bought a Guts-Man here as well.
When I did, I found an extra bottle down there.
Say, there's a sticker on that Guts-Man!
It's for a special campaign, but it ended three days ago!
As proof, there aren't any on your bottles.
No, there aren't.
Nor on this one!
I see. This may serve as a vital clue.
I just remembered! I stopped and questioned that man before!
What?!
It was about three weeks ago.
A woman in an apartment up ahead
reported being troubled
by a creepy man who constantly followed her around.
That's when I found this man
loitering out in front!
So that means he was a stalker!
Yes. He followed her because he liked her.
But he hadn't actually done anything,
so I gave him a stern warning.
What was his job?
He said he was studying for entrance exams.
Is that woman's apartment near here?
Yeah, just past where he died...
So maybe he was heading there again? Or following her?!
Well?
But she didn't report anything since then,
so I figured he had stopped following her...
Alright! Let's go talk to her for now!
He's dead?!
Yes. He consumed a poisoned energy drink only 40 minutes ago.
Pardon my asking,
but where were you at the time?
Forty minutes ago?
I had just gotten home...
I work at a restaurant in Haido.
We close up at 4:00, so I left around 5:00.
Did you take the train to Beika Station?
Yes.
And did you walk home from there?
Which means it's just as Conan said...
Let us see your map.
Yes, sir.
Nishitani-san. Please show us
what route you took coming home.
Alright...
I went from the station like so.
Just as I thought!
She passed by the vending machine
and the spot where he collapsed!
What does that mean?!
Nagai-san collapsed here.
In other words, he was following you.
That can't be!
And I was so relieved once he disappeared after he was warned!
Did she really not realize she was being followed?
The windows and door have extra locks...
And she even has defense spray ready...
Were these merely from when she was afraid of her stalker?
It was an organic phosphate compound in the Guts-Man.
Only Nagai-san's fingerprints were found on the bottle.
In other words, it's very likely the killer prepared it in advance.
Did you determine where that Guts-Man bottle was purchased?
Not yet, but if it was from that machine,
then it was bought between yesterday afternoon and 7 days ago.
Yesterday, the company replaced all the bottles with unstickered ones.
I see.
Thank you.
Nagai-san's mother recently moved here from Shizuoka.
I checked her apartment and found this.
Photos of that woman we spoke to this morning.
And they all seem to be sneak shots.
I visited Nishitani-san again before coming here.
She had no idea she was photographed...
She seemed extremely shocked.
Huh?
That's not the same apartment...
And that's not a restaurant...
She lived in Yokohama,
where she worked at a bakery
and dreamed of opening her own store.
Did she move here to escape Nagai-san?
Apparently so.
But she couldn't sleep due to fear,
so she started working nights at a restaurant instead.
She must've been so scared. Poor girl...
But Nagai-san received money from his father, an ironsmith,
so he didn't need to work.
Meaning he could follow her
whenever he wanted.
That's one lousy man she got caught up with.
About her...
Did she really not know she was being followed?
I agree. There's something about her!
Are you saying she poisoned the Guts-Man and had him drink it?
We can't rule it out.
Perhaps she knew she was being followed,
bought a Guts-Man from that machine,
and left the poisoned one when she picked it up.
If Nagai-san also bought one and grabbed the wrong one—
But there was no guarantee he'd buy the same drink...
Say, Inspector.
You're forgetting something important. Look.
See how the bottom ring is cut?
Nobody would drink it if they saw the cap had already been undone.
That's true!
Which means the killer didn't leave it in that vending machine?
Now nothing makes sense...
Oh, one other thing about Nagai-san...
His neighbors saw him leave his apartment around 10:00 last night
with a small bag in hand.
He was empty-handed when he collapsed this morning...
It might have nothing to do with the incident, but it bothers me...
A bag?
Isn't there a way she could've had him drink an opened Guts-Man?
Can't drink any more!
Conan-kun! Let's swim!
I'm gonna stay here a little longer.
I'm gonna go swim then!
What's with you guys?
- Nothing!
You're after the rest of her cola, aren't you?
Yeah, right! That's crazy talk!
Yeah!
Let's take a swim, Mitsuhiko-kun!
Good idea, Genta-san!
It sure is hot!
That it is!
Geez. Kids acting like perverts...
That's it! I've figured it out!
I know how it was done, but there's no proof!
Oh! Policeman!
Conan-kun, was it?
Yes!
Are you questioning people?
Yeah.
I was hoping to learn that the victim bought the Guts-Man here...
Did you check the fingerprints on the coins in the vending machine?
Yes, but we didn't find the victim's prints.
But we did find two coins totaling 110 yen that had been wiped clean.
So the killer did buy the Guts-Man here!
If only this had been a bigger shop...
Sometimes you'll catch 'em
on surveillance video...
Video? What if—
Say, did you check everything Nagai-san was carrying?
What was he carrying?
Mr. Mouri asked me to ask you.
Okay...
Let's see...
A wallet, a license, cigarettes, an apartment key, and a lighter.
A lighter?! What kind?!
It had a flip top and was a little bigger than normal ones.
Where is it now?
We returned it to the victim's mother.
Great! Thanks!
Pardon me!
Yes?
May I ask you something?
Sure...
The paint that was on the victim!
Mister! Where did you get that paint?!
Mouri Detective Agency.
Mouri-kun. Megure here...
But didn't you call me here?
What are you talking about?
You called me here.
Huh?
What is this about? I need to leave for work...
Um, well...
Inspector! It appears I called you.
Oh! It's started! Please continue!
Nishitani-san. Please tell work you won't be in.
Because you're the one who poisoned and killed Nagai-san!
What are you—
That morning, you knew Nagai-san was following you
so you bought a Guts-Man from that vending machine.
Let us call that Bottle A.
You then took your pre-prepared Bottle B
and pretended to pick up Bottle A as he watched on.
You removed the cap and drank it as you walked.
Then you put a closed bottle on a wall.
But it was not the Bottle B which you had just drunk;
it was yet another bottle you had prepared in advance: Bottle C.
Incidentally, stalkers are known to collect their prey's belongings.
So Nagai-san naturally took Guts-Man Bottle C.
He found a large amount of the drink left inside.
As he was infatuated with you, he happily drank it down...
...unaware it had been poisoned.
The reason you left the Guts-Man in the machine
was to make it look like an indiscriminate murder.
Your fingerprints were absent from the coins used to buy Bottle A
and from empty Bottle C
because you likely put glue on your fingers in the station restroom.
Glue?!
When we first visited, she slyly rubbed something off her fingers.
It was dried glue.
It's unnatural to wear gloves this time of year,
and holding the bottle in a tissue would've roused his suspicion.
So you used glue instead.
Theorize all you want. You have no proof.
Oh, but I do.
Conan!
Here.
These are—
It seems you didn't know he was secretly photographing you.
I can't blame you; he was using a customized camera.
A customized camera?
This.
This lighter works like normal,
but slide this and it becomes a camera.
This button works the shutter.
He was good with his hands, like his skilled ironsmith father.
Closer inspection of those photographs will show
that there is a sticker on the Guts-Man there.
The special campaign sticker?
As you said, all the Guts-Man bottles in that vending machine
were replaced with new, unstickered bottles yesterday afternoon.
In other words...
Yes.
I killed him.
I thought he would kill me if I didn't.
What do you mean?
One week ago, when I walked down the station stairs...
His look said, "How dare you tell the police! I'm gonna kill you!"
So I felt my only choice was to kill him first!
Inspector. It's a fact that Nagai-san planned to kill her.
What?!
Look at the bag behind you.
It belonged to Nagai-san,
and was hidden by a nearby lamppost that had been freshly painted.
Please have a look inside.
Nagai-san probably planned to get the bag when she came home,
wait for his chance to get inside by cutting a hole in the window,
and then kill her with that knife.
So she was almost—
It won't hold up as self-defense,
but you'll likely get off
on mitigating circumstances.
Nishitani-san.
Atone for your sin as quickly as possible
and then continue toward your dream
of running your own bakery.
You're still so very young.
Thank you.
This case really made me think, especially about stalkers.
You do get clients who talk about being followed
or receiving silent phone calls.
Proving this kind of crime is difficult.
The police won't do much,
but even if they do do something,
the instant the crazed person finds out you're strongly repulsed,
they can turn into a full-fledged criminal.
Yeah, I'll need to be careful.
Don't worry! Nobody'd ever go crazy for a shrew like you!
What'd you say?!
I never wanna be on her bad side!
Conan-kun!
There's no blood around a part of his wrist!
The suspects are triplets?!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's hint: Home Run
Next time, we're annoyed as we
get deceived by triplets. Lame!
osomatsu
Osomatsu is a sextuplet!