A racing second hand, a shooting comet!
Conan's logic works great on hearts
tired by modern society!
Today's case is Shinigami Jin'nai
and his devious crime!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid
but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Created by
Gosho Aoyama
"Detective Conan"
Serialized in Shogakukan's
"Weekly Shonen Sunday"
Planning
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Character Design
Masatomo Sudo
Art Director
Yukihiro Shibutani
Art Design
Hiroyuki Mitsumoto
Director of Photography
Takahisa Ogawa
Sound Director
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
Music Producer
Hiroki Horio
(PolyGram)
Music
Katsuo Ono
Opening Theme
"Nazo"
Performed by
Lyrics
Music
Arrangement
Miho Komatsu
Hirohito Furui
(Spoonful/Zain Records)
Editor
Teramitsu Okada
Story Editor
Jun'ichi Iioka
Color Key
Reiko Hirayama
Associate Producer
Satoshi Yokoyama
Planning Support
Toyohiko Okuyama
Mitome Asai
Director
Kenji Kodama
Producers
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Masahito Yoshioka
(Tokyo Movie)
"I am coming for the foul Kenzo Kuroda.
—Shinigami Jin'nai"
Wicked lawyer Kenzo Kuroda!
I'm here to send you to Hell!
Help...!
It's time!
"Shinigami Jin'nai—
A New Challenge"
Does he usually fall asleep
in the first five minutes?!
Really, now!
We were lucky to see an early
screening and you fall asleep!
I couldn't help it!
I was up all night working!
You mean drinking!
But the movie wasn't that great.
Really? I liked it...
Well, I guess this series
IS getting stale...
It's Shinigami Jin'nai's actor,
Hayato Nanjo!
Hayato Nanjo (42)
Movie Actor
Excuse me...
Aren't you the famous Kogoro Mouri-san?
Yes, I'm Kogoro Mouri,
the great detective!
Miyuki Nanjo (37)
Nanjo's Wife
I'm Hayato Nanjo's wife.
Nice to meet you! That was a great movie!
Gimme a break...
There's something I'd like
to talk to you about...
Right in here, Detective Mouri.
This is quite a nice office!
No, we couldn't find anywhere new...
Here you are.
Satomi-san.
This is Kogoro Mouri-san,
the famous detective.
Satomi Yoshino (28)
Nanjo's Manager
I'm Hayato Nanjo's manager,
Satomi Yoshino.
Satomi-san. Show it to him...
But, ma'am...!
Just show it to him.
Alright...
What the...?!
"I am coming for Hayato Nanjo tonight.
—Shinigami Jin'nai"
A warning from Shinigami Jin'nai?!
It was in the office
mailbox this morning.
Did you take it to the police?
No...
There's no need.
It's obviously a prank!
But, Honey...!
I told you not to do anything!
Sorry, but I must ask you to leave.
But, Nanjo-san! Your wife
is this worried about you...
Even if the letter is real,
I'll protect myself!
But, still...!
Anyway, I'm busy! Get out!
Yoshino-kun. You can
leave for today, too.
Behind me is the office of Hayato Nanjo,
who has received a death threat
from Shinigami Jin'nai.
It's just past 9:00.
Will Shinigami Jin'nai appear as warned?
The famous Kogoro Mouri-san
is also present,
so the tension is high!
Hello. I'm the great Kogoro Mouri.
What're you doing?
OK, we're done! Take a short break!
Everything will be all right.
The culprit can't make a move
as long as we're here!
Now, now, Mouri-san.
Tadao Ohno (45)
TV Director
There's no need to get excited;
he's not gonna show.
What do you mean?
It's obvious that Nanjo did
this just to promote the movie!
How dare you say that?!
Please, calm down, ma'am...!
I'll go buy something to drink!
Let's go, Conan-kun!
Huh? Isn't that Satomi-san, his manager?
You're right! I guess
she didn't go home yet...
What do you think she's doing?
She could watch the office from there!
She's probably worried too!
Let's go, Conan-kun!
So Nanjo-san's the only
one here this late...
Hey, where's Ohno-san?
He went to the bathroom...
What do we do next?
I'll go look for him...
What is it?
Over there...!
Shinigami Jin'nai!
Hey! Get the camera!
Give yourself up!
Damn! I lost him!
Nanjo-san's in danger!
Crap!
Satomi-san! Why are you here?!
I was in that burger shop
when I saw Shinigami Jin'nai
run inside the building!
What?!
Dammit!
No you don't, Conan-kun!
But...!
Conan-kun! Was that—
The culprit's still on the 7th floor!
I just saw his shadow!
Alright!
Damn, what's this tape for?!
Vinyl tape...?
So the killer disappeared
from the scene, Mouri-kun?
Yeah, Inspector.
The windows are all
locked from the inside,
and the elevator and the stairs
are the only way off the 7th floor.
But he was gone when we rushed in.
And you're certain that
nobody left the building?
Yes, we and the reporters
were out front the whole time...
But what about the emergency stairs?
Inspector.
The emergency stairs here meet up
with the first-floor elevator
and lead to the same exit.
I watched the emergency stairs,
but nobody used them.
So the killer just
disappeared like smoke...
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
Doesn't it seem strange?
We saw the killer standing at
the window when the lights came on.
But the light switch is by the door.
How exactly did he turn the lights on?
That is strange...
Why did the killer turn the lights
on after murdering Nanjo-san?
And—
Why on earth did the killer
leave this vinyl tape behind?
Most likely so we would trip
and get tangled up in it,
allowing him to make his getaway.
But you're the only one
who tripped on it!
"Nanjo-sama, please
look over the article."
An article check request...
10:03 PM. Just before he was murdered...
Just about the time Shinigami
Jin'nai appeared in the park...
But isn't this—
Alright, you!
Don't touch that!
That's an interview that's being
published in a magazine next week.
Nanjo-san was waiting
for it to arrive tonight.
Let go of me!
Inspector! This shady
character was lurking about!
How rude! I'm no shady character!
Ohno-san! Where have you been?!
I returned from the bathroom
to find everyone gone,
so I was looking around the park!
So it was you who killed my husband!
What are you talking about?!
Come to think of it,
you're the only one without an alibi!
You were still bitter about
the accident 3 years ago...
...so you killed him!
That's insane!
What is she referring to?
I work on an entertainment show now,
but I was once a movie director.
Until the accident 3 years ago during
the filming of Shinigami Jin'nai...
The designated stuntman
never showed up that day...
We have no choice.
We'll do it without him.
I dunno, Nanjo. It's too dangerous!
You can handle it, right, Kitano?
Hiroyuki Kitano (28)
Movie Actor
Up-and-coming actors need
to be able to do this much.
Yeah...
Director! I'll do it!
But...!
Kitano-kun had agreed, so filming
began upon Nanjo's insistence.
The car flipped over and exploded.
Kitano-kun was killed.
I took full responsibility
and gave up the director's chair.
I did resent Nanjo.
But there's someone who
resented him much more right there!
After all, she was Kitano-kun's lover!
Is this true?!
Yes. Hiroyuki Kitano was my lover.
I worked for the same agency as a
second-rate action movie actress.
Yes, it was a terrible accident!
But I don't blame Nanjo-san for it!
Satomi-san was out front with us
when Nanjo-san was killed!
Oh yeah! I caught Shinigami
Jin'nai on tape in the park!
What?! So that should show—
There's a VCR on the 6th floor!
I'll go set it up!
Come to think of it, why did the
killer show himself in the park?
The same with the window locks—
there must be some reason!
It came from downstairs!
Come on!
The stairs are faster!
Shinigami Jin'nai just—
What?!
And when you got off the elevator,
the emergency exit was open.
Then Shinigami Jin'nai came out
of the office, fired, and ran off?
Yes...
That's odd. It's exactly one hour
since Nanjo-san was killed.
Did he hide in the building and
avoid police detection the whole time?
And why did he shoot, anyway?
Satomi-san was alone.
Running off would've been far safer
than firing and attracting attention!
Inspector.
We finished examining the murder scene.
Good work. Did you find the bullet?
No. It probably flew outside
through the emergency exit.
In which case,
finding it will be difficult.
Inspector. The video's all set.
Let's have a look.
Why's this one by itself?
It's still warm.
And it's not rewound!
Could it be...?!
You shouldn't touch
other people's things.
I'm sorry!
Aha! I've figured out the killer's trick!
But I need more proof!
That's it! That fax!
Hey, Conan! Where're you going?
Just as I thought!
No question about it!
That person is the killer!
Hey! Conan! Quit running around!
Look at this!
Huh? This is just that fax...
What's so big about it?
Hello?
Right.
Inspector.
It's Mouri-san.
Thanks...
Hello? Mouri-kun?
What?! You solved the mystery?!
Yes. The killer didn't disappear.
He was never there in the first place!
What?! What does that mean?
It means Nanjo-san was already dead
when we got to the building.
But Conan-kun and the others
saw the killer in the window!
That was a trick the killer set up.
Trick?!
I'll demonstrate it for you.
Have everyone come back upstairs.
Please bring some vinyl tape
and fishing line as well.
Vinyl tape and fishing line?
It seems everyone's here, so I'll begin.
First, after murdering Nanjo-san,
the killer cut the lights
and placed the vinyl tape
on the window in a zigzag manner
to create the shape of a person.
Next, he affixed the
fishing line to the area
between the elevator and the outer door.
He then wrapped the line around
the light switch in the office,
and tied the end to the
tape roll on the window.
All that remained was for someone
to call the elevator down...
The light made it look like
someone was in the room.
The tape came undone
when the line was pulled,
making it look like
the person was crouching.
When pulled far enough,
the tape roll caught on the elevator,
and then the line snapped,
leaving the roll behind.
But what about the gunshot?
That was a cassette tape recording.
A cassette tape?
Yes. The killer shot Nanjo-san
with a silencer-equipped gun,
set up the elevator trick,
took the stairs to the 6th floor,
and put a tape with a
gunshot on it in the stereo.
There'd be no way to make certain
the gunshot was heard below...
The killer added 15 minutes of
silence to the start of the tape
and used that time to appear
in the park as Shinigami Jin'nai
and lure us to the building.
The killer then met up and heard the
gunshot with us to create an alibi.
Hold on a second!
Does that mean the killer is—
Yes! The only one capable
of pulling off this trick...
...was you, Satomi Yoshino-san!
But what was the second gunshot for?
The second gunshot
wasn't meant to happen.
Yoshino-san didn't realize
the stereo was set on auto-rewind.
As it was a 60-minute tape,
the same gunshot rang out one hour later!
When you went downstairs
to set up the VCR,
you probably recovered the fishing line!
Then the gunshot suddenly played!
Surprised, you quickly hid the tape
and came up with a lie.
There's no proof!
But there is.
Inspector. Have a look at the faxes.
Alright...
One of the pages should
have bloodstains on it.
That fax came in just as
the murder was taking place.
Here it is!
In other words, the time on
the page with bloodstains
is the real time Nanjo-san was murdered.
9:59 PM.
We heard the gunshot at around 10:15.
That makes it 15 minutes before then.
There should be a gunshot on
that tape you took from Conan.
Plus, Shinigami Jin'nai could
move so nimbly in the park
because you used to be
an action movie actress.
You're right. I killed Nanjo.
To get revenge on him for
killing Hiroyuki three years ago!
But that was an accident...
I thought so too at first!
But then I found Hiroyuki's diary.
The week before the accident,
there was talk of him replacing
Nanjo as Shinigami Jin'nai!
I joined Nanjo's agency as a manager
to learn the truth about his death!
And then a month ago,
Nanjo got drunk and divulged everything!
Hey, Yoshino. Remember that kid
who died three years ago
during the filming of Shinigami Jin'nai?
Yes. Didn't he get in an accident
while doing his own stunt?
Accident, huh...
Accident, indeed...
Here's something interesting.
I lied to the stuntman
so he wouldn't come that day.
The kid was a beginner
but thought he could steal my role!
You know what this is?
No. What is it?
My good luck charm.
A bolt that keeps a
car's front wheels in place.
What?! That means—
That's right! He didn't wait
for an accident to happen!
He killed Hiroyuki himself!
I wrote the letter to
use the media as an alibi.
When I advised using it to promote
the movie, Nanjo readily agreed.
The rest was as you said.
Shinigami Jin'nai versus
Detective Kogoro Mouri.
Looks like Shinigami Jin'nai
lost completely.
Of course he did!
The word "unsolvable" isn't
in Kogoro Mouri's dictionary!
And who do you have to thank for that?
Damn it! We'll just
have to bust it down!
Eh?!
None of their things came out positive?!
The one behind this manipulated
the victim in this empty office
and poisoned him!
As if by magic!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Toilet
Next time, it's really tough!
That guy smells.
Sorry.