A racing second hand, a shooting comet!
Conan's logic is the tonic
for hearts tired by modern society!
Today's the Kaitō Kid special!
Detective and thief square off!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
I'm high school student Shin'ichi Kudo.
I went with Ran Mouri, childhood friend and classmate,
to an amusement park,
where I witnessed a suspicious deal involving a man in black.
I was so engrossed with watching that I didn't see his partner hiding!
I was knocked down and given a poison.
When I woke up, my body had shrunk!
If they learned Shin'ichi Kudo was alive,
people around me would be in danger!
After following Dr. Agasa's advice to conceal my identity,
Ran asked me my name and I quickly said...
Conan Edogawa!
Then, to uncover information about them,
I moved in with Ran and her detective father.
Kaitō #1412?
Yeah! He's an older thief that all the young girls are crazy about!
"Older?"
Your dad's a detective and you never heard of him?!
That doesn't mean I love following crimes.
But hear me out!
So you want my dad to catch this thief?
That's right!
You know Beika Museum's exhibit of world-famous jewels?!
Daddy submitted our family gem,
the lucky Black Star pearl,
and wants it protected from Kaitō #1412's evil grasp!
Black Star
But why ask my dad and not the police?
We can't do that! The police would haul him off if they caught him!
But if your dad catches him, he might let us see his face!
His face?
Yeah! Don't you wonder what he looks like?!
#1412 has the entire world going crazy!
I bet he's a fabulous guy!
Like Harrison Ford or John Lennon...
You live so happily...
The light's green, Sonoko.
Coming!
It'd be nice if he was like Brad Pitt!
Shin'ichi!
Hey, now! The light's red!
But, that was Shin'ichi!
It was Shin'ichi...
You sure it wasn't just a look-alike?
You passed by Shin'ichi-niichan in Shibuya?!
Yeah, right!
It's true!
But he wouldn't respond! Isn't that horrible?!
Hey, now! I wasn't in Shibuya!
And besides, I haven't even changed bodies!
Yeah, he's probably sick of you.
Just forget about that mystery dweeb.
Yeah... He was walking with a girl, too...
It was someone else! Don't worry about it!
What?
Anyway, do they really want me to catch this Kaitō something-or-other?
Kaitō #1412!
What's with the 1412?
No one's really sure where it comes from.
According to Sonoko, he steals art and jewels from all over the world,
and his top secret FBI or CIA or Interpol number was 1412.
The leading theory is that people learned the number and it just stuck!
Sounds fake to me.
Apparently he has a different name in Japan, though.
It's probably just word play.
Like "The Crazy Thief" or something.
I don't think it was anything that old man-like.
How dumb. Who cares about some thief?
I'm going to bed.
Oh, yeah. I have a copy of a weird warning letter
that Kaitō #1412 sent to Sonoko's house.
A weird warning letter?
It doesn't make any sense! It's like a code!
"April Fools."
"When the moon splits the two,
I shall enter upon waves"
"in the name of the black star."
"Kaitō..."
It's torn here...
Yeah, Sonoko's father tore it up in anger when it arrived
then taped it back together.
Still, this makes no sense at all.
All I do get is that "April Fools" means he'll show up on April 1st...
Hey! I thought you went to bed!
Lemme see...
Conan-kun?
March 31
Beika Museum
1:42 PM
Wow...
It's like all the police in Tokyo
have been mobilized...
I guess he really is a big international thief!
All that work and I still didn't break the code...
Detective Mouri!
Thank you for coming!
I truly appreciate your listening to my daughter!
Shiro Suzuki (51)
Head of Suzuki Industries
We're 100 men strong with a detective like you here!
We're counting on you, Detective Mouri!
It's just one measly thief.
I'll capture him with no trouble at all!
Sure you will! You haven't even cracked the code yet!
So this is the largest black pearl in the world, the Black Star?
Yes. The Suzuki family has been
blessed with prosperity
ever since my grandfather first purchased it.
It's the family's guardian angel.
Security sure is tight for the day before the theft.
Yes. All we got from the letter was the date.
I'm told that security will be on full detail starting tonight—
there's no telling from when
or where Kaitō #1412 will strike.
What?!
I already told you! The river!
Deploy men along the river bank!
Shintaro Chaki (49)
Police Commissioner, Section 2
Kaitō #1412 plans to sneak inside from the nearby Teimuzu River!
You cracked the code?
Sure did!
The "enter upon waves" bit refers to the Teimuzu River!
The Teimuzu River is the only place in the vicinity with waves!
Teimuzu River
Beika Museum
Weren't you Mouri from Section 1?
You're sloppy, Commissioner!
What?!
Don't you get it?
"Waves" means the ocean, which means "coast"!
oki
And "star" means a pop star!
In other words, the idol star who performs live tomorrow
at the nearby Beika Town Hall, Yoko Okino-chan!
What's more, her last song will be "Moon Lady"!
"When the moon splits the two" means that...
Beika Museum
Beika Town Hall
...Kaitō #1412 will come from the vicinity of Beika Town Hall
Beika Museum
when the show ends at 9:00 pm!
Beika Town Hall
Whatever you say...
Yes, that does make sense.
Well done, Detective Mouri!
Hey, now...
Alright! Have Teams C through E assemble near Beika Town Hall!
Yes, sir!
Hey!
Still, I haven't broken the code either...
Say, where's the fellow who was transferred to us last month?
The inspector? He took some officers somewhere this morning...
What's he thinking?!
Anyway, it's 2:00! Why don't we have lunch nearby?
Are you guys gonna have lunch?
We ate on the way here...
Eat?
Wait a minute! Could it be?!
Conan-kun! Where are you going?
What are you doing, Conan-kun?
Checking the direction with my watch.
The direction?
Yeah. First, you point the hour hand toward the sun.
Japan's in the northern hemisphere, so halfway between it and 12
is where south is!
I was just testing something Shin'ichi-niichan told me, of course!
Which means south is at
1 o'clock, and southeast at 2:30!
Aha! I've figured you out, Kaitō #1412!
March 31
11:04 PM
Fast asleep!
Agasa here.
Oh, Shin'ichi! Eh? What?
You want me to find out about Kaitō #1412?
Please, Doc. He should be in my dad's crime files.
But what do you need it for?
I want to know about him before I meet him!
Meet him?! You know where he is?!
Yup! I've figured out his route inside!
Then why didn't you tell the police?!
I suddenly wanna see it, too...
...the face of a retro thief who sends warning notices in this day and age!
The "two" in "when the moon splits the two"
refers to a satellite and the sun!
And if the splitting refers to the moon creating an eclipse between them...
...then he'll show up between 12:30 and 4:00 am when BS TV is off!
Yes! The Black Star's initials are BS!
Broadcast Satellite
If the "waves" refer to a satellite signal...
...then he'll be coming from the direction of the BS signal!
The BS signal is sent from south to west at a 45° angle
and from 42.3° above the horizon.
Haido City Hotel
The only place that fits the bill is the roof of the Haido City Hotel!
Inspector! A strange kid ran into the hotel! What do we do?!
Nothing. There's only one person I'm after.
And not even he could dress up as a child.
Employees Only
Beika Museum is... right around there.
12:28.
Now I just wait for him to show up...
Hello? Doc?
Hi, Shin'ichi.
I checked your dad's files with recent newspaper articles.
Kaitō #1412 is enveloped in quite a bit of mystery.
His first appearance was in Paris 18 years ago.
He suddenly disappeared 10 years later and was presumed dead,
but he's back after 8 years and is primarily active in Japan.
18 years ago? He must be pretty old then...
He has all kinds of names...
"The Modern Lupin," "The Moonlight Magician"...
But there's one alias that people like the most...
Alias?
A young novelist interested in the crafty Kaitō #1412
once jokingly read the number like so...
"K I D."
"K I D?"
That's right. Kaitō #1412 is known as...
...the Kaitō Kid!
He landed silently before me,
so as not to disturb the stillness of the night.
Together with a fearless smile,
as if he saw through everything.
What's going on, Shin'ichi? Shin—
A cape and a silk hat...
An impenetrable stance...
I can't make out his face, but he's surprisingly young.
His thirties. Twenties? No, even younger!
Hey, little boy.
What are you doing up here?
Fireworks!
What?!
A strange flash and sound?!
Yes. Above the Haido City Hotel, southwest of the museum.
Shall I check it out, Commissioner?
Of course you shall!
Look! A helicopter! I think it noticed!
Seems you're no ordinary kid.
I'm Conan Edogawa. A detective.
Shouldn't you be escaping, Kaitō Kid-san?
The helicopter will be here any minute.
I only have one chance to get him with my tranquilizer gun!
The instant he turns away to escape!
A radio?!
Chaki here! Kaitō Kid sighted on top of the Haido City Hotel!
Attention all patrol cars in Beika and Haido
and all helicopters in the air above Beika!
Proceed to the scene at once and capture the Kaitō Kid!
He's using my voice!
Wait! That's not me!
It's his trap! All units, return at once!
This is Helicopter #1! I'm above the hotel!
Sighting confirmed!
What?!
I think he sent the orders!
This is Nakamori!
Attention all officers inside the Haido City Hotel!
The Kid's on the roof! Rush to the scene at once! Seize him!
This guy's incredible...
He can imitate any voice without a machine!
Damn it!
Your voice is on the radio!
It's the Kid! He's using my voice to bring us to him!
Ginzo Nakamori (41)
Police Inspector, Section 2
That's insane! Why on earth would he do that?!
What's he doing?!
Satisfied, Detective?
Freeze, Kid!
Oh, my. Inspector Nakamori. You certainly arrived quickly.
Ha! You knew I cracked your code and had the place staked out!
I figured you might hang-glide in, so I checked everyone in the hotel
and fortified the main entrance,
but I never expected you to go around Tohto Tower and then land here.
Forget about the pearl! You have nowhere to run!
I'm only here to observe you tonight. I don't plan to steal anything.
What?!
Oh? I clearly wrote so at the start of the letter!
"April Fools." It was a lie!
Don't let him escape! Get him!
A flash grenade!
Are you aware, little boy?
A phantom thief is a creative artist
who skillfully steals his prey,
kaitō
but a detective is nothing more than a critic
who finds fault in what is left behind!
What?!
He disappeared!
He vanished!
Helicopters! Track him using radar!
It only shows our three helicopters in the area!
Has he gotten away again?!
This is insane! No one can just disappear like that!
What's this?!
"On April 19th, I will appear on the Queen Selizabeth"
"leaving from Yokohama Port to steal the real Black Star."
"—Kaitō Kid"
April 19th
Queen Selizabeth, Yokohama Port
Please cancel it, Commissioner Chaki!
We're dealing with the Kaitō Kid!
We can't let him get near the jewel with such lousy security as that!
Don't be like that, Nakamori-kun!
Tonight's party is full of important people!
We can't do anything rough!
Besides, we'll lose face if we cancel the party out of fear of him!
Don't worry. It'll take three hours for the ship to get to Tokyo.
It's a floating prison! Even if he does get on, he's like a rat in a trap!
Suzuki Industries 60th Anniversary Boat Party
This year marks Suzuki Industries' 60th anniversary.
This is entirely because of the support from you all.
Please forget about sneak thieves for tonight
and enjoy this elegant and grand party
to which 500 have been invited!
But, first!
Tomoko Suzuki (43)
Sonoko's Mother
I have devised a special plan for tonight.
Please open the small boxes given to you before you boarded.
They are my letter of challenge to any foolish thieves.
This is—
Yes! These are our family's symbol,
as well as the Kaitō Kid's prey tonight! The Black Star!
Only one is real, of course.
And only I know to whom it was given.
The rest are imitation pearls!
Now, then. Please put them on your chests
and tell the Kid, "Go ahead and take it, if you dare!"
Of course, that's assuming he manages to determine which one is real
during the three hours we're at sea!
Your mom's pretty smart!
What's wrong, Sonoko?
I can't find my sister...
Don't tell me she's still at home!
Yeah, right!
Eh?! The ship already left?! How come?!
Suzuki Residence
That's my line! Do you know what time it is?!
But the commissioner called
to say he was delaying it 2 hours...
Right, Dad?
Daddy's there?!
Bastard!
Where did the company president go?!
He went to the restroom...
Now I see! He got on board disguised as the president!
I thank you, Kaitō Kid!
You've given me a chance to tear off that bold mask of yours!
Eh?! Kaitō #1412 disguised himself as Daddy to get on the ship?!
I just found his disguise and props in the bathroom!
The officers are checking it now!
Geez.
But this is him. I doubt they'll find any evidence...
Oh? Where's Ran-neechan?
Out looking for you, since you didn't come back.
She was worried Kaitō #1412 had caught you.
It's not "#1412".
His name is Kaitō Kid! Get it right!
Okay...
Who's he?
Inspector Nakamori. He works full-time pursuing the Kaitō Kid.
Like you, he's a reliable knight we hired to protect the Black Star.
Still, Madam!
All 500 people here are wearing black pearls!
And except for the real one, they're all imitations!
I can't guard it unless I know which one is real...
They all look alike, but they're still imitations.
Close scrutiny could narrow it down a bit;
among them are dull and dreary ones such as mine
and excessively shiny rubbish such as yours.
But checking every person in this crowd would be...
Then I'll give you a special hint.
The Black Star, the black pearl with a peacock-green luster
that fascinated my grandfather 60 years ago,
is with someone especially worthy of it.
Worthy?!
Coincidentally, that someone is one out of five hundred...
It must be a woman, if the jewel suits them...
Oh, but it suits you, too, Mouri-san!
Oh, so it is you!
Joji Hatamoto (41)
French Restaurant Chef
It's good to see you again!
Thank you for your help a while back!
Aren't you the Hatamoto Group's—
Yes! Thanks to this fine woman
and the president,
I've opened up more restaurants!
In fact, tonight's meal is my own—
So sorry, Joji-san.
Takuya Mifune (26)
President of Mifune Electronics
Seems Mr. Suzuki won't be there,
thanks to the Kaitō Kid.
Your flattery food will go to waste!
You're as reprehensible as ever!
Nothing of the sort!
The guy from the Yotsui girl's birthday party...
Oh? You're not wearing yours?
I hate childish games like this.
But you'll seem suspicious if you don't wear it.
Fine.
Eh? Ayako-san isn't here?
Yuzo Tomizawa (28)
Sonoko's Sister's Fiancée
No, she couldn't make it...
Oh. That's too bad...
This is the Suzuki Industries party, all right.
It's teeming with rich kids and company presidents.
Ran's taking a long time...
She's probably lost somewhere!
Ran has no sense of direction!
Who has no sense of direction?!
Oh, Ran! I didn't see you there!
I'm Police Commissioner Chaki!
You may have already heard,
but that pesky villain has somehow boarded the ship!
As you know, he's a master of disguise!
He possesses an immeasurable evil talent that he uses
to learn about his target and fully imitate them,
even down to their face, voice, and personality!
He may even be among you already!
Normally, we would carefully inspect each and every person,
but we'll refrain from such incivility here.
Passwords!
Pair up with the person next to you and decide on a password!
I get it! That way he can't keep disguising himself,
which will allow the police to single him out!
What should our password be?
OK, when I say "Holmes"...
...I'll say "Lupin"!
What're you doing, Power Room?!
No, this is—
Kaitō Kid!
Your passwords are pointless.
What?!
The Black Star is already in my hands.
Impossible!
Oh, dear. It's the pesky thief.
I'll just have to punish this scheming boy.
Mom!
What have you done?!
There's no need to worry, Inspector. After all...
...he's still alive!
My guards caught him in the tablecloth
after I pretended to shoot him
with this model gun.
Yes. He's a brilliant magician I hired as entertainment...
...Kazumi Sanada-kun!
Kazumi Sanada (27)
Magician
Let's give him a round of applause for acting out
the Kaitō Kid's pitiable end for us!
I see. Kaitō Kid is an expert magician—
the perfect role for you.
The two of us do happen to be artists who deceive the eyes...
Artists?!
...but I'm a magician by nature. A thief is no match for me!
Now, then! Please come to the stage!
I'll show you some of my magic!
A phantom thief is a creative artist
who skillfully steals his prey,
but a detective is nothing more than a critic
who finds fault in what is left behind!
This sensation!
It's him! He's somewhere in here!
I'll begin with a simple card trick!
Hold on. I've always been the skeptical type.
May I cut that deck?
Certainly. Would any others like to as well?
Who is it?! Who's the Kaitō Kid?!
Damn it!
They all seem suspicious!
There's what she said...
The black pearl is with someone especially worthy of it.
If only I knew what that meant!
I apologize!
That's all right!
Spilled cards won't ruin my luck.
tsuki
Moon?
Say, didn't you have a list of everyone at this party?
Yeah...
Can I see it?
This? Here.
Here you are!
Thank you, ladies!
Let me give you a card in return!
Are you sure?!
Wait! First, let me use my X-ray eye to read your minds
and predict your card!
I'm so excited!
Yeah!
Now I see!
That's why he said that in the second letter!
I've figured it out, Kaitō Kid!
The location of your prey, that is!
A pigeon? Hato? Heart?
hato
hāto
The Ace of Hearts, then!
Please pick any card you wish!
Ran! The right! The right one!
"As Caesar was with Cleopatra, I am already by your side."
"—Kaitō Kid"
The Kid!
He's here!
Calm down, everyone! Confirm your passwords!
Hey! Nakamori-kun! Don't tell me
it's already been stolen!
No, he doesn't have it yet, nor has he escaped!
He's simply confusing us
to make things work his way!
Don't worry, we can catch him! He's not a wizard!
He's a human being who relies on tricks!
Kaitō Kid really left a message?!
Yep! It was on the card Ran just picked!
But when and how did he put this in there?!
The Kid is crafty! Everything about him is a mystery!
All we know is that he's somewhere in here!
Please calm down, everyone!
Does that mean he knows where the real pearl is?!
Even if he did, this is a floating prison.
Could he possibly make off with the Black Star
with this police presence?
Inspector! We'll arrive in Tokyo Harbor in 30 minutes!
Alright! Seal all the exits! Let no one outside!
Time to show yourself, Kaitō Kid!
This is your only chance to strike
while everyone's restless!
Hey, Ran! Where'd your pearl go?!
Eh?! No way!
Excuse me! Could someone pick up that pearl?
What the...
What was that sound?!
The pearl! It exploded!
Don't tell me the Kid rigged them!
Forget this!
I'm not wearing this thing!
Calm down, everyone! Calm down!
Mom!
Are you all right?!
Yes. Thank you, Ran-chan!
Open the door this instant!
I can't do that!
Huh?! Your pearl is gone, too!
The Kid! He stole the Black Star!
What?! So you were wearing the real one?!
Inspector! We can't hold them back!
Inspector! A large group has gotten out!
The Kid's with them! Capture him!
Yes, sir!
Ran-neechan! Let's go catch him, too!
Wait, Conan-kun!
I know who the Kaitō Kid is!
A letter declaring the upcoming theft of the Suzuki family's Black Star
arrived at Sonoko's house.
The sender was one Kaitō Kid.
Upon cracking his code, I waited for him atop the Haido City Hotel.
He landed silently before me
so as not to disturb the stillness of the night.
I only had one chance to use my tranquilizer gun!
The instant he turned away to escape!
But instead of running, he imitated multiple voices without a machine
to lure the police in,
and then vanished like smoke!
All that remained was another letter.
Against Inspector Nakamori's protests,
the Suzuki Industries' 60th anniversary boat party began as scheduled.
Sonoko's mother, Suzuki Tomoko, devised a plan
that looked to spell failure for the Kaitō Kid,
but he blew up the pearls and stole
the Black Star during the confusion!
I've figured out who you are, Kaitō Kid!
What?! You didn't find the Kid?!
No. We checked all the passengers who left the room earlier, but...
He has to be on board still! Check every last person on the ship!
Yes, sir!
But how did he know she was wearing the real Black Star?!
This is the engine room, Conan-kun!
Is the Kaitō Kid really in here?
Say, Ran-neechan. Do you know about the language of jewels?
The language of jewels?
A pearl means "moon" or "woman."
Of the passengers on board,
the only woman with moons in her name
is Tomoko Suzuki-san.
In other words, she had the real one!
But how does that tell you who the Kid is?
The cards!
You know how the card
you chose had his message?
Yeah...
It's a basic trick in which the magician used the pigeon in his right hand
to distract the audience while
he switched decks in his left hand.
So the chosen card would be fixed regardless of who cut the deck.
So if the message was on that card...
...does that mean Kaitō Kid was that magician?!
No! I watched the whole time,
but he never got near the lady!
Then who is it?!
There's one other person
who could've switched cards!
Yes! That person made them fall,
pretended to pick them up,
then removed a card and added the message!
They hid it in their palm
and pretended to pull it from the deck!
Right, Ran-neechan?
Or should I say, Kaitō Kid-san!
This is Chopper #1! He hasn't fled outside!
This is Chopper #2! No suspicious people on deck!
This is Surveillance! Sonar and radar show nothing!
Alright! Keep your eyes peeled!
All onboard officers are to split up onto each floor
and capture the Kid on sight!
Don't let a familiar face fool you!
He's a master of disguise!
Yes. You switched places with Ran
when she left to find me.
Impressive. I hadn't noticed at all.
After becoming Ran, you agitated everyone with your message
and scattered the exploding pearls
to cause mass panic.
You then stole the real Black Star
during the confusion
by pretending to prop her up.
Huh?! Your pearl is gone, too!
The Kid! He stole the Black Star!
The fact that you prepared those fireworks means you knew
she had a large number of replicas made.
Quit joking around, Conan-kun!
I didn't know which one was real,
and I didn't have any hints!
You didn't need hints
to know which one was real!
Once she took her pearl out with a glove, that is.
Pearls are made of calcium carbonate
and are highly reactive to acid.
Oil in the fingers would oxidize the surface and make it lose its luster.
Some people realized, though...
Realized that she'd never give such a delicate jewel to anyone else!
But that's not enough to—
Indeed, that wouldn't be enough.
But add her dull pearl to the equation and speculation becomes certainty!
Yes. Just as old pearls in famous museums fade in color over time,
a pearl's luster lasts a few decades at most.
The Black Star was purchased 60 years ago;
it can't possibly look flawless now.
So it would have been obvious
once you saw her carefully handle
her faded pearl with gloves!
Talk about pathetic!
I was so concerned with you
that I completely forgot!
But wasn't the Black Star
in the museum all shiny?
That's why you didn't take it.
You knew it was a fake.
Then you challenged her in your second letter
and told her to bring the real one.
You even made sure to write "the real one."
Here! If you suspect me that much,
I'll call a policeman to—
I won't let you disappear like you did on that roof!
You didn't call for the police that time to spite me!
You acted like you were about to hang-glide out,
but you quickly dressed up as an officer during the flash,
and hid yourself among them!
Besides, it's senseless to ask for help here.
I set up this one-on-one match out of respect
for the criminal artist who snuck on board amidst all the security.
Yes. Most great artists become famous after they die.
I'll make you a great master, Kaitō Kid.
Once I place you in the cemetery known as jail.
I surrender. I'll give up on this pearl.
Tell the lady I'm sorry for ruining the party!
Now you're sorry...
Oh, yeah! The girl I knocked out to get these clothes...
She'll catch cold if we don't hurry!
I'm a perfectionist, you see!
Another flash grenade!
Oh no!
Damn! I won't let you escape!
Bastard!
I'll get you for this!
Hey! There's a girl asleep in this boat!
What?!
What's she doing in here? Anyway, let's get her out...
Stop!
No! Don't take her out! Stop!
Huh? Wha...
"This crimson dress you gave me the other day suits you wonderfully."
"—The Occasional Dry Cleaner, Kaitō Kid"
Bastard...
They later found the hang glider Kaitō Kid planned to escape with,
but he, himself, had completely vanished from the ship.
Kaito Kid Thwarted!
Grade-schooler Protects Black Star!
There you are! "Grade-schooler Protects Black Star!"
You're a big hero, Conan-kun!
Come on, it was just luck!
But you guys actually met the Kid!
You're so lucky!
Not.
Say, what did he look like?!
Ran?
What?
The Kid's face!
Sorry! He knocked me out too fast...
I saw his face, though.
What kind of older man was he?!
He was surprisingly young.
In his twenties, or maybe...
Don't give me your cold!
Falling into the ocean while touring the Selizabeth! Talk about stupid!
You're so annoying.
It's that brat's fault!
Swimming away was my only option!
Hey! That high-schooler...
Doesn't he look like Shin'ichi-kun?
You think?
Maybe the guy you saw in Shibuya was...
Whew!
That's good to hear!
Hey! Are you alright?!
Mitsuaki-san! What's going on?!
Mitsuaki-san!
Where's Mitsuaki-san?!
He's there. Down below.
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Great Detective of the West
The next episode airs October 20!
Fuu-kun, Ryo-kun, Hazuki-chan, wait for me!