A racing second hand, a glittering shooting star!
Conan's logic is good medicine
for hearts dried by modern society!
Today's case is a sad memory
hidden behind bandages!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Created by
Gosho Aoyama
"Detective Conan"
Serialized in Shogakukan's
"Weekly Shonen Sunday"
Planning
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Character Design
Masatomo Sudo
Art Director
Yukihiro Shibutani
Art Design
Hiroyuki Mitsumoto
Director of Photography
Takahisa Ogawa
Sound Director
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
Music Producer
Hiroki Horio
(PolyGram)
Music
Katsuo Ono
Opening Theme
"Nazo"
Performed by
Lyrics
Music
Arrangement
Miho Komatsu
Hirohito Furui
(Spoonful/Zain Records)
Editor
Teramitsu Okada
Story Editor
Jun'ichi Iioka
Color Key
Reiko Hirayama
Associate Producer
Satoshi Yokoyama
Planning Support
Toyohiko Okuyama
Mitome Asai
Director
Kenji Kodama
Producers
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Masahito Yoshioka
(Tokyo Movie)
During the birthday party of the Nagato Group president,
Mitsuaki-san, husband of second daughter Yasue-san,
was attacked by someone in the room below!
The eldest son, Hideomi-san, appeared on the balcony
with a knife in his mouth!
We rushed to the room below but were too late...
Mitsuaki-san had been impaled on the fence below!
Two days later, Hideomi-san's body was found in the pond,
along with his will!
It seemed certain that he had done it...
There's something unnatural about that will!
In other words, Hideomi-san had been murdered before it happened!
What?! Nobody left?!
None of them left the premises.
Miyuki Hyuga (26)
Mr. Nagato's Secretary
They went inside before evening...
Yasue Nagato (32)
Second Daughter
of Nagato Family
Hideomi Nagato (36)
Eldest Son of
Nagato Family
Your father told us to be especially alert, too...
Nobuko Nagato (39)
Eldest Daughter
of Nagato Family
Kuranosuke Take (72)
Nagato Family Butler
There's no mistake.
After all, we only left the front door for 1 or 2 minutes
when we discovered the body with you.
Hideomi-san must've used that chance to enter the pond
from the other direction.
The late Mitsuaki-san was the only one who went outside.
Mitsuaki-san did?! When was this?!
I'd say about 9:30...
He said he was looking for Hideomi-san...
He was searching all over. Between trees, around the pond...
Anything strange about Hideomi-san lately?
Nagato Family Kitchen
Yeah! Anything at all! Like, was anything bothering him?
Not sure. He didn't talk much.
Oh, yeah! His meals!
His meals?
He ate much more than usual the day of the murder and the day before!
Yeah! He even ate dessert for once!
It was surprising because he rarely even ate breakfast!
Say, did Hideomi-san always wear the same bandages?
No, Yasue-san changed them every three days.
I think they were last changed 2 days before the incident...
Wait, there was something weird!
One of his sheets disappeared 3 days ago!
Did you count right?!
Yeah...
Hey, Kudo! Come with me!
Over here!
Check it out.
The bottom of Mitsuaki-san's and Yasue-san's balcony.
What's that mark? lt's like something hit it...
And that's the balcony Mitsuaki-san was pushed off of...
Hey!
There's some here, too!
But, there's a lot more on this one.
Whose room is that?
Nobuko-san's.
Seems mighty fishy...
Alright! Let's check it out!
You sure about this, Kudo?!
Nobuko's Room
This makes us no different than thieves!
It's fine!
No, it's not fine...
It's the phone! What do we do?!
This is Nobuko.
He's got some guts...
So, what is it you want?
Remember those drunken messages you left me two days ago?
What time two days ago?
You mean you forgot?
You left a bunch of half-hour messages before 10:00 at night...
Oh, I did?
You don't remember, so never mind. Bye!
10:00 PM two nights ago was when the murder happened!
Yeah.
That at least means the bandaged man on the balcony
wasn't Nobuko-san.
That means only Hideomi-san coulda done it!
Let's look around his room for now!
Hideomi's Room
All these books! He was a writer, all right!
Just look who's trashing the place up...
An answering machine!
We got some messages here!
Really?!
Let's listen!
Hi! This is Yamada from Literature Era!
I'll be at the usual place at 1:00 tomorrow
to discuss your next manuscript!
October 31st, 1:28 PM.
October 31st? That's the day before the incident...
This is Yamada. I'm at the usual coffee shop.
November 1st, 3:04 PM.
This is Yamada. I waited for 6 hours.
I guess you can't come, so I'll be going.
Hey! Don't tell me Hideomi-san was actually—
Yeah, right! His estimated time of death was...
There was a way after all!
Yeah! And only that person could've done it!
Which means...
...it should be here!
Mitsuaki's and Yasue's Room
If our theory is correct, it's probably in here...
Bingo!
A muddy sheet! Oh, and a swimming cap!
Found what I was looking for, too!
Here you are, Hattori-kun!
Give Miyuki-san her pen back now!
Sorry! I forgot!
We're leaving now, Conan-kun. It's already dark out...
What time is it?
10 to 7:00...
Great! The store's still open!
Ran-neechan! Could you buy these for us?
Oh, and do you know who used the room above Nobuko-san's?
I am for now...
Then, please have everyone come there in one hour!
I'll watch this runt until then!
Wait!
Tell old man Kogoro to come right away!
What's with them?!
We put the old man to sleep with the tranquilizer gun...
Miyuki's Room
We had them buy everything we need for our theory...
And our logic is flawless!
But, we forgot something important...
Yeah.
The proof. We have no proof!
We were so focused on our theory that we completely forgot...
Hey. What time is it?
7:40. They'll be here in 10 minutes.
Why didn't you realize it!
Aren't you the great eastern detective!
Shut up! You're the western...
Wait!
Why did that person...
Now I see!
So that was it!
OK! We'll begin in 10 minutes, as scheduled!
What's wrong?
Say, Hattori.
Have you ever killed someone?
We're here, Hattori-kun. What's this about?
Huh? Where's Hattori-kun?
It was I who called you here.
You did?
What's going on?
I finally figured out who killed Mitsuaki-san
and threw Hideomi-san into the pond!
Hey, now. It was Hideomi-san who killed Mitsuaki-san!
Then he poisoned himself in the pond!
Even the handwriting on the will matched up with—
The phone...
Now, then, Inspector. Please pick it up.
Do so and the tragic night Mitsuaki-san died on the fence
will play out once more!
Hello?
Heya! It's me!
Oh, it's just you...
What the hell're you doing?!
Hey! What's going on?!
Someone cut the lights and attacked—
Where are you?!
The room below! Take a look!
What the...
What is going on?!
I don't know! But we have to save him!
Stop right there.
This was how the killer drove everyone from the room...
to hide the terrifying truth that happened in here afterward.
W-Who are you?!
It's me.
Hattori-kun?!
The alarming phone call and the knife and bandaged face
were all an act by Mitsuaki-san to frame Hideomi-san!
That's absurd! The killer was covered in Mitsuaki-san's blood!
And there were cuts on Mitsuaki-san's body!
Those cuts he made himself.
The blood was applied to the bandaged face with a syringe.
The bandages and hat likely belonged to Hideomi-san.
So he wore a swimming cap to keep his own hairs out.
We found the syringe and cap
in Mitsuaki-san's room!
But, Mitsuaki-san was the one murdered!
Why would he do all that?
Most likely to murder President Nagato.
The president?!
Yes. The same president his accomplice drugged.
Accomplice?!
That's right.
The plan was probably for Mitsuaki-san to kill the president
and return below while his accomplice kept everyone downstairs.
But, he was killed by his accomplice instead.
Killed by the person who stayed behind...
you, Miyuki Hyuga-san!
Miyuki-san did it? No way...
Mitsuaki-san musta been shocked
to see you on the balcony
of the supposedly-empty room.
So much so that he fell off!
But, then he should've fallen
with the knife on him!
He likely tossed his knife, bandages, and hat outside before his climb.
Mitsuaki-san planned to strangle the president with the grappling hook
in his jacket pocket!
Naturally, Miyuki-san's only target was Mitsuaki-san.
Nobody would suspect a dead man had used a trick!
Then what was that grappling hook?
That's simple.
She pulled his rope in, grabbed the weight on the opposite end,
then lowered it onto the railing below.
When she tossed the other end over...
the weight hit the bottom of the balcony
and it stopped on its own!
As proof, there are marks on the bottom of the balconies
in the president's room and Mitsuaki-san's room.
And, on Nobuko-san's balcony below us.
Miyuki-san probably tested it
the day before to see if it was possible.
The day before?
Yes. The president had heard it.
He did...
Yes. And the sound of someone running through the hall.
Those footsteps belonged to Miyuki-san, who was calculating the time
to run from Mitsuaki-san's room
to the spare key and back.
In other words, she had planned this murder the day before!
Are you saying she killed Hideomi-san, too?
And what about the will?!
I already told you, Inspector.
Her only target was Mitsuaki-san.
What?!
The will was written by Hideomi-san,
who committed suicide the day before.
The day before?!
Yes.
Miyuki-san most likely found him dead in his room
and then devised this murder!
But, Mouri-kun. The coroner calculated his time of death—
The ground.
Eh?
If you put a body in the ground
and deprive it of air,
it will decay at 1/8 the normal rate.
She probably had Mitsuaki-san help her wrap him in a sheet,
and then they secretly buried him
by the pond in the morning!
There were already lots of holes for trees to be planted in,
so nobody would notice an extra one.
So, who threw him in the pond?
Mitsuaki-san.
He dug him up and threw him
in there just before the murder...
While pretending to look for him, of course...
But, we saw Hideomi-sama the day of the murder...
Nope. What you saw was a disguised Miyuki-san or Mitsuaki-san.
It was clear once we checked his answering machine
that he was dead the day before the murder!
But, why did Mitsuaki-san
go along with Miyuki-san's plan?
She probably told him this,
"I have a good way for you
to take the title of president"
"and place all the blame on Hideomi-san."
That can't be! He saved her life!
She couldn't possibly frame him!
Besides, you don't even have proof!
Do you have the time, Miyuki-san?
What's that have to do with anything, Dad?
Oh? What happened to your watch?
Um, I just forgot to—
No, you didn't forget to put it on.
You can't put it on.
Because its strap broke.
When you pushed Mitsuaki-san off the balcony,
he caught on to your watch strap.
If he tore it off, your watch would land with his body.
Flustered, you used something on you to stab his right hand!
Something? Don't tell me it was...
her pen?!
Yes. She removed the cap with her mouth and stabbed him
with her father's keepsake pen!
But, how did you find that out?
I took the cap off to write some notes
and saw the tip was bent!
Not even a fire could bend something like that!
But, why would Miyuki-san do that?!
The fire was probably the cause.
If our theory is correct, the ones who started that fire 20 years ago...
...were Hideomi-san and Mitsuaki-san!
What?!
Assuming Hideomi-san didn't fix his burn scars to atone for his sin...
And if there was more to his will in which he confessed everything...
...everything would fit.
Now I see. It was revenge for her parents who died in the fire...
But one thing doesn't make sense.
Why did you make Nobuko-san angry
so we'd find Hideomi-san?
You did that on purpose, right?
The police would've found him soon enough...
I didn't want to leave him
in that cold water any more...
Miyuki-san!
Stay away! There's gasoline inside here!
Hey, now! Don't do anything foolish—
I'm serious!
Miyuki-san...
The detective's right! His will explained everything about the fire!
They had to pay... The carefree Mitsuaki...
and Hideomi-san, who never said a word about it...
But, I...
couldn't help but fall in love with him!
He risked his life to save me!
He always came to cheer me up after I lost my family!
And he accepted my proposal!
But Hideomi-san is gone now...
I'm all alone again... I have to hurry to him...
No!
That's pointless.
There's only water inside.
Why? Why?!
Why?! Why?! Why?!
His fire lit so easily! Why won't mine?!
Y'know, Kudo. Maybe we shoulda let her die after all...
Don't be dumb.
A detective who corners someone with logic,
but lets them commit suicide,
is no different from a murderer.
Pains me to hear that. Only the "perfect" you could say such a line!
There's no such thing as a perfect person.
Even I'm just one person...
Just one person...
Besides, I'm sure "he'll" save Miyuki-san.
"He"?
That's enough, Hyuga-kun.
No more foolish talk about following Hideomi...
Sir!
Your mother wasn't that sort of person.
What would you know?! You never knew her!
But I did!
After all, that pen of yours
is a present I gave your mother
when she transferred to my grade school!
It seems you thought it was your father's, though.
I won't ask you to forgive what Hideomi did,
but you're still young! Your life's just begun!
Live strongly for Hideomi, too!
I'm certain your mother wishes that as well!
Shin-Yokohama Station
What?!
His first love was Miyuki-san's mother?!
Yeah, probably. So he made up that lie to cover for her.
I thought he lied and said, "Miyuki-san was with me the whole time,"
as atonement for his son, but I guess it had another meaning!
I bet he wanted to see his first love
because he saw her image in Miyuki-san's face!
Alright, Kudo. Don't tell me you knew that the whole time!
You said "Kudo" again!
Don't tell me "Kudo" means—
No, I said, "Kudoi (annoying)!"
This runt wanted details about the incident, more
so I called him annoying!
You're from Osaka, all right!
I'm the Japanese king of comedy!
So, when the killer struck at Maejima-san with the wooden sword,
this cell phone in Maejima-san's pocket rang?
No! There's another side to this case!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Cellular Phone
keitai denwa
Another interesting case next time!
I call the cell, and get no answer.
keitai
den wa
Lame, fishy, gack!