A racing second hand, a glittering shooting star!
Conan's logic is good medicine for hearts dried by modern society!
Today's case is a bank robbery! But something's a little off!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Created by
Gosho Aoyama
"Detective Conan"
Serialized in Shogakukan's
"Weekly Shonen Sunday"
Planning
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Character Design
Masatomo Sudo
Art Director
Yukihiro Shibutani
Art Design
Hiroyuki Mitsumoto
Director of Photography
Takahisa Ogawa
Sound Director
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
Music Producer
Hiroki Horio
(PolyGram)
Music
Katsuo Ono
Opening Theme
"Nazo"
Performed by
Lyrics
Music
Arrangement
Miho Komatsu
Hirohito Furui
(Spoonful/Zain Records)
Editor
Teramitsu Okada
Story Editor
Jun'ichi Iioka
Color Key
Reiko Hirayama
Executive Producer
Satoshi Yokoyama
Planning Support
Toyohiko Okuyama
Mitome Asai
Director
Kenji Kodama
Producers
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Masahito Yoshioka
(Tokyo Movie)
Wow! A turkey!
That was fun!
Bowling alleys are nice and empty on weekdays!
Definitely!
And it feels great to be done with midterms!
You're always feeling great...
Are you alright, Conan-kun?
I wonder if you caught a cold...
You don't seem to have a fever...
It's early, but maybe we should go home.
Oh no!
What's wrong?!
I forgot to go to the bank!
The bank?
Yeah, Dad asked me to cash a check a client wrote him!
Wasn't there a bank around here?
Tohto Bank is just around... that corner.
Tohto Bank
North Beika Park Branch Office
We just made it, Ran-neechan!
Yeah!
This shouldn't take too long, Conan-kun.
Saburo Tsuji
College Student
Takashi Nagai (60)
Bank Manager
Thank you.
Looks like the cold's really going around.
Hi!
Kazuo Ebisawa (45)
Branch Manager
Sonoko-ojousama! What brings you here today?
I'm just here with a friend...
Is that so?
Please give your father my regards.
Hey, Sonoko. Who was that?
The branch manager here.
The daughter of the Suzuki family shows herself!
Conan-kun...
Totally sounds like a cold.
You all right, little boy?
Noboru Taniguchi
Tohto Bank Clerk
That's a nasty cough. Have some cough drops.
You can keep them.
Thanks!
Thank you!
Not at all.
Taniguchi-san! Could you come here?
Sure!
If you'll excuse me.
It's this...
Lemme see.
Tetsuya Maejima (28)
Tohto Bank Clerk
Branch Manager. I'm going to make my rounds now.
Right. Go get 'em!
Everyone, stand up with your hands up!
Okay! Do anything funny and you're dead!
Move!
You deaf or something?!
This goin' to one of your clients?!
The world's so unfair!
You, there!
Yeah, you! Fill this up!
The rest, out from behind the counter!
Alright! Everyone stay where you are!
Now fill the bag!
Ran! What do we do?!
We'll be fine if we just stand here.
Oh no!
What the—
S-S-Shut up!
Be quiet! Quiet, I say!
Shut up!
Conan-kun!
Maejima-san's bullet wound was serious, but not life-threatening.
So, when Maejima-san went to hit the robber with the wooden sword,
this cell phone in his pocket went off?
That's right. Then the robber turned around, saw him, and fired!
And immediately after, Taniguchi-san, you jumped on the robber?
I saw Maejima get shot and then the women started screaming,
so I panicked.
The robber did too, so he pointed the gun at the women...
The moment things looked bad, I just—
My only focus was on pointing the gun elsewhere...
Then that happened...
Inspector Megure.
We're done examining,
so you can come back now.
Please wait here a moment.
The gun was a modified model gun.
And this corner wasn't recorded by the security camera.
The robber had a cell phone, too...
Inspector.
Tohru Saeki. Born in 1970.
Understood.
Does anyone here recognize the robber?
Whoops.
Oh, it wasn't me.
It's Maejima-san's cell phone.
Huh?
Hello, this is Police Inspector Megure.
May I ask who's calling?
Koike-san?
Maejima-san's client.
Actually, Maejima-san was injured during an incident.
Pardon my asking, but did you call this phone at around 3:05?
You didn't?
I see.
Hey! Let me listen, too!
You recorded during the robbery, right?
Not so loud! I'm gonna sell this to the media later for a lot!
In that case...
Fine.
Don't move! Stay right where you are!
I thought so!
That's enough!
We have some idea about the situation now.
Detective!
Will Taniguchi be blamed for what he did?
Certainly not!
Had he not jumped at the robber, you folks might've been shot!
He acted courageously and risked his own life!
If anything, he should be rewarded!
Is that so?! That's great news, Taniguchi!
We owe you a reward, as well!
No...
Maejima-san was unlucky, though.
We still don't know who called him.
If his phone hadn't rung just then, he might never have been shot...
No! Everyone's got it all wrong!
Here it is!
This isn't a toy, little boy. It's important.
Taniguchi-san. I'll be filing the report,
so could you accompany me to the station?
All right.
I need to use the restroom first.
Sure thing.
What is it, little boy?
Need the restroom?
Yeah...
Oh...
Why did Taniguchi-san get nervous and hide his phone?
Was he trying to call somewhere? Or—
Could there be another side to this case?!
To think you kids were involved, too...
It's a miracle you weren't hurt!
A card-based security lock.
Taniguchi-san's jacket!
Come to think of it...
what was the robber looking for?
Cigarettes? A lighter? I doubt it...
Then what, exactly?
Empty...
Wait! Before that, he—
lt was right around here...
This is...
I've figured it out!
So, this case does have a more sinister side!
The old man's not here today,
so I'll have to rely on Sonoko again!
Sorry to keep you waiting.
I'm sorry to burden you after all that's happened...
Say, Ran!
What is it, Sonoko? Sonoko?
Not again...
Sonoko!
Inspector, I've figured it out.
Figured what out, Sonoko-kun?
There's a sinister side to this thingy, err, dealy!
"Thingy, err, dealy"?
I mean incident!
Boy, it's hard to talk like a girl!
To begin with, what rang when Maejima-san went to use the sword
was not his phone, but the robber's!
Impossible! Everyone's confirmed that it was his phone that rang!
But when his cell phone rang earlier,
both you and Taniguchi-san mistakenly grabbed your own phones!
Similarly, everyone thought it was Maejima-san's phone that rang!
That is possible, but how are you sure it was the robber's phone instead?
The ringtone.
The ringtone?
Compare the ringtones of the two phones and you'll see.
Also, that college guy has the ringtone from the robbery on tape!
Is this true? Do you have this?!
No!
Quit yer lyin'!
I did it again!
I mean, don't bother lying! I know you do!
Well?! Help us out if you have it!
Okay, okay... but give it back later!
Inspector! I got a tape player!
Maejima
Robber
Alright, let's begin.
Please.
First, Maejima-san's cell phone.
Next, the robber's cell phone.
It's the same sound, but a different pattern...
And here's the one during the incident...
Shut up! Shut up!
A little before that!
Right!
Go back again!
Yes, sir!
That's definitely the ringtone from the robber's cell phone.
Sonoko-kun. Just as you said,
it seems it was the robber's phone that rang.
Did someone just happen to call his phone then, or—
It was likely his accomplice who called.
Accomplice?!
That accomplice saw Maejima-san about to hit him with the sword,
and quickly called the robber's phone using his own...
to warn him of the danger!
What?! Then that means his accomplice is still in here!
Yes. And that would be you, Taniguchi-san!
You can't be serious. Don't joke like that.
Taniguchi-san.
First, you used your cell phone to signal the robber outside
to bust inside at just the right time.
Because the staff door opens from the inside when someone leaves,
but you need a card to get in from the outside!
Branch Manager. I'm going to make my rounds now.
Right, that's it.
Hold on a sec while I get the list.
Alright.
Everyone stand up with your hands up!
Then, as planned, you filled the bag with cash as he ordered,
and were the only one left behind the counter.
Looking back, he barely seemed concerned about you!
Your original plan had him leaving without hurting anyone
and making off with the money-filled bag!
Then, you'd meet up with him later to split the money!
But something unexpected happened!
Maejima-san regained consciousness!
You wanted to warn him somehow.
You probably wanted to shout, "Behind you!"
but that would've exposed you.
Thinking quickly...
you pressed your redial button.
The robber's phone rang, but Maejima-san thought it was his own
and was shot when he froze!
The biggest mistake, in your eyes,
was when he shot him.
The robber lost his cool and looked ready to shoot other people.
Realizing that the plan was out of control, you jumped at him...
and shut him up by pretending to shoot him during the struggle!
This is nonsense! She's just making this up!
Could I see your cell phone?
If she's right, the redial button should call the robber's phone.
Certainly.
I thought so!
You erased your redial memory when you went to the restroom!
Inspector. There's definitive proof that they were accomplices.
Are you serious, Sonoko-kun?!
Conan-kun.
Right!
Inspector. Put your hands out.
Like this?
Here you go!
What is this?
Cough drops! I got them from Taniguchi-san before the robbery!
Sonoko-neechan! I handed them over!
Inspector. In your right hand is paper the robber threw away.
Right afterwards, he fumbled around in Taniguchi-san's jacket pockets!
He was looking for cough drops.
He and Taniguchi-san probably met somewhere this afternoon
for a final meeting.
Both had colds and sore throats,
so one of them split a pack of cough drops and gave half to the other.
Afterwards, the robber's throat hurt again after shouting
so, he went to get a cough drop from his pocket, but they were all gone
and only the wrapper remained.
Then, he remembered Taniguchi-san had some in his jacket pocket
and went to get them...
unaware he had given them away to Conan-kun.
As proof, the tears on the wrappers should fit perfectly!
You're right!
Also, fingerprints from Taniguchi-san or the robber should be on both!
Have them checked at once.
Yes, sir!
Taniguchi-san. Do you have anything to say?
Saeki gave me the cough drops.
I met him through a loan shark.
We came up with this robbery to repay the loan and for play money.
Had I known this would happen,
I wouldn't have given you the cough drops.
You're incredible, Sonoko! You solved another case!
I don't remember much,
but I felt this sharp pinprick—
Pinprick?
Yikes!
But Shin'ichi-kun has nothing on me!
It's all about the cute and charming high school detective Sonoko Suzuki!
Damn it! I knew I shouldn't have used her!
Such regrets...
I got it! It's all mine—
You OK, Genta?
What the...
He was strangled with string or something!
He was murdered?!
This was no mugging!
She's the killer!
But I have no proof!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: House Cleaning
Next time the search for evidence is tough!
It was her!
I know that.