A racing second hand, a glittering galaxy!
Conan's logic is good medicine
for hearts dried by modern society!
Today's case has a crazy secret
behind a kidnapping!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Genta, Mitsuhiko, Ayumi, and I
were playing Kick-the-Can,
but soon found ourselves having lunch at a restaurant
with Two-Mix vocalist, Minami Takayama-san.
She had snuck out to look for her missing partner, Shiina Nagano-san.
But at the restaurant, she was kidnapped before our very eyes!
The kidnappers demanded
the bag she left at the restaurant.
What's more, they demanded that we take it.
It appeared they were after a Two-Mix demo tape.
After taking the bag as ordered, the kidnappers contacted us
and said to lose the officers and have Ayumi deliver the tape alone.
I can't put Ayumi in danger!
So, I devised a plan...
Hello?
Good work, little girl.
There aren't any cops around, I hope?
No, there doesn't seem to be anyone...
Perfect.
Ready to come, like I told ya?
Yeah...
I'll try my hardest!
What?! Conan-kun and Ayumi-kun switched places?!
My word...
The kidnappers are after the demo tape!
They said to have Ayumi deliver it
and to lose the police...
...so Conan-kun switched with me!
But, why didn't you tell us you switched?
They'd be most off guard if we let them think their plan worked!
So, Conan-kun said we couldn't let anyone know until then!
But, now we can't locate the kidnappers...
Conan-kun is in danger.
Oh, he said that these Tracking Glasses should—
At this rate, Conan's gonna get all the credit!
We can still find their hideout and then tell the police!
And then, after we've saved Two-Mix...
"Detective Boys Save the Day!"
Thank you, boys!
It's all thanks to you!
OK! Let's go catch those kidnappers!
What are you shouting about?
No, we were saying, "Oh! We're so hungry!"
Right?
Y-Yeah... We were saying, "Oh! We're so hungry!"
Well, we're off to buy some food!
Come back quickly, now.
We will!
"We're so hungry! We're so hungry!
We're so hungry!"
Hello?
As agreed, it looks like you came alone.
Now, bring the tape up to the second floor of the nearby warehouse.
Your beloved Two-Mix is waiting!
Won't be needing you anymore!
Say your prayers while you still have time.
I brought it, Mister!
Oh, thanks, little girl!
Who're you—
Huh? Where's the guy from the coffee shop?
Is he out somewhere?
That the place?
No question about it!
Do you think Conan-kun is OK?
Now what?
We need to contact the police for now.
There's a phone booth over there!
OK! Let's go!
Yeah!
1-1-9...
Wait! That's the fire department!
The police is 110!
Oh yeah.
And don't you need to press this button?
This is 110.
Um, Inspector Megure, please!
Hello? Where'd you go, little boy? Hello?
Hello?!
Ow!
How did you find us?!
I was told to bring this tape here.
Yeah, they really questioned us
about where the tape was...
But why would they want it?
Let's save the details for after we've escaped.
And the police are on their way.
The police?!
They're on their way here right now,
using my Tracking Glasses.
It homes in on this badge's transmitter.
Who are you?
Conan Edogawa.
A detective.
Detective?!
Let's hurry before the other kidnapper comes back...
Are those your "Tracking Glasses"?
Conan-kun...
You guys!
What're you doing here?!
I caught 'em snooping around here.
You idiots! Why didn't you give the glasses to the police?!
We just wanted...
You'll have plenty of time to fight...
in the afterlife!
So long.
I'm nice enough to turn you into ashes. Be grateful.
Wait! At least tell us why you kidnapped us!
Ask Buddha in the afterlife.
"The countdown bell sounds..."
"and says to change hearts and run."
"It rings once, twice..."
"Like the sound of off-season fireworks..."
"Like the sound of someone, somewhere, confessing their love..."
You damn kid...
That's right. The lyrics on the Two-Mix demo tape.
And the reason you kidnapped Two-Mix!
Isn't that right, Satoshi Miyahara-san?
The night of New Year's Eve,
you killed a man near Shoenji Temple
and were investigated by Inspector Megure.
New Year's Eve?!
Shoenji?
That's where we came up with that song!
There was a murder near that temple
when the bell rang at 11:50...
Since the man died holding the gun,
had gunpowder on his hands,
and there was an empty shell in the barrel,
the police believed your claim
that it went off during your struggle
with the gun-toting maniac.
But, that wasn't actually the case.
You had brought the gun
to kill him from the very start!
After shooting him through the heart with the first shot,
you loaded another bullet into the barrel and fired at the ground...
with his hand on the gun, to leave behind traces of gunpowder!
There were no witnesses around, so while you called the police,
the man sleeping outside was to run off
with the extra bullet and shell
to put you in the clear.
But, there were people who heard those sounds...
You don't mean—
Yeah. You two from Two-Mix.
The "countdown bell" was the New Year's bell.
The two fireworks were the two gunshots.
And the line, "1996 just flew right by,"
indicated the year it happened.
Add in Shoenji Temple,
which you mentioned on the radio,
and the time and place
of the gunshots becomes clear.
I assume you heard the radio show the demo tape was played on.
So you kidnapped Two-Mix...
to get rid of the tape and them before the police found out!
Pretty clever.
That's right. I'm Satoshi Miyahara.
The guy I killed was an old bank-robbing partner of ours.
He suddenly threatened
to tell the cops, so I offed him.
Couldn't you have just run off after that?
I had no choice.
A temple priest had seen my face while I was on my way there.
Luckily, he was hard of hearing.
Said he had to stay at the temple to ring the bell, so I let him live.
Never expected someone to hear the shots and make a song about it...
A cell phone, huh? Give it here!
This is that long-haired guy's phone
I had my partner hold onto...
Damn, can't be careless around you...
But, even if you did call the police,
you'd die before they get here...
Well then, please enjoy your stay.
Hello?
Oh, Inspector Megure. I let them and those kids go unharmed.
Bye.
That's odd. He didn't even mention Conan-kun switching places...
Inspector. I just got word on the radio
that some kids had called 110 and asked for you.
What?! When?!
Um, some 15 minutes ago.
Why didn't they tell us sooner?!
They didn't state their emergency,
so the operator thought it was a prank.
Do we know the location?!
No, it was too short to trace...
This is bad! If the kidnappers were the ones who hung up...
It's no use! It's not budging!
OK! Time for my Power Kick Shoes...
Move!
Ow! It's no use!
Are you kids OK?!
This is bad! At this rate, we won't survive!
Hey! Don't breathe the smoke! Get lower to the—
Little boy!
Are you OK?!
Pull yourself together!
Little boy!
Talk about a nuisance...
Those annoying cops...
Hey! Quit—
Yay! We're long gone!
What?!
We're calling from a police box!
See for yourself if you don't believe me!
That's impossible!
They're gone!
How did...
How did they get out?
We did it!
See! Told you this Earring Cell Phone was useful!
It sure was!
Hurry! We can still get to the concert in time!
OK!
Everyone duck!
Shiina-kun!
Don't mock me, kids!
I'm gonna kill each one of you!
- Bastard!
That was awesome, Minami-chan!
Talk about strong!
That was close...
10 minutes later, a fire truck arrived with police cars,
and the two-man gang was put under arrest.
Naturally, the Detective Boys
got a harsh scolding,
but Minami Takayama-san
stuck up for us, so we were acquitted
and then we rushed to the Budokan
in Inspector Megure's car.
What are you guys doing?!
It's already 30 minutes past!
Not good. The crowd's getting antsy.
We need to go change, so wait backstage.
Backstage?
We wanna introduce you to everyone later!
Everyone?
Hey! Is Minami-chan still not here?
Geez! What's she doing?!
Um... Is this backstage?
Hey, now! You're not allowed back here!
Get back to your seats!
Takayama-san told us to come here...
Eh?! Minami-chan's here?!
OK! Put the opening song on standby!
Hey! Someone go to the dressing rooms
and ask how much longer!
Right!
Say, what does this do?
Hey! Don't touch that!
Sorry!
Whoops!
My turn!
Hey!
Oh no! The song's started!
What do we do?! They're not here yet!
Stop the song!
Are you crazy?! They'd get even madder if we did that!
So what do we do?!
I'm figuring that out!
Say, do you have this song's lyrics?
Eh? Yeah, they're in that CD case...
But, what do you want them for...
Hey, you're not gonna...
BREAK MY LIES
"kakedasu senaka o oikakete mou ichido..."
Chase after me again as I rush off
SAVE MY HEART!
"hontou wa matteru ...dakishimete..."
I'm actually waiting... Embrace me...
ima RETURN TO LOVE...
Now return to love
I could swear I've heard that singing voice before...
Don't joke like that!
Who the hell's singing?!
Talk about off-key...
But it is Takayama-san's voice...
Bad idea?
"tatta hito-koto" ga sunao ni iezu ni kizutsuketa yo
It hurt that I couldn't say that one little thing
nakitai-kurai ni nukumori kono te ni motomenagara...
as I sought this warm hand almost in tears
keiken fuereba yume mo
And with every new experience
Look!
mujaki ni mirenaku naru-kara...
I find it harder to dream in innocence
Conan-kun!
sore de mo dokoka de kitto shinjitakute mitsumeteta...
Even so, I searched because I still believed deep down
BREAK MY LIES
"hitomi ni yureteru shinjitsu ni kidzuite..."
Realize the quivering truth in my eyes
SAVE MY HEART!
"furueru kuchibiru kuchidzukete..."
Kiss these trembling lips
ima RETURN TO LOVE...
Now return to love
soba ni iru-toki kanjite ita no wa yowasa ja naku
What I felt when I was with you wasn't weakness
jibun ni tarinai nanika o oginau-you na yasuragi
It was a kind of serenity that made up for something I lacked
daiji na mono-hodo itsuka
The more important the person,
ushinau itami ga kowakute
the more afraid I am to lose them
hitogomi no naka de hitori... kaeru basho o sagashiteta...
All alone in the crowd, I searched for a place to return to
BREAK MY LIES
"kotoba ni dekinai setsunasa o ubatte..."
Snatch away the pain I can't put into words
And so the Two-Mix concert that we barged into ended without a hitch.
SAVE MY HEART!
"doko ni mo ikenai ...sono mune ni..."
I've nowhere to go... Trapped in your heart...
ima RETURN TO LOVE...
Now return to love
See ya later!
Good work today!
Good work!
So, what did you think of singing on stage?
It was the greatest!
I was moved!
I could do it again!
I bet! Just once, and you're hooked!
So, what did the little detective think?
How was the concert?
Oh. It was OK, I guess.
You're so cheeky!
Come on in.
So, this is your dressing room?
Oh, Inspector! Can we help you?
I'm sorry to ask when you're so exhausted,
but I was hoping you could come to the station to give a statement...
Oh, okay. Just a minute.
Please, take your time...
That was a wonderful concert!
Thank you.
Here you go!
This is for saving us today! Practice at home, OK?
OK!
And some for you, too!
Why, thank you!
Could I get autographs and pictures, too?
Sure!
Ready?! What's 1 plus 1?
Two!
"Karaoke Box"
That's all he's been singing...
But he hasn't gotten any better...
Return to love
The old man was staying at the hospital,
but just when he woke up,
he witnessed a murder in the opposite ward
and rushed to the scene!
But...
Old man! Dr. Eto!
Dr. Eto's murderer was you, Mouri-kun!
What?!
No! The old man fell into a trap!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Coffee
Next time the stage is a scary hospital!
I hate getting shots!