A racing second hand, a shimmering nebula!
Conan's logic is good medicine
for hearts dried by modern society!
Today's case is in a general hospital!
Old Mouri's a killer?!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
"East Beika General Hospital"
I'm so bored.
Oh, Dad...
This is the old man's third week in the hospital.
He broke his leg while trying to catch a criminal...
but naturally, I took him down instead.
But, you've been so busy lately that this is a good chance to relax.
It's meal time!
Food, at last!
The famous detective sure has an appetite!
How I'd love some beer and sashimi...
That's not how a famous detective acts, Dad! How pathetic!
Kazumi Nakayama (26)
Nurse
But everyone is gossiping about wanting to see the famous Mouri-san!
Angels in white, gossiping about me?!
Yes!
I'd love to hear some stories, myself!
I could learn a lot!
Mitsuo Shirai (40)
Physician
You're too kind, Dr. Shirai... How embarrassing!
Learn a lot of what?!
Be careful you're not made into a guinea pig, Detective!
How rude!
Katsutoshi Eto (40)
Surgeon
Ooooh! What a scary look!
Detective, if I'm ever killed, Dr. Shirai will have done it!
Who was that?
That was Eto-kun, a fellow surgeon. We attended college together.
He has a sharp tongue,
but he's a talented surgeon.
He may be talented, but he's a jerk.
It's started raining. Maybe we should get going, Conan-kun?
Okay.
Mouri-san, you can't have alcohol, but you can have some coffee.
Could I trouble you for a story?
Sure!
This latest case was a good one I solved using my great skills!
It was ripe with mystery, as the killer had left not a thing behind!
Yikes! He's got a real sweet tooth!
Huh? Where's Dr. Shirai?
It's already this late?
A murder!
Call the police!
Someone's being murdered! Call 110! Hurry!
Right away!
Wait, Mouri-san!
This room is empty!
Huh? I could swear it was in here...
The body disappeared?!
That's the only possibility, but I did see it...
You sure there ever was one?!
Are you doubting me?!
But it's a fact that there was nothing—
Now, now. It's late. You'll disturb the patients.
Let's call it a night—
Doctor! I saw it with my own two eyes—
You've been quite exhausted lately.
Well, I guess I did fall asleep while telling you my story...
So, the famous detective was tired.
Talk about a panic monger...
Well, we'll be leaving, too.
Thank you for your time!
However, the old man witnessed the same thing many more times!
There's no doubt about it this time!
110! Call 110!
Again?
That's impossible...
Excuse me!
What's with you, Dad?! This is the fourth time!
I'm not lying! I really did see it!
Dad...
I can only guess that the stress of dealing with all those crimes
has gotten to him and caused him to hallucinate...
No! Those were no hallucinations!
Dad! Calm down! Pull yourself together!
What's happened to you?!
Guess I'll check it out just to be safe...
These blotches were recently made...
It did rain twice during the time he witnessed the murders...
In other words, this window was open then...
His room is diagonal from here...
No curtains... Is that an unused room?
That's it! Now I see!
If the lights are on in that room at night,
the dark building behind it will cause the window to act like a mirror.
And, depending on the angle of the open window,
it'll project into a certain room...
the old man's!
The real room isn't visible from his window.
What's in that room...
...is reflected onto this window...
...and looks to him as if it's happening in here!
This is a mirror trick involving windows!
"Storeroom"
This is it!
A first-aid dummy...
They used this to act it out...
Is this just a prank, or is there another reason behind it?
I'm gonna stay with him tonight to look after him!
How nice of you!
Well, Mouri-san, take these and get some sleep.
It's really coming down.
Well, good night!
Old man!
Conan! Did you see that, too?!
Yeah! That was no hallucination!
I didn't think so!
Ok!
Mouri Kogoro's back!
"Storeroom"
There's nobody here, and the dummy hasn't been used...
What does that mean?
Oh, no! This is bad!
Old man!
Dr. Eto!
There are two stab wounds on the body,
and there were no vital reactions on the second one.
So, the first killed him...
Mouri-kun!
What happened here?!
I'm not entirely sure, myself...
Someone suddenly hit me and...
Dad!
What on earth's going on?!
I'm not really sure...
Conan-kun! What happened?!
I don't know, either—
Mouri-san killed Eto-kun?!
Doesn't surprise me...
Pardon me, but who are you?
Mouri-san's doctor, Shirai. I'm on night duty tonight...
You said that this doesn't surprise you...
Oh, Mouri-san has been under a lot of stress lately, you see...
he even had recurring hallucinations,
so I was worried he might do something like this...
Oh...
But I saw the murder in the opposite room, too!
I know how you feel, Conan-kun,
but your testimony would be deemed as a cover for Mouri-kun
and most likely won't hold up in court.
You can't be serious...
come to think of it, my memory does go blank sometimes...
I could have easily committed a murder during then!
Old man...
What?!
Stop being stupid! Pull yourself together, Dad!
Now, now, Ran-kun...
Anyway, from the locations of the room, stairs, elevators,
and nurse stations, it's unlikely the killer snuck in from outside.
Incidentally, I hear you and the victim had heated disagreements?
No, nothing that big!
Nevertheless, could I have your alibi?
Yes. It happened at 11:30, right?
I was in my own room on the 2nd floor of the north ward.
Can you prove this?
Okita-kun. You delivered my charts at about that time, right?
Yes. It was around then.
And you're certain he was in the room at the time?
Yes. He was on the phone, though...
...for quite some time.
Dr. Shirai. I brought your charts. And some coffee.
Oh, thanks!
I'm on the phone, so could you just leave 'em on the desk?
Okay!
It was just then that all this happened...
So, although you didn't see him, you're sure you spoke with him
and not a recording?
Yes.
So my alibi checks out, Inspector.
But what kind of call was it?
Did you call them, or did they call you?
What's that matter?
Well?
An anonymous person had called to complain about my diagnosis.
You get them once in a while.
In other words, we can't ID the caller.
Which means Mouri-kun is the most suspect...
What?!
Is that really so?
Dr. Shirai's alibi does seem airtight. But...
Dr. Shirai clearly opened the old man's curtains
and set the alarm clock
so he would witness those murder scenes...
But that alibi of his...
"Shirai"
A speakerphone...
He didn't use any sugar...
That's it! Now I understand his alibi trick!
No doubt about it! The killer was Dr. Shirai!
But I have no proof...
Wait. Could this coffee cup...
Hey, Mister Examiner!
Oh, the boy staying with Mouri-san!
Things don't look so good this time...
Actually, Inspector Megure said he wants you to check something.
"Shirai"
So?!
Yeah, it was just like you said!
I thought so!
I found proof on the coffee cup that Dr. Shirai was the killer!
Here it comes, Inspector!
What?!
What's going on, Megure-san?!
Don't worry! This is the unique pose "Sleeping Kogoro" takes
when using his logic!
This is a cleverly devised two-step crime, everyone.
The first step was to mentally drive me into a corner enough
to convince me and everyone else that I committed a murder
out of stress.
The second step was to commit that murder
and then execute his alibi trick to avoid being suspected himself.
To do so, he first used the first-aid dummy in the fourth floor storeroom.
The killer opened the murder room window at a certain angle
and made his fake murders in the storeroom reflect off of it
so that I would see it from the south ward.
And then, at 11:30,
he called the victim into the room and murdered him.
Just like his previous acts, but this time for real.
That's what Conan and I witnessed.
But how could he get you to witness it so conveniently?
To do that, the killer visited my room, opened the curtains,
and had me take an adjusted amount of sleeping medicine.
In addition, he set the alarm clock to 11:30, the time of the murder.
He then knocked me out with a blunt object after I rushed into the room
and put the knife in my hand to get my fingerprints on it.
Who, exactly?!
Don't tell me you did it...
Isn't that what you want to say, Mouri-san?
Yes. Dr. Eto's murderer was you, Dr. Shirai!
But I have an alibi, Mouri-san.
He's right, Mouri-kun!
He had her deliver the charts then, and he even talked with her!
It wasn't a recording, either!
It was the cell phone.
Cell phone?
First, the doctor called his cell phone from his room just after 11:00,
turned on the speaker, and went to the murder room in the north ward.
He then murdered Dr. Eto, who he had called there ahead of time,
used the body to act out a murder at 11:30,
and then used his cell phone to converse with the nurse over the phone.
Then, when I arrived on the scene, he hit me with a blunt object,
knocked me out, and put the knife in my hands to put my prints on it.
Finally, he returned to his room during the commotion
and turned the phone off.
He must have felt quite relieved that it was all over.
But he made one big oversight.
The coffee the nurse kindly brought him.
I assume you all know Dr. Shirai has a real sweet tooth?
However, the coffee's sugar hadn't been used at all.
This means Dr. Shirai hadn't drunk the coffee.
Ridiculous. Even I take it without sugar sometimes.
I would hardly call that proof.
So, then you did drink it?
Yeah, but if you're going to say how there was no saliva on it,
that might be because I gave it a quick rinse.
There's something else missing.
Oh? What would that be?
Your fingerprints. There aren't any on the coffee cup.
That's because I rinsed it...
But the fingerprints of the nurse who brought it are on the handle.
Are you saying you washed off your fingerprints from on top of hers?
That'd be impossible.
In short, when you rinsed the coffee cup, you had gloves on.
The surgical gloves you had used during the murder...
Why was he wearing gloves before then?
When he returned to his room after the murder,
he probably still had the weapon he hit me with.
He couldn't get his prints on it before he disposed of it.
At any rate, once back in his room, he felt he had to down the coffee,
or else his alibi of being in the room would seem suspect,
so he hurriedly poured it out, with gloves still on, and rinsed the cup.
But only the inside.
For that reason, only the nurse's fingerprints remained on the cup.
You said you drank the coffee.
Are there any other reasons your fingerprints weren't on the handle?
How ironic.
Leaving evidence because of the gloves I wore to leave no evidence...
So you admit to it?
It's all as Mouri-san said.
Why? What was your motive?!
Our chief surgeon is being forced to retire next month.
Eto and I were the candidates for his position...
But Eto blackmailed me into declining!
I had no choice but to accept his demand...
He knew I had bought my way into medical school.
After all, the professor I paid off was his father!
Why did I ever pay out all that money to get into school?
In other words, crime and dishonesty doesn't pay, Doctor.
I hate this! I'm through with this Sleeping Kogoro stuff!
How come? You solved that case easily enough!
I did?
That's right!
I guess old Sleeping Kogoro is still going strong after all!
He never learns...
Teacher! Sonoko!
After she was knocked out with chloroform,
she was strangled with a rope!
There are still tracks here!
The front door...
That means the killer is still inside this lodge!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Heater
Next time, it's a two-parter's—
- Part 1!