A racing second hand, a broken communication!
Conan's logic works great
on hearts tired by modern society!
It's already ski season! Be wary of chilly crimes!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
The Ski Lodge Murder Case
(Part 1)
Winter! And snow-covered mountains mean skiing!
And my long-awaited boy-hunt!
Though, there's only 5 or 6 guys on the slopes
and they're all with their girlfriends...
Yeah, the place really is empty...
The only untaken guy here is Conan-kun...
Yeah, yeah, yeah...
That's okay, let's just have fun skiing!
It's okay for you since you have Shin'ichi-kun!
I've tried my hardest these past 17 years,
but nothing good has ever happened to me...
Sonoko...
So, you can pay for lunch!
Eh?!
Hey, kittens!
Would you like to ski with us?
But of course!
Kittens?!
We're ski instructors. Right?
Yep!
Really?!
Oh? Is that Mouri-san and Suzuki-san?
It is you! Good to see you again!
Yonehara-sensei!
Oh? You know these girls?!
Yes! They were students of mine when I taught at Teitan Elementary!
Oh yeah, I remember a teacher like her...
But, you two sure have grown womanly!
And, you're as stunning as ever with that long hair!
Oh, just my hair?
Akiko Yonehara (30)
Haido Elementary Teacher
(Ran and Sonoko's former teacher)
Says the 30 year old woman who could never get married!
Very funny!
But, what about these nice instructor friends of yours?
Instructors?
Instructors, indeed...
Eh? Grade school teachers?!
So, you both work with Yonehara-sensei at Haido Elementary?
That's right! They're my coworkers!
Kohei Shimoda (30)
Haido Elementary Teacher
The teacher for Class 5-1, Shimoda-sensei...
...and boys P.E. instructor, Sakai-sensei.
Ryuichi Sakai (29)
Haido Elementary P.E. Teacher
Nice to meet you!
Minori Nakamura (27)
Haido Elementary Health Teacher
But, grade school teachers trying to pick up high school girls...
You two are still so young at heart!
But nobody uses "kittens" nowadays!
Where could he be? Sugiyama-sensei sure is late...
Sugiyama-sensei?
A music teacher who wound up coming, too.
We agreed to meet here at 2:00, but he's late...
Do you suppose he went on ahead to the lodge we're staying at
so he can scare us?
It's very possible. He loves that sort of thing.
Would you like to come to the lodge, too?
Can we?!
Hey, now! No seducing my students!
Don't worry! We'll drive 'em back in time for their ski bus home!
Hey, are you sure this is the road?!
Oh, a car!
They live here?
Pardon me! Are there any lodges around here?
Yeah, there's one halfway up that mountain,
but don't tell me you're goin' up there?
Yeah...
I wouldn't if I were you.
This area gets pounded by blizzards every evening!
Turn back while you still can.
Should we go back?
But Sugiyama-sensei might be waiting for us...
Ugh! Who booked us out here, anyway?
Huh? I thought you did.
Not me. Wasn't it you?
No...
So, was it Yonehara-sensei?
Annual (Secret) Ski Tour
2 Days 1 Night
Set for December 21
Will Attend   Will Not Attend
Please Circle Selection
Location & Members To Be
Kept Secret Until Just
Before The Event ♥
No.
I just did what that card I found in my desk two weeks ago said to do,
and circled that I would attend.
You usually organize our trips,
so I thought you did this one, too...
No. Plus, there was another note
in my desk yesterday...
Yeah!
A list of the attendees and a map to the meeting place and lodge!
I got one, too! Who could've put them there?
Maybe the person with the key to the place?
Someone here must have gotten it from the lodge's owner.
I have the key. I found it in my desk yesterday...
So, who rented the car?
Me. Sugiyama-sensei called me last night
and told me to get a rental car.
Then, wasn't he the one who planned all this?!
Conan-kun, what're you doing? Let's go inside!
Right...
It's so big!
It was cold out there!
Hey! A fireplace!
Aren't you glad we came, Ran?!
But I don't think we can leave in this blizzard...
Sorry. I'll phone your parents,
so stay here tonight.
Okay!
But, is it really OK to rent such a fancy lodge?
Let's have Sugiyama-sensei pay,
since he planned this tour!
Speak of the devil!
There's our sponsor, Sugiyama-sensei!
Coming, coming!
I got it!
Sorry for taking so long, Sugiyama-sensei...
I see you're all here.
Who's he?
Atsushi Mori (37)
Newspaper Reporter
Just a newshound who these folks really helped out three years ago.
Three years ago?
Why are you here?!
I got a tip-off that something's gonna happen here tonight...
Something's...
gonna happen...
...here?!
I parked in the forest and waited for you
when a blizzard suddenly hit.
I'm coming in for a bit.
Not so fast...
Is that wise? I'll just write,
"Haido Elementary Teacher Throws Reporter Out Into Blizzard."
Let's just be friends.
Huh? Where are Yonehara-sensei and the others?
Dunno. Everyone suddenly stopped talking...
And we were having so much fun.
That guy ruined it all!
Suzuki-san.
Forget about him and
help me make everyone's beds.
Okay!
And you two can help Nakamura-sensei with dinner.
OK!
Say, has Sugiyama-sensei called or anything yet?
No. I got his machine at home, so I think he's on his way...
You do that room.
Right!
Huh? Nakamura-sensei isn't here...
Is anything wrong, Yonehara-sensei?
Sonoko?!
Teacher! Say something, Teacher!
What's that?
"Mi"...
ミ
Sonoko! What's going on?! Open up!
You're in there, right?!
What's wrong?! Sonoko!
Please! Open your eyes!
You're asleep?
Ow...
Yonehara-sensei!
What's all the commotion here?!
What happened?!
Eh? Someone attacked you?! Honestly?!
Yes.
Someone covered my mouth from behind
while I was making the bed,
and then I felt faint...
Was it this handkerchief? People on TV do it a lot,
knocking someone out with
a handkerchief soaked in chloroform.
Then, what's the rope for?
She was strangled with it after she was knocked out.
See? There are rope marks on her neck.
There's no question about it.
Were you strangled, too?!
I'm not sure.
I put up a fight, but I don't know what happened after I passed out...
A fight?!
Yeah. I even had my head bashed into the wall!
Just look at this!
What?
What happened to your hand?
My hand?
What is this?!
"Mi"...
This is lipstick.
Don't tell me my...
My lipstick is gone! I had it in here!
Look! There's some on Sonoko's hand, too!
This one says, "Na..."
ナ
"Mi" and "na"?
What do they mean?
A massacre.
minagoroshi
A massacre?!
Maybe the culprit is trying to tell you that?
Good thing nobody died, though.
Now, you won't have to bend the truth
like you did three years ago.
Eh?
Enough already! Are you still stuck on that?!
Besides, I bet you attacked them!
Get real.
I was in front of the fireplace when that girl screamed.
Anyways, is it really a good idea
to have a brat chase the culprit alone?
Conan-kun!
Perfect! There are still tracks here!
Wait, Conan-kun!
If I follow these...
The front door?!
Wait! That means the attacker...
...is still inside!
Sonoko...
She must have inhaled too much chloroform.
She'll wake up soon enough.
Ow!
Anyways, was the stuff about the footprints true?
Yes. They went from the window to the front door.
But who says the attacker made them?
You sure are dumb.
Ran-neechan kicked the door down 'cause it was locked.
Conan-kun!
That door only locks from the inside,
so the window was the only way out.
That's true...
So, the attacker might've taken refuge inside the lodge?!
It's probably just Sugiyama-sensei's doing!
I thought so! That jerk did all this to scare us!
Get serious! Myself aside, Suzuki-san has been strangled!
That's too much to be a prank!
Oh, sorry!
Still, what could Sugiyama-sensei be thinking?!
If only he'd show up...
I bet he can't come out now that it's not funny!
And what about you two?!
Where were you when there were two women being attacked?!
Don't blame me. I was takin' a bath.
I was in my room listening to music on my headphones!
Could you watch Suzuki-san?
If she gets attacked again, bust out your karate!
Right!
Nakamura-sensei's shoes are wet...
Say, Nakamura-sensei. Where were you earlier?
You weren't in the kitchen...
Oh, the gas wasn't coming out,
so I went out the back to check the gas tanks.
Anyways, where's dinner?
Just wait a little more. It's cooking right now.
Smells like curry!
I'll finish making the beds until then.
I'll be in the bath!
I guess I'll go check on dinner!
Planning to filch some food, are we?
Thanks for making me some, too.
No problem. There was an extra helping, anyways...
But, I'll never forget what happened three years ago.
Is that so?
Say, what's this "three years ago" stuff?
You needn't worry about it, little boy!
Oh? Those two didn't eat?
She said they'll eat when Sonoko-chan wakes up.
Oh. We sure have inconvenienced her...
Who could that be?
Maybe it's Sugiyama-sensei?!
That jerk...
Alright, Sugiyama! We know you're in here!
Quit sneaking around and get out... Eh?
Yes. We're all right. The heater's working.
That was the lodge's owner.
It was snowing, so he was worried if the heater was working or not.
How odd. There's definitely something going on in this lodge...
Looks like I'll need to investigate!
First is the incident three years ago
everybody's tight-lipped about!
Where are you going, little boy?!
Just the bathroom!
Huh? I'm sure I brought it...
Found it!
Doc's Earring Cell Phone!
Let's see, Doc's number is...
Dr. Agasa's Home
Eh? An incident at Haido Elementary three years ago?
Just look into it!
But how?
There should be case files in my dad's study!
Just hurry! I got a bad feeling about this!
If we don't hurry, someone else might...
Coming!
I knew it was you, Sugiyama-sensei!
The music teacher has arrived!
Don't scare us like that!
What're ya doin'? Come inside already!
Hey! What's wrong?! Sugiyama-sensei! Say something!
Sugiyama-sensei!
It's no use. He's passed away...
But how...
Don't tell me he froze to death?!
No.
This man was murdered.
Eh?!
Strangled.
See this rope mark?
Plus, the body's stiff.
Isn't that called rigor mortis?
Yes...
Though that means he was killed over 9 hours ago...
The fact that his body rang the bell means someone set him there...
But, we were all eating by the fireplace when it rang...
That means the killer isn't one of us!
Who, then?!
Probably the one who attacked Yonehara-sensei and Sonoko-neechan.
What?!
Look at the "ko" on his hand!
コ
He has a letter written in lipstick just like they did!
Yonehara-sensei had "mi" and Sonoko-neechan had "na", which makes:
"Mi-na-ko."
What is it, Shimoda-sensei?!
Don't touch me!
I got nothing to do with it! Nothing!
Shimoda-sensei! It's Yonehara! Open the door!
Shut up! Leave me alone!
Nothing we can do.
Let's wait until he cools down.
For now, let's call the police!
Right!
Someone was murdered?!
Yes, we found Sugiyama-sensei's body leaning by the front door...
What about the killer?!
They could've snuck inside while we were all gathered at the door...
Don't worry. Sakai-sensei is calling the police as we speak...
It's no good!
They said it's too dangerous to send cars in the blizzard,
so we gotta wait until it dies down in the morning!
Oh, no!
So, they want us to sit here until morning?!
When the killer could still be inside...
Why did all this have to happen? It was such a fun ski tour...
If only he were here now...
Eh?
I mean Shin'ichi! Don't you remember?
"School Lunch Money"
He's the one who found everyone's lunch money
when I lost it in 4th grade!
Oh, that cheeky runt from the class next door who acted like a detective?
Excuse me for being cheeky...
He's a high school detective now!
Come to think of it, I did see him in the papers. I think his name was...
Shin'ichi Kudo.
A brilliant 16 year old detective who handled unsolvable cases...
He was pretty good for a kid, so I was gonna do a feature on him,
but there's been no word on him lately.
Rumor has it he croaked after poking his nose into some case.
How rude! Shin'ichi is ali...
What do you want, anyway?!
I just came to warn you
to not take your eyes off that guy holed up in his room upstairs...
If my reporter's instinct is right,
he'll be next to go.
But, the more casualties, the better the article and the better for me.
Yeah, right. The upstairs windows don't open,
and he won't get attacked if he's holed up.
But, he is a bit agitated.
It's dangerous to leave him alone!
Let's give him some coffee to calm down.
Nakamura-sensei and I will make some,
so you go be with him.
Right.
Be extra careful! The killer could be hiding inside!
I'm dead! I'm dead!
Someone's gonna kill me!
Here you are, Mouri-san! Coffee and cocoa!
Thank you...
Oh? Where's that boy?
Huh? Wasn't he with you?
An outside job... Or was it?
When the doorbell rang, everyone was together but Ran and Sonoko,
so it was definitely someone else
who placed the body here...
Huh? Only that part of the railing is missing snow...
Did someone get on it?
What's with that groove?
There's one on the other side!
Could this have been...
Found you!
You know, you shouldn't wander around!
Go back to your room and get in bed!
Shut up! Leave me alone!
What's going on?
Shimoda-sensei won't let me in.
Then let's leave him alone, lock our rooms,
and get some rest until morning.
It's the Doc!
Hey, Doc. Figure anything out?
Yes, I finally found the file.
Three years ago, a girl hanged herself in the volleyball room
at Haido Elementary.
A suicide?
Seems the cause was "exam neurosis."
As a result, the blame was focused on her teacher.
What was the teacher's name?!
It's not listed here, but the girl's name is...
Haido Elementary, Class 6-2, Minako Mochizuki.
Minako?!
Does it mention anything else?!
What're you doing there, Conan-kun?
What is that?
Hello?
Huh? That's the Doc. Is this a phone?
Hey, Shin'ichi!
Shin'ichi?
Is Shin'ichi there, Doc?!
Eh?! Ran-kun!
Upstairs... Oh, crap!
NEXT EPISODE
What is it?!
What happened?!
It's Shimoda-sensei!
Wait!
Not here! Not here! Not here!
If it's not hidden anywhere,
that means the killer still has the rope!
One of them...
The killer... is you!
Next Conan:
The Ski Lodge Murder Case
(Part 2)
Next Conan's Hint: Hair
Hair
Look forward to the next episode!
Next time, it's the first Conan of the new year!
Christmas, New Ye—
Figure out the killer yet?
Yikes, uh-oh.