A racing second hand, a broken satellite!
Conan's logic is good medicine
for hearts tired by modern society!
Today's a tearful conclusion!
Depend on him for the case and feelings!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Sonoko, Ran, and I went out
skiing on our day off.
There, we met their old grade school teacher, Yonehara-sensei,
and took up her invitation to stay at a lodge.
That night, someone attacked Sonoko and Yonehara-sensei
and the overdue Sugiyama-sensei was found strangled to death!
On each of their hands was a "mi", "na", and "ko"...
Upon seeing this, Shimoda-sensei holed himself up in his room!
Thanks to Dr. Agasa,
I learned there was a suicide at Haido Elementary three years ago
and that the name of the deceased student was Minako Mochizuki.
Just then...
Upstairs?! Oh, crap!
Conan-kun!
Stay right where you are!
Wait...
What is it?!
What happened?!
It's Shimoda-sensei!
Rope marks on his neck!
The murder weapon isn't here!
The upstairs windows don't open,
and there aren't any exits!
Which means it's in someone's room...
Wait!
Not here! Not here! Not here!
It's not anywhere!
Which means the rope is still...
...in the killer's possession!
One of them has it!
You're sure there's no murder weapon, kid?
Yeah.
Here, look at his neck.
See how he has rope marks, just like Sugiyama-sensei did?
But, I don't see any rope in the room.
Minori Nakamura (27)
Haido Elementary Health Teacher
Akiko Yonehara (30)
Haido Elementary Teacher
(Ran & Sonoko's former teacher)
Does that mean the killer
ran off somewhere with the rope?
I don't think so.
I was by the staircase the entire time.
Maybe they're still upstairs?!
But it's strange.
I just checked all the upstairs rooms,
but didn't find any suspicious people or rope.
Ryuichi Sakai (29)
Haido Elementary P.E. Teacher
You checked our bags?!
Sorry...
Interesting. If what the runt says is true...
Atsushi Mori (37)
Newspaper Reporter
...then one of you is the killer and is still carrying the rope.
And you're not a suspect?!
Get serious. This is my first time upstairs.
Besides, if I were the killer, this brat would've seen me go downstairs.
Anyways, whoever has the rope is the killer.
Let's do some body searches...
Well?!
You're so dumb! There was no rope!
Never thought I'd get stripped down in this weather!
But, is it true that Shimoda-sensei was murdered...
Yes. A cell phone kept ringing in his room next door.
But, when I opened his door to check, he was already...
The sound turned out to be his phone's alarm clock...
I heard it from my room across the hall, too!
Huh? I thought you had a downstairs room?
Yes, but I moved upstairs after you broke my door.
Oh!
But, if neither of us is the killer, then...
...that leaves only Sakai-sensei...
Huh? You're done body-searching already?
Yes...
Did he find the rope?
Of course he didn't! Right?!
Yeah. How about you two?
Of course not!
Which means there's only one possibility.
That brat is lying!
So, the killer might still be inside the lodge?!
Oh, no! Sonoko's still asleep downstairs!
For now, let's hurry to her room!
I never left the staircase!
The killer is definitely one of those three!
But why?! Why won't the weapon turn up?!
It's all right. She's just sleeping.
Whew.
Sonoko!
Ran! It's terrible! Yonehara-sensei was murdered in her room!
And then the killer strangled me with rope, like this...
Huh? You're alive?
Yes, somehow. Are you all right?
I guess, I'm still a little dizzy...
Then get some more rest...
You weren't strangled?
No, but I had my forehead bashed into the wall instead.
But I'm glad you're all right! I always looked up to you!
Eh?
Not just her! All the girls
in our class looked up to you!
Don't overrate me.
I'm just a woman who can't do
anything for her students.
I couldn't even help you today when you were attacked...
It's not your fault!
The killer's to blame!
That's how the students covered for you three years ago, too.
You were the teacher for the girl
who killed herself, Minako Mochizuki.
If the killer's goal is to avenge her death,
then it's not surprising you were attacked first.
How dare you?!
You're in the same boat.
You were in charge of the volleyball club she was in.
Ah, yes.
And, she was Nakamura-sensei's favorite in the Health Committee.
You could've stopped her from committing suicide, too...
It looks like this murder mystery will continue yet.
Murder mystery?! Don't tell me someone's been killed?!
We can explain later.
In any case, it's dangerous to be split up!
Let's gather in the living room
and wait for the police!
Damn it! What the heck's going on?!
Think! There's gotta be a key to unlocking this mystery!
Somewhere in this ski lodge...
What's that?
String?
It's a long strand of fishing line!
There's a broken rubber band on the end.
Wait!
Was this...
OK! I've figured out the ringing-doorbell trick!
That just leaves the murder weapon, now!
If I can just find that...
Hair?
That's it! I've figured out the disappearing-weapon trick!
This means that person is the killer!
But how do I tell everyone?!
I can't use Sonoko as a detective; she barely knows what happened!
And I can't use Ran! I can't fool her afterwards like I can Sonoko!
My best bet is to pretend I heard everything from Conan
and then use my real voice to explain it over the phone...
No! If I do that with him there,
it'll get into the paper!
"Shin'ichi Kudo Makes Dashing Entrance"
If my name gets into the paper,
they'll find out I'm alive!
Those men in black who shrunk me with a pill!
Hold it! No wandering off!
The doc's weird phone, huh?
Wait! He mentioned that my Voice-Altering Bow Tie can transmit to it!
Here goes!
Conan-kun! Your phone's ringing!
Hello?
It's me, Ran! Shin'ichi!
Shin'ichi?!
I figured out who killed the two teachers at that lodge!
Eh?! How?!
Conan-kun told me.
Now, I need you to do something.
Do something?
Explain the truth to everyone in my place!
Eh?! Me?!
Yeah. I'll say it over the phone,
so you just repeat it...
No way! You can tell everyone over the phone yourself!
Oh, OK. You don't have to.
I'll tell the police when they get there.
Alright. I'll try.
I just put this on my ear
and say what you say, right?
Let's go back to the others, Conan-kun!
Right!
We're gonna get the person who attacked Sonoko and Yonehara-sensei
and killed the two teachers!
Thanks, Ran...
Eh?! You figured out who did it?!
- Eh?!
Yes, and everything else!
Incident #1, in which Yonehara-sensei and Sonoko were attacked...
Incident #2, in which the strangled Sugiyama-sensei
was set by the door to ring the doorbell...
Incident #3, in which the killer strangled Shimoda-sensei upstairs
and disappeared with the murder weapon...
I've figured out the one behind these three incidents.
And that that person is...
is one of you!
The killer is one of us?!
A high school girl playing detective?
Fine, we'll hear you out.
But, are you prepared for what happens if you're wrong?
You'd naturally be hit with a libel suit.
If I put it in the paper and you're wrong, you'll be expelled!
Expelled?!
I assume you're prepared for that?
Ran...
Don't worry, Ran. I'm with you.
Just leave it to me!
Shin'ichi...
It's all right. If you just trust me and say what I say,
the truth will be revealed!
Well, li'l lady?!
You can write it if you want...
"Daughter of Great Kogoro Mouri Solves Murder Case at Ski Lodge"!
What?!
But, Mouri-san!
When the doorbell rang during Incident #2,
everyone was here in the living room but you three!
How could we have done that?!
Yes, that would seem impossible. But...
...with this fishing line and the rubber band at the end,
that problem is easily overcome!
A fishing line and rubber band?
The trick is simple.
You tie the rubber band to one end of the line,
wrap the line around the two pillars by the door,
then tie the other end to the rubber band while making a small loop.
Then, you attach the rubber band to the stiff Sugiyama-sensei's neck,
lean him toward the door,
and support his feet with snow.
Naturally, you measure the line
so he'll stop just before the doorbell.
Given time, the rubber band will snap due to the cold
and the body will fall and ring the doorbell.
The fishing line would then blow away and vanish from the scene.
So, the killer murdered Sugiyama-sensei hours before so he'd be stiff?
Yes.
The killer most likely called him out here and killed him
before we arrived.
After all, Conan-kun saw icicles when we arrived.
Icicles?
Icicles couldn't have formed unless someone had been using the heater.
That is an interesting trick,
but would it really work that well?
Proof over theory! Go see for yourself!
What is this?!
A ski I set up, using the same trick as I just explained.
But, the mystery behind Incident #3 has yet to be solved...
I'll explain that back in the living room.
Wow! You're so cool, Ran!
Just wait! I'm about to beat your attacker hollow!
Alright, li'l lady. If one of us is the killer, then let's hear about
the mysterious trick used to make the rope disappear from upstairs.
Mysterious?
The killer never intended to make it vanish to scare us all.
What?
It only looked that way because Conan-kun happened to be by the stairs
when the murder occurred.
Had he not been there,
we would've thought the killer had fled downstairs with the weapon,
allowing them to escape suspicion as they were still upstairs.
That's why they set the phone off and had the body found right away.
If it were discovered late,
their clever trick to get rid of the weapon would've been in vain!
So, the killer was one of us three upstairs?!
Then explain this weapon-disappearing trick already...
The rope wasn't in any of the upstairs rooms.
Of course it wasn't.
Because it's still in the killer's possession!
What?!
Impossible! We searched all three of them!
Yes. But not for one thing.
What?!
What thing?!
Who has it?!
Yes. The one who murdered Sugiyama-sensei and Shimoda-sensei
and...
...and attacked Yonehara-sensei and Sonoko was...
No way...
Hey, what's wrong?!
Who did it?!
It can't be...
Hurry up and say it!
The killer...
...is you, Yonehara-sensei!
Yonehara-sensei?!
No way!
She braided her hair like a rope and strangled Shimoda-sensei with it,
as if it was real rope...
But, as long as her hair is,
she couldn't just strangle people with it!
What if it was a wig?
A wig?!
This was wrapped around Shimoda-sensei's neck.
This is hair from a wig.
Its cuticle has been removed for easy processing,
so I can tell just by touching...
And, with her long hair, she's the only one capable of this trick!
That can't be! I saw her lying right there when I was being strangled!
That was probably Sugiyama-sensei's body...
Yes. During Incident #1,
she dressed up his body, which she hid under her bed, just like her!
After luring Sonoko from the next room over,
attacking from behind, and knocking her out,
she hid the body under the bed again
and lied down in the same spot.
After making tracks in the snow
so we'd think the attacker ran out the window, of course.
Thus, she would look like a victim of the attacker,
making it easier to get near Shimoda-sensei, her next target...
Yonehara-sensei most likely called him on his cell phone and said this:
"I know who did it. Let me in and I'll tell you."
You are a great detective's daughter.
You're right, this is a wig.
But, I only wore it to hide my hair after I cut it too short.
It doesn't prove anything.
It's no use.
There's still proof in your wig
that you're the killer...
Eh?
Remember? There were scratch marks on Shimoda-sensei's neck.
So, there should be some on that wig...
Blood that matches his scratches' perfectly!
Your motive was likely the "Minako" written on the victims' hands...
That's right.
I did it for her.
To avenge my student murdered three years ago, Minako Mochizuki!
Murdered?!
This time three years ago, she came to me.
She said two teachers were helping kids cheat on entrance exams.
She told me one was Sugiyama-sensei, but she didn't name the other.
She was shocked it was one she looked up to,
so she was going to ask them herself.
The next day, she hanged herself in the volleyball room.
But I knew Sugiyama-sensei and someone else
had killed her to keep her quiet!
So, I gathered teachers she liked
and planned this ski tour.
You all know the result. I quickly learned it was Shimoda-sensei.
But, you didn't have to kill them!
As fellow teachers, they had to pay for betraying and killing a student
who had looked up to them!
But, who am I to talk?
I troubled Suzuki-san for my own trick...
I'm sorry for being such a horrible teacher...
Hold on.
As agreed, I'm gonna write an article about that great detective work,
High School Detective Girl.
Do whatever.
Umm, Ran...
Shin'ichi...
Shin'ichi!
Two hours later, the blizzard stopped and the police finally arrived.
I managed to stop the criminal,
but there was no stopping
the large teardrops spilling from the eyes of the gentle detective...
Mitsuhiko's radio scanner picked up a kidnapper talking on the phone!
If we don't locate the kid's father and the kidnapper right away,
something bad'll happen!
We'll catch the kidnapper!
That's definitely his father!
And the kidnapper is...
...in those apartments!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Train
Next time, it's the new year! Make sure to watch our movie!
Merry Christmas and Happy New Year!