A racing second hand, a returning satellite!
Conan's logic is good medicine
for hearts tired by modern society!
It's the lively Detective Boys again!
This year's Conan is a little different!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Created by
Gosho Aoyama
"Detective Conan"
Serialized in Shogakukan's
"Weekly Shonen Sunday"
Story Development
Ei'ichi Yamagishi
"Detective Conan Special"
Serialized in Shogakukan's
"Shogaku 5-nensei"
Planning
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Character Design
Masatomo Sudo
Art Director
Yukihiro Shibutani
Art Design
Hiroyuki Mitsumoto
Director of Photography
Takahisa Ogawa
Sound Director
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
Music Producer
Hiroki Horio
(PolyGram)
Music
Katsuo Ono
Opening Theme
"Nazo"
Performed by
Lyrics
Music
Arrangement
Miho Komatsu
Hirohito Furui
(Spoonful/Zain Records)
Editor
Teramitsu Okada
Story Editor
Jun'ichi Iioka
Color Key
Reiko Hirayama
Executive Producer
Satoshi Yokoyama
Planning Support
Toyohiko Okuyama
Mitome Asai
Director
Kenji Kodama
Producers
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Masahito Yoshioka
(Tokyo Movie)
If my opponent goes for my upper body,
I'll smash 'em with a mid-section to upper body kick!
Scary!
Ran's always tense on days she has karate matches...
Conan-kun! You better come cheer me on!
Yeah... I'll come right after school!
You better! I absolutely can't lose to my opponent today!
So, you better come!
If you don't...
Ran's really raring to go!
Oh, it's just construction...
See you, Conan-kun!
I'm in a hurry, so I'm off! 4:00, now!
I gotta hurry to the karate arena
or else I'll meet that roundhouse again!
Hey, Conan!
Just the voice I don't wanna hear...
Yeah?
Crap! I got caught!
Check this out! It's a wideband reversy!
No, Genta-kun! It's called a wideband receiver!
Same difference.
What does it do, again?
It's like a powerful radio!
It can even pick up taxi and cordless phone conversations!
Looks like a toy to me...
Send a fire truck immediately!
Rairaiken? I'd like three ramens and two dumplings...
That's awesome!
But, isn't it wrong to listen in
on people's phone conversations?
That's called "wiretapping"...
We can't bother anybody if we're just listening!
It's pretty creepy, though...
Whoops, I'm in trouble if
I don't go see Ran's match...
I know! Let's listen in on Amie Namuro, that singer!
OK?!
Eh? She lives in this area?!
I dunno...
Then we can't.
This receiver only picks up random signals within a 1 kilometer radius.
Random? That's no fun...
So, we can't choose who to listen to.
Watch. You turn the dial like so...
until you find someone talking, like before.
See! I found one!
I have your daughter.
What?!
What did he say?!
I said, I've kidnapped your daughter.
Call the cops and she's dead!
A threatening phone call!
This for reals?! Where are they talking from?!
This only listens, so I can't tell!
He kidnapped his daughter! Conan-kun...
Don't look at me...
What if it really is a kidnapping?!
Even if it was real kidnapping,
all we know is that they're within a 1 kilometer radius!
It's just 1 kilometer.
He might call again!
Let's wait and see! Okay, Conan-kun?!
OK!
The Detective Boys are back in action!
Oh, geez...
"Beika Martial Arts Arena"
"Gyokushinkai Karate Tournament"
In blue, Ran Mouri.
Ossu!
Not good. At this rate,
I'll get stuck with them, again...
Where are you going, Conan-kun?
Nowhere...
Looks like you haven't called the cops.
Daddy!
Junko!
What are you going to do to her?!
I'll do anything you want!
So, please let her go!
For now, take your cordless phone and step out onto the balcony.
Good. Now stand there.
Your satellite dish is in the way! Take it down!
Eh?!
Just do what I say!
What's he making him do?!
The kidnapper is watching him from somewhere!
He probably told him to go onto the balcony to see him better!
I'd forget about calling the cops if I were you.
I can see you nice and clear.
Do anything funny and I'll kill your daughter on the spot!
He's going to kill her!
What do we do?! Shouldn't we tell the police—
Alright! I'll do whatever you say!
What is it you want?! Money?!
Do you want money?!
That sound...
Don't get worked up. Just wait there for a while.
He hung up!
What now?!
Tell the police?
But would they believe us?
He's right! All we know is that a Junko-chan might've been kidnapped!
Plus, they hung up...
Let's do it ourselves!
Eh?!
We don't have time to go to the police and sit around!
Okay! We'll catch the kidnapper!
But how? We don't have any clues...
Oh, yeah...
I learned something from that last call.
Eh?
What did you learn?
What're you getting your math notebook out for?!
It's not what you think!
It's Dr. Agasa's Electronic Map Notebook!
Oh! That inventor relative of yours?
Alright. Here's our school.
That receiver picks up signals within a 1 kilometer radius.
The victim's home is somewhere in this circle.
And, that faint sound in the background...
It was a train. The victim probably lives along a train line.
There's only one railway that goes through this area!
The Beika Line!
Ah!
Alright! To the Beika Line!
We made it to the train tracks...
Now what?
These are the only tracks within the receiver's range!
In other words, the victim is along this 600-meter length of track!
OK! It's only 600 meters!
But, isn't there any other way, Conan?
I have one more hint, but...
What is it?!
The kidnapper told him to take down his satellite dish, right?
Yeah...
Satellite dishes are pointed to the southwest.
Which means the victim has a balcony facing southwest, but...
OK! Then the victim's house...
Has a balcony on the south or west!
Let's go!
Satellite dish?
No question about it! That's it!
Thought so...
But, there's tons of 'em!
They're on the opposite buildings, too!
Yeah, we don't have enough clues yet!
But...
Hello.
The kidnapper called back!
Great! Now give us some sort of hint!
I'll find a clue this time!
No, I will!
Quiet!
Seems you haven't contacted the cops.
Is Junko all right?!
That all depends on you.
You mentioned you'd do anything I said.
So first, I want you to get naked.
Eh?!
Naked! Take your clothes off!
Naked?!
I got it! He's making him go to a public bath nearby!
What?!
Good! Some high school girls are about to pass below your apartment!
Wave to them!
Or, do you not care what happens to your daughter?!
Shout, "Hello!" and wave to them!
Alright...
Hello! Hello!
Whoa, look!
Totally lame!
Hello! Hello!
How's it feel to be made fun of
by high school girls in sailor uniforms?
Keep doing that for a while.
Sailor uniforms...
I could hear quite a few high school girls over the wideband receiver...
That apartment building is likely on the way to a girls' school.
The only girls' schools in that 600 meter area
are Seijun Girls' Academy and Beika Girls' High School...
I bet high school girls always made fun of the kidnapper.
Yeah, a girls' school teacher!
No teacher would do this!
I've figured out the schools, but I don't know their uniforms...
Seijun uses blazers. Beika uses sailor uniforms.
Eh? Come again?!
I used to dream about wearing a sailor outfit when I get to high school,
but lately I've been considering a blazer and loose socks, too.
Which do you think is better?!
They're both okay...
A blazer would look better!
A sailor outfit!
Beika Girls' High School!
That narrows it down to a 300 meter radius!
That way!
Hey, wait up!
A man waving from his balcony?
I don't see any...
Maybe we should ask some high school girls?
Alright!
You can quit waving now. Now, sing a song!
Sing loud enough for the whole neighborhood to hear! Do it!
I don't hear him...
It must not be this neighborhood.
There's some kind of sound!
That sounds like a temple bell!
That's it! The victim lives behind a temple!
It sounds like a taiko drum!
The kidnapper must be playing along!
No! That sound...
It sounded just like that!
It's a pile driver!
Pile driver?
Yeah! The machines that pound piles in at construction sites!
But, finding construction sites around here would—
I got it!
If we follow that, it'll lead us to a construction site!
This narrows it down to a 150 meter radius!
I don't hear him...
As close as we are now,
it's still a 150 meter radius!
Without anything definitive...
Parents sure are pathetic.
They'll do anything for their kids!
I know how it feels. I used to be a parent myself...
"Used to be"?!
The little girl who fell to her death one year ago...
I'm sure you remember, as it was from your apartment building.
That was my daughter who died!
"Young Girl Falls to Death"
Tomidokoro-san?! Is this Tomidokoro-san?!
That's right. I'm the one whose daughter you murdered.
What?! That was an accident!
Shut up! The door to your roof was always off-limits and locked!
So, why was it unlocked then?!
Someone had picked it, or it just broke by chance!
One whole week earlier! So why didn't you do anything about it?!
I figured nobody ever went up there...
So it was nobody's fault?! Quit screwing around!
I'm gonna let you experience the same sadness I did!
The exact same sadness!
What're you gonna do to Junko?!
This is bad!
We have to do something!
Stupid train crossing! Now we can't hear!
That's it!
Gimme that!
Hey, that's...
Never mind that!
One... Two...
Three... Four...
Five... Six...
Seven... Eight...
There it is! 8.2 seconds!
This way!
How do you know they're this way?!
The sound of the train!
It took 8.2 seconds after it passed until I heard it on the receiver!
Beika Line
Speed
Trains on the Beika Line go 100 km/h!
That's about 27.8 meters per second!
1 Second
I heard the train on the receiver
8.2 seconds after it passed the crossing!
Seconds
In other words, the victim's house
is 27.8 meters x 8.2 seconds away!
Victim's Home
And that would be...
...here!
A building around here with balconies facing south or west!
And an apartment with a naked man on the balcony...
There he is!
That's the man whose daughter was kidnapped!
That just leaves the kidnapper's location...
Damn it! Where is he?!
I'll do anything you say! Just spare my daughter's life!
Anything?
Anything at all!
Good! I was waiting to hear that!
Go get a knife from the kitchen.
A knife?! Alright...
Now I see! The kidnapper's going to force him to kill himself
to get revenge without dirtying his own hands!
I brought it.
Alright. This will be my last demand.
Thrust the knife into your throat
and I'll let your daughter go.
I can't do that!
Oh?
So, you don't care what happens to your daughter?
Damn it! If I don't hurry...!
Where's the kidnapper?!
Alright... I'll do what you say!
Just let me talk to Junko one last time!
Fine.
Daddy!
Junko! Are you all right?!
Just hold on a little longer!
Daddy! I wanna go home!
I hate this smell! It smells like rubber!
Rubber?!
The tire factory!
Over there!
I can't see the building!
Damn! It's not the tire factory?!
Calm down!
What buildings near the factory have a view of the victim's balcony?
There's three of them!
Which one?! Which apartment building?!
The only one downwind from it... is that building!
That's gotta be it!
Somewhere in that building are the kidnapper and Junko-chan!
Conan! Do something, quick!
He's really gonna kill himself!
Junko-chan is in danger, too!
I'm gonna let you experience the same sadness I did!
The exact same sadness!
The exact same sadness...
The roof!
The kidnapper is on the roof!
Eh?!
Of that apartment building!
One of you two call the police!
Right!
Wait for me, Conan!
That's it! Jab it right in!
Don't be rash!
That's it! Just thrust it in!
Do it! Thrust it in!
Junko!
What're you hesitating for?! Do it! Jab it in!
Who's there?!
Who the hell are you?!
Conan Edogawa! A detective!
Eat this!
You did great!
Junko... forgive me!
Junko-chan's dad! She's safe!
I caught the kidnapper!
Daddy! I'm safe now!
I was rescued!
Junko...
You really are safe?!
Thank goodness! Thank goodness!
Here I come, kidnapper!
Huh?!
Aw, you beat him up yourself?
No, uh, he was so surprised when I showed up
that he fell and hit his head!
Aw, man...
It's broken!
I'm really sorry...
Guess that means good riddance to these things!
But, at least it was useful before it broke, Mitsuhiko-kun!
Yeah...
Oh, geez...
Crap! I forgot!
"Beika Martial Arts Arena"
"Gyokushinkai Karate Tournament"
Yikes!
It's over already?!
But, that was one mean roundhouse that high school girl won with!
Yeah! You mean Ran Mouri?! She was awesome!
So, the clincher was Ran's special roundhouse kick?
Conan-kun!
Did you watch?!
Of course! Your roundhouse in the finals was awesome!
I used my roundhouse to win in the semi-finals!
I won the finals by default because my opponent was hurt!
Conan-kun...
You broke your promise, didn't you?!
I'm sorry!
So, the arrow was shot through this window?
What's this?
The shards are all lined up...
Part of the soot is gone...
An unburned wood chip...
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Bird's Nest
Next time, an animal appears!
A tiger, a tiger, it's the Year of the Tiger!
It's a crane!
Crane?