A racing second hand, tiny shooting stars!
Conan's logic is good medicine
for hearts tired by modern society!
Today's case is a Western legend!
Don't put much stake in theories!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Dracula Manor?!
Yeah. Most of Mr. Torakura's novels are centered around vampires,
so he's earned the nickname "Mr. Dracula."
And that's why it's called Dracula Manor?
Is Daisuke Torakura a famous writer?
He's the most popular writer in the Japan Horror Novel Association.
He's even started to branch out into heroic fantasy novels,
and is gaining female fans, too.
You sure know a lot about him, Dad!
Of course I do! I am a brilliant detective, you know!
Ran-neechan.
Horror Times Monthly—
Special Daisuke Torakura Issue!
Ah, a cheat sheet, huh?
Shut up!
There it is!
That's Dracula Manor?
The Dracula Manor Murder Case
(Part 1)
Detective Mouri-san, right?
Yes.
Thank you for coming all this way!
Who are you?
Toshiya Tadokoro (26)
Student of Daisuke Torakura
I'm Tadokoro, I'm studying under Torakura-sensei.
He's been waiting for you. Come this way.
Who is she?
Etsuko Torakura (30)
Daisuke Torakura's Wife
Oh, that's his wife.
What a beautiful woman! I'm jealous!
Dad!
Geez...
Old mansions certainly have a unique feel to them,
I get a chill down my spine for some reason...
That's why I...
Oh? Is that...
Might you be Kogoro Mouri-san, the detective?!
Yes... that's right.
I knew it! It's an honor to meet you!
Fumio Doi (48)
Chief Editor, Horror Times Monthly
I'm Doi, editor in chief for Daigakukan's Horror Times Monthly.
Oh, I know that magazine.
Wow, so you're the famous detective?
Shuichi Hamura (33)
North Kanto University Folklore Researcher
I am Shuichi Hamura.
I'm a folklore researcher at North Kanto University.
Oh? What sort of research do you do?
Mainly... vampire legends.
O-Oh. That's interesting research...
Say, where's Mr. Torakura?
He's in the study, writing.
That's... a study room?
He's right in here.
A black-out curtain...
Just a movie...
Kogoro Mouri-san, I take it?
Welcome to Dracula Manor.
Daisuke Torakura (50)
Horror Writer
I am Daisuke Torakura.
Octagonal rooms certainly are rare...
Umm... do you always dress up like Dracula like that?
By writing while cloaked in Dracula attire as I play Dracula films,
I've brought many a masterpiece into the world.
So, how can I help you?
I wish to hire you to investigate the behavior of my wife, Etsuko.
Behavior? An affair, in other words?
Yes.
I want you to find definitive proof of the affair, and the man it's with.
Bastard called me all the way out here just for some stupid affair...
I am willing to pay one million yen, and related expenses, of course.
Certainly! I gladly accept the job!
Damn. I didn't bring any chains for the car...
No worries. You may spend the night here, in Dracula Manor.
I think I'll do that, then...
What a lovely smell!
It's homemade rosemary tea.
And dinner was delicious, too! You're a good cook, Tadokoro-san!
Thanks to him, the lady of the house
can live an easy, carefree life.
Hamura-san...
No, I'm studying novel-writing here,
so it's only natural that I help out.
Great. I look forward to your new series starting next month.
Though, I must finish this month's manuscript first.
Tadokoro, bring wine and a movie to the study.
Of course. What movie would you like?
You decide.
Say! Ran-san! Conan-kun! Want to come with me?
There's lots of rare stuff to see!
Rare stuff?
He means Torakura-sensei's prized "Dracula Collection,"
full of props and costumes from vampire films.
Let's go see, Ran-neechan!
I think I'll...
C'mon!
His vast collection of props and films are kept in here.
Hey, where do these stairs go?
Oh, there's a library in the basement.
It's filled with vampire books and old texts from around the world.
A Dracula Library, you could call it.
Whoa, a Dracula mask!
A Dracula hand!
A cross sword!
Yes, this one'll do.
Have you decided on a movie?
Yes. An old British movie called Banquet of Fresh Blood.
He just loves this one!
See that wooden stake there?
It was driven through the vampire's heart in the last scene of this film.
In his study, he also has the cross the vampire was strung up on.
Huh? I smell oil paint...
That's odd. There aren't any oil paintings...
Well, let's go back.
Okay!
Oh, Ran-san.
Sorry to ask, but could you make sure all the windows are locked?
Sure, no problem!
They're locked!
Thanks!
What did you think of the Dracula Collection?
It was kind of gross!
Say, Hamura-san. Dracula is just fiction, right?
It's true that the Count Dracula we know
was a monster created by Bram Stoker
in his 1897 novel, Dracula.
But, there were several noblemen in medieval Europe
who were feared as vampires because of the atrocities they committed.
Torakura-sensei has collected many old documents concerning that,
which is why I visit here personally.
Conan-kun! Want to play cards?
Yeah!
Great! Hold on while I make sure everything's locked up.
Tadokoro-san seems really nice, does he like horror novels, too?
If anything, I'd say he's probably more into fantasy.
I was the one who introduced him to Torakura-sensei!
He seemed to have real talent, you see!
Is it still snowing?
No, it's stopped now.
Won't you two play cards with us, too?
Sorry. I have a headache, so I'm going to bed now.
And I'd like to browse the library a bit more. If you'll excuse me.
Conan-kun! Use your 6 of Hearts already!
Not gonna happen.
And my theory was right on the mark!
Oh!
Won't you join us, Hamura-san?
Mouri-san is retelling his many exploits!
That sounds interesting.
I need to use the restroom. I've been feeling ill since this morning.
Sure, go ahead.
Sorry.
Dad. We're going to bed now.
You do that. It's grownup time now.
Huh? That's weird.
What is it?
He won't answer the phone.
You think maybe he dozed off?
He'd never do that! Late nights and alcohol never affect him!
I'll go have a look.
I'll go with him.
Sensei! Say something!
Torakura-sensei!
Sensei!
It's locked.
What's all the noise?
Ma'am! Your husband isn't responding to us!
Oh, that's strange.
I can hear the projector!
That can't be! Shouldn't the movie be long over by now?!
Let's go outside and call for him from the window.
Right!
It's cold!
The window's open.
Only the snow by the window's been trampled on!
What's going on?!
Torakura-san! Are you in here?!
W-What the...
W-What is it?!
What's going on?!
All the windows, but the one we entered from, are fixed in place.
And...
the only door is locked from the inside.
Rubber sealing...
It'd be impossible to use string to lock it from the outside.
It would appear the killer entered and exited through that window.
But, Mouri-san, how did the killer get here?
Only the snow in front of the window was trampled...
there were no other footprints.
Climbing up the cliff would be impossible,
and the rough waves in the lake would quickly capsize any boat.
So, even with the window open,
this study room was still as good as locked...
What did the police say?
It's no good!
The snowstorm caused an avalanche that blocked the only road here!
They say they can't clear the road until at least morning!
Damn... Looks like I'll have to examine the body...
What a vulgar murderer,
killing him with a wooden stake,
as if he were Dracula...
and sticking his body on a cross, on top of that.
Hold on, now!
Why did the killer move the projector and light up the body?!
Is there some reason behind it?!
It's almost like the last scene of Banquet of Fresh Blood.
Banquet of Fresh Blood?
That's the movie Tadokoro-san brought him!
T-That's right!
It was Torakura-sensei's most beloved vampire film.
So, the killer set it up to look like the movie's last scene?!
Rigor mortis has set in.
Meaning he's probably been dead for at least an hour.
In short, the time of the murder was between 9:00 and 11:00 pm.
There's a wound on the back of his head.
He must've been hit with this. There's some blood on it.
I see.
He was strung up and impaled with the stake after being knocked out.
Mouri-san, that stake came from the collection room!
What?!
In short, the killer snuck in and stole the stake
after Tadokoro-san came to get the movie.
Then, after Tadokoro-san delivered the movie to the study room,
the person murdered Mr. Torakura.
Huh?
It doesn't smell like oil paint...
But all the windows were locked from the inside.
There's not a single footprint outside the window.
Which means the killer is an insider!
Mister! Look!
The end of a twig...
That's got nothin' to do with this!
Hamura-san!
The only one who could've stolen the stake
is you, who went to browse the library.
Yes, that's true.
But, Mouri-san, how exactly did I take the stake to the study?
I would've had to pass through the living room, where you all were.
W-Well...
There is one way!
What?!
By going upstairs and walking across the corridor's roof!
You could get to the study that way!
Ah.
I don't need your help! I already knew that!
If I wanted to leave, I would still have to go through the living room.
Either way, I couldn't have done it.
Ma'am.
Yes?
Your room is above the collection room, yes?
Ma'am, you conspired with Hamura-san, didn't you?
W-What are you saying, Mouri-san?!
You could dangle a rope to the collection room window from here.
Hamura-san used it to climb up to your room,
then traversed the corridor roof to reach the study.
He then scaled the roof there and set down in front of that window.
Then, he called out to Mr. Torakura to let him inside,
then murdered him when he got the chance!
He used the same course in reverse to get back.
Am I wrong?
Ridiculous!
Why would Hamura-san and I need to conspire to kill my husband?!
Mr. Torakura suspected you of having an affair.
Ma'am, were you having an affair with Hamura-san?
W-What makes you think we're...
Etsuko, let's not hide the truth.
Hamura-san!
The police would find out right away, anyway.
So, you admit it, then?
I do. But, we truly love each other!
Yeah! Hamura-san is the only one I love!
I never once loved Torakura!
Then why did you get married?
Eight years ago, my father's business took a nosedive
and was on the verge of bankruptcy.
Torakura was an old acquaintance of my father's,
and in exchange for financing the business,
he demanded my hand in marriage after I had just graduated college!
If the company went bankrupt,
so many people, and families, would be affected!
So, I had no choice but to...
We later learned that the business' downfall
was actually because of Torakura's behind-the-scenes dirty work.
But, by the time we found out,
the company was already in his name,
and he threatened to destroy the company if we divorced...
That's horrible!
I see.
If Mr. Torakura died, his wife would inherit his company...
So, that's why you...
No! It wasn't us!
Do you have proof that we killed him?
Very well. If that's how you want it, then I'll show you.
You left her room, climbed onto the corridor roof from this window,
and went to the study.
The old guy's on the ball today!
Which is why Hamura-san's footprints are still on the roof!
T-There aren't any footprints!
Say what?!
That's impossible!
There's not a single footprint!
With the corridor unusable,
this roof was the only way to the study!
Don't tell me the killer actually flew through the air, like a vampire?!
NEXT EPISODE
Leave the rest to me, old guy!
First, I thought only Hamura-san could have taken the stake,
but actually, anyone could have stolen it from outside!
Anyone?
There were no footprints because the killer walked through the air.
Walked through the air?
Next Conan:
The Dracula Manor Murder Case
(Part 2)
Next Conan's Hint: Art paint
Look forward to the next episode!
Next time Dad delivers knockout deductions!
More like he just gets knocked out.