A racing second hand, shining shooting stars!
Conan's logic is good medicine
for hearts tired by modern society!
Today is the Dracula solution!
The trick is exposed before sunrise!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
The old man was hired by
Mr. Torakura, owner of Dracula Manor,
to investigate his wife's infidelity.
That night, someone killed
Mr. Torakura with a stake to the heart,
in his completely-locked study room!
To get to the study, one would have to pass through the living room,
where everyone was at the time!
Breaking in from outside was also impossible!
Did the killer fly through the air, like a vampire?!
My, what a farce that was.
That's the roof above the collection room...
What are those imprints in the snow?
Wait a minute!
The collection room didn't smell like oil paint after the incident!
Does that mean...
Huh?! It doesn't smell!
Hey, you!
What're you doing?
Nothing!
Was that stake not the source of the smell?
Let's first organize what we know about the incident.
First, at around 8:30,
Mr. Torakura went to the study
and Tadokoro-san, Ran, and Conan went to the collection room
to get a film.
At that time, the stake used as the murder weapon was still there.
In other words, the killer stole the stake after that.
Moreover, Ran confirmed that
all the windows in the collection room
had been locked from the inside.
In short, the only way into the room was from the living room.
Next, Tadokoro-san went to the study
to deliver the wine and movie.
Yes. At around 8:50, I left the wine and film and left the study.
Huh?
The wine bottle's seal hasn't been broken.
Did anything seem odd about Mr. Torakura then?
No, not really.
You returned to the living room shortly after 9:00,
then left to make sure that everything was locked up.
Yes. I believe I returned 10 minutes afterward.
The snow had already stopped by then.
Shortly after, his wife retired to her room upstairs.
Around 9:15, I'd say?
And then she came down when
the body was found around midnight.
In short, she has no alibi for that period of time.
Hamura-san.
You left the living room the same time she did, to go to the library.
Yes. I returned to the living room at about 10:30.
Which means I have no alibi for that period of time.
You had the opportunity to steal the stake from the collection room.
Doi-san. Right after Hamura-san returned to the living room,
you went to the restroom.
You were gone about
20 minutes, wouldn't you say?
Y-Yes.
20 minutes is enough time to commit the murder.
But I never went to the collection room.
Yeah! Doi-san only went to the bathroom!
He even bumped into Hamura-san on his way!
That's right! I didn't think of that!
Hamura-san. Perhaps you secretly had the stake when that happened?
And then Doi-san pretended to bump into you and took it.
Quit joking around! Why would I need to kill Torakura-sensei?!
What's this?
T-That's...
"Call of Darkness, by Yoshihiko Nakajima"
These aren't Mr. Torakura's manuscripts...
Could they be novels submitted to Doi-san's magazine by readers?
See, it says "Horror Times" on the envelope.
WEEKLY
Come to think of it, I have heard an odd rumor,
from my university's Horror Novel Association,
that novels submitted to the Horror Times
wound up being plagiarized by Torakura.
Plagiarized?
Don't tell me you were involved with this too, Editor-in-Chief?
W-What makes you think—
In that case, we can compare Torakura's manuscripts on this PC
with these submitted novels.
T-That's...
Doi-san.
It'd be in your best interest
to come clean while you still can.
Torakura... His talent had been dried up for years now.
About seven years ago,
I failed in the stock market
and found myself in incredible debt.
Torakura offered to take over my debt
if I would leak novels to him.
So, you murdered him
to dissolve your relationship, then?
N-No!
But you have a motive!
If it's motives you want,
Tadokoro-kun has one, too!
He was Torakura's ghostwriter!
Ghostwriter?!
It was five years ago.
No longer able to endure leaking him novels submitted to me,
I introduced him to Tadokoro-kun,
who I learned of through literary magazines.
Come to think of it,
didn't Mr. Torakura start publishing fantasy works five years ago?
Tadokoro-kun wrote them.
Is this true, Tadokoro-san?!
It's true.
But I don't bear a grudge against him for it.
Even if I did, there's a reason I couldn't kill him!
A reason you couldn't kill him?
I have a sister named Kaori,
who's 10 years younger than me.
She was born with a slightly-faulty heart,
and as our parents died when she was young,
I wasn't able to get her decent medical help.
But, thanks to Torakura-sensei,
she's now in a hospital in Tokyo.
He offered to pay Kaori's medical and hospital fees
if I became his ghostwriter.
So, killing Mr. Torakura would cut off your sister's treatment...
Yes.
Mr. Torakura sure was one horrible man.
A true vampire.
Even if the victim was as merciless as a vampire, murder is murder!
It can't be forgiven.
I guess, unless Hamura-san worked with one of the other two,
the murder would've been impossible.
But, the only way to get to the only corridor is from the living room.
It'd be impossible to sneak past us all.
Even if it was possible, the study room was locked from the inside.
The door had a rubber seal,
so outside tricks would be impossible.
And, if the window was used to enter and exit,
only the snow in front of the window had footprints.
The weapon was the wooden stake in the collection room,
so the killer was someone in Dracula Manor tonight.
Wait! Why did the person kill him with the stake?
That limited the suspects to those inside the building.
That would be very bad for the killer!
Yet... why did they dare to use that weapon?
Could it be that...
I knew it! There's a slight smell of oil paint left!
The windows were locked from the inside.
The small ventilation windows have spring stoppers...
The twig piece I found on the floor under the window...
And the strange imprints in the snow on the roof above the window...
There's gotta be a connection! What is it?!
That's it! So, that's the deal!
What's this plastic bag?
This is...
There's gotta be a secret passageway here somewhere!
There's nothing of the sort!
I have a good idea who's behind this.
But there's still a big mystery left!
Just how did the killer manage to...
Come to think of it,
why did the killer use the projector to light up the body?
Was it just to recreate
the last scene of the movie?
What's that?
Cellophane tape? What's it doing here?
This is...
That's it! I know the real reason why the killer lit up the body!
Now, I see the truth behind this case!
Dammit! There's no secret passage!
Hamura-san! Ma'am! Doi-san!
Don't tell me there's a real vampire among you!
A vampire would be able to fly to the study room and back!
Dear me. You appear to be exhausted, Mouri-san.
Take a nice nap and leave the rest to me, old man!
Here we go again...
Let's return to our rooms, too.
Not so fast!
I was merely joking before.
Now, it's time to get down to business.
Down to business?
Are you suggesting you've discovered the truth to this incident?
Of course I am.
Really?!
Yes. All of it.
Let us hear your theory then, Mouri-san.
First, the wooden stake used as the murder weapon.
I thought only Hamura-san could have taken the stake,
but actually, anyone could have stolen it from outside!
From outside?
There wasn't a single footstep in the snow outside, you know.
There were no footprints because the killer walked through the air.
Walked through the air?
Is this another of your jokes?
Were you aware that the window by the entrance hall is as high up
as the roof above the collection room window?
The killer used that fact to make a bridge...
using a ladder.
A ladder?
Yes.
Walking across it, the killer could get to the collection room window
without leaving any footsteps.
As proof, there are ladder marks
on the snow on the roof.
But, the windows were locked...
They could easily be opened with a simple little trick.
By sticking the twig piece Conan found
between the ventilation window's stopper and the glass.
This way, the stopper will look like it's set,
but the window can still be opened freely.
The killer stole the stake from there.
Afterward, simply closing the window would make the stopper lock.
But, Mouri-san! The stake was two meters from that window!
2 meters
The killer used a tree pruner.
You used one this afternoon, Tadokoro-san.
There are attachments for those for picking fruit.
The killer attached one and stuck it through the ventilation window
to steal the stake.
Using this method, anyone could have obtained the stake.
You can't be serious...
But, Mouri-san, how did the person go to the study and back?
Simple, by crossing the corridor.
What are you talking about? That's absolute nonsense.
Is it?
Isn't it much more logical than having the killer fly through the air?
You were in the living room, too. You know no one used the corridor.
Oh, but one person did.
Yes. The killer...
was you, Toshiya Tadokoro-san!
Tadokoro-kun?
T-That can't be!
W-What are you talking about?!
The stake was still in the collection room when I went to the study!
Isn't that right?!
That's true, Dad!
Ran, what you two saw was an elaborately-made fake.
A fake?!
Yes.
When Tadokoro-san went to get the film, he invited you and Conan
and showed you the stake, so you would confirm it had been there.
Then, after killing Mr. Torakura with the real stake,
which he had hidden in the study in advance,
he pretended to check all the locks and stole the fake stake.
But, Mouri-san. Do you have proof the stake was a fake?
What's this?
This turned up after I instructed Conan to look through the storeroom.
Yes, it's very well-made.
Was the fake blood added using oil paint?
His wife does oil painting, so it would've been easy to get the paint.
Tadokoro-kun...
Mouri-san. Even if he did use the corridor to reach the study,
how did he get inside?
It was locked from the inside, so he couldn't have gone out the door.
And if he left through the window, how did he return to the corridor?
There were no other footprints, except those in front of the window.
The open window and the trampled snow were simply a red herring.
Tadokoro-san entered and exited through the door.
Then how could I have locked it from the outside?!
Locking the door is no problem at all...
if you use that projector, that is!
Projector?
W-What are you talking about? How could a projector do that?
Tadokoro-san, I've figured it all out, you know...
Including why you lit up the body.
Wasn't it to recreate the last scene of the movie?!
No, it wasn't.
The body was lit up to camouflage the real reason
for moving the projector!
The real reason?
For this trick to work,
it was absolutely vital to move the projector in front of the door.
But, the trick would be obvious
if only the projector were moved.
So, by lighting up the body as a bit of an informed performance,
our attention was diverted.
I'll now reenact this trick I speak of.
Ran.
Yes!
Lend me a hand.
Okay!
First, pull about five meters of film from the reel.
Right!
Next, stick a piece of cellophane tape
on the end of the film.
After that, throw the film over the blackout curtain rail by the door,
and attach it to the lock on the door.
All done, Dad!
Now everything is set.
Ran. Start the projector.
Right!
This is how Tadokoro-san locked the door.
But, unfortunately for him,
as the film was being pulled in,
the piece of tape caught on the curtain rail and remained there.
On the piece of tape are small, square marks...
from perforations.
The square holes in the film, in other words.
Tadokoro-san, can you give any other explanation
as to why that perforation-marked tape
was stuck on the curtain rail?
W-Well...
I think it's about time you tell us the truth.
You already confessed you were the killer when the body was found.
At the time, you said you could hear the projector.
Don't you find that strange?
The door had airtight, sound-proof rubber sealing.
How could you hear what was happening inside?
You knew that the projector was on inside.
Or, shall we see if the projector
is audible behind the closed door?
I... killed him.
Tadokoro-san...
But why would you kill Torakura-san?!
What about your sister?!
My sister... Kaori... has been dead for a year now...
That can't be...
Torakura never gave Kaori real medical treatment.
He paid off her doctor so she would get neither better nor worse.
Just to keep Kaori hospitalized longer.
But, then her condition suddenly took a turn for the worse, and she...
I only found out about this one month ago.
Torakura kept my sister's death secret the entire time!
I believed his lie about sending her to a better hospital in America...
But, one month ago...
Kaori's nurse couldn't bear it anymore
and secretly came to tell me.
She said Kaori deliriously cried
my name over and over as she died...
If she had had real treatment...
If she had had real treatment,
that never would've happened!
Torakura murdered Kaori!
That's why... That's why I...
They say a vampire's bite can turn a normal person into a vampire.
Unknowingly, Tadokoro-san might have become a vampire himself.
A vampire known as a murderer...
Franken Manor?!
Yeah. It belongs to Kenzo Furano, an engineering professor.
Apparently, he conducts strange experiments every night and—
This time it's Frankenstein...
Now we just need a wolfman and we're all set.
Mr. Shiraki!
Something's not right! What could it be?!
Wait a minute!
When he was in the dressing room,
the flower on his chest was—
If Rika Okano-san is the killer,
who will she go after next?!
Who is it?! Who is she trying to kill?!
This is bad! I'm not gonna make it in time!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Ice
The next episode suits me perfectly!
The scent of flowers!
A pretty flower might have thorns!