A racing second hand, shining shooting stars!
Conan's logic is good medicine
for hearts tired by modern society!
Today's case is of a different color!
What flowers have thorns?
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
"Rika Okano — World Art Award
Congratulatory Party"
"World Art Award Party."
Did she win that big of an award?
Look! It's Marika Aochi, the actress!
Look! It's Koji Takahata, the soccer player!
Geez. Knock it off, you're acting uncool...
Wow! So many famous people, from celebrities to sports players!
You idiots! Who do you think I am?!
I said let go! I was asked to come here!
- Dad?!
- Old man?!
Don't you bums even know
what the unrivaled Detective Kogoro Mouri looks like?!
I'm very sorry, but only those with invitations may enter.
Midori Ozaki (33)
Rika Okano's Assistant
Wait. I called him here.
Now do you see?
The peerless Kogoro Mouri-sama has arrived on the scene
to investigate a murder threat!
M-Mouri-san!
The Flower Scent Murder Case
Rika Okano (28)
Avant-Garde Flower Arranger
We received the threat letter several days ago.
"Flowers of death will bloom in the Bay Front Hotel."
It's clearly a prank. You're taking this too seriously.
Just ignore it.
But, Sensei. It could be real,
so there's no harm in being cautious.
It's just some people getting back at me for winning the award.
Paying them any attention would be a waste of time.
Who's she?
Rika Okano. An avant-garde flower-arranging artist.
You know her; she's on TV all the time.
Avant-garde flower-arranging?
She's amazing! She makes flower buds open right up!
Sorta like a magic trick!
You could call it that, but would you also call me an art world fraud?
What a nasty woman...
Actually, the secret is in the temperature.
Oh?
Mr. Shiraki!
I hear you were sent some stupid threat letter.
Daisuke Shiraki (58)
Owner of Bay Front Hotel
Y-Yes.
I don't expect any, of course,
but I assume there'll be
no changes to today's party?
That's—
Don't worry.
This party is for me, so it will all go as scheduled.
But what if something happens?
It's not just this party.
Don't forget the Shiraki Group,
which has always backed you up.
No, of course I won't!
I'll see you around.
What a jerk...
He's the owner of this hotel
and the company that finances her art.
Bastard thinks money can buy him art!
His face makes me sick!
Wow! These flowers are—
Don't get into trouble now.
What is this?
Liquid nitrogen.
Isn't that the stuff that can freeze stuff fast?
That's right! You're really smart!
It's the Sensei's art secret.
Is she the one who thought up the idea?
She made it popular, more than anything.
Made it popular?
This looks great!
Stop that, Dad! You're embarrassing us!
Umm... Are you the famous Detective Mouri-sama?
Yep!
I'm sorry to bother you, but I have a favor to ask.
I came to tell him it's almost time,
but he won't respond.
I see. Say, are there any spare keys?
Y-Yes! Right here!
Mr. Shiraki!
Whose tie is that around his neck?
It was his.
Definitely looks like he was strangled to death.
But something's strange about this body.
What do you mean?
When did you get in here?!
I mean, look! The knot on the tie is in front!
That's true...
I get it! The killer strangled him from the front!
You'd expect him to put up quite a fight if he was being strangled,
especially from the front.
In other words, the killer was someone strong enough
that the victim's struggling posed no problem at all.
A man... and a rather large one, at that!
But it looks like he didn't put up a fight at all.
What?!
He'd still struggle, no matter how strong the killer was, right?
Yes. Like scratching at the killer or trying to undo the necktie.
Right?
Yet, look at his hand.
There are no marks on his nails at all.
Interesting. There aren't any marks on his nails.
No, that's no guarantee.
It's possible to black out instantly if strangled with enough force.
The killer must've been someone as strong as a pro wrestler!
Yeah. Check at once to see if any such people
are among the party guests!
Yes, sir!
C'mon, now. Isn't that a little too simple?
In any case, we can't move the body until medical examiners arrive.
Conan! Are you still here?!
Get out, you!
I'd like to speak with whomever's in charge.
Yes, that would be me.
I'm Megure of Police Investigative Unit #1.
I hear the owner was killed.
So, what do you plan to do?
Have the party cancelled immediately, of course.
You can't!
Huh?!
We've invited all these high-profile guests.
Canceling this event would tarnish my career!
Sensei...
What selfishness!
Listen, you! This is a premeditated murder!
I know that, obviously!
But the target was the owner, not me.
That means there's no danger now.
Maybe so, but...
She's a really selfish woman...
Still...
Bastard thinks money can buy him art!
His face makes me sick!
Don't tell me she—
But she wouldn't have the strength for this.
Inspector!
I found several guests matching your description!
Anaconda Katagiri, the pro wrestler,
Kotaro Imamura, the football player, and—
Anaconda Katagiri-sama
once got into a fight with the owner
about royalties, at a dinner show.
He's the one! No doubt about it!
We can only hope the incident is that straightforward...
Thank you all for coming today
to Rika Okano-sensei's
World Art Award congratulatory party!
Yeah?
Anaconda Katagiri (35)
Pro Wrestler
What?
Anaconda Katagiri-san.
Could we have a word with you?
Later! I want some more food!
Damn you!
Inspector! He has an alibi!
This guy... No, Anaconda-san's been with his friends the whole time.
Several people vouch for him!
Sorry!
The inspector's in trouble!
He says he needs your help!
There's a faint smell of chloroform.
Hold on!
If he were knocked out first,
even someone weak could strangle him!
But how did they get him to breathe the chloroform?
Something's not right about this flower... What could it be?
Wait a minute! When he was in the dressing room,
the flower on his chest...
...was closed!
Yet, now it's open!
His dying was the greatest commemoration gift ever!
He was nothing but a stepping stone on my way to fame!
A stepping stone is just a stepping stone!
I was never his puppet!
Sensei! What if someone hears you?!
Midori-san. You just need to shut up
and handle my management.
Who do you have to thank
that you can make a living?!
I'm sorry for talking out of line.
Man, she's a real bitch...
Coming!
Oh, little boy!
They say it's almost time for the show.
Oh, thank you!
Sensei. You should be going now.
Yes! Here we go!
Chloroform, just as I thought.
And this other bottle has...
...a cyanide compound?!
Is the killer still going after someone else?!
But how?
Ice cubes?
Chloroform ice!
Now I see!
The frozen chloroform slowly melted in the room's temperature
and the victim inhaled it!
And this time, it'll be cyanide!
But how?
A flower petal?
She's amazing! She makes flower buds open right up!
It's the Sensei's art secret.
So the closed flower had a secret hidden inside it!
The flower had been frozen, too!
The frozen chloroform was placed inside,
then the flower was frozen.
No one would suspect a thing this way—
because all the party guests were wearing flowers on their chests.
And then, when the flower warmed up in the room's temperature,
it started to re-open, and the chloroform also vaporized.
The owner breathed in the chloroform and went comatose,
upon which he was slowly strangled to death.
His dying was the greatest commemoration gift ever!
If Rika Okano is the killer, who will she go after next?!
What's wrong?! Fight me!
The target's flower should be closed!
I have to find it quickly!
Cyanide evaporates at 25.7°C!
Once the flower opens, it's all over!
Thank you for your patience, ladies and gentlemen!
Here is Rika Okano's Congratulatory One-Man Show!
Damn!
The ice is beginning to melt!
At this temperature, so will the killer's ice!
Wait a minute!
All the guests were given flowers at the reception desk beforehand!
In which case, the flower would've opened long ago!
Was I over-analyzing things?! Was the owner the only target?
No, then there'd be no reason to have cyanide ready!
The killer must be planning to murder someone with it!
That's not it! Where is it?! Where could it be?!
She's amazing! She makes flower buds open right up!
Yes! That's it! Don't tell me she plans to kill her?!
No good! I'm not gonna make it!
That's...
Alright!
What?!
W-What the...
This kid has ruined my show!
You damn kid! What were you thinking?!
I'm sorry! I swung it and it suddenly shot out!
What were you—
Hey, now!
What's wrong, mister?!
What is it, Mouri-kun?!
Have you found a clue to solving the case?!
It was actually I who had him interrupt the show.
Why would you do that?! You'll pay for this!
The moment the flowers opened
was to be the moment your life closed.
Come again?!
Mouri-kun! Can't you explain more clearly?
Inspector. Please seal up all the arranged flowers.
Double and triple seal them so that no air can leak out.
Hidden inside the flowers is the secret to the owner's murder...
...and a failed murder plot!
Quickly!
R-Right!
We've bagged them all up, Mouri-kun! Now talk to us!
The method behind Shiraki-san's murder and the other murder plot
was the very theme of Rika-san's avant-garde flower-arranging...
Yes... making closed flowers open!
Then Rika Okano-san is the killer?!
Was it you?!
N-No!
What nonsense is this?!
Why would I have to kill the owner?!
That's right. It wasn't you.
Because you were the next to die after the owner!
What?! I was?!
Then just who is the killer?!
The person who put the flower on the owner
and prepared the flowers on the stage.
Rika-san. You know who that was.
Yes. It was your manager... Midori Ozaki-san!
Midori tried to kill me?
After all, only Midori-san could've rigged the flowers on the stage.
But if she's the killer,
she would've died from the flowers she set, too!
Yes. She intended to exact revenge
and die with Rika-san...
Revenge?
Yes.
Her motive was most likely...
Most likely, her motive was...
She made it popular, more than anything.
Judging from what she said,
Rika-san probably didn't come up
with the flower-opening idea.
That's right. I had to make Shiraki and Rika pay.
My sister Haruka started this avant-garde flower-arranging,
and Rika Okano was her student!
But she got Shiraki to sponsor her
in an attempt to become the top avant-garde flower arranger!
In the art world, it's natural for
the skilled to kick down the unskilled.
But Rika Okano knew she could never be the best
as long as my sister was around.
So she used dirty tactics and Shiraki's support to pressure her
into being unable to take credit for what Rika stole!
On top of that, it was my sister who came up with
the idea of opening closed flowers!
And Rika decided to—
What happened to your sister after that?
She lost all hope in everything
and took her own life...
Rika doesn't love flowers in the slightest.
She only used them to gain fame and money.
I learned that all too well
after I changed my name and became her manager!
That's why she had to pay!
Through this incident,
Rika Okano's plagiarism was made public,
meaning she'll probably never step onto a center stage ever again.
As for me...
You damn kid!
I wound up being punished by
the old guy, who slept through it all.
Oww!
NEXT EPISODE
There's still a good chance
the criminal group is nearby.
So he's the one responsible?
Don't do it.
You've been asked to kill that Akabane guy, right?
Wow! So cool!
The officer, too?!
Next Conan:
The Robber Hospitalization Case
Next Conan's Hint: Cream Puff
Look forward to the next episode!
Next time, old man Kogoro's in the hospital!
Let's go, Megure-kun! By Detective Takagi.
Say what?!