A racing second hand, a shining comet!
Conan's logic is good medicine
for hearts tired by modern society!
Today's stage is a significant hospital room!
Find the case's virus!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Created by
Gosho Aoyama
"Detective Conan"
Serialized in Shogakukan's
"Weekly Shonen Sunday"
Planning
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Character Design
Masatomo Sudo
Art Director
Yukihiro Shibutani
Art Design
Hiroyuki Mitsumoto
Director of Photography
Takahisa Ogawa
Sound Director
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
Music Producer
Hiroki Horio
(PolyGram)
Music
Katsuo Ono
Opening Theme
"Nazo"
Performed by
Lyrics
Music
Arrangement
Miho Komatsu
Hirohito Furui
(Spoonful/Zain Records)
Editor
Teramitsu Okada
Story Editor
Jun'ichi Iioka
Color Key
Reiko Hirayama
Executive Producer
Satoshi Yokoyama
Planning Support
Toyohiko Okuyama
Mitome Asai
Director
Kenji Kodama
Producers
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Masahito Yoshioka
(Tokyo Movie)
I'm home—Huh?
Weren't you going to Yoko Okino's concert today, Dad?
- Socks! Socks!
- Oh, Dad.
- Necktie! Necktie!
- Be careful!
Jacket! Jacket! Ticket! Ticket!
And...
...watch your step.
Please! Drop me off at Yoko Okino-chan's concert hall!
Today's her last day playing there.
You broke your leg and you're in an ambulance, not a taxi!
Yoko-chan! Oww!
"Beika General Hospital"
What a huge hospital!
That's for certain...
What room is he in?
I dunno. I'll go ask at the desk.
He's in Room 503!
Alright! Let's go!
"Goemon Akabane"
"Daisaburo Sekiguchi"
"Kogoro Mouri"
How lame! Falling down some steps and breaking a bone!
Not to mention the cause was an Yoko Okino concert!
You know you shouldn't rush down stairs.
Shaddup. I don't feel like hearing that from you,
especially since you only dropped by on your way to play.
You found us out?
Conan-kun's going to teach us to play soccer in the park!
Then get lost already.
Now, now, Mouri-san. Does it really matter if they only dropped by?
I had lots of visitors when I first came here, but now I get none.
You should be happy that someone came to see you.
Right, neighbor?
He sure isn't friendly...
He was carried in here a week ago.
Apparently, he was seriously hurt in a car accident.
Oh, Yoshio! How rare it is to see you!
How's your back, Dad?
Oh, it's much better now.
Two weeks in the hospital because of a bad back... how pathetic.
Are you making sure to take your pills?
I forgot to take today's.
You know that's no good. You're diabetic, you know.
Say, where's Yumi-chan?
Did she not come with you?
O-Oh, Yumiko, she, uhh, you know, went ice-skating with a friend.
Oh, that's a shame. It would've been nice to see my granddaughter.
It can't be helped. Yumiko just loves to play.
What's yer problem?!
N-Nothing!
Quit starin' at me!
S-Sorry!
Say, have they caught the guys yet?
You know, the guys who robbed your bank last week.
N-No, I hear they're still on the run.
In that case, why not speak with Kogoro Mouri-san there?
Maybe he'll figure something out!
Hello.
M-Mouri? The famous detective?
Yes!
Oh, but all I did was tremble in fear under a desk...
How pathetic.
Say! Are those the guys from the criminal group
that stole 100 million yen and still hasn't been caught?!
That's right. They stole 100 million in broad daylight,
without hurting anyone!
"Beika Bank"
They disabled the security in advance and acted with precision,
so their crime syndicate must be quite a large organization.
100 million yen? Could that buy a boxed eel lunch?
That could buy you anything!
Using stolen money is bad!
Y-Yeah, you're right!
How many robbers were in the bank?
L-Like I said, I was under my desk, shaking, so...
But the leader must've said to put your hands up or something, right?
Shut up! If you don't wanna die, hit the floor and stay there!
Oh, well...
Oh, Dad. I have things to do, so I should be going.
You're leaving?
I'll see you later.
Bring a present or something next time you come!
Yeah.
Excuse me.
We're with the police. You're Yoshio Sekiguchi-san, correct?
Y-Yes. Why do you ask?
We'd like to ask you a few things.
That man in the bed next to your father was in a car accident.
Has anyone come to visit him?
I-I don't know. I only met him today.
W-Well, I have things to do, so...
My guess is that the robbers probably escaped overseas in a boat.
They're hiding out in some mountains somewhere.
Nah, they're probably on a shopping spree with their stolen money!
I doubt they'd immediately use the money they stole.
Where could they be hiding?
There's still a good chance the criminal group is nearby.
A bank robber can only be nearby.
ginkō
kinkō
Bank (ginkō)
Nearby (kinkō)
Get it?!
Let's go.
Let's let him rest in peace.
What do you think, Sekiguchi-san?
Oh...
And he was so full of energy earlier...
Did he get tired out, I wonder?
It wouldn't be nice to wake him up, so our theory party is over.
Aww, you're no fun.
Conan. Yoko Okino-chan's on a music show at 3:00,
and I wanna watch it in the lobby.
Could you get me a wheelchair from downstairs?
Sure.
Living the hospital life isn't all that bad!
I can't... I just can't do it...
What's the problem?
Don't tell me you're gonna wimp out at this point?
A-Are you aware that Kogoro Mouri is in that room?!
Not to mention there are police lurking outside the room...
Forget about the cops. I have that taken care of.
And don't worry about the detective.
He'll be gone from the room before your 3:30 deadline.
He's gonna watch some idol TV show in the lobby at 3:00.
Those brats are off getting him a wheelchair.
B-But I can't do it right in front of my father!
You gave him the sleeping pills, right?
Then there's nothin' to worry about.
M-My daughter! Is Yumiko all right?!
Damn, you're annoying.
Yeah? What's going on?
His daughter?
She's having a blast. Should I put her on?
Here.
Daddy?
Y-Yumiko!
I'm having lots of fun with a nice lady here!
Come get me when you're done talking with the doctor, okay?
Yumiko!
"Cream puffs"
Here. Here's his present.
You know what to do, right?
Your chance to do it is before the doctors make their rounds at 3:30,
when surveillance isn't so tight. Should be simple.
B-But I've never killed anyone, or even shot a gun before!
Whoops! You'll only rouse suspicion if you shout.
Listen. Put the gun up to him and pull the trigger. You can't miss.
Grow some balls and shoot the guy.
Then it'll all be over.
B-But...
You still got time. Freshen up in the john and calm down first.
Do it for your daughter.
What took so long, Conan-kun?
Geez! What were you doin'?!
Sorry! My stomach suddenly hurt, so...
Did you remember to wash your hands?
I don't feel like hearing that from you...
So you're certain of it?
Yes. The tire tracks from the car used in the robbery
match with the car Akabane was in.
The robbers likely thought Akabane was dead and left him behind.
Just by coincidence, Akabane is in Detective Mouri's room.
Oh? I hear he broke a bone...
Yes. His right leg.
Again?!
He broke that leg not too long ago, too!
Talk about an unlucky guy.
Anyways, I'm heading back to the station.
When you deem he's fit enough for questioning, haul him on over.
Understood, Inspector!
"I-Inspector"?!
T-This is my chance! He's not here to keep watch over me!
If I tell the inspector everything here, he might be able to...
U-Umm!
Is something the matter?
Y-Yes! A-Actually...
Quit screwing around.
You heard my partner. You're always under our watch.
Any more funny business and you'll be dealt with immediately.
What is it?
Oh, it's nothing. He asked if I had any medicine, since he feels ill.
You should ask doctors that, not policemen!
Seriously!
How long does it take to borrow a stupid wheelchair?!
Conan suddenly ran off, so we went looking for him!
Damn you, Conan! You're gonna get a Cobra Twist later!
Damn you, Conan!
Push! Push! Push! Push!
Oww!
That's my line!
What were you doing?! Yoko-chan's show is about to start!
You always run off!
Conan! Help push! I gotta get to the TV!
Sorry, sorry!
It's all you guys' fault if I miss Yoko-chan's singing!
It hasn't even started yet!
See!
I made it in time!
Hey. I need you guys to do something.
Oh?
What is it?
Sure! Leave it to us!
Just tell her that?
Let's go!
Hey! Hey! You're not gonna watch?!
I can't do it. I'm up against a wall. No one'll believe me now.
3:24.
3:30 is the deadline. If I don't do it before then, Yumiko'll be...
Yumiko'll be thrown off that roof...
Yeah. I have to do it.
I have to, or she'll die!
He did say they'd take care of things so I wouldn't be found out,
and I'd only be killing a bank robber...
Nobody would give a care if I—
Don't do it.
You've been asked to kill that Akabane guy, right?
Using the weapon inside that cream puff box.
How do you know that?!
Shh! Don't look at me! They'll notice!
How did you—
That cream puff box.
Your father can't have sweets—he's diabetic.
It was obvious something was up,
given you're still in the hospital with a box that can't be a present,
especially after you said you had to leave to take care of things.
Plus, it's forbidden to use cell phones inside hospitals.
Yet strange men carrying them are lurking around, watching you.
Your daughter's being held hostage atop that department store, right?
You mumbled her name while glancing out the window,
and someone there is looking this way through binoculars.
I-I've been caught in a trap.
I got a call to come here with my daughter
to discuss my father's condition...
If you value your daughter's life, you'll kill Akabane!
If you wanna hate anyone, hate the man who just happened
to get stuck in the same room as your old man!
They plan to kill you, too.
Immediately after you kill Akabane.
They're those bank robbers, most likely.
Their plan is to silence their partner and place all the blame on you
by making it look like you worked at the bank as a spy for them.
Y-You can't be serious...
That's the story, based on what the inspector also said in the bathroom.
The doctors will be making their rounds. Please return to your rooms.
O-Oh no! Three minutes left! I have to go!
Dammit! Doesn't look like Genta and the others'll make it in time!
And I don't know how many of them are in here...
Got no choice!
Wow! Cream puffs! Let me have one, mister!
S-Stop!
Huh? There's a gun inside!
So cool!
Watch out!
That officer, too?!
You know better than that, kid!
Let me go!
H-Hey!
What's going on?!
It looks like they slipped on my ball!
Crap! There's another one!
Yeah? Did it go as planned?
No! It failed! Take the kid hostage and get—
Hey! Hello?!
You dumbass! I'm down here!
Look at the entrance to the hospital!
Hey, lady...
Yumiko-chan!
Is there a Yumiko-chan here?
Yeah, I'm Yumiko.
So was this lady the person you were with?
She's out cold, but should we tell her what Conan said to?
Yeah.
"The plan has failed! I'll contact you later! Leave the kid and scram!"
What do you think that means?
Him, too?
Daddy!
Daddy! Daddy!
Yumiko...
Yumiko!
Yumiko! Yumiko!
That hurts, Daddy!
Good for you!
I contacted Inspector Megure and told him to come here,
so you'll be all right if you explain everything to him.
C'mon! Let's go, Conan!
Aren't you going to teach us to play soccer?!
Yeah!
Wait, hold on!
Just who are you?
Conan Edogawa. A detective.
Let's go!
What happened to the ball, Conan-kun?
Could you tell me what room Kogoro Mouri is in? He has a broken leg.
Of course!
Let's go! Let's go! Yoko-san! Yoko-chan!
Yoko-chan! You're the best!
Mouri-san is in Room—
- No, that's alright.
- Yoko! Yoko! Yoko!
Yoko! Yoko! Yoko! Yoko!
Yoko! Yoko! Yoko!
Dad!
I sprained my foot! Call a doctor!
Whatever!
Doctor!
The Fox is out to kill you?!
Look out!
Those are bullets! Stay down!
Allow the great Kogoro Mouri to catch the deadly Fox
that's given the police so much trouble!
Something's not right!
There's something more to this guy!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Knife
Next time, "traverse"! The Japanese word is written like "running longitudinally"!
It just means simple mountain climbing though.