A racing second hand, a shooting comet!
Conan's logic is good medicine
for hearts tired by modern society!
Today's case is a "traverse"!
Look it up and you'll find a zigzag hike!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Created by
Gosho Aoyama
"Detective Conan"
Serialized in Shogakukan's
"Weekly Shonen Sunday"
Planning
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Character Design
Masatomo Sudo
Art Director
Yukihiro Shibutani
Art Design
Hiroyuki Mitsumoto
Director of Photography
Takahisa Ogawa
Sound Director
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
Music Producer
Hiroki Horio
(PolyGram)
Music
Katsuo Ono
Opening Theme
"Nazo"
Performed by
Lyrics
Music
Arrangement
Miho Komatsu
Hirohito Furui
(Spoonful/Zain Records)
Editor
Teramitsu Okada
Story Editor
Jun'ichi Iioka
Color Key
Reiko Hirayama
Executive Producer
Satoshi Yokoyama
Planning Support
Toyohiko Okuyama
Mitome Asai
Director
Kenji Kodama
Producers
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Masahito Yoshioka
(Tokyo Movie)
"Bus Accident!
Kindergartener Killed! CEO Murdered!!"
The CEO of a quick-loan company was murdered,
and one child perished when a school bus was caught in the accident.
The man who ordered the murder has been arrested!
He appears to have had a debt-related grudge.
The murder was done by an unknown pro hitman known as the "Fox."
"The Fox was the Murderer!!"
Investigations have been futile, and his whereabouts are unknown.
I'm at the scene of the kindergartener's death six months ago.
The man responsible, the "Fox,"
is still at large, and the police—
Dad. You have a client.
Client!
Shut up... Don't yell...
He's already here.
Oof.
Sorry for showing up so suddenly.
Not at all...
F-Find the hitman and keep him from killing?!
I may not look it,
but I'm president of a Kansai real estate agency branch.
Bunzo Ushio (40)
Real Estate Branch President
When I underwent the company's health check five days ago,
they mistook a simple ulcer for stomach cancer!
I overheard the doctor and nurse,
so I was really shocked when I heard it was cancer!
So don't tell me you... hired a hitman to kill you?
Yes. The Fox.
Fox?!
But I only realized the mistake
after I used my various work contacts
to get in touch with him.
My money transfer had been deposited,
and his always-changing internet addresses had been closed out.
Even if I could contact him,
it wouldn't be until a month later—
basically, I can't contact him
while he's out to kill me!
I see. So that's why you came to the great Kogoro Mouri.
But are you being serious?
This isn't some hidden camera thing, is it?
What?! Are you saying you can't trust me?!
No, I do!
Look out!
Bullets! Stay down!
That damn Fox...
Damn! He got away!
It looks safe now.
Oh, man...
Oh! What a big wallet! What's this?
It's nothing!
What was that?
Damn. We gotta call the police.
No!
I hired a killer to kill me!
They wouldn't think too fondly of that!
No police!
Please! I beg you! I'll even pay for your windows!
Yeah, okay. I'll take the case.
Really, detective?!
Allow the great Kogoro Mouri to catch the deadly Fox
that's given the police so much trouble!
Great!
Whoa, are you sure about this?
But how are you gonna catch the Fox?
You don't know what he's like, right?
Don't worry about that!
The truth is, I included a condition with it!
I asked him to kill me while I'm on one of my beloved traverse trips!
Traverse?
You mean like a trek up a mountain ridge?
If it's to be during a traverse, then what was that attack just now?!
It's dangerous by the window. Let's talk over here.
R-Right.
There's definitely something more to this guy...
Tanbara Mountains
The next day, we set out on a traverse up the Tanbara Mountain ridge.
This feels great!
Take a picture, Conan-kun!
We're gonna run out of film before we even go hiking, Ran-neechan.
We'll be fine! Here, let's get one together!
Hey, Dad! Take our picture!
Ugh! We're not here for fun, you know!
Here, Dad!
You guys understand, right?!
Of course! We're here to make it look like you're an ordinary hiker!
Which means we'll seem suspicious
if we don't take pictures!
Oh, right.
Oh, man...
Shortly after, we filled out the hiking forms at the office
at the base of the mountain.
They faxed the number of hikers
and their names to a mountain lodge
so they could prepare our meals
and such before we stayed the night.
Let's see... Here we go, the mountain lodge.
We're staying the night here.
It's a route for experts, so you better be ready!
You too, Ran-neechan!
Oh, what's with that tone?
Hey there! Is this your first time?
Ken'ichi Hirai (22)
Tohto University Hiking Club
I'm Hirai. I'm in my college's hiking club.
I come here every year.
So you can count on me!
Great! We appreciate the help!
Hey, now. He could be the Fox, you know!
I'm Ran! Oh, and this is my little brother, Conan!
Oh, uhh...
And this is my father!
I'm from Tokyo. My name's Mouri—
Moriyama!
I'm Ushio, from Kansai! Good to know you!
Nice to meet you!
Well then, let's all go cheerily!
I work for a real estate agency. How about you?
Wataru Takanashi (50)
Company Exec
W-What does it matter?!
Given these clouds, the weather might change.
I'll give the mountain lodge a call.
Does he have a thing for you?!
The Fox is apparently left-handed.
He's thrown all his knives with his left hand.
Take a look at that man there.
He's left-handed!
So he is!
Oh, Gramps? This is Hirai.
I'll be staying again tonight!
Umm, Moriyama-san, was it? Have we met somewhere before?
Shingo Nose (35)
Novelist
I'm Shingo Nose. I write novels.
Oh, the Shingo Nose-san who wrote "The Beautiful Amnesiac Case"?!
Oh, wow! I'm so happy to meet one of my very few readers!
You read it too, didn't you, Conan-kun?
Y-Yeah.
It was about a killer with amnesia,
if I'm not mistaken.
I recall the trick being pretty lame...
We haven't missed the check-in time, have we?!
Please add us to the list, too!
Looks like it's gonna be a pretty big group...
Kyoko Saegusa (25)
Hiker
We don't know the way, so I hope you don't mind us coming along.
No, not at all!
Come to think of it, we don't know the Fox's gender for sure.
It could be a woman!
Sorry to keep you waiting! I'm Kawabe! It's nice to meet you!
Akira Kawabe (28)
Hiker
And so the traverse began.
Assuming the Fox is going to strike in this limited time and space,
he's either waiting in the mountains for his chance, like a guerilla,
or he's one of the hikers.
In short, there's a good chance
one of the other five people is the Fox!
Be careful, it's slippery here!
There you go.
Please hold onto the rope.
Watch out!
Are you all right, Ushio-san?!
How dare you...
W-What are you doing?!
You did that on purpose!
No! This snapped on its own! See!
It was all old and worn out.
Don't scare me like that!
T-That's my line!
When I consider the Fox being one of the traverse members...
...everyone seems a likely suspect!
Those two really seem suspicious.
Him, too.
He's been glaring like crazy this whole time.
He looks like he has something against Ushio-san.
Plus he was way ahead before,
but now he's with us...
Hey, you two.
Whatcha talkin' about? Are you people-watching?
N-No, we're just...
Nothing happened after that,
as we approached the final rest spot before our lodging for the night.
What?
Nothing... You just seem full of energy...
Of course I am! I'm in shape because of my karate training!
Want to try out a leg technique?
No, that's okay.
Say, where's that college guy?
Probably taking a rest somewhere.
Or he ran off 'cause his cover got blown!
Shh! Ushio-san!
They said the cover's been blown!
Keep quiet! Let's go!
There seems to be something to those two...
H-Help! Someone!
Hurry! Someone!
What's going on?!
D-Down there!
Down there...
Hirai-san!
W-Why?!
Why? Why Hirai-san...
So it wasn't him?
You did this!
You threw him over, didn't you?!
L-Let go! Don't touch me!
Stop!
Shouldn't we hurry down there and take a look?
Oh, right!
Poor guy...
He had to have died instantly...
Hey, you. Don't be wandering around. It's dangerous.
A knife! There's a little blood on it!
What?! A knife?! D-Don't tell me the Fox did this!
But he doesn't have any stab marks...
This mark!
Ah!
Look! This cut looks like the knife grazed him!
And the fact that the knife is lying there...
...means he dodged a knife the killer threw...
...but he lost his footing and fell off the cliff...
So he intended to kill him?
You! Where've you been?!
I've been around.
The hell you have!
I went on ahead, but came back
when I heard screaming.
I mean, those guys seem pretty fishy if you ask me...
What?! Them?!
Screw this! These people are nothing but trouble!
Let's get going!
Hold it! We're all going to wait
at the mountain lodge!
I must ask you all to stay with us until the police arrive.
Screw that! W-What gives you the right to do that?!
Whoever leaves a murder scene will seem all the more suspicious.
Damn!
Moriyama-san. You seem quite accustomed to this. What's your job?
Oh, I, uh...
He's an office worker! Right, Dad?
Y-Yeah, that's right!
An office worker, huh?
He definitely doesn't look like it...
Rain!
Let's hurry!
Yes! It's getting dark!
Jukichi Iwata (60)
Cabin Manager
Dry yourselves off. You'll filthy up the cabin.
Are you the manager of this cabin, old man?
Yes. Come inside, already! You'll catch cold!
Whew...
I'm exhausted...
Dad. Aren't you going to call?
Oh, right.
I'm gonna use the phone, mister.
What the—I'm not even getting a tone! Umm—
The lines probably got knocked out during all that lightning earlier...
Happens all the time.
Now what? It's raining, it's night...
It's dangerous to go down mountains at night! I'd advise against it!
Not to mention this is the summit. There are no other cabins nearby.
Meaning we're pretty much completely isolated.
You can't be serious!
What the hell?! I can't believe we're trapped in here with a murderer!
Murderer?
One of our companions was murdered in a fake accident.
A fake accident?
Tarnishing these mountains like that... how shameful!
Anyway, the killer could be in this very room.
Who knows? Maybe it was you, Ushio-san.
S-Say what?!
It's common sense in mysteries that the killer is the least likely person.
Rubbish! I'm starving! Food!
Rice
This... is dinner?
What do you want? We're in the mountains.
H-Huh?
What's wrong?
Oh, nothing.
What is this feeling of strangeness?
Something's not right!
What could it be?!
What do you think's wrong with Takanashi-san?
He knows what he's done.
You really did...
N-No!
D-Don't kill us!
What nonsense! Everyone carries hunting knives when hiking!
T-That's true, but...
I remember now! Moriyama-san!
You're Mouri Kogoro-san, the great detective, aren't you?!
D-Detective?!
D-Don't tell me...
What's with the false name? Are you on some sorta case?
Personal reasons? Or... could it have to do with this murder?
Sheesh! How long is it going to rain?
What's the forecast got in store?
You can tell me in secret. C'mon.
Now for the next news item.
This morning, Tanaka Yoro, 60,
was fatally stabbed in Tanbara Village,
and the suspects may have fled into the Tanbara Mountains.
Police and fire departments have a 50-man team searching the area.
Oh, come on! I can't sleep like this!
Look out!
What the—?!
Dad?!
Someone just left!
What's going on?
Takanashi-san is gone!
I knew it was him!
Damn you! You can't get away from us!
Be careful! You're the one he's after!
Let's go!
Someone!
Takanashi-san!
What was that?
Help! Help me!
H-H-Help!
H-Help me!
Watch out, Conan!
It's the Fox!
Wait! Something's not right!
T-The ceiling's falling!
The walls are closing in! I'm scared! I'm scared!
Help me!
H-Huh?
I think he might have claustrophobia.
Claustrophobia?
Meaning that's why he rushed out of the cabin?
Yeah. And he came here to avoid the rain,
but then it happened again.
Which means he's...
...not the Fox...
Some land sharks once held me captive.
I got them mad when I refused to sell my land.
I've been afraid of cramped places ever since...
So that's also why you don't like the real estate guy!
Good call, kid.
But that means the Fox is still on the loose!
Which one of the other four is the hitman?!
That was Ran!
D-Don't tell me something's happened to Ran?!
The Fox is in this room.
And he's the one behind these murders!
C-Come again?!
The hitman?!
The Fox?!
Yes! The peerless hitman, the Fox,
the one behind these incidents...
...is you, the novelist, Shingo Nose!
R-Really?!
Damn you!
W-What are you doing?!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Mountain Lodge Guestbook
Next time, what a shock! Thunder rolls like falling rocks!
A fox goes "ko—n"!
Yes?