A racing second hand, a shining nebula!
Conan's logic is good medicine
for hearts tired by modern society!
Today's stage is on a mountain again!
The case is solved nicely in the fresh air!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Six months ago, the master hitman, the Fox,
murdered a man and vanished without a trace!
Surprisingly, Bunzo Ushio, president of a real estate company,
hired the Fox to kill himself.
Ran and I accompanied him with the old man,
who was hired to be his bodyguard, on a mountain traverse.
The five other hikers were Wataru Takanashi, the company exec,
Wataru Takanashi (50)
Company Exec
Ken'ichi Hirai, a member of his college hiking club,
Ken'ichi Hirai (22)
Tohto University Hiking Club
Shingo Nose (35)
Novelist
Shingo Nose, the novelist,
and the hikers Kyoko Saegusa and Akira Kawabe.
Kyoko Saegusa (25)
Hiker
Akira Kawabe (28)
There's a good chance that the Fox is one of these five!
Because Ushio-san had requested his death be during this traverse!
The first murder occurred!
Suspicion piled up about who did it!
And then it happened again!
Ran! I'm coming! Hang on!
Damn it! What the hell's going on?!
C-Conan-kun, Dad... It's terrible!
Ran-neechan...
R-Ran... You're... alright!
I thought you had been killed...
She's the one who's been killed!
Kyoko Saegusa-san!
What?!
W-What is this?! Why was she killed?!
Killed with a knife...
Don't tell me this was the Fox's second murder?!
K-Kyoko! Who?! Who killed you?!
Say! This knife is going diagonally left and down!
Meaning the killer was left-handed!
Just as I thought...
But why did she have to be killed?!
Ran-neechan! Was this lady all alone in the cabin?
I don't know. I'm not sure.
What do you mean, you're not sure?!
Weren't you in here?!
But everyone had split up to look outside...
That's right. Everyone went off
in different directions.
There's no way to know where everyone else was.
No one's got an alibi.
His left hand?
Wasn't Nose-san right-handed, though?
What on earth is going on?!
Who's doing this, and why?!
Very well. I'll tell you everything.
The truth is, among us is
a hitman known as the "Fox."
He's the one responsible for these murders.
C-Come again?!
The...
...Fox?!
Dad!
Detective! Is this wise?!
Two people have been killed. I can't keep it under wraps any more.
Yeah, this is the limit...
but it's still too early to assume the same person killed them both!
But, Detective!
Fear not.
I, the great Kogoro Mouri,
have figured out the Fox's identity.
You what?!
Really, Dad?!
That's amazing. The great Kogoro Mouri-san is truly impressive.
So, who's the infamous Fox, then?
The Fox is left-handed.
Judging from the angle of the knife in her body,
Saegusa-san's killer was also left-handed.
And there's one person here who's left-handed.
But I do believe the only left-handed person among us was Hirai-san,
who was killed yesterday, Mouri-san.
It would appear you have quite the observational skills, Nose-san.
I am a writer. Observation and curiosity are vital tools of the trade.
Might another vital tool be your left-handedness, which you're hiding?
What?!
There's no point hiding it.
You're most likely a lefty who learned to be right-handed, right?
Meaning you can use both. You're a switch-hitter.
There's no question that's the truth about Nose-san.
But...
Yes! The peerless Fox,
the one behind these incidents...
...is you, the novelist, Shingo Nose!
R-Really?!
What a shock! To think I'd be Fox, the killer!
Mouri-san. You'd make a better novelist than a detective.
Don't play innocent!
You write novels about hitmen!
Ones based on real experience!
Really?! This guy is really the Fox?!
Damn you!
What are you doing?! I-I can't breathe!
Ushio-san! Hold on! Violence isn't the answer!
Shut up!
I have... I have business with this guy!
H-Help!
Hey, now! This is bad! Ushio-san has lost it! He's gonna kill him!
I gotta stop him!
Huh?
Scraps of yarn... This color!
Hey, Ran-neechan.
What is it?
Do you really think it was the Fox who killed her?
Quit spouting your nonsense
when I'm busy like this!
Dad! You don't need to be so disparaging like that!
So, what do you mean, Conan-kun?
What I mean is, she may've been stabbed from behind with a left hand,
but couldn't she have been stabbed from the front, too?
What're you talking about?
You mean like this?
Here, Conan-kun. You'll be her.
O-Okay...
The killer stabbed her from behind like so.
Well? It could've been done with the right hand like this.
W-What? Get real!
But it wouldn't be very easy to stab her this way...
Meaning it wasn't unnatural
for the killer to be in that situation.
Look! There are yarn scraps caught around her fingernails!
This yarn's color...
What?!
That's it! Only one person has this color sweater and could stab her
without her being wary...
Oh, crap!
He's not here!
I-It's Kawabe?! He's the Fox?!
No, that can't be right!
The Fox is left-handed,
yet Kawabe-san is right-handed!
So why did he commit this murder?
Hey! Look! There are tons of 10,000-yen bills in this backpack!
And there's blood on them!
What?!
She didn't bleed very much,
so this must be someone else's!
But it's not that old... So whose is it?
The mystery seems to go ever deeper...
This could make for good writing!
Say, where'd Ushio-san go?
Huh? He was here just a minute ago.
He rushed out frantically only a moment ago!
You don't suppose he's trying to catch Kawabe-san?!
This is bad! Ushio-san is the Fox's target!
We can't leave him alone!
The old cabin manager is gone too!
What?!
You don't think Kawabe-san's taken him hostage?!
It's very possible. He knows a lot about the paths in this area...
You two stay here!
If he's gonna lead the way,
he wouldn't use the path we took, huh?
Meaning he's taking the path headed out of the prefecture!
Damn that Fox!
Yamanashi Prefecture
Do you wanna die, old man?! Walk! Come on!
What's that?!
A-An earthquake?!
Help! S-Someone!
Fox!
Oh no! That boulder's about to fall!
T-This is bad!
H-Help!
Mister! This!
Oh! Right!
Alright! Hurry!
Climb up!
Hurry! The boulder's gonna fall!
That was a close one...
We're saved...
Hey! Where's Ushio-san's group?!
Hey! Where are the other two?!
I-I don't know! The cabin manager pushed me down and ran off!
That the truth?!
I hope they went back to the cabin...
This mountain path's been torn up.
We'll have to go back to look for them anyway.
Case closed! The great Kogoro Mouri-sama is truly brilliant!
Whadya think now, Fox?!
Y-You got it all wrong! I'm not a hitman!
That's the hitman who's given the police so much trouble? It can't be!
In which case, who is he?
Still, where could Ushio-san have gone?
I caught the Fox; it's safe for him to come out now...
It's strange. The old man is still gone, too.
Where could they both be?
Hey! Where are they?! Where'd they go?!
Don't tell me you killed them both?!
I-I don't know! And I'm not the Fox!
Playing dumb won't help you now! Give it up and tell me everything!
Mr. Mouri! Look at this! Inside Kawabe-san's bag!
Look at all this money!
Blood! There's blood on it!
What?!
It looks like the blood on the 10,000-yen bills in Saegusa-san's bag!
Hey! What's the story?!
Mouri-san! Listen to this!
What is it?!
Given that the murdered Tanaka-san was a former mob boss,
it's possible this was the result of a strife between two gangs.
However, given that the man and woman forced Tanaka-san
into opening his safe so they could steal the 100 million yen inside,
it appears to have been a simple robbery-murder.
I see! So the male and female suspects
are you and Saegusa-san...
Given that they killed a mob boss, people might come after them.
That's why they were so afraid.
Then, the blood on the bills is...
Yeah. The blood of the person they robbed.
And he was also the one who murdered Saegusa-san, his accomplice.
Yeah! That's right! I killed Kyoko!
Because we thought you were after us! It's all your fault!
Say what?!
He probably thought the mob had hired you to follow and catch him.
So he panicked, and had a falling out with her!
Is that true?! Hey!
Yeah!
Then you're also the one who tried to kill me?!
Yeah! That's right!
It's too late now! Our only option is to turn ourselves in!
Don't be stupid. I'll take care of the guy following us.
Leave it to me!
I don't want to kill any more!
If you do that, I'll go to the police!
Sorry I snapped earlier, Kyoko.
Let's escape together!
I was going to be in danger if I didn't kill her first!
Damn it! We shouldn't have tried to hide in these mountains!
But I don't know who killed that college guy,
and I got nothing to do with this "Fox"!
Hold on, now! Then what about the Fox?!
That's the biggest question of all!
I can't imagine the Fox letting this chance slip by.
Slip...
Wait a minute! The fax machine!
Hey! There's a fax machine here, right?
What?
That's right! One for contacting the office!
It should be on a different line
than the public phone!
Yeah! If the lightning hasn't knocked it out...
...we can contact the police!
Well?!
No good, no good, no good!
Is our only choice to go down the mountain now?!
W-What the—?!
The phone line's been severed!
The phone line we thought had been knocked out
had been severed inside the cabin!
Why? Why?!
What?! What does this mean?!
Someone had cut the phone line...
Oh, Gramps? This is Hirai. I'll be staying again tonight!
That's right!
What's wrong?
"Mountain Lodge Guestbook"
This is it! There's a clue inside here!
"Ken'ichi Hirai"
Here it is!
Here, too!
Hirai-san really was a regular here.
Of course he was. He was a member
of his college hiking club.
If this is the reason Hirai-san was killed, then...
Now, then. Let's split up to look for Ushio-san and contact the police.
I'll stay here and watch him.
Not you! You will accompany me!
You still suspect me? Sheesh...
I just don't wanna get sunburned!
Today's a sizzling, after-storm day!
Quit talking like some girl!
Of course you're gonna get sunburned in the mountains!
Sunburned?
Yes! That's it!
That's what always seemed out of place!
Even though he manages a mountain cabin,
that old man doesn't have a tan at all!
Which means someone's disguised as him!
He's the Fox!
What?! That old man isn't the cabin manager?
How can you tell that?
The cabin manager should be really tan
from always being in the sun!
That's right, now that you mention it.
That old man had pale skin.
Does that mean the old man is the Fox?!
And Hirai-san's killer?
Yes. Hirai-san knew the real cabin manager.
If he came to the cabin, he would've known the Fox took his place.
That's why the Fox killed Hirai-san!
He must've heard Hirai-san call the cabin
while filling out the forms!
He knocked Hirai-san over a cliff on the way here,
then rushed ahead of us to cut the phone lines.
Then he waited for his target to arrive...
...disguised as the cabin manager,
someone more accustomed to the mountains than the guests!
Damn him! Pretending to be the manager!
Even if we know who the Fox is,
we still don't know where he is!
A gunshot!
Is it the Fox?!
Wait, Conan-kun!
The Fox is a professional killer!
He'd have planned an escape route
to get to safety before anyone else!
The quickest path down the mountain, in other words!
Around here!
A wallet?
Isn't this...
What's this?
It's nothing!
It's Ushio-san's wallet!
Is this a photo of his daughter?
"Takagi Kindergarten"
Takagi Kindergarten?
Wasn't that...
"Takagi Kindergarten"
"Kindergartener Killed in Accident!"
"Chisato Ushio-chan (5)"
That damn Fox...
That's it! Now I see!
Never thought your suicidal target would attack back, did you?!
W-What's going on?!
He wants revenge for his beloved daughter's death!
Remember that quick-loan company CEO
you killed six months ago?!
A school bus got caught in the accident
and a kindergartener died!
A kindergartener?
Don't pretend you've forgotten!
You killed my one and only daughter!
But you didn't know the Fox's face or identity.
With no other choice, you made yourself a target and hired old Mouri
as a way to lure him out, right?
Even the sniper was probably—
That's right! I had an associate do it!
To get the detective out here!
The guy I ran after was that Kawabe kid!
But to my surprise, the old man
he had hostage pushed him and ran!
It was suddenly very clear
who the professional killer was!
We finally meet...
Die, Fox!
Stop!
That's nothing at all,
compared to Chisato's suffering!
Time to die, Fox! I'll kill you slowly and painfully!
Don't shoot! Doing that won't bring Chisato-chan back!
If you kill him, you'll be a murderer, too!
Do you think Chisato-chan would be happy about that?!
Chisato...
Chisato!
Quit being a sore loser!
Fox! So here you are!
Hi, fake manager. So you're the Fox, huh?
He's definitely the Fox!
Not so fast!
How do you like Kogoro Mouri-sama's—
Huh?! What's this?
No way!
The Fox was still a young man!
The real cabin manager
was being held in a nearby cave.
Eventually, the police arrived,
and Fox the hitman and Kawabe-san the robber-murderer were arrested.
As was Ushio-san.
Boy. You're no ordinary kid.
I'm Conan Edogawa. A detective.
Now the case is closed!
Now to head home for a bath,
wild boar stew, and some beer!
Oh, Dad...
I guess he's no ordinary guy, either...
Stew sounds great!
A ghost?
I saw her! The Snow Woman in a white kimono!
Eh?! Makiko-san was found dead,
in her Snow Woman costume?!
You must not take that body away!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Sunblock lotion
Next time, there's a scary snow woman!
If you can't solve the case, you'll freeze!
Scary.