A racing second hand, a shooting comet!
Conan's logic is good medicine
for hearts tired by modern society!
Today is the legendary Snow Woman! A heart-chilling and sad case!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Created by
Gosho Aoyama
"Detective Conan"
Serialized in Shogakukan's
"Weekly Shonen Sunday"
Planning
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Character Design
Masatomo Sudo
Art Director
Yukihiro Shibutani
Art Design
Hiroyuki Mitsumoto
Director of Photography
Takahisa Ogawa
Sound Director
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
Music Producer
Hiroki Horio
(PolyGram)
Music
Katsuo Ono
Opening Theme
"Nazo"
Performed by
Lyrics
Music
Arrangement
Miho Komatsu
Hirohito Furui
(Spoonful/Zain Records)
Editor
Teramitsu Okada
Story Editor
Jun'ichi Iioka
Color Key
Reiko Hirayama
Executive Producer
Satoshi Yokoyama
Planning Support
Toyohiko Okuyama
Mitome Asai
Director
Kenji Kodama
Producers
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Masahito Yoshioka
(Tokyo Movie)
"Genbee Ski Lodge"
Though my body may die,
know that my spirit will someday be revived with the snow!
Love of the Snow Woman
To Be Continued
It's always such a powerful show!
W-What's this?
It's a mechanical doll.
Have some tea!
A doll, huh?
It's really well-made!
That's a rare thing you have!
The previous owners of this place left it behind.
Genbee Kitamura (65)
Lodge Owner
Kayo Kitamura (61)
Genbee's Wife
Were you watching the Snow Woman on TV?
Yes!
She was really scary!
But Snow Women aren't for real!
That's not true!
This area is famous for its Snow Woman sightings!
Who knows, maybe she'll even show up tonight!
Good evening!
Are we really staying here, Yoko?
How is this a "great inn"?
Akiko Kinoshita (26)
Actress
Yoko Asanuma (26)
But there's no other place to stay,
and the bus already left!
Welcome!
Hello! I made a reservation the other day!
Yes, yes! Akiko Kinoshita-san and Yoko Asanuma-san, yes?
Thank you for coming all this way!
Your skis have already arrived!
What?! Did you just say "Akiko Kinoshita-san"?!
Whoa! It's really you!
I was just watching
"Love of the Snow Woman" on TV!
Hey! It's Akiko Kinoshita-san, the actress! In the flesh!
I'm Kogoro Mouri, the detective!
Oh! That scene where you throw yourself into the lake was amazing!
You fell straight for the lake, like, "Whoosh!"
It was actually Yoko who did that dive, not me.
I'm a stuntwoman.
Oh, so you act out dangerous scenes
in the place of main actors?
Yoko is my exclusive stuntwoman.
My double, you could even say!
Umm, where might the restroom be?
It's so chilly outside...
Oh, the restroom is—
At the far end of the hall, on the left.
Does our room have a view of a persimmon tree?
Yes, just as you requested!
Let's hit the hay, Conan-kun.
Yeah.
Say, Ran-neechan. Yoko-san said this is her first time here, right?
So how did she know where the bathroom was?
Oh, you're so curious about everything, Conan-kun!
Aren't bathrooms usually always in the same general area?
Especially in older buildings like this!
I hope the weather is clear tomorrow!
T-The Snow Woman!
Conan-kun! The Snow Woman!
What? The Snow Woman?
There's no one out there.
That can't be! I saw her!
I know I saw her!
What's all the commotion?
Dad! I saw the Snow Woman!
The Snow Woman?!
No one's out there.
You were just so afraid of the Snow Woman
that a pile of snow looked like her to you!
Really? It was just my imagination?
Yes! I'll be back tomorrow evening!
So I'd like to schedule a body massage and a facial!
Great! Thank you!
Akiko-san. Don't forget these.
Oh, right!
You almost look like a bank robber gang!
Actresses can't afford to be sunburned.
Move! Look out!
Coming through!
Oh! There's Yoko-san and Akiko-san!
Mountain weather sure changes fast.
This snow came out of nowhere.
Oh, Yoko-san! Are you by yourself?
Yes. Akiko-san wanted to ski for a little bit longer.
Akiko-san sure is full of power!
No, she pretends to be full of energy...
...but she's actually not well.
See you later!
Akiko-san not being well... Is she sick somehow?
Yeah. I'm concerned.
I'm back!
Has Yoko returned yet?
Yes! Just now!
Do you suppose she caught a cold?
You're a real life-saver!
Not at all!
That was a delicious meal!
Akiko-san was coughing. Is she all right?
Yes. She doesn't seem to have an appetite, though.
She's resting now.
Miss! Can we use the bath?
Yes, go right ahead! You have it to yourselves until 8:00!
Okay!
You can take a bath after 8:00, Ran-chan!
And you have the men's bath all to yourselves!
Akiko-san. Are you all right?
You really should see a doctor.
Yes, I'll do that. I think I'll get out for now.
Okay. I think I'll stay in a little longer.
Mouri-san! Are you there?
Yes!
What do you say to having an after-bath drink?
I-I'd love to!
Oh, so they're making it into a play?
Yes! It received such critical acclaim!
Just like on TV, Akiko-san's going to play the main character!
I assume you're going to be in it too?!
Yes, but of course! Please come and watch!
Here!
Of course I'll go to see you!
Oh, I guess there wasn't very much in here.
Hey, Conan. Go bring us some beer.
It's already 10:00. The owners are asleep now.
I have some whiskey in my room,
if you'd prefer that!
Oh, uhh...
Let's drink a little more! I'll go get it!
Dad!
Oh, come on!
Let's have fun tonight!
Oh? What about the whiskey?
Actually, it's apparently at the bottom of Akiko-san's suitcase,
so she said she'll bring it to us in a bit.
Akiko-san will?
Oh! Is that her?
Oh, I'll go check.
Thanks—
Not yet?
No, still not yet.
Oh! I think that is her now!
Thanks, Akiko-san!
The whiskey's here!
I had so much fun!
Me too!
Well, Ran-san. Go on ahead to the bath.
I'm going to check on Akiko-san real quick first.
Okay!
Huh?
What is it?
I don't seem to remember that doll being there when I looked earlier.
But it's there.
Uh oh! Did I drink a little too much?
Where could Yoko-san be?
T-That's...
...the Snow Woman!
You saw her?
I really did! She was wearing a white kimono!
Mouri-san! It's terrible! It's Akiko-san!
What about her?
Look at this! It's Akiko-san's will!
Will?!
"Will"
She was gone when I returned to our room!
I checked around the building, but I couldn't find her!
Then, when I checked our room closer, I found that!
Akiko-san has lung cancer?!
I don't know! But her strange coughing had her worried, too!
She says her father suffered from the same illness...
I heard he died of lung cancer...
She may have been secretly worried she had cancer too.
"I want to die as the Snow Woman..."
Then the Snow Woman I saw just now?!
It might've been Akiko-san!
Yoko-san. Contact the police right away.
It's very cold out! We need to find Akiko-san as quickly as possible!
Right!
Alright! We're going out to search, too! Get ready right away!
But, mister! Akiko-san made a beauty salon appointment!
Would someone committing suicide really schedule an appointment?
She probably decided to kill herself in the spur of the moment!
- Hey!
- Akiko-san!
- Where are you?!
- Please say something!
- Akiko-san!
Akiko-san!
The next morning,
Akiko-san was found dead,
wearing her Snow Woman costume.
Akiko-san! Akiko-san!
I guess there's no doubt
she is Akiko Kinoshita-san.
Thank you for your hard work.
And you are?
I'm Kogoro Mouri, a detective.
I was staying in the same lodge.
Detective Kawada
Mikkamachi Police
Oh! You're that famous detective?
I'm Kawada, of the Mikkamachi Police.
Actually, there was a sedative bottle lying next to Akiko-san.
Akiko-san brought the whiskey after 10:00 PM.
Meaning she committed suicide after then.
I think the Snow Woman I saw
was probably Akiko-san.
This is how the scene looked when we found her.
What the—?! Could it be?!
Since this was a suicide,
help from the Great Detective Mouri
probably won't be needed.
Signs that someone climbed up!
What are you doing, Conan-kun?
Say. Where is the previous owner of this lodge now?
Huh? The previous owner?
He lives in the next village over now.
Why do you ask?
There's something I'd like to ask him.
Huh?
This was no suicide! It was a murder!
And the killer was that person!
I'm going to send the body off for mandatory autopsy now.
Though it's pretty clear it's a suicide.
Oh no!
You must not take that body away!
Akiko Kinoshita-san's death was a murder, not a suicide!
Mouri-san! What evidence
do you have it was a murder?!
Detective Kawada.
Look closer at the photographs from when her body was found.
Akiko-san's hair is inside the collar of the kimono.
A person seeking out death wouldn't wear clothes so brazenly.
Someone changed her clothes.
W-Who?!
It was you, Yoko Asanuma-san!
Mouri-san! You know Akiko-san wasn't in a normal state of mind!
I doubt she worried about her hair
when putting on the kimono!
Detective Kawada.
Please look at the photographs.
It appears her body was buried quite deeply in the snow.
The snow started yesterday around 5:00 PM and ended around 8:00.
If Akiko-san had killed herself
after 10:00 last night,
her body wouldn't have been buried in that much snow.
And one other thing.
Look closely at Akiko-san's face.
She has a foundation on to prevent sunburn.
Would someone at night,
and someone about to commit suicide,
really put such a foundation on?
Yes, she does have foundation on!
Akiko-san was most likely given
the sedative without her realizing it.
And no one else but you could have done that, Yoko-san!
But, Mouri-san! You all saw Akiko-san last night!
What we saw was you acting as Akiko-san.
Acting?! What do you mean?!
You were the one who invited Akiko-san skiing
and booked a room here.
Why did you choose this place?
Because it would be easiest
to play two people at once here.
Two people at once?
You and Akiko-san share similar stature.
After killing her, you needed to make it appear she was still alive.
That's why you chose this lodge.
But isn't this Yoko-san's first time here?
Yoko-san.
You worked here part-time one winter
during your student days.
The previous owner remembered your name.
Yesterday, you gave her the sedative to knock her out.
You then put her in her Snow Woman outfit and left her outside.
Lucky for you, it had just started to snow.
But what you didn't count on
was the snow stopping soon after.
Ran. The Snow Woman you saw our first day here was Yoko-san.
She covered herself with a white kimono to keep from standing out
as she went to hide another kimono.
There were two Snow Woman outfits:
one for Akiko-san and one for Yoko-san, the stuntwoman.
She buried one of them in the snow in advance.
Then, the following day, yesterday evening to be precise,
she put it on the sleeping Akiko-san.
Then you returned here
as if nothing had happened.
But Akiko-san came back, too!
You disguised yourself as her
as soon as you returned to your room.
To make it seem like the dead Akiko-san was still quite alive.
You climbed to the roof via the persimmon tree outside your window.
As a stuntwoman, that would be simple to do.
You then put on Akiko-san's ski boots, which you had hidden,
and returned with her skis.
You also played the role of two people for us in the open-air bath.
You, if anyone, can imitate Akiko-san's voice.
The final touch was the Snow Woman
that Ran saw from the bath.
You were pretending to be Akiko-san as she strode off to die,
to make it look like she had committed suicide
and that she had still been alive at that point.
Then what about the whiskey she brought us?
Yes, that was another act of yours.
We never saw Akiko-san's face.
But I received the whiskey!
If Akiko-san was dead,
just who brought the whiskey?!
You chose this lodge for one other reason:
the mechanical doll.
You went to get the whiskey.
But you had the mechanical doll bring it.
Then, when I went to look,
the doll was nowhere to be seen.
But it wasn't my imagination;
the doll was actually behind me.
Thanks, Akiko-san!
You later returned the doll to its platform
when pretending to use the restroom.
In other words, you used the doll to fill in for Akiko-san.
Akiko-san's fingerprints should be missing from the bottle.
And that's more proof than anything that she no longer existed.
I... I drugged Akiko-san... and killed her.
I also wrote the will.
The part about her father's death was true,
but there was nothing wrong with her at all.
Then why?
I was always being outdone by her.
I made it to the final audition of my very first drama role,
and lost to Akiko-san!
It was always the same ever since!
I would always lose to her in the final audition!
She went on to become a star,
while all I ever heard was,
"You look like Akiko Kinoshita.
We don't want a copycat show."
When I thought I'd always be her double
as long as she was around...
It's the Snow Man! The Snow Man!
Oh! It's you, Sachiko-san!
The old guy fell asleep along the way?!
But he was awake until 9:00,
chatting with Sachiko-san!
Her alibi is airtight!
Wait a minute!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Candy
Next time, the old man's in big trouble!
That's why Mom ran out on him!
Yep.