A racing second hand, a shining comet!
Conan's logic is good medicine
for hearts tired by modern society!
The old guy goes on a date today!
All kinds of ripples are made!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Created by
Gosho Aoyama
"Detective Conan"
Serialized in Shogakukan's
"Weekly Shonen Sunday"
Planning
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Character Design
Masatomo Sudo
Art Director
Yukihiro Shibutani
Art Design
Hiroyuki Mitsumoto
Director of Photography
Takahisa Ogawa
Sound Director
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
Music Producer
Hiroki Horio
(PolyGram)
Music
Katsuo Ono
Opening Theme
"Nazo"
Performed by
Lyrics
Music
Arrangement
Miho Komatsu
Hirohito Furui
(Spoonful/Zain Records)
Editor
Teramitsu Okada
Story Editor
Jun'ichi Iioka
Color Key
Reiko Hirayama
Executive Producer
Satoshi Yokoyama
Planning Support
Toyohiko Okuyama
Mitome Asai
Director
Kenji Kodama
Producers
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Masahito Yoshioka
(Tokyo Movie)
Yum!
Ordering pizza was a good idea!
That's for sure! We can't eat dinners like this when Dad's around!
He sure knows how to be careless, though! He forgot everything!
He must've been really happy.
It's been 10 years since he's seen his friend, right?
Yeah. He said he was going to drink like crazy,
so he'll be back late tonight.
I'm really sorry!
Yeesh! What bad timing!
But I guess it is a company emergency.
We can get together another time soon. Bye!
Train #2 on the Tohto Loop Line will be arriving momentarily.
Please stand behind the yellow line for your safety.
It's still only 7:30?
I should've gone somewhere for more drinks.
Six stops until Beika Station...
"Beika"
"Beika"...
Just a second!
That was close. I almost missed my stop.
Candy?
Was I eating this before?
What a poetic sight!
Oh! It's you, Sachiko-san!
It's me, Mouri! Kogoro Mouri!
Remember? We've met in the Poirot shop below my office!
Oh, the great detective, Kogoro Mouri-san!
Sachiko Shimamura (31)
Import Company Manager
Yes! Come to think of it, isn't your apartment building near here?
8:00?
Whoops! I forgot my watch!
Say, Mouri-san! Would you like to go for a drive?
I know a place with a beautiful night view!
But it's no fun unless you go with someone else!
Won't you come with me?
Sounds great! Let's go!
Then I'll pull the car out!
Are you cramped?
You can pull the seat back.
There's a lever under the seat.
Thanks...
Huh?
I was working late by myself earlier,
but I came back to check on my roommate, who caught a cold.
Don't you need to go back to work, then?
It's alright!
Hearing your exploits as a great detective would be even more useful!
I'm so glad he had an emergency come up!
And the night is still young!
Sachiko Shimamura
Kazumi Takenaka
I had so much fun tonight!
I had a lot of fun, too!
Well, good night!
Good night!
Huh?
Is something the matter?
The door... It's unlocked...
Kazumi Takenaka (29)
Attendant
The deceased is Kazumi Takenaka-san, a 29 year-old attendant.
Mouri-san and her roommate Sachiko Shimamura-san found her.
Judging from the rigor mortis of her lower jaw and neck,
she died approximately two-and-a-half hours ago, around 9:00 PM.
Still...
Mouri-kun! What are those two doing here?!
Sorry about that!
I called to let them know,
and they came here on their own!
What was Dad doing in a girl's home?!
This is Sachiko-san's room.
It connects to the victim's room
via dining room and kitchen.
"Sachiko Shimamura"
"Kazumi Takenaka"
"Dining Room"
And, as you can see, this window is slightly open.
She says she might've forgotten to lock it.
Meaning the killer entered through this window?
But how would they get onto this balcony?
Inspector!
Wait! That's dangerous!
See! You can jump onto the balcony from the emergency stairs!
What do you think you're doing?!
The intruder probably didn't realize
Kazumi-san was sick in bed.
So, during a search for things of value in the kitchen,
the sound woke Kazumi-san,
and the thief stabbed her out of surprise!
And then the intruder escaped through the front door.
In other words, it was a robbery-murder!
It would seem so.
I'm sorry to ask, but where were you at around 9:00?
At that time, I was taking a drive with Mouri-san.
Eh?! With Mouri-kun?
Y-Yes, well...
But, Dad! Weren't you meeting a friend tonight?
I did meet him, but something came up, so we ended early.
So I returned to Beika Station, strolled around 2nd Street to sober up,
and then ran into Sachiko-san behind Beika Middle School,
as she was getting into her car!
Behind the middle school?
When was this?
Right at 8:00. Then we both went for a drive.
She knew a nice spot with a good view of the Tohto Bay Bridge,
and we arrived there at about 8:30.
We chatted for about an hour and a half
while we drank beer and juice
she bought from a vending machine,
and then left at around 10:10.
We stopped by her office for about five minutes,
and then arrived here at about 10:50.
That's when we found the body and contacted you.
Meaning you're her...
Yes! I'm witness to her alibi!
Still, what were you doing with Mouri-kun behind Beika Middle School?
I run a small import company in Akebono.
I was working late by myself tonight.
But I was worried about Kazumi,
since she was in bed with a cold,
so I came back to check on her at around 7:50.
Did you see Kazumi-san then?
I didn't really talk to her; she was fast asleep,
so I left her alone and went straight back to my car.
Say. Why did you park your car
behind the middle school?
Eh?
Why didn't you use the apartment building's parking lot?
Our parking lot is a two-level, top-bottom type, so it's a pain to use.
And I planned to return to my office right after.
Then couldn't you park in front of the apartment building?
I would have gotten in the way
of the buses that pass by the front.
"To Sachiko Shimamura"...
This is addressed to you.
Eh?
When did this package arrive?
I don't know...
Was it here when you came to check on Kazumi-san?
No, I don't remember.
Understood. We'll check with the delivery people tomorrow.
Something really bothers me...
Huh? The fish bones?
Not that. The reason Sachiko-san parked her car behind Beika Middle School.
Say, Dad.
What did you talk about for an hour and a half
at the Bay Bridge view point?!
And why did you go on a drive with her, anyway?!
Dad! Don't tell me you two—
W-What are you trying to say?!
I didn't do anything improper!
Then tell me what you talked about!
I don't remember everything we said!
Besides, halfway through—
Halfway through... what?!
No, uhh...
Dad!
The truth is, we only chatted for the first half hour.
I fell deep asleep after that.
You fell asleep?
Yeah. Drunkenness started to set in while I had those beers.
It was after 10:00 when she woke me up.
That's so funny! You fell asleep during a date!
Quit laughing! Sheesh!
That's why I didn't want to say anything!
He fell asleep halfway through?
But he was awake until 9:00, chatting with her.
The murder took place around 9:00. Her alibi is airtight.
Wait a minute!
Hey. You forgot your watch yesterday, right?
How did you know the time?
I saw the clock in the car.
What about before then?
There was a clock in the bar,
and I saw a clock at Shibahama Station.
What time was it?!
7:30.
7:30?
It's 15 minutes from Shibahama Station to Beika Station.
It's 10 minutes by foot from Beika Station to Beika Middle School.
Which means you ran into Sachiko-san at around...
I already told you! 8:00 exactly!
I heard the clock in a nearby house ring!
Now eat your damn food and go to school!
Okay!
He's right. I should just forget about it.
Three laps around the schoolyard is really exhausting!
I can't go on...
Just a little more! Hang in there, Genta!
Hey! Thinking about something you like makes it go quicker!
Something I like?
Alright! I'm gonna have boxed eel lunch tonight!
Boxed eel lunch! Boxed eel lunch! Tonight—
Wait, Genta! We're done now!
Oh no. He's too busy thinking about boxed eel lunches.
I bet he's going to do another lap!
Could it be?!
One trip around the Loop Line?!
Could you have fallen asleep after you got on at Shibahama Station?
A trip around the Loop Line takes an hour!
If you had gone around it once while you were asleep,
you would've reached Beika Station at 8:40 instead of 7:40!
Nonsense! I only slept for 15 minutes! I couldn't have looped around!
Then let's see for ourselves!
What?
Let's all ride the Loop Line tonight!
In the same train and train car leaving Shibahama Station at 7:30!
I guess that'll be fine...
Well, Dad? Remember anything?
No, I guess I was pretty out of it.
But she can't be the killer!
Let's just take a full trip around. Okay?
This is the furthest stop from Shibahama Station.
What is it? Do you know that man?
Candy!
He was sleeping with his mouth wide open yesterday...
...so he tossed a piece of candy in there!
What time was that?!
The same as today. Around 8:00.
Which means I arrived at Beika Station just before 9:00!
And that I ran into Sachiko-san at 9:00!
Real Time
False Time
Yes! You arrived at the Tohto Bay Bridge view point at 9:30!
Real Time
False Time
Then you chatted for 30 minutes, until 10:00!
Real Time
False Time
And then you woke up at 10:10!
You were wrong about sleeping for an hour and 10 minutes!
You only slept for 10 minutes!
In other words, she turned the clock back an hour
to use me for her alibi...
Last night, she parked her car in this out-of-the-way location
and left to kill the victim.
She entered through the window she had unlocked in advance,
made sound on purpose,
then killed the awoken victim to make it look like a robbery-murder.
After that, she returned here and ran into you.
Come to think of it, she...
Were they the bloodied clothes and gloves she used in the murder?!
If so, then she disposed of them at the view point while you slept.
She set the car clock an hour ahead before you got in.
Then, while you were asleep, she put it back to normal.
Damn it! How dare she toy with the great Kogoro Mouri?!
Was there anything else out of the ordinary?
The children saw Mouri-san?
Your alibi no longer holds.
You met Mouri-kun behind Beika Middle School just after the crime.
But isn't it possible the children mistook Mouri-san
for someone else who looks similar?
That possibility does exist.
Even if by some chance my alibi doesn't check out,
that doesn't mean that I killed Kazumi-san.
Yes, that's correct. But there is proof!
I leave it in your hands today, old guy!
Do you recognize this pen?
Yes. It's your pen, isn't it?
Dad!
Are you alright, Mouri-kun?!
Oh, geez! Do I have to do it after all?!
Let us go back to 8:30 PM two nights ago.
A deliveryman knocked on the door,
and Kazumi-san answered it.
However, she couldn't find her ink stamp.
With no other choice,
she decided to sign for it with a pen in the dining room.
But it wouldn't write.
Supposedly, the deliveryman said it might be the ink,
so he took the pen and looked inside.
Some ink was still left, and when she tried to write again, it worked.
When the deliveryman left, Kazumi-san placed the pen by the phone
and returned to her room to sleep.
Twenty minutes later...
Seeing your own pen lying next to her body
right after you killed her,
you instinctively picked it up and...
Oh! It's you, Sachiko-san!
Afterward, you invited me for a drive
and moved the clothes and gloves under the passenger seat
to under the back seat.
When you did, the pen in your pocket fell out.
You didn't seem to notice, but after I got into the passenger seat,
I dropped a pen from my suit, too.
I assume you can guess what happened next.
What I picked up was your pen instead of mine!
We found the fingerprints of you and Mouri-kun on this pen.
In addition, the fingerprints of the deliveryman were on the ink stick.
These fingerprints mean you entered the apartment after 8:30!
Isn't that right?
Kazumi was blackmailing me!
One year ago, I unknowingly imported and sold outlawed goods.
Kazumi knew this, and demanded
I pay her a set amount each month.
She threatened to tell the banks and cut off my financing if I said no,
so I did as she said.
But when I considered being blackmailed for the rest of my life...
You decided to kill her at once.
Yes.
When Mouri-san called out to me,
I thought I was already done for.
But I realized he thought it was an hour earlier than it really was
and decided to use that to my advantage.
But what did you plan to do for an alibi if he hadn't shown up?
I set a video camera in my office window
and recorded the pub across the street.
I planned to tell the police it was one of the customers leaving
at the time of the crime.
So you stopped by your office after your drive with Mouri-kun
to take down that video camera?
Yes. The rest is all as Mouri-san deduced.
I'm sorry for all the trouble.
Say. Can I ask you one thing?
You could've killed him after he fell asleep at the view point, right?
Conan-kun!
But you didn't. How come?
I don't hold anything against Mouri-san, after all.
This face... I've seen it somewhere long ago...
Come to think of it, you're always wearing glasses, Conan-kun.
Even when sleeping or taking a bath. Why?
I-I can't relax without them on.
.
Next Conan Special:
Next Conan's Hint: Actress
Next week is our first two-hour special!
Challenge the two mysteries!