Encounters are mysterious!
But cases are even more so!
I'm so glad to have met you!
Today's earthenware is second to none!
And the mystery is on the national treasure level!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
"Mouri Detective Agency"
Eh?! You got a call from Kikuemon?!
Yep! From the very man himself!
Who's Kikuemon again?
You've never heard of Kikuemon, the living national treasure?
He's a potter, Ran-neechan.
O-Oh, I thought he was a kabuki actor or something!
Geez...
So, what did someone so great want with you, Dad?
He said he'd give details when we meet.
He wants me to visit him in West Tama this Sunday with my family.
With your family? I guess it's not about hiring you, then.
No, there's no telling.
Being with the family might be a type of camouflage.
Camouflage?
To keep others from realizing I'm investigating a case.
He probably wanted to come here himself, but he is almost 80!
Oh! You're so good at reading into things, Dad!
Of course I am!
If Kikuemon-san is a living national treasure of pottery,
I'm a living national treasure of detectiving!
Yeah, that optimistic personality is on the national treasure level...
Wow! This color, this shape... it's a true masterpiece!
Just as I'd expect from the work of a living national treasure!
Please don't call me a national treasure.
Kikuemon (78)
(Real name: Mankichi Tsuchiya)
Ceramic Artist
I'm a person, not a thing.
Here you are!
Thank you!
Oh, this isn't much, but...
Oh, sponge cake! Wonderful! I just love it! Thank you!
So, what did you need to see me for?
Do you need me to see if your young wife is having an affair?
No, no. She's my son's wife.
She's been taking care of things for me for a while.
Sadly, my wife and son both died in a car accident two years ago.
I'm sorry to hear it...
I've asked you here for but one reason:
to ask the opinion of the great detective everyone is talking about!
I've noticed your deductions as of late have been so full of flaws!
F-Flaws?
That's right! For example, the case last month...
Now, now! Don't act haughty, Father!
Masuko Tsuchiya (42)
Kikuemon's son's wife
Just be honest and say you're a big fan of the great Kogoro Mouri-san!
M-Masuko-san!
He's a big fan?!
Yes!
He gets so excited whenever Mouri-san solves a case!
In fact, he just put up a big fuss
when I forgot to file an article from the other day about a case of his!
C-Come, now!
Okay, yeah, it's true!
Oh, he's here!
Wow! It's really him!
Who're those two?
My pupils. Let me introduce you.
Yoshihiko Arita (36)
Kikuemon's pupil
This is Arita-kun.
His skill has made leaps and bounds, and his work shows promise.
Hi!
Ryuichi Seto (35)
Kikuemon's pupil
On the other hand is Seto-kun.
His works have dropped in number, and he's stuck in a standstill.
I'm just in a slump, that's all!
That's what you get for always copying our master!
Aw, shut up!
Please, pull yourself together, Seto-san!
You're to be the sixth-generation Kikuemon, after all!
Sixth-generation?
The Kikuemon name has been passed down from master to pupil.
I'm the fifth.
Anyway, tell us what kind of pottery Detective Mouri chose!
Yeah!
Hold your horses! I still haven't told him!
What are they talking about?
I want you to have one of my works.
I could've brought one to your office,
but I wanted you to choose one for yourself.
Well, make your choice.
Any of the ones in this room.
Y-You're sure?
They're all masterpieces,
worth millions of yen each!
M-Millions?
Hold on, Dad. This is too generous.
Show some restraint, okay?
Yeah, I know.
In that case...
I guess I'll just choose this cup!
Just as I'd expect from a great detective! You have sharp eyes!
Looks like I win the bet!
Bet?
We all bet on what you would choose.
And, just as I expected you would, you chose that cup,
which is hailed the world over as a masterware!
It was just dumb luck...
Masterware indeed...
I never intended to give that away, but I don't mind in your case!
But, Father!
Oh, yes. I'd also like Mouri-san to see the Fusui-maru, my latest work.
Could you bring it from the storeroom?
Y-Yes. Right away.
Oh, come to think of it, I don't see Otani-kun...
Yes, he's by the kiln.
Perfect!
Mouri-san! Won't you come see the kiln?
Oh, sure.
Umm, about how much is that cup worth?
Hmm. If it had a price, it'd maybe go for about 10 million yen?
10 million?!
You're such a joker! You already knew that!
I shouldn't have made that bet...
It's worth 10 million...
T-That's a thousand 10,000 yen bills...
What a big kiln!
How is it going, Otani-kun?
Kaoru Otani (36)
Kikuemon's Pupil
Oh, I should be able to fire it before dinner.
Say, what is this pile of broken pieces?
The remains of pottery that the lady of the house demolished.
D-Demolished? By that woman?
Yes. Despite how she seems, she has a very sharp eye.
So, our master won't look at anything that doesn't meet her standards.
After all, she has the eyes that my son,
who was to be my successor,
fell in love with.
That's why I've left her in charge of deciding
who will succeed the Kikuemon name after I die.
But hasn't she been a bit strict lately?
You have it good! She only okayed two of my wares this month!
She hasn't okayed one of mine in three months...
I guess I'm at my limit now...
Any uncertainty in the heart soon shows up in earthenware.
Any pottery made with such feelings will also be bent out of shape.
Calm your mind like the water of a still lake, and it will naturally—
Hey! Was that her just now?!
It came from the storeroom...
I-It couldn't be!
The Fusui-maru!
I can't believe this!
I-I'm so sorry! It tumbled down when I went to climb the ladder!
U-Uhh, really, I didn't mean to...
No matter. All that has shape will someday break.
The Fusui-maru has simply returned to the earth.
You students can take care of this.
Masuko-san, you can start on the nice meal for Mouri-san.
R-Right.
I'm a tad exhausted. Please don't wake me until dinner.
This must be Otani's "everything gets broken" curse!
No, it's not!
Umm, do you need any help?
Oh, we'll clean up here.
You can relax in the living room.
I-I see.
What's this?
A marble?
I haven't had enough to drink! Keep it coming!
Is she a bad drunk?
Yes, her personality changes whenever she drinks!
But, is it really okay to accept something so valuable?
You don't need to act reserved!
He isn't long for this world, anyway! He can't make much anymore!
Isn't that right, Father?
M-Madam!
Now, now.
It's true, I'm up there in age.
I can only make two or three decent things a year now.
Huh? I seem to recall you exhibited 10 or so items last year...
Never mind pottery! Let's hear about some more of your cases!
Yes, good idea!
Then tell us about the Tsukikage Island case!
I wanna hear about the Kiri Tengu!
Then how about the incident that happened during my class reunion?
You just told us that one!
And the art museum one and magician one!
Let's see... That leaves...
Those were the only three that you actually solved while conscious...
Umm, you'll catch cold if you sleep here...
It's no use. She's not easily woken once she falls asleep drunk.
Oh well. I guess I'll carry her to her room.
Hey! Hurry back!
Yeah, I know!
After that, the party continued late into the night.
The seven people in the stateroom
forgot all their worries,
drank up, and made merry.
Little did we know that a horrible incident we'd never forget
would be waiting for us in a few hours' time...
What? It's already 8:00!
I hate to ask, but could you go wake Masuko-san?
I'd like to have some rice and tea.
Yes.
You slept here too, Ran-neechan?
Something wrong with that?
Mouri-san! It's morning! Mouri-san!
He's fast asleep...
It's only natural, Master.
After all, he is "Sleeping Kogoro"!
Yes, that's a good point!
Umm, her futon is empty...
That's odd. Where could she have gone this early in the morning?
Maybe she went to buy some things for breakfast?
Should we give her a call?
She did have a cell phone with her...
Yes, please do.
I can't have anything too heavy first thing in the morning.
That's strange. She's not answering.
W-What was that?!
It sounded like pottery breaking!
Hey, now! Don't tell me someone's inside the storeroom?!
K-Kid!
M-Madam!
She hanged herself just now!
She might survive if we get her down!
Hurry!
I'll get her legs! Otani, hold her steady!
Right!
I'll undo the rope!
Hurry!
Lay her down here!
We're too late! She's dead!
Master. Contact the police.
Yes.
That's strange! Those are missing, yet...
Could this mean...
The deceased is Masuko Tsuchiya-san, age 42.
The wife of the son of Kikuemon-san, the head of this house...
And you were all in the stateroom when you heard something break?
Y-Yes. We had partied late into the night yesterday.
She went to sleep first,
so I carried her to her room.
Her futon was empty when I went to wake her this morning.
Just before we went to look for her, we heard something break,
and when we rushed here, we found her...
The sound was of the pottery that's lying in pieces on the floor.
She had probably stood on it when hanging herself.
It's been trampled on quite a bit...
S-Sorry, Inspector. We stepped on it.
That little boy said she might live if we brought her down quickly...
H-Hold on!
What do you think you're doing?
And, soundly asleep as always despite just happening to be present...
is you again, Mouri-kun?!
P-Please don't shout. I have a hangover and my head is killing me...
This isn't funny!
Every place you go, there's a pile of dead bodies! Do you get it?!
I-I'm sorry?
Inspector. There are no signs that anyone climbed onto the beams.
That so?
That ladder doesn't reach to the roof beams, either;
something must've been tied to the end of the rope and thrown over.
And there seem to be plenty of things to tie to it here...
But would anyone use such important works of art?
The shelves don't hold just the master's work, but ours as well.
If she had used anything, it probably would've been ours.
Still, these certainly are immaculate...
We did spring cleaning not too long ago...
Which means the last remaining issue...
...is this open cut on her calf.
There seems to have been quite a lot of blood, too.
She probably messed up and fell to the floor the first time.
When she did, she cut her leg on a piece of the pot
but ignored it and tried again.
It's not uncommon for a noose to be so big that the head slips out,
or for a weak knot to come undone.
There's blood everywhere because she probably writhed around.
But I'm pretty sure we only heard one pot break...
Then her first attempt must've been while you were still asleep.
If the rope had come untied, it would've taken too long to fix it.
But why would she commit suicide?
She didn't seem like the type at all...
Can you think of any reasons?
She was drinking so happily just last night...
The Fusui-maru.
She most likely did this out of regret for breaking the Fusui-maru.
The poor woman...
Fusui-maru?
The master's latest pot, which was to be put on exhibition soon.
She broke it yesterday when she came to get it from the storeroom.
If she had been deeply troubled by it, then...
Then, it's not out of the question?
Yes, she had the motive and circumstances for this to be a suicide.
But...
Examiner.
Please compare the cut with the shapes of the broken pieces.
Yes, sir.
But the pieces have been trampled quite a lot,
so I can't say if any will match the cut...
A match would make this question go away, but...
Suicide! It's clearly a suicide!
Hey, now!
Ouch!
What's wrong, Conan-kun?!
I stepped on a broken piece...
What's with you? You aren't wearing anything on your feet...
I can't help it! I rushed here! That lady's the same way!
Come to think of it, I don't see her footwear anywhere...
But it's strange.
If she came barefoot, the bottoms of her feet should be dirty like mine.
Eh?!
Now that you mention it, the bottoms of her feet aren't dirty!
Oh! Then maybe someone carried her here?
Eh?!
Y-You're not saying...
She was murdered, then?!
If so, then that places the suspicion on all of you,
as you were in the nearby stateroom just before the body was found!
Could it be?!
Yes! This is it!
I finally found a trace that the killer failed to hide!
Using this method, you wouldn't need to be in the room to kill her!
Just what did you find?
Evidence that the killer failed to hide completely!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Lipstick
Next time, a pit in a place that can't be seen!
I ain't so sure about "can't be seen"...