Encounters are mysterious!
But cases are even more so!
I'm so glad I'm with you!
Today is the pottery case solution!
There are no cracks in Conan's logic!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Kikuemon-san, a potter and living national treasure,
invited me, Ran, and the old guy to his home in West Tama.
Before long, an incident occurred!
Masuko-san broke Kikuemon-san's latest work, the Fusui-maru!
That night, during a get-together, Masuko-san became very drunk.
The following morning in the storeroom...
...she was hanged to death!
Were you really all together in the stateroom?
Y-Yes. The only one who left was Otani, who went to wake her.
Right?
Eh?
Don't tell me you pretended to wake her and hung her in her sleep!
N-No! I was only gone for a moment!
Her room is only two over from the stateroom!
Is this true?
Yes.
I think he was gone for less than 10 seconds.
He couldn't have done anything in such a short time...
Did anyone else leave?
Well, I left for a short moment to call her.
We thought she had gone somewhere.
I didn't really leave, though;
I only called her cell phone from the phone in the connecting hallway.
That's strange. She's not answering.
Cell phone? Hers?
That's right. I had Masuko-san always carry a cell phone.
She was in charge of everything else,
so that we could focus on making our works.
What is "everything else"?
Things like business transactions and scheduling exhibitions.
So our master very rarely goes anywhere.
But that's odd. We didn't find a cell phone by her body.
Oh, a cell phone was found in the victim's room.
It was apparently under her futon...
Under her futon?
She always put it under her pillow and used it as an alarm clock.
The cell phone was apparently turned off.
I see. So that's why a call from just the other room wouldn't be heard.
So, did anyone else leave the room?
No, no one else.
No one...
Not that I know of.
Then who could have carried her in here and killed her?
Assuming she was found right after she was hanged,
everyone has an alibi of being in the stateroom.
That's what I'm saying! It was a suicide!
Her feet were bare because she was upset and about to kill herself,
and her feet weren't dirty because she used the stepping stones
between the house and the storeroom.
Plus, she had broken the Fusui-maru in this storeroom.
I can imagine her seeing the storeroom when she woke up
and walking in without too much thought.
That's true. The rope was used in this storeroom for packing things.
Plus we all heard the pot break at the same time.
In any case, we won't make any progress
until we examine the storeroom in more detail.
I ask that you all wait in the stateroom for the time being.
Please don't do anything without permission.
Suicide? Is that really what it was?
Still, too many things are out of the ordinary.
The open cut on her right leg...
Her unusual lack of footwear and the clean bottoms of her feet...
And...
...this marble I found by the broken Fusui-maru the day before...
And what's the other thing?!
Something I saw at the scene of the crime is bugging me!
Alright, you!
Oh, just a marble.
Only kids would be interested in junk like that.
Oh no!
Gimme a break, old guy!
Huh?! What the?!
Hold on, Conan-kun! Where do you think you're going?! Stop!
What's that?
Lipstick?
I didn't put it there...
What is lipstick doing here?
Wait a minute!
H-Hold on!
W-Wait! S-Stop!
Where are you going, Conan-kun?!
The thing that bugged me...
Could it be?!
What is it?
I forgot something.
Maybe so, but you can't just barge in here.
Huh? Where's the lady's body?
Taken to the police hospital.
Oh?
Yes! This is it!
I finally found a trace that the killer failed to hide!
The fact it's here means that up above is...
Just as I thought!
Using this method, you wouldn't need to be in the room to kill her!
But to ensure she would die, it would have to be around there...
Alright!
H-Hey! What are you doing! Come down!
I told you, I'm looking for something I forgot!
We just checked that area, but there was nothing out of the ordinary!
Now come down! It's dangerous!
Yeah. Doesn't seem to be anything but pottery here...
Interesting! That's a potter for you!
Come down this minute!
Okay!
Which means one of those two is the killer...
...but it's probably that one.
He laid a trap for her and killed her to make it look like a suicide...
And only he would still have proof of it on him!
Alright! I know who did it and how!
The question now is how to tell Inspector Megure...
Umm, how long do we have to stay in the stateroom?
Oh, I'm sorry! We'll still be a little while longer!
Could we get something to eat? We haven't eaten at all today...
I'd like to change clothes, too...
Oh, that should be fine, as long as you tell my men first!
No! If they do that, the evidence'll be gone!
Evidence?
Shut up, you stupid kid!
Dad!
Evidence, my butt! This was a suicide! There was no killer!
Right, Inspector?
Y-Yes...
Ouch...
Guess I'll just have to knock him out with this stun-gun wristwatch...
Say! I found the thing you were talking about earlier!
W-What thing?
You don't care if I say it out loud for everyone to hear?
Huh?!
Here, listen.
As I was saying, earlier, you told me...
Now I'll just put the button speaker on his collar...
Oh! You found it! Well done!
Hold on. Just what did you find?
Evidence that the killer failed to hide completely, of course!
K-Killer?! Are you saying?!
Yes. She didn't commit suicide at all. She was murdered.
By someone here, in fact.
Oh! This should be interesting!
It's an honor to watch the great Sleeping Kogoro at work firsthand!
Mori-kun! If the body was found right after she died,
these people couldn't possibly have done it!
Besides, you were the one who insisted it was a suicide!
That was a lie meant to throw the killer off guard.
Because we wouldn't want the evidence to be destroyed, after all.
Again, just what is this evidence?!
Blood, Inspector!
Blood?
Yeah! Kogoro-ojisan asked me to look for strange blood on the floor!
Strange blood?
See? He must've meant blood like this!
W-What is this?!
You carried the body over here, right?
Yes. We thought she might still be alive.
I had her arms and Seto had her legs
when we set her down in the corner.
Right?
Yeah.
If so, then this really is strange.
What's the deal with that blood?
I think blood dripped from the body when we were carrying it...
No, not all of the blood was from then.
It's hard to tell, since it's mixed with other blood,
but there's something else here.
S-Something else?
The shape that drops of human blood make
is pretty much determined by how far they fall.
The farther the fall, the larger the circle,
and the more developed the surrounding splatter is.
If you had carried her by her arms and legs,
the distance from her toenails to the floor was 50 cm at best.
However, these blood drops clearly fell more than a meter.
The fact that such blood is here...
Are you saying she was on top of this shelf?
But why?
Could it be?!
Yes. The killer had carried her to the top of the shelf last night...
...where she slept, with a rope around her neck, tied to the roof beam.
That way, when she woke in the morning, she would lose her balance,
fall from the shelf, and wind up hanging herself.
The loud sound right after she was hanged
was from the pots left directly below the noose.
Being hanged from that height would result in an almost instant death.
The broken pots would then look like a stepstool she had overturned.
Of course, this was also meant to hasten the body's discovery
and solidify the alibi of the killer inside the stateroom.
Then what about the cut on her right calf?
Look closely at the top of the shelf. Do you see a protruding nail?
Yes, I do.
When she lost her balance and fell, she likely cut her calf on that nail.
The blood landed on a different spot on the floor
probably because she had held on to the shelf for a few seconds.
Meaning she just happened to get the cut on her calf?
Yes. It wasn't part of the killer's plan.
He was probably quite shocked when he saw her cut.
But the killer would've quickly discovered the cause of it,
as well as the blood right by the shelf.
Even if the body swung, the shelf would still have been too far away.
Fearing his trick would be figured out if this blood was found,
the killer directed the others carrying her body to the blood
to try to hide it with new blood.
Isn't that right, the one who left last night's party
to carry her to the storeroom and set up this trick...
...Ryuichi Seto-san?!
S-Seto?! Don't tell me it was you?!
Hold on, now! I wasn't the only one who left during the party!
Besides, why would I do something so daring
with a great detective like you around?!
You had no other choice.
Because she had broken the Fusui-maru.
Wasn't it you who put a marble under the Fusui-maru
to make it easy to fall?
To make this murder look like a suicide that she committed
because of her own mishandling of things?!
I get it.
If she was in charge of selling these works,
she would've been the one who stored and removed them here.
So she was bound to drop it eventually.
Moreover, she fell asleep drunk during the party.
Last night was the perfect chance.
Please knock this off! You shouldn't blame me without any proof...
Actually, I believe you're still wearing the proof.
Now then, Inspector! Please lift up the back of his jacket!
What's this?!
Lipstick?!
That most likely got there while you were carrying her up the shelf.
You'd have to carry her on your shoulders to use the ladder, after all.
And then you returned to the stateroom, as if nothing had happened.
You had left the party to carry her here before she sobered up!
Have a look at the sitting cushions in the stateroom.
One has a bit of the lipstick he brought back with him.
Come on, now! Yes, this might be her lipstick.
But maybe she just happened to touch my back
while she was sleeping during the party.
I was drunk last night, so I don't really remember,
but can you say that isn't a possibility?
Oh?
You leave me no choice then. I'll show my trump card.
Hey, Conan! Show 'em what you found.
C-Conan-kun!
Here it is, mister!
Conan-kun! That's dangerous!
Huh?
W-What the?!
A cell phone!
What's this doing inside a pot?!
To make sure this murder worked as planned.
Even if she was atop a narrow shelf,
there'd be no guarantee she'd lose her balance.
But it'd be a different story if a phone under her pillow rang.
In that situation, most people would reach out without thinking.
Even more so if she used her cell phone as an alarm clock.
Yes. Seto-san placed that pot in the shelf directly under her
and had the cell phone in this special double-bottomed pot ring.
Checking the cell phone's number should make it immediately clear
that it belongs to Seto-san.
Tell me, detective. How did you know it was me?
Yes, I made the call. But Otani could have too when he left the room!
That's right.
I thought so too when Conan found the pot with the phone in it.
Then how?!
After all, when you tried to call her, you said this:
That's strange. She's not answering.
But her cell phone had been turned off when it was found.
The cell phone was apparently turned off.
In such cases, a cell phone would reply
by saying that it is either turned off or out of signal range.
My suspicion was confirmed once I remembered that.
My suspicion that when you called, you called a different number.
I see. I guess I should've said I couldn't get through to her phone.
But I can't believe you'd destroy Master's Fusui-maru to kill her!
That thing can turn to dust for all I care.
After all, it's a counterfeit copy I made of the real Fusui-maru.
C-Counterfeit?!
Yeah. The real one is stored in a different location.
Still, even though it broke, to think I could fool even her eyes...
My skill has really come far.
Though that's why she sold my works for high prices, of course.
H-High prices?!
You don't mean—?!
Yeah.
She took my works and sold them to rich, artistic know-nothings,
claiming they were Master's works!
W-What?!
By the time I realized it, she had already sold several dozen.
I questioned her about it, of course,
but she not only didn't apologize...
You should be thankful more than anything.
I'm actually selling the unoriginal junk that you make!
Wait, does that mean your recent slump was?
Yeah! It was on purpose!
I didn't want to harm Master's name any further...
But she threatened to kick me out
if I didn't keep making stuff!
I couldn't put up with it anymore, so...
Y-You fool!
Why didn't you tell Master about it?! Surely he—
I couldn't.
I couldn't tell him my fakes sold for more than his authentic works...
Let's go.
Oh! So that's the cup worth 10 million yen?!
I don't know. It doesn't seem that valuable to me...
Appearances don't always match what's on the inside.
Hot!
Gotcha!
In his case, his appearance does match what's on the inside...
F-First love?
Uh oh!
Asami-senpai was Shin'ichi's first love?
That's our lodge!
Oh no! Asami-senpai is...
Asami-senpai is...
still in there!
Senpai!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Lemon Pie
Next time...
When you think of first love,
what does it taste like?
Boxed eel lunch, of course!
Hey, now.