Encounters are mysterious!
But cases are even more so!
I'm so glad I'm with you!
Today's case is about the acting spirit!
Great actor versus great detective!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Kozaburo Hijikata, the historical drama actor, hired the old guy
and showed us to his home on the 5th floor of an apartment building.
While we were on the balcony, taking in the view,
the dead body of Isami, Kozaburo's wife, collapsed onto the balcony
of Hajime Okita, who lived next door!
Okita was home, but denies killing her.
Even so, the police and the old guy are convinced he did it.
But, having seen a smile on Hijikata's face instead of sadness,
I started to doubt it was Okita...
...and finally found the proof to flip the case completely upside-down!
There are a lot more here than I thought...
Conan! Go back to where Ran is!
Okay!
Conan-kun? Where are you, Conan-kun?
That's weird. Where could he be?
Umm, have you seen Conan-kun?
Maybe he's in my apartment?
Oh, right!
Just as I thought!
Conan-kun?
Huh? He's not here?
I guess he wouldn't be.
His shoes weren't at the door...
I've figured out the trick.
But there's still no proof.
I could probably corner Hijikata-san
by showing everyone this strange sight...
But I'd really prefer to have some definitive proof!
C'mon, Conan-kun. Are you really not here?
Damn. If only we had touched much more obvious stuff...
Huh? Wait. As I recall...
Yes! This is it!
And, given the old guy's personality, it should be around here...
No question about it! Hijikata-san is the killer!
He used this trick to deceive us
and lead us to this deceptive place!
Detective Mouri! Is it true there was a murder in this building?!
C'mon! You can tell us, Mouri-san!
I hear that the deceased is Isami Nagakura, the former actress,
and that you've been to the murder scene!
Well, Mouri-san?!
Now, now. I'd like to have a smoke first.
Inspector.
How do things look in there, Takagi-kun?
Mouri-san has the press' undivided attention by the front entrance.
The reporters at the back entrance have started to come to the front.
Good. Just as we planned.
While Mouri-kun has them distracted,
we'll bring the suspect, Okita-san, and the witness, Hijikata-san,
down from the 5th floor, and head to the station out the back door.
Yes, sir!
Oh! Mr. Detective!
Oh, Conan-kun! What is it?
Kogoro-ojisan said he has a favor to ask you!
You see...
Please, Mouri-san!
Tell us about the incident!
Seems fishy if you ask me!
I bet you don't know anything at all!
Alright! Fine!
I'll give you just one hint! Now come close!
Hajime Okita is the killer?!
The actor?!
This is still a secret! Don't let the inspector hear!
But you're certain, Mouri-san?!
You saw Isami-san collapse onto the balcony next door
from her husband's own balcony?!
And that balcony belongs to Hajime Okita, who lives on the 5th floor,
and when the police rushed in afterward,
both the body and Okita were there?!
That'd mean Hajime Okita was clearly the killer!
Yep, pretty much.
Alright! Big scoop!
This'll be tonight's top news!
It's me! Get a camera and newscaster here on the double!
We have a breaking story!
Hey, now!
Hold it!
N-No, that wasn't me...
Huh?
M-Mouri-san?!
Do you have more information?
And now to use this voice-changer to talk for him...
Yes, it would seem clear that Okita-san killed her,
but that isn't the case.
What do you mean?! Please explain, Mouri-san!
Alright! Hurry out the back door while Mouri-kun's distracting them!
Are you saying someone else killed her, Mouri-san?!
Yeah. The killer used a trick to fool my eyes into seeing it like that.
Isn't that right? The real killer, who's trying to sneak out the back...
...Kozaburo Hijikata-san!
What?!
It's Kozaburo Hijikata!
And Hajime Okita!
H-Hey, now! Hold on!
What's going on here, Inspector Megure?!
Is what Detective Mouri said true?!
Who do the police consider a suspect?!
Well?!
Mouri! Knock this off!
Besides, how could it be Hijikata-san?!
He was with you when you saw Isami-san fall over!
Plus, the fishing line used to strangle her
was found in Okita-san's apartment!
He was even in his 5th floor apartment,
where the body was found,
when the murder took place!
How could anyone else have carried the body into his room?!
Then the killer really is Hajime Okita?!
What was his motive?!
Don't tell us it had to do with his affair with Isami-san?!
No! I'm not at liberty to...!
We'll be questioning him soon about all of that.
Yes, given these circumstances,
Hijikata-san couldn't have done it,
and Okita-san clearly seems to be the killer.
Assuming the balcony we witnessed Isami-san fall onto
was really on the 5th floor, of course!
Come again?! What do you mean, Mouri-kun?!
Assuming the balcony we witnessed Isami-san fall onto
was really on the 5th floor, of course.
Come again?! What do you mean, Mouri-kun?!
Whose cell phone is that?! Turn it off!
It's mine, Inspector. It seems to have rung at the perfect time.
What nonsense is this?!
Are you saying your cell phone will help explain the incident?!
Yes. Please take it from my pants pocket.
One of your men is taking a look
at the unusual sight Hijikata-san created.
Yes? Hello?
Huh? Takagi? Takagi-kun?!
Why did you call Mouri-kun's phone?
Where are you, anyway?!
The living room in Hijikata-san's
extra apartment on the 6th floor...
...but it's strange.
What? It's strange?
It's the same. The TV, the sofa,
the curtains, the table...
Even their positions are the same...
It's all exactly identical to his
living room directly below this one!
E-Exactly identical?!
Yes.
The only difference is that the 5th floor room
has four cups filled with tea on the table,
but the 6th floor table is bare...
What is the meaning of this, Hijikata-san?
Why are your living rooms on the 5th and 6th floors exactly alike?
W-Well...
It was to fool me into thinking
that Isami-san collapsed on the 5th floor balcony, rather than the 6th.
What?!
Yes.
After he took me to his fake room on the 6th floor,
Hijikata-san had me wait in the living room
while he strangled Isami-san in the 5th floor room
and carried her to the 6th floor room
directly above Okita-san's.
He set things up so she would fall onto the balcony at the right time
and then returned to the living room,
pretending to have had a hard time preparing the tea.
He then invited me onto the balcony,
and, at just the right time, he used his cell phone's speed-dial button.
He had the sound of the phone next door attract our attention
so we would witness Isami-san falling onto the balcony.
He did it in such a way
that it looked like it had been
Okita-san's balcony one floor below!
But that can't be right. Her body really was in Okita-san's apartment.
Now, now. Hear me out, Inspector.
After that, Hijikata-san ran straight to the next-door apartment
and shouted and pounded on the door,
but without reply, of course.
That's because it wasn't Okita-san's apartment, but Hijikata-san's.
All the rooms on the 6th floor belong to Hijikata-san, actually.
Afterward, while I went downstairs to get the spare key,
Hijikata-san entered the room,
and used the rope he had prepared
to lower Isami-san to Okita-san's balcony below.
With rope?! H-How?!
He probably wrapped the rope under her arms,
lifted her over, lowered her down, swung her onto the balcony,
and then pulled the rope free.
As proof, her body has a scrape mark
from when he pulled the rope.
And the scrapes all over her body
are from when she was swung onto the balcony?
It was a dangerous and unreliable method,
but the balcony faces the river,
so the chance of being seen was slim,
plus, even if he accidentally dropped her,
he could explain it away by saying the killer threw her over
in the heat of the moment.
After lowering Isami-san's body,
Hijikata-san put the 6th floor room nameplate back to normal,
hurried to Okita-san's door one floor below,
and then nonchalantly waited for me to bring the spare key.
As if he had been waiting there the entire time.
But could he really lower the body, replace the plate, and all that
while you were getting the key?!
You could easily buy that much time by stopping the elevator above.
Hijikata-san probably did many test runs to figure out the timing.
But, Mouri-kun! You took the elevator when he first brought you here!
Why didn't you realize you were on the 6th floor?
The floor number display would've made it obvious right away!
Yes. From the moment I got on the elevator,
Hijikata-san's spell was already at work on me.
Eh? Spell?
Here, Inspector. Have a look at the elevator's floor number display.
There's still a little bit left...
Signs of the trick he used to lead me to his place of deception!
What's that black smudge?
It's most likely black marker ink
that he failed to wipe away!
He marked out the vertical line on the lower left
to make the 6 look like a 5!
I get it!
I wouldn't have thought of that!
Hold on, Mouri-kun! Then what about "2"?!
If it's as you say, then that'd make the number 2 look strange!
Yes. I was cleverly fooled there, too.
He gave us his business card inside the elevator,
while his back covered the floor buttons.
I see! That would direct your eyes to the cards,
and hide the floor buttons and display from view...
He probably wiped the ink off when he stopped the elevator.
My only chance to see the strange "2"
was when I went downstairs,
but I was in a hurry and there was no time for that.
Not so fast, detective.
You've been saying, "trick this, deception that,"
and claiming I'm some criminal.
Do you have proof that I killed Isami?
Proof that I took you to the 6th floor instead of the 5th?
But how do you explain that the living rooms on both floors
are exactly the same?
Oh? Is something wrong with that?
I happen to like that furniture and layout.
Before you accuse, could we see this infallible proof of yours?
Otherwise, this is nonsense.
Oh?
Your confidence must mean that you wiped away our fingerprints
from everything we might've touched in the 6th floor room!
What?!
I would surmise you wiped them away while I was downstairs,
and when you hurriedly took away the teacups in the 6th floor room.
Hurriedly took away?
Yeah.
The fact that Detective Takagi was able to enter the 6th floor room easily
means he made the grave blunder of forgetting to lock the door.
I already told you! Show some proof!
Inspector. Please confirm with Detective Takagi.
Ask if there's anything odd on the floor of the 6th floor living room.
T-The floor?!
Takagi-kun! Is there anything unusual on the floor?
Huh? Anything unusual?
There is something! A metallic, pointed thing.
A metallic, pointed thing?
In that case, please flip over the cushions of the nearby sofa.
Something I quickly hid should be there,
with my fingerprints on it!
I-Inspector! A model gun! There's a model gun under the cushion!
A model gun?!
What?!
Mouri-kun! You're certain your fingerprints are on this model gun?!
Yes.
Because I broke it while waiting for Hijikata-san in the living room.
I didn't have the courage to tell him,
so I hid it under the cushion.
Never did I imagine it would be the key to breaking the spell
of Hijikata-san's trick like this.
I assume you realize, Hijikata-san...
I was with you in Okita-san's room
the entire time after the murder,
and I was with Inspector Megure when I came down here.
In other words, unless I'd been in that 6th floor room from the start...
...I wouldn't have been able to touch that model gun.
Incidentally, the trick to making Isami-san fall over
was probably done by holding her up with fishing line over a rail,
and the line would break or come undone when the time came.
Inspector. Please inspect the room directly above Okita-san's.
Traces of his set-up might still be there.
Not "might." It's definitely still there.
The mechanism I used to make Isami's body fall on its own.
Then you admit to killing her, Hijikata-san?!
Yes, that's right!
It was I, Kozaburo Hijikata, who murdered my wife Isami!
She had to pay for getting together with this lowlife,
and I wanted the money to rebuild my film studio!
The money from her insurance, that is!
Stop that, all of you!
So, when did you figure it out, Detective?
It was the sound of Okita-san's phone.
It was different from what I heard on the balcony.
Huh? That's odd. I'm certain I prepared a phone with the same sound.
I just happened to buy a new one yesterday.
Oh. I have no luck.
Though, the main cause of your downfall was probably that
you underestimated Mouri-kun and had him witness your trick.
I never underestimated him.
It was a bet.
Had I been able to completely fool the great Mouri-san,
I would've made a great detective in my first modern drama role.
Dad! Dad!
That's the great detective Kogoro Mouri for you!
Mouri-san! How does it feel to have caught a historical drama actor?!
Oh, uhh...
I guess I feel like Toyama-no-Kin-san!
You're a real star!
This clown is such a pain!
W-What is this?
It's crazy, Dad! All the clocks in the house are ringing!
What?! The entire house?!
Even the VCR is running...
What exactly is going to happen?!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Postage stamp
Next time, there's lots of clocks!
The sound of bells is the scent of a case!
You mean "of lateness", don't you?
Yikes!