Encounters are mysterious!
But cases are even more so!
I'm so glad I'm with you!
Today's stage is a clock manor!
The case's alarms all ring together!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
"Dear Kogoro Mouri.
I'm sorry for the sudden letter.
Getting directly to the point,
I would like you, the great detective,
to solve the mysteries concerning strange events in my home.
It's actually an old mansion given to me by my grandfather,
who passed away very recently.
Since moving in, strange events have been occurring daily,
and I've even had the feeling that I'm being watched lately.
I tried to figure it out on my own, as I'm a simple mystery writer,
but seeing as I haven't been here long
and don't know the house well,
I figured I wouldn't discover anything on my own,
which is why I've sent you this letter."
"On his deathbed, my grandfather said the mansion was special,
which I find very strange now.
If you're interested, please come before 10:30 AM.
I look forward to hearing from you. Misao Nakamura."
I'm coming, Misao-chan!
I've deduced that she's a lonely, talented woman in her late 20s!
Are you sure? It sounded like some glum guy in his early 30s to me.
How dumb! Why would I rent a car and go there on a Sunday then?!
Couldn't you have told if it was a man or a woman on the phone?
I didn't call. I'm gonna show up and make an exciting entrance!
What do you want to excite this person for?!
He's such a lost cause...
What do you think, Conan-kun?
Is it a man or a woman?
I don't know. The handwriting is nice...
Maybe it is a woman?
Dad! That's dangerous!
S-Sorry! I messed up!
I haven't done this in a while!
Forgive me, Misao-chan!
No one can forgive this!
I think I'll take the train back.
What're you talking about?
That was a pleasant family drive!
You call that pleasant?
Just look at this refreshing sunlight coming through the leaves!
Doesn't it just relieve your mind?!
Yeah. I'm relieved we actually made it to our destination.
Whadya think? This large mansion is surrounded by trees and nature!
But..."It's so lonely for a single woman!"
"Misao-san! At long last, your Kogoro Mouri has arrived!"
I've recently started to understand why Mom left you...
Yeah...
Yes?
Oh, Mouri-san! You came!
Here, we can say hello inside!
Y-Yeah...
See! I told you!
Say. Did you send this letter?
No, the person who wrote that letter is my three-years-younger...
Your younger sister?!
My younger brother, Misao.
Hi, there!
Oh...
I'm the one who inherited this mansion,
but it's so big that I moved in with my brother.
What happened to your arm?
I hurt it while moving some shelves.
That's bad. Especially for a writer.
It's only a sprain. The doctor just went overboard and wrapped it up.
Anyways, come inside!
What is it, Conan-kun?
Doesn't this seem strange?
There's a tiger on that pillar, but not on this one.
It has weird holes instead...
Maybe they planned to put something there, but decided not to?
Hey.
Come in already.
Okay.
Let's go, Conan-kun.
Okay!
Wow! How cute!
What an amazing collection!
There are animals on almost all the furniture and dishes!
Oh! Is this a seal?!
Ran-neechan. That's a walrus.
Really?
All this junk everywhere makes the place stuffy...
Surprised? Our late grandfather absolutely loved animals!
He always used to say that animals that hunted to live
were much better than humans who fool others out of sheer greed.
Animals aside, there sure are a lot of clocks here...
But of course. Our grandfather was a clockmaker!
A clockmaker?
Yes. His name was Monjiro Izubuchi.
He made quite a name for himself;
"Monjiro's clocks last a lifetime,"
people came to say!
Then this digital bunny clock was his, too?
No, our grandfather only made screw-operated clocks.
He probably just collected those ones for fun.
I see. There's a crack on this digital clock.
He must've handled things he didn't make without much care.
See? This one, too. And this one.
That's strange. He always took great care of his things...
Doesn't this clock seem strange too?
It looks like something used to be attached to it...
It probably came off when he dropped it or something.
Huh?
Is this a photo of Monjiro-san?
Yes! It's from quite a long time ago, though.
Who's the girl with him?
Oh, that's his friend's granddaughter.
He always used to take me and my brother to the golf course.
Then this golf bag was Monjiro-san's?
"Demon"?
You know, it's what they call people who score over 100 in golf.
Our grandfather could never improve his score,
so we gave him that as a joke present.
Say, wasn't "Demons" the name of an old bandit gang?
You know, the gang that only stole from bad companies and people!
Don't be dumb. Those were the Goblins, not the Demons.
I'm sorry! I should've been helping!
Here it is again!
All the other cups have animals on their handles, but not this one.
And it's been carefully filed down afterwards.
If the animal had fallen off, it could've been easily glued back on.
So why?
Conan-kun.
Thanks.
I'll clean this up!
Oh, thanks...
So, could you tell me about these strange happenings you spoke of?
Oh, you mean the clock.
Clock?
10:48... Perfect timing...
Come to the study. I'll let you see for yourself.
Damn. It's stuck again.
Hey, have you forgotten? You gotta kick the bottom right part.
See?
Oh, right.
You leave the curtains shut,
even though it's so stifling in here?
It's like I mentioned in the letter.
It feels like someone's watching us.
So that's why.
There's a hole over here.
Oh, really? Well, this house is old and falling apart.
Only a tool could've made such a clean hole!
What in the world is it for?!
So, about this clock...
Oh, right. Let's see... It's a cuckoo-clock...
Huh?
Isn't this it?
Oh, yes! That's it!
Geez...
Looks like an ordinary cuckoo clock to me.
Is there something to it?
It rings at a certain time.
Of course it does. It's a cuckoo clock.
No, it happens at a weird time.
Every 10:50 or so.
And something strange comes out of it instead of a cuckoo.
Something strange?
Just watch!
Should be any time now!
Nothing's happening.
T-That's odd! It came out last time!
Are you sure it isn't just broken?
Of course it isn't!
Our grandfather's clocks are known for never breaking!
This is ridiculous. I'm going home.
W-Wait, Mouri-san! There's another strange thing that needs solving!
Please!
The VCR's timer has been set, too...
Let go! I told you, I'm leaving!
W-What is this?
It's crazy, Dad! All the clocks in the house are ringing!
T-The entire house?!
Even the VCR is running!
What in the world is going on here?!
All the clocks in the house are ringing?!
I-It stopped!
The video ran for only a minute, too.
But why?
What was that?!
A cat.
A big cat's taken up lodging in the attic and we can't get rid of it.
Anyway, think you can solve the mystery of the clocks
that all ring at the same time every day at 11:00 AM?
I dunno. Maybe it's just one of your grandfather's pranks?
But isn't it strange?
I'd use all the clocks in the house if I were going to pull a prank,
but it looks like only the digital clocks rang.
Only the digital clocks?
Yeah.
I checked. That cuckoo clock and this alarm clock were set to "off."
He's right! All the analog clocks are set to "off"!
Sure you guys didn't turn them off?
No! We decided not to touch anything
until this mystery is solved!
It wasn't just the clocks.
This VCR was running, too.
VCR?
Yeah.
Now I see!
Monjiro-san must've had a TV show he watched every day at 11:00!
That's why he set the alarms!
But don't you think he set too many alarms?
The old guy didn't wake easily.
Anyways, one look at the video and it'll all be clear!
"Play"
This TV isn't connected to an antenna!
It would seem not.
Why would you need to wake up
if you had the recorder on a timer?!
So why is this video on a timer?
Huh?
Look here, at the numbers!
There's a weird crack after the zero!
This digital clock has a crack, too!
See! In the same spot!
Oh, so does this one...
A-And this one...
Come to think of it,
that digital clock in the living room had a similar crack.
What is it, then?
Don't tell me this "110" was left behind by Monjiro-san as...
...a code.
What?!
Maybe!
If 110 is a code, it'd make sense that only the digital clocks rang.
On an analog clock, 11:00 would just be 11 o'clock.
But what could 110 be?
110 is the emergency police number...
And when you think of the police...
Yes?
That's it!
Dogs!
The police have police dogs!
This "110" means we have to find all the dogs in this house!
Alright! Let's split up and gather every dog in the living room!
One of the dogs has to be hiding something!
Collie, German Shepherd, Siberian Husky, Tosa, Doberman...
Dobermans are police dogs, but there's nothing here.
Maybe it's the Dalmatian?!
Remember the movie about those dogs?!
That was "101."
There might still be some other dogs. Keep looking.
Okay!
Dog, dog, dog...
The attic...
It's locked!
Now, now! There's nothing in that room!
And these stairs are dangerous!
There's no handrail!
Now come downstairs with me!
B-B-But there was someone in there!
It's the cat!
I'm sure the kitty would be sad if you hurt yourself.
I'm sorry.
Conan-kun. What do you say we check the study again?
'Kay...
No, those were human eyes!
Why is he trying to hide it?!
Conan-kun!
Conan-kun. Anything with a dog design. Got it?
Yeah.
It's strange. It's too strange!
There's gotta be something to this mansion!
"File 'Goblin'"...
You mean them?
Bandits of the Wind!
It is! These are articles about the Goblins, the Bandits of the Wind!
But why are these articles filed here?
The Goblins targeted corrupt businessmen's safes and illicit deals!
Because they were so swift, they were called the Bandits of the Wind
and they always left creepy goblin figures wherever they struck.
The name "Goblin" refers to the malicious European spirits
and familiars that would take up residence in homes.
They possess a bizarre form.
They've Stopped!? Mystery of the Goblins
It's been ten years since the Goblins ceased their activities.
Oh, so no one's been caught yet?
"Estimated to Have Eight Members! Leader Named 'Demon'"...
Demon?
That was the name on the golf bag...
Could it be?
A mirror?
Huh? It's attached to the desk! Why?
Say, there was a hole in the wall behind me...
And right above it is the cuckoo clock.
The hole in the wall.
The immobile mirror facing the hole.
And the cuckoo clock opposite it and above the hole...
Ran!
Ran! I'm coming!
What is it, Ran?!
T-There!
Demon figures...
Demons aren't animals! What are such creepy things doing there?
Those aren't just demons. They're goblins!
They're definitely what the Bandits of the Wind used to leave behind!
But why three of them?!
Just what kind of mystery are these three goblins hiding?!
Hey! Don't tell me those figures are...
What did you say?
Oh, nothing!
Ah.
Now I see what's going on here!
So that's it!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Door
Next time, I solve the mansion's mystery!
yōkan
It's actually azuki bean jelly.
Huh?