Encounters are mysterious!
But cases are even more so!
I'm so glad I'm with you!
Today is the mansion solution!
There's more than just a code here!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Created by
Gosho Aoyama
"Detective Conan"
Serialized in Shogakukan's
"Weekly Shonen Sunday"
Planning
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Character Design
Masatomo Sudo
Art Director
Yukihiro Shibutani
Art Design
Hiroyuki Mitsumoto
Director of Photography
Takahisa Ogawa
Sound Director
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
Music Producer
Hiroki Horio
(PolyGram)
Music
Katsuo Ono
Opening Theme
"Unmei no Roulette mawashite"
Performed by
Lyrics
Music
Arrangement
Izumi Sakai
Sei'ichiro Kuribayashi
Daisuke Ikeda
(B-GRAM RECORDS)
Editor
Teramitsu Okada
Story Editor
Jun'ichi Iioka
Color Key
Reiko Hirayama
Associate Producer
Satoshi Yokoyama
Planning Support
Toyohiko Okuyama
Mitome Asai
Director
Kenji Kodama
Producers
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Masahito Yoshioka
(Tokyo Movie)
The old guy received a letter from someone named Misao Nakamura,
asking him to solve the strange mysteries of an inherited mansion.
The mansion really was full of mysteries.
One handrail post by the front door
had a tiger sculpture on it.
The other post had strange holes in it.
The house was filled with clocks.
One clock had had something removed from it.
At exactly 11:00, all the digital clocks in the house rang.
The VCR's timer was set for exactly one minute.
All the digital clocks had a crack in the same spot.
It all seems to have been set up to convey something.
What's more, someone seemed to be hiding in the attic!
In the desk was a file filled with newspaper clippings
about the Goblins, a bandit gang that had disappeared 10 years ago.
Demon, the name of the Goblins' leader, was found on a golf bag.
Even stranger was the mirror affixed to the desk
and the hole in the wall directly below the cuckoo clock!
And what came out of the cuckoo clock at 1:10...
...were ghastly goblin figures!
Where is the key to solving these mysteries?!
Demon figures from the cuckoo clock...
Demons aren't animals!
What are such creepy things doing there?
Those aren't just demons.
They're definitely the goblin figures
the Bandits of the Wind used to leave behind!
But why three of them?!
Oh, that's it! That's the weird thing I saw the other day!
What?
L-Look!
There are letters on each of their heads!
Oh! What are these?!
The far right demon has "R"...
The middle one has "N"...
And the left demon has "L"...
If the "L" and "R" mean "left" and "right,"
what does the "N" in the middle mean?
North?
It stopped.
When did those demons start crying out?!
At exactly 1:10.
1:10... That's another "110"...
But it's strange.
When I saw those earlier, it was at 10:50!
Not 1:10, but 10:50?
Does that mean...
Hey! Don't tell me those figures were...
Those figures?!
What did you say?
Oh, nothing!
Ah.
Now I see what's going on here!
But I still can't figure out
what these strange signs and tricks Monjiro-san left behind mean!
The digital clocks and VCR all went off at 11:00...
The significant marks on all of the digital clocks' panels...
The cuckoo clock that suddenly went off at 1:10...
And the three goblins that came out of the clock...
...and the L, N, and R that were engraved on their foreheads...
What is the key to answering all these mysteries?
That's it!
What's what?
Didn't you notice it while looking for animals around the house?
I thought something was missing!
A lion!
I didn't see any at all! They should be really easy to design, too!
Don't be stupid! There were two big lions on the front door!
Oh? There were?
Seriously, if he collected all these animals, he wouldn't forget lions.
The lion is the king of the animals!
King?
What's going on?
What is it, Conan-kun?
Nothing! I just remembered something funny!
Weird kid.
If I'm right, it's truly a unique code!
But, wait.
If so, the letter O or the number 0 should've come out of the clock!
But L, N, and R came out.
Could the cuckoo clock's code be separate from the digital clocks'?
If so...
1:10... 110...
The L, N, and R on their heads...
A trio of goblins...
Trio... Three...
Triplets... Triplets?
The L, N, and R are triplets!
Wait a minute!
Could it be?!
Ah! I've got it completely figured out!
Conan-kun? Where are you?
Conan-kun!
Sheesh! Where did you go?
Where's your dad?
In the study, still figuring out the code.
At this rate, it's going to get dark soon.
Rushing won't help.
But...
The answer might come
if we think hard into the night!
I can't figure it out.
The digital clocks all went off at 11:00 AM.
There's a crack on all the digital panels after the digits "110"...
And the cuckoo clock rang at 1:10. Another "110."
They're all 110!
What does 110 mean?!
Is it the emergency police number after all?
Hey. Maybe it's time we give up and go home?
But it's strange.
It would've made more sense
to set the digital clocks to 1:10, too.
Hey, Dad.
Dad! Earth to Dad!
Shut up! If you wanna go home, then go home!
Don't get mad at me!
I guess it's late enough now.
110... 110... 11...
That's it! Stripes!
"11" refers to a striped pattern!
So if we check all the zebras in the house, we'll find something!
But wouldn't he have chosen 11:11 instead?
Plus, tigers have stripes, too.
Yeah. There are striped cats, too...
Say. Which are stronger, zebras or tigers?
Eh? Tigers, right?
Then tigers are the #1 animal?
Lions are probably #1, little boy.
Oh! Lions are?
No wonder they're called "king of all 60 beasts"!
60?
You're dumb. They're "king of all 100 beasts."
King of 100 beasts?!
hyaku jū no ō
Eh? King of 110?
hyaku-jū no ō
"King of all 100 Beasts"
That's it! I've figured it out!
This "1100" is a code referring to the king of all the beasts: the lion!
The mark between the zeroes
was trying to tell us to think of them as separate words!
Checking the lions will solve this mystery!
B-But I don't see any lions...
Monjiro-san probably got rid of all unrelated lions in the house
to keep them from distracting us!
So that's why some things seemed broken or scraped away!
Yup!
Then are the lions in question the ones on the front door?!
Yes! We should find something if we check them out!
Nothing seems strange about them.
It would seem not.
Besides, how do you explain that cuckoo clock?
"King" in Japanese starts with the letter "O."
T-True. "LNR" doesn't fit with the "king" thing.
Could it have meant something else?
That only appeared in the cuckoo clock.
It isn't out of the question...
...but then what? Is there yet another way to read 110?
It's 1:10, so if you split the 1 and 10...
One, "i," ten, "to"...
One, ten... One, "to"..."Hi," "to"...
Secluded Hot Spring (hitō)
Secluded hot spring?
Thread (ito)
Thread?
Ito (a last name)
Ito?
Yeah, Ito!
Did Monjiro-san know anyone named "Ito-san"?!
I don't know...
Then how about a Naito-san or a Saito-san?!
What's so funny?!
It's neat! Changing the first letter makes completely different names!
What's so neat about that?!
Come to think of it, those goblins had letters on their heads.
They all looked the same, too.
The L, N, and R on their heads...
And they looked the same?
Three similar words that start
with L, N, and R, followed by 110?
Yes!
That's it!
The cuckoo clock code was saying to put L, N, and R before "ight"!
It was saying, "Light! Night! Right!"
Something will happen if we shine a light on the right lion at night!
Amazing, Dad!
But you just shone light on it.
Yeah, huh?
Huh? What could that be?
See? Right behind the right lion!
What now?
It's not very obvious, but it looks like it opens up.
It does!
I see! If you shine the light through here...
Huh?
T-This is...
Hey, Ran. Close the door and shine the light through here.
Right!
The light is reflecting!
Oh! There's a mirror in the post!
Let's just follow the light!
It goes inside the mansion through a hole in the wall!
That's the hole in the study!
Alright! To the study!
Did you find anything?!
Just keep shining the light with the door closed!
Eh? Still?
What's that sound?
It's a bird this time!
Ah!
The light from outside reflects off the mirror on the desk
and shines on the cuckoo clock from below.
Is there a photometer inside?
Photometer (light detector)
It must be set up to only work at night,
so the sun won't set it off.
There's something on the bird...
A wristwatch?
Oh! That must be a present our grandfather left for me!
It sure is fancy, though! It's covered with gems!
If these are premium jewels, it could be worth billions of yen!
Of course! After all...
it's probably a stolen item that Demon, the leader of the Goblins,
secretly held on to!
Demon, the leader of the Goblins?
The person who lived here: Monjiro-san!
The figures that came out of the cuckoo clock
looked just like the goblin figures the bandit gang always left behind,
and it looks like he received a golf bag with the alias "Demon" on it!
And I don't think either of them are the Misao-san who sent the letter.
After all, the letter said this:
"I haven't been here long and don't know the house well.
I figured I wouldn't discover anything on my own."
Yet, they knew how to open the old door,
and they live here together.
Plus, he thought the cuckoo came out at 10:50 instead of 1:10.
This is because he didn't see the clock directly.
Instead, he looked through the hole and saw the clock in the mirror!
In short, when Misao-san mentioned being watched by someone...
that was referring to these two!
Besides, I think Misao-san is a woman.
What?
Here! Look at the stamp on this letter!
See the lipstick on the underside?
Oh! She licked it when sticking it on here...
But I'm sure you had this all figured out already!
Oh, uhh, yeah...
So, does that mean...?!
Impressive.
We're the remnants of the Goblins.
We came to get the last treasure our boss had held on to.
Held on to?
Yeah! When we disbanded, he gave us almost everything we stole,
but he kept the most valuable items all for himself.
And those would be the jewels on this watch?
He finally kicked the bucket,
so we decided to scour this house
he used to hole up in...
but there was someone already here.
I assume it was the real Misao-san,
who's locked in the attic now?
Yeah. When we tossed her up there,
she just kept wailing on
about how some great detective
would be here soon to get us.
And then you showed up at the perfect time,
so I pretended to be her to have you solve the code our boss left.
Now hand over the watch.
Hand it over quietly and I won't kill you.
Here you go.
B-Bastard!
What was that just now?
Don't move! Move and I snap her neck!
You idiot!
Don't do that!
A-A heel drop...
That scared me!
It did?
Alright! Let's contact the police!
After we contacted them,
the local police rushed to the scene.
Still knocked out, the criminal duo
was carried into ambulances,
and Misao-san was rescued from the attic, safe and sound.
Just as I thought, she was the girl in the photo with Monjiro-san.
I see.
So this was in the cuckoo clock?
Monjiro-san probably made the watch for you out of stolen jewels.
Nobody will know about it if you don't say anything...
But stolen goods are stolen goods. I can't accept it.
Besides, my grandfather has already given me
something more valuable than jewels.
Huh?
The mysteries scattered about this mansion.
For a mystery writer like me,
it's the greatest present!
Oh...
Still, it's a waste...
It's all right.
Who knows, maybe it was actually meant for whoever found it!
Then it's for me?!
Dad!
I don't think so, old guy.
That was most definitely a watch Monjiro-san made for Misao-san.
Look closely at the watch face.
It's stopped at 3:30. 330 can be read as "Misao."
Nakai-san!
That's...!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Express Bus
Next time, it's a scoop case!
Dad, who's that next to you in the photo?
Yikes!