Encounters are mysterious!
But cases are even more so!
I'm so glad I'm with you!
Luck and skill make a photo opportunity!
Pictures reveal everything!
He especially sees the truth today,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Created by
Gosho Aoyama
"Detective Conan"
Serialized in Shogakukan's
"Weekly Shonen Sunday"
Planning
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Character Design
Masatomo Sudo
Art Director
Yukihiro Shibutani
Art Design
Hiroyuki Mitsumoto
Director of Photography
Takahisa Ogawa
Sound Director
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
Music Producer
Hiroki Horio
(PolyGram)
Music
Katsuo Ono
Opening Theme
"Unmei no Roulette mawashite"
Performed by
Lyrics
Music
Arrangement
Izumi Sakai
Sei'ichiro Kuribayashi
Daisuke Ikeda
(B-GRAM RECORDS)
Editor
Teramitsu Okada
Story Editor
Jun'ichi Iioka
Color Key
Reiko Hirayama
Executive Producer
Satoshi Yokoyama
Planning Support
Toyohiko Okuyama
Mitome Asai
Director
Kenji Kodama
Producers
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Masahito Yoshioka
(Tokyo Movie)
Because I... no, the old guy, solved the case that day,
the client invited us to a famous award ceremony.
"35th Yomikiri Photography Award"
And now, for the announcement.
The winner of the 35th Yomikiri Photography Award...
...is Mr. Ryuichi Yanase's work, nominated by the News Branch!
Yes!
Thank you! I have God and sheer luck to thank for this award!
And a little bit of my skill.
This is that big of a ceremony?
Apparently it's the biggest one in this industry.
I hear each winner gets a contract with most major news outlets.
They're going to show his work!
The scene of a fire!
They definitely are photos of decisive moments!
It's an honor to be in the same room as the great Mouri-san!
A news photographer who chases incidents,
and a detective who solves them.
We're not so unrelated!
It's a pleasure.
Likewise!
Those were amazing photos! How did you take them?
Like I said, I have God to thank.
I just happened to pass by that fire at the time.
Yeah, "just happened." Sure.
What are you doing here?!
Uhh, who might you be?
You're Kogoro Mouri-san, yes?
"Akira Nakai, Investigative Reporter"
Here is my card.
Nice to meet you.
Nakai-san, an investigative reporter?
Yanase-san will be helping me quite a bit from now on.
You better quit it!
Sure that's wise?
What?!
What is this?!
To hell with you!
What was that white powder?
Was it drugs?!
It's just limestone.
Limestone?
What's the deal?
Dad! Answer the phone!
I can't talk right now!
I'll get it, Ran-neechan!
Hello, Mouri Detective Agency!
Yeah, this is Nakai. Get the detective.
He's asleep now.
What? He's asleep?!
Then wake him up!
I got something important to tell him! My life is in danger!
His life is in danger?!
Hold on!
Mister! Wake up! Mister!
I can't drink any more...
Sheesh. Guess I have no choice...
Hello. This is Kogoro Mouri.
Oh, about time! Took long enough!
What is this about your life being in danger?
Someone's out to get me.
If anything happens to me, investigate it.
What do you mean?
Just listen to me!
Nakai-san! What happened?! Nakai-san!
Hello?! Nakai-san! Hello?!
It couldn't be!
Mister! Wake up! Mister!
I already told you, I can't drink any more...
Damn! I have no choice!
Here it is! Nakai-san's business card!
Taxi!
Hurry here, Driver! My daddy ran out on me!
What?!
Alright! Leave it to me, kiddo!
C'mon! Hurry! Hurry!
Nakai-san!
That's...!
"Man on Fire Plummets"
"Man Falls While on Fire"
"Man Jumps to Avoid Fire"
It was just sheer luck.
I have God to thank, yet again.
For a news photographer, he is incredibly lucky.
Still, it's too much of a coincidence!
Well, Dad?
The investigative reporter Nakai-san was murdered, wasn't he?
It would seem not.
What do you mean, Dad?
He did suffer a blow to the head...
but the examiners believe he slipped and hit his head while drunk.
That can't be!
As a result, the police have deemed this an accident, not a crime.
What caused the fire?!
I don't know the details, but apparently it started in the kitchen sink.
Sink? Maybe a thrown-out cigarette lit something on fire?
Anyways, that was where the fire burned the most.
In either case, it would've been an unfortunate accident.
Conan-kun!
Forget about 'im.
Doing questioning first thing in the morning has me starved!
Let's get some grub!
No Entrance
The call meant for the old guy last night was at 10:30 PM.
I arrived here in the taxi at 10:50.
Judging from how the fire was,
it must've started right after the call.
Yanase, the photographer,
was taking pictures from there...
The only way up there is by car.
What's that?!
The highway bus drop-off point!
It's the same height as Nakai-san's apartment!
It's too perfect for someone who just happened to pass by!
Plus, it's only three minutes between here and there!
This powder...
Limestone!
Wait a minute! The fire started in the kitchen sink!
Could it be?!
This, please!
Okay!
This is it!
Oh! These are some great photos!
They really are from the decisive moment!
I want you to analyze them!
This one in particular! See the mirror far in the back?
Mirror?
Oh, this? Yeah, I see it!
The kitchen can be seen in it...
Oh, you're right.
Think you can zoom in on it and make it clearer?
I guess you can't if it's not film?
No, that's not true. Leave it to me!
Magazine found!
Yeah, you can't tell what's in the mirror...
Hold on, now. I'm just getting started.
Let's see. Yesterday's weather...
The time of the fire...
The positions of the moon and stars...
The fire's heat had about this much effect...
Whoa! You're good, Doc!
It's nothing out of the ordinary!
That's...!
Did you figure something out, Shin'ichi?
Yeah. It really was a murder!
Yanase, the photographer, did it!
Really?!
But this is still circumstantial evidence.
He could play dumb and that'd be it.
This Yanase guy is going to be on TV tomorrow. I saw an ad for it.
He's going to be on TV?!
People in the spotlight these days
all get their own shows.
And his guest is going to be Mouri-san!
The old guy?!
Which means this will be my last chance...
In the spotlight, huh... I'm so jealous!
Doc! Help me out!
You'll be in the spotlight, too!
What?! Really?!
Thanks for coming today, Mouri-san.
It's my pleasure.
A police ticket...
Yeah, I have to pay a fine.
Fine?
I must've gone over the speed limit when I saw smoke from the fire.
A surveillance camera caught me.
A photographer out to get a decisive moment
was caught at a decisive moment himself. It's hilarious!
Wait, don't tell me...
Conan-kun! Where are you going?
Hello? Metro Police? This is Kogoro Mouri.
Please get Inspector Megure immediately.
Mouri-san! It's time!
Now to show my cool side!
Mister! Come here a second!
What do you want? I'm busy...
There's something on your collar.
I'll get it for you!
Thanks.
The button speaker is attached! All set to go!
Hello, everyone. I'm Ryuichi Yanase.
Our guest for the first episode of Yanase World
is the great detective, Kogoro Mouri-san!
You're also known as Sleeping Kogoro,
which I'd like to ask about.
What's wrong, Mouri-san?
Oh, nothing.
I hate to be sudden, Yanase-san,
but I think I'd rather focus on the incident.
Huh?
You know, the one where you committed arson
and murdered Nakai-san, the investigative reporter?
C-Come again?!
This certainly comes as a surprise, but sure.
I'll humor you, if you'd like.
But your accusation was completely off, Mouri-san.
Let me ask this.
There's a happening in the very first episode!
Yeah! This is great! The battle of the century!
First of all, I was taking photos of the highway at the time.
How could I have possibly lit a fire inside Nakai-san's apartment?
Simple.
Using the exit point for passengers getting off the highway bus,
you could travel between the photo spot and the scene in 3 minutes.
You used that to enter his apartment and attack and knock him out.
You then set up an ignition timer and returned to the highway,
where you waited for the fire to start
so you could photograph it.
Oh? But no timing devices were found in the remnants of the fire.
Correct. Nothing was found. It must've burned away.
Then how can you make such a claim?
Limestone. Or, to be technical, quicklime.
"Quicklime"
It was the timing device you used.
Unlike slaked lime, which is used for drawing lines on fields,
"Slaked Lime"
when quicklime and water are combined,
a chemical reaction occurs
that exceeds 300 degrees Celsius.
Sake
Self-heating canned sake utilizes this effect.
Quicklime
Reaction Solution
Press Here
There are cases in which bags of quicklime left at construction sites
have ignited and caused fires after rainwater leaked inside.
This is what you used.
You placed quicklime in the sink and had water leak in and ignite it.
With some paper and flammable objects all around it,
you'd have a fire in no time.
This is probably how you took your award-winning photos as well.
But your victim found out and blackmailed you!
Most impressive!
It may be true that such a trick is possible, but you have no proof.
Proof as definitive as photographs.
But I do.
A photograph you took is definitive proof.
What?!
Dr. Agasa.
Nobody told me about this!
Doc?!
Now, then! Let me show you the definitive proof!
Here you are!
First, the kitchen faucet. Have a look at the handle.
This is the type where lowering the handle will produce water,
and it's one-fourth down here.
In other words, when the fire started, this water was running...
...in order to activate the igniter.
I don't know. It might've just been left on.
In that case, Yanase-san.
What happened to the watch you received for winning the contest?
I asked the head office.
Apparently, there's only one wristwatch like it in the world.
So why is it in the victim's kitchen?
Are you sure you didn't remove it
before adjusting the faucet
to keep it from getting wet,
but then accidentally left it there?
As it was quite close to the source of the fire, it was rather burned.
Sorry, but it was stolen from me.
Oh? When was it stolen?
Right after the award ceremony.
I just realized now that it was the late Nakai who stole it!
So you intend on playing innocent to the end?
In that case... Inspector!
V!
Jeez! V?!
This is data from the camera on the highway to catch speeders.
Detective Mouri asked me to bring it here.
It's from 10:20 PM, on the night of the incident.
In other words, it's from 10 minutes before the victim called me.
Doc. Can you display it on the computer monitor?
Piece of cake!
Now, zoom in, please.
Got it!
You claim your wristwatch was stolen right after the ceremony.
So why do you have it on right before photographing the fire?
The fact that wristwatch was in Nakai-san's apartment
is proof that you were there!
A photographer out to capture a definitive moment
was caught at a definitive moment himself.
This can't be...
It seems you forgot the most important fact for a photographer.
is written as "displaying the truth" in Japanese!
"Photograph"
"Displaying the Truth"
The staff said the ratings were through the roof!
Ironically enough, now I'm in the spotlight too!
Huh? Where's Dad?
Oh no! I forgot about him!
Hi!
I'm the great Kogoro Mouri!
Yoko Okino-chan! Where are you?!
Huh?!
Your sister was killed and buried in the yard?!
But it's illegal to enter others' yards without permission.
But is there really a body buried in this yard?!
What exactly does Koda-san plan to do?!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Jewel Robbery
Next time...
I'm a Moletian!
What?
M-Mole. See?
Don't even.