Encounters are mysterious!
But cases are even more so!
I'm so glad I'm with you!
Today is the mole solution!
People's feelings connect underground!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Created by
Gosho Aoyama
"Detective Conan"
Serialized in Shogakukan's
"Weekly Shonen Sunday"
Planning
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Character Design
Masatomo Sudo
Art Director
Yukihiro Shibutani
Art Design
Hiroyuki Mitsumoto
Director of Photography
Takahisa Ogawa
Sound Director
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
Music Producer
Hiroki Horio
(PolyGram)
Music
Katsuo Ono
Opening Theme
"Unmei no Roulette mawashite"
Performed by
Lyrics
Music
Arrangement
Izumi Sakai
Sei'ichiro Kuribayashi
Daisuke Ikeda
(B-GRAM RECORDS)
Editor
Teramitsu Okada
Story Editor
Jun'ichi Iioka
Color Key
Reiko Hirayama
Executive Producer
Hiroaki Kobayashi
Planning Support
Toyohiko Okuyama
Mitome Asai
Director
Kenji Kodama
Producers
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Masahito Yoshioka
(Tokyo Movie)
Genta, Mitsuhiko, Ayumi, and I were playing baseball
in the parking lot of an unfinished apartment building.
We went to get the ball after it landed in the yard next door,
but the house's owner, Yoshikazu Watanuki, sent us away.
Waiting for us back at the detective agency was Masao Koda,
who looked just like the Moletian from Kamen Yaiba.
He claimed that his missing sister had been killed by Watanuki
and buried somewhere in his yard, so he wanted help finding her.
But sneaking onto others' property and digging things up is illegal.
After his request was turned down,
Masao Koda left angrily.
But, convinced he would dig up the yard
while Watanuki was at the hospital, we continued our stakeout!
Just then, a jewel robbery took place!
And the robber was none other than Masao Koda!
Just what is his true objective?!
Saturday
What's taking the Moletian so long?
Come on, let's stop calling him that.
He only looks like one.
What? You're the one who first mentioned it!
It's him!
He really is a Moletian!
What do we do, Genta-kun?!
Let's have a look for now!
What's he doing?
Wasn't he going to dig up the yard?
Then should I lend him my shovel?
Wait. Let's watch a little longer...
If my theory is correct, Koda-san is...
Beika Central Hospital
What? No one called me?
That's right. We don't call patients about such things here.
Then who was that call from?
Take me to 1st Street in Beika! Hurry!
R-Right!
Genta-kun! This is Mitsuhiko! Do you read me?!
Team leader here! What's going on, Mitsuhiko?
Oh, brother. The old man just headed back there in a taxi!
Got it!
What now, Ayumi?
It might be best to let him know.
Hey! Mister! Watanuki-san is gonna be back soon!
He's gonna see you if you don't hurry and run!
Conan-kun!
Just as I thought!
What do you mean, Conan?
Koda-san is...
Hey! What the hell do you think you're doing?!
I'm about to prove what you did!
What?
Whoa! He punched the Moletian!
Get out! Get out this instant! That goes for you, too!
Yikes...
What's that?!
Something's sparkling!
Sanae's earring!
A glass shard...
Damn it!
I'll make the call for you, Mister.
You're turning yourself in, right?
I know an inspector there!
Inspector Megure, correct? I've been expecting you.
What is this, Koda-san?
Did you really commit a jewel robbery?
Yes. The jewels I stole are buried throughout Watanuki's yard.
I don't remember where I buried them,
so you'll have to dig up the yard to find them.
What?!
What are all those holes?!
Koda-san made them!
The jewels are buried in some of them!
So, you'll have to dig the whole yard up to find them all!
Koda-san!
Don't tell me you did the robbery to have the police dig up this yard?!
Then you never intended to escape from the start?!
Koda-san just wanted enough time to dig holes in the yard.
That's why he left a jewel on the station stairs
and made it look like he escaped by train!
This is the model gun I used in the robbery.
Yoshikazu Watanuki-san, correct?
Yes.
Mouri-kun there has told me about your incident with Koda-san.
Do you mind if we dig up your yard?
Y-You can't be serious! What gives you the right?!
It's absolutely necessary for the investigation of the jewel robbery.
Or is there some reason digging up your yard would be bad for you?
O-Of course not!
In that case... Takagi-kun! Contact headquarters!
Yes, sir!
Alright!
Good for you, Mister!
Yeah!
What's that smile for?! Don't tell me he...?!
The jewels are quite small! Dig everything up!
Inspector!
Only the jewels have turned up.
I don't think there are any bodies buried here...
That can't be!
Look harder!
We are looking hard!
Where else are we supposed to dig?!
Oh, you've really dug everything up.
Maybe I should use this opportunity to start a vegetable garden.
Right, Inspector?
Dammit!
Koda-san!
Koda-san...
Shut up! Sanae is here! I know she's buried in this yard somewhere!
I can understand how you feel,
but there's no point in continuing this.
Sanae...
Sanae!
The police took Koda-san into custody?!
Yeah. No matter what his reason, he did commit a jewel robbery.
But why didn't the body turn up?
Koda-san was mistaken.
Watanuki-san didn't kill her;
she went missing for some other reason.
No! Watanuki-san definitely killed her!
That smile then...
That look was more proof than anything!
But it's a fact she said she was going to visit Watanuki-san's house
before heading home on the night of May 8th, right?
Yeah. That's what her co-worker said.
Eh? You went to her company? Did you find anything out?!
The only other thing I learned
was that that co-worker gave her some cosmos seeds during lunch.
Cosmos seeds?
Yeah, don't you remember? Koda-san said she loved cosmos flowers.
Anyways, the most likely possibility
is that she was caught up in some incident and went missing
on her way to Watanuki-san's house from her company.
Supposedly, the police are going to investigate from that angle, too.
The next day (Sunday)
Then you think that old man killed her, Conan-kun?
Yeah. I'm almost certain of it.
But they never found her body.
Hmm, maybe it was buried under a floorboard instead of the garden?
No. There wouldn't have been a digging sound in the back alley.
Hey. Let's check out the library.
L-Library?
Yeah!
If we check the newspapers from May 8th, we might find something!
Yeah! But we don't want to check newspapers from the 8th.
Because news from the night of the 8th won't be in that day's paper.
There's a Kamen Yaiba show at Tohto Dept. Store the 23rd and 24th!
We gotta see it!
Genta-kun. You're reading last month's paper.
Not to mention, we all went to that show!
Oh, really?
Yes, really!
I don't see any pertinent articles...
Conan-kun.
There was a strong easterly wind from the night of the 8th to the 9th.
What's that got to do with this case?
No, I don't know...
There don't seem to be any clues here,
so let's go see the Mochida-san person
who heard the digging sound!
It was a month ago, and I was drunk,
so I don't remember clearly.
Shin'ichi Mochida (35)
You entered the alley from this road, right?
Yeah. There was loud construction on this road that night.
So I hurried into this alley,
and lit a cigarette a little ways down.
That's when I heard a shovel by the house to the left.
You're certain it was this house?
Well, I was drunk, so...
Yeah. I'm certain of it.
I heard it coming from my left.
Could you act out what you did again?
Yeah, okay.
There was a construction truck parked there.
So I went into the alley while thinking what a nuisance it was.
Yeah, it was around here where I lit my cigarette.
Wait a minute! This way is east!
Say! Was there a strong wind coming straight at you?!
Oh, now that you mention it...
The wind was so strong it kept putting out the lighter,
Main Road
Apartments
Watanuki's Home
East
West
so I turned around to light it.
Huh? Does that mean...
Left was right, and right was left?
Conan-kun!
Oh! So that's why he...!
Alright! This manhole will be the home plate!
All right! I figured it out!
Eh?! You know where the body is?!
Yes! We, the Detective Boys, found it!
So, where is it?!
Forget 'em. The brats are obviously spewing nonsense.
But Shin'ichi-niichan said there was no doubt about it, too!
What?!
You saw Shin'ichi, Conan-kun?!
No, I talked to him on the phone just now!
He said he would call Inspector Megure!
So, you two should come along!
Come along where?
What is this about, Inspector?! I'd like an explanation!
R-Right...
Are you kids really sure about this?
I never would've agreed to this had Shin'ichi-kun not called me...
Leave it to us, Inspector!
Okay, let's begin!
The night of May 8th, Koda-san's sister, Sanae-san,
stopped by this house after work,
just like she had said.
And, just as Koda-san surmises...
...Watanuki-san killed her.
Ridiculous! What nonsense!
They dug up the entire yard yesterday!
But you buried the body not in your yard, but somewhere else!
Tell me! Where is my sister buried?!
The answer to that is upstairs!
Follow me!
Hey! Wait!
Hey, Conan! Where in this room could she be?!
She's not in here.
Here!
What's that?
An unfinished apartment building.
Your sister's body is buried there.
At the time of the incident,
its construction was going as scheduled.
Burying a body there would mean it wouldn't be dug up for decades.
This fact was a relief to him.
But something unexpected happened half a month later.
The apartments' construction was suddenly canceled.
Eh?! Then they're going to be demolished?!
It's very possible. And the body would be found right away.
I'm so worried I can't sleep at night!
Let's watch the place with binoculars!
And that's why Watanuki-san stopped leaving the house
for everything but hospital visits.
And it's why he watched the premises with these binoculars.
But I have no way to enter those premises!
The area is fenced off, and the gate was locked that night!
You speak as if you investigated these things.
But there's a hole in the back!
No, that was made just recently.
Conan. How did he get in there?
Koda-san has the answer to that.
By sheer coincidence,
he used the exact same method!
You mean?!
Oh!
I get it!
The sewer system!
That night, there was a construction truck parked in the alley,
so this house's back entrance couldn't be seen from the main street.
I see! So the sewer system connects here!
The night of May 8th, major construction covered the main street,
so the sound of a shovel digging wouldn't seem suspicious to anyone.
To anyone but Mochida-san, that is.
Isn't that right, Watanuki-san?
Damn you!
Why did you kill Sanae?!
Stop it!
D-Do you have proof?!
This is all nothing but that child's conjecture!
So what if I could've entered this parking lot?!
Anyone could've used that method to get in here!
And besides, where is the body anyway?!
Right here.
The body of Koda-san's sister is resting beneath this plant.
What?!
But, Conan-kun! How do you know it's here?!
Look!
A cosmos...
Oh, yeah! A coworker gave your sister some cosmos seeds that day!
And one must've fallen out and sprouted after she was buried...
I didn't mean to kill her...
I snapped that night when she refused to compensate me...
Then our deal is off!
Leave!
W-Wait! Watanuki-san!
Watanuki-san!
Shut up!
Sanae...
That night, his sister's body was found beneath the cosmos seedling.
After that, Koda-san was given a suspended sentence for his robbery.
He decided to return to his hometown
with the cosmos seedling.
It won't bring his sister back,
but he said he'll take great care of it, as if it were her.
And thus the mystery of the Moletian was solved!
By the way, Conan-kun.
Yes, Ran-neechan?
You said you talked to Shin'ichi on the phone, right?
Y-Yeah...
Uh oh!
Tell me. Where is he?
Oh, uhh, actually...
Answer me, Conan-kun!
She's scarier than Moletians!
Hey! A car's coming!
Ayumi! Damn!
Ishikura-san's killer was you, Shishido-san!
Next Conan:
All together now, Next Conan's Hint: Muddy Water
Next time...
This is your fault, Genta-kun! Own up!
What did you do?!
Genta-kun's in trouble.