Encounters are mysterious!
But the world is even more so!
I'm so glad I'm with you!
Today is a strict cooking class!
What's on the menu? Accident or incident?
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Cooking classroom?
Yeah.
A teacher named Michi Uemori runs it out of her home.
I've heard of her!
She teaches French cooking, right?
Yeah! Sonoko asked if I'd like to go with her this Sunday.
Thanks for the food!
I've always wanted to study French cuisine, so I told her I'd go!
What time does it start?
It starts at 6:30 and ends at around 9:30.
9:30?
Forget it! That's too late!
But it's right nearby, in Haido!
That still doesn't matter!
Hey! Let's go with her, then!
What?
We might get to eat the teacher's yummy French food for free!
Yummy French food...
Sunday
Something suddenly came up,
so Sonoko couldn't come.
Listen, Ran. I didn't come along because I want to eat French food.
I'm just worried about you.
Yes, yes. I understand.
Do you really?
"Uemori"
Dad! This is it!
Ran Mouri-san, yes?
Yes!
We were told you were coming!
Here you are!
Thank you!
Thanks!
Yuko Komiyama (24)
I'm Yuko Komiyama, the teacher's assistant.
Over there is a student,
the teacher's old high school classmate,
and a boutique owner, Kazue Yashiro-san.
Kazue Yashiro (52)
Nice to meet you.
It's nice to meet you!
This is my father and Conan-kun.
What an impressive classroom!
Are these the cooking counters?!
Wow! What a big oven!
Ovens are vital to French cooking!
And we get to eat the food you make at that table?
Yes.
It's Nishitani-kun.
Bonsoir! Let's have another good class!
I slept well...
Let me introduce you!
This is Ran Mouri-san,
who's filling in for Sonoko-san tonight!
And this is her father and Conan-kun.
It's nice to meet you!
Kaoru Uemori (25)
Oh. Well, good luck.
Kaoru-san is the teacher's son's wife.
Hiroaki Nishitani (29)
I'm Nishitani. Nice to meet you.
Nishitani-san is a French chef.
Oh, Kaoru-san. What's with that eye patch?
I have a stye...
Is Sonoko-san not feeling well?
No, apparently something urgent came up.
It's only natural that she'd want to skip class...
Being yelled at every time...
You should be ready for it yourself.
Kazue-san! Quit scaring her!
Don't worry. You won't be the only one she yells at.
Okay...
Uemori-sensei sounds really strict...
Ah. So that's why ol' Sonoko ran off
and used Ran as a replacement.
Oh, Yuko-san! I'll help!
Incidentally, has Uemori-sensei gone somewhere?
Yes. The beauty salon.
The beauty salon?
Beauty salon?!
Her French recipe book became a best-seller,
and there's a party tomorrow in celebration of that.
She's really something.
Making lots of money off of others' ideas...
Eh?
One-third of the recipes in that book are hers... Yuko-san's.
Stop it, Kazue-san. That doesn't matter.
Oh? Why not?! Your own recipes have been stolen!
You came up with those original recipes
while working so hard these past five years as Michi's assistant!
But she did help...
So what if she helped a little?
They're clearly your recipes!
Yet, you don't complain at all. You must be crazy!
Quit it, Kazue-san!
This is between our teacher and Yuko-san!
It's none of our business!
Oh, really?
I guess you're right.
Michi has been giving you financial assistance all this time.
So you can't say anything bad about her.
That has nothing to do with this.
Oh? I'd love to hear how they're not related.
It's...!
Oh, man. Things are getting weird in here...
She's back!
Welcome back, Teacher!
Michi Uemori (52)
I'm back. I'm a little late, it seems.
You must be Ran Mouri-san.
Yes! It's nice to meet you!
I'm Ran's father, Mouri...
Oh, my shoulders are stiff.
Nishitani-kun. If you would.
Right.
U-Umm, I'm M-Mouri...
Here's the blouse you asked me to mend.
Yeah. Put it there.
Kaoru-san. Check my pulse.
Right.
Sheesh. Can't even say, "Thank you."
Is she unwell?
She's just fat.
She always has her pulse checked like that after going somewhere.
Kaoru-san used to be a nurse.
It's a little fast, but it's fine.
Her son is an elite businessman,
but he grew up as an only child and has a terrible mother complex.
Kaoru-san has it tough, being Michi's daughter-in-law.
I heard the teacher's husband died of an illness.
Yes.
He was such a nice, gentle man...
That'll do. I'm going to change now.
Okay.
I need to use the bathroom.
I'll just go get an apron.
Hold on!
There's no smoking in here!
I'm sorry, but you'll have to smoke outside.
Sorry.
Umm, where is the bathroom?
Through that door and to the left.
There's one for men and women.
Thank you.
Guess I'll go, too.
Yuko-san. I know what I said earlier, but...
Ran-san!
Sorry! My mistake! You look alike!
Okay, let's begin.
Today, we'll be making mushroom terrine and duck in orange sauce.
Dessert will be pear clafouti.
Whoa, now. You're cooking with a ring on?
Even if you are good, that's not very professional...
Nishitani-san is wearing a ring, too?!
Like teacher, like student...
That sounds great! Duck, huh?! I just love duck!
Yuko-san.
R-Right! I'm sorry!
Huh? You're closing it?
I'm sorry.
Geez!
Oh, Dad...
We'll start with the mushroom terrine.
I'll make some myself, so watch me
and follow my example.
First, slice 200 grams of champignon.
Hey. What's champignon?
It means "mushroom."
Now, we sauté it in butter.
Make sure to boil the moisture away.
It's starting to smell good!
But we won't get to eat it for a long while.
You're quite good at that!
Thank you!
You're so inept. You haven't changed one bit.
What's this? Now you can't separate the white and the yolk.
We're only using the white.
I'm sorry. I can only see with my right eye, so it's hard to tell...
No excuses!
Yuko-san. I don't see the Gruyère cheese!
Right! I'm sorry! I'll get it now!
All three of you are hopeless!
She's an intense teacher...
Yeah. It's no wonder Sonoko is avoiding her.
Nishitani-san is skilled,
so she has nothing to say to him.
I can't stand it anymore!
I'm going for a smoke!
Wait a minute. The only way outside is through the kitchen.
I saw a back door past the bathrooms.
Huh? It's unlocked...
What a careless household...
What happened? A blackout?
Who's there?
Yuko-san! Go to the electrical room
and check the breaker!
Right!
Say! Did you hear a sliding door open?!
A sliding door?
Excuse me!
I'm sorry, but could you give me some light?
Right.
"Electrical Room"
That's strange. Why is the switch off?
I'll turn it on.
Ice...
What's this doing here?
What's this?
Mister! Someone set up a trick here to cut the power!
What?
That weight's tied to a ring.
They put the ring around the switch,
and the weight on the ice!
In other words, if the ice melted...
...the ring would be pulled down
and turn the switch off.
But who set this up?
Let's go back to the classroom!
Something might've happened!
Alright!
Dad!
What happened?!
It's the teacher! She says her chest hurts and it's hard to breathe!
Hey! Who opened the front sliding door?!
Nobody did.
Nobody?!
M-My back hurts...
I felt a sharp pain in my back
while the lights were out...
I can barely breathe...
Did you strain a muscle?
She can barely breathe?! Could it be?!
Let me see!
H-Hey! What are you doing?!
C-Conan-kun?!
Just as I thought!
She was stung by a bee!
A bee?
See? Here!
There's a red speck here!
It's right behind her right lung!
Her right lung?
T-This is...!
Ran! Call an ambulance right away!
And Inspector Megure, too!
R-Right!
She needs to get to a hospital right away!
But who did this?!
No one is to step outside this classroom!
And don't touch the front door, either!
What gives you the right to give us orders?!
Pardon my late introduction.
I am Kogoro Mouri, the detective.
The famous detective...
...Kogoro Mouri?
Could you explain what's happened here?
I believe someone stabbed Michi Uemori-san in the back
with something with a sharp tip, like an ice pick or an awl.
Come again?!
She was stabbed...
...in the back?
Yes. There was a red speck on her back, like a bug bite.
An ice pick or something similar would leave such a mark.
And, even though ice pick stab marks don't look like much,
they can often pierce lungs and other internal organs.
So the reason her chest hurt and she couldn't breathe was because...
She may have a hole in her lung.
So, who did this?
Ran and the others heard the sliding door shortly after the blackout,
so it's highly likely the perpetrator entered from outside.
Outside?
But that doesn't rule out an inside attacker.
I see.
I must ask that none of you leave the room.
We'll check for fingerprints on the door first.
Who was the last person to touch the door handle?
Nishitani-san was!
He was the last person here to arrive,
and when Uemori-sensei came,
he opened the door from the inside!
Then we'll need to take your fingerprints
to differentiate them from the attacker's.
Tell me about this other thing of yours.
Right.
So this back door was unlocked?
Yes, Inspector.
I believe the attacker snuck into the electrical room via the back door
and set up the ice trick.
The attacker then went around to the front,
hid in the shrubbery in the yard,
and waited for the power to go out.
The instant it went out, they opened the door, leapt into the classroom,
and stabbed Uemori-san and fled!
But the classroom was pitch-dark.
How did the attacker find her?
Well, uhh...
She had something shiny on,
or something that made her stand out.
No.
She wasn't wearing anything like that.
I don't think she was, either.
Then the attacker must've used infrared goggles or something.
That would let them see in the dark.
Yes.
Are you serious? Infrared goggles aren't that easy to get a hold of.
Incidentally, the old guy says
it was likely an outside attacker,
but it's strange that there are no shoeprints left on the floor.
Did the person actually take off their shoes before coming in?
That's crazy!
Well?
Right. Only Nishitani-san's fingerprints were on both door handles.
The attacker was probably wearing gloves,
and Nishitani-san touched the door last, so that's to be expected.
Yes.
But, oddly enough, the outside handle fingerprints are fully there.
Only the inside fingerprints are somewhat gone.
What?!
That's not right!
If the attacker opened the door from the outside,
Nishitani-san's fingerprints on the outside handle should be gone!
The fact the inside fingerprints have rubbed off...
...means the attacker opened the door from the inside!
Huh? What are you getting at?
The attacker didn't enter from outside!
Someone in the classroom opened it
from the inside to deceive us!
They most likely used a handkerchief or something to do it!
In other words, one of you four is responsible!
Y-You can't be serious!
It's me.
What?!
All right.
Uemori-san has just passed away
due to respiratory failure
resulting from a punctured lung.
That means this is now a murder case.
You killed her, Kazue-san!
Nishitani-kun. I hear she was going to cut off your financial support.
Yuko-san. You held a grudge because she stole your recipes.
Now I got it!
You killed her, Kaoru-san!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Ring
Next time, I know who did it!
From the beginning, the pitcher hit a home run!