Encounters are mysterious!
But the world is even more so!
I'm so glad I'm with you!
Today's all deduction!
Let's change our view of people sometimes!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Thanks to Ran's plan to bring her parents back together,
we came to a midsummer beach.
But a girl we met fell into critical condition after a sea snake bit her.
This was no accident! It's a criminal act disguised as an accident!
Izu
Queen Hotel
What? Bring her insurance card to the hospital right away?
The hospital staff says it'd be best to have it,
plus I feel all alone...
Kiwako always takes it when traveling, so it should be somewhere.
But never mind that! How is she?!
She's still in the Intensive Care Unit.
I think her condition's gotten worse.
The doctors keep rushing in and out, but they won't tell me anything.
Do you think she might die?
You idiot! What kind of crap is that?!
I'll get her insurance card and be right there! Just wait quietly!
You and Kiwako are in the same room, right?
Yeah.
Oh no! The card key is still in the room!
I forgot it when she asked me to get a bath towel from our room.
What do we do?
It locks automatically, so we can't get inside.
Sheesh.
I'll call the front desk from our room and have 'em bring a spare key.
Yes, that's right. Room 406. Yes. Yes.
Thanks. Sorry for the bother.
Hey!
W-What is it, kid? Don't scare me like that.
You all went scuba diving around noon, right?
Yeah.
Did you catch anything?
Like fish.
No, I didn't get anything this time.
What about the others?
I dunno.
We're familiar with these waters, and we all did our own thing,
so I'm not sure who did what.
I think Masahiko and Kiwako-chan wore matching wetsuits
and did their diving at the same spot, though.
They're really close!
Yeah. Them and Hiroshi are all childhood friends.
They've always had fun together, since they were kids.
They're all classmates?
No, Hiroshi and Masahiko are the same age as me,
but Kiwako-chan is one year younger, the same age as Harumi-chan.
To be honest, I planned to quit this club my second year of college.
But I changed my mind when Kiwako-chan's group joined.
I guess it was love at first sight.
Huh?!
How stupid! Why am I telling all this to a kid?
Wait a minute!
Does that mean...?
That person and that person... Could it be?!
- There you are.
- Thank you.
Let's see...
Insurance card, insurance card...
Geez! Here's where you left it!
- I assume this is your card key?
- Yeah.
Can you help me? I can't find Kiwako's insurance card.
Did she maybe forget it?
Inside the towel at the bottom of the bag.
Just look.
The towel at the bottom of the bag...
H-Here it is! How did you know?!
My grandmother taught it to me when I was a kid, and I taught them.
That's childhood friends for ya!
I'm not the only one. Masahiko knows it, too.
Say, Detective. You have a car, right?
Yeah. It's a rental.
Then could you drive us three to the hospital?
Yeah, no problem.
Then let me come, too!
I'm worried about Kiwako-san...
Don't be stupid. Five people can't fit in that tiny car.
It's all right.
It's all right. I can drop her off at the hospital.
What are those suitcases for, Mom?!
Oh, you can't tell? As soon as I drop you off, I'm going home.
Wait, Mom!
I don't want to share the same space with this lunkhead anymore.
- Hey, Eri.
- What?
We need to talk later.
Oh? What about? I can't wait to find out.
Come on!
You're going too fast, Mom!
Sheesh. You don't have to sulk because he didn't notice your ring.
It's not the ring. It's the incident.
The incident?
Not everything adds up yet, but this is clearly a murder case.
Murder?!
And I'm angry at him for not even realizing it!
Yes. It's a murder case, and I have an idea who's responsible.
There's just one thing I don't understand...
Why did that person do that then?
What could it be?
- Do you mean the incident?
- No, what he wants to tell me.
He said we have to talk later.
Oh, yeah.
Divorce... Custody rights... Or perhaps...
Mom...
It's probably nothing at all. He's only testing me.
Testing?!
It's always the same.
He gets me worked up and then watches me squirm.
He's so self-conceited!
Now I see! So that's what the deal is!
Ran. Sorry, but I can't stand it anymore.
Mom!
No question about it! That person is behind this!
West Izu Hospital
Masahiko! I brought it!
Kiwako's insurance card!
Everyone!
- So, how's her condition?!
- How is she, Brother?
I don't know. She's still in the ICU.
Let me know when you find out how she is.
You're leaving, Mom?! But Dad said he has to talk with you!
Talk? Do I really need to lend my ear to that lady-killer?
Oh, really?! You're fans of mine?
Dad!
What a lost cause. Maybe I should give the guy a hand.
- Say, Nurse.
- Yes?
I have a favor to ask.
Wait, Mom! He can't help it! He's famous!
He's all smiles at a time like this! I've had enough of his callousness!
But that's because...
Paging Eri Kisaki and Harumi Matsuzaki from the Queen Hotel.
Please come to the hospital director's office immediately.
- Kogoro Mouri is waiting.
- Alright!
Me?
- Mouri-san!
- Are you okay?!
Wait! Little boy!
I'm sorry! I'll bring it right back!
"Director"
Why did you call us here like that?!
If you have something to tell me, just say it already!
Mom...
Yikes...
Umm, I can come back later if I'm in the way.
I'm concerned about Kiwako, too.
So you are concerned about her?
Can't say I blame you.
After all, the difference between murder and attempted murder hangs in the balance.
Yes. That wasn't an accident.
It was a premeditated act meant to kill.
Someone purposely had the sea snake bite Kiwako-san.
Harumi Matsuzaki-san... That someone was you!
- You can't be serious!
- The fang marks.
Fang marks?
Sea snakes have rather small heads.
If one bit a human, it'd be somewhere small, like a fingertip.
Yet, Kiwako-san's fang marks were on the back of her hand,
where a sea snake couldn't have bitten her.
When rushing to help, she held the head of the snake she had hidden,
forced its mouth open, and had it bite down as if it had attached.
Isn't that right, Harumi-san?!
I see. You pretended to play dumb but actually saw through it all.
Then tell us this, Great Detective.
How can you be sure it was Harumi-san?
Couldn't any of the others have done it too?
Besides, it was by sheer chance that Kiwako-san started to drown.
And what if it wasn't by chance?
What if Kiwako-san had done it on purpose?
On purpose? What for?
It's natural for lovers to want to know the other's true feelings.
To arouse the other's interest, one might get close to another person,
or even purposely not wear a wedding ring...
Then, you're saying Kiwako-san...
Yes.
Kiwako-san pretended to drown to test Masahiko-san, her fiancé.
To see if he would come to her rescue, even though he can't swim.
As proof, she murmured this after confirming that he tried to help...
"That's a relief..."
But they're getting married next week. Why do that now?
She wanted to be extra sure.
She was irritated that her fiancé didn't even bat an eye
when she clung to this famous celebrity.
And then she executed the fake drowning plan they made in advance.
"They"?
Yes. Two people.
For the plan to work, someone had to tell Masahiko-san right away.
It'd be a disgrace if someone else on the beach rescued her first.
And that other person was you, Harumi-san.
The signal for the start of the plan was probably when she said...
Could you get a fresh beach towel from our room?
Or so I'd assume. After that...
Later, Harumi! Don't forget!
...Is something else she said, so that sounds about right.
But Harumi-san tried to stop her from going into the water!
Besides, she wouldn't have done that in front of a famous detective!
That's why she tried to stop her. Because I was right there watching.
You don't have to do it today. Can't you go tomorrow?
I'll be fine!
But Kiwako-san continued with the plan anyway.
Unaware that Harumi-san had another, more sinister plan in store.
Y-You can't be serious...
Upon returning to her room to get the bath towel,
Harumi-san concealed her sea snake in her pouch
and went back to the seaside restaurant.
Then, at the proper time, she signaled Kiwako-san to falsely drown.
Then, when rushing to help with everyone else,
she took out the hidden sea snake and had it bite Kiwako-san.
But what's your plan, Great Detective?
The murder weapon is gracefully swimming in the Pacific Ocean.
Without a weapon, this case won't stand up in court.
I already told you. She placed the sea snake in her waist pouch.
What's more, whether out of confidence or confusion,
she never left our side after the incident.
It should still be there in her pouch:
adhesive tape with black-banded sea krait scales still attached!
- Tape?
- Yes.
Simply stuffing it in would make it seem unnatural when taking it out,
and there'd be a chance it could bite her fingers instead.
She most likely taped the snake down in several spots in the pouch
and left only the snake's head sticking out.
That way, she could pull it out and have it bite in an instant.
Then the feather-like things I saw on the snake were...
Probably some of the tape.
The rest of the tape is probably still inside her pouch.
Inside her pouch?
But we still don't know for sure she put a snake in...
We do. Because of her card key.
As soon as I saw her compact, wallet, and everything
on top of the card key she left in the room, it hit me
that she might've emptied her pouch and put something else in it.
But why would she harm Kiwako-san?! She's her brother's fiancée!
This is purely speculation,
but I wonder if Harumi-san might've liked Masahiko-san.
No... loved him. A lot.
Don't be silly, Dad! She and Masahiko-san are brother and sister!
No. They probably aren't.
If they were, all four in their group would've been childhood friends.
Especially given that she's the same age as Kiwako-san.
Then they're step-siblings from when their parents remarried?
Yes. Probably.
Seeing as Hiroshi-san calls her "-san" even though she's younger,
they were probably in college when it happened.
No. It was my second year in high school
when my mom remarried and I first met Masahiko-san.
He's a little helpless but nice, and I fell for him.
I never had anyone like him around me before.
But Kiwako-san was always by his side.
Whenever she spoke about his childhood, I'd get very sad and angry.
It was like she was saying, "You don't know anything about him!"
My only choice was to hide my feelings and call him my brother.
Their sudden engagement and marriage was a huge shock.
To top it all off, she came to me with that plan, knowing how I felt.
Almost as if she was mocking me.
- Pretending to drown?
- Please? Can you do it?
And then you devised your own plan?
Yes. That's right.
I didn't want to hand Masahiko-san over to her! So I...
So I...
I'm so stupid, aren't I? Doing that would only make him sad...
I'm really so stupid...
You're Kiwako Toda-san's friends, correct?!
We managed to administer an antitoxin just in time!
A few more days and she'll be just fine!
It's all thanks to your emergency treatment!
It was nothing!
That's wonderful news, Kiwako!
W-Where's Harumi?
She's here! Harumi!
C'mon! Why so bashful?
I'm sorry.
I didn't know how you felt...
I had no idea, until I saw your serious look when you rushed to me.
Kiwako...
Yet, I asked you for that favor... I'm really sorry! I regret it!
What are you saying?! I tried to... I tried to...
W-Wait! Did something happen?!
It's nothing. I was punished for testing the heart of another.
That's why a sea snake bit me.
That's all.
That was amazing detective work again, Dad!
Sometimes I can't remember anything at all...
Plus, it sounds like you noticed what Mom did.
Oh? Noticing but pretending not to know is all the worse.
Mom!
- What's she talking about?
- Look at you playing dumb again!
- She's talking about the ring!
- Ring?
Oh, that's...!
Oh.
You mean this?
No way!
I found it under the beach umbrella you were using.
How did you know I lost my ring there?!
Don't be stupid. Nobody dries their hair with their glasses on.
That was evidence you were looking for something.
People really only lose contacts, earrings, and rings on beaches.
So the sand on your knees was because you were looking for the ring!
I get it! You wanted to tell her about the ring!
The old guy did notice!
Geez. If only he was always that sharp.
Besides, could you be any more obvious?
Drinking tea with your left hand, wringing your hands nervously...
I couldn't help it...
Kogoro Mouri-san!
Hi!
Dad! Hey, Dad!
Mom! Mom!
Mom!
Alright! Next time for sure!
It'll never, ever happen.
They match perfectly!
I wonder why. The ones in Chapters 1 through 6 are all slightly off.
He obviously copied an earlier signature.
Why would he do that?
Because he didn't want to write it anymore...
...or he couldn't anymore?
That means Shinmei-sensei might already be dead, doesn't it?
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: "Halves at the Top"
Next time is the mystery of a mystery writer!
The best mysteries are the mysterious ones!
You said it!