Encounters are mysterious!
But the world is even more so!
I'm so glad I'm with you!
Today's an author mystery!
Some mysteries exist outside of writing!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
I, Samonji Matsuda, have solved tonight's bloody string of murders!
That person is undoubtedly the killer!
"Detective Samonji"
The son! The son! The son did it!
That's dumb! The son is a fake! It's the wife of the murdered man!
Who do you think did it, Conan-kun?
I'll say the same person as you!
See! Even he thinks so!
How would he know? Kids don't know anything!
The killer...
...is you, his son!
- I knew it!
- That's impossible!
It was different the last time I saw it...
The Detective Samonji series is always being remade,
and the killer changes each time!
That's why it's always so interesting!
You blockhead!
What was that for?! Don't make me mad!
That's not mad!
What are you doing, Dad?!
Quick-draw detective, my butt! How pathetic!
Turn it back! Samonji's about to pull out his sword and say a haiku!
Too bad!
Come on! Turn it back! It's going to end!
Things sure are peaceful for father and daughter to argue over this...
So many people have fallen victim to their organization.
But nobody realizes it's the organization's fault.
If I want to be normal again,
I have to turn this bumbling detective into a real master detective
and obtain information on the men in black's organization!
If he gets more work, I'll eventually run into a case involving them!
If I continue to seek the truth, I know I can do it!
Now it's over!
What's so good about it anyway? He's just a third-rate detective.
So says the dimwitted detective...
Besides, the original series ended long ago.
It's annoying that they keep putting it on TV.
Oh, they started the serials again!
Let's see. I'm sure it's around here.
Literature Era started it two months ago.
See!
"Nintaro Shinmei's highly anticipated 'Detective Samonji' returns!"
Seriously?!
This takes me back!
He and a killer disappeared into a fire 10 years ago,
but I guess he survived!
It takes you back?
That's what Shin'ichi-niichan said on the phone the other day...
Shin'ichi did?
That mystery nerd, huh...
Oh? I think someone's at your office downstairs...
Yeah, tell them it's late and to come back tomorrow.
Okay.
I'm sorry! The office is closed for the day!
But I really do need to talk to Detective Mouri about something.
Could he at least hear what I have to say?
Hottie!
It's rather late, so could you come back tomorrow?
Wait, wait, wait!
What are you saying to our guest?!
Sorry to keep you waiting! I am Kogoro Mouri!
I apologize for my rude daughter!
Please! Come right in!
- Thank you.
- Right this way!
What's with that attitude? You told me to turn her away!
Please, have a seat!
My apologies! Go right ahead!
Thank you.
- It's nothing special, but...
- Thanks.
Now, then. May I ask what brings you here?
Yes. My name is Kaori Shinmei.
"Kaori Shinmei"
- Shinmei? You don't mean...?!
- The mystery writer's...?
Kaori Shinmei (22)
Office worker
Yes. Nintaro Shinmei is my father.
You're the daughter of that great master?!
I can never get enough of Samonji's haikus!
Right?!
So, how can I help you? Does he want to use me in a novel?
No, actually... My father has been missing for two months.
- He's...
- ...missing?!
That is quite...
Don't be silly!
He's been writing serials for Literature Era for the past two months!
But it's the truth! He and my mother disappeared from their home!
Y-Your mother, too?
They both vanished about one week before this serialization began.
I checked with all our relatives and acquaintances of course,
but no one knew anything.
Still, don't his serials mean that he is writing manuscripts?
Yes.
Oddly enough, the manuscripts are faxed to the editing department.
Every Saturday, at exactly midnight.
But don't the faxes have the sender's phone number or anything?
No, nothing at all.
It seems the sender has it configured not to display those things.
Hmm...
It's probably because he and his wife are on vacation somewhere
and he sends the faxes from the hotel they're staying at!
I thought so too at first!
But they've never been quiet for two months like this before!
I can only think that something happened!
Did you contact the police?
Yes.
I asked them to investigate, but there had been no ransom calls
and the manuscripts were being sent, so they said not to worry.
I tried the other detective agencies, but they all said the same thing.
You're my last hope, Mouri-san!
This is pointless!
We're only wasting time by sitting here!
Let's check the editing department where his manuscripts get sent!
You can save your troubles for after that!
R-Right!
Taxi!
After you!
Yes, Shinmei-sensei's manuscripts get sent here every week.
"Daigakukan"
More should be sent today, at any time now...
Are these manuscripts really written by him?
Yes. Although they're typed out, the words are most definitely his!
He signs his name next to the title each time, too.
I can show you the faxed manuscripts, if you'd like.
"Halves at the Top"
The title is "Halves at the Top"?
And he's signed them, too.
Are you certain this is his signature?
Yes. We confirmed it when I came here earlier.
There's nothing to worry about, Kaori-san!
I'm sure he's just so focused on writing that he forgot to contact you.
The same thing happens to lots of other writers!
But are you sure he forgot? His wife's with him...
Yeah, now that you mention it...
Did he seem different in any way?
Different?
You know, like during a meeting or something.
Yes, we had a simple meeting before we started the serials,
but he didn't seem any different...
Anything at all? Even the tiniest thing might help...
I suppose there is the fact he restarted his Detective Samonji series.
Huh?
You see, I asked him to restart this series for the past four years.
But he always answered by saying...
Samonji is dead. There's no bringing him back.
So I had half given up when he suddenly called two months ago
to ask if we could make room for his new Samonji series.
We were more than happy to oblige, of course,
so we hurriedly canceled the new series we were running
and replaced it with Samonji.
I see. Anything else?
Oh, come to think of it, this doesn't pertain to him exactly,
but for the dedication, he wrote this:
"Attention, all master detectives throughout Japan!
If you wish to surpass my intellect, solve this case's true mystery."
That's quite a provocative dedication.
Yes. And ever since the first chapter, we've received
tons of calls and fan letters saying, "This is how it was done!"
As an editor, it makes me happy,
but it seemed like a rare move for such a mild-mannered writer.
Though, fans have been waiting like crazy for over 10 years,
so it's only natural he's getting such a big reception.
"Like crazy"?
Yes, there was even a scary call last year from a crazed fan
who threatened to set this place on fire if he didn't restart the series!
Talk about extreme...
Oh, yes! There's one other thing that seemed strange!
He appears in his own novel!
Come again?
Shinmei-sensei appears in the story, as an old friend of Samonji's!
He's a struggling writer who resides in France.
There are about 40 stories in the series, but this is a first!
I think it's going to end with all the previous cases
being things Samonji told him about!
Kind of like how Watson is to Sherlock Holmes!
Say! Could you show me that scene?
Sure!
But can you read kanji, little boy?
A little!
Oh, you're right! Here he is!
Shinmei-sensei makes his first appearance
when Samonji calls a friend living in France for advice on a case.
His character is absentminded and funny!
W-What's this?!
This is strange!
Look at this!
10:00 is written in kanji here, but 1:00 is written with a number!
This guy must've been pretty tired, huh?
That is strange. Could this actually be...
...a misprint on your part?
No!
We wanted to fix it to make it easier to read, too!
But he said, "The lay of the letters is a novel's life! Don't change it!"
He said it many times before the serialization.
He also said he'd cancel the series immediately if we defied his wish.
Then that makes it all the odder.
It's almost as if something is being hidden in the writing.
And then there are Shinmei-sensei's signatures.
If my theory is correct, it's possible that he's already...
Oh! Here's his latest fax!
Let's see here...
You can't look yet!
It's a mystery story! Wait until it's in book form to read it!
Hey!
I thought so!
Hey, you!
But his signature is weird!
Chapters 6 through 8 match perfectly.
"Nintaro"
T-They do!
Chapters 1 through 6 are all slightly different, though. I wonder why!
He obviously just copied an earlier signature.
Why would he do that?
Because he didn't want to write it anymore...
...or he couldn't anymore?
Mouri-san!
If he can't write anymore,
that means Shinmei-sensei might already be dead, doesn't it?
Y-You can't be serious!
This is bad! This requires immediate action!
You! The police! Call the police!
Right!
It's not 100% yet! There's a chance he's still alive!
The key to saving his life is probably hidden inside this novel!
As a message he's left for us detectives!
"Daigakukan"
You can't open an investigation?
No, we still can't. Not at this stage.
Hold on, Inspector!
Nintaro Shinmei, her father and a mystery writer,
has been missing for two months now!
What's more, his wife is also gone!
I can only think they got caught up in some sort of incident!
Even so, his manuscripts are being faxed here every single week.
Even though they're faxes,
his daughter and the editors all agree it's his writing!
And like I said, those faxes are the issue here!
Don't those signatures seem strange to you?!
Signatures? But they were already confirmed to be his.
Between Chapter 1 and 6, his signatures are all slightly different,
but between Chapter 6 and 8, they're all exactly the same!
They're obviously copies of a previous signature
and evidence that he's now in a condition in which he can't write!
In other words, something has happened to him!
Then tell me... Who did what to Mr. Shinmei?
I'd believe you more if there was a threatening phone call,
but there's been nothing at all.
Besides, maybe he got sick of signing them and used copies instead.
True. Given the circumstances, Inspector Megure is right.
It wouldn't be surprising for an eccentric writer
to take his wife and hole up somewhere to focus on his writing.
But something bugs me! It wasn't like him to write that dedication.
"Attention, all master detectives throughout Japan!"
It was very extreme and provocative for someone so mild-mannered.
Then, there's the fact the writer suddenly appears in the series.
And then there's his odd dialogue
that mixes numbers, kanji numbers, and English letters...
If my theory is correct,
there must be a message from Shinmei-sensei in here!
Inspector! I made copies of all the lines Mouri-san was curious about.
Mr. Shinmei makes four appearances so far?
Can I have a copy, too?
Stop that! Don't get in the way!
It's okay! There are extras!
- Here you go!
- Thank you!
Let's see, his first appearance is when the main detective character
calls Mr. Shinmei, who is residing in France.
He's also in France the second time...
He's in France the third time...
And the fourth time, too.
Does Mr. Shinmei like France?
Yes. He and my mother often traveled there.
Damn! Reading them backwards or rearranging them doesn't work!
If only I had a point to start from!
Umm, do you mind if we use Chapter 8 of "Halves at the Top,"
the manuscript he just faxed?
Halves at the top?
It's the title of the work you're reading right now!
Halves at the...?
Halves at the top?!
Hold on, now! Could this actually be...?!
T-This is...!
Just as I thought!
There's a message from Shinmei-sensei hidden in these lines!
Which makes it all fit: that provocative dedication,
the author's appearance in the story, and the odd lines of dialogue!
But what is the goal of the person holding him and his wife captive?!
Inspector!
What is it, Takagi-kun?
Look at this manuscript! There's more dialogue!
Huh? This is the eighth chapter that was just faxed here?
"Hurry..."
"There's..."
"...no time..."
"Hurry, there's no time!"
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: French
A message from the creator, Aoyama-sensei!
What, did he say this corner's popular?