Encounters are mysterious!
But the world is even more so!
I'm so glad I'm with you!
Today is a serious code!
If adding doesn't work, try subtracting!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Kaori, the daughter of the novelist Nintaro Shinmei,
asked the old guy to find her parents who went missing.
They've been missing for two months,
but the publisher still receives his manuscripts for his new series.
We went straight to the publishing company.
We found several incomprehensible things about his manuscripts,
and they turned out to be a code calling for help!
T-This is...!
Just as I thought!
There's a message from Shinmei-sensei hidden in these lines!
Which makes it all fit:
that provocative dedication,
the author's appearance in the story,
and the odd lines of dialogue!
But what is the goal of the person holding him and his wife captive?!
The Mystery Writer Disappearance Case
(Part 2)
What is it? Did you realize something else?!
It's nothing much, but...
Literature Era, Editing Department.
All the first letters of dialogue are half...
Huh?! You figured out the code?!
Who are you?!
Is something the matter?
A boy speaking in Kansai dialect
said he figured out the code,
so I should call the police here.
A boy speaking in Kansai dialect?
Hello?
C'mon! Don't make me repeat myself, idiot! Just get the cops!
Oh, Hattori-kun. This is Megure.
Oh, you're already there! It's been awhile!
So, what's with you?
The code. I cracked the code hidden in "Halves at the Top."
I pegged him as an angry old man after I first read his dedication,
but I started to understand as I read
that Shinmei-han's dialogue in the story was all a code.
It's a code?
Yeah. In other words, the dedication wasn't meant to provoke us.
He was askin' someone to find the real message hidden in the novel!
I-I assume you've deciphered the coded message then?!
Yeah. The first part deciphers perfectly.
The key was the novel's title: "Halves of the Top."
This means the letter at the top of each line is half of a full letter.
Half of a full letter?
Reading with that in mind,
with chikara and me, you get suke...
with jū and 1 you get ke...
with C and ichi you get te...
and at the very end,
with no and 1 you get a re.
The ku and hoka (other) before it are strange,
but if hoka is meant to be a blank placeholder, you get ku.
And if you read it all together...
"Tasu-ke-te-ku-re"...
"Tasukete-kure (Help us)"
"Help us!" It's an SOS?!
Yep. My guess is he's bein' held somewhere and forced to write.
I see. And that's why he used this method.
He could get a message to his readers
without his captor noticing.
My mom was excited because
it's the first new story in 10 years,
so the perp is a crazed fan or someone
plannin' to swipe the story.
Have these manuscripts been paid for yet?
Not yet.
He said he'd tell where to send the money
when the story was done.
Alright! Check all suspicious fan letters!
Right!
Oh, but I haven't cracked the entire code yet!
Hey! Inspector?! Inspector?!
Hey, Inspector! Hey!
Where'd you go?! Quit playing around!
Still, Hattori.
About Shinmei-sensei's other lines...
Oh! If it isn't Kudo! What're you doing there?!
Nothing, I just happened to be here.
Yeah, I bet! You an' me are a lot alike!
We cross paths before we even know it!
Let's just get back to the code.
Hey! You should come to Osaka!
I'll treat you to some great udon!
I can't stand the heavy flavor in Tokyo!
I'm hanging up.
Sorry! Sorry! The code, right?!
I managed to decipher the first lines of dialogue,
but "halves at the top"
doesn't fit with the next ones.
Put together, you get...
"Watashi hoka ka i he ima i
haku re no tokoro han hito wa."
Even if you remove the second hoka,
only watashi makes sense.
He and ima are iffy, but they don't combine into anything.
It seems we still don't have all the pieces to this code.
Yeah. There has to be a big piece to this code hidden somewhere.
Hattori? What's wrong?
How stupid.
If you're there, why should I puzzle over it from so far away?
So the rest's all yours, Kudo!
Lemme know if you figure anything out! Good luck!
H-Hey! Wait!
Oh! That's right! Hattori-kun should know the rest of the code!
Damn!
It wasn't me! He was the one who...!
Inspector. This is Tokyo.
Let's forget about the Osaka boy
and solve this ourselves!
Oh! Good call!
So, are you feeling sleepy?
Huh? What do you mean?
You know! When you always go,
"Funya!" or "Hohe!"
Nope, nothing yet...
Oh. That's a shame.
Help us! Help us!
Help us!
Dad... Mom...
Don't worry. I'm sure we'll find
your mother and father.
Don't give up.
So let's use our heads, too.
Okay!
Damn! Adding or removing
nearby letters doesn't do anything!
What is this code?!
I also don't know who abducted them!
It would be natural to pay close attention to your captive's writings.
If the captor is a fan,
he'd clearly be suspicious of that
atypical dedication and character.
He would've at least deciphered
the first "help me" by now!
In which case, he'd be after
the manuscript payment.
No, that can't be it.
You wouldn't hold a person captive
two whole months for that.
I can't figure out the captor's identity or this code!
Damn it!
Hey! This is wrong!
Using French to fancy things up is fine,
but don't spell stuff wrong!
Sorry...
French?
"Humour" is spelled "h-u-m-o-u-r."
You're missing the "h."
It's not pronounced, though,
so I can understand the mistake.
That's it! Now I see!
In which case, the code is...
I can read it! I can read it!
I can read every single letter!
That's it! That's definitely where
Shinmei-sensei is being held!
Inspector!
Shinmei-sensei also has dialogue
in the eighth chapter we just got!
What?!
This is the scene...
Oh no! There's no time!
If we don't hurry, he and his wife will be...!
Alright! I'll just do like always...
and use this Tranquilizer Wristwatch
to knock the old guy out!
Mouri-san. Let me introduce you.
This is our chief editor...
I-I missed!
Whoops! I guess I have no choice!
Chief! Chief! What's wrong?!
I'll just have to have him play a detective!
Now to set the Voice-Changing Bowtie to use his voice...
Let's see...
Wait a minute! I don't know what he sounds like!
Hey, Conan-kun.
What are you doing down there?
O-Oh, just playing Hide-and-Seek!
This is bad! There's only one tranquilizer dart!
I'll have to wait for them
to crack the code themselves.
But...
If we don't hurry, Shinmei-sensei will...!
What happened?! Please wake up, Chief! Chief!
He's snoring. Almost reminds me
of "Sleeping Kogoro."
Yes...
What're you laughing about?
The chief editor is copying how you sleep!
He seems like he has lots of humor!
Humor? As always, you know strange words for a kid.
Those men were talking about it just now!
They were saying stuff about "humour"! Right?
Yes...
He misspelled the word, so I fixed it for him.
I forgot to add the "h."
What rubbish.
But French people sure are strange!
They don't read "h" at the start of words!
If they don't say "h",
they should remove it from the start!
- Remove it...
- ...from the start?
That reminds me, Shinmei-sensei's character lives in France, right?
Yeah.
M-Mouri-kun. Could this be...?
Yes. The other key to this code might be the fact
that "h" isn't pronounced at the start of words in French.
Silent "h"s!
Characters that start with "h"?!
Could it mean to remove the "h"
from ha, hi, hu, he, and ho?!
I see!
If it means you have to drop the "h" letter when combining letters,
the hoka in the first part works.
Using all of this to decipher Mr. Shinmei's second scene,
watashi and hoka become watashi...
i and ka is ga...
then he and ima is ima...
then i and haku is i...
then re with no makes ru...
then tokoro with han is tokoro...
then hito with wa is wa...
All together, it's "watashi-ga-ima-i-ru-tokoro-wa"...
"The place I'm at now"?!
watashi ga ima iru-tokoro wa
Wow! It makes a sentence!
I see. He used that "wa" instead of "ha" because of the "h" rule.
Alright! When you decipher
the third scene he's in, you get...
"Ki-to-shi-te-i-ho-te-ru"...
Kido City Hotel? What hotel is that?
I've never heard of it.
It could be using Hepburn romanization!
In which case, ふ wouldn't be hu, but fu.
And if you keep the first fu, it would combine with moku to make hai.
H-Haido City Hotel?!
Meaning the fourth set of lines
is probably the room number.
Let's see...
"2-4-0-7-go-shitsu"...
"Room 2407"!
2407-go shitsu
Okay! We go straight to
Haido City Hotel, Room 2407!
Yes, sir!
Inspector!
What is it, Takagi-kun?!
Look at this manuscript! There's more dialogue!
Oh, this is the eighth chapter
that was just faxed here.
Let's see...
Haya-ku...
Ji-kan-ga-nai...
"Hurry, there's no time!"
hayaku, jikan ga nai
Hey! Hurry it up!
Haido City Hotel. Follow those police cars.
- Hurry!
- R-Right!
Dad... Mom...
Dad! Mom! Please be okay!
They're alive.
"There's not much time" can also mean
that danger is looming but it's not too late.
It's been barely an hour since that manuscript was sent,
and it's still the middle of the novel.
There's a good chance they're alive.
Right?
But I don't understand what the captor wants.
Is a crazed fan anxious for the new
Detective Samonji series behind this?
No...
Was it an abduction to get
a popular writer's money?
No, Room 2407 is a suite. That doesn't fit.
Then what is the captor after?!
What is the plan of the person
who's forcing Shinmei-sensei to write
even when he can't sign his own name?
Wait a minute! If he can't sign his name...
...that means he's dictating his story to someone!
Then he's having someone else type it all out,
even when one misplaced letter
could ruin the code?!
That's crazy!
Adding and removing for no reason
would make anyone suspicious!
Even if his wife was typing,
the person watching would notice!
Wait! Hold on! Could this incident actually be...?!
Room 2407... Alright! This is the room!
The captor may have a weapon!
Everyone stay sharp!
Umm, can I help you?
Mom!
Kaori! Why are you here?!
Get back, Madam!
Freeze! Police!
Dad! Dad!
Your father passed away just moments ago.
Kaori-san.
I called your home many times,
but I couldn't get a hold of you.
So you're the one who abducted Mr. Shinmei?
No, I'm...
He's my husband's personal physician.
Then who's the kidnapper?
There is no kidnapper. If there was,
it'd be Shinmei himself.
- Does that mean the code was...?!
- You can't mean...!
A fabrication put together by my husband.
B-But why?
My husband was always saying this...
I, of course, feel happiness
when I receive praise for my works,
but in my 40 years of writing,
there's a happiness I've yet to have.
Just once, I'd like to see with my own eyes
the face of a reader who solves a
mystery before I give the solution.
He said he wanted to do so before he died,
so his physician and I helped him write his story here.
Before dying?
He lost use of his arms two weeks ago,
due to terminal cancer.
So that's why his signatures were copies?
I'm sorry for worrying you, Kaori.
Your father told me not to tell you,
to give believability to his code.
Forgive your father, and consider it
his last selfish act, Kaori...
Talk about your false alarms...
Surely he knew a code like that
could've caused a big police panic!
But he always wrote at the end of his novels
that he wanted to see the proud look of one of his readers.
He was probably waiting for a reader who figured everything out
to show up and say, "I solved it!"
But no one ever came.
And now that he's gone,
the novel will stay unfinished.
I won't let that happen.
I'll write the rest of it.
I won't shame the name Nintaro Shinmei!
Two months after this incident,
Kaori-san spectacularly completed her father's novel
and "Halves at the Top"
managed to become a bestseller!
Naturally, a TV version was soon made
and earned great reviews,
which led her to enter the writing world!
Although this was because
she was as skilled as her father,
the dimwitted detective, tomboy girl,
and the cheeky boy in glasses
who assisted Samonji in the last half of the story also helped.
I won't say who they were based on...
...but I could do without the "cheeky" part.
NEXT EPISODE
I'm just a regular Tokyo...
Sorry!
I get a bad feeling that the killer is playing with us...
Bad feeling?
Kudo!
Next Conan Special:
The Naniwa Serial Murder Case
Next Conan's Special Hint: Rearview Mirror
Look forward to the next episode!
Next time, it's a one-hour special!
Conan's going to Osaka! Vroom, vroom!