Encounters are mysterious!
But Osaka is even more so!
I'm so glad I'm with you!
Today is a 60-minute Naniwa special
filled with incidents and mystery!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Created by
Gosho Aoyama
"Detective Conan"
Serialized in Shogakukan's
"Weekly Shonen Sunday"
Planning
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Character Design
Masatomo Sudo
Art Director
Yukihiro Shibutani
Art Design
Hiroyuki Mitsumoto
Director of Photography
Takahisa Ogawa
Sound Director
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
Music Producer
Hiroki Horio
(PolyGram)
Music
Katsuo Ono
Opening Theme
"Unmei no Roulette mawashite"
Performed by
Lyrics
Music
Arrangement
Izumi Sakai
Sei'ichiro Kuribayashi
Daisuke Ikeda
(B-GRAM RECORDS)
Editor
Teramitsu Okada
Story Editor
Jun'ichi Iioka
Color Key
Reiko Hirayama
Executive Producer
Hiroaki Kobayashi
Planning Support
Toyohiko Okuyama
Mitome Asai
Director
Kenji Kodama
Producers
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Masahito Yoshioka
(Tokyo Movie)
This is the incident in Toyonaka.
And this is last week's incident in Hirakata.
There were no witnesses to these killings,
and they're dozens of kilometers away.
We're checking into how
these two victims are connected,
but they still have nothing in common.
There's only one thing:
the knife.
I don't know why, but they
were both stabbed in the heart,
through their wallets in their jackets.
Have you told the media about this?
No, not the wallet part.
That means the second killing
wasn't some moron's copycat attack.
Correct. It was definitely the same person.
Serial murders...
If the murders are at
random, it'll cause a panic.
Toyama. You'd best be extra careful.
Yes. I know.
That's the Tennoji Zoo!
That's the Osaka Dome!
And this is the Tsutenkaku Tower!
Whadya think? Osaka's nice, huh?!
Yeah! This is a great view!
I dunno, it's no different
from the Tokyo Tower...
Don't be dumb! Don't compare
this with that tasteless red thing!
The Tsutenkaku and the Shinsekai around it
are brimming with the Osakans' humanity!
It's almost like downtown Tokyo!
How about some food now?
Just a little longer!
I'm waiting for someone!
Fine. Guess I'll have a smoke.
Hey, Hattori.
Tell me why you called me to Osaka.
Huh? You're concerned about that?
You have another real reason, right?
No, no! There's really no work this time!
I just thought I'd show
you guys around Osaka!
There's no telling when you'll die, after all.
W-What's that mean?
I had a bad dream...
Dream?
Yeah. It happens when we catch a bad guy.
But he winds up stabbing
and killing you instead!
Hey, now! Don't kill people on your own!
There you have it. So just enjoy Osaka!
Sorry! Heiji-kun!
Oh! He's finally here!
I'm Sakata of the Osaka Police, Tojiri Station!
Sorry for being so late!
Why is a police detective here?
My old man said that if
Mouri-han's coming to Osaka,
he should have a proper tour guide!
Huh? Where is my old man?
He said he was going to stop by.
The chief is busy in a
meeting about the incidents.
"The incidents"?
So, did you get the car?
Of course!
I did just like you asked and
borrowed the Tojiri station's best one!
H-Hey, now. Don't tell me this car is...
Well, let's go!
Isn't this the best?! Cop cars are great!
You can pass other cars even in traffic jams!
So, where would you like to go, guests?
Tell me...
Are you making us tour Osaka in this thing?!
Huh? You don't like it? It's brand new!
Oh, I know! Should I turn on the siren?
We can go even faster!
No, that's not what he means...
It feels like we're being arrested,
so it's kind of embarrassing.
Oh, don't worry about that!
You haven't done anything wrong!
Hold your heads high!
Whadya think?! This is real udon!
The soup's so clear you can see the bottom!
Yeah, you can!
It's a light flavor, but good!
Tastes like nothing.
Oh, Heiji! Who's she? A new girlfriend?
Does it seem that way?
No! I'm just a regular Tokyo...
What is it?
I suddenly got a chill...
So, where to next?
Hmm, the next thing Osaka is famous for is...
Yum!
This takoyaki is great!
I've never had ones with such big octopus!
What is it?
Nothing. It just feels like
someone's been watching me...
Oh, don't worry about it and eat up!
I can't take my eyes off you!
I thought you were on a diet, Ran-neechan?
Okonomiyaki? Why didn't you
say so before the takoyaki?
We already passed a great place I know!
We're going the wrong way!
We can't get there on Midosuji!
Osaka is full of one-way roads,
so you often have to go way out of your way!
In that case, shall I show
them a nearby place I know?
It's a good thing this place was nearby!
I'm gonna call my mom real quick.
Mister! Don't forget the rice!
You eat okonomiyaki with rice?
Of course! It's a main dish!
Rice with the sauce on it is great, too!
Osaka's neat!
Yeah!
Oh! That seat is taken...
You're Kudo, aren't you?
Heiji's always talking about you.
Whoa, now!
Hattori-kun does?!
Don't play dumb.
I already know everything.
H-Hold on!
I know you're the Kudo broad
from Tokyo who's seducing him!
Umm, I think you have the wrong idea...
I have just one thing to say to you:
Heiji and I were once
bound by "chains of steel"!
If you want to mess with Heiji,
you gotta go through me...!
Hey, Kazuha.
What're you doing here?
You're hilarious!
The "Kudo" I talked about is a guy! A guy!
And this girl is Kudo's squeeze.
Squeeze?
I-It isn't like that!
She says she isn't.
She's just embarrassed.
Then why didn't you ask Kudo to come too?
Don't be stupid! Kudo's sitting right...!
H-He couldn't make it!
Anyway, tell us more about
this "chains of steel" thing!
When we were kids, we found my
old man's handcuffs in the attic.
Then we got stuck together when
I pretended to be a policeman!
It was lame; we found ourselves in big trouble!
It was not lame! We had to bathe
and use the bathroom together!
You moron! Don't tell them that!
Bathe and use the bathroom?
Sounds like a smelly relationship.
To commemorate it, I put a piece
of the chain in here for good luck!
Gross! Throw that thing away!
Say! Are you two going out?!
No, no! Heiji and I are just childhood friends!
I'm like his big sister who's
always looking after him!
Sure you are.
Her dad's chief detective of the
Osaka police and my dad's friend,
so we've known each other
since we were kids, that's all.
A detective runt and the
daughter of a police detective...
What an ominous couple...
Eh? How come? What's wrong with that?
Still, why are you here?
I was acting as your big
sister and keeping watch
so the creepy Tokyo girl
won't try and seduce you!
Keeping watch? From where?
The Tsutenkaku Tower.
Now I see! She was the
one I sensed watching me!
...attitude?! I was worried about you!
Thanks for the meal!
I'm stuffed!
That was delicious!
Sorry to keep you waiting!
You should've joined us!
No, no, I'm just here to show you around!
Where to next?
I guess only Osaka Castle is left...
What are you doing in here?
Oh, come on! Take me with you!
What a pain...
Huh?
What happened to this man?!
I don't know! He suddenly
fell onto the hood of the car!
From the roof of this building!
Someone's up there!
Sakata-han! Contact the police!
G-Got it!
H-Hey!
Heiji!
Conan-kun!
Alright!
Now you tell us why you dropped
that body on top of a police car!
N-No! I'm just a...!
What?! He was called to the roof?!
Yeah. Someone called this guy
about a strange man on the roof.
I run a tea shop on the second floor, you see...
But what sent the body falling?
The body was wrapped in rope,
attached to the roof's handrail,
and covered with a tarp, while
the other end of the rope
was tied to the door so the rope
would come undone when opened.
I put his estimated time of
death at about one full day ago.
So someone murdered him this
time yesterday and left him hanging.
But why on top of a police car?
It was probably just coincidence,
but it could be someone
trying to make an example...
Example?
The knife through the wallet and heart...
This is clearly connected
with those incidents...
Hey! Lady! Hold up!
Hey! Wait!
There she goes!
It's all right. I got her license plate number.
But never mind that. Tell me
about "those incidents," Hattori!
Serial murders?!
And that man who fell was the third one?!
Yep.
In each case, they were stabbed
in the chest, through their wallets.
After they were strangled
to death with something.
Maybe it was someone who
held a grudge about money?
No, we can't say that for sure.
The first victim, Hidetoshi Nagao,
was a convenience store owner.
The next victim, Tayo Nishiguchi,
was the mistress of a small pub.
And the one who fell was
Kazuto Noyasu, a taxi driver.
None of them had enough money
to incur someone's wrath.
In fact, none of them
are connected in any way.
There's no connection?
Nope.
They were all born, raised,
schooled, and employed in Osaka,
but all in different places.
We found it, Heiji-kun!
We found a link between the victims!
Seriously?!
Goshi-san! Any comments?!
Goshi-san!
Huh? Isn't this from Sotaro Goshi's
corruption case six years ago?
The case where his secretary took
responsibility for him and quit?
As I recall, the secretary's name was Nagao...
Hey! Is our Nagao...?!
Yes.
Hidetoshi Nagao, the first one who was killed!
But didn't you already
investigate this? Why now?
No, take a look at the driver.
The driver?
T-That's Noyasu, the third victim!
It seems he was Assemblyman
Goshi's driver until four years ago.
His former secretary and his former driver...
Assemblyman Goshi may be involved in this.
We thought so too, so one of my
seniors is headed to his place now.
Still, he's famous for his hatred of police.
Just going to see him won't help anything.
Then what do you say we
pay a visit too, Sakata-han?
Hold on! You should leave that to the police!
Don't be stupid.
I can't just let the guy who
screwed up your Osaka tour get away!
Head over to my house!
Kazuha can tell you where it is!
Heiji! Do you have the good luck charm?!
Yep, sure do. Don't worry.
Well, later!
What good luck charm?
A good luck charm I gave him.
It's always protected his life.
What nonsense.
It's true!
The last time he forgot it, he
got really hurt in a kendo match!
They're very important charms!
There are only two in the world!
Two?
Yeah, remember that story
about us and the handcuffs?
I secretly put a piece of the
chain in his good luck charm!
Oh?
Though it's none of your business!
Y-Yeah.
Never mind that. I don't
see the runt anywhere...
Eh?!
Did he go to the bathroom?
I guess this means no more police cars...
Sorry, Sakata-han.
You gotta write a letter apologizing
for the crushed car, don't you?
It's fine. I'm used to it.
But what's with the gut?
Oh, this?
This kid'll be helpful!
But won't Mouri-han be worried?!
It's okay! I'll call him later!
Oh, that reminds me, we used
the license plate number to get
the address and phone number
of that suspicious woman you saw.
Her name is Sumie Okazaki, age 39.
She divorced last year and lives
alone in the West Side Apartments.
Want to check her out first?
Yeah. It seemed like she knew something.
Here, I'll call to see if she's home or not.
At 1:00 PM today, a body
fell near the Shinsai Bridge.
The deceased was identified
as Kazuto Noyasu-san, age 41.
Moreover...
Forgive me... Forgive me...
Yes?
Oh, is this Okazaki-san's residence?
My name is Sakata, I'm with
the Tojiri Police Department.
O-Officer! Hurry here and protect me!
I'm going to be killed!
I'll tell you everything!
Just hurry here! Hurry!
Just calm down! I'll be right there!
Lock your door and don't let anyone in!
Oh no! We passed the West Side Apartments!
What now?! It's a one-way road
and it's a heavy traffic day!
It'll take forever to turn around!
It'll be faster on foot! Stop the car!
H-Heiji-kun!
Watch it!
Sorry!
Hey! Lady! We're with that
cop who called earlier! Open up!
It's unlocked!
Hey! Lady!
Hey!
Lady! Where are you?!
This is Sakata.
Eh?! Okazaki-san isn't home?!
Nope. The place is empty.
That's crazy! I told her not to leave!
Did she contact you at all?
Of course not. I didn't give her my number.
Oh, right.
Anyway, hurry here. Something's not right.
I just got off the one-way road,
so I'll be there in a few minutes.
It's from downstairs!
The public restroom!
D-Don't tell me she...!
Too late. She's dead.
But why?! Why did she go outside?!
And there's a knife
through her wallet and chest...
Who's doing this?! And why?!
The victim is Sumie Okazaki-san, age 39.
She was strangled to
death with a rope of some sort.
She appears to have been
stabbed after being strangled.
What time did you find the body?
Three or four minutes before you arrived.
This bathroom cleaner guy found her.
But why does the killer
stab their wallets every time?
You told this lady not to go outside,
but it looks like she died here.
Come to the Shinsai Bridge now if
you want to see some old friends.
1:08 PM.
See that? You're the next to wind up like that.
1:10 PM.
There's no question that's the killer!
In other words, the lady
heard the first message
and went to the Shinsai Bridge.
Then, when she came back,
she heard the second message
and trembled in fear inside.
But what does "old friends" mean?
Could it refer to the people
who've been killed so far?
Detective Sakata.
There's a call from headquarters.
Oh, thanks.
Hey, Hattori. These answering
machine messages are strange.
How so?
The times and the contents of the messages.
There were only two minutes
between the "come" message
and the "see that" message.
Does that mean the killer was watching her?
Something's odd about these four murders.
I get a bad feeling that the
killer is playing with us...
Bad feeling?
Kudo!
What?!
N-Nothing! Don't sweat it!
Yikes! I just remembered that
ominous dream from the other day!
So, Heiji-kun. Where to next?
Shall we visit Goshi-san's office?
Heiji-kun?
Oh, right.
These sure are strange cases.
There are no witnesses and it's
not clear how they're all connected,
yet we can ID the victims easily enough.
Yeah, now that you mention it.
The victims' names were on the
news right after the first two killings.
That's only natural.
All four had their driver's
licenses in their stabbed wallets.
Driver's licenses? That's it!
So all four have clean driving records...
Yes.
I thought there might be a car
connection. Guess I was wrong again.
They also all got their licenses
different years at different places.
Hey. It says Okazaki-san learned
to drive in Hyogo and not Osaka.
So it does.
Why that far away?
Oh, that place is famous for
its cheap license school.
License school?! Does that mean...?!
...If you want to see some old friends.
There's her friends!
Do you have the number for that place, Mister?
Yes.
Sumie Okazaki and Tayo Nishiguchi
shared a room at the school?!
Seriously?!
Alright! We're starting to
connect the four victims now!
But... isn't it strange?
Okazaki-san got her license that same year,
but Nishiguchi-san got his three years later.
Maybe he sucked at driving
and didn't graduate that year?
That's crazy!
You're really sure about that?!
Huh?! What is it?!
The others were at that
school 20 years ago, too!
The first victim, Hidetoshi Nagao-san,
the third victim, Kazuto Noyasu-san,
and Assemblyman Sotaro Goshi-san!
They were all at the same place!
What?!
And that's not all.
There was also a man whose
name is all too familiar now.
Familiar?! Who?!
N-Numabuchi. Ki'ichiro Numabuchi.
Ki'ichiro Numabuchi? You don't mean...!
The robber and murderer...
...who's on the run?!
Here it comes! The school photo!
No question about it! It's Numabuchi!
The faces and names of
the other five match, too!
But this is strange!
"August 23, 1978 graduates"
See? It says they all graduated then...
...but only Okazaki-san
went on to get her license.
Something happened at this
school 20 years ago. Something...
I see. Thanks.
None of the current staff know
anything that happened 20 years ago.
I figured as much.
But there had to have
been some sort of incident
involving that training ground 20 years ago.
Bingo! This is it!
"Driving Instructor Dies in Accident"
"Drunk Driving Suspected"
On that day 20 years ago
when those six graduated,
one of the instructors died
in a drunk driving accident!
His name was Tetsuji Inaba.
The strictest instructor at the school...
Hey, how does this sound to you?
Numabuchi, broke and in trouble,
decided to use the old incident
to blackmail the assemblyman
out of money but was refused.
So he killed off everyone
involved in the incident
and then repeated his threat.
That, or Goshi used
Numabuchi to kill off everyone
to keep the scandal from interfering
with his Diet member campaign.
Both sound plausible enough.
When Nagao-san and Noyasu-san
quit working for him,
they received a lot of severance pay.
Mention the instructor's death
and his companions back then,
and I bet that cop-hater will start talking!
Okay! Let's go!
Conan-kun! What are you doing here?!
You suddenly disappeared!
Oh no! I forgot to call!
Hey, Hei-chan! Long time, no see!
Otaki-han from headquarters?!
Why are you here?!
Kazuha-chan asked me to be a driver.
Sakata-san called us about the glasses boy.
Now why'd you do that?
Must be convenient, always having
the cops at your beck and call!
Who're you to talk?! You were
touring Osaka in a police car!
Now, now!
I can drive the boy to the
chief's house if you'd like.
Shall we go?
No! I wanna stay with Heiji-niichan!
Just a minute, Otaki-han.
This is Osaka. Just leave this
to us and go on your way, Kudo!
But knowing you, you'll just
find a way to butt in again.
Fine, then. I'll let you hold onto this.
Your good luck charm?
In exchange, hold yourself
back as much as you can today.
When I come home, I'll tell
you all about what happened!
'Kay?
Conan-kun! Hurry up!
Don't worry. I won't let
them mess with Osaka anymore!
I bet my life on it!
See you later!
Who's he talking to?
I'm starving...
We'll be at the chief's house
in Neyagawa in half an hour...
Heiji's mom is making blowfish stew tonight!
Oh?!
I can't wait!
Otaki.
What?!
You found the car of Numabuchi, the fugitive,
in the Mino mountains?!
I'll be right there!
Sorry, Mouri-han, but you'll have to
wait longer for the blowfish stew.
I'm taking a side trip!
Sorry! I'll have a youngster
come get you in a minute.
Okay...
Isn't Numabuchi that
murderer who escaped with a gun?
Things have gotten really bad. Right, Conan...?
Conan-kun!
How's it look?
Oh, Inspector Otaki!
We found the car covered in
plants, but Numabuchi is still...
And that shack?
It was empty when I peeked inside.
Maybe he ditched the car
and ran off somewhere else?
He's in there.
L-Little boy! When did you get here?!
Have a look here!
I found these burned at the bottom of this can.
See? Convenience store receipts
from five and three days ago,
and stickers from lots of convenience
store lunches that expire today.
Not many people would eat
convenience store lunches
at a place like this every day, right?
But, boy, if a wanted man
showed up at a convenience store...
Someone else probably bought it.
Someone's sheltering him.
For some reason...
Hey! You find Numabuchi?!
Well?!
No! There are signs that
someone lived here awhile ago, but...
There's mud on the windowsill!
That pillar and those
beams are free of cobwebs...
I see! He stood on the windowsill and...
S-Stop, little boy!
Oh?! It looks like this leads to the attic!
Wait, boy! Leave the rest to us!
Numabuchi!
Ki'ichiro Numabuchi! You're under
arrest for robbery and murder!
F-Food!
Hurry, give me food!
What?! Old man Goshi won't come out?!
No, he's kept us waiting
in here since this evening.
I'll go see him myself!
Now, now! Please simmer down
and let my senior save face!
Sir! We can't keep the police
detectives waiting any longer!
Forget 'em. They'll give
up and leave eventually.
Shall I at least tell them about the
phone call with the strange voice?
N-No! I absolutely can't...
Let's make a deal in one hour
about the incident 20 years ago.
Go out the back gate and
wait in the far storehouse.
We absolutely can't tell them!
Sheesh! I told you to stop
scampering around, Conan-kun!
All you do is worry me...
Sorry.
Come on! Get walking!
Hey!
Hey, you alright?
Hey, you!
Outta the way!
It's no use!
Conan-kun!
Conan-kun! Hang in there! Conan-kun!
It can't be...!
What is it, Heiji-kun?
Oh, nothing!
Huh? Where's Sakata-han?
He just left to use the bathroom.
I should probably go, too.
Conan-kun! Conan-kun!
Someone rush him to the hospital!
Yes, sir!
I'm okay... It only pricked me!
That can't be! The knife went...!
A good luck charm?
It must be thanks to the good
luck charm Heiji-niichan lent me!
Heiji's?
See? The knife got caught in the
chain link, so it couldn't stab me!
Never do that again!
Up, you!
No funny business!
Why does he have two
handcuffs on his left hand?
Oh, this? I'm not sure why, but
he was handcuffed to a pillar.
We had to get him free, so we cut
the chain and put our cuffs on him.
He was handcuffed?!
Looks like you were right about
someone bringing him food, kid.
Wait a minute!
It couldn't be! It couldn't be!
It couldn't be!
Oh no!
Wait all you want, old man Goshi won't come.
Sakata-han. You're the
serial murderer, aren't you?!
P-Please don't joke like that!
I was just admiring how
unusual this storehouse is!
First, when the body fell onto the cop car...
You craftily took us there.
Mere moments before we exited
the restaurant, you made a call
and put the special set-up in action.
Then, while I was on the roof, you
called Okazaki-san to the scene,
left a threatening call on her
machine when you knew she was gone,
and led her to hole up in her apartment.
After you had me witness her
and made an impression on her,
you brought up the topic and called
her after passing her apartment.
Then, after I heard her frightened
voice and leapt from the car,
you parked the car in an alley and
called her again while chasing me.
I'm the detective who just
called! You're in danger there!
Please wait in the nearby
public restroom! Got it?!
And then, while we were in her room,
you killed her in the restroom!
You were able to arrive by car
immediately after she was found
because you had rented two
cars of the exact same model!
After you killed her, you got in
the other rental car that was nearby
to make it look like you'd just
gotten there after some time.
You drove for us and got us
closer to the heart of the case
to get everyone here so you
could kill old man Goshi!
He's a prefectural assemblyman.
He'd stand out if he left his home.
And he could even take bodyguards with him.
But if you came here with us,
you could wander around freely.
When you did you realize it, Heiji-kun?
The rental cars' side-view
mirrors were the first thing.
It was at a different angle the second time.
And then I noticed the instructor
in the picture from 20 years ago
looked a lot like you.
It was your habit in the car
that finally convinced me.
You fiddled with the rear-view mirror
the same way Noyasu-san
and Okazaki-san did!
That's proof you'd all been
involved with the same person.
I don't know what happened 20 years ago,
but shouldn't you turn
yourself in, Sakata-han?
I'm sorry, Heiji-kun.
It's all over at this point...
Y-You idiot!
Sakata is the killer?!
That's right! Numabuchi told us everything!
After he committed the murders,
he planned to frame Numabuchi
and then kill him in a fake suicide!
Where's Sakata?!
H-He's been gone awhile...
There, it's empty! Now you
can't do anything stupid!
A bullet hit your leg?!
N-Never mind me, Heiji-kun...
Hurry and escape!
No can do... Looks like I got hit, too...
He was my father...
The instructor who died 20 years ago.
He was a strict driver,
and was always telling my
mother to check the rear-view mirror.
That's probably where I got it from.
Do you think someone like
that would drive drunk?!
And then I became a police detective...
to expose the truth of my father's death!
I solved the mystery when I found
Numabuchi in a mountain shack.
I look like my father, so the
instant he saw me, he grew frightened
and blurted everything out.
F-Forgive me, Instructor Inaba!
It was just a prank!
We just wanted to see your scared face
when we forced you to drink and
drive a car without brake fluid!
And then you went after all
six people who took part in it?
The statute of limitations
for murder is 15 years.
So I decided that if the law
can't punish them, I would!
I'm sorry I dragged you into this, Heiji-kun.
D-Don't talk like that!
You're a cop! You're the only ones
in Japan allowed to carry guns!
Why don't you feel any pride for that?!
Get up, Sakata!
You put the cherry blossom
emblem on your notebook to shame!
O-Otaki-san...
How's Heiji-kun?!
They took him away in
another ambulance just now.
He's really something. He carried
you out of that fire on his back.
Yes...
Is this the homicidal
maniac who tried to kill me?!
Why, you...!
He is still my subordinate. Hands off.
O-Old man Toyama!
I'll pay a visit later, Goshi-san.
When I do, we can talk about
what happened 20 years ago.
Heiji! Hang in there!
Heiji!
How's Hattori-kun's injury?
Can't tell yet.
We have to get the bullet out.
B-Bullet?
Did Sakata-san shoot you?
No, he didn't!
I was trying to stop him from committing suicide, and I kinda got shot.
Why?
Why did you have to put yourself in such danger?
S-Some dummy I know once told me...
a detective must never hound a criminal to his death.
Hattori...
Oh...I can't...stay awake...
Let me sleep just a little...
No! You can't fall asleep, Heiji!
Heiji!
No...
Shaddup!
Didn't you hear me, you damn moron?! I wanna sleep!
He sure has a lot of energy. He'll be okay.
I didn't sleep last night. I was up planning the Osaka tour!
Don't jinx me with your banshee moans!
Well, excuse me for sounding like a banshee!
What do you think you're doin', stupid?
Who are you calling stupid? You're the one flopping all over the ambulance!
Now, now, you two.
Hey, I'm injured here!
Ain't that just great?
I doubt he'll croak anytime soon.
NEXT EPISODE
No!
Stop, Conan-kun!
Why?
This was a bonafide murder.
Plotted by a certain someone from the start.
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Model Gun
Look forward to the next episode!
The next episode airs October 12!
Read Sunday!
You'll wait for us, right?