Encounters are mysterious!
But the world is even more so!
I'm so glad I'm with you!
Today is finally Kamen Yaiba!
Inside the costume is an incident!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Oh? You're eating out today, Conan-kun?
Yeah. I'm meeting them
in front of this shrine at 6:00.
You're so lucky. Is it eel?
No. I think a good curry restaurant opened up near here.
I love curry!
Let's eat, too!
I want a jumbo fried shrimp curry!
Geez, you guys...
The Laser Police!
Laser Police?
The police squad in Kamen Yaiba!
H-Hi, kids. Are you fans of Kamen Yaiba?
I love Kamen Yaiba!
Does this mean they're filming Kamen Yaiba at this shrine?!
Oh, no, it's not like that...
This gun's so cool!
Don't touch that!
Sorry!
This gun is important for fighting monsters, so only I can touch it.
Bye!
What's the big deal?
Conan-kun! Been waiting long?
No, I just got here.
What's with you guys?
They want to eat curry with us!
What?!
Oh, come on! The more the merrier!
And who's gonna pay for 'em?
You.
Oh, but call your moms first, so they won't worry!
Okay!
Geez!
What kind of parents are they,
all saying, "That would be great!"?!
Look!
It's Kamen Yaiba!
Yaiba Kick!
Awesome! Awesome!
So cool!
This is like a dream!
First the Laser Police, and now Kamen Yaiba? What's with today?
Oh! Aren't you Kogoro Mouri-san,
the great detective?!
Yes, that's me...
Wow! This is incredible! I'm a big fan!
Let me shake your hand!
Look! He's shaking hands with Kamen Yaiba!
No, I'm not the real Kamen Yaiba.
Yasuyuki Tsutsumi (21)
Jonan University, Law Dept.
I'm Yasuyuki Tsutsumi, and I'm a member of a college fan club.
He's right! He isn't Kamen Yaiba!
Yes, the real one looks a lot more handsome.
Sorry for disappointing you.
Then that other person was also...
Say! Want to come to a party?
Party?
Our fan club is having a costume party!
Wow! That sounds like fun!
I'd love to go!
Go! Go!
Now I won't have to pay for their food!
You're invited too, Mouri-san!
There'll be beer, too!
B-Beer?! I'd love to! I'd love to!
Now you won't have to pay for your beer!
The party is in the basement of this mansion!
Look at all the monsters!
Even Monkeyshroom and Pork-n-Bones are here!
The Moletian, too!
Mouri-san. Let me introduce you.
This is our club's president, Madoka Saotome-san. This is her house.
Are you a college student?
Yes! I'm in my 3rd year studying literature!
Madoka Saotome (21)
Shirakaba Women's College, Lit. Dept.
It's an honor to speak with the great Mouri-san!
It's my pleasure!
I can recount my humble exploits anytime you want, day or night!
Do you know who she's dressed up as?
Yeah! Rei Natsume, right?
Correct! You must tune in a lot!
Have you ever watched Kamen Yaiba, Mouri-san?
I'd really like to, but I'm so busy with work that time of day...
More like drinking that time of day...
Kamen Yaiba is really a young man who sells hot dogs at the park
with Rei Natsume, his childhood friend!
Each time an incident occurs,
he rushes there on his motorcycle
and fights the evil bad guys and aliens!
But Rei Natsume doesn't know his secret identity!
So he's always ditching work to rush off on his motorcycle!
Even so, Rei Natsume forgives him with gentle feelings!
For some reason, I somehow know how that feels...
Come to think of it, that does sound kind of like me and Ran...
Okay, everyone! Let's go to the tables!
We have some juice!
Yay!
What about me, Madoka-san?
She loves kids.
Oh, I wish I could be a kid again!
I wish I could be an adult again!
Hey there, Honda! You're late!
Yeah, sorry. It took longer than I thought.
Osamu Honda (21)
Jonan Univ., Engineering Dept.
He's that other guy. I guess he is a member of the fan club.
Huh? Why're you dressed like that?
I thought I'd change things up a bit.
What a shock. You've only ever dressed as Kamen Yaiba before.
Oh, yeah! This is Kogoro Mouri-san, the famous detective!
M-Mouri?
He's Osamu Honda. He's in his 3rd year of engineering at Jonan U.
He's only been in the club half a year,
but he's a very passionate Kamen Yaiba fan!
That gun wouldn't happen to be real, would it?
Don't be silly! It's only a model! See for yourself!
I bet it's well-made! He's a real gun fanatic!
The texture and weight are impressive...
The bullets are all blanks.
The barrel is plugged too, of course.
Indeed.
Mouri-san! Won't you come and tell us a story?
Yes, Madoka-san! Right away!
What a nice reply.
Yes.
Come over to the tables, too!
Okay!
Honda!
Katsuji Mishima (21)
Tohto University, P.E. Dept.
I've had enough! Get ready, Honda! I'm gonna kill you!
Mishima-kun?!
W-Wait, Mishima! What did I ever do?!
I can't stand you anymore!
Calm down, Mishima! Let's talk it over!
Shut up! Die!
Honda-kun!
- No!
- Stop, Conan-kun!
Mishima!
What the hell?!
What?!
A bulletproof vest...
Wearing this saved me...
Honda!
Honda-kun! Are you okay?!
Don't move!
There's no burn mark on his temple!
Come to think of it, he kept the gun away from his head when he shot.
Why?
The deceased is Katsuji Mishima-san, age 21.
A 3rd year student at Tohto U.'s physical education department.
Inspector.
This was a genuine suicide.
After all, we all witnessed it.
Still... this is a rather odd sight...
The Laser Police always wear these vests when fighting monsters,
so I bought one from a security store.
So, convinced he'd killed you,
Mishima-san then shot himself in the head?
But why would he try to kill you?
That's because...
Inspector.
Honda-kun and Mishima-kun
were actually very good friends.
So what happened?
About ten days ago, when we had gathered to plan this party,
Mishima-kun got mad at an off-hand comment by Honda-kun
and stormed out.
What did you say to him?
I told him, "Your motorcycle is lame."
That's it?!
That's absurd! Nobody would be driven to murder because of that!
No, it's not as crazy as it sounds.
He was especially obsessive about Kamen Yaiba, even among us.
He spent half a year remodeling a normal motorcycle
into a Kamen Yaiba motorcycle.
So I can understand why making fun of it would make him mad.
I see...
I guess that's the only way to explain it.
His explanation seems truthful enough.
But something bugs me!
There's something about this incident!
Inspector Megure. The gun
was a modified model gun.
The bullet in the bulletproof vest
was also made by hand.
Thank you.
Was Mishima-san knowledgeable about guns at all?
I don't believe so.
He once asked me the difference
between automatics and revolvers.
Come to think of it,
do all Kamen Yaiba members...?
Hey, what characters in Kamen Yaiba carry guns?
Only the Laser Police carry guns, duh!
Kamen Yaiba himself doesn't?
Conan-kun! Kamen Yaiba has no need for guns!
He always fights with his bare hands!
I thought so!
Still, that leaves too many things unclear...
It sure is shocking to see something like this happen, though.
That's for sure. I guess TV dramas
aren't entirely fiction after all.
Dramas? Acting?
All the mysteries connect now!
This was a murder!
If my theory is correct, it solves all the mysteries.
Damn... Committing a murder right in front of me...
Unforgivable!
Proof! I need to find undeniable proof!
That's it! As I recall...!
Genta! Let me borrow your Detective Boys badge for a minute!
Huh? Mine?
Mouri-san did?
Yeah. He asked me to get it examined right away. Says it's urgent.
Inspector. I'd like to take Honda to the hospital...
Oh, right.
Even with the bulletproof vest on,
he was shot from close range.
He could have a cracked rib.
Let's drive him there right away.
Huh? W-Why...?
Not so fast, Inspector.
Please wait until later to take him to the hospital.
Allow me to solve the mystery of
this detestable murder for you.
What're you talking about, Mouri-kun?
Didn't Mishima-san commit suicide?
No. This was a bonafide murder.
Plotted by a certain someone from the start.
Come again?!
This someone suggested to Mishima-san
that they act out a little play
to surprise everyone at the party.
Act?
In it, Mishima-san would pretend
to shoot someone, then kill himself.
To lay the groundwork for this,
they had a fake argument beforehand.
Yes. That someone was you, Osamu Honda-san!
What?
First, you modified two model guns of the same type
and prepared two types of bullets.
One type was a real lead bullet.
The other was an empty "blank."
You initially gave Mishima-san
the gun with the blanks.
Today, before the party began,
you met him at the Beika Shrine
and switched his gun
with the gun with real bullets.
Probably by saying you were doing final checks.
Then the gun on Honda-san's hip is Mishima-san's?!
No, wait. Wasn't the barrel of that gun plugged?
Plus, the gun with real bullets wasn't plugged...
Wouldn't Mishima-san have noticed?
No. The gun he handed Mishima-san wasn't plugged.
He plugged it after the switch,
so he wouldn't rouse suspicion after the fact.
Honda-san dressed up as a Laser Police member
instead of his usual choice of Kamen Yaiba
because it wouldn't seem strange for a Laser Police member
to carry a gun and wear a bulletproof vest.
When Mishima-san jumped down,
you moved as if taking us out of harm's way,
but it was actually to make you an easier target for him.
B-But, Mouri-san!
Wouldn't Mishima know something was up if a real bullet came out?
He and Honda-san had probably done rehearsals
in which he would pretend to be hit the same time the gun sounded.
So, after seeing Honda-san being "hit" this time,
Mishima-san believed it was just like it was during rehearsal.
It's your so-called "autosuggestion."
But do you have any evidence that he didn't commit suicide?
If you were to kill yourself by putting a gun to your head and firing,
burn marks would be left on your head.
However, there were none on Mishima-san.
Even with blanks, it still produces a small flame.
Which is why he held the gun slightly away from his head,
to prevent being burned.
You can't be sure about that! He was a weird guy!
Then allow me to show you some proof.
Examiner!
Another set of fingerprints not belonging to the late Mishima-san
was found on this gun.
They also match the child fingerprints on this badge.
Oh! That badge!
That's Genta-kun's!
Which means...
...I'm the killer?
Genta-kun! When did you touch Mishima-san's gun?!
I-I didn't!
Yes.
If Genta didn't touch Mishima-san's gun,
how did his prints get on it?
The answer to that is... Conan!
Right!
Honda-san.
You ran into us at the Beika Shrine
before coming here, right?
And then Genta...
This gun's so cool!
Don't touch that!
H-He touched it then?
The fact you had Mishima-san's gun then
is evidence that you switched your guns later!
Honda-kun...
Mouri-san. When did you start to suspect me?
Tsutsumi-san said that you were a real gun aficionado.
Yet, you had a plugged gun. That seemed odd to me.
I see. Plugging the gun to be extra safe proved to be my downfall...
Mishima... killed my kid brother!
Two years ago, my brother Hiroshi was heading to a friend's house
To Hiroshi-kun
Kamen Yaiba
with a Kamen Yaiba signboard that he won in a magazine contest.
Wait! Give it back!
Hiroshi died two days later.
His final words were,
"Get Kamen Yaiba to catch him..."
I joined a number of Kamen Yaiba fan clubs to gather information
and figure out who stole it!
Then, half a year ago...
...Mishima finally showed me that signboard!
He said his older brother
had won it and given it to him!
But he doesn't have a brother named Hiroshi!
So then you got your revenge on him?
Inspector. It's not discussed in the TV drama,
but Kamen Yaiba has a back story
in which his sister was killed.
I joined fan clubs to kill the person who drove my brother to death,
but at some point, I began
to feel just like Kamen Yaiba.
You and Kamen Yaiba are nothing alike!
Kamen Yaiba doesn't fight for revenge!
Yeah! He fights for justice!
Yes. The children are right.
It's a shame you were that wrong about Kamen Yaiba all along.
Oh! Yoko-chan's on a music show starting at 7:30!
Oh, but we're watching Kamen Yaiba at 7:30.
What?! We never watch that junk!
We decided to watch it starting tonight!
After all, Kamen Yaiba fights for justice!
We gotta support him!
Right, Conan-kun?
Don't be stupid! What about Yoko-chan?!
What about her?
S-She's singing for me!
This old guy's gonna live a long life...
T-That was President Yamazaki!
What's this sticky stuff?!
So it was a completely locked room...
This might not have been an accident!
It's possible it was a murder plotted by one of these people!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Balloon
The next case tastes like honey!
hachimitsu
24!
Huh? Why?
8×3, right?
hachi ga mitsu