Alibis, codes, tricks, deals.
The mysterious Black Organization.
Today we solve the sniper case!
Even the crime and its motive are full of mysteries!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Invited to participate in the sumo wrestling celebration party, uncle
Accepted the investigation commissioned by Mr. Ishimoto Seiji.
Mr. Ishimoto received a letter threatening to take his life.
When the party got dark,
Politician Takada was about to give a speech.
As Takada Masao was passing by,
Bullets fired from the lighting control room.
Grazing Ishimoto's shoulder and ending up
In the middle of Politician Takada's chest.
In the chaos,
I saw a suspicious person fleeing from the lighting control room.
Then the next day,
The man who specializes in intimidating for money, Hiraoka Shiro
Was found dead in an abandoned building.
I see.
We have unwittingly fallen into a trap.
But I will find the evidence.
From the pile of complexly tangled threads...
I will find the thread of truth!
The Mysterious Sniper Murder Case
(Part 2)
The top floor.
That's the president's office.
It's Niikura-san, personal secretary
of the late Politician Takada.
Hiraoka Shiro?
I don't know this man at all.
Considering the fact you received a death threat...
And someone definitely attempted to take your life...
Furthermore, the bullet that missed you
hit Politician Takada in the chest...
Causing his death!
This could be a murder case.
To be honest...
President!
It's all right, Yukiko-kun.
I can't keep it secret for much longer.
Like you said, I was indeed threatened by Hiraoka.
It'd be inconvenient if I exposed your
secret account, don't you think?
If that happened, you'd be arrested on tax evasion...
And your company's reputation would go down the drain.
Even so, you can't just demand a billion yen from me!
I'm giving you a good price.
How much did you earn, Ishimoto-san?
I considered paying him, but I refused in the end.
If you give that guy money one
time, he'll ask for more later.
That's why I asked Mouri-san to protect me.
I never thought I would've caused the
innocent death of Politician Takada.
I was told that by Secretary Niikura.
Niikura-san?
He told me not to let Politician Takada die in vain.
He came here earlier and told me to
tell the police everything I know.
Huh?
Little boy, what's wrong?
I'm...
Conan, how did you get over here!?
Ran-neechan told me to bring you your clothes.
Ishimoto-san, please come
with us to the police station.
Yes.
By saying that, does that mean I...
It was for a short time, but thank you for your service.
I knew it...
Such bad luck...
Never thought the case would be solved this quickly...
If you think your luck is bad, then
Hiraoka's luck must be terrible!
Because he was aiming for Ishimoto-san,
but ended up shooting the wrong guy.
And in the end, he fell down some stairs to his death.
His luck was pretty awful!
He sure had bad luck.
Or rather, too many coincidences there.
Perhaps Hiraoka had an accomplice...
And Hiraoka was merely killed
off because of his failure.
That means Ishimoto-san is still in danger!
Yukiko-san, my work still isn't finished!
Wait, Uncle!
Forget it...
Now's my chance.
Sorry about that.
Are you all right?
Then, if you'll excuse me.
Someone's coming.
That man?
I'm sure that after Politician Takada was killed...
He was talking with Yukiko-san in the event hall.
That's...
What's his relationship to Yukiko-san?
Beyond that, what's that remote control for?
Could it be?
If Hiraoka had suspected that the culprit had
only hired him to set him up as the murderer...
No, even if he didn't suspect it...
Hiraoka was a blackmailer to begin with.
He probably concealed some
important evidence just in case.
Why is there a hole here?
Yukiko-san...
I'm home!
Conan-kun, where have you been?
Just went out for a bit.
Uncle, what happened to guarding Ishimoto-san?
He's with the police and won't be needing me.
I want to closely guard Yukiko-san now!
Hey, hey, is that all you can think about, Uncle?
Sorry to intrude, Mouri-kun.
Inspector Megure!
Inspector!
Actually, there was something
l wanted to confirm with you.
Here you go.
Sorry about that, Ran-kun.
Well, Inspector...
What is it you want to confirm with me?
Last night, you personally saw Ishimoto to the hospital.
After that, how long did his secretary,
Tanaka Yukiko-san, stay there?
Yukiko-san, you say?
About that, I remember...
After Ishimoto-san went back to his hospital room...
I was drinking cola and chatting with her.
That was about the time you called me, Inspector.
After that, I got all dazed and fell asleep...
I woke up around the time you
called me in the morning.
At that point, I didn't see
Yukiko-san in the hospital room.
That means that you don't know
when Yukiko-san left the hospital?
Inspector, you can't mean...
What you said means that Yukiko-san
had plenty of time to kill Hiraoka.
That's ridiculous!
How could someone as pretty
as Yukiko-san kill Hiraoka!?
I'm only saying that the possibility exists.
Because right now we can't confirm whether
Hiraoka's death was an accident or a murder.
That's just stupid.
Why would Yukiko-san kill him?
Actually, Yukiko-san has a
boyfriend named Shibata Kenichi.
A boyfriend!?
What, is something on your mind?
Nothing, nothing at all.
That man's father committed suicide.
Suicide?
The reason was because the company he
owned was brought down by Ishimoto.
Because of that, Shibata developed
a grudge against Ishimoto.
Since Yukiko-san is his girlfriend, there's
a chance that she hated Ishimoto too.
But Yukiko-san would never be someone like that...
Say, what kind of person is Shibata-san?
Here's a picture of him.
As I thought.
This guy... I think I've seen him before.
Really, Mouri-kun?
I think it was pretty recently...
That's right!
I see, so that's how it was.
Inspector...
Please bring everyone involved with the
case into the event hall from last night.
What's this?
The great detective Mouri Kogoro...
Shall solve the mystery of this case for you to see!
Geez, after Takada-sensei died, I was
left with a lot of things to deal with.
Niikura Tsuneaki (32)
Politician Takada's Secretary
Is it a joke to call me out now?
Shibata Kenichi (29)
Tanaka Yukiko's Boyfriend
Why was I called here even though
I have nothing to do with this!?
Tanaka Yukiko (25)
President Ishimoto's Secretary
Kenichi-san, calm down.
It'll be over soon.
Ishimoto Seiji (54)
Ishimoto Precision Device President
Wasn't this murder case already solved?
We're about to get to that in a moment.
Although we shouldn't have brought you
here in the middle of a police inquiry...
My apologies for having you wait.
Mouri-kun!
You're all gathered here today so that, at the
scene where Politician Takada was killed...
I can reveal the identity of the real culprit.
Wasn't the killer Hiraoka, who died by accident?
No.
Hiraoka was merely used by the true
culprit and was killed in the end.
In that case, hurry up and tell us the
name of the real culprit or whatnot.
The committee meeting has already started.
I have to get back to work, too.
If you don't hurry up, I'm leaving.
Very well, I will reveal everything to you all.
The real culprit... is you!
You planned to kill Ishimoto-san to avenge your
father's suicide, so you spent money to hire Hiraoka.
But, Hiraoka failed to kill Ishimoto-san.
That's why you used last night to silence Hiraoka.
Hold on.
I may hold some hatred for Ishimoto,
and I was at the party last night...
But I've never seen this Hiraoka guy's face.
And, right after I left last
night, I went straight to work.
I didn't even go anywhere else.
Well, it's about time I went back to
work, so why don't you join me?
There are plenty of people who can confirm my alibi.
Oh, no...
He's hopeless.
This is happening again...
Mouri-san!
What's wrong, Uncle?
Are you OK?
I'm only sitting because I'm
going to be talking for a while.
You go somewhere else!
All right.
All I just said was a joke.
Before I reveal the identity of the real culprit,
we'll go over exactly what happened last night.
Let us start from when Politician
Takada was walking up to the stage.
Now, everyone, please return to your
exact positions from last night.
As for politician Takada, we'll
have the inspector play his role.
Me?
Yes, that's right.
Fine with me.
And Inspector, please attach the
microphone on the table to your chest.
Microphone?
Right.
It's the same type Politician
Takada had on him last night.
Mr. Detective, what am I supposed to do then?
You can just stand against the wall.
OK.
Now, let's begin.
Lighting guy, please turn off the
lights and ready the spotlight.
All right, Niikura-san.
Please walk as if you were leading
Politician Takada forward.
Takagi-san?
What's up, Conan-kun?
Uncle Mouri wants you to go to
the lighting control box now.
Say, the remote control is with you now, right?
Uncle Mouri already saw through everything.
When I give the signal, I want you to use the remote.
Now!
That was only a blank.
Afterwards, the bullet would graze Ishimoto-san's
shoulder and go through the inspector's chest.
What does that mean?
Please turn on the lights.
What?
No...
Takagi-kun!
Did you shoot the gun!?
I didn't do anything!
This is...
There's a gun strapped onto one of the lights!
What!?
And, taped to the gun is a motor
that's tied to the trigger by a string.
If the motor were to start, it would
wind the string, pulling the trigger!
Mouri-kun, what's going on?
This means that Hiraoka wasn't
the one who fired the gun...
It was the gun strapped to the light all along!
This event hall has one of the most
state-of-the-art lighting systems available.
That spotlight will respond to the movement
of the microphone on the inspector...
And automatically follow him wherever he goes.
I see.
In other words, if the culprit set it up so that
they could remotely control the motor...
They would be free to fire the gun anytime...
With it aimed at Politician Takada's chest.
What are you talking about, Mouri-san?
It was Ishimoto-san that was targeted!
He received threats!
The culprit only did that to fool the police.
In reality, the target was Politician
Takada from the beginning.
This culprit first sent Ishimoto-san a written threat...
To make everyone believe that there was someone
who wanted to take Ishimoto-san's life.
Later, they utilized the fact that the spotlight
would follow the microphone he was wearing...
So that the moment he passed by Ishimoto-san...
With this, everyone would think that the
bullet meant for Ishimoto-san missed...
And Politician Takada was killed instead.
Afterwards, Hiraoka retrieved
the gun and motor, and fled.
Then, who is this person that killed Politician Takada?
It's Ishimoto!
It's Ishimoto who killed Politician Takada.
What the hell!?
Don't talk nonsense!
No use feigning innocence.
I already have the evidence.
What is that?
It's the remote that controlled the motor on the gun.
I found it at your company.
What?
Hey, is that true?
You played your hand well, Ishimoto.
You pretended that you were threatened by Hiraoka,
but actually you two were in on this together.
That's why, when Politician Takada passed by
you yesterday, you used the remote to kill him.
Isn't that so, Mr. Detective?
Shibata-san, there's a crucial flaw in your deduction.
What?
Think about it.
The reason Takada passed by Ishimoto-san was
because he was being led by Niikura-san.
There was no way for Ishimoto-san to know
beforehand that they would pass by each other.
Then, why was the remote found in
Ishimoto-san's presidential office?
Everyone here, did you hear that?
Yeah, I heard it loud and clear.
I only said I found the remote at Ishimoto's company.
But I never mentioned anything
about his presidential office.
You dug yourself a hole, Niikura-san.
The culprit...
Is you!
You had been dubbed by everyone
as Politician Takada's successor.
But he wasn't planning to retire.
So you grew impatient and worked with
Hiraoka to devise a plan to kill him.
After it was complete, in an abandoned building...
You pushed Hiraoka down the stairs to silence him.
Then, you looked in vain for the motor,
which Hiraoka had hidden in the floor crack.
Frustrated, you came up with another idea.
Even if the police did find the motor by chance...
You could put the blame on someone else, so you
hid the remote in President Ishimoto's office.
That's ridiculous.
Can you really prove that the remote control is mine?
You're meticulous, I admit.
You probably even removed your fingerprints.
But only on the outside.
Do you remember?
Yesterday, while exchanging business
cards, you dropped the remote.
At the time, you put the battery back
inside the remote with your bare hands.
Looks like you remembered.
That's right, that battery has your fingerprints on it!
How...
How did this happen...
He's been like that ever since
he read Yukiko-san's letter.
Yukiko-san said she's starting over with Shibata-san.
I really wish Mom and Dad would start over, too...
This love ended too soon!
Uhm...
I was wondering if you could help me find someone...
Just leave it to me!
With the great detective Mouri Kogoro...
Be it finding someone or finding scandals...
It'll be a piece of cake, piece of pizza!
The old man recovered too quickly...
The chairman may be young,
but to treat him like that?
He was hit in the head...
Is this jar the weapon?
Next Conan:
The Traveling Drama Troupe Murder Case (Part 1)
Next Conan's hint!
Transfer student
The next episode is about a play.
Once upon a time, in a land...
Why did you end it there?