Alibis, codes, tricks, pacts.
The mysterious Black Organisation.
Today's stage is an actual stage.
And the play is a case scenario!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a child with the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
"The Travelling Drama Troupe Murder Case (Part I)"
"Teitan High"
Eh?! Drama Troupe Chairman?!
Ah, it's true! It says "Tamanosuke Itô will show a special performance to announce the new chairman."
So you're moving up in your career!
I guess. Before tonight's performance,
"Tamanosuke Itô (17)
Drama Troupe Chairman"
I want to dance 3 songs, changing clothes between each.
We'll go, we'll go! We'll definitely go!
Ahh, what shall I do?
How pretty...
But comedians like you who
travel through Japan are so lucky!
Yeah. We usually do repeat performances every one or two years in the same place, to thank our fans.
Eh? Then, does that mean you've come to Beika Theatre before?
Yeah. Two years ago.
But at the time my dad was the chairman, and I was just an actor. So we didn't announce it as much.
So your dad... died?
He died a year ago from cancer. Afterwards, only half of the troupe remained.
I'm ashamed to say it, but we've been through pretty bad times.
I'm sorry...
Don't worry! I'll go and warn everyone else to go too! You can count on me, so keep practicing as much as you can!
Thank you! Good luck!
And that's his story.
I know he's going to another school next month, but I want to help him as much as possible.
I suppose that's how he tricks people into advertising for him, huh?
That's not it! Advertising is just an excuse! What I want is to see the backstage!
Idiot! If you have so much time to waste, try to use it to study!
Sorry, I'll take Ran with me! Bye!
Hey!
Don't worry! Tamanosuke-san's a great person! There's no way he's a bad guy, right?
Besides, if we get in trouble, you'll give him one of your kicks and that's it!
What's that supposed to mean? I'm not your bodyguard!
Sorry, sorry. Let's hurry and go!
Hey, hey, Ran-neechan?
You again?
Can I go too?
- We'll go too!
- Let's go, let's go!
You can't! We'd be a bother if we all went.
But I promise I'll take you there later during the first performance.
We'll be back by lunch time!
He said to go through the personnel entry, but...
Look, isn't the main entrance open?
"Beika Theatre"
Let's go through it.
Eh?
I'm sure they're practicing.
Uh...
Wait, Sonoko!
It's okay, it's okay!
They're there, they're there!
So cool!
Hey, welcome!
Thank you!
Sorry to bother you.
Sorry to bother you!
Not at all. You kids too, welcome.
We told you guys not to come!
Eh, don't worry about it!
I'm glad you all came.
Really? You're so nice, Tamanosuke-san!
Allow me to introduce you.
Let's see... this guy can do it all: Ryûichi Muraki-san.
Yo!
Yuri Chirai-san, the lead girl.
A pleasure.
We're here to help distribute the leaflets. We're Sonoko and Ran!
Muraki-san, your acting was so awesome and cool!
"Ryûichi Muraki (26)
Actor"
Nowadays, if you don't have special skills,
the audience won't pay attention.
"Yuri Shirai (22)
Actress"
That's right. We were hired because
we were part of the high school gymnastics club, so we could do these.
That's not true... I'm sure you'll do fine!
Then we'll leave the rest to you.
So, can you come up this way?
Yes!
Chairman, could you hurry
with the script while you're at it?
I... I got it.
Sorry about this. You'll have to wait a bit more.
Geez...
We might as well have the theatre closed tomorrow...
Umm... We'll leave as soon as he's given us the leaflets.
We apologise.
Don't worry about it.
He's complaining because he doesn't have the final script for tomorrow's show.
But don't you have your first performance tomorrow?
Yeah, but we can't rent the theatre every day to practice,
so this always happens.
You really are busy.
But why are we doing a new performance instead of the original one?
Me... Megumi!
Oh, this is my little sister.
Hello!
I'm his little sister, Megumi, but
"Megumi Itô (7)
Tamanosuke's little sister"
since he's a disaster at everything, I'm more like his mother.
Nice to meet you!
Why you...
Anyway, everybody's angry with your selfishness.
Now's not the time to be
playing with pretty girls.
Hey, Megumi...
We're only staying for a bit to pick up the leaflets.
I'll take care of these people then.
And you go take care of the final script, Chairman.
Y- Yeah.
Hurry, go already!
Enjoy the backstage visit then.
See you later!
Geez...
Hey, hey. He says he's had bad times since his father died,
but isn't he just askin' for it?
If it isn't Edogawa-kun!
I'm so glad you're here!
Wait! How do you know Conan-kun's name?
Because I started going to Teitan Primary School with you guys today.
But you're not in our class, right?
I'm in Class C.
But since Conan-kun looks as lot like big brother when he was younger, I asked the other girls in my class what his name was.
I'm so happy!
I never thought I could be friends with Conan!
But what are you doing standing there?
I'll show you the room I have here in the theatre!
You guys can come too!
What's with that girl?
How cute... I see he's pretty popular.
Hold on, wait up!
I haven't gotten all of my stuff out yet. Let's see...
Hey...
I found it!
Here, look!
See? Doesn't he look like you?
So cute!
Hey, hey... Where on Earth does that look like me?!
What? Ain't that a cross-dresser [okama]?
It's an oyama.
(male actor playing a female character)
Let's see...
Tamanosuke-san was so cute!
It's true! He did look like Conan-kun!
Conan-kun would look so cute if he dressed like that!
Wouldn't he?
So, let's all go to the dressing rooms!
Here! Here, here, this way!
Kids are so innocent...
Oh?
Please let us take a look, Itoe-san!
Itoe Ogiwara-san is our accountant, though she's also an actress.
This is Conan Edogawa-kun, his friends, and his big sister!
"Itoe Ogiwara (28)
Actress and Accountant"
Nice to meet you.
Please, come on in.
As you can tell, I already took off the outfit. I was just heading to the workshop.
Is that kid your boyfriend, Megumi-chan?
No!
Oh, sorry.
Then he's yours, right?
You got it wrong again...
I'm a princess...
It's so funny!
Conan-kun, your turn!
Ran-neechan, let's hurry and go home!
Please!
It's a perfect chance! Why don't you try it on?
S-S-Stop it!
What?
Shut up!
What?!
Chairman!
Why you... What are you doing?!
Hm. We were just arguing over something.
Big brother!
Are you all right?
Y-Yeah.
I'm fine.
Big brother!
And what's with the scripts, Chikaishi-san?
They're done. I'm printing them out right now.
He told me to rewrite the last part,
"Tetsuo Chikaishi (35)
Writer for the Drama Troupe"
so I had to give him a good beating.
We have to teach him how life is while he's young, or he'll be useless once he's an adult.
Isn't that right, Tajima-san?
"Kenzô Tajima (45)
Actor"
We'll be better off if everyone knows their place.
Oh, I'm out of tobacco.
Tajima-san, can you go buy another pack for me?
Tajima-san, I'll go buy the tobacco.
No.
Tajima-san...
I won't forgive you for this, Chikaishi-sensei!
Megu, it's okay.
Chikaishi-san, why did you change the script from what we agreed?
The story is the story. And the drama is the drama. That's all I can say.
I get it.
We'll do as you say.
But we should start practicing right away.
I'm fine.
Once the script's printed out, make copies for everyone.
I'm going to rest in my room.
Tamanosuke-san...
What the...?
The chairman may be young, but to treat him like that?
What the hell's wrong with this troupe?
It's so cool! The sheets come one after the other!
It's done!
Mister, thanks for your hard work.
"The memoirs of Detective Itarô: The phantom thief, Edo Kid."
Eh?
This phantom thief, the "Edo Kid"...
Yeah. It's about the kid from the Edo era, about 400 years ago.
He's the protagonist in this story.
Here, boy. I'll take it.
Thank you, sensei.
Then I'll go and make the copies.
Yeah.
Well, I'm done.
I'll go take a nap now.
Hey, what are you guys doing?
These are articles on the Edo Kid, right?
What was this Edo Kid?
He's a thief who used to rob tons of places throughout Japan, especially Tôkyô.
He lived like a thief from the old era, hopping through roofs, doing acrobatic leaps and the like.
The police called him the "Ôedo Kid",
but when the media started talking about him, they called him the "Edo Kid".
Mister, did you pick Edo Kid as the protagonist in the play because you had actors capable of doing acrobatic stunts?
Yeah, of course. Though sometimes the police suspected us.
Those two even got interrogated
by the police at one point.
Well, I don't really know what's up with our chairman,
but I think he wanted to create
a new version of the Edo Kid.
Is that why you've been investigating about him?
Sort of. When I put this in my computer, I always get his profile.
Conan-kun, come here.
Oh? Apparently your cute sister's here for you.
You guys better go before I sock you a good one!
Sorry for bothering you!
Geez...
What were you doing with someone who treated Tamanosuke-san so horribly?
And Tamanosuke-san is...?
He's resting in his room.
He was really affected.
So, we're going home now.
We still have to hand out these leaflets, so follow us!
I don't wanna go home yet!
Since you're here, you're gonna help us hand these out.
We get it.
But that man went that way.
I think it's faster to go through the set.
But if we go this way, we'll be closer to the station.
Hurry up.
Is she going to invite us to anything in the station?
That's not it. It appears we're going to be assisting them to deliver leaflets.
Oh...
I'll invite you to something, so hurry up.
All right! A boxed eel lunch!
Thank you in advance!
Please!
I'm sure there's something hiding behind those people.
How many times have we told you not to ditch us, Conan?
Geez...
What happened to handing out the leaflets?
That old lady who works for a community just took them all.
Conan, you're not gonna fool us.
You wanted to lose us and go back to the theatre, right?
Right. That's the Detective Boys for you...
Yeah, I guess.
All right! I thought you'd gone back home!
Look, look! We're gonna start
rehearsing now! Wish me luck!
R-Right.
Where's the chairman?
I'm fine. Sorry about what happened before.
Tamanosuke-san, you look so pretty!
Look, it's Itarô!
Since the act's short, if you want, you can stay.
Yes! Thank you so much!
Look, look! There's a house there!
It's like a samurai movie on TV!
Look out! Don't move!
W- What's that hole doing there?
Sorry. It's an exit platform.
Be careful!
You don't want to fall in that hole! It's very deep and dangerous!
- Sorry
- We're sorry.
It's the thief! So cool!
1 minute and 40 seconds.
It takes too long for you to show up.
If he goes behind the curtain, down the stairs while changing clothes,
then goes back out that way,
it's like a really cool magic trick!
But he takes too long because he doesn't have anyone to help him change his clothes.
Hey! Stop talking about the troupe's secrets,
and show your friends where they can sit.
Yes!
These seats are the center-most ones, and where you can get the best view.
Megumi-chan, don't you have to practice, too?
That's right!
Don't go home and watch, okay?
- Good luck!
- Right! See you!
I wonder why Chikaishi-san changed the last scene in the script...
After doing the first rehearsal, they've been repeating it over and over.
"The Memoirs of Detective Itarô".
A story about Edo-era detective Itarô,
and his little sister, his assistant.
Together, they discover the identity of Japan's number one thief, the Edo Kid.
They suspect that one of the members of the group is the real Edo Kid,
but after arresting him, they find out that the real Edo Kid is someone else.
Apparently, the true criminal was actually the twin brother of the man they arrested.
And then they decide to go with the group somewhere else.
The title is "The Memoirs of Detective Itarô",
but it's odd that the main character, Itarô, would arrest the wrong criminal.
Conan-kun, how was that?
You were great!
Amazing!
That was great, Megu.
Can I take some juice to my friends?
Yeah, sure.
Guys, wait a bit for me!
That's right, Megu.
We're gonna be done soon, so can you call Chikaishi-sensei?
Right, got it!
Sensei! Sensei!
He's still asleep? I'm coming in!
Sensei, di--
Megumi!
Megumi, what's wrong?
Big brother!
Chikaishi-sensei is dead!
He was hit in the head...
It looks like it was with this jar...
Someone please call the police!
Yes!
What?
Why is he so nervous?
Is he just that restless?
Or maybe...
The floppy disk is gone!
What's wrong, big brother? Are you all right?
No...
It's nothing.
Is something missing? The room looks like it was ransacked...
I... It's nothing.
What's with this guy? Why won't he say that the floppy's gone?
The victim is the troupe's script-writer, Tetsuo Chikaishi-san, 35 years old, right?
Yes. You're right.
Conan-kun?
I didn't know where you were, so I came here to see if you'd come back.
Sorry...
Geez... It's always the same thing!
Greetings, Inspector.
Oh, Mouri-kun! What do you think?
They say he died about an hour ago.
Sounds like a job for my agency, huh?
Yeah...
Where were you all an hour ago?
Umm...
We were all practicing for the play!
That's right. We saw how they practiced over and over again.
And being a general practice, even those without parts were here.
The only time we lost sight of them was when they went to change clothes...
Then when the platform was used, there was only one person working?
Right.
He's the only theatre employee who came to work today.
Y- Yeah. That's right.
Somebody killed Chikaishi-san, stole the floppy, then came back to the stage...
That's right!
Hey, Inspector, you have to find the missing floppy disk!
Chikaishi-san had it on the
table with the script, right?
Isn't that right, Mr. Chairman?
Why did he hide this?
It's possible that he killed him and someone else stole the floppy.
Or is he protecting the killer?
Still, the killer is one of the people here!
Conan-kun!
I'm fine!
Itoe-san!
The note we found was well analysed and was definitely written by Tamanosuke.
Tamanosuke-san's in danger!
The killer is someone else!
On the next Conan: "The Travelling Drama Troupe Murder Case (Part 2)"