Alibis, codes, tricks, pacts.
The mysterious Black Organisation.
Today is the troupe's stage performance.
The case and scenario come to a conclusion!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
TRUTH
Song by Two-Mix
Original Comic Books By:
Gôshô Aoyama
"Detective Conan"
Published in Shogakukan's
"Shônen Sunday"
Planning:
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Character Design:
Masatomo Sudô
Art Director:
Yukihiro Shibutani
Art Design:
Hiroyuki Mitsumoto
Camera Director:
Takahisa Ogawa
Recording Director:
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
Music Producer:
Hiroki Horio (Polygram)
Music:
Katsuo Ôno
Editor:
Terimitsu Okada
Story Editor:
Jun'ichi Îoka
Color Design:
Reiko Hirayama
Production Chief:
Hiroaki Kobayashi
Planning Committee:
- Toyohiko Okuyama
- Mitomu Asai
General Director:
Kenji Kodama
Director:
Yasuichirô Yamamoto
Producers:
- Michihiko Suwa (Yomiuri TV)
- Masahito Yoshioka (TMS)
We went to see a drama troupe practicing, because its young chairman, Tamanosuke Itô, had joined Ran's class.
But we found a serious problem within the theater's backstage.
and then a murder was committed!
At the time of the crime, everybody was on stage practicing.
However, while we were
in the audience and didn't notice,
one of them committed this crime!
A TROUP
RT II)
NG DRAMA TROUPE
(PART II)
AVELLING DRAMA TROUPE MURDER
THE TRAVELLING DRAMA TROUPE MURDER CASE
(PART II)
"The Travelling Drama Troupe Murder Case (Part II)"
Last night, drama writer Tetsuo Chikaishi was killed.
We're in front of the inn where the drama troupe he belonged to has been staying.
The group's young chairman
was interrogated by the police
Geez...
Megu-chan, your big brother's back.
Big brother!
Are you all right?
Yeah.
I'm fine.
You haven't slept all night, how can you be okay?
Big brother...
Still, why don't you rest for a bit?
I hope you feel as if you were at home.
Sorry for the bother.
Not at all. We've always taken care of you.
Big brother?
- Big brother, why'd you come here so late?
- Why did he come to the theater?
Conan-kun!
You surprised me!
You're worried about your brother, right?
I- I guess.
And why are you here, Conan-kun?
I was worried your brother might be in danger.
Anyway, you can leave it to me and go back to the inn.
Conan-kun, are you trying to get rid of me?
That's not it!
I just mean this isn't the time for a child to be out.
But Conan-kun, aren't you the same age as me?
Where did big brother go?
What?
Behind the stage.
Big brother...
Big brother, wake up!
Damn! The criminal can't have gone too far!
- Megu-chan, call an ambulance!
- Right!
Conan-kun!
I'm fine.
Itoe-san!
Tamanosuke Itô-san took a blow to the head and is unconscious.
He was immediately taken to the hospital.
The dead woman in the shaft was Itoe Hagiwara-san, the group's accountant and actress.
The cause of death was the fall into the shaft.
What's this?
"ITOE: I will reveal your true identity! Wait for me in the stage at 24h."
Identity?
Inspector, there's something in her hand.
Looks like a note.
Inspector, there's another
one just like it on the floor.
What does this mean?
Hey, Conan!
What are you doing here?
Thanks for coming, Mouri-kun.
Conan-kun was the one who found the body.
Wha... What?
There's lots of wood splinters around the body.
What is this?
Brat, hurry up and go to bed!
What time do you think it is?
Next day, afternoon
Uncle, what do you mean?
How can you suspect Tamanosuke-san is the criminal when he was assaulted?
Can't be helped. We found his prints on the lever, the murder weapon.
And there were no more prints?
There were prints from the other troupe members too,
Itoe-san being the only exception.
Therefore, it's impossible that Itoe-san attacked Tamanosuke,
before falling in the shaft and dying.
But Tamanosuke-san's uncapable of killing anyone!
Ran, let's go visit him at the hospital.
Right.
Dad, take care of Conan-kun & co, okay?
He can't receive visitors
because he's a murder suspect.
But Megumi-chan's probably with him.
We're just taking him flowers.
Come on, let's go.
He's still unconscious.
Our feelings are what matters.
Geez...
Uncle, if Tamanosuke-san is a suspect, does that mean he hit himself in the head?
I dunno.
The doc says the injury's not too serious.
He's unconscious due to the
emotional shock at the moment.
I see. If they say it's a mental shock,
that means he's trying to escape reality after committing the crime,
therefore being the prime suspect.
The note's handwriting was analysed,
and it was definitely written by Tamanosuke.
Furthermore, the same note was sent to all the members of the group.
Why did he want to get Itoe-san's attention?
How should I know?
Besides that, she had a lot of money hidden in her dressing room,
and it sounds like she was ripping off the company
In other words, the young chairman punished the scriptwriter Chikaishi
who wouldn't obey him, and Itoe,
who was ripping them off.
Would he really commit murder for something like that?
Hey, Conan, wait a minute.
Bring me a beer.
It's still daytime.
That doesn't matter.
I'll tell you more about the case if you do.
Geez...
Here. I brought you a snack, too.
Ahh! Thank you!
So, did they find Chikaishi-san's floppy?
It was in Tamanosuke's room.
He erased it and threw it in the trash.
Eh? He erased it?
Yeah. It probably had something he didn't want anyone to see.
What if someone found it there and just took it?
I dunno. Go play for a bit.
He always does the same thing when he has no idea what happened. Not worth talking to him anymore.
- Let's go, then.
- Yeah.
Hey, wait! Bring me another one!
Hey, there's no wooden splinters here like there were down below.
That's right. Maybe we'll find them on that side.
I know! She must have been killed somewhere else and then pushed into the elevator shaft!
It's the same color...
I think they were splinters from this plywood.
You mean this?
Idiot...
Huh? What's the matter?
There's blood here!
There's blood he
T
lood
It's the same size as the shaft.
The color is like the stage's, too.
It was a lid.
Yeah. And it was cut by about 3 mm and it's easy to break.
(1/8 inch)
And after she fell and died,
the plywood was hidden.
So, did Tamanosuke-san hurt himself?
No. Megumi-chan and I followed Tamanosuke-san from the inn, so he had no time to set this trap.
Big trouble.
Hurry!
What's wrong?
Tamanosuke-san's in danger!
The killer is someone else!
All right. Got it, Mouri-kun.
Everything's ready.
I'm leaving it in your hands.
Inspector.
Yes. Conan here.
This is Ayumi.
We got inside the inn.
All the drama troupe members are here.
The one closest to the stairs, Tajima-san,
is in his room watching TV.
Yuri Shirai-san is cleaning her clothes.
Muraki-san, who moved to the dead Chikaishi-san's room, seems to be cleaning it.
That's all. How was that?
All right. That's all, guys.
You can go home now.
Hey, Conan!
Wait, Conan-kun!
He did it again...
Hold it right there!
He's getting away!
What?!
You won't get away!
Oh, no!
The Edo Kid was always known for his ability.
The Edo Kid was part of the troupe!
And when Tamanosuke-san figured it out, he tried to reveal his identity in the play.
But Chikaishi-san figured it out first.
It's likely that Chikaishi-san was blackmailing the Edo Kid!
That's why Chikaishi-san always kept that floppy!
But the Edo Kid killed him, and Tamanosuke-san,
who confirmed his presence in the troupe, was disturbed by the murder
and that's why he sent that note.
Yes?
Inspector!
Sorry to disturb you, Tajima-san, but did you leave this room tonight?
No.
He was here.
None of the troupe members left the inn.
You guys!
Does this mean Conan's here too?
No. I just got here.
Conan-kun!
So they stayed here after all...
They'll be alibi witnesses.
I'm sure the killer is both the Edo Kid and that person.
But I have no proof...
So cool!
Isn't it fun?
Why did they let Conan-kun stay but not me?
Can't be helped. Conan-kun's going home with his uncle.
Yeah, besides, we get to ride in a patrol car, don't we?
- Let's go!
- I don't wanna go home!
This is the life!
Thank you for your hard work, Mouri-san. One more?
No thanks, I'm on duty.
Come on, one glass won't hurt.
Is that so?
How can they be so calm?
We're running out of time...
out of time...
That's it!
Only two people had time to kill Chikaishi-san,
but Tamanosuke-san's attacker
can only be that one!
Everyone, please come here.
Hm? What is it?
I found out who the killer is.
Oh! That again?
The person who killed Chikaishi-san and Itoe Ogiwara,
as well as attacking Tamanosuke-san twice,
is in this room!
What did you say?
You're lying!
Now, now. At least let him speak.
After all, it's thanks to Mouri-kun that we saved Tamanosuke-kun's life.
The criminal who attacked Tamanosuke-san in the hospital
was as agile as the famous "Edo Kid".
Yes. This entire story starts with the Edo Kid.
The Edo Kid was a thief who, using samurai movements,
jumped from one place to another with great agility.
During the past six months, I'm sure he appeared in the places where they performed.
It's true. Yuri-san and I were both interrogated
and we have alibis for every time he appeared.
Are you two the only ones capable of acrobatic stunts in the troupe?
Yes, but it was Tajima-san who taught us.
He has back problems and hasn't done acrobatic stunts in three years.
This time, young Tamanosuke-san was trying to recreate a play on the Edo Kid.
However, the script written by Chikaishi-san
was not like the one Tamanosuke-san wanted.
Why did Chikaishi-san change the story?
That's because, during his research on the Edo Kid,
Chikaishi-san discovered his identity.
Likely, Chikaishi-san was blackmailing him
in exchange for changing the script he was writing.
Isn't that so, Edo Kid, or should I say,
Kenzô Tajima-san!
Ta... Tajima-san is...?
Then was his back injury a lie?
It's true that he injured himself 3 years ago,
but I bet he's been healed for exactly 6 months.
Ridiculous!
I'm not listening to this!
I'm sorry, but you can't leave just yet.
Tajima-san, are you really the killer?
N... No...
However...
I must tell you that
the circumstances point to you.
What was that?!
That day, only you three had the chance to kill Chikaishi-san in his dressing room.
Due to a lack of actors, the three of you were playing two roles each.
You and Yuri-san were changing your clothes backstage,
and Muraki-san had to change quickly, while running down the stairs into the shaft.
The Beika Theatre's elevator shaft is deep, and the platform rises slowly,
which means Muraki-san had to switch his clothes while rushing to the shaft,
and therefore had no time to commit the crime and return to the stage.
Furthermore, Chikaishi-san's room was right next to the back-stage.
Both Tajima-san and Yuri-san passed by his room
therefore having time to kill Chikaishi-san.
But Itoe-san died accidentally.
Because she mistakenly read the rômaji saying "ITOE" thinking it was for her,
when it was actually for me.
Why do you say that?
Because that chairman tended to write
"Detective Itarô to Edo Kid" like that.
That's right. The rômaji read "i-to-e",
"I to E", that is to say, "Itarô to Edo Kid".
Then why did he send the note to every member?
How should I know? I was so angry over the chairman thinking the thief was me that I went out for some air.
What if the note was for the real Edo Kid?
Though Tamanosuke-san was sure that the Edo Kid killed Chikaishi-san,
he didn't know which member actually was the Edo Kid.
He didn't know his identity.
However, since Itoe-san thought the note was for her,
she fell through the lid in
the shaft and died from the fall.
Tamanosuke-san was injured the moment he entered the theatre,
which means he didn't have the time to cover the hole with the lid.
Besides, at the time there was someone else in the theatre.
As proof, another note was found in the elevator shaft.
Is that why you think I did it? Just because I had the time to kill Chikaishi doesn't mean I did it!
- Yuri had the time too!
- Hey!
Ta... Tajima-san!
The man who appeared in
the hospital was exactly like you.
Just because we look alike, you think I'm the killer!
Fine, then.
Then, Inspector Megure, please check the fingerprints in Chikaishi-san's computer.
We checked those during the first murder but we found nothing. Why are you asking now?
Because I'm sure the killer used the computer
to check the contents of the floppy he stole from Chikaishi-san.
He probably used his hands because he didn't imagine it'd be re-checked.
Takagi-kun, check it.
Yes.
All right.
Just stop it.
It's true. I killed Chikaishi and Itoe.
I was so relieved when Chikaishi, who knew my identity as Edo Kid, died,
But then I found this note in my pocket,
which disturbed me so much that without thinking,
I set up the lid trap.
However, after Itoe died and I went to hide the plywood,
I turned around and saw the young chairman, staring at me!
I tried to kill the chairman, but I couldn't.
Tajima-san...
It's all my fault, for insisting on the play.
Chairman!
I wasn't trying to trap you for being Edo Kid,
I just wanted you to regret your sins and stop it!
Chairman...
I'm so sorry! Please forgive me!
I shouldn't have committed bad deeds just for fun!
I'm sorry for dirtying the name of our troupe!
Afterwards, the theatre opened its doors again,
and after altering the script, despite his injuries,
Tamanosuke-san did an excellent performance.
We, who were beginners, got to be stars too.
They're bank robbers!
Don't go, Masami Hirota-san...
If you go, you'll be killed...
The men in black...
I will never forgive them!
I will catch them with my own hands!
On the next Conan: "The Black Organisation's 1 Billion Yen Robbery Case"
THE BLACK ORGANISATION'S
1 BILLION YEN ROBBERY CASE