Alibis, codes, tricks, deals.
The mysterious Black Organization.
At last, Conan's target appears!
It smells like a big case!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Thanks for waiting, Conan-kun.
Was the money for the detective services deposited?
Yes! Plenty! So much, it filled up the entire book.
All right! Then let's eat lunch out somewhere and go home.
It's been a while since I've had a drink during the daytime.
Dad...
We're talking about lunch!
I'll go get this savings book replaced with a new one.
Geez. What a hopeless drunk.
The counter is... Let's see... Wow!
What a beauty!
Miss...
Y-Yes?
Would you exchange this pass book for a new one please?
I'm very sorry, sir.
Please take a number over there,
then please have a seat and wait your turn.
Yes, we should all wait our turn, very true...
I'll be right back. I've got to get a number, a number!
Miss!
Oh, Conan-kun...
What's wrong? You seem to be concerned and looking at your watch...
Huh? Oh... I'm a bit busy,
so I was hoping that it would be lunch time soon.
I'll see you later then, Conan-kun.
Do you know her, Conan-kun?
Yeah.
Her name is Masami Hirota-san.
She's a new employee who just started here a while ago.
She's usually much nicer, though...
S-She's gone! She's not here!
Oh, no...
Ran-neechan, I think he's going to be in here for a while, so I'll wait outside.
Okay. Watch out for cars.
It's the parking lot of the bank...
I wonder what that sound was...
They're robbing the bank's armored cash transport truck!
There are two robbers...
One has a shotgun and the other has a pistol.
Are the other security guards...
Dead?!
I can't tell from here...
Conan-kun?
What are you doing in a place like this?
We're going home!
Help! It's a robbery!
W-What's with that car?!
It's an cash transport armored car robbery!
What?!
Ran-neechan, please call the police!
Wait, Conan-kun!
Get an ambulance too, because there seems to be some people who are hurt!
Ran, notify the bank first!
I'll go check on the people who are hurt!
Okay!
Damn! Talk about high speed!
It's like a race! I can barely keep up with them!
Great! A railway crossing!
All right then!
What? He's going to run the crossing?!
Damn! I'm not letting them get away!
Dammit, they got away!
What?! One billion yen were stolen?!
Yeah, all the cash that was supposed to be delivered
from the main bank to all the branches were stolen.
One billion, eh...
Conan-kun, you're sure of the license plate number you just gave me?
Yes, I'm sure!
There are two of them armed with a pistol and a shotgun, eh...
Well, fortunately, the security guard wasn't seriously hurt.
The armored truck stopped, so we were getting ready to unload the cash.
Then suddenly...
Koyama-san? Murata-san?!
Hey! Driver! Is somebody there?!
Since I got no response from the driver, I thought they were killed,
and had no choice but to open the door.
Strange... I'm sure that back then I...
After hearing the gun and the window crack,
I ran right over to the entrance of the parking lot and looked in.
At that time, they were already loading the cash out of the truck...
He shouldn't have had any time to call the driver!
You understand too, don't you?
I really had no other choice...
Excuse me, sir.
You sure are lucky, sir.
How so?
Because the window of the armored truck is tinted
so that you can't see anything from the outside, right?
Yeah.
The bullet that was fired through that tinted window, and yet it didn't hit you.
Besides, the bullet hit the coin bag, so it didn't bounce back at you.
You had to either be real lucky, or had planned
where to place the coin bag, and where to hide beforehand.
Right?
Don't be ridiculous.
This is still just one possible deduction...
But...
Hirota-kun!
Where were you at a time like this?!
I'm sorry, I changed shifts and went out to lunch...
Talk about the young girls nowadays...
Just what time do you think it is?!
Is your watch broken or something?
There is one more possibility...
Inspector Megure!
What's up, Takagi-kun?
There was a report that what looked to be the getaway van was found.
What?! Where?
By the bed of the Teimuzu River, beside the TR railway bridge!
Okay, let's head off, right away. Come with me too, Mouri-kun.
Sure!
Ran, you take Conan and go on home!
Okay!
Let's get going then...
Conan-kun?
Conan-k—
He's gone again!
So, what's the story, Tome-san?
Oh, Inspector Megure!
I just took a quick look, but the fingerprints have been wiped clean.
What other clues are left?
Well, as for pretty large sized clues, there are 5 cases in the back of the car.
There are no fingerprints on them either.
And...
Hey, bring me the stuff we found a while ago!
This was thrown out on the driver's seat.
Oh, thanks.
Take a look at this.
These are...
A mask and gloves...
Well, although I'm pretty sure we can't expect any prints on them either...
Oh, so you're here too, boy...
Boy?
Hello, Tome-san!
Hey! I thought I told you to go on home with Ran!
Oh, there's something on the inside of the mask...
On the inside of the mask?
What's this pink colored mark?
This pink color is probably...
But, why?
Okay, then!
I'm borrowing this for a while!
Hey!
Just as I thought...
Ow!
Don't "ow" me!
What do you think you're doing with the important clues?!
That's enough, kid!
So, the case started off as an ordinary robbery case.
But it was no ordinary robbery.
It didn't take me long to prove that my hunch was right.
The robber from the other day was killed?
Yeah, a former racer, Shiro Kaizuka, was found shot to death in bed.
Former racer... No wonder they carried it out so fast.
Say. How did they figure out that he was the robber?
A memo of the blueprint of the bank,
the schedule of the armored cash transport truck.
as well as a map of the getaway route were found in his room.
Furthermore...
Another person was killed last night with same gun he had...
Security guard, Kishii!
Then Kishii-san was also a member of the group?
I'm sure he was an accomplice...
He liked gambling and seemed to have a lot of debts...
He probably played the role of being frightened
into opening the rear of the armored truck from the inside.
The rear door of an armored truck cannot be opened except from the inside.
Does that mean that the two may have been killed by the other robber?
Probably,
because the money that was stolen is gone.
The other robber probably killed the two to take all the money.
It seems that Inspector Megure is also going to check in on things on that end.
But I'm sure that it's only a matter of time before they are caught.
What do you mean?
Pink-colored lipstick was found in Kaizuka's room.
Lipstick?
It matched the color that was found on the mask that the robbers left behind.
Moreover...
It also matched the color that bank teller Masami Hirota-san is using, right?
Conan-kun?!
One of her colleagues testified that it matched the color of the lipstick she wears.
She left the bank saying she was going out lunch,
so I'm sure she went to the back door and joined them.
But why would a bank employee do something like that?
I don't know,
but she has already quit the bank...
She handed in her resignation this morning.
What?!
She started working for this bank only half a year ago.
What do you mean?
She just snuck into the bank to check things out before committing the crime.
It's more natural if you think of it that way.
Well, I guess that's how it is...
I'm sure... I'm sure that is the way things took place on the whole...
But there's still one question left...
I wonder if she would really make her lipstick rub off...
After all, she spent a half a year checking the bank out.
Besides, the lipstick on the mask was placed too low.
that the chin would be there and not the lips
And above all...
It would've smelled of make-up if she wore the mask,
but there was no such smell on it...
If someone schemed this all and is trying to frame her as the robber...
Oh, no!
Conan-kun, where are you going?
Let him be, let him be...
Metropolitan Police Department
Hello, this is Megure...
Oh, Mouri-kun?
Masami Hirota's address?
We've already checked her place out.
Yes, I know, but I have something I'd like to confirm.
Here it is!
It's this room!
Let's... see...
If my deduction is right, Masami-san's in danger...
I wonder if... if there's some clue somewhere...
Huh? The outlet is blocked off by the leg of the desk...
Maybe its deliberately blocked off... Could it be that...
Hmm?... What's this?
This is a key to a coin locker...?!
This is probably where the stolen money is hidden!
Don't go... Masami Hirota-san...
If you go, you'll be killed...
Thank you... I'm sorry, Conan-kun.
Wait!
Damn! There's nobody here...
There she is! It's Masami-san!
Okay... I'll use this transmitter and my... suspenders...
Stick on, please...
Go!
All right!
Alright, there she goes.
I won't let you get away!
There's no doubt that someone is using her.
But who on earth is pulling the strings behind her?
Where are you?! Come out here!
Good work.
Masami Hirota...
Or should I say...
Akemi Miyano!
May I ask you a question?
Why did you kill those two?
That's the way we do things.
Now, hand over the cash.
It's not here. I have it in another place.
What?!
Before I give it to you, get my sister! Bring my sister here!
You promised, didn't you?!
That when this job is over, you'd let me and my sister out of this organization!
We can't do that.
Because she's an indispensable brain to the organization.
Unlike you, your sister is a necessity to the organization.
Then you never intended to...!
Come on, this is your last chance. Tell us where the money is.
Don't be silly.
If you kill me, you'll never know where the cash is.
You're the one who's being silly.
We already know that you have the key to the coin locker.
I told you that this was your last chance...
Gunfire?!
That way!
Masami-san!
Hang in there, Masami-san!
C-Conan-kun...
How did you know I was here?
I stuck a transmitter onto your car,
because I was sure that you were coming to see the people pulling the strings from behind the scenes.
Damn! If I only explained everything to you back then...
W-Who are you...?
Edogawa...
No...
Shin'ichi Kudo, a detective...
Shin'ichi... Kudo... You're...
Yes... I've heard rumors about you...
The two men that I hired were killed...
And me too, by the organization...
Organization?
It's a large, mysterious organization.
The only thing that someone on the bottom line knows
is that the color of this organization is black...
Black?
Yes...
The people of the organization like to wear that color...
Black clothes as black as a crow...
M-May I ask you one last favor?
Take this...
This is the real key.
The one they took is fake.
It's for the coin locker at the east exit of Beika Station...
Please... Before they realize what's going on...
I don't ever want to be used by them again.
I'm counting on you... Little detective...
Hello?
I'd like to speak to Inspector Megure of the 1st Division.
Since the only fingerprints found on the gun were hers,
it was concluded that she committed suicide thinking she couldn't get away.
The one billion yen that was robbed was safely recovered.
And it looked to be that the case was closed.
No. It's not over at all!
I will never forgive these guys...
I'll nab them for sure with these very hands of mine.
For sure...