Alibis, codes, tricks, deals.
The mysterious Black Organization.
The scene is a packed stadium.
Amidst the cheers, terror approaches!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
I'm a high school detective, Shin'ichi Kudo.
I went with an old friend and classmate,
Ran Mouri, to an amusement park
where I witnessed a suspicious deal
with a man dressed in black!
I was so absorbed with watching the deal
that I didn't notice a second man
sneak up from behind me!
He beat me up and forced me to
take a poison, and when I woke up...
...my body had shrunk!
If they learned Shin'ichi Kudo is still alive,
people around me would be in danger!
Per Dr. Agasa's advice,
I decided to conceal my identity.
When Ran asked my name, I quickly answered "Conan Edogawa".
To get information on the men,
I wound up living with Ran
and her detective father.
Hey, hey.
Doesn't the lion dance-beast look like Inspector Megure?
What do you think you're doing, Takagi?!
It's true, it's just like him!
Doesn't it, doesn't it?
It looks like Genta-kun, too.
What?!
Look, look, like that.
Why, you...!
Wait!
Hey! If we don't hurry, the match's about to start!
I know.
Come on, let's go, Mitsuhiko.
Right...
Hey, Ran.
Another one.
Eh, again?
That was the sixth one!
It's fine, isn't it?
It's the new year, lemme drink as much as I like.
But you always drink as much as you like.
By the way, where's the brat?
Conan-kun went to a soccer match.
He went to the Emperor's Cup's finals.
He shouldn't have gone to watch a soccer game on the first day of the year...
To start the year, there's nothing better than having alcohol while watching Yoko-chan on TV.
Like this!
Invite me!
Invite me!!
Rock-Paper-Scissors Squad!
What is this thing?
Isn't it a New Year special?
If you want to watch Yoko-chan's, I think they have a special drama with her in the afternoon.
What?!
Not until the afternoon?
That sucks.
I'll take a nap. Wake me up when it starts.
Wait, Dad! You'll catch a cold!
January 1st
National Stadium
Emperor's Cup Finals
Big Osaka
Tokyo Spirits
Goal from the Tokyo Spirits, four minutes into the first half! Scored by Hideo Akagi!
Hey, who scored? Who? Who?
Hide of the Spirits!
Hide scored with a header from Naoki's centering!
That's Hide for ya.
Yeah.
If he doesn't get injured, then he's sure to get in Japan's National Team.
Ah, Japan's National Team. Shame we lost in the World Cup...
It's embarrassing that we couldn't even win a single game.
But why were the adults all so excited?
My dad said it was like a dream come true, seeing Japan in the World Cup.
I guess it's a really important competition, but...
Mo-ron.
The World Cup's the sports world's biggest event,
where each country fights with its dignity on the line.
It's no wonder all of Japan's so excited.
Well, it's maddening that Japan couldn't win a single game,
but that just shows that such a worldwide competition's not easy.
Why are you acting so cool?
When they were showing the games on TV,
you were the angriest one of all.
Right, right.
You even started beating your feet against the table at the Doc's house.
I couldn't help it...
Seeing Japan in the World Cup's been my dream since childhood...
What are you on about? You're still a child.
Aren't you a child now?
How long have you been watching soccer?
No, that's... you see...
What's so funny, Haibara?
When soccer's in the mix, even the Great Detective becomes an enthusiastic teenager.
Leave me alone.
Why aren't you watching the game?
I just came with you.
They know my childhood face.
It's a 1000-to-1 chance, but if
a TV camera broadcasts my face,
they'd find me out immediately.
If that happened, you'd be in danger, too.
That's why I didn't feel like coming...
Hey, wait!
How's that?
This way it's fine even if they see you, right?
Come on!
Forget about them for now.
The match, the match!
Soccer matches are the best live!
All right! Go!
Kudo-kun...
You can't even imagine in your dreams...
You're already deeply connected to the secret project our Organization's been working on
for half a century.
All right, now go from camera two to camera three.
Don't miss the goal play on camera one!
Camera four, what are you doing?
Hey, Kaneko-san?
What is it? I'm busy.
Come and take this phone call.
Phone? For me?
He's been calling for a while.
Guess it can't be helped.
Director Kaneko here.
Hello? Who are you?
I'm only going to say this once, so listen well.
Central stand, the spectators on the right side.
Look at the group of brats leaning on the handrail in the first row.
What?
Hey, camera thirteen's free, right?
Zoom on the spectators on the right stand.
Okay.
Hey, camera thirteen!
Cool, aren't you?
Someone watching a game as interesting as this normally reacts like that.
Go, Hide!
Hang in there!
Come on, dribble!
Don't you have feelings like when your heart is beating or you feel excited?
Who knows? Maybe if I look around I'll find them somewhere.
When you arrived at the school,
you were like that too.
Having to study with kids is embarassing, but can't be helped.
You're always super-calm.
Of course.
It's your one.
You're in that class, so I can take it easier.
Because you've been through the same as me...
Yeah, there's five children.
The boy in the left with the blue hat?
Yeah, what about it?
Look...
Can I ask you something?
What?
How old are you, really?
84 years old.
Just kidding.
I'm actually...
What?
What happened?
The ball jumped all of a sudden...
Conan-kun!
Hey!
A hole in the ball...
Two of them? It can't be.
You can't just jump onto the pitch.
But my hat fell off!
Your hat?
If I'm right, it should be around here...
Somewhere in the rubber coating...
Found it. It's this.
Here it is, kid.
Found your hat...
H-Hey, kid! What are you doing?!
Hey!
What do you think you're doing, kid?
This is a 7.62mm bullet!
Full Metal Jacket!
It's a gun, a gun!
Somebody fired a gun in this stadium, Inspector!
And where's the victim?
They didn't shoot at a person, they shot a soccer ball.
A soccer ball?
As the man on the phone said,
I focused the monitor on the ball that rolled next to the boy in the blue hat in the first row.
And then suddenly, the ball jumped and deflated.
That can only be a gun!
Still, something like that can be a prank with an air gun.
It was probably a Tokarev.
Conan-kun?
The Detective Boys are here!
Hey...
You're here too?
It was her, right? The kid in the blue hat you saw on the monitor.
Yes, that's right.
So you saw it too?
The ball suddenly jumped and deflated.
Then I jumped onto the pitch and found this.
This bullet was in the rubber coating.
What?
A 7.62mm bullet.
Russian-made...
The most common Russian handgun to use that ammo...
is the Tokarev, which often enters Japan from China.
Either way, it's clearly a powerful, deadly weapon.
And since we didn't hear a gunshot,
the criminal must have used a silencer...
But how do you know all of this?
Of course, I heard it all from Uncle Kogoro!
Geez... What's that guy teaching kids?!
Either way, suspend the game! End the match and evacuate the spectators and players!
Yes, sir!
You can't!
The man on the phone said...
if the game ends, the spectators run
or something strange happens...
he'll start indiscriminately shooting people.
What?!
What's the blackmailer demanding?
At half-time, have a bag ready with 50 million yen.
He'll call again afterwards with the place to leave it.
And he demanded this of you?
Yes, Nichiuri TV.
Then the blackmailer could be someone with a grudge against Nichiuri TV.
Or he could be a terrorist...
Do you remember anything special about his voice?
Umm...
It was a heavy voice, hard to understand.
Maybe he covered the phone, or used some sort of mask.
And do you have the 50 million yen ready?
Yes, it's being brought as we speak.
All right! We'll slip undercover agents into the audience!
Once the blackmailer calls again, we'll catch him!
When that happens, hold everyone who's using a cell phone in the stadium!
Yes, sir!
You're in danger here. Go home.
Oh? The kid with the blue hat's a girl?
How rude! Can't you tell?
Strange...
I'm sure the man said "from the five kids, focus on the boy with the blue hat on the left."
Wait, Inspector!
If you try to arrest the blackmailer,
it'll be a disaster!
What do you mean?
If the ball was shot next to us,
then the blackmailer was right next to us, right?
Right.
A handgun's scope is limited,
and if he'd missed it'd be a total failure.
If he was next to us, then why did the blackmailer mistake her for a boy?
Dressed like this, anyone can tell she's a girl.
He probably didn't see her skirt because of the wall...
If he didn't see her skirt because of the wall,
then he was watching us from the backstand.
In other words, the one who was watching us, and called to foretell the shot,
and the one who actually shot the gun, are different people.
There must be at least two people amongst the blackmailers.
Hey!
Inform all the agents!
Until I give the signal, nobody move!
Y-Yes, sir!
But what can we do?
How can we find the blackmailers with so few clues?
How do we find him in this stadium packed with 56,000 people?
To all personnel spread through the stands...
There are two or more blackmailers.
We have reasons to believe one of them has a Tokarev.
If you see anyone suspicious, don't take action.
Until I say otherwise, continue surveillance.
We don't know what the other blackmailer can do to save his accomplice.
Attention: don't let anyone suspect that you're police.
Proceed with caution and do everything possible so we can catch them!
The blackmailers' next move should be to call to say where the money should be left.
When that happens, be sure to know the location of everybody using a cell phone in this stadium.
There's the binoculars, too.
Remember what I told you?
When the blackmailer called, he was watching us from the backstand.
From that far away, he could tell there were five children and that one of them had a blue hat.
He was also able to see the ball that landed next to us. You can't do that with the naked eye.
The blackmailer probably has not just a cell phone,
but also binoculars, or maybe...
Opera glasses?
A telescope?
A portable video camera?
A camera with a telephoto would be suspicious...
That's right.
One of the blackmailers should have something that'll let him see far away.
Look at the spectators...
Inspector! The call!
It's probably the blackmailer, right?
Anyway, calm down.
All right! We have a call.
It could be the blackmailer.
Now, check everybody using a cell phone and report their positions.
Listen. If it's the blackmailer,
try to delay him as long as possible.
Right.
H-Hello?
This is director Kaneko.
Hello? Hello?
Why didn't you answer immediately?
You didn't call the police, did you?
Of course not. It took me a while to find the phone.
It's the blackmailer. Find him.
All right. Do you have the money?
Yes. Yes.
Leave the money at the 18th exit gate.
Leave it there during the first half's injury time.
Don't make a mistake.
Ah, wait! Hello? Hello?
The call's over. How was it, did you find him?
Sector E here. An old man with a black sweater was talking on his cell phone just now.
Sector K here. There's one here,
but he's still talking...
He could be calling his accomplice. Keep watching.
Hey, Takagi, what about you?
At the time of the call,
eight people were using a cell phone.
You checked the stadium's internal rooms and hallways, right?
Yes.
I also checked the bathrooms,
but there was nobody on the phone.
Of course, nobody left the stadium.
I also checked the spectators with the free cameras we have,
but at the time, only those eight were talking on a cell phone.
It seems that one of the blackmailers must be one of those eight.
But Inspector...
One of the blackmailers should come to get the money, right?
Yeah, I suppose he will.
Either way, don't take your eyes off those eight.
We have to catch them
before they realize we're here.
Oh? Where's my radio?
You mean this?
Ah, that's it.
Here.
Thank you, Conan-kun.
Attention all units inside the building, station around the 18th exit gate.
Hey, what did you do to the radio?
Oh, I put a listening device on it.
I need to be aware of the police's movements.
By the way, where's Genta and the others?
Oh, those three?
After I told them that so long as they showed their torn tickets,
they could go back in, they did so quite happily.
H-Happily?
Don't tell me they...
This is Genta. This is Genta.
Did you find anyone suspicious? Over.
This is Mitsuhiko.
I don't see anyone suspicious. Over.
Ayumi-chan! How's it going over there?
Nobody here either.
Yes? This is Ayumi!
Don't "this is Ayumi" me!
What the hell are you doing?!
He's got a gun!
If he shoots you, you die!
Leave the blackmailers to the police and me!
You kids get out of the stadium immediately!
No way!
Aren't you a kid too?
We want to help catch the blackmailer too!
Aren't we part of the Detective Boys too?
All right.
But if you find anyone suspicious, don't take him on alone.
Contact me immediately, all right?
Yes.
Geez...
Oh, but it's not that bad an idea.
They won't see kids as a threat...
I know, but...
Damn. It's injury time.
Then it's time for them to put the bag with the money in the 18th exit gate...
This is Sato.
The bag's still there.
This is Tamiya. Same.
Nobody's approached the bag yet.
He's here, Inspector. A man with a grey coat, a white mask and sunglasses.
The man took the bag.
Anybody around?
No, he's alone.
All right...
Get him!!!
The gun!
Find the gun!
I can't find it!
Where is it? Where do you have the gun?
Don't touch him!
Don't touch my partner!
Or I'll kill someone in the audience!
Let him go, now!
Partner?
So you did call the cops...
That wasn't what we agreed on!
Kaneko-san from Nichiuri TV!
T-That's...
You felt like mocking us. How about I kill someone to show we're serious?
H-Hey, wait!
This guy's dangerous!
So, who should I kill?
There's so many targets around...
Ayumi!
Ayumi-chan!
Ayumi, where's the blackmailer?
It's him.
Got you!
- What are you doing?
- Don't let him go!
I finally figured it out, mister.
It's you, right?
The one blackmailing Nichiuri TV?
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: TV Camera
Next time, the match concludes!
Goal to the blackmailer!