Alibis, codes, tricks, deals.
The mysterious Black Organization.
Today's the first three-parter in a long time.
A case springs forth from a magic show!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Yes, everybody, pay attention!
As you can see, I have a white handkerchief here.
And here, I have a red string and a silver ring.
Yes, yes.
Then, miss, if you'd be so kind, please tie a knot in the middle of the string.
Is this good?
Place the knot on the palm of your hand, and the ring right next to it.
I'll lay this handkerchief on top.
Watch my fingers as they're possessed by the devil and go under the handkerchief
as I pronounce the dark magic words:
"opekepe... opekepe..."
Wonder of wonders! We now have the ring on the string!
Amazing!
How'd you do that, Sonoko?
It's a secret, a secret.
I'll do it tonight in front of everybody.
I see. Today's where the Magic Club's gathering at the lodge, right?
Yeah, yeah. I met them all through the Internet, and this is what we call "an offline meeting."
Though, who'd have thought the Suzuki Financial Group's daughter was a computer addict?
Oh my, don't you know that the Internet is indispensable in this information society?
Why don't you get up-to-date and install a computer in the agency?
But I'm surprised that you've suddenly got an interest for the Internet and magic, Sonoko!
Well, I have to admit I met an incredible guy!
An incredible guy?
His name's Katsuki Doito-san, 21 years old.
He's a member of the Magic Lovers League like me.
His language is refined, his jokes have wit,
and sometimes he says things that just stay in your mind...
I'm sure he's gorgeous!
Then you haven't met him yet?
No. It's the first time we're meeting.
You'll see how he'll love the trick I learned just for him!
You're not gonna impress him.
It's the typical trick they show on TV for beginners.
Well, see...
Pass the knot through the ring, and pull it with your thumb until the string comes out the other side.
I see.
You're as uncute as ever, I see.
Don't mind him.
He's been in a bad mood ever
since I told him I wanted to come.
But are you sure I won't be in the way?
No problem. I told them I was bringing my girlfriend.
Girlfriend?
What?
You've been pretending to be a man?!
Yeah. A 30-year old to be exact. This should be interesting!
But didn't they figure it out when you said your name was Sonoko Suzuki?
Don't worry.
Everybody uses usernames, that is, false names.
For example, I'm the "Apprentice Magician."
Katsuki-san is the "Red Herring."
They're words taken from an old magic book.
Then how do you know his real name?
I asked him in an e-mail.
Oh. You're as direct as ever.
You know me.
Well? We've been chat buddies over the Internet, but we never met in real life.
Isn't it exciting?
Yeah.
It's like going to a costume ball.
Isn't there an odd smell here?
Greetings. I'm here for the meeting.
Welcome. You're the "Apprentice Magician," right?
Y-Yes.
We were expecting you.
But how did you know that I'm the "Apprentice Magician?"
I figured it out as soon as I saw how you spoke.
It was obviously a girl trying to pretend to be an older man.
Right, everybody?
Yeah. It was funny from the other side of the monitor.
Yeah, yeah.
Oh, geez.
Though when it comes to gender-bendin', nobody can beat Tanaka-san.
Oh my.
Kikue Tanaka (28)
Username: "The Fake Child"
I'd never be able to pass off as a guy.
Though I was certain that "The Disappearing Bunny" was a girl.
Toshiya Hamano (27)
Username: "The Disappearing Bunny"
Is that so? Then I did a good job.
Don't you "good job" me!
Naoko Kuroda (25)
Username: "Illusion"
I thought you were a woman and talked to you about underwear and other similarly intimate things!
Yeah. You held nothin' back.
Oh, allow me to introduce myself.
Yoshinori Ara (46)
Username: "The Silent Ventriloquist"
I'm the owner of this lodge, Yoshinori Ara.
And he is...
Kiyohiro Sugama (23)
Part-Time Worker
And this is a part-time worker here, Sugama-kun.
Greetings.
Umm... Isn't Katsuki-san...
I mean, is the Red Herring here yet?
Ah, he's upstairs.
Oh, there he is, there he is.
Katsuki Doito (21)
Username: "Red Herring"
Oh?
Could you be the Apprentice Magician?
It's me. Katsuki Doito.
No way...
My mental image...
I see! I thought you were a girl.
How exciting.
And you guys are?
She invited me along. I'm Ran Mouri.
And I'm her father, who brought them here.
Oh, how rude of me.
Please, come in.
Ah, allow me.
Remember this: Don't you dare lay a hand on my daughter or her friend!
Dad!
You can rest assured.
Hey, you!
We're going home.
I wanna stay too!
Moron, can't you see you have a cold?
Then, please take care of my daughter and her friend.
Yes.
Then the only ones left are...
The board leader, the Escape King,
and the Shadow Priest.
The Shadow Priest's coming too?
What's wrong, Sonoko?
It's just that he's always saying...
"I will fly through the sky."
"I can hide myself at will."
And other weird stuff like that.
Anyway, we can't start without the leader...
On that note, does anyone have the Escape King's phone number?
Yeah, I know it. His real name too.
Hello. Nishiyama here. Unfortunately, I'm not at home at the moment.
Oh? It went to the answering machine.
Please leave a message after the beep.
He is but the first one...
- The Shadow Priest
Can't be helped. Shall we entertain ourselves until he gets here?
Then Sugama-kun and I will go take care of the food,
so you might as well go to your rooms, and make yourselves at home.
Yes!
Wow, such a huge garden!
It's so beautiful!
I'm glad we came.
If only Doito-san'd been like I imagined him to be...
Hey, hey, don't be like that.
Umm... dinner's ready.
R... Right.
That was scary!
Geez... There isn't a single decent man here.
Well, no matter. In the end, I only love one man.
You have someone you love?
Of course. My prince, who I haven't met yet.
Hey, what's for dinner tonight?
I'll make you some rice when we get home.
Go to sleep until then.
Tsutomu Nishiyama, 41 years old, was found dead in his apartment in the Haido District.
Nishiyama-san's mother found the body when she entered his room to clean up.
In his computer, these odd words were found: "He is but the first one...", signed "The Shadow Priest."
The police are investigating the relationship between this phrase and his death.
Apparently, Nishiyama-san was connected to the Internet,
and today was going to be the board leader in a weekend meeting of amateur magicians.
The next news is...
Hey, you can't mean the meeting Ran's in right now!
Uncle, turn the car around. Hurry!
Eh? My favorite Japanese magician?
I like Toichi Kuroba-san.
His stage acts were like a dream.
Yeah. I like Kuroba-san too.
Mine is Yoshiro Kinoshita-san.
A genius who got every title in the championship when he was just 20 years old.
I prefer his teacher, Motoyasu Tsukumo-san.
What are you saying? Those are all dead!
I like Kazumi Sanada-san, who's gotten famous recently. And you guys?
Mine is, of course...
...the great Kaito Kid!
But isn't he a thief?
I don't care what you think. I like the Kaito Kid.
Hey, you can't be saying that "prince" of yours from earlier was...
Yeah. Got a problem with that?
Hurry! Uncle, get a move on!
Shut up! I'm going as fast as I can!
What's that?
A fire?!
The bridge is burning!
There's no other path to that lodge!
Uncle, call the police!
H-Hey!
Ran, wait for me.
Ran!
Huh? That's odd...
The phone line's dead.
What's wrong, Ran?
I just... it was as if someone'd called my name.
Someone calling "Ran" in the middle of the mountains?
I'll just take a look in the entrance.
Are you crazy? Nobody's gonna come here.
Conan-kun!
What?
Why's he lying there?
And he's burning up!
Ran... run away...
Hurry... get away... from here...
Conan-kun...
Hang in there, Conan-kun!
Conan-kun... Conan-kun...!
What?!
That kid was passed out at the entrance?
But why was he still...?
Maybe he wanted to stay here.
I don't think that's it.
Conan-kun was saying...
"Run away..."
"Hurry, get away from here..."
What does that mean?
I don't know. He fainted right after.
Umm, I brought some fever medicine.
My diagnosis is that he has a cold, so with the medicine and lots of rest, he should be fine.
My apologies.
Don't worry.
Your diagnosis, you say?
I don't look it, but I'm a medicine student.
Anyway, let's try to call the board leader again.
What did you say?!
What do you mean "you can't do anything until the morning", Inspector?!
Don't yell, Mouri-kun.
Plotting another route through those mountains at night is too dangerous,
and though we could take a helicopter there in three minutes,
we could end up hitting the power lines and crashing.
Then why don't you call the lodge's phone number?
We've been trying for a while, but the phone line's busy or it was cut.
Anyway, I'm going there now, wait for me.
Damn it!
Huh? It's not working...
Maybe the line got cut somewhere.
But what a problem...
He's the one who we left handling the plans for this get-together...
Then we could choose a temporary replacement leader.
That's true...
Well, I don't want to be leader.
What if we play rock-paper-scissors?
Wait, wait. Just decidin' like that's no fun.
This is an amateur magicians' club. Let's let magic decide.
Magic?
Sonoko-san, lend me a hand.
Me?
Yeah.
First we use this white handkerchief to blindfold Lady Sonoko's beautiful eyes.
Anybody got a pen and paper?
Ah... Will this do, Mr. Magician?
OK.
First, write the names of everybody here in each paper.
Yes, yes.
Once you're done, put 'em together, turn 'em, and give 'em to Lady Sonoko.
Let's see... The members are these.
Yes. There you go, Sonoko-chan.
Oh, and the pen too.
All right. Then, here.
Everybody, please stand back.
Then, Lady Sonoko, without showin' anybody, mark three papers with a circle, a cross, and a triangle.
A circle, a cross and a triangle?
The circle is the temporary leader.
The cross is the ceremony master, who'll be plannin' the get-together.
And the triangle is, I dunno. He can set up the bath or something.
I can set up the bath.
Don't worry about it. It's a game, so there's gotta be some kind of punishment.
Right! I've written the symbols!
Now, someone put all the papers on the table, makin' sure the names are all face-down.
Then, we flip them over to see who's the leader?
Wait!
Before you flip them over, I want to guess the names under each paper.
Guess?
If my intuition's right...
The temporary leader is...
Kuroda-san, it's you.
No way...
Kuroda
No way!
He guessed it...
Next, the one to prepare the bath...
Tanaka-san, it's you!
Me?
Tanaka
Amazing, he guessed it!
See?
It's true...
Tanaka
You didn't swap them out or anything, did you?
Of course not!
You saw it, right? I didn't touch the papers at any point.
And the drawings were made by Lady Sonoko.
Got it. I'll go set up the bath, then.
Sorry.
Umm... do you know where the firewood is?
Don't worry. We all looked around the place when we got here.
Well, then, only the cross is left.
The ceremony master...
Doito-kun, it's you!
You've gotta be kidding...
Let's see, let's see...
Oh?
The ceremony master's name...
Hamano
...it's yours, Hamano-san.
Look, no doubt about it.
Huh?
That's odd...
Come on, come on! Go to your room and think of something cool!
Try not to miss anything!
Yeah, yeah...
But what do I do? The last time I was a leader was when I was with the boy scouts.
Don't worry, it's just temporary.
Well then, I'm gonna get a good wine from the cellar.
Sugama-kun, please go to the kitchen and make us something to eat.
Yes.
Well then, see you later... leader.
Then uh, Sonoko-chan, please go check how that child's cold is.
Yes! Got it.
We might as well set the table.
Well? How's Conan-kun doing?
His fever's gone down a bit.
Doito-san's medicine worked.
I'm glad.
He may not be like you imagined him, but he's not that bad a guy, Sonoko.
You think? Well, him being in medical school's cool, but...
By the way, Ran, you should've seen Hamano-san's magic!
Though at the end he got one wrong, he was still really cool!
He's getting something cool set up, so make sure you come down later, Ran!
But what about Conan-kun?
Don't worry! His fever's going down, so we can leave him here for a couple of hours!
Ah, everything's set!
Now sit, sit, get in your seat.
Huh? Where are the others?
The ceremony master, Hamano-san, is practicing for his magic show up there.
Ara-san went to get wine.
Oh, so cold!
Ah, he's here.
The Escape King and the Shadow Priest aren't here yet.
Those two don't get along at all, they probably got in a fight somewhere.
They don't get along?
That's right. A while ago they fought over a magician.
Now, now. Don't talk about unpleasant things at a time like this.
The Shadow Priest and the board leader, the Escape King should be here any minute now.
They're not coming.
Conan-kun!
That man was killed at his apartment!
Killed?!
What do you mean, Conan-kun?
That man... Tsutomu Nishiyama, right?
Y-Yeah.
Then it's like they said on the radio. No doubt about it.
I turned around to tell you. Everybody here's in danger!
Why us?
The dead Nishiyama-san's
computer monitor had a message...
"He is but the first one...", signed "The Shadow Priest."
He is but the first one...
- The Shadow Priest
What did you say?!
Now that I think about it, Hamano-san was also in that fight between those two.
A-Anyway, we have to let him know about this.
Hamano-san? Hamano-san, we're coming in.
Eh? He's not here.
The window's open...
Could he have...
At least he didn't fall...
Hey...
Over there!
Isn't that Hamano-san?
No way!
That's impossible!
Hamano-san!
What's wrong, Hamano-san?
Stay where you are!
It's no use... he's already dead.
No way!
And we shouldn't touch anything in the crime scene.
Crime scene?
Look, don't you see?
He's over 10 meters away from the lodge,
and there's no footprints around except the ones that guy who just ran over made.
But that's...
Yes. A crime no man can commit without wings.
An impossible crime!
You know the Shadow Priest's identity?
A suspicious person among those in the lodge, who's transmitting with a fake ID...
What...?
An arrow came suddenly...
Who's there? Come out!
Don't!
Get away from the window!
On the next Conan:
The Magic Lovers' Club Murder Case (The Suspicion)
Next Conan's Hint: Boat sail
Next time we're tackling an impossible crime!
Okay, let's go!