Alibi, Deceit, Deception.
A Mysterious Dark Organization.
Today Ayumi is in peril!
True reasoning lies in silence!
Seeing the one and only truth,
A child with the intelligence of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
SOS! Messages from Ayumi
Let's see, let's see... yes, this one!
Hm, what should I do next...
Yes, I've won!
So, that leaves Mitsuhiko and me again...
Good, it's your turn Mitsuhiko.
This will be easy.
Let's see...
This one!
Yes, I've won!
Damn, why do I always lose?!
From your expressions, even a
preschooler could beat you.
Your face especially winces when you
have the Joker over other cards.
You shouldn't have said anything Conan-kun!
I get it now.
Right, let's play again...
This time you won't see anything from my face.
Does Haibara-san want to join us?
I would rather read this book.
Books can't be friends, you know.
She still acts so cool...
That's right, Conan-kun.
Have you heard...
About the burglary murder case from yesterday?
Yeah.
The owner of the French restaurant Lu
Escargot was killed in the case right?
That's a strange name for a shop.
Not at all.
Escargot is...
A snail used for cooking in France.
Eh, snails are edible?
Could there be snail rice?
Disgusting.
What are you imagining?
So, did you find out any details?
Yeah. Last night, I overheard a conversation
between Inspector Megure and Mouri-san.
They say the burglar broke into the victim's room in
the afternoon and killed him while he was sleeping.
That means, the burglar thought no
one was home when he broke in.
I believe so.
The victim was bound and killed by a knife.
The criminal probably needed to know
the location of items such as money.
Then killed the victim just as he left.
Perhaps the murder was to ensure the
criminal's identity remain concealed?
Most likely.
That's brutal!
An evil offender.
I guess this one isn't for the Detective Boys.
Of course not!
You children shouldn't be discussing
murder cases anyway.
You should talk about children's things, like dreams.
Hey Professor, do you have throat medicine?
You have a sore throat?
That's right, Ayumi-chan! Your voice is weak today.
Open your mouth so I can see.
It definitely seems swollen.
And you have a fever.
Maybe the flu?
If you have the flu, eat some eel with rice.
Genta-kun, you're different from her.
Ayumi-chan, you should go home.
We'll all go home together.
That's right, get some rest at home.
That's good.
Good idea. Wait here while I get the car.
Stand!
Good morning.
Yes, welcome back to class.
Sit!
Before we start lessons, I just received
a call from Ayumi-chan's mother.
Ayumi-chan is sick and can't come today.
I knew it.
Why didn't she have her eel with rice?
She really did look sick yesterday.
Hey, worried?
Of course.
Hard to believe your compassion.
Shut up.
Well Ayumi-chan, mom is going out for a while.
I'll finish my errands quickly and be back by noon.
You need to rest, alright?
Be safe...
Don't worry. When your throat clears
up you'll be able to talk again.
Goodbye.
This is Yoshida, I'm not available right now.
Please leave a message after the beep.
Yes?
Yaiga-san? I have your package.
Yes, come in.
It's mom!
No, it's not mom.
Mom wouldn't chime the bell.
A burglar!
I have to... call the police!
This is a kid's bedroom.
Come on out my sweet child.
I won't hurt you.
What to do?
He must be the burglar Conan-kun mentioned.
If I'm discovered...
I'll be treated like that owner.
Hey, let's all visit Ayumi at her
house today when school ends.
Yes! She would be very happy.
Will she really?
Girls hate to be seen when they don't look their cutest.
Especially by boys they like.
Hey, hey...
I'm joking. Primary School girls probably wouldn't care.
What do you mean?
She IS a Primary School girl.
It must be Ayumi-chan!
She's playing that keyboard.
Ayumi-chan?
Today is the 5th, 10:30AM.
It's the Yaiba clock.
That's right. It's a Masked Yaiba Clock.
Professor Agasa bought them for everyone.
Just push the button on the head
and it states the date and time.
Then why is Ayumi-chan not talking us?
Maybe she can't speak?
Hello, Ayumi-chan?
Ayumi-chan, can you not speak right now?
Tap once for yes.
Tap twice on the badge for no.
Great, she means "yes".
I guess she can't talk.
I think she's bored right now
and just wanted to hear us.
Yes, I should sing for her.
Hold on a second.
Eh?
Something is wrong.
But just now the clock was five minutes late.
Plus it's not the 5th today.
Then...
Maybe there's something wrong with Ayumi-chan
that she wants us to know.
Ayumi-chan, is something wrong there?
Ayumi-chan, tap once for yes, and
twice on the badge for no.
It's no.
She's just bored and wanted to talk with us.
It's almost time for class, we'll talk to you later!
Oh no, we have Music next.
We have to hurry. Kobayashi-sensei
is pretty scary when she's upset.
Let's go!
I can't believe a child has such technology.
As I'm sure most of you know,
There will be a music concert
contest in school next month.
I really think that Group-B should play the piano.
But we have to decide on the song today.
Does anyone have suggestions?
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
Are you worried about Ayumi-chan?
Yeah.
So am I.
The melody that she first played...
It seemed rather familiar.
Do you have any clues?
Not really.
I think it was, Mi-Mi-Re-Do-Re.
Besides that...
Why were the date and time wrong?
Today is the 5th, 10:30AM.
The 5th... 10:30...
The song's been chosen now.
Let's all sing together first.
Yes!
mi
re
do
It's a snail!
She was telling us "snail"!
I see!
Teacher, please call the police!
Ayumi-chan is in immediate danger!
Wait, Edogawa-kun!
Damn, why didn't I see it earlier?
That melody details a snail.
Snail
Which refers to Lu Escargot!
Lu Escargot
Fifth Day of the Month, 1:30
From the date and time to "Goutouhan",
Go
Tou
Han
She means the event from the other day!
burglar at the Tower
At that time, the burglar must've
answered as Ayumi-chan!
Ayumi-chan, is something wrong there?
Ayumi-chan, tap once for yes, and
twice on the badge for no.
Just be alright... Ayumi!
I understand now, Haibara-san.
Everyone, Teacher is going to call the police.
Be quiet and study!
Genta-kun.
Yeah, let's go Mitsuhiko.
Damn, I'm running out of time.
Wait, when the burglar killed the owner...
He only killed him right before he was leaving.
It's only 짜75,000.
I can't believe there's nothing valuable
in this expensive apartment.
Now... it's time to leave.
This is Yoshida, I'm not available right now.
Please leave a message after the beep.
Hey, it's me.
Professor Agasa!
I'm right by your home now.
You know, that 짜5,000,000 yen I borrowed
the other day, I want to pay it back.
I'm on my way from the bank.
짜5,000,000!
I collected the money for my invention.
I guess you're probably shopping
at the market nearby.
I'll go by now.
That's right... Professor Agasa
was notified by Conan-kun.
Hey. That person who called, is he your grandfather?
짜5,000,000...
I can't miss that.
It's me. Open the door.
Yes!
This is bad! Professor Agasa will be captured...
What should I do?
Here, here.
Who are you? Where's the old man?
It's only been me from the beginning.
You're a burglar, right?
I wonder if you know...
How painful a soccer ball can be when you get hit.
Especially one kicked by Power-Enhancing Shoes?
Want to know?!
Ayumi-chan!
Are you alright, Ayumi-chan?
Wait, let me get those.
You treat me like this...
Damn! The helmet weakened the kick's power!
I can't forgive you.
Die!
Stop that!
Who are you?
Kojima Genta!
Tsubaraya Mitsuhiko!
Of the Detective Boys Group!
What?
Run!
Don't underestimate me.
We... We...
Succeeded!
The Detective Boys win!
You guys...
Awesome!
We did something great!
It's great you've recovered, Ayumi-kun.
Yeah, my voice is back to normal.
I still can't believe the criminal wasn't the
one involved with the murder case.
It's hard to believe.
I heard the murderer was caught in Yokohama.
According to Inspector Megure,
The criminal that broke into Ayumi-chan's home
had no intention of hurting Ayumi-chan.
He believed, even if a child saw his face, since she's a
child, the testimony wouldn't be accepted in court.
But he attacked Conan-kun himself.
So he deserved to be charged.
You idiots!
What do you mean "deserved to be charged"?!
I'm glad I happened to overhear this.
Wait for the police to arrive next
time and leave it to them.
Yes. It will be done next time!
Then... I'm glad you understand.
Hey, let's play on the swings!
Let's go.
I'll race you there!
But do they really understand?
Shinichi, you too.
I know.
I try not to be like them.
Not that.
No matter your intelligence, you
look like a boy to others.
You are...
Professor?
Thank you!
If you didn't call my house, the
criminal would've gotten away!
Eh? Yeah...
It's alright to imitate my voice, but as her grandfather?
Sorry, sorry.
Well... if I had grandchildren like you
guys, my life would be complete.
Come on, let Grandpa push you!
He's involved.
If he wants grandchildren he should
try getting married first.
Next Conan:
The Night Before the Wedding Locked Room Case
(Part 1)
Next Conan's Hint:
Pendant