Alibis, codes, tricks, deals.
The mysterious Black Organization.
Today's stage is a big mansion!
A soon-to-be bride has a lot on her mind!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Whoa, what's with all the people?
Is there a festival goin' on or somethin'?
This is normal.
Shibuya's always like this on weekends.
There sure are a lotta people around, though.
It's like being at the big Tenjin festival.
Yer right!
Or like the cherry blossom viewing at the Japan Mint.
Sheesh.
You call me from Tokyo Station,
announcing that you're in town and you want a sightseeing tour.
Don't be so stingy! You weren't doin' nothin'!
I've got some business here,
and I've never looked around Tokyo.
It's the perfect opportunity!
So what brings you here?
My mom's classmate's son's wedding!
My mom was gonna attend it herself,
but she dropped a takoyaki grill
on her foot and broke a bone.
That sounds painful.
And in her place, you're attending
the wedding with Kazuha-chan?
That's right.
She's just tagging along!
I am not!
I didn't want to come,
but Heiji's mother begged me to look after him!
Yeah, right. You were all giddy about shopping in Shibuya.
Oh, I know this great shop on—
Don't sweat it.
I've already researched the stores I wanna hit.
I see.
This is cute!
Do you think it'll look good on me?
Why not? You're super-cute.
If you like it, you'd better buy it,
or someone else'll get it first!
I-I guess you're right...
Yeesh! What's takin' Heiji and the others so long?!
And after they nagged us about spending too much time in the shops!
Hey...
What?
What's bothering you?
It's me, isn't it?
It's the same.
You're wearin' the same kind of shirt as Heiji, aren't ya?
Huh? It's just a coincidence.
This isn't the first time!
You two were both wearin' black, collared shirts when you came to Osaka!
I bet you picked 'em out beforehand, right?
Talk about tacky!
It's so lame for a couple to wear matching clothes, don't ya think?
It grosses me out.
Hey! We're in the middle of town, ya know?!
There! Now I'm wearing a different shirt!
You're... a nice person.
You think so?
So this is the Meiji Temple...
Kazuha! Pray for your thighs to get thinner!
Shut that trap!
Ran, you took off that shirt your mother gave you.
Yeah, it got a little sweaty.
I'm sorry, Ran-chan.
No problem.
Oh? Is that you, Heiji-kun?
Shigematsu-han?
I never thought I'd see you up here!
I thought you'd be at the house by now.
Who's this guy?
This is the butler of the family
my mom's classmate is marryin' into!
Akio Shigematsu (51)
Morizono Family Butler
Pleased to meet you. I'm Shigematsu.
And what're you doing at a place like this?
Escorting the young lady.
She wanted to look around Tokyo before the wedding.
Then this must be...
That's right.
Kaede-san, who'll be marrying young master Kikuhito tomorrow!
Kaede Katagiri (22)
Kikuhito Morizono's fiancée
Nice to meet you. I'm Kaede Katagiri.
Ah, likewise.
But shouldn't her fiancé be showing her around?
I invited him to join us.
It's my fault. I wanted to go to Tokyo Tower.
Young master has been afraid of heights since he was small.
Well? What did you pray for?
To be blessed with children.
With children?
That wasn't the look I saw on her face...
A girl getting married has a lot on her mind, ya know!
That's right. Wedding blues, right?
Right!
When did those two get all chummy?
Wow!
This house is huge!
It hasn't changed since I visited it as a kid.
Are you sure we can just drop in?
Of course! If you have the time,
you should have dinner here too.
Sakuraba-kun! Don't be so rude in front of the guests!
Yuji Sakuraba (23)
Morizono Family Servant
I'm sorry.
The master's cat ran away and climbbed a tree again.
Oh, it's so cute!
Let us see it!
Ouch!
Hey! Wait, Rebecca!
I'm sorry!
Ah, you must be my little brother's princess.
I don't care if you're the daughter
of the chairman of a big company.
You'd better be ready!
I'm going to beat the rules of
this family into your bones!
Er... okay...
Just kidding!
I'm his sister, Yurie.
Yurie Morizono (28)
Eldest Morizono Daughter
I'm usually abroad, so I won't
be here to get on your back!
Miss!
And you really are something!
I heard you came here over and over
to pin my playboy brother down!
Oh, no, ma'am! The young master fell in love at first sight!
That's not what you told me before...
Really?
In any case, you arranged this marriage, right?
My father may reward you for it!
Yeah...
And here's the famous detective.
Kogoro Mouri, at your service!
It's certainly an honor
to dine with a man like you.
No, the honor's all mine.
I used to have a yearning
to become a detective myself.
Mikio Morizono
Head of the Morizono family
So how does it feel to be called one of
the greatest forensic minds of our era?
Well, it sure is surprising that all
my cases are solved so quickly.
It's like a dream.
A dream? You've got that right, mister!
What do you mean?
Oh, I know! Shigematsu-kun!
Could you bring the camera?
We should get a picture of this!
Of course.
And I'll need you to drop by my room later.
You've done so much for my son's marriage.
I want to thank you.
I'll give you anything!
Yes, sir.
Oh, Sakuraba-kun!
My cat seems to have disappeared again. Could you have a look?
Yes, sir.
It's a very skittish cat.
It was attached to my wife, but...
Your wife?
Kikuhito Morizono (26)
Eldest Morizono Son
My mother passed away four years ago,
in an unfortunate road accident.
Oh, sorry. This is my son, Kikuhito.
Did you enjoy your day in Tokyo, my honey?
Yes, very much.
"Honey"?
Cheesy.
Well, see ya!
I'll drop by your office after the wedding tomorrow!
Well, see you tomorrow. Good night!
Yeah, good night.
What was that for?
Just a sigh of relief!
Every time I'm with him, I get dragged into a case!
You mean Ran-chan's dad?
Uh... right! That guy's a magnet for...
What was that?
The window on the third floor!
Somebody broke it!
Ran-neechan, keep an eye on that window!
Kazuha! Just in case, go call Shigematsu-han!
Heiji?!
That's the room...
Hey, what's up?
What's going on in there?
Geez! It's locked!
Heiji!
Guys! Where's Shigematsu-han?
That's the problem!
He's been missing for a while now!
Shoot! He's the one with all the keys!
Better break down the door!
Blood!
It continues into the next room.
Hey, what's wrong?
What are you...
What was that scream just now?
What's this?
What's the matter?
What happened?
There's been a murder.
It's the butler.
Shigematsu-han is dead.
N-No...
How can that be?
Come on! This has gotta be a joke, right?
Kaede-san!
Hey, what're you guys doin'?!
Hang in there, Kaede-san!
I've called for the police.
Please stay where you are until they arrive.
This side's locked.
So is this one.
Hang on, you two...
Hey!
Don't start tinkering around!
Hey, you've been watchin' this window till now, right?
You didn't see anyone come out this way, did you?
No! Nothing like that!
So that means...
No way...
Hey! Didn't I tell you to stay put?!
Hey! Shigematsu-han is the only person who had all the keys to the house, right?
Er, yes...
Is there a spare key for this room?
Everyone has a spare key to their private rooms.
But for rooms we don't often use, like this one,
Shigematsu-san kept all the keys.
Then I'm gonna have to test something.
Test?
The key to the door we just broke through!
If the key to this door...
is somewhere on this keyring...
So what?
Don't ya get it?
We had to break down the door 'cause it was locked, right, old man?
The room where the body was found has two locked windows...
and nobody escaped through the window in the next room.
And the only key to this room...
was in the inner pocket of Shigematsu-han's jacket.
I see.
Yes. There's another answer.
It's a locked-room murder.
But Shigematsu-san could have locked the door himself and committed suicide.
Then we'd find some sort of weapon next to him.
The body has obviously been stabbed in the chest.
So somebody, somehow, disappeared from this room, along with the murder weapon...
into thin air.
Oh, geez.
Whoever did it, it's going to cause problems with the wedding tomorrow.
What are you talking about, Kikuhito?
We can't possibly have the wedding now!
Come on, big sis.
The victim isn't a member of the Morizono family.
And I don't want to bother to change my honeymoon schedule.
I know he was with the house for a long time, and I'm sorry for him.
But we spent a fortune on the ceremony tomorrow.
I'm sure Shigematsu-san would be happier that way.
Damn you...
Stop it, Kikuhito!
A man has died, and that's all you've got to say?!
Shame on you!
Sakuraba-kun lost his parents at a young age, and Shigematsu-kun was like a father to him!
Show a little human feeling!
And Shigematsu-kun was the person who arranged this marriage in the first place!
Also, Shigematsu-kun worked hard at the company I'm putting you in charge of!
How dare you be so disrespectful to him?
And you, Sakuraba-kun!
Never raise a hand against a member of the family you serve!
From now on, restrain yourself.
Yes, sir.
Yurie, I'll need you to contact Kaede-san's parents.
Tell them the wedding has been postponed.
D-Did that man just move?
What? That's ridiculous!
Oh, it's just the cat.
Come here, Rebecca.
So that cat was at the scene of the crime all along?
Too bad cats can't talk.
She seems close to that cat.
Yurie is the spitting image of my late wife.
The cat only comes near my son or me when we feed her.
Master! The police are here! Has something happened?
Don't worry about that. I'll be right there!
What happened to your leg?
I was riding with my wife when our car crashed.
I only injured my leg, but my wife...
Morizono-san!
Is it true that your butler's been murdered?
Will your son's wedding tomorrow be canceled?
There are rumors of bribery in your son's company!
Does that have anything to do with this case?
Hey! Save the questions for later!
I'm Megure, from the Metro Police!
Thank you for coming.
I've already heard the details of this case...
from that walking bad-luck charm over there.
Come on. I'm not bad luck.
Cases just happen to call the name of the great Kogoro Mouri!
A locked-room murder?
That's right!
Both the door and the windows were locked,
nobody escaped through the window in the next room,
and the murder weapon's missing. Which means it's a locked-room murder!
A locked room...
But how did you know there was a body in this room?
That window suddenly shattered while I was just outside.
We ran up and knocked on the door, but no one answered,
so we forced our way in, and found the corpse.
But it's premature to call this a murder.
The victim could have stabbed himself in the chest,
then thrown the knife through the window.
That ain't possible.
We looked at the window right after it broke,
but we didn't see anything come flyin' out of it.
And what are you doing here?
And if he'd chucked the weapon out...
there'd be more blood around the window, right?
But look at the bloodstains! The body was obviously dragged to where it's lyin' now!
The window must've been broken by accident during the struggle.
Or somebody saw us outside and used this chair to break the window.
Maybe they wanted to draw our attention.
Inspector!
When the body was discovered, an hour and a half ago,
most of the household servants were having dinner in the kitchen
and discussing the wedding plans when the murder took place.
The only people who don't have clear alibis seem to be these five.
Good work.
I'll be talking to each of you later!
Until then, I'd like you to submit to a quick body search, then wait in your rooms!
Officers, go over the house and grounds with a fine-tooth comb!
The weapon must be somewhere!
I want you to find it at all costs!
Hey, Kudo.
How many have ya got?
Four.
Yeah, I noticed four suspicious points, too.
First, there's the missing murder weapon.
The killer took the trouble to create a locked-room scenario.
Leaving the weapon behind would've made it look more like a suicide.
Then there are those bloodstains.
Why'd the killer drag the body into the next room?
Third, why was the light on in the room with the body?
And most suspicious of all...
- The cat!
Actually, I thought I had one more.
Huh? You too?
Please, Detective!
Please let me help in the investigation!
No! You have to stay in your room!
But I can't sit idly by!
Hey...
Knock it the hell off!
Can't you tell that every time you do something...
you just cause more trouble for the Morizono family?
Don't forget your place, servant!
Are you okay?
What's up with that guy?!
I'm... fine.
They match.
No!
Not your clothes! The pendants!
Pendants?
Yeah!
I saw it come off his neck...
Sakuraba-san and Kaede-san are wearin' the same pendant!
I wonder why.
You're right. It can't be a coincidence.
Hey, Kudo...
Yeah.
Looks like we've found another piece of this puzzle.
Well, let's give it a try using the next balcony over.
Give what a try?
What else?
We have to find out if this escape method is really possible.
And who's gonna do it?
There's something stuck in that tree!
What are you doing?!
K-Kudo!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Bag
Next time, it's the Great Detectives of the East and West again!
Inspector, we've got to arrest the killer, or else!