Alibis, codes, tricks, deals.
The mysterious Black Organization.
A big case on the eve of a wedding!
The lovers are closer than they seem!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
While showing Tokyo to Heiji and Kazuha,
who had come to attend the wedding of a friend,
we met with Shigematsu-san,
the butler of the family who were celebrating the marriage, the Morizonos.
He invited us to go to the Morizonos' mansion.
That very evening, Shigematsu-san
was murdered in a locked room.
Kazuha found something in common
between two of the suspects.
What? You can't find the weapon?
We've searched the house and grounds, but we've found nothing.
Well, search again! It's got to be lying around somewhere!
We've got to find the weapon that killed Shigematsu-san!
It's not just the weapon.
You may also find the murderer's bloodstained clothes!
Look at Shigematsu-han's body.
It's covered in blood.
When the killer pulled the knife out,
blood must've spattered everywhere.
I-I see...
But the murderer could've just been some random burglar.
Maybe the butler saw him,
so the thief stabbed him and ran!
No, that's not possible!
The house's security system is perfect,
and the only outsiders who have entered recently
are us, the police, and the reporters,
who showed up after the crime.
And don't forget that the doors
and windows were locked.
A random thief couldn't have
gotten in and out so easily!
The killer's gotta be somebody who knows
this house and doesn't have an alibi.
That leaves just five people!
You questioned those people,
didn't ya, Inspector? How'd it go?
Well...
Mr. Mikio, the master of the house,
claims to have been in his room
waiting for Shigematsu-san.
They were planning to have a talk.
Their daughter, Yurie-san,
was by herself, taking a bath.
Kikuhito-san, the son, was in his room
reading a magazine and listening to music.
And Sakuraba-san, the servant,
was looking around the house for the cat, as he'd been ordered.
Kaede-san, the fiancée,
told a story that sounds a little fishy.
She says she was taking a nap in her room
while she waited for her parents to pick her up.
Fishy?
Seems Yurie-san knocked on her door
to ask if she'd like to join her in the bath,
but she never got a reply.
By the way, what happened to that window?
I heard there was a scuffle
after the body was found.
Kikuhito made some rude remarks,
so Sakuraba fed him a knuckle sandwich!
He punched him so hard, Kikuhito crashed into that window!
Inspector Megure! Could you come here for a moment?
What is it, Tome-san?
Look over here.
What happened?
At the bottom of this latch,
there's a small blood stain.
You're right!
The killer must've touched it
with blood-stained gloves.
That means the killer opened and closed this window after the murder.
But why?
The window was locked from the inside.
Hey, Hattori.
Look at this piece of broken glass.
There's a little hole in it.
Whoa. I wonder why...
I didn't notice it when I checked out the window before.
I can't blame you for overlooking it.
Judging from the shape of this broken piece,
the hole was right on the edge of the windowpane, where it was barely visible.
That means we know what to look for.
Yeah. It should be somewhere on this balcony.
Inspector, may I have a word?
What is it?
Shigematsu-kun was our butler,
but also a dear friend to my wife and myself.
I would like to hold a funeral as soon as possible,
and bury him near my wife's grave.
I'm sure that's what she would have wanted.
I'm sorry, but I can't let you do anything until we're finished with the autopsy.
I see. What a shame.
Sounds like that story my mom told me is true...
Story?
The wife who died four years ago was actually in love with Shigematsu-han!
She started dropping by this house to see Shigematsu-han,
but the man of the house thought she was coming to see him instead.
In the end, he proposed to her.
The parents of both families hit it off really well.
She once told my mom that she was overwhelmed by his courtship and gave in.
The wife and the butler, huh? Interesting.
Yup. Sounds like the same old story.
Look at those two, wearing the same pendant...
So have you been able to find it, Hattori?
Nope, nowhere.
But if the killer escaped from the balcony, it's gotta be here.
Well, let's give it a try using the next balcony over.
Give what a try?
What else?
We have to find out if this escape method is really possible!
And who's gonna do it?
Who else but you, Heiji-kun?
Hey, Kudo!
Keep your eye on the rope, will ya?
I know!
Hey! How's it coming, Hattori?
It's a lot easier than I thought!
Then the murderer escaped downstairs from this balcony...
Hey, what's that?
There's something stuck in that tree!
What? Where?
That tree, in front of the room with the body!
What are you doing?!
Hang on, Kudo! I'll be there in a sec!
Hey, Ran-chan! Ain't that Conan-kun?!
No way!
What're you doin'?
Hey, you! What do you think you're doing?!
You've gotta help that kid!
H-Help him?
B-But I...
What a relief.
What was that?!
The kid was about to fall.
Hey! Why didn't ya help him?!
You were right there, weren't ya?!
Don't blame him.
Kikuhito's been terrified of heights
ever since he was small.
Oh... Come to think of it,
Shigematsu-han mentioned that.
Hattori, that thing you saw up in the tree...
Yeah. Let's go check it out.
Hey! What're you two doing now?! Climbing trees?
It's dangerous!
Found it!
This is it!
A blood-stained shirt!
There's a pair of gloves with blood on them...
and a kitchen knife.
It's just as we suspected. Look, a piece of cellophane tape at the end of the string!
Now we know who the killer is,
and how the room was locked!
- Case closed!
Okay, this feels wrong.
Yeah. There's a bunch of questions
that still ain't been answered.
R-Rain?
It's really coming down.
Hey, it started to rain!
Rain, huh?
Wait a minute...
Wasn't that...
The rain shutter.
Aha! Now I get it!
It makes sense now...
The missin' weapon from the scene of the crime,
the blood marks on the floor
from the body bein' dragged,
the light turned off in the room,
the cat in the same room as the body,
and the evidence tied up in a neat little bundle,
it all makes perfect sense!
That's who the killer is!
But what're we gonna do? We've got no proof!
If we can't find the proof...
We'll make the killer hand it over!
Hey, Kazuha! Tell everybody to gather in the room with the body!
What?!
Ran-neechan, can you ask the Inspector to come here?
Heiji-niichan's got something important to tell him!
Right?
You betcha.
What's this about? Calling us all here suddenly...
Sorry to keep y'all waitin'.
Come on, now. What's the meaning of this?
You're not thinking of putting on a deduction show for us, are you?
That's exactly what I'm gonna do.
What?!
We figured out the locked-room trick, the killer, everything.
Yup. The person who stabbed Shigematsu-han to death, locked the room and escaped from it...
Sakuraba-san... I'm talking about you!
A lie...
He can't be the killer!
No way!
I can't believe it.
So how'd he create the locked room?
Can you explain that?
You betcha!
The key is to make a small hole in the glass of the window behind the victim.
A hole?
The lab team has already checked that, you know...
Just take a look, will ya?
First, I stick the loop onto the latch
with some cellophane tape.
Then, I put the broken piece of glass back into the windowpane and run the string through the hole.
Now, I get out onto the balcony and close the window.
Then, I just pull the string gently...
I-It's locked!
After that, I pull the string a little harder,
making the string slip off the tape,
and pull it out the window.
Now we've got ourselves a locked-room murder!
But that hole...
What if the police found it?
That's why Sakuraba-san punched Kikuhito-san.
He wanted to hide the hole in the window by shattering the glass.
But he punched him because
Kikuhito was being so rude!
Just an excuse!
From the start Sakuraba-san was lookin'
for an opportunity to break the window.
But unluckily for him, the window didn't
break too neatly. The hole's still there.
But that doesn't prove he's the murderer...
Think again, will ya?
The murderer escaped from that balcony!
You couldn't possibly do it,
since you've got a bad leg.
Neither could Kaede-san or Yurie-san.
Kikuhito-san's out of the question
since he's afraid of heights.
That leaves one person, a guy nimble enough to get a cat out of the tree.
Sakuraba-san, you're the only one capable of doing it!
You stabbed Shigematsu-san,
used that trick to lock the window,
then escaped downstairs from the balcony!
Then you came back up here,
pretendin' you knew nothin'.
Well? Am I wrong, Sakuraba-san?
N-No...
It wasn't me...
I didn't kill anyone...
That's right! Sakuraba-san can't be the killer!
Because...
Before he ran up here with everyone else...
He was with me!
R-Really?
Yes! We were looking around the house for the cat...
But why didn't you tell us that in the first place?
Well, I...
You didn't want the others to know
about your relationship, right?
Relationship?
Those two are wearin' the same pendant!
They must've bought it together somewhere.
I see. You two are lovers.
You killed Shigematsu-san because
he thwarted your relationship
by arranging her marriage to
someone else with the master.
No! I didn't kill anyone!
Let's talk back at the police station.
Wait! We really were together the whole time!
I'm very sorry,
but a testimony from someone who's intimate with the suspect isn't much evidence.
N-No...
Take him away!
Yes, sir!
N-No! It wasn't me! Please believe me!
I really...
Sakuraba-san... Sakuraba-san!
Here, dry your tears...
I'm willing to wait forever...
until that man disappears from your heart.
But I can't believe he killed Shigematsu-kun.
I'm shocked.
Sorry, but it's the truth.
He's nothing but a monster in human form.
Who else would kill kindly old Shigematsu?
Heiji...
But I'm sure he'll accept his fate
once the murder weapon is discovered among his belongings or somethin'...
Huh? You haven't found the weapon yet?
Well, that's it for today!
We'll be back again tomorrow to look for the weapon.
Guess we'll be heading out, too!
Hey!
It's already late, so let's spend the night here!
Please?
"Sakuraba"
I knew it was you...
Kikuhito-san.
You thought you could get away with it
by leaving all that fake evidence against Sakuraba-san...
but you can't deceive us!
W-What are you talking about?
I couldn't have done it! I'm afraid of heights!
That whole trick was a bluff!
You left the bloodstain on the window latch on purpose!
There were no traces of blood on the balcony!
After leaving that one stain,
why would the killer suddenly take off his bloody gloves to climb down the balcony?
S-So what trick did I use to get out of the locked room?
There was no trick.
You were in that room the whole time!
What?!
You were probably hiding behind a curtain
in the corner of the room next to the room where the body was found.
That's why you closed one of the rain shutters, right?
So nobody outside would see you hiding behind the curtain.
You prepared the taped string with the loop at the end and drilled the hole in the window.
Then you called Shigematsu-han into the room and stabbed him.
The blood spattered on you,
but you were wearing one of Sakuraba-san's shirts, which you'd stolen in advance.
You dragged his body into the room next door,
wrapped the gloves and weapon in that shirt,
and threw it out the window.
When you saw us outside the window,
you broke the glass with the chair,
and hid behind the curtain.
That way, after we broke down the door,
we'd follow the blood into the next room and discover the body!
So it was pretty easy for you to come out from behind the curtain.
Since the room was dark and everyone was focused on the body,
nobody saw you, so you were able to mingle yourself among everybody
as if you'd just heard the yell and came to see what was going on.
You shut the cat in the room to make sure Sakuraba-san didn't have a solid alibi.
You knew that when the cat went missing, he'd be told to go look for it.
B-But anyone could have done that.
No, only you.
The fact that all the evidence was bundled up with string proves it.
Ordinarily, no criminal would just package up the evidence and throw it all away!
Because of your fear of heights, you couldn't go out on the balcony.
You had to use the murder weapon as a weight to throw the clothes away.
You goaded Sakuraba-san into a fight so you could break the window with the hole.
But by tricking Sakuraba-san into punching you,
you could make it seem like he broke the window on purpose.
What are you talking about?
I came here to look for the weapon myself, to help with the case!
I just found this knife in his bag!
Oh, yeah? Take a closer look.
That bag ain't Sakuraba-san's...
it's mine!
Sakuraba-san's room is really next door!
The room, the bag, the weapon you found in the bushes,
and the whole racket about Sakuraba-san's arrest...
it was all a trap we created with the Inspector's help!
We knew you'd lower your guard...
and hand us the solid evidence on a platter!
I-It's all his fault...
He threatened to tell my father about my company's misdeeds
unless I called off the marriage.
I didn't get it. He was the one who set up the marriage in the first place.
Even if I cancelled the marriage,
I was afraid he'd go on blackmailing me.
That's why I decided to incriminate that guy who stole my fiancée.
He never stole anybody.
Kaede-san was in love with Sakuraba-san from the very beginning.
Shigematsu-han must've thought
she was droppin' by to see you,
so he pushed for the marriage.
No... He never said anything about that...
He probably didn't want to hurt your feelings.
After all, he was the one
who suggested the marriage.
And I'm sure Shigematsu-san
never wanted to blackmail you.
He just wanted to stop the marriage
so that two people who loved
each other could be together.
After all, he'd been in the
same situation once before.
Tokyo Station
Thanks for everything, old man.
Just consider it payback for
the time you helped us in Osaka.
I can't believe you pulled off that
trick without letting me in on it.
Ya know how the sayin' goes. "To fool your enemies, you must fool your friends first..."
Hey, how are Sakuraba-san and Kaede-san doing?
You just saw them, right?
Yeah. I apologized for
treating him like a murderer.
Anyway, what's takin' Kazuha so long?
Come on, Ran-chan! Let me off the hook!
I'm gonna die of embarrassment!
It's too late to complain!
Hey, Kazuha, you're wearin' a striped shirt too?
I-It's not like that! This is Ran-chan's shirt!
For some reason, she forced me to wear it, and...
I'm gonna change in the john!
Hold on!
I don't mind you wearin' that.
Y'know, we kinda look like...
L-Look like...?
Like brother and sister, dontcha think?
Rather than brother and sister,
more like a comedy duo...
He's dead.
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Photo of a star
Next time, a starry night!
Oh, hey, get my net!