Perceiving in a flash,
Once starts moving, it won't stop!
An ill-omened case and a night train.
The bell signifying the train start-off chills your spine.
Seeing the one and only truth,
A child with an adult's intelligence...
His name: Detective Conan!
The North Star #3 Express Leaving Ueno, Part One!
Dear Mouri Kogorou-sama,
And Ran-san, Conan-kun,
How are you?
Here are the Northern Star Express tickets I promised
you, I somehow managed to get them.
Takeshi-san and I are anticipating everyone's arrival.
We will talk about other stuff when you
arrive, so enjoy this luxurious train ride,
Hatamoto Natsue.
That's all.
I remember Natsue-san from the luxurious cruise case.
Yeah,
They left Hatamoto family together and moved to Hokkaido.
It's nostalgic.
We haven't seen them since that case.
Well, I don't want to gloat,
But the reason that we can enjoy this ride in this
royal room on the North Star Express is...
All thanks to me, sleeping Kogorou, who solved all the cases.
Yes, yes. Thanks a lot.
As long as you know.
That's the seventh time you've said
that ever since we got on this train.
But first of all, I'm hungry now...
That's right,
Natsue-san even reserved and paid in advance for dinner.
Let's visit the dining car.
I've heard the dining car is luxurious also.
Moron, watch where you're going!
You are...
Huh?
What is it? What happened?
I'm not sure.
Right, let's eat.
I believe they're serving French cooking tonight.
Really?
Great!
Enjoying French dishes on a train, it's like a dream.
Right.
Damn, it's Mouri Kogorou.
No one said he would be here.
That was great.
It was delicious.
Yeah.
The food is great and the room is gorgeous.
There's nothing else to mention.
What do you mean by that small room?!
Didn't I tell you to book a royal room?
I'm sorry.
But owner, you only decided to take the Northern star a week ago.
Since this is a famous train, we're lucky
to have gotten a room for everyone at all.
To think I'm in the same type of room as you are.
Not to mention, my wife considers it a disgrace.
She won't even come out of her room.
That's why I said we should have taken a plane...
Enough!
I wanted to go to tomorrow's auction by this train.
Well...
Have we met before?
Probably on TV or the newspapers.
The robbers tried to rob our jewelry shop just a few days ago,
Our owner allowed broadcasting of interviews later on.
Ah, I see.
The one who dealt with the burglars by himself was...
Hey, was there such a case?
Oh, it was during your camping trip, that afternoon.
Oh...
I didn't really do much.
When I pressed the alarm bell, the burglars got scared and fled.
But, the nearby neighbors are impressed with owner's bravery.
It was only a small affair.
But it was surely a nice advertisement in the neighborhood,
For your election campaign.
Such a clever scheme.
Mayor Ishizuchi, what are you doing here?
I'm going to Hokkaido on vacation.
What do you mean by scheme?
It's only a rumor.
Someone in the press began a rumor saying the boss
wanted to promote himself for this mayor election,
It's just some rumor that has no end.
There can't be smoke without a fire.
Hey, hey.
I've heard, the robbery was caught on security video.
I read the burglar was a retired wrestler.
It was unlikely a publicity stunt.
That's why it's suspicious.
That sort of burglar just got scared and
fled due to a simple alarm bell,
Without taking anything at all?
That's not enough to make you suspect him.
It's not only that.
The culprit said something weird as he ran away.
The shopkeepers heard him say it, right?
Something weird?
While the criminal was making his escape, he said;
"It's different from what we agreed on!"
Is that true?
Y-yeah...
I heard him say this myself.
That's definitely suspicious.
Something like this has happened before, right?
Who are you to make such accusations?
Huh?
You don't recognize me?
To be honest, I didn't mean to hide.
Mouri Kogorou-san... am I right?
Yes.
I can't believe it!
I didn't expect to see the renowned
detective Mouri Kogorou-san here!
Would you mind taking a picture together later?
Well...
Mouri...
Kogorou.
Really.
Coincidence is scary.
Your reserved table is ready, Akechi-sama.
Please follow me.
Sorry, I want to cancel dinner.
Um... Akechi-sama...
This trip will be interesting.
Hey hey, I'm pretty sure I remember a case,
Where a burglar ran without taking anything before.
I don't remember,
Maybe you were watching some suspense
movies that were similar.
No, it wasn't recent...
More like... a long time ago.
When I was a child...
Look look, we're passing through Seikan Tunnel!
Why aren't you two in bed?
Hey, it's 4 A.M.
Get some sleep.
Damn, I can't remember...
Where am I remembering this from?
That same incident...
Where?
The gunshot and scream merged inside of a tunnel...
What was that?
What was that scream just now?!
There was an odd sound before the scream.
It was gunfire.
Someone has been shot!
Moron.
How would you know without looking?
That's right.
As if he were an animal, he scoured the dark hallway...
Again.
Damn, what is that?!
Hey, you!
It's a murder!
That man, he just shot someone!
What did you say?!
What?
But he was not there anymore...
Stop, I won't let you go!
Damn, we're late.
The gunshot and train running sound were
making a melody by themselves...
Hey! Call the police immediately!
I see...
It's the story...
This...
Is like that story!
Written by my father...
That fictional story!
Well, according to the persona ID,
And driver's license found on the body...
The victim is an active resident of Tokyo,
Izumo Keitarou, 56 years old.
He's the owner of a big jewelry shop.
Gunshot?
Yeah.
From witness testimony,
The victim was shot by the culprit from behind.
I see that.
Then where's the culprit?
He fled that way.
The manager and others immediately chased after him...
But they lost him,
The criminal ran past in front of my room.
He used the gun to break the window in his room,
And then escaped from there.
Who are you?
Huh?
You don't recognize me?
Oh, you are...
I thought I saw you somewhere...
Seeping Kogorou.
That renowned detective, Mouri Kogorou?
He's cursed, they say everywhere he goes a crime occurs!
What kind of rumors are going around?
Then, you were the only one to see the criminal flee?
No, there were three of us.
Including myself, then my daughter Ran, and another...
Huh?
That kid's gone.
He was just here.
Jeez, where is he now?
Conan-kun?
It's exactly the same.
The robber's strange message...
And, the murder case on the train...
Whatever it is,
It's exactly like that story.
Just like the one I read when I was a kid,
He never published it, only finished the draft.
Damn,
I can't remember exactly since I was only a child.
I thought maybe father should know something.
Where did he go?!
Conan-kun, there you are.
Why do you always run off?
Excuse us.
The police are calling far us.
Okay...
Jeez, didn't I just explain this?
The criminal ran this way,
Opened this door himself,
Fired the gun at the window,
And after firing at us,
He then jumped from the train to escape.
Hold on, so you didn't really see him
escaping from the window, right?
Ah, right.
Normally, a criminal wouldn't leave their gun when escaping.
But after firing six shots inside the train,
There are bullets remaining.
Perhaps he fired the shots to scare you,
Then hid in another room?
No way!
Before I made it here, the criminal closed the door.
What if it just looked like that?
The hallway's light was off,
You were blinded by the gunfire.
Hey hey, Officer-san...
Right,
The door closed then.
But the Inspector is right.
After all, we never saw him escaping from the window.
Not to mention the culprit left his loaded gun behind.
Also,
With the door closed...
Why didn't he lock it?
Locking the door would give him more time to escape.
And,
The biggest mystery...
This case, why...
Why does it resemble the story my father wrote?
Still, he could have ran into another room.
Should we search every room from here?
Starting from these rooms around it.
Yeah.
Huh, no one is inside?
So noisy!
Do you know what time this is?
I'm sorry.
I'm Nishimura with the Hokkaido Police.
An incident has occurred on this train.
An incident?
How could you not notice all of this?
There was a loud noise from next door.
I wouldn't know since I was deeply asleep.
So what kind of incident occurred?
Uh, well ...
What's going on?
A man was shot,
Killed in the lobby on this train.
A jewelry shop owner, Izumo Keitarou-san.
There's... no way!
Why?!
Why my husband?!
Your husband?
Please move so I can search your room.
Lady, may I open it?
Alright.
But who killed my husband?
We're investigating at the moment.
But...
Isn't this a shotgun?
Yes, it's a hobby of mine.
I was going to go shooting in Hokkaido.
There is no one else here.
Yes.
Now your room, please.
Officer-san, my husband...
Please let me see my husband!
Lady, please calm yourself.
It's here.
What's inside of that bag?
Fishing gear.
The owner likes fishing with us, unlike
his wife, so I always bring these.
I see.
This is the next room.
Hey, that's the owner's room.
Nothing suspicious.
The only room left is this one.
Damn, everyone's being this way.
Hey, it's the police.
Open up!
What is it?
Police, I'm here to search your room.
Please.
Hey, what's that on the bed?
Ah, it's my bamboo sword.
It's broken, so I'm fixing it.
There's a kendo competition in Sapporo tomorrow.
Did something happen?
An unfortunate incident.
Damn, this is taking too long.
Tell the other officers to search all the rooms.
Right!
Why is it so noisy?
I was woken up.
Where is your room?
It's just up there.
Excuse me.
Hey hey!
Who are you?
It's just an ordinary golf bag.
Hey! You should stop before I call the police!
I'm the police. You've got a problem?
Did you find him... the criminal?
If it were that easy, there would be no need for police.
I remember, just before the incident,
There was a suspicious woman in the lobby car.
Woman?
Yes, she wore sunglasses and watched the victim the entire time.
Would you be ta king about me?
That's her!
What?
When I left the lobby, I was going to the toilet.
I only noticed him because I could smell his cigar.
I'm sorry, where's your room?
Right here.
Hey, your only luggage is that shoulder bag?
Yes,
I'm only going to Hokkaido to ride horses.
Horses?
Ah, I've seen it before.
Isn't that the one you wear a helmet and
different pants when riding a horse?
You mean my colette?
Of course I wear it.
You have everything, awesome.
Of course, boy.
Then, you clean the boro yourself too?
Yes.
I change it myself if it's old, just like boots or gloves.
Um... my guests are becoming impatient.
Can we proceed to the next station?
No way.
We can't move until we search all the rooms.
Someone might discard evidence from the window.
In that case, you should search the tunnel.
I've already issued that order.
Inspector Nishimura, the tunnel!
We found a male's body in the tunnel!
Wh... what?!
Well, it looks like he injured his head.
He probably hit his head when he tried
to escape through the window.
He's stupid.
Is this the man you guys saw?
Yeah.
Yes, I believe so.
What's this?
A fake mustache...
This is...
Asama Yasuji.
Hey, the same Asama Yasuji that...
Yeah, the robber of that Tokyo jewelry
store who didn't take anything.
He used to be in a three member group before,
But one died from a drug overdose while the others vanished.
I had heard he finally returned,
But I didn't think I'd see him here.
Hold on a second.
The victim on the train was the owner from
the jewelry story Asama robbed, right?
What?
Then, they're related.
Even if he's dead,
He's gone, we have our culprit.
Tell the conductor he can start the train again.
Yes.
The phone call you're trying to make, due to no
reception or power, cannot be connected.
The phone call you're trying to make, due to...
Hey hey.
Oh, it's you, boy.
Are you here to see me?
I just wanted to tell you...
That your disguise is pretty good.
Your true reason for being here isn't horseback riding,
But for something else, right?
What are you saying, boy?
I really am going horseback riding.
Moron.
What I said earlier about boro is something else.
You have no idea...
How to ride a horse, do you?
Right, reveal your identity.
I'm already suspecting you...
Lady.
You saw something odd?
I remember, just before the crime occurred...
Well, whose was it, I wonder.
Wait...
If that gunshot.... if it's still there...
If it's still there...
There, that's it!
Next Conan:
The North Star #3 Express Leaving Ueno, Part Two!
Next Conan's Hint:
Disguise
Next, the trip and the case both come to close.
These two are coming, Conan-kun.