In the moment, the truth is suddenly revealed.
Once it starts rolling, it won't stop.
There is a big surprise today. Those two will appear.
There will be danger on the platform.
Seeing through the one and only truth...
A child with the intelligence of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
We were going to Hokkaido by the
new Northern Star number 3 train.
While it was going through the Seikan tunnel...
The jewelry trader, Izumo Keitaro-san...
Was shot to death from behind his head.
The criminal then opened the window
of the room and jumped off the train.
Later, in the tunnel, the suspect was found...
The body of Asama Yasuji...
This case...
And the unpublished work by my father are identical...
Reveal your identity.
You're already suspected,
Auntie.
The North Star #3 Express Leaving Ueno (Part 2).
Oh, you got me.
Kudo Yukiko
Shinichi's mother
Shin-chan, you're so bright.
It wouldn't matter if you were a stranger,
But you can't fool your own son by just altering
your hair style and lipstick color.
It took me a while to set this hairstyle.
What's your reason for disguising yourself?
Well, why can't I disguise myself?
In Japan, I'm so famous.
How many years ago are you talking about...
Shut up.
I got on this train because...
I read some news in a Japanese newspaper
while I was in Los Angeles.
The robber who tried to rob a jewelry shop said some weird things,
Then ran away without taking anything.
Then, it's really...
Yeah, according to Yusaku...
The professional robbers inexpertly planned the crime...
And what the robber said when he was running away,
"It's not supposed to be like this."
It's identical to the work he wrote ten years ago.
Although there is a difference from the novel,
As the place robbed was an antique
store rather than a jewelry store.
What happened next?
We called the jewelry store.
We asked if the owner planned to take
a long distance journey by train.
Because the owner of the antique store in the novel,
Gets killed in the train tunnel.
Then they said he will get on the Northern Star six days later.
Why didn't you stop them?
H... How was I supposed to know it would
happen while I went to the bathroom?
At least, you should have discussed it with me.
But Shin-chan was with Ran-chan all this time.
Even so, you should have done something to prevent the murder.
What? Then, you think his death was my fault?
I didn't say that.
Where's the writer of the novel?
He took the earlier Northern Star and should be at Sapporo by now.
When we called the jewelry store,
They didn't tell us which one of the three trains he will take.
So, Yusaku and I took different trains.
He got on Train 1 while I got on Train 3.
The other one, Train 5 crossed the tunnel early in the morning.
So we believed that one would be safe.
I see. So this trick is better to do at night.
Then, what's the trick?
What?
Didn't you ask Dad about the story?
That...
What! He forgot the trick!
Because it was a work written ten years ago.
He said when the novel was stolen, only
the first part of the story was finished.
It was stolen?
Yes, a person from the publishing firm that kept the draft,
Was robbed while stopping at a bank.
Hey, would that robber be the...
Yes, that's right.
There were three robbers.
The head was called... Asama Yasuji,
The one found dead in the tunnel.
But isn't it strange?
How come the robber who stole the novel,
Has been murdered as written in the novel?
Yeah...
Hey, Conan-kun.
R-Ran-neechan.
What are you doing here?
Ah... I'm with this Auntie...!
You were talking with me, onee-san, right?
Yes...
Let's go to the lobby car.
Dad said he's going to show off his deduction.
It looks like he beat you to it.
It would be good if he's right.
Deduction show? Isn't the criminal the body found in the tunnel,
Asama Yasuji?
No, the criminal is Asama Yasuji.
Then, what's your deduction about?
It's about his intentions.
Intentions?
Right, the key to unfolding this puzzle is
When Asama-san broke into Izumo-san's jewelry store, he said,
"It's not supposed to be like this."
If this was the case, then it would have been a difficult puzzle.
But if Asama-san and Izumo-san were partners,
Then everything can be explained.
What?
I think Izumo-san allowed his store to be robbed on purpose,
Then have that jewelry returned back to him afterwards, secretly,
But also take the insurance money for the
stolen jewelry. He found Asama-san,
That he would get 50% of the insurance money.
But when the robbery happened,
Izumo-san pressed the alarm button
to force Asama-san to run away.
From the very beginning, Izumo-san didn't intend
to allow the robbers to get the jewels.
What?
He intended to show off that he got the robbers well,
So he could boost his popularity for the
next election to increase his votes.
Unfortunately, Asama-san ran away.
Izumo-san became worried and received a call from him.
Get on the specified Northern Star Train,
And finish the transaction, away from the police.
And Izumo-san, who was called, out this way,
Was shot by Asama, and Asama, who
wanted to escape from the window,
Hit his head hard on the ground, and died.
Now that I think about it, the bass decided to
catch the Northern Star after the robbery.
Yes, he sudden y decided to catch the train instead of the plane.
But how did Izumo-san first get to know Asama?
It's probably "that".
Wasn't it on the newspaper before?
Izumo-san was dealing drugs in the black market.
That was proven not to be true.
But it's like what the detective said,
He wasn't dealing with legal trading business.
This kind of disgusting person shouldn't be the next mayor.
How dare you say that in front of me.
Well, well.
That's true...
If it was an ordinary incident... Uncle's
deduction would be accurate...
But this incident is the same as the draft written by my Dad...
Hey, Inspector.
Doesn't that robber belong to the "Three-people gang"?
That's right.
Do you know the names of them all?
No, only the head Asama-san and the dead woman are known,
But we don't know who the third member is.
But, in the last robbery at the jewelry
store, only Asama was involved.
I guess the other one retired from the gang.
It's possible that one of these four people
belong to the "Three-People Group".
That means, someone here has read my Dad's novel.
This is the room plan for everyone.
If there's a way to not be discovered when
moving into another bedroom, then...
Hang on, how about using some type of equipment?
Azusa-san has a practice gun.
Kaetsu-san brought some fishing equipment.
Aoba-san brought a bamboo sword and equipment for kendo.
Ishizuchi-san has some golf clubs.
Right, if the body of Asama-san was
thrown away from the window,
Before Izumo-san was killed... Then...
If that thing was used, then he would be able to fool us easily...
Inspector Nishimura.
We just received a phone call from the site,
The time which Asama fell from the train has been determined.
From the speed of the train and the position
of the body, it occurred at about 4:10 AM.
It matches with the time when the criminal
entered the room, as witnesses say.
How can it be!
Then the criminal threw away the body in a relatively short time,
And vanished from the room?!
That's impossible.
It can't be done by a human being.
Then, how did he do it?
Dad.
Right, the broken pieces from the window are still missing.
Tell them to search for it carefully.
Also, the belt on the dead body has some strange stuff stuck on it.
Some strange stuff?
Yes, something like plastic tape.
Wait. If that is...
Over there...
If it's really there...
Found it. I found it.
The criminal used this.
The criminal should be that person.
That person murdered Izumo-san and diverted
our attention onto Asama-san.
By using the construction of the Northern Star and Seikan tunnels.
Shin-chan, what is it?
I figured everything out now.
What?
It's really a crappy method that Dad used in the novel.
A kid wearing black-frame glasses smiled arrogantly
because he was confident of his win...
Eh!
It's incredible.
Then we can make fun of him for being the loser this time.
Yeah...
Mom, in that novel,
Was there anything about a young guy with black-frame glasses?
Yes, a boy who loves deductions.
I remember, he's too confident of himself,
On top of his amazing deduction,
He didn't realize his life will pay for the truth he discovered...
... That doesn't sound good...
Idiot, don't think too much, Shin-chan.
Although the incident is identical to Yusaku's novel,
Shin-chan won't be killed.
The boy in the novel doesn't have any evidence,
So he sets a trap and ends up falling into his own trap.
That's way different from Shin-chan.
I don't think will be murdered, but the situation is almost the same.
I have no evidence so far.
I know the trick used, and the person who did it,
But I don't have any evidence to prove that he's the one.
Then we can't catch him.
I guess the evidence is still inside his luggage.
But with this situation with everyone
thinking Asama Yasuji is the one,
It is impossible to ask him to show his luggage.
I have a good idea.
What?
Let's follow the storyline of the novel.
While you were in the front of Asama's
room, you saw something weird.
Really?
Yeah, it happened just before the crime.
Yeah, right before we entered the Seikan tunnel.
In front of Asama's room, there was a very strange, very long...
"Long,"... What was it?
I forgot.
You...
But don't worry, I will remember it very soon.
Right? That someone.
Satsu Horo Station
Sapporo, Sapporo.
Listen, Shin-chan.
I will take a walk within a short distance.
You have to follow me closely.
Yeah, if he gets close to you, I will shoot
him with the anesthetic needle.
It's so exciting.
Mom?
Conan-kun.
See you. I'm counting on you.
What are you doing here, Conan?
Hey, let's go. Natsue-san and others should be waiting for us.
Ahh, I think I forgot something on the train.
I'll ask to see if I can go and have a look,
You can go back first.
Hey...
Mom, where is Mom?
Found her.
Hey, why did you run to another platform?
This is too dangerous.
Damn Mom! Behind you!
Dang it!
What is this? Why is Shin-chan over there?
Didn't he say that he would protect me?
The train will be coming to Platform 7 shortly.
The criminal walked towards the young detective's back slowly,
With his hands covered in blood...
He pushed the innocent one down,
And the platform was full of blood.
Maybe it's hasn't ended yet, but let's leave it at that.
It's meaningless to continue now.
Dear... Why?
heard it from Inspector Nishimura,
I confirmed everything, and rushed over here immediately.
The criminal who killed the owner of the jewelry store...
Then diverted our attention onto the robber Asama...
That criminal is...
Kaetsu-san.
You're the only one who can do this.
What are you saying?
The criminal is the man called Asama.
He was seen killing the jewelry store
owner and jumping out the window.
The Asama seen by the witnesses was you in disguise.
After all, he's a fleeing criminal.
It's easy to pretend to be someone whose face is covered.
That, the incident of fleeing out of the train...
How can you explain that?
I was inside the train the entire time.
That's just a part of your trick.
You used the fishing equipment over there.
You killed Asama in his room.
At the back of his trousers, you hooked a fishing line.
Then left it outside of the broken window.
You brought the ends into your room...
Tied one side to something outside...
And the other end at the door knob.
Then everything is all set.
Then you went to the lobby car and shot the owner.
Ran to Asama's room and shot at the window.
And then shot at Detective Mouri and the others.
While they weren't paying much attention, you ran up the stairs,
And cut off one end of the fishing line.
Then Asama's body would fall out of the train.
Then, the time when the criminal ran away,
And the time Asama fell out of the train would be the same.
This way, it created an illusion that the criminal is Asama.
But when Detective Mouri rushed to
the room, he saw the door close.
Ah, sorry. I forgot to say this.
Isn't there a hook on the door?
You stuck another fishing line with plastic
tape at the back of the door,
And taped it at the hook.
You tied it up with the fishing line on the body.
When the line was cut off, this line would
be pulled off at the same time,
Due to the weight of the body, the tape will release.
The door would be closed automatically.
The evidence is shown on the body's trousers
on which there is a piece of tape.
But... this thing could have been done by someone else too.
Hey, your luggage seems to have
the clothes of the original suspect.
Ahh, also the sunglasses and the hat.
Why is that?
Boy...!
Sorry, Kaetsu-san.
The weak point of this method is the impossibility
to throw away the clothing.
If your luggage is checked,
There is no way for you to walk away from the crime.
To follow the storyline of the novel...
It was just too outrageous.
This is the unpublished work by my favorite author,
So, I believed it would work out perfectly.
This is just what I think, but...
Your intention was revenge for the dead
woman from the group of robbers.
Is it right?
The target is Izumo Owner who is the drug dealer,
And also the person who allowed her to get addicted to drugs,
The robbers' head, Asama Yasuji.
As the novel you took, it unintentionally
was so similar to your own story.
So you decided to follow the novel and start the plan.
Who are you?
I forgot to introduce myself.
I am Kudo Yusaku, the author of the unpublished novel.
That's...
If...
If you understand my novel, I hope you
will give yourself up to the police.
Because the ending of the novel is about the criminal
who regretted what he did at the end,
And gave himself up to the police.
Yes.
New Millennium Airport
Hey, Shin-chan.
Did you come to send us off?
No, have something to tell Dad.
I solved all of Dad's tricks.
Right, it was solved by my own son.
That sign of "the world's number one
mystery novelist" was taken down.
Sorry. It was fake.
It's a trap for the buyers.
Because only the first half of the draft was finished, but I
think the criminal thought it was complete and used it.
I recall there was a trick to get rid of the criminal's disguise as well.
He better not be just making this up.
It's a true destiny that at my most critical
moment, you suddenly appeared.
Suddenly?
I remember was beside you at least for two minutes.
Oh, what's that?
Until the moment before I was pushed down,
You were just standing right there, watching me?
Yes I wanted to know whether or not he was the culprit.
And after all, the trick happened in Seikan tunnel.
So I remained silent to view it.
Very cold.
Yes, because this is Hokkaido.
Next Conan:
The Metropolitan Police Officer Love Story: Part One!
Next Conan's Hint:
Exercise bike
And next:
Someone we know will appear as a policeman!
Who?
Surprise!