Perceiving in a flash,
Once it starts, it won't stop!
Today's stage is the police headquarters.
Police officers are people, too.
They're always busy with cases!
Seeing the one and only truth,
A child with an adult's intelligence...
His name: Detective Conan!
The Metropolitan Police Officer Love Story: Part One!
This is the police headquarters? It's big.
They must deal with a lot of cases here.
Well, this place is the parent to all of Japan's police.
It's so exciting!
Now now, we're only here as witnesses to the blue castle case.
We're not here to have a picnic.
What do you mean?
Even you were excited, saying you wanted
to hear about some unsolved cases.
Right! The one anticipating this the most was Conan-kun!
Oh, is that right?
I'm going home.
Relay your statements in my absence.
Hey, Ai-kun.
You're Agasa-san, right?
Takagi Wataru
Investigation Division Police Officer - 1st Division
It's nice to meet you, I'm Takagi from the first division.
Just follow me, everyone this way.
Alright.
I apologize for your trip here.
It's nothing.
This place is pretty clean.
This place is weird.
I thought it would be disorganized and filled with cigarette smoke.
They only made it look nice out here, I bet.
Right right, I bet the officers' quarters must be...
This place seems empty...
You all seem surprised, is it really that surprising?
Well, thought the officers' quarters would
be filled with cigarette smoke.
I expected scary middle aged men to glare at us as we entered.
You all have been watching too many police dramas.
Look, I'm an officer.
He doesn't look very strong.
He doesn't look like he could apprehend a criminal.
He's definitely not popular with the women.
By the way, where's Inspector Megure?
We came at his request...
The Inspector is working on the bank robbery case.
Would you mean the 200 million yen stolen at the
bank around the Haido area three days ago?
Right.
At that time, the Inspector's wife, Midori-san, was inside the bank.
She was wounded by the criminals who pushed her around.
So the Inspector is taking it very seriously.
That's why you have to replace him to take our testimony?
Right, that's how it is.
Well, let's head to the other room to start.
There's another appointment at 5:00.
Oh, the button on your cuff is falling off.
Oh, it really is.
Your collar isn't well cleaned.
Your shirt is also wrinkled.
Could it be, Officer...
You have no girlfriend?
If that's the case, allow me to introduce
you to my sister's granddaughter.
There's no need.
I actually like someone already.
Hey, Takagi-kun.
Oh!
What's with these children?
For lost kids, it's the lost children department.
No, that's not, these kids are...
Who is this lady?
She is...
Why are you blushing?
I understand it now!
It's Officer Takagi's lover!
Hey, hey, hey!
Is it right to bring your lover to your work?
It's not like that.
My name is Sato Miwako.
Sato Miwako
Violent Crimes Unit Police Officer
Even though I'm a female, I'm also from the
1st Division, in the Violent Crimes Unit.
A female officer...
That's impressive.
Now, who are these kids?
They are witnesses for that blue castle case.
Huh? So these are those brave kids?
Right.
The suspect confessed everything, so we asked
them to confirm the background of the story.
Ah! I remember now!
Onee-san, you're that officer from the stadium case!
You were awesome back then, Onee-san!
I see. You were the children running around then.
We weren't just running around.
We were assisting the investigation.
We didn't interfere with you guys.
Right, right Our detective group is for justice.
Is that wrong?
H-Hey!
That's right.
The stadium case, and the blue castle case,
Might have been solved thanks to you all.
But, boy. Remember this:
Justice isn't something you can just proclaim.
It's a feeling you should keep near your heart.
Do you understand, little detectives?
Yes...
Was that too harsh?
No, but wait, Sato-san.
Weren't you supposed to be investigating the 200
million yen robbery case with Inspector Megure?
That case brought me back.
I received a call from the bank's manager last night.
He said he had something he wanted to discuss with me.
So we decided to meet here.
Both of them at 2:00.
Why both of them?
When the incident happened, the wife was also present.
She had a gun held to her by the criminal.
Maybe she remembered something about the case.
But, that's odd...
Last night I received a similar call from the bank manager's wife.
She wanted to tell me something she
remembered about the criminal.
So she would come alone at 5:00.
Oh, the bank manager also mentioned that.
He's afraid the criminal may attack his wife.
That's why he wants to come during the day with her.
So that's how it is...
By the way, has Yumi from the traffic department told you anything?
I remember drinking with her last night and telling her something...
But I can't recall what it was.
N-No, she hasn't said anything.
Listen, listen Takagi-kun.
Last night, let her drink, and she told me she has one.
She told me she really likes someone in the 1st Division.
You may be the one, may be! You're blushing, how cute!
Officer Sato, I've brought the manager of the bank as requested.
Thanks for your trouble. Please join us.
Masuo Keizou (53)
Tokyo Bank Branch Manager
It seems I made it.
Oh, your wife isn't with you?
I had something to do at the bank,
So I arranged to meet my wife here.
She hasn't made it yet?
Right.
That's strange. Is she still asleep?
Officer-san, may I use the phone?
Go ahead.
It's the third time.
Oh? What is?
The amount of times he looked at his watch.
This is Masuo.
Oh, it's you.
Eh, you're at the police station?
I'll put an officer on.
Hello. You're now speaking with me.
Masuo Kayo
Wife of Masuo Keizou
Ah, you're that officer.
Takagi-san, I believe?
Yes.
I assume you're still at home.
Is something wrong?
Hmm, what?
Isn't the appointment at 5:00?
Well, your husband said the appointment was at 2:00.
So we assumed you were coming.
I wasn't told about that.
You didn't know?
Wait, what are you saying?!
Here!
Hello, Miss?
Are you there, Miss?
What's wrong, Miss?
Takagi-kun, prepare the mobile team.
I'll get the car ready.
Alright.
The mobile team?
They're the ones deployed for a field case.
They're called the mobile investigation team.
Right, Conan-kun?
Conan-kun?
Well?
My wife is fine, isn't she?
As of late,
Have you noticed anything suspicious?
Suspicious?
Right, that's right!
She said she saw someone suspicious outside last night.
That must be one of the criminals.
Fearing identification by your wife, they're wanting to silence her.
That can't be!
It may have been a petty thief that caused her to scream.
She was speaking with the police.
Wouldn't she shout "thief" if it were so?
When did you get in here?!
What do we do?
There's no time to take him back.
We have to check on the woman.
Boy, don't bite your tongue.
Hey! Kayo? Kayo?
Officer, please head upstairs!
I'll head to the hall.
Let's go, Takagi-kun!
Yes!
There is glass missing.
Did someone break in?
What's wrong?!
Kayo... Kayo...!
Lady!
I'll call an ambulance.
No, call for the lab team and the coroner.
She's already gone.
How... How is this...?
Give me the time.
14 hours, 46 minutes. Body discovered.
Translator Note: Takagi said the time in Military time as
14 hours, 46 minutes. This translates to 2:46 P.M.
Who could be so evil?
Was it really those criminals, Officer?
That's odd.
When you enter...
The lady's body is in sight.
Though, then...
Before I discovered the damaged glass,
and before telling them to go upstairs...
He didn't say anything of it.
Why is that?
Regardless, is it normal to attack someone using a phone?
Without caution, the attacker's voice may be overheard.
The other person on the phone would
come to the victim's aid immediately.
Then, his peculiar actions and words at the police headquarters...
Is it possible he planned this murder?
Is it possible?
The victim is Masuo Kayo-san, age 42.
The murder weapon is a knife to the back.
There's no indication as to struggle.
That wound must have been fatal.
The estimated time of her death is when she screamed.
Officer Sato, you heard the victim scream?
The husband was at headquarters speaking
with the victim over the phone.
I accidentally switched to the loudspeaker.
At that time...
I heard my wife's cry for help...
Then, during the phone conversation,
someone assaulted her from behind?
I don't believe she was only talking.
She must have been riding this aerobic
bike while being on the phone.
Even so, look here...
There's sweat on her body and shirt.
Since all metabolic processes cease after death,
Even a high temperature wouldn't cause sweat.
The sweat has yet to dry.
That means, before the victim was killed,
She was partaking in a demanding activity.
I searched the shoe cabinet and didn't see any jogging shoes.
And in this room, the only thing capable...
The electric bike near the body.
Hey, children shouldn't be near crime scenes.
That's impressive.
Boy, I still don't know your name.
Edogawa Conan, a detective.
D-Detective?
Um, he's the boy staying with Detective Mouri.
I see.
That's how you know these things.
Well boy, you should become a police officer.
If you make it to our unit, we'll treat you well.
Right, Takagi-kun?
Yes!
Well Officer Sato, we'll speak with the neighbors.
Perhaps there's a witness.
Also, don't forget to investigate this residence.
The motive may be money.
Yes!
No, this doesn't relate to greed.
The criminal's target was the life of this woman.
That's my opinion.
Secondary Inspector Shiratori...
Well, I'm not a secondary inspector any longer.
Shiratori Ninzaburou
Police Inspector - 1st Division
I've been promoted to full inspector.
Thus I will be assuming control of this case.
Not bad. You're adept at fawning.
Always getting promotions...
If you don't mind, please allow me to assist in the investigation.
Yes, that will be fine.
Does that means Sato-san actually likes...
Shiratori-san!?
No way, no way.
How can I get so distracted while being on duty.
Hey, how do you know it isn't a simple theft?
It's because of the scream during the telephone conversation.
Normally, a thief wouldn't attack someone who is on the phone.
If she saw the thief and screamed, he would have fled.
Even so, wasn't the victim supposed to
visit the police headquarters today?
Yeah, she sad it was in regards to the bank robbery.
She was supposed to come with her husband.
But she didn't show up at the appointed time.
The husband was worried, so he called her.
During the phone call, did she happen to
mention she was talking to the police?
She noticed, when I took the phone,
that I was the officer from last night.
Then there's no mistake.
The criminal didn't want the victim to speak
with the police, and thus murdered her.
Wait, that means...
Right, the criminal must be one of the two bank thieves.
During the incident, the victim was held at gunpoint.
That would place her near one of the thieves.
I believe the criminal realized she could identity him.
And murdered her to keep her quiet.
Not to mention, when the victim was taken hostage...
She struggled to get away and grabbed at the intruder's mask.
Yes, and by coincidence Megure's wife became
the second hostage at the bank.
She even volunteered to be a hostage.
Yes! My wife told me about a foreigner!
That's it!
I believe the lady was attempting to refer a clue to us.
Takagi-kun, contact headquarters.
One of the criminals is foreign!
Yes, sir!
But isn't it strange?
Behind the bike, there's only two meters of space.
There's no door beyond it.
Why would the criminal attack from that
direction while she was riding the bike?
It's that kid again.
Do you know him?
Yeah, he's always following Mouri-san.
A little detective, no?
I didn't know you were famous, boy.
What's wrong, Takagi-kun?
It's nothing.
Hey, don't you think it's strange, too?
But boy...
Even if you're stabbed in the back, the attack
doesn't always originate from behind.
It's possible the victim saw the criminal,
And was about to flee when she was stabbed in the back.
If that's true, the body would be further
away from the electronic vehicle, right?
The telephone lies only a few inches away.
If she fell elsewhere, there would be traces of sweat.
Then the criminal would have no reason to move the bike, right?
You do have a point.
Masuo-san, did your wife usually ride the bike during this time?
Yes. Each day at 2:00 she would exercise on that bike.
Excuse my asking, but at what time does she normally wake up?
I'm always required to leave early due to my work.
More recently though, my wife has began drinking
out with some friends and returning late.
I would gauge it around noon.
Then I have the answer.
If my reasoning is correct...
The criminal was hiding...
On the shelf behind the curtains!
What?
Hey hey, this is convenient.
There aren't many books.
It's possible for a person to hide here.
There aren't many other obstructions.
Only this single curtain is, unlike the others, beige in color.
The curtain is meant to modify the color
scheme, and was installed just recently.
We were a so planning to change the other curtains...
But can it really conceal a person?
If you remove two pieces, an adult could easily hide here.
As you see, that is what the criminal did.
The criminal observed the residents' schedules.
And with the master gone,
He snuck in before the lady awoke.
He then concealed himself in the shelf
and awaited his murder victim.
With the victim on the bike, her back was unguarded.
However, his plans were foiled slightly.
For better or worse, the police called.
The anxious criminal quickly committed the crime.
The criminal entered through the window with the missing glass.
That's right. The wife had claimed to witness
someone suspicious in the area.
Then he familiarized himself with her living habits...
That's not surprising.
No. There's a large flaw in that deduction.
That man is the culprit.
From the police headquarters ten kilometers away...
To kill his wife...
There must be a way to do it!
There's only one person...
Who could restore the bookshelf to its original condition.
Impossible! Regardless, you can't just accuse people without proof!
What's wrong, Uncle? What's this wound on your finger from?
Next Conan:
The Metropolitan Police Officer Love Story: Part Two!
Next Conan's Hint:
Bookshelf
Next is the finale!
Sato-san... tell me it isn't true...