Perceiving in a flash,
Once it starts, it won't stop!
Many puzzles remain in this case.
It's the same as the love story.
That's unfortunate for a certain officer!
Seeing the one and only truth,
A child with an adult's intelligence...
His name: Detective Conan!
After the bank manager lost 200 million during a robbery,
He came to the police headquarters to testify.
But then his wife was murdered...
I know the manager is the culprit.
Though I know that...
With him being at the police headquarters
at that time, he has a perfect alibi.
The Metropolitan Police Officer Love Story, Part Two!
Secondary Inspector Shiratori.
I've searched the victim's bedroom.
The jewelry and valuables seem undisturbed.
It seems the possibility of thievery has declined.
So that's how it is.
Alright. You two visit the neighbors and ask of
anything suspicious from the last few days.
Ask about any strangers and their activities.
Yes, sir!
Oh, and...
I have recently been promoted from
Secondary Inspector to Inspector.
Is that understood?
Yes, I understand.
Inspector Shiratori's reasoning contains one major flaw.
If he doesn't discover it soon...
Hey there, Inspector Shiratori-san.
Boy, you should go home.
I'll arrange a ride for you.
D-Don't you think it's strange?
The culprit murdered the victim as the
she spoke with the police, right?
Why would he restore the book shelf to its original condition?
The culprit should have known the police
would respond immediately.
As for that...
It's a peculiar point.
One shelf is filled with books, so no one could hide there.
Inspector Shiratori!
W-What is it?
I found a strange photo album in the victim's room.
Take a look.
There are circles on some photographs.
A-Ah, those are...
Those are little marks by my wife.
I told her those little marks would hinder the photos.
I see.
That's why your wife...
I'm sure. He's our criminal.
But he has an alibi.
He was at the police headquarters.
But even I can confirm his alibi with my own eyes...
How did he do it?
Being at the police headquarters...
But still being capable of killing the victim.
But how?
Shiratori-kun.
We should call in the crime scene team.
There are still some uncertain factors in this case.
Then I'll ask you people:
Who's the criminal?
But one fact remains:
The criminal invaded this house.
That's the starting point for our reasoning.
Just look around you.
There's no other place to hide and commit
the murder in this room, right?
Don't tell me the knife flew on its own.
A flying knife?!
Hold on, could it have been...
I found it, this is it!
Then that means, there must be...
It must be over there.
H-Hey!
Get down, boy.
Huh, it's missing?
That's odd.
The shelf and curtain each have strange bloodstains.
Why isn't it here?
Something's smeared the blood.
I see now, that's how it was done.
I now understand everything.
How you utilized such distance...
To kill your wife.
In closing:
Judging from this very scene,
The culprit entered from outside...
And then stabbed the victim in the back with a knife.
That is a mere fact.
And the culprit may well be one of the bank thieves.
As for the motive, the victim was held hostage then...
And may have been able to identify the thief.
This murder was to protect the identity of the thief.
Well, even though some minor issues remain,
We should hurry, as it's probably best
we contact the Theft and Larceny Unit.
Wouldn't you agree?
I understand, I'll make the call.
Oh, and Takagi-kun...
I would like you to take this boy to Mouri-san's.
What are you doing?
It's origami.
Origami?
Boy, you can't play here.
You can do this at home.
I have something to ask you police officers.
So I borrowed some paper from that officer to make a knife.
What is it you want to ask, boy?
When you stab someone with a knife, is it held this way...
Or is it like this?
That's right.
This lady was riding an aerobic bike while talking on
the phone, and was attacked from behind, right?
Right. There is sweat on the victim's body...
Where she and the phone landed are near the aerobic bike.
The victim was without footwear.
Though there's no trace of the victim's sweat,
it seems she was stabbed that way.
Then she was stabbed and fell onto the ground, you see?
Then isn't weird?
What do you mean, it's weird?
It's the knife's position.
Look the knife is in sideways.
It really is!
If the attack was from behind, the knife would be inserted vertically.
That's true, because the victim couldn't
be attacked from the other side.
If the criminal came from the other side,
The victim would see him.
If that happened, it's odd that she wasn't able to avoid it.
The answer is quite simple.
The culprit attacked the victim from behind
and knocked her to the floor.
And by using his knees to hold her down,
He was able to kill her that way.
As I expected, Inspector! You're so smart!
Oh, it's nothing.
But, it didn't happen that way.
Because if she were on the floor,
Wouldn't she try to escape?
Officer Sato said it earlier.
There's no trace of nearby sweat.
And, the phone that fell to the floor looks odd.
That's right. After the scream...
Takagi-kun tried to call the victim.
The culprit should have heard it.
If he knew the caller was with the police,
Why didn't he cut the phone's power?
If he didn't disconnect the line,
He may have left a clue to his voice behind.
And if the police had heard his voice...
That's true, the criminal would usually attempt to leave quickly.
If that's true, then the criminal may have
identified himself by leaving his knife.
He shouldn't have left this at the crime scene, right?
But, when we came in...
The living room door was locked.
If the criminal was leaving quickly...
Why would he bother to lock the door?
Moreover, how did the criminal enter?
The glass windows are all still locked and attached.
Inspector, this case is getting more and more peculiar, isn't it?
After seeing the evidence, I believe the victim was alone here.
It's definitely peculiar.
The boy is right.
We're going to have to investigate this room more thoroughly.
Then, you actually believe the victim died from...
A knife flying on its own, and inflicting a critical wound?
Then that means you would have seen
that when you found the victim.
What is this string for?
String?
What's wrong with it?
Look here.
There's a wound string inside.
Right?
Well, there is a wound string inside.
Do you know what this string is for?
N-No...
What? It's only some string that got caught inside.
But, look at the end of the string.
There's a loop on the end.
Here.
It's true, that is a little strange.
Right, now remember!
About half a year ago, my friend's child was in here.
He was playing near the aerobic bike I believe.
It must have been something he did back then.
But even so...
No reason to think about that.
What relevance does this string have?
Please wait a second!
What if...
What if, from the top of the bookshelf...
The knife was held by tape.
And with the curtain concealing the string...
The winding of the string would begin as
soon as someone uses the aerobic bike.
After enough use, the bookshelf would
fa l and the knife would hit the victim!
That is an interesting point.
But doesn't that rely on coincidence?
The pan could easily go awry.
No, it would most likely go as planned.
Just beside that shelf...
There is another shelf of books, so it couldn't fall any other way.
If the target was to ride the bike at that time...
The shelf would eventually fall on the victim.
But no matter which method, the bike would
have reacted to the increasing weight.
Don't you know?
Aerobic bikes have a strong resistance.
If the victim had maintained that speed,
There wouldn't be a problem.
But wait...
When you found the body, the bookshelf wasn't on the body, right?
If the culprit snuck in to use this method,
Then wouldn't he stay to assure the plan actually worked?
There's only one person...
Who could restore the book shelf to its original condition.
There's only one person who could have performed this trick.
That person knew the layout of this
house and schedule of the victim...
The one who arrived in this room before everyone else...
Masuo Keizou-san...
It can only be you!
What do you mean?
I see.
That's why you called from the police station.
As long as you knew your wife rode
her aerobic bike at 2:00 every day,
You could be assured the knife would kill her after a while.
If you were with us, when your wife was killed...
You would acquire a perfect alibi.
By giving the phone to Takagi-kun, you ensured that
one of us was talking to her during that time.
That's why when we arrived, you ordered us upstairs.
I see now. You took advantage of our absence...
And restored the bookshelf to its original state.
Please don't say silly things like that.
See if any police officers had come here before me...
They would have seen the knife and bookshelf together.
I guess it was like this, Uncle?
See, the upper level of the shelf is tightly packed with books.
If a knife was inserted in this slot, there would be no need for tape.
The more top-heavy, the easier it would fall.
I see!
That means, after the knife struck the victim,
the books on the shelf fell around the body.
And then the bookshelf was restored,
effectively concealing the trick.
But wait, boy...
If the knife had been up there, my wife would have seen it.
Then you mean...
Even like this?
That's it!
This way, the knife wouldn't be discovered and it
explains why the victim was stabbed sideways.
Not bad, boy.
Even with the bookshelf and books everywhere,
the police would easily claim...
It was during the struggle between the victim and the killer.
And then no one would know about the trick!
Is this correct, Masuo-san?
The string... What about the string?
If the string was connected to the curtain, the
police would discover the trick in a moment.
Regardless, you have no evidence that I'm the culprit.
What's wrong, Uncle?
Whats it that injured your finger?
Ah, I see!
When you put your handkerchief in your pocket, you looked hurt.
You have something in your pocket, then?
Would you mind showing us?
Inside of his pocket...
There should be nails and tape.
Each probably stained with the victim's blood.
How do you know that?
There is smeared blood on the bookshelf.
It told me something must have been taped there.
After he fastened a nail to the shelf,
He attached the string's loop.
By doing this, it would detach as the shelf fell.
And then, the string would retract into the aerobic bike.
But, if the police found the blood and nail...
How would you explain it?
It seems...
The nail connected to the aerobic bike...
Was actually placed there by the wife.
Her blood being there is a mere coincidence.
So, that's his explanation.
Since evidence is more worthy than theories, let's experiment.
I believe the item in your pocket will work well with that shelf.
It's useless without practice.
Many nights...
I practiced this trick many times to perfect the angle.
It's odd, I only removed it as a precaution after restoring the shelf.
But instead it became a clue.
Why did you kill your wife?!
For the insurance payout.
I insured my wife's life with a beneficial sum.
After the bank robbery, I needed the money from my wife...
Even doing it with assistance,
You would have been discovered.
The assistance you received...
To steal from your own bank!
Is that true?
Yes, he's the one who planned it.
With the bank manager planning it, the
robbery wouldn't face many troubles.
The unfortunate issue is how your wife incidentally
came by the bank at that me.
It seems they accidentally took her hostage.
It wasn't until after that you realized your
wife could identify your associate.
You didn't want the police to discover this, so you silenced her.
Then, during the robbery, the idea to interchange hostages...
Was because she was the culprit's wife...
But, how did you know about it?
Hey, isn't there a picture album with certain pictures encircled?
Your wife was going to bring the pictures to the police station,
And then confirm they were the robbers.
The boy has been holding the album for a while, right?
Two hours later...
The two robbers were arrested at home,
while counting the stolen notes.
Thus assisting in solving both cases at once.
In Masuo-san's confession,
He claimed it was his wife's expensive tastes...
That caused him to engineer the robbery.
For money to also be the reason for killing his wife...
It's an unfortunate case.
Hey, I've heard about it, Shiratori!
How you solved a case just after being promoted to Inspector!
That's impressive!
Don't praise me that way, Chief Matsumoto.
Such simple matters hardly require my attention.
That's right, because those matters...
Were solved by this boy.
Aren't you the one always with Mouri?
He's very good.
He knew a lot.
It's nothing major.
That's true.
Children see things differently, that is
how they notice things we do not.
Oh no, it's already late.
It's no wonder I'm hungry.
Um, Sato-san...
If possible, would you join me...
Would you like to join me for dinner?
Holding a glass of wine over the brilliant night sky.
Right, I have a classy French restaurant in mind.
That's not bad.
It's true... It's really that way.
The restaurant's chef is rated three-star.
Really? That's great.
But I'll pass.
I don't like French food actually.
That's unfortunate...
Good-bye.
Sato-san, you don't like French food?
I like most foods, actually.
I just don't like expensive restaurants like that.
How about it? I know a nice Ramen shop nearby.
Want to come with me?
Yes! It's my pleasure!
Sato-kun! Takagi-kun!
How about it? A drink for the closed case?
The others have already gone out to the bar.
Yes. Sato Miwako: Willing to join.
Could it be... Sato-san actually likes...?
Hey, come with us, Takagi-kun.
No, I have some things to do.
Hey, when are you actually going to take our testimony?
It's already 8:00!
We've been waiting so long, I'm going to forget.
He's hopeless.
Awesome!
I know, it really is different from the games.
Huh? What's wrong?
This person...
Has ceased breathing.
Next Conan:
The Streetcar's Sudden Stopping Case!
Next Conan's Hint:
Camera case
The next case is the "ching ching" train!
Ching ching...
That's wrong...
Zoo zoo!
That's wrong.
Ching ching!
Oohh...