Perceiving in a flash,
Once it starts, it won't stop!
The streetcar has stopped!
Is this an accident or a case at this strange place?
Seeing the one and only truth,
A child with an adult's intelligence...
His name: Detective Conan!
The Streetcar's Sudden Stopping Case!
What's taking Conan-kun so long?
It's already 5:40.
Oh, there he is.
Conan-kun, over here!
You're late, Conan.
Sorry, sorry.
What were you doing?
You're ten minutes late!
Well, I overslept.
And you talk about it so lightly.
The new rollercoaster at Beika Land is supposed to have long lines.
But, if we go now, we'll be the first ones in line.
Of course. It's not even 6:00 in the morning yet.
Passengers: The Beika Land tram is arriving.
For your safety, please stay behind the line.
Oh, it's here!
Alright, let's go!
Awesome! It's like we rented the entire carriage!
Who else is going to ride the tram so early on a Sunday?
What? They aren't here yet?
What are those two doing?
Kawasaki Tetsuya (22)
Hanayama University - 4th Year
Horii is usualy late...
But for Shimizu to be late, it's strange.
Excuse me, sir. Are you alone today?
No, there should be two others.
Is something wrong?
It's alright to take photos inside the carriage,
But please don't disturb the other passengers.
Ah, yes...
I finally made it.
You're late, Shimizu!
I'm sorry, Kawasaki-senpai.
I overslept a little.
Huh? Where's Horii-senpai?
He isn't here yet.
He always arrives at the very last moment.
Shimizu Rumi (20)
Hanayama University - 2nd Year
Then he'll be here soon.
The tram is about to depart.
I guess you're right.
Good morning.
Horii Masao (22)
Hanayama University - 4th Year
Sorry, sorry.
It seems I'm a little late.
Why apologize? You're late every time.
Awesome!
It really is different from the driving games, isn't it?
That's right, the real thing is much different.
Onee-san, are you going to Beika Land?
We're from the Hanayama Unversity Railroad Society.
We've come to take pictures of the electric tram in action.
There have been less and less trams on the tracks lately.
I'll be going to Germany to study abroad,
So I thought I should take more photos while I'm still here.
Just leave it to us.
Right, we're counting on you.
Even if he looks like that, Kawasaki-senpai is
only a professional in terms of photography.
Hey, Shimizu...
What do you mean by "only"?
Ah, I'm sorry.
The next stop is Harii Station, Harii Station.
Oh, this is the place.
Huh? You want to get off?
Yeah. Not far from there is the best point for taking photos.
The best point?
Two knots should do it, I guess.
Hey, Horii, Shimizu.
This camera case is brand new.
There's also a new camera inside.
Don't let anyone touch it.
OK. Do your best, Kawasaki.
Take some great photos.
Leave it to me.
The tram is about to leave.
Take off!
I'm just in time.
Hello?
Kawasaki-senpai?
The tram has just departed.
OK. I'm in position.
Do your best.
Well, Horii-senpai.
Let's go to the back for more photos.
Alright.
Hey, are you alright?
Kawasaki-senpai, are you hurt?
Uh, uh...
I'm fine, just a little startled.
Jeez, that's enough!
You could have died!
I'm sorry.
Onii-san, how did you fall onto the tracks?
I was standing on that ladder to take the photos.
And then it suddenly collapsed.
I remember all four of the ladder's legs were steady before.
What's this mark?
There are marks there, too.
What is that?
It's an S-shaped hook.
And with a piano wire tied to it?
This couldn't have been...
I'm really sorry.
It's fine as long as you're alright.
Alright, everyone back on the tram.
We're leaving.
Conan-kun, what are you doing?
The tram is leaving again.
Yeah, I know.
Is everybody here?
Everyone here is ready.
When Genta-kun gets here, then everyone's here.
Right, right... What does that mean?
Huh?
Horii-senpai, what is it now?
Hey, Horii, what are you doing?
Don't touch him.
Hey, boy...
Don't touch him? What do you mean?
Operator, please call the police.
Call the police?
C-Could it be...
Yeah.
He's dead.
This is...
A lump on his forehead...
The wound to the back of his head...
A camera case stained by blood...
The blood on the floor...
Is this really...
The deceased is Horii Masao-san, age 22.
There's a lump on his forehead and an open wound opposite it.
Wakai Kenji (28)
Hariisho Police - Investigator
The cause of death is likely the open wound to the rear of the head.
Alright everyone. I'm Wakai from the Hariisho police.
Can you describe the situation before Horii-san's death?
I was at the front of the tram looking at
Kawasaki-san as he fell on the tracks.
Since the tram suddenly stopped, I was trying to keep my balance.
I saw nothing.
I was frightened, so closed my eyes...
I was watching from the front, so I didn't see anything.
I was taking photos with Horii-senpai in the back.
And then, due to the sudden stopping of the tram,
I was thrown to the front.
What happened to Horii-san after that, I just don't know...
I see. How about you?
I applied the emergency brakes to stop the tram,
And immediately ran outside to check on this young man.
But about the deceased...
I see, I see.
Everyone ran outside to the front of the tram.
Did anyone sneak back onto the tram during that time?
We were only outside for a few minutes.
I don't recall anyone coming back inside early.
I see.
From the open wound to the rear of his head,
and the blood on the camera case...
I believe Horii-san lost his balance due to the emergency braking...
And died from the injury he received
after falling on the camera case.
This is an accident.
It's a very simple accident.
Huh? But isn't that strange?
What is so strange about it?!
As the future head of the Crime Investigation Unit,
I never assess a problem incorrectly.
What does a boy like you know?
Aiming is up to you...
But we're the Detective Boys.
Right, we're pupils of Meitantei Mouri Kogoro-san.
Jeez...
What? The renowned "Sleeping Kogoro"?
Then where's the problem, boy?
Look at this camera case.
There's a lot of blood at the bottom.
If he fell and hit it above,
Wouldn't there be more blood up here?
I see, that's what you meant.
I believe the braking caused the camera case to turn over.
But I recall the victim tying the camera case to the handrail.
It shouldn't have moved, right?
This knot...
I remember that time...
Two knots should do it, I guess.
Hey, Horii, Shimizu.
This camera case is brand new.
Huh? That's strange.
Before I left the tram, that shoulder belt was tied in two knots.
Since it was new,
I didn't want anyone to touch it.
Now even the other side is scratched.
In that case...
It means someone untied the case from the handrail.
Hey, Officer...
Isn't it strange that the lump is on his forehead
but he hit his head on the other side?
I see.
And look over there.
There's a large amount of blood.
Maybe he was hit by... No, it's impossible.
There's no time to attack him during the sudden braking.
It can only be an accident then.
It must be an accident!
This is bad.
That is...
Wait a second!
The S-shaped hook by the post...
And the scratch on that side of the camera case...
That's it, I have it.
An impossible act during an unexpected braking...
This was no accident...
Horii-san was murdered!
And...
The criminal is among us.
Operator, the tram can't stay here all day.
I need to take their testimonies. Can we go to the next station?
Yes.
Hey, after we arrive at the station,
Call the related personnel to investigate this immediately.
Yes.
This is bad, I need to deal with Officer Wakai.
But I can't use the Stun-gun with everyone around...
Not to mention there's nowhere in the carriage to hide.
Therefore, Kawasaki-san, Shimizu-san...
We'll need to take your statements regarding
Horii-san's accidental death.
Please accompany us to the police station.
Yes.
I understand.
Will you kids come as well?
Yes.
Hey, wait a second, Officer.
What is it, boy?
We'll ask for your statement, too.
Just relax.
It's not that.
Earlier, when I was outside the tram,
I found this.
I think it somehow relates to the case.
This S-shaped hook and Horii-san's death...
How are they related?
Because if the ladder hadn't fallen,
The tram wouldn't have braked suddenly, right?
And how does that... Oh!
Hey, let me see that hook.
Here, Officer.
Is it possible...
A perfect fit.
As I thought, the mark matches perfectly.
This hook had been attached to the ladder.
And this piano wire...
Officer Wakai, about the piano wire...
Some of it was found entangled in the tram's bumper.
What? Show me!
Here it is.
The width, material, and length are all similar.
Boy, this S-shaped hook...
Where did you find it?
It was attached to the loop of this post.
I see.
The marks on this loop are also new.
Then there should be other marks.
Look, there are marks here, too.
And on the opposite sign post.
As I thought...
I see.
There are remains from the piano wire on this sign as well.
Then that means...
The piano wire and S-shaped hook were attached to the ladder...
And then passed through the nearest post's loop.
Afterwards, it was ran around the outside of the furthest pole.
And finally, it was tied to the sign post.
When the tram passed the point, the piano wire was pulled.
The force moved the ladder, and tossed the occupant off.
Thus, the ladder fell intentionally.
But who did it? It's too much for a prank.
I think the collapsing ladder incident, and Horii-san's death...
Are somehow connected.
I see! That's it.
Allow me, Officer Wakai, to explain how this event happened.
Alright, let's return.
Hey, hey. Is it alright?
So, is everyone ready?
Horii-san didn't die in an accident.
He was murdered!
But you just said it was an accident.
Yes, and I should also mention that
Kawasaki-san's ladder accident...
Was the work of someone.
Then, you're saying someone was trying to kill me?
Right, it's a possibility.
What are you saying?
You're not just saying that Horii-san's death wasn't an accident,
But you're saying Kawasaki-senpai's fall wasn't either?
I will now begin to explain...
The method that was used to murder Horii-san.
It requires that the criminal knows how to
cause an emergency braking of the tram.
Right, if Kawasaki-san's ladder could be
pulled down at a specific moment...
It would provide the opportunity to murder Horii-san.
After Kawasaki-san fell,
Everyone's attention was drawn to the front.
But it was then that the criminal took the camera
case and hit Horii-san in the back of the head.
It was then that Horii-san hit his head on the railing.
Due to the impact, he fell to the floor and left a pool of blood.
Even though the criminal tied the camera case again,
There wasn't enough time, so there was only one knot tied.
And then, there was the emergency braking.
Horii-san slid forward and hit his head on the camera case.
At that time, the person closest to Horii-san...
It was you, Shimizu-san.
Stop joking around.
When the tram began braking suddenly,
I could have fallen and died as well!
Hey, Operator...
Besides this tram, weren't there other trams passing on this line?
Well, there was one passing at 5:40.
Then you're saying the criminal tied the piano wire after 5:40?
That means the culprit knew Kawasaki-san
would be taking photos there.
Yesterday, Horii, Shimizu and decided to take photos here.
As for the ladder, it was before we
came to the station this morning.
But, by 5:54, I was already at Harii Station.
From here to Harii Station, it's about four kilometers, right?
It's a ten minute trip on a bicycle.
And when the tram left Harii Station,
Shimizu-san called Kawasaki-san.
You were making sure that Kawasaki-san
was atop the ladder in time.
Could it be, you really...
I didn't touch your camera case and I didn't kill Horii-senpai.
Anyway, where's your proof?
Proof? Well...
You suspect people even without proof.
Shimizu-san...
The wounds to your palm and watch, how did they happen?
What do these wounds have to do with this?
And what about that? The blood on the camera case...
Isn't that the same blood from your hand?
It was when you hit Horii-san with the camera
case that you received these injuries, right?
That's wrong!
Even after the lab testing,
Will you still deny it?
According to the test, the blood on that corner of the camera case...
Has been confirmed not to be Horii-san's.
Also, we found fingerprints not belonging
to neither Horii-san or Kawasaki-san.
Is that right, Shimizu-san?
Shimizu, why did you do that to Horii?
I...
Was on good terms with Horii-san.
We were discussing our wedding...
But, because he was going to study in Germany...
I said wanted to go with him.
I'm sorry, but you can't come with me.
My father has arranged a marriage for me over there,
So I have to get married there.
It was unforgivable...
I couldn't forgive him.
That Horii-san...
I just couldn't forgive him...
Detective Boys' members, you have done well!
I'll give you my autograph as a souvenir.
The Detective Boys' members have helped in this tram case,
And even solved a murder case.
"Sincerely yours, Wakai Kenji."
Hey, hey...
Well, Detective Boys' members, I'll see you again!
Be careful not to fall in terms of promotion...
This water...
Comes from over there...
Next Conan:
The Bungee Jumping Case!
Next Conan's Hint:
Kamen Yaiba Show
The next case involves an amusement park!
Officer Takagi's biggest calamity.
Is that so?