Perceiving in a flash,
Once it starts, it won't stop!
Today's event is bungee jumping.
Using the courage to jump, let's solve the case!
Seeing the one and only truth,
A child with an adult's intelligence...
His name: Detective Conan!
The Bungee Jumping Case!
What is this place?
Didn't you say you wanted to come to "Land"?
I did...
This is the "Land", Nichiuri Land.
Jeez, when people say "Land", they usually mean...
This one.
Tropical Land!
Exactly how did it turn into Nichiuri Land?
There's no difference between them.
There are plenty of things here.
They're not the same...
Be quiet, you!
There aren't even shows here.
Isn't that a show over there?
Yaiba!
Yaiba...
Flight!
The attractions aren't the same here.
Does that really matter?
Well, you two go on. I'll be right back.
Huh?
Why would Oji-San bring a catalog about boat racing?
What? How did that get there?
Dad...
Yaiba Kick!
Damn! I'll remember this, Yaiba!
Yaiba!
This would be exciting if I were ten years younger.
How lousy...
Come with me, Conan-kun.
Where did Oji-san go?
Look, he's up there.
Were you surprised?
It's a bungee jump.
Jeez, that's startling.
That was great!
Conan-kun, look over there!
Just... Just remember...
The deal we made...
What?
I was joking.
I said if Dad bungee jumped, he could watch the boat races.
This is really scary...
But I have to...
Excuse me, sir, but please hurry.
There are other people waiting.
That's dangerous!
Are you alright? Maybe you shouldn't go right now.
I can't do that...
I have a reason to jump.
Oji-san is afraid of heights, isn't he?
Is that so?
You... What are you doing?!
You have a reason, right?
Here.
Please hurry and jump.
Be quiet, I'll jump when I want to.
Kamen Yaiba ran from me because he's scared!
Now this world belongs to me, Black Planet Man!
That's it. You need to move.
I'm not sure why, but at least I'm saved.
Hey, have a great jump.
No matter how much you want, Yaiba won't come.
That guy left to save himself.
That's impossible!
Yaiba will... He will come to save me!
Save me, Yaiba!
Yaiba!
Be quiet!
Even if you cheer, Yaiba won't show!
Yaiba: Appearing!
What?!
Yaiba?!
Yaiba!
Just like normal.
When the doll on the rollercoaster disappears,
it's time for your appearance.
Sorry to have kept you waiting, Black Planet Man!
You can't have your way!
This show is quite elaborate.
Yeah.
Ah, I'm sorry.
Stay calm, Princess.
I'll save you!
Here we go, Yaiba.
Was that a part of the show?
No, I don't think so.
If he fell into the water, the spectators wouldn't be able to see him.
Hey, Hosono!
Are you alright, Hosono?!
Damn! Call the rescue team!
Hosono fell into the water!
What? Fell?
He's been missing for twenty minutes.
That...
The bungee cable is burnt?
Then that means... This isn't an accident?
At that time...
Could it be...
Um, excuse me...
Hey, we found him!
So unfortunate...
Oji-San, you should call Inspector Megure.
This could be...
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
Look at that.
That rubber ring shows traces of having been burnt.
If it was broken normally, it wouldn't be black.
I see.
It didn't break naturally.
It looks like a murder case, Inspector.
Is that really for you to decide?
I guess not.
Takagi-kun, gather the witnesses.
Yes.
The body was recovered around here.
This water...
Comes from over here...
I remember that boy...
He looked bored during the Yaiba show.
Could he have...
Hey, you!
How was it, Oji-san?
I just looked and you were right, boy.
One piece is wet.
I knew it.
But why did you ask?
Aright, let's go, Tomohiro-kun.
Hey, where are you going?
We have to catch this bad guy...
In place of Kamen Yaiba.
The victim is Hosono Yuuta, age 28.
He was a member of the H.O. Company.
While performing in the Kamen Yaiba show as Yaiba,
His bungee cord broke and he fell to his death.
It was you who attached the cord to his feet, right?
Yes, I always do it.
At that time, was there anything wrong?
If there was, I wouldn't have let him jump.
Well, that's true.
So...
The rest of you are from the same group as Hosono-san?
Yes. My name is Ookubo.
We primarily do these theater acts,
but it doesn't provide a full living.
I see. That's why you host the Yaiba show.
So Ookubo-san plays the bad guy.
You are...
I play the princess, Harukawa Kanako.
I am Ootake Wataru.
The props and effects are my specialty.
Effects?
Special effects.
I operate the explosions on stage.
Yes.
And you?
I schedule the shows here at Nichiuri Land, my name is Fujita.
Huh? What about the Yaiba on the jet coaster?
That was a doll.
We originally wanted to use an actor for the
part, but we didn't have enough people.
Anyway, why did you call us all here?
Wasn't his death an accident?
We're still investigating.
There are some aspects that infer it wasn't an accident.
No.
This is obviously a murder case.
And the criminal is one of you!
One of you hated Hosono-san.
Isn't that right, Ishijima-san?
It's true that Ookubo had problems with
Hosono's managing of the group...
Weren't you the one who tried to borrow money
from Hosono-san and had trouble?
That doesn't really matter.
That's right, Kanako. You were cornered
by Hosono and feared him, right?
I was only feeling a bit troubled.
Ootake, he treated you like a servant. You were upset, weren't you?
It's the same for everyone!
Hosono-kun and didn't have any disagreements.
Then that means...
Besides Fujita-san,
Everyone has a potential motive to murder Hosono-san.
The culprit responsible for killing Kamen
Yaiba's actor, Hosono-san...
It's you!
Don't joke about it! I only operate the bungee
jump, and that makes me the culprit?!
This rubber ring broke due to an explosion,
And the only person in a position to fit the explosives...
Was you.
You'll understand if you watch this.
What?
It's a video recording of Yaiba's jump, filmed
by a spectator onto this video tape.
Really? That may prove to be evidence.
Let's watch it, Mouri-kun.
A-Alright...
I'm sorry.
Ah, stop!
This smoke was generated by explosives.
I believe...
When the rubber was attached to Yaiba's feet...
The explosives were also attached.
Then at the time Yaiba jumped,
With careful timing, the explosives were
detonated exactly at the right time.
Are you ready to confess, Ishijima-san?
How can I confess to something I didn't do?!
Stop denying it!
Wait, look over here.
It's right here.
Doesn't it look like Kamen Yaiba is touching the ring?
It really seems that way.
What do you think, Mouri-kun?
Weren't you behind him?
Now that you mention it...
Kamen Yaiba definitely looked down
and touched the ring at his feet.
And look at this.
Don't you see something strange?
What's strange is you.
Oh, his left hand is open.
His right is clasped shut.
Correct!
Isn't this Yaiba's pose?
No. That's the first time I've seen such a pose.
Maybe the right hand was holding something,
Such as... a bomb detonator.
What do you mean?
Then it was a suicide?
That's right, it was a suicide!
Hosono committed suicide!
Right?
That's a possibility as well.
Ah, if you say so, Inspector...
No. This was a murder.
Then the criminal is Ishijima-san?
It wasn't me!
Before identifying a culprit, let's verify everyone's alibis.
First, Ookubo-san.
I was on stage as Black Planet Man.
I was also on stage, playing the princess.
I was backstage preparing the explosives.
And Ishijima-san was on the bungee jump platform above?
Right.
And Fujita-san?
I was here doing paper work.
Can anyone verify that?
No. I was here alone.
I didn't mention it earlier,
But you had a problem with Hosono as well.
What are you trying to say?!
For using Hosono's story for the performance,
he bribed you with a part of the profit.
But Hosono never paid, did he?
Be quiet!
Stop, let Mouri-kun continue his reasoning.
Just as the video suggests...
Kamen Yaiba may have placed the explosives there himself.
Then it's a suicide!
No. It's still a form of murder...
As long as the one portraying Kamen Yaiba wasn't Hosono-san.
I believe the criminal...
Found Hosono-san while he was alone, and made him faint.
And, while still wearing his Kamen Yaiba suit,
He moved the body to the river.
And drowned him.
It was then that the culprit returned to the dressing room,
Put on the alternate Kamen Yaiba costume,
And entered the act as Kamen Yaiba.
The culprit pretended to check the rubber, but
actually placed explosives there. Then, he...
Jumped!
During the fall, he activated the detonator in his right hand.
The criminal then swam slowly to the power center.
Then he put on his normal clothes and joined the spectators.
But there's at least a 100 meter distance
between power center and platform.
He used a compact regulator.
With this, he could stay underwater for at least ten minutes.
What about that?
Did I miss anything?
Hosono-san's murderer...
Ootake Wataru-san?
I-Impossible!
During the show, I was preparing the explosions!
Did anyone else see Ootake-san during the show?
No, I didn't.
Me neither.
Then who activated the explosions during the show?
The one to solve that puzzle...
Is Kamen Yaiba's biggest fan, a boy...
Takata Tomohiro-kun.
Alright, go ahead, Tomohiro-kun.
Immediately, I noticed this Yaiba wasn't the same Yaiba as before.
Hs movements were bad and the Yaba Kick was poorly done.
And before every explosion, he would do a pose.
Like this, and then this!
Then, that's the pose performed during every show's explosions?
Right. But today, it was different.
How was it today?
The explosion occurred when his hand was on his waist.
Usually, it would happen after the "Yaiba!" call.
Now that you mention it, it was a bit early.
T-Then I just timed it wrong.
Also...
The final pose was different.
Normally, the Yaiba pose...
Involves not closing all of his left hand, but
pointing to the sky with his index finger.
This pose is different from the Yaiba on TV,
But this Yaiba show has a different pose.
When the Yaiba show first started here,
the show was stopped because of rain.
At that time, it's the pose Yaiba uses to inspire us.
That means the explosion during the show...
Was activated by a detonator attached to your body?
What proof do you have?!
The evidence... is on you.
It's on your feet.
There should be a scar.
Because to sever the bungee jump cord...
It took a certain amount of explosives.
Sorry.
Don't touch me!
Wataru-kun...
Tomohiro-kun, let's get some ice cream.
He, Hosono, pointed at me and said
I could never play Kamen Yaiba.
I know I can play Kamen Yaiba better than you, Hosono!
Don't think it only takes looks to play Kamen Yaiba.
To act as a hero, you must be someone
who emanates natural authority.
That guy talked about the 'right to play' the part.
He was always looking down on me.
He was trying to crush me!
I think...
I think the further qualification that Hosono-san mentioned...
Should be will power.
What?
With that degree of jealousy in your heart,
You'll never be able to play the part of the hero.
When Hisono-san pointed his index finger to the sky...
It was to signify the friendship between himself and the children.
I still didn't get to see the results.
Well, I guess I'll have to go to Tropical Land with a boyfriend.
B-B-Boyfriend?!
Is it that detective kid?
No way, it's not Shinichi.
Then who is it?
This is my boyfriend.
Well... Well I guess so...
The car was filled with explosives.
Explosives?
As I thought.
Huh, this guy...
Hey, doesn't this guy look familiar?
Remember, the car that was speeding at Megumi-san's house?
Next Conan:
The Truth of the Exploding Car Case: Part One!
Next Conan's Hint:
Car garage
The next case is a dangerous one!