As bright as a spark,
with a sharp and precise wit.
Once he gets started, you can't stop him!
In today's episode, a car explodes.
The adult world is a bit complicated!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Nishitama City
Thanks for waiting.
What are you looking at so intently?
I was just remembering the past.
The past?
You may not know,
but in the past, in every bank, there was a space open for the general public.
They had a bulletin board with messages like "Looking for nice home for kitten," or such.
I once put up a "please hire tutor" message on the board too.
Oh, were you tutoring, Uncle?
Really? I had no idea!
Well, I didn't have money, but I married your mother while I was still a student,
so I had no choice but to do part-time work to make a living.
Oh.
You and Mom had quite a tough time, I see!
But, the one who really had a tough time must've been the one who was taught by Uncle.
You can say that again.
What're you talking about? I was a pretty good tutor.
As proof of that, the student I taught for 3 years entered the law department of Jonan University!
That's right!
She used to live in Beika Town!
Follow me!
I'll introduce you to Megumi-chan.
Oh, Megumi-chan...
H-Hey, wait, what do you mean?
She's a woman?
Oh, geez...
This takes me back...
I haven't been in this part of Beika Town often, but it hasn't changed much.
Are you sure you haven't seen her in a long time?
Yeah!
Her name is Megumi Tanaka-chan,
and her father is a lawyer.
He used to let me drink beer after lessons.
Oh, that's why he lasted for 3 years...
What's with that car?
Hey! Hey!
Get back, Conan!
Geez. What's with that car anyway, speeding like that on such a narrow road?
Her house is right around that tobacco shop!
Maybe this Megumi-san person got married long ago,
and doesn't live there anymore?
Could be.
But there's also a possibility that she's still single!
Sheesh, Dad!
I hope you're not thinking of anything funny.
Come off it. What can I do with you kids along with me?
Oh, it's her!
Megumi-kun!
Mouri-sensei?!
Hi!
You've really grown to be an adult, haven't you?!
Wait, Sensei!
Good.
Alright, alright...
Hiromi...
Megumi-kun!
My little sister...
Hiromi is inside!
What?! Hiromi-kun is?
There it is!
A fire extinguisher!
Gimme that!
I'll handle this.
H-Hiromi...
Megumi-san!
Beika Central Hospital
I'm sure you're in shock because it is right after the accident,
but may I ask you a few questions?
Yes...
Your name is Megumi Sakihara-san, is that right?
Megumi Sakihara (35)
Yes, that's right...
The person who died in the car that exploded
is your younger sister, Hiromi Tanaka-san, right?
Hiromi Tanaka (32)
Yes, that's right...
An explosive was rigged onto the car.
Explosives?!
Just as I thought...
Yeah.
It seems that the explosive was hooked up under the car along with an ignition device.
It was probably rigged so that when the tires turned, an explosion would occur.
Yes.
I also remember that the car exploded soon after she started to back up.
Sakihara-san, I know how you feel, but let me ask a few more questions.
That house you came out of is your parents' house, isn't it?
Yes...
My parents died in a car accident 6 months ago...
What?!
You mean your father?
Yes, that's right.
My sister's been living there alone ever since...
Was that car your sister's?
No, it was mine.
Yours?
What?!
That's the car that I drove all the way here from my residence in Nishitama today.
My sister's car was at an auto shop for inspection,
so I parked my car in the empty garage.
Since I'm not good at backing up,
my sister was getting the car out for me, so I could head on home.
She offered to back it out for me...
Then you were the one who was actually supposed to be driving that car?!
Y-Yes...
Then the killer mistakenly killed your younger sister?!
I don't know!
I don't know what on earth is going on...
Megumi-san!
Megumi-san.
About what time did you leave your residence in Nishitama?
A little before 2:00 in the afternoon.
Did you notice anything unusual about the car back then?
No...
What time did you arrive at your parents' house?
I think it was around 2:30.
The explosion occurred at 3:00 sharp.
If so, then most likely the explosive was rigged to the car during those 30 minutes.
Do you have any idea as to who it may be?
Do you know if anyone may have a grudge on you?
No... only...
Only?
About a week ago,
I was being watched by a man at a supermarket near my house.
A stranger?
Yes...
I pretended not to notice,
but I felt quite uncomfortable.
Do you remember that man's face?
Yes...
He had a very distinctive face.
We'll get an officer who is good at drawing portraits,
so we'd like your cooperation.
Megumi-kun...
It didn't even occur to me that I'd be meeting you again like this...
I knew that you had become a famous detective, Mouri-sensei.
I brag to my friends that you used to be my tutor.
I see, I see.
I'll be sure to track down the killer who did such a terrible thing to Hiromi-kun.
Please do that, Sensei.
You can count on me.
What a surprise that she used to be a student of yours.
You also knew her younger sister too, didn't you?
Yes...
She was still in middle school back then,
and used to always serve us cake and tea.
Unlike her older sister Megumi-kun, who was quiet and easy-going,
Hiromi-kun used to joke a lot, had many friends,
was outgoing and very cheerful.
They don't seem to have changed much to this day.
After Megumi-san graduated from college, she went to work for a securities company.
She stayed there only for a short while and got married.
She has no children, but seems to be living a peaceful life as a housewife.
Hiromi-san, on the contrary, after graduating from a two-year college,
drifted from job to job,
and even after she turned 30, still seemed to be living a carefree life.
It seems the investigation on Hiromi-san's going to take some time.
Inspector Megure.
The portrait is finished.
Oh, thank you.
Let me see too!
Huh, that guy...
Doesn't he look like that man?
Remember the driver who blitzed past us on our way to Megumi-san's house?
Although he was wearing sunglasses,
his hairstyle and chin look exactly the same!
Come to think of it...
He looks just like that man!
About what time did you see him?
About 10 minutes before we got to Megumi-kun's house...
at the alley about 500 meters before reaching her house.
Which means, he could've been fleeing after setting up the explosive...
Do you remember the model and license number of the car?
Uh...
It was a red RV, with a Shinjuku license number.
All right!
Let's search for it immediately.
Excuse me.
How is Megumi?
My wife? How is she?
Excuse me...
but are you Kazuo Sakihara-san?
Yes, that's right.
Kazuo Sakihara (37)
I got a call from the police, saying that my wife had a bombing accident.
So how is she?
Please don't worry. Your wife is fine.
But your wife's younger sister passed away.
H-Hiromi?!
Oh, I mean...
Why her?!
An explosive was rigged to your wife's car,
but Hiromi-san was driving the car in her place.
Sakihara-san, have you ever seen anyone like this before?
It seems you have.
N-No, never.
Excuse me.
He sure is acting strange.
Inspector Megure!
Investigation at the scene of the explosion has been completed.
How was the portrait?
Here it is.
Mouri-kun and the others seem to have seen him near the scene of the explosion.
That's reliable evidence!
Huh? This man...
What's up, Takagi-kun?
Uh, well,
I thought I saw him among the papers of the case that Detective Sato is handling.
What?!
You mean the woman who was killed in Shinjuku?
Yeah.
I only took a glimpse, but he looks a lot like the victim's husband.
Alright, check on that portrait right away and contact Sato-kun!
Yes, sir!
Metropolitan Police Department
They certainly look alike.
I've met the man himself, so I think there is no mistake about it.
He's the husband of the woman who was stabbed to death on her way home
from shopping at a convenience store at night.
Hiromasa Takahashi (33)
His name is Hiromasa Takahashi, age 33,
an employee at a chemicals company.
And over here is his wife, the victim,
Sachiko Takahashi-san, age 27.
We're investigating it as a random murder,
but she was covered by a very expensive insurance policy.
Her husband, who is in debt, was also a suspect,
but he has a perfect alibi.
I see...
Is Takahashi's car a red RV with a Shinjuku license plate number?
Yes, exactly...
What?!
Now, it is quite definite that the man we saw was Takahashi.
And if he works for a chemicals company, he could easily get a hold of explosives too.
A random murder case and a bombing incident,
they seem to be two very different cases, but maybe there's a link?
Although there are no names that correlate in both cases...
Too many things fit in for this to be a coincidence.
Another deduction could be...
Hey, Takagi-san!
You've got a cool looking badge there!
Please exchange it with mine.
Oh, no, Conan-kun, this is not a badge.
Please exchange it, please exchange it.
Conan-kun!
Hey!
Don't you understand that you can't exchange it?!
Exchange?!
I've figured it out, Inspector!
This is an exchange murder!
Exchange murder?
Aha!
If so, both incidents connect!
You mean like this?
An agreement of an exchange murder was made between Kazuo Sakihara and Hiromasa Takahashi.
First, Sakihara kills Takahashi's wife, Sachiko-san.
Next, Takahashi tried to kill Sakihara's wife, Megumi-san.
I see.
When Sakihara saw the sketch of Takahashi at the hospital,
he looked right shocked.
That's because he knew that Takahashi was the killer!
But, why did Sakihara-san want to kill Megumi-san?
That can be imagined from his remark when he found out that the one who died
was his wife's younger sister.
H-Hiromi?!
His remark sounded obviously more intimate than just a brother-in-law relationship with her!
All right!
Let's investigate the case with all what was pointed out just now!
Yes, sir!
Takahashi-san, right?
You seem to be in a rush, but are you going anywhere?
Damn!
Freeze!
You're under arrest on charges of assault and battery!
Damn!
There's explosives in the bag!
What?!
We did it, Takagi-kun!
Yeah.
A few days later
After Sakihara saw the sketch,
he informed Takahashi to run for it.
But that, in turn, was a breakthrough for us.
After hearing that Takahashi had admitted the crime, Sakihara turned himself in
and confessed that he has killed Takahashi's wife.
He seems to have talked Takahashi into committing an exchange murder
when they happened to see each other at a bar.
They never met after that first meeting, and all arrangements were done by phone.
They used a pay phone, so that no evidence would be left.
Sakihara had a phone exclusively for himself in his study upstairs.
He seems to have made sure to take all calls with this phone.
That must be why Megumi-san didn't realize what was going on.
And, what was Sakihara's motive?
Just as you had deduced,
Sakihara had an intimate relationship with Megumi-san's younger sister, Hiromi-san.
Sakihara seems to have thought up killing Megumi-san to come up with cash
for opening a boutique that Hiromi-san said she wanted to start.
Because if Megumi-san dies, all the money that he inherits from her,
and the money for the insurance that she is covered by,
would become his.
How cruel! Poor Megumi-san...
Does Megumi-kun know about this?
Yeah, although it seems she couldn't make herself believe it at first.
All she could do after finding it to be true was cry.
It's understandable, because although she wasn't involved in the crime at all,
she was backstabbed by her own younger sister.
I'll go check up on her in a few days.
That's a good idea.
So, the case has been solved and is closed.
Help her out as an old friend, will you?
Yes, sure thing.
I'll see you later, then, Ran-kun.
Goodbye, Inspector Megure.
I wonder if everything has really been solved.
Somehow...
I feel something is being overlooked...
A few days later
Dad!
You promised to meet Megumi-san at 1:00, didn't you?
Look! We're an hour early!
Let's go have some coffee!
Huh?
Isn't this the supermarket where Megumi-san mentioned she saw Takahashi?
Conan-kun!
Hurry, come.
Right.
Huh?
Dad, isn't that Megumi-san?!
What? Megumi-kun?
Hey, Megumi-kun!
Hey!
She's gone...
Conan-kun?
She backed out of a parking space that narrow...
But didn't Megumi-san say...
Since I'm not good at backing up,
my sister was getting out the car for me, so I could head on home.
She offered to back it out for me...
But what I saw doesn't look like a person who has trouble backing up her car.
Then why did Megumi-san ask Hiromi-san to take her place?
Because of that, the explosion killed Hiromi-san.
Can this really be an unlucky coincidence?
If...
If Megumi-san already knew the whole plot...
This case isn't solved yet!
Are you saying that Megumi-kun has something to do with this case?
The Megumi-san you know is the Megumi-san in her high school days.
Megumi-san could've changed after becoming an adult.
She has not changed!
She's what she used to be before!
You want to believe so, don't you, Uncle.
But actually she's already...
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Window
Next time, the solution!
Whether love or deductions, I'll do it!