As bright as a spark,
with a sharp and precise wit.
Once he gets started, you can't stop him!
Stay right there for a sudden reversal of circumstances!
Today's episode has the smallest cast ever!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
A car rigged with an explosive blew up at the home of the parents
of Megumi Sakihara-san, a person who the old guy used to tutor in his school days.
The victim who passed away in the incident was Megumi-san's younger sister Hiromi-san,
who was backing the car out of the garage for Megumi-san,
because she was supposedly not good at it.
The suspect was a man named Hiromasa Takahashi.
He agreed to carry out an exchange murder with Megumi-san's husband Kazuo Sakihara,
but he inadvertently kills Hiromi-san instead of Megumi-san.
Both men confessed to their crime,
and it looked like the case was solved. But...
She backed out of a parking space that narrow...
This case isn't solved yet!
Conan-kun! What's gotten into you?
Hey, did something happen?
Oh, it's nothing.
I think Megumi-san came here to buy us some cake or something.
Let's hurry and go to Megumi-san's house!
Geez. What's with that kid anyway?
It's too early to tell the old man about this.
I've got to get more solid proof.
I, uh... I just don't know what to say...
Thank you very much. I'm fine, so please don't worry about me.
I-I see...
Please have some tea before it gets cold.
Thank you.
I'll have some too.
How about some cake, Conan-kun?
Sure!
May I go to the restroom first?
Over there...
Sakihara had a phone exclusively for himself upstairs
and took all his calls with that phone.
What's that?
That's the remains of masking tape that was peeled off!
Just as I thought...
So, "it" was set up there after all...
I'll bet you're relieved that Megumi-san looked way better than you expected, right, Dad?
Yeah. I think she'll be fine.
I've got somewhere to go when we get to Beika Station,
so you can both leave me and go home.
All right, but remember, don't be too late.
There's a window...
I see... If it's from that window...
Just as I thought...!
Okay! I've got the overall picture! Now all I need is proof!
I'm back!
Hey, Uncle...
Something bothers me about the case.
What?
Because, remember Megumi-san backed her car
out of the narrow parking space at the supermarket today, right?
Then why did she have her younger sister back her car out for her
when the incident happened...?
Besides, on the wall near the telephone of the upstairs study of Megumi-san's house,
it looked like masking tape was peeled off.
That means that something was stuck on there, right?
Masking tape?
Did you know that there was a window way inside the garage
where the incident occurred, Uncle?
It seems that the window cracked from the impact of the explosion
and a wooden board was placed over it.
But with a window like that over there,
it's good because you can get a good view of the car from inside the house.
What are you trying to get at?
Are you insinuating that Megumi-kun has something to do with this case?
I don't know. But...
Don't be ridiculous!
I know her best because she used to be my student!
You knew her as a high school student, right, Uncle?
Megumi-san could've changed after growing up.
Don't you dare get cheeky with me!
She hasn't changed a bit! She's the way she always used to be!
You want to believe that, don't you, Uncle?
What?!
But actually, she's already...
Shut up and go on upstairs!
I'll go take a bath.
Geez! How dare that brat talk to me like that!
A secret window?
Yes, Hiromi and I call it that.
Megumi During High School
It seems that Dad actually wanted to use this as a door, though...
When I was little and getting into things in the garage,
I would always be scolded from here...
Metropolitan Police Department
The record of the testimonies of Sakihara and Takahashi?
Yes. I'd like to take a quick look, and review the results.
Did anything new come up in later investigations?
Now that you mention it, one of Hiromi-san's friends told me
that when Hiromi-san was younger, she took two boyfriends away from Megumi-san.
Well, I guess you could say that she was very carefree...
It seems that Hiromi-san was only fooling around for the fun of it.
But it seems that when Megumi-san decided to marry Sakihara,
although jokingly, she told her that if she did it again,
she would make her pay for it.
Most likely, the old guy will find some sort of circumstantial evidence in his investigation.
But when it comes to concrete evidence...
I've got it! Maybe...
Inspector, about what I asked you over the phone a while ago...
Yeah. I confirmed with Takahashi,
but the only time he saw her face was at that supermarket.
That's the first and last time he ever appeared before Megumi-san!
And, how was Takahashi dressed at that time?
He was wearing a jacket and sunglasses.
Just as I thought!
Mouri-kun, what are you up to anyway?
Thank you very much, Inspector! Goodbye!
H-Hey! Mouri-kun!
Okay! Now I've got the proof!
Huh? What do you mean? Hey, Dad?
He hung up.
What's the matter, Ran-neechan?
Dad's in Akihabara, and says he's about to go to Megumi-san's house.
He said he's "the only one who can persuade her"...
I wonder what he means?
Ran-neechan, let's go to Megumi-san's house too!
Geez!
Why'd you guys have to come too?
Sorry. I was really concerned about your call.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Thank you very much.
So what did you want to talk to me about?
Megumi-kun. I came here today to advise you to turn yourself in.
Hey, Dad!
After finding out that your husband and your younger sister were having an affair,
as an exchange murder was being planned between your husband and Takahashi,
you decided to use all this
to kill your younger sister that you have always hated,
and send your husband to jail on charges of murder, isn't that right?
Dad, what a thing to say!
Two months ago, you bought a wiretap and automatic recorder at a shop in Akihabara.
You asked the salesperson to give you the details on how to use the machines.
These are the same modular-type wiretap and automatic recorder that you bought!
I didn't want to do it,
but when I went to the restroom a while ago, I checked out the upstairs study.
You rigged a wiretap to your husband's study
and bugged his conversations with Takahashi.
The remains of masking tape peeled off the wall is proof.
You were probably planning to listen to the conversation
between your husband and your younger sister at first, weren't you?
But along the way, you found out something absolutely dreadful...
that your husband had agreed to an exchange murder with a complete stranger
and that he had already killed the wife of that man...
The time came when it was your turn to be killed by that man Takahashi.
You found out that he was planning to rig your car with an explosive,
but was undecided because if he does so in front of your house
your husband Kazuo, may turn up as a suspect to...
So you deliberately told your husband
you were driving over to your sister's place,
because her car just happened to be at the shop for inspection,
and the garage was open.
Your husband then goes out to a pay phone
and tells Takahashi everything you told him.
Although you didn't listen to their phone conversation,
almost positive that Takahashi was going to carry out his murder plan,
you went over to Hiromi's.
And after telling Hiromi that you were not good at backing cars,
Megumi's Parents' Home
you made her back the car out of the garage for you
As expected, your younger sister died.
But at that time, just one thing that you didn't expect happened.
I happened to come and see you!
You were surprised and...
Wait, Sensei!
Good.
Alright, alright...
You wanted her to back out right away
because you didn't want me to see through your plan.
I did buy the wiretap, as you say.
I set it up behind the desk after suspecting my husband of having an affair.
But I thought it over that night and immediately threw it away.
So I didn't actually use it.
Did you know that the person he was having an affair with was your younger sister?
I had no idea.
Let's presume—this is just a presumption, now—that I did act as you had deduced,
what crime am I guilty of?
Takahashi is the one who rigged the explosive onto the car,
and the person who put him up to it is my husband.
All I did, if anything, was make my younger sister get into a car
that may have been rigged with explosives.
I'm not an accomplice in a crime, nor did I urge anyone to commit murder for me.
Isn't that right, Sensei?
Just as expected of a student in the law department, and a lawyer's daughter.
Just as you say,
if all you did was get your younger sister to ride the car,
you wouldn't be found guilty of anything.
Then...
However.
in the case that you made your sister get in the car despite knowing
that an explosive was rigged to the car, or if there was a good chance you knew,
you would be charged with homicide!
You mentioned back then...
that you had to look for something, and went into the closet alone.
Then you watched the garage from the window.
And, just as expected, Takahashi came into the garage
to set the explosive onto the car.
After you confirmed all that, you asked your sister to back the car out.
In other words, there was a very good chance that the explosive was
being rigged to the car, and you still made your sister drive it!
Do you have any proof that I was watching the garage through the closet?
If you do, please show it to me right now!
Right now!
You've got proof, Uncle.
Remember? The sketch of the man that Megumi-san said she saw,
that was drawn by police officer Honjo.
Megumi-san, where did you say you saw his face?
A-At the supermarket near my house.
Huh? Strange. The officer mentioned that Takahashi
was wearing a jacket and sunglasses back then.
But why is the man in the sketch not wearing sunglasses?
Megumi-san, you didn't even notice Takahashi watching you at the supermarket, did you?
You found out only after you listened to Kazuo-san's phone call that you tapped, right?
Then where did she see his face?
From the closet!
She saw him from the secret window of the closet.
Megumi-kun, you were watching Takahashi's face from the closet of your parents' house!
The face of Takahashi who was setting up the explosive!
H-How can you be so sure?
That day, Takahashi didn't want anybody to notice him,
so he was wearing sunglasses until he entered the garage.
Of course, he were his sunglasses when coming out too.
But there was just one time he had to take off his sunglasses!
It was when he was setting the explosive onto the car!
Because nobody would even dream of doing a dangerous job
like setting up an explosive onto a car while wearing sunglasses
In other words, this sketch of Takahashi without his sunglasses is proof that
you witnessed Takahashi rigging the explosive to the car in the garage!
Just as you say, I happened to hear them.
He was planning to kill me and use the insurance money that I was covered with,
along with the inheritance money my parents left for me,
to open a new boutique that Hiromi was to own...
Ah, I remember the good old days...
I was really happy back then...
I kept hoping that I could go back to those good old days all this time...
But...
15 years ago,
there was something very important that I was supposed to have taught you.
Something more important than studying.
But, maybe I can't really teach you much,
since I'm separated from my wife and all now.
True!
But it's not too late.
Repent for the crime that you have committed and study all over again.
This time, the study of life!
Will you watch over me... then again?
Sure! By all means!
It's good that the case was solved, but...
This case must've really come as a shock to Uncle...
Yes, Mouri Detective Agency...
Yoko-chan?!
A concert? Of course I'll go!
If for you, I'll go and cheer for you or tutor.
I'll do anything you wish! Yes!
I guess we've got nothing to worry about.
Really! It takes the old guy no time at all to get back on his feet.
It bothers me! I met him somewhere,
but I can't remember where...
An MO disc?
What's this?
I don't remember buying this...
The old man who disappeared! The man wearing sunglasses!
Something... Something smells fishy!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Window glass
Next time, a mysterious old man!
Geez, young people these days!
Is he the mysterious old man?
No idea.