Perceiving in a flash,
Once it starts rolling, it won't stop!
Today, we meet a strange bus passenger.
The case that unfolds is beyond imagination.
Seeing the one and only truth,
A child with the intelligence of an adult.
His name is: Detective Conan!
Oh!
Come on!
W-Wait.
Ran, hurry up.
Hurry!
Driver, wait, wait!
We're saved.
I'm so tired!
Because you wanted to buy everything in sight.
Look who's talking.
Buying this imported brand name bag on sale.
That's because I'd been wanting to buy this all along.
Is that so?
How wonderful for you.
Good job.
Good night.
Oh, how cruel...
Wake me up when we get to the station.
The Mysterious Old Man Disappearance Case.
Are you all right?
Oh, I thought I was finally done for.
This pushed into my stomach.
I'm sorry!
Oh? Aren't you Mouri-san's daughter?
Yes. And you are...?
My name is Shitara. Shitara Juukichi.
Well, it's no surprise that you don't remember.
Shitara-san...?
It's written like this.
What a nice name!
I'm Mouri Ran.
It's really hot and stuffy today.
Yes. It's the rainy season, after all.
It's written like this.
Oh. Thank you for writing it out for me.
You're welcome.
Actually, was wondering if should
go and see your father just now.
A case?
Yes.
It's not something you can talk about over the phone.
By the way, are we still going towards Muromachi Hospital?
You mean, on the Daryu Street?
Oh... Still four stops to go.
My stop's a little further on.
Should I remind you when we get closer to it?
Thank you for your kindness.
You're welcome.
Ran. Ran!
How long are you going to sleep? Wake up!
We're nearly home.
Oh... Right.
Really! I asked you to wake me up, but it's the opposite.
Huh? What about the stop in front of Muromachi Hospital?
We passed that one a long time ago.
What? Did that uncle get off okay?
Oh?
An old uncle.
I remember his name was... Shitara-san.
Who is that?
He was sitting right next to me.
How should I know?
I didn't see him.
That's because you were asleep at the time.
Then, don't ask me about it.
Maybe you just dreamed it.
Dreamed it?
Was I dreaming?
Ran?
Excuse me. Did an older man get off at the stop
at Muromachi Hospital's front entrance?
He was wearing a hat and holding an umbrella.
I don't know...
Lots of people usually get on and off there.
I see.
Finally back at last!
What should we do next? Wanna eat something?
Eh?
Hello?
I'm still worried.
About what?
Taxi!
Sonoko, come with me.
Wait, Ran...
So? What are you gonna do now?
Go and ask about him.
Why does that guy bother you so much?
I'm just really worried.
I feel like I've met that man somewhere
before, but I can't remember.
Besides...
Actually, I was wondering if should
go and see your father just now.
He seemed to have something important to see Dad about.
In that case, you should go there.
Beika News Agency?
The place opposite that.
Shitara Juukichi-san...
No such person.
No?
Right. He's not among the out-patients or in-patients here.
Is that so?
That's strange.
Didn't that man say he was going to the hospital?
I think so...
Maybe he's visiting someone here?
Also no such person.
Among the visitors coming to see patients today,
There was no one named Shitara-san.
You worry too much.
If he had something important to tell your father,
He should have phoned your father's office.
You think so?
Or...
There was no such man like that from the beginning.
Oh, so you still don't believe me.
You mean the old man disappeared?
That's the only way I see it.
Sonoko said I'm overreacting.
But I somehow feel like it wasn't a dream.
You should ask Chief Megure to help look for...
Impossible, right?
Naturally.
You must be over-thinking things, or just had a dream.
Maybe I really was dreaming.
Note: An MO disk drive is a magnetic storage device which
utilizes an optical laser. This recording technology has
high reliability and low cost per megabyte of storage.
An MO disk.
What's this all about?
What is it? I don't remember buying this.
Maybe it belongs to the old man.
But... Why?
No good.
I can't access it without the password.
Is that so?
Here.
Top secret. Strictly not to be removed.
That's natural...
Doctor, is it possible to crack the password,
And see what's on this?
That would take a bit of time,
But you're in a hurry, right?
Yeah.
We're thinking of going to the bus company
of the bus I took in the afternoon.
Maybe there are other clues.
All right.
Wait till I've verified the file, and I'll notify you.
Thank you for your help.
Yes, yes. Is that so?
Thank you.
No problem. I just asked the bus company.
That bus is still running.
Good. Let's go.
Wait a minute!
Why do I have to go with you?
Because... Conan-kun said, rather than going
alone, I should get you to come with us.
It might help me remember something.
I should have known it was you.
Please. Please help, Sonoko.
Aw, man... I just finished my shower and I'm all ready for bed...
What's up with that car?
Conan. Face forward. It's dangerous.
Ran-neechan, that car...
Eh?
There's nothing there. Now, turn around.
Just like I said this afternoon,
I simply don't remember anything about that old man.
Is that so?
Maybe there could be some clues left in his old seat.
That's true.
Wait. It wasn't this bus.
There was some problem with that bus.
Right now, it's being repaired at the company.
Let's go, Ran-neechan!
Yes.
Maybe it was about you.
What's that?
Someone asked me where a girl named "Mouri" got off...
Really? I wonder why. That's creepy.
Who asked that question?
Who...
He was wearing a coat and sunglasses.
Could it be...
That man.
Do you know him?
But why?
Let's hurry, Ran-neechan.
A disappearing old man. A top secret MO disk.
A man wearing sunglasses.
Something's going on.
Please wait here.
Just a moment, sir!
Hey, hey. You can't come in here!
I'm sorry. I forgot something I left behind.
It was right there, Conan-kun.
Hey...
I'm not mistaken, it's right here.
I was sitting here and he sat next to me.
Do you remember anything else?
Yes. The name.
Name?
Right. He wrote his name on the window.
Because the glass was fogged up,
He used his fingers...
But it's gone now.
So it wasn't a dream!
What is this? I just don't get it.
Hello?
You hacked the password?
Yes. About the contents on the disk...
It's a double entry accounting record.
A double entry accounting record?
You know about Beika Construction, right?
This was been taken from the management unit of that company.
One is an accounting record open to the public.
The other one is a secret internal accounting record.
The disk also has,
Info on some politicians linked with different enterprises,
Along with behind-the-scene dealings and a list of names.
So that's it.
Because he had that double entry accounting record,
He was being followed.
Oh, I thought I was finally done for.
Oh?
So that man wearing sunglasses,
The target was not me, but the old uncle.
Yeah, and the old uncle realized he was being followed,
So he put the MO disk into your bag.
Right. And he also knew,
That was the Mouri Kogorou's daughter.
I've got to hurry and find him.
Find him?
Since the old uncle got off from the bus,
No one knows where he's gone.
The newspaper agency.
He must have first given me the double entry accounts,
And then went to the newspaper agency.
I see!
No.
Try to remember.
Didn't the man wearing sunglasses
Ask the driver about Ran-neechan?
That means he knew the old man didn't
have the account record, right?
That's why he was looking for you, the one
who sat next to the old man on the bus.
Right. In other words...
The old uncle is in the hands of the man wearing sunglasses.
Ran-neechan, you notify Uncle and the police.
Where are you going?
I'll go to the stop where the old man got off.
Then I'll come...
No way!
Because you're still being watched, Ran-neechan.
It's safer to stay at the bus company.
Okay.
Excuse me. May I use the phone, please?
Please go ahead.
Telephone card...
Hold this for me.
Okay.
No, that's not it. Dad, are you listening?
Don't fall asleep!
Yeah... I'm listening.
Geez, at an urgent time like this!
Well? Is he coming over right away?
No good. I'll try calling Chief Megure.
Well, as a sale item, this bag doesn't look too bad.
No... Oh, no!
Yes. I'm now at the bus company, at their parking station.
Trouble...!
The other girl just got kidnapped!
Shinichi, it's me.
What's up, professor?
I just got a phone call from Ran.
She said Sonoko was kidnapped.
What?
The criminal's car came out of the bus
company gate and turned left.
The left is... This side.
Driver, please turn back.
Oh?
What took you so long?
I'm sorry. I couldn't get a clear opportunity.
That's weird.
We should be coming across the culprit's car right about now.
There's only one factory in this direction.
That means... He must have taken a turn somewhere.
Driver, turn right over there.
Where does this road lead to?
Nowhere. This is the road to the warehouse.
If you're trying to get somewhere, this is a much longer route.
That means Sonoko is somewhere nearby.
I remember the name was Beika Construction.
Wait, wait. If the double entry account records are made public,
Beika Construction won't be the only
place to receive that bad publicity.
Any company with inside dealings with them will also be affected.
Professor, on the MO disk,
Was there a Yujin Economic Research Institute?
Just a minute.
Yes, Shinichi.
And the amounts involved were pretty large.
Thanks, professor.
Stupid. She's not the one!
Eh? Then it must be the other girl.
What are you doing, getting the wrong person!
S-Sorry, big brother.
She was wearing a bag, so I thought...
Go out there again, and bring her back here.
I know.
You'd better not screw up this time.
Yes. It'll be all right.
But, what should we do with these people?
They're useless without the disk.
Get rid of them.
What's going on?
Who the hell are you, you brat?
Edogawa Conan, a detective.
Quit screwing around...!
Shoot!
So the men wearing sunglasses,
Were associated with insider dealings with Beika Construction,
And were from the underworld, hired by the companies involved.
And Shitara Juukichi-san,
Was a long-term employee of Beika Construction.
He didn't know what to do,
So he took out the double entry accounting records.
Sonoko!
Ran... Ran!
I was so scared!
Thank goodness you're all right. I'm so glad, Sonoko!
The day after, Beika Construction received
a letter from the Anti-Corruption Office.
Delivered by an old, loyal employee.
But that old uncle,
I feel like I've seen him somewhere before...
Still can't remember, Ran-neechan?
Nope.
Since he's an old Beika Construction employee,
Maybe you saw him on TV or in the newspaper.
I wonder...
All right.
Sandwiches, iced coffee, and orange juice.
Thank you for waiting.
Here.
Thank you.
Was it my imagination?
No, it wasn't.
Oh!
Ojii-san!
So, Shitara Juukichi-san is.
A regular customer at the coffee shop
below Mouri Detective Agency.
What's wrong, Ran-neechan?
I know I've seen that guy with glasses before...
But where did see him at?
Where is it? Where did you see it, Ran-neechan?
Ran-neechan!
Next Conan.
Sonoko's Dangerous Summer Story, Part 1.
Next Conan's Hint:
Sonoko's camera
Next, Ran, that swim suit is pretty bold.
Sonoko yours is too!