As bright as a spark,
with a sharp and precise wit.
Once he gets started,
you can't stop him!
Today, there's lots of Sonoko
in her natural state.
Danger, romance and fate await!
He sees the single truth
for what it is,
and looks like a kid
but has the mind of an adult!
His name?
Detective Conan!
Izu
Perfect!
Hey, Sonoko! What are you doing?
Taking a picture of your butt while
you were fixing your swimsuit.
A real close-up!
It's an eyeful!
What are you going to do
with a photo like that?
Isn't it obvious?
I'm gonna show it to Shin'ichi-kun
when he gets back!
Think how happy he'll be!
Don't be silly!
Shin'ichi wouldn't be
happy about that!
Don't you think
so too, Conan-kun?
Umm, yeah.
What does a little kid know?
Ugh... I can't wait to
get back to normal...
You've been acting weird, Sonoko.
You've been picking on me
non-stop for a while now.
Don't mind me.
I'm just a bit jealous.
Eh? Why?
Did I do something?
Haven't you noticed, Ran?
Why'd we come on a weekend
beach trip to Izu in the first place?
For you, it's your usual
man-hunting trip, isn't it, Sonoko?
Right!
And it's a carefully planned
poor girl vacation, too!
What are you on about?
We always stay at my family's
summer house, or an expensive hotel!
"Oh, how can I talk to a girl
who's so far beyond my reach?"
This time, we're staying at an old inn,
where we can reel in unexpecting boys.
I-I see...
Pointless.
But... But...
Sonoko...
On the train here...
At the fireworks show last night...
And even at this beach...
All of the guys are after you.
Every single one of them, Ran!
I'm sure that's not true.
Well, whatever.
I'll just show Shin'ichi-kun a photo of you
in your underwear that I took last night!
Hey!
Don't even think about it, Sonoko!
If you do that,
I'll never forgive you for it!
Just kidding.
Never took any photo.
For crying out loud, Sonoko!
Oh, she was bluffing?
Hey, you two...
Are you busy?
Tadahiko Michiwaki
Would you like to get some lunch?
It's on me, of course.
Y-Yes! We'd love...
...to.
You want her, don't you?
Here, take her! She's in season!
Sonoko!
But don't try anything funny!
She's already taken.
Er, I was kinda hoping to
get to know you better.
No way!
You did it, Sonoko!
It's great!
Impossible. This is Sonoko
we're talking about.
There has to be
something behind this...
I've got to stop thinking
like a detective all the time.
Shall we go?
Then Conan-kun and I
will stay here!
Nagisa Beach House
Famous for our Grilled Amberjack
You're a student at Beika
University, Michiwaki-san?
Ran's dad used to
study there, didn't he?
Y-Yeah.
Come on.
She gets all excited about a guy,
but she wimps out and drags us along?
So, Michiwaki-san,
what brings you to Izu?
It's just a trip
to heal a broken heart.
My girlfriend dumped me.
I was gazing into
the sea in despair...
...when an angel
appeared before me!
I have a hunch you're the
goddess who's going to save me...
G-Goddess?
Here's your draft beer.
Oh, thanks.
Makoto Kyogoku
Sir, please don't drop cigarette
butts all over the floor.
They're a pain to clean up later.
R-Right.
What a rude waiter.
Say.
Haven't we seen that
waiter somewhere before?
Of course we have. His dad owns
the inn where we're staying!
He's come to help
over summer vacation.
How do you know that?
He was staring at us from the front steps
of the inn, so I asked one of the workers.
Then why's he working here?
It's probably run by the same person who takes
care of Kawaraya Inn, where we're staying.
Oh? You're staying at Kawaraya Inn?
Yeah, that's right.
Fancy that, it's right next to my hotel.
Then how about we all have dinner at
a fancy restaurant by the sea tonight?
I'll pick you up in my car.
Really?!
But don't forget to
bring your camera!
What for?
I just learned this from a local,
but there was an incident at
the beach near the restaurant.
An incident?
Yeah.
About a year ago,
a girl with long brown hair was stabbed
repeatedly in the stomach and killed.
A murder?
Yeah.
She was killed on her
way to that restaurant,
but there were no witnesses.
The police are still looking for the killer.
It's been a year since the case,
so most people forgot about it,
and the restaurant's doing well.
Unfortunately, she seems to have taken a
liking to that restaurant, and still drops by...
S-Still...
The victimized woman shows up...
as a grotesque ghost in photos taken inside the restaurant!
That's just stupid.
So let's see if she really
appears in a photograph.
H-Hey, what do you think?
I still have about ten
shots left in my camera...
No! Don't even bring it!
But if we showed it to Shin'ichi-kun,
he might notice something.
After all, we're going to show him
the shocking photo, too.
What's the point of showing him that one?
You can't even tell who it is!
He could figure it out with
his super deductive skills!
Come on...
Deductive skills?
Her boyfriend's a detective.
Oh, he is?
And what's in that photo?
Well...
Sonoko!
Here's your yakisoba.
We've got a lot of customers waiting,
so hurry up and eat.
Geez, what's with that waiter?
Does he have a grudge
against us or something?
Shoji Terabayashi
Can't we eat somewhere
other than that restaurant?
It sounds creepy.
Don't worry!
The ghost thing's just a rumor,
and it's been a year since the murder!
I'm sure the dead woman got
bored of that restaurant by now.
Hey, did you hear?!
They found another one in
the forest by the train tracks!
Another what?
A body!
The bloody body of a
woman with brown hair!
I'll be right back!
Conan-kun, no!
Conan-kun!
Sheesh, what a bundle of curiosity.
Detective Yokomizo
Shizuoka Police Detective
Stabbed multiple times
in the abdominal area.
Just like a year ago.
Yeah.
This woman seems to
have been a tourist, too.
By the way, what's the
estimated time of death?
Between 8 and 9 PM last night.
So it was right after the fireworks.
Hey, isn't that around
the time we passed by here?
Yeah...
This is scary...
Don't be silly!
There's no way you'll be attacked!
But look at me!
I have brown hair too!
There's no guarantee
I won't be next!
I don't want to die out here...
Not with my whole
life ahead of me...
Sonoko...
Don't worry.
I'll protect you as long
as you're here in Izu.
Anyway, I guess we should change
our dinner reservations, huh?
Yeah.
A-And no cameras!
Of course not.
I'll pick you up around 7.
Wait for me in front of the inn!
Will do.
Wasn't that guy just at
the Beach House, too?
See you then.
Yeah.
I'll be looking forward to it!
We should go back
to change clothes, too.
Yeah!
Hey!
If it isn't Ran-san and Sonoko-san!
So you've come to Izu, huh?
Yeah, we came for the beach.
So, is the great
Detective Mouri here too?
No, it's just us three.
Three?
Good afternoon!
Ah, you're the knight accompanying
these two damsels, huh, Conan-kun?
Be sure to protect them!
Sure!
Please be careful.
As you can see,
we've had a troubling incident.
Yeah. We'll be careful.
Then I'll be leaving.
Give Detective Mouri my regards.
Okay!
He's as cheerful
as always, I see.
Looks like he's not
having any luck, though.
If your dad was here,
he'd solve the case in no time!
Detective Yokomizo is far more
competent than the old man...
Oh, it's starting to rain...
I hope Michiwaki-san
shows up soon.
Calm down!
The hero always appears
at the last second!
Stop! You're embarrassing me!
What's with the umbrella?
I guess he wants us to use it.
Maybe he's got a crush
on you, Sonoko-neechan.
You're getting popular, Sonoko!
Not the dark guy too!
Of course, you already
have Michiwaki-san.
Stop it, Ran,
you're making me blush...
Oh, drat.
I left my purse in my room.
Hold on,
I'll be back in a sec!
Okay!
What's wrong, Ran-neechan?
I know I've seen the guy
in glasses somewhere, but where?
Somewhere in this inn, right?
No, not just here.
Somewhere else...
Really?
Where? Where'd you
see him, Ran-neechan?
Ran-neechan!
Sonoko? What's taking you so long?
Maybe she's changing...
Sonoko! What happened?
A weird guy jumped me...
He escaped through the window...
What?!
Damn! He got away...
I was so scared!
But why would anybody...
How should I know?!
When I opened the door,
he was searching our bags.
I tried to shout,
and he grabbed me!
Searching our bags?
I bet he was trying to
steal our underwear! Yuck!
What did he look like?
You saw his face, right?
I never had the chance...
It was pitch dark in here...
I was so scared,
I just about passed out...
But how do you know it's a guy?
I bit his arm in the struggle.
It was hairy!
Way to go...
What's wrong?
Why are the lights out?
Michiwaki-san!
My car broke down on the way here,
so I ran here as fast as I could.
Please accept my
apologies for being late.
But how'd you find our room?
I couldn't find you two outside,
so I asked one of the staff.
His shirt's wet
and his pants are muddy...
Don't tell me, he...
Hey, Michiwaki-san.
Would you mind
taking your shirt off?
I was wondering if you could
show me your upper arm.
Conan-kun!
I'm not sure what you mean...
Is there anything
wrong with my arm?
Nothing. No tooth
marks from Sonoko...
Happy now, kid?
Yeah.
Is anything wrong?
A bandage!
What happened to your right arm?
This is from a little struggle I had with a drunk customer earlier...
When was that? Please tell me.
I don't think it was him.
The guy who attacked me was hairier.
Attacked?
Yeah. A man came in through this
window, dug through our bags,
and attacked Sonoko when she
happened to walk in on him!
But he ran off as soon
as he heard us coming.
Must've been a thief.
We've had this happen before.
You did? Then why
didn't you tell us?
I did tell you to make
sure to lock up, didn't I?
Walking around in a midriff top at this
time of night, what are you expecting?
You're practically asking
to be attacked.
It doesn't even look
good on you, anyway.
This is my favorite top, you jerk!
Don't worry. You look
good in anything.
Yukata, swimsuit, whatever!
W-What are you doing?
I'm going to move you.
There's another room open.
Unless you want to spend the night
in the room where you were attacked.
No...
I'd also advise you not to go out,
and have dinner here at the inn instead.
You never know if that man
might be waiting for you outside.
W-What do we do, Ran?
Let's eat here.
The food's much better than I thought!
If we'd known this before,
we would've eaten here last night, too!
We would've been able to get you a nicer meal
if you'd made reservations in advance.
Of course, the meal's on the house...
...if you don't spread any "rumors"
about a thief lurking around the inn.
Right, right! Whatever!
I won't talk about the inn with an
underwear thief who pulled a knife on me!
A knife?
That's right!
I caught a glimpse of it shining in the light coming through the side screen!
It was a sharp, gleaming knife!
It couldn't be...
What if our thief is the same man who
killed the woman found in the woods today?
Supposedly a year ago, here in Izu,
a brown-haired woman was stabbed.
But why would the
killer target Sonoko?
Just because she has brown hair?
That's ridiculous...
Hold on...
The guy who attacked Sonoko
ransacked her belongings.
There's one thing in her luggage that
could be connected to the murders.
The camera!
Maybe one of the photos captured
something related to the murder!
Sonoko-neechan! Did the guy who
attacked you steal your camera?
It was still in my bag.
But the compartment
where I had it was open.
So he stole the film?
It wasn't there in the first place.
Since I finished off
all thirty-six photos,
I thought we could all
look at them over dinner,
so I had them developed
this afternoon.
See?
I've got the photos here.
Mind if I take a look?
Go ahead!
W-Wai—
Don't worry.
I kept that special photo
of you for safe-keeping.
Don't scare me like that, Sonoko!
You know all of these people?
You seem to have interrupted
a lot of lovers...
Sonoko was all cranky
before she met you.
She kept pranking
all the couples we met!
R-Ran...
Strange... There's nothing
odd about the photos.
I don't see the victim, either.
We did pass through the forest
where the body was found last night,
but Sonoko didn't
take any photos then.
So what made the killer think
Sonoko'd taken an incriminating photo?
Why?
Maybe someone overheard her at lunch...
He could figure it out with
his super deductive skills!
Nagisa Beach House
Famous for our Grilled Amberjack
The killer could've been in
the Beach House at the time.
But was it really that
suspicious a remark?
Hey, you're going home
tomorrow at noon, right?
Yeah.
So how about we stop by the
cursed restaurant in the morning?
Let's go, let's go!
It won't be as scary
in the daylight!
But no cameras!
I know!
Am I imagining things,
or does this guy keep watching us?
And what about that guy in the glasses,
the one Ran thinks she's seen before?
And as for the guy
who attacked Sonoko...
Was he really just a simple thief?
The hand brake's disengaged!
Sonoko, wake up! Sonoko!
It's him again!
Oh no!
Sonoko's in danger!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Toothmarks
Next time...
Finally Sonoko's got herself a boyfriend!
I'm so happy!
This won't end with just being happy!