As bright as a spark,
with a sharp and precise wit.
Once he gets started,
you can't stop him!
Summer vacation's only just begun!
What kind of guy has
Sonoko taken a liking to?
He sees the single truth
for what it is,
and looks like a kid
but has the mind of an adult!
His name?
Detective Conan!
At the beach in Izu, Ran and I
witnessed a strange summer event!
Somehow, Sonoko got herself a boyfriend by the name of Michiwaki-san!
But while Sonoko's
in seventh heaven,
waiting for Michiwaki-san to
pick her up for their dinner date,
someone attacked her!
Am I imagining things,
or does this guy keep watching us?
Then there's that guy in the glasses who Ran thinks she's seen somewhere before.
And as for the guy
who attacked Sonoko...
Was he really just a simple thief?
There it is!
What a lovely restaurant!
There don't seem to be
many customers, though.
Maybe we came too early.
Are you sure you
aren't coming, Sonoko?
I'm sure.
Because I kept remembering that guy last night,
I couldn't sleep much,
so I'm going to sleep here.
Oh, all right.
But what a waste...
In that case, there are drinks in this cooler,
so help yourself whenever you'd like.
Thank you so much!
Then, we'll see you later, Sonoko.
Have a nice time.
Sonoko-kun, if you're feeling up to it
after your nap, join us in the restaurant.
I will.
I can't stay up another minute...
The seafood here is delicious.
This is a shame, since I wanted to let Sonoko-kun try it, too.
You think she'll be all right?
She's sleeping inside a hot car.
Don't worry. I turned
the air conditioner on.
Wow, look at this!
Is this for one person?
Yep!
There's plenty
and the price is low.
That's the secret to
this restaurant's popularity!
Oh geez. A full-course
meal for lunch?
See? Didn't I tell you
the food was great?
Yes, it was delicious!
I'm completely stuffed.
Thank you very much!
I feel a bit bad
for Sonoko though.
Oh?
You're from the inn...
Do you come here often?
No, this is my first time.
By the way, where's your
brown-haired friend?
I haven't seen her anywhere...
You mean Sonoko?
It seems she's
a bit sleep-deprived,
so she's resting in
the car parked outside.
Huh?
Isn't that your car, Michiwaki-san?
W-Why's it moving?!
This is bad! It's heading
straight for the cliff!
Please come again.
Hey, where do you think
you're going? Pay your bill!
That's a lockpick!
The hand brake's disengaged!
Sonoko, wake up! Sonoko!
I can't put full strength in
while I'm running!
Oh no!
We're almost there!
Conan-kun,
get away from the car!
Ran!
Sonoko, grab onto me!
Hey!
Are you guys all right?!
Yeah... Somehow...
That was close.
I'm glad you're safe.
Hey, you!
Why didn't you put
the hand brake on?
Don't be ridiculous!
I did have it on.
If it weren't on, the car would've
fallen off the cliff a lot sooner.
Someone released the hand brake.
Someone broke into the car
using a lockpick.
Someone who was after
Sonoko-neechan's life.
I see.
So someone broke into the car
while Sonoko-san was asleep inside,
released the hand brake,
and made the car roll down
this slope and off the cliff.
Here's the diver's report.
The hand brake of the car underwater
was disengaged, just as we suspected.
Also, we found this lying on the road.
It's a lockpick!
We're dealing with a pro here...
It's been wiped clean of prints!
Did you find any other clues?
No.
Just a puddle of water that must've
leaked out of the car's air conditioner
where the car was parked
in the parking lot.
Sonoko-san, did you notice any
suspicious figures around the car?
Dunno...
I couldn't sleep much last night,
so I was sound asleep in the car.
But ever since we arrived in Izu,
someone suspicious has been
tailing us for some reason...
And that's him over there.
Pardon my rudeness,
but could you identify yourself?
I work at the inn where
the girls are staying.
The inn's not busy
during the afternoon,
and I had some free time,
so I came here today to have some tea.
He isn't behind this.
When the car started moving, he was
already in the restaurant with us.
If he'd forced the car door open,
released the hand brake,
and then come into the restaurant,
we would have seen him
come in through the entrance.
When I asked the waiter, he told me
that the back door is always kept locked.
We first noticed him when
he came out of the restroom,
but there's no window leading out
from inside that restroom.
And of course, Michiwaki-san's
in the clear too.
He was eating with us
and never left the table.
That means...
The most likely suspect is
the man who's been following us!
Who is he anyway?
Listen up, everyone.
We'll take all your statements
down at the station.
So please get into the car.
The car?
U-Umm, I don't feel like
riding in a car right now.
I'm kinda scared.
Then how about I walk you
to the police station?
It's not that far, and we can
enjoy the scenery. How's that?
Yes, sounds good!
W-Wait just a minute!
What if she gets attacked again?
Sonoko-san does have
brown hair, you know.
Her assailant could also be
the same killer from that other case.
You have nothing to worry about.
No one would be foolish enough to attack her in broad daylight.
B-But you never know!
Don't worry, Detective.
Michiwaki-san will be with me,
And if worse comes
to worst, so will Ran.
Just don't stop anywhere.
Come straight to the station.
Yes, sir.
But, man...
The attack at the inn last night,
and then the car incident today.
They sure are after you.
Sonoko, are you sure you don't
have any idea what's going on?
No, none at all.
Maybe it's because
you're so charming?
Right, why is she being targeted?
And if he was after her life, why didn't
he do it when he broke into the car?
There was no need to put the car in gear
and have it plunge off the cliff.
But we planned on going home as soon
as we had lunch at the restaurant,
so all of our luggage
was in the car.
It's all gone up in flames now.
Sheesh, why do we have to
be put through all of this?
Yours is nothing in comparison!
After all, I lost my car!
Yeah, you're right.
Just because you got
involved with me.
I guess I brought you bad luck.
No. That's not right, either.
It's nothing compared to losing
all the memorable photos you took.
Photos are something
you can never replace.
All that's left now
is that one photo.
One photo?
You know, the one I'm going
to show Shin'ichi-kun.
I have it on me at all times—
you have nothing to worry about!
You still have it?!
C'mon, get rid of it!
You're making me mad!
That's it!
It's that photo.
I'm certain the killer wants
to get rid of that photo!
That's why he had to send the car
over the cliff to get rid of Sonoko's luggage!
But I don't understand...
Why does he think Sonoko took
an incriminating picture of him?
There wasn't a single unusual
photo in the ones she took.
Or did I overlook something?
It's him again!
I think we're being followed.
Is it the killer?
Can you run?
Y-Yeah.
Then let's go!
Let's go too!
But isn't it more dangerous
to go through the woods?
No, this is more thrilling!
Right?
Yeah.
Anyway, let's split up
to shake him off!
That's strange.
If he's Sonoko's attacker,
why's he still after her?
All the photos were burned!
A train?
Come to think of it, they found
a body in this forest yesterday.
When we passed this place a couple
nights ago, I'm sure a train went by.
What is this?
I'm missing something here!
Damn! I've lost them.
The situation's turning bad.
Enough is enough!
If you thought we'd just run,
you've made a big mistake!
H-Hey!
Owowowowow!
You shouldn't have run
through the forest in sandals!
Sandals?
It was you, wasn't it?
You're the one who attacked
Sonoko last night at the inn,
and sent the car over the cliff!
H-Hold on there! That's—
No use lying!
Your hairy arms
are proof enough!
Let's have a look!
There should be bite marks
where Sonoko bit you last night!
N-No way...
There's no bite marks!
Maybe on the other arm!
Huh? No marks on
this arm either!
What's going on?
Who are you anyway?!
Well, actually...
I'm a detective with the Chiba
Prefecture Police Department.
You're just showing me the cover.
You're dead wrong if you think
I'd fall for that trick!
My father used to be a police
officer. You can't fool me!
When an officer has to
identify him or herself,
they must show the first page
of the police notebook
with the photo
and corresponding data.
The name's Shoji Terabayashi.
Oh, my.
It's the real thing?
I'm on the trail of a suspect.
A suspect?
Ran-neechan.
You don't usually wear
socks with sandals, do you?
No, not really.
Oh no!
Sonoko's in danger!
Ouch!
I stepped on a twig.
I guess running about in the forest
with sandals wasn't such a good idea.
Are you all right?
Tooth marks...
Why are you so surprised?
There's nothing to be so
surprised about, is there?
After all...
This is the mark
you gave me last night.
So that's it!
That's what happened!
Sonoko didn't bite his arm
last night—she bit his leg!
She must've gotten
mixed up in the dark!
He probably thought
Sonoko took his picture
because the sparks the
train's pantograph produces
lit him from behind
at the time of the murder!
And seeing Sonoko, who passed by
holding a camera immediately after that,
he jumped to
the wrong conclusion!
He thought he'd
been seen with the victim!
Come to think of it,
I remember him saying...
Don't worry. You look
good in anything.
Yukata, swimsuit, whatever!
The only time Sonoko wore a yukata was
during the fireworks show two nights ago!
We only met him yesterday.
He wouldn't have known
what she looks like in a yukata!
Damn it! Why didn't I...
Why didn't I figure it out sooner?!
What are you doing?!
Give me that picture.
The picture you were going to
have some detective look at!
You probably planned on taking
a romantic picture of a couple,
but that photo shows me in the
middle of committing murder!
Just like I am now!
F-Four?
Michiwaki-san killed four people?
If he was responsible for
the murder the other night,
then she's probably the fourth!
For some reason, he only
kills girls with brown hair!
I've had my eyes on
him for a while now.
I got him on a stolen
vehicle charge once,
but there wasn't enough
proof on the murder charge.
I came to Izu because I heard that
a similar murder happened here,
and here he was!
But I arrived too late
to save his latest victim.
But there's something
I still don't get.
How did he make the car move on its own
if he was in the restaurant the whole time?
With ice.
He had a cooler.
He took a wedge-shaped
piece of ice out,
and placed it under the left front tire
to prevent it from moving.
Then he pretended to talk to
Sonoko-neechan who was inside,
and released the hand brake!
Then he left a
lockpick on the ground,
to divert the investigation!
I see.
That's why he left two
spaces open when he parked!
Then there'd be no cars obstructing
his car's path when it moved!
On top of that, the melted ice would
just appear to be water from the AC.
But why?
Why does he kill only
girls with brown hair?
I told you, didn't I?
A heartless girl dumped me.
And that's... That's why...
Whenever I see flirty girls like you...
I get so mad!
Especially when I see girls with brown hair,
just like the one who dumped me!
Look over there!
Isn't that Sonoko?!
What?!
Oh no!
Why? Why?!
Why are all the guys that
make a play for me so weird?
I hate you, God!
Are you all right?
A-Am I all right?
What about you?
Oh, this?
Now I remember!
I knew I'd seen that guy
with the glasses before.
It was at the tournament!
He's the captain of the Haido
High School Karate Club!
The Prince of Kicks!
Makoto Kyogoku!
Wow.
You're a very reckless lady.
You're lucky I was nearby
and had some free time.
F-Free time?
Do you mean you were
following me all this time?
Yes, I was following you
the whole time.
Until I lost sight
of you in the forest.
I knew you might mistake
me for a stalker.
Before he met you,
he'd been flirting
with a few other girls.
It got me worried.
Why did you worry about me?
You don't even know me.
You probably didn't notice me,
but I'd seen you once before,
at a karate tournament.
You were cheering on your friend.
I never thought you'd
reserve a room in our inn.
Oh, and...
I'd like to recommend that,
as much possible,
you avoid wearing those lingerie-like outfits that arouse men.
Of course, you're free
to ignore my advice,
and pass it off as
just another casual remark
made by one of
your many admirers.
Teitan High School
Kyogoku-san's gone abroad to study?
But why?
You and he were getting along
so well since then, weren't you?
He said he ran out of strong opponents
in Japan, so he went abroad to train.
THREE DAYS LATER
Ran!
Let's go see the baseball team's practice game!
The other team's ace is a
first-year high school student.
I hear he's so cute
and just so adorable!
Sheesh.
I thought you were going to wait
for Kyogoku-san to return.
That's that, this is this!
I knew it.
A key in the water?
The window?
No...
There's no way a person
could come in through that.
Just what trick was used to
turn this into a locked room?
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Crayons
The key to the next case is a key!
What? I don't get it!
You don't have to screech...
Is that supposed to be a dad joke?