Perceiving in a flash.
Once it starts moving, it never stops.
Today we tackle the truth behind a mysterious key.
A shocking trick in a locked room!
Seeing the one and only truth.
He has the appearance of a child, and the brain of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
It should be around here somewhere.
You mean the Hikari Maison apartments?
Well... It's probably been condemned by now.
Hey, could it be this place?
Light Maison.
No... No way.
The Underwater Key in the Locked Room Case.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I remodeled the apartments earlier this spring.
I had no idea. It really surprised me.
This place is completely different from
when you were studying as a student, right?
It was on a whim that I even lived here.
And because your parents kept meddling in your business,
You ran off six months later.
R-really?
Hey, Grandma.
Do you live here alone?
I sure do.
My children all grew up and moved away long ago.
But I do have one grandson living with me now.
Here. Eat up.
It looks really good!
Well, it's great that you're not lonely.
Yes. His name's Makoto.
He studies architecture at Jounan University.
But recently, he's been locking
himself up in his room for hours on end.
I keep asking him why, but he won't tell me anything.
That's why I thought that a famous
detective like you might be able to make him talk.
So that's why you called me.
He said he'd be here about eight o'clock.
Let's go take a look.
My grandson and I live on the fourth floor.
I rent out the first through third floors.
That's strange.
Maybe he's asleep.
I'll just use the spare key.
Are you sure that's okay?
Don't worry about it. He's my grandson, after all.
Makoto, are you here?
Really! What a dirty child!
Ahh! What in the world?
Excuse me, ma'am.
Uncle.
Don't tell me that's...
No, it's only crayon.
Gross.
It's even on the door.
An Underwater Monument.
What's this?
This is horrible!
Makoto!
There's a key in the water?
Makoto!!
What is it?
Makoto! Hang on, Makoto!
Makoto! Makoto!
The vein in his left arm's been slit open.
No other knife marks in sight.
Quick! Call an ambulance!
No. It's too late.
It can't be!
I know! Call Kido-kun.
Kido-kun?
He's a medical student and lives just below us.
He's a friend of Makoto's.
But your grandson is...
Just go get him!
I'll go.
Kido-san! Kido-san!
Kido-san?
Kido-san... Something smells!
Great. He must have gotten drunk and fell asleep.
What's with this room?
Who are you?
Kido-san, Makoto-san had an accident!
Hurry. Come with me.
Wha... Uh?
Makoto~!
The deceased is Souda Makoto-san, age 22.
He was a senior architecture student at Jounan University.
The cause of death was a severed vein
in the left arm and excessive blood loss.
Judging from the stiffness of his neck,
He's probably been dead for two or three hours.
Which makes the estimated time of death,
Around six or seven o'clock in the evening.
Inspector, this was a suicide.
What? A suicide?
Yes. Please come here.
It's this.
What is it?
It's a model that Makoto made.
There's a key in the water.
The door can only be opened by a special key.
And it can't be easily duplicated.
The spare keys are kept by his
grandmother and the security company.
How was the lock when you arrived?
The door was locked.
That makes this a locked room case.
That's why it can be determined to be suicide.
It can't be!
Makoto would never commit suicide.
When I brought him juice this afternoon,
He even said he wanted to eat pumpkin for dinner.
And what time was that?
It was about five PM.
Then I left.
And while I was gone, Makoto was...
So what kind of juice was it?
I made it myself to prevent dehydration. It's a special blend.
The main ingredients are honey, garlic and banana juice.
Anyway, there were never any signs,
That Makoto had suicidal tendencies.
Makoto was really stressed out.
What do you mean?
He said the model he was making
for his graduation wasn't going well.
I knew it.
That's why he was depressed.
What?
Just look at the messy crayon
drawings and the setup of the apartment itself.
He was surely emotionally disturbed.
Hey, Inspector.
What's the white stuff on this key?
Really? What is it?
Whaa!?
Aww... Look what you did! Stupid!
I wonder if it's toilet paper.
Toilet paper?
Yeah. It could be tissue or some other paper,
But tissue doesn't melt like that.
My guess it is toilet tissue cut into strips, then made into string.
But, why in the world,
Did he put it on there?
I don't know. He did have some weird habits, though.
It was probably just some hobby of his.
Anyway, this is a locked...
No, it's not.
What?
Look over there.
The air vent's open.
Ah?
So what?
Do you think really think someone
could get through a gap that small?
Look here. It's only 15 millimeters long.
All the other windows are locked.
Which makes this a locked room!
But don't you think it's weird that he committed suicide?
It'd be nearly impossible to cut your vein in the dark.
In the dark...?
Were any of the lights on when you came in?
Well... Maybe the bathroom...
It was off.
I turned it on myself.
The estimated time of death is
about six to seven o'clock in the evening.
It was still daylight outside.
But there aren't any windows in the bathroom.
Without some kind of light, there's no
way he could have cut his vein open.
Maybe the criminal turned off the lights after the crime.
So if it was a murder,
The criminal probably did those crayon drawings, too.
And then there's the key.
How did the criminal put the key in the water?
We still have two other questions to answer.
Instead of the same random drawings he did on the walls,
Why did the criminal carefully
color in that line on the door post?
And... That window.
Even if it were darker outside,
It's hard to imagine that the criminal didn't notice it.
Wait a minute.
The window wasn't the only thing that was open!
Now I see!
Inspector, I've got it!
I take back what I said. This was a murder!
Everyone, please follow me.
The key to this mysterious trick is...
This mail box slot.
First, the criminal...
Linked a string to the model.
Then pulled it to the door.
He drew it through the opening in the mail slot,
Then used the key to lock the door.
After that, he put the key back on the string,
And kept stretching the string.
The key moved slowly back into the room.
When it reached the water in the model,
The wet toilet tissue broke, and it dropped into the water.
How's that?
I think the mystery's been solved now.
I see now. I should have known you'd figure it out.
I see! That's why...
Uncle, there's something I don't get.
You have to turn left from the
entrance to get to the living room, right?
Yeah. What about it?
If you drew a string from here to that room,
Wouldn't it pass over the doorjamb and leave a mark?
It's not there.
That's why the criminal used crayon to mark the doorjamb.
He wanted to make sure that people
knew he didn't use string to commit the murder.
And here, he...
Oh. Right. Now I get it.
The criminal put the key straight into the mail slot and...
No trace there, either.
That's it.
The air vent. He did the string trick using the air vent.
It's certainly possible that he tried.
No, that's impossible.
See? You see that dog there?
He's a good watchdog.
He barks at everyone but family members.
Right, Kido-kun?
Yeah. He always barks at me.
It's wide open in that yard.
If someone was acting weird out there, he'd bark even louder.
So it wasn't the air vent.
I guess it really was suicide, Inspector.
No. This was a murder.
And the criminal...
The victim only had one wound.
There are no other signs of injury.
Just one very accurate and deep incision.
The only person who could do that...
Is someone who has medical knowledge.
But what trick did he use?
Bug trap?
Hold on. That sweater by the door...
The crayon all over the walls.
And... That's it!
That's why that window's slightly open.
It's just a halfway locked room!
Now for the evidence.
There's gotta be something. There's gotta be!
What?
This smell...
It's coming from here!
Could it be...
Found it!
Hey, Grandma...
Yes?
Is this cup the one you used for the juice?
Yes, that's right.
I can't believe Makoto actually washed the cup.
I knew it!
I've found the proof.
Thank you for your help.
This is it for today...
I got it!
I know the trick the criminal used.
What?
Really, Conan-kun?
Yeah. Let me show you.
Grandma, can I borrow the key?
You idiot! How could you know...
Son, you just need the key, right?
Take it.
Thank you.
Wait right here.
Uh, just what are you doing?
Don't worry about it.
Oh, yeah, Grandma. When I go out,
Make sure the lights are off like they were before, okay?
Yes. All right.
Ready?
I'm gonna start now, so everyone be quiet.
Little punk.
Hmm?
Sounds like something fell...
A beetle?
It's a male beetle.
No way!
The bug trap!
How'd it go?
Conan-kun.
So that's it. That's how the criminal did it.
But why did the beetle do that?
It's the smell.
The top of the model is covered with a scent male beetles love.
Then what about that sweater it ran across?
The criminal put his sweater on the floor
so that the beetle could walk through easier.
Floor tiles are hard for beetles to walk across.
The hallway and the living room are carpeted, though.
Which made it convenient for the criminal.
Conan-kun, you're incredible.
Hey. That beetle... Where'd you get it?
Oh! I took it from Kido-san's place. He's got tons.
Sorry one got away, Kido-san.
It's okay. No problem.
Kido-san, before I came and got you
earlier, had you already come up here?
Huh? No, I didn't.
Really? Are you sure?
Of course I'm sure. Why do you ask?
Because I was just wondering why your
handkerchief smelled like Grandmas homemade juice.
Grandma brought the juice around five PM.
Kido-san, you took the cup that
Makoto-san drank from and washed it, didn't you?
And then you used your handkerchief
to wipe up some that spilled on the floor.
Why did you do that?
Because, you were scared that the male beetle...
Would take one whiff of that strong-smelling juice,
And forget about the scent you'd put on the model tower.
You rubbed a female beetle's scent
all over the top of the model, didn't you?
Kido-kun! Don't tell me you...
Please take out your handkerchief.
I'm really clumsy.
I was so stoked that my plan succeeded,
That I forgot to deal with the handkerchief.
I had a few drinks to celebrate, and I fell asleep.
Why did you kill Makoto-san?
About a year ago, he had this idea,
That we steal some sedatives from the university and sell them.
Then later, he said he changed his mind.
I heard that you'd be coming tonight.
I got freaked about what would happen if he leaked it.
You bastard!
I'm sure Makoto-san...
Truly regretted what he'd done.
That's probably why he decided to stop.
Although it's a little late to say this,
A man's life is more precious than you can ever imagine.
You can keep thinking about that all the while you're in jail!
Think long and hard.
It's cost you a big part of your life.
Poor Mitsue-san...
Yeah. It won't make up for losing Makoto-san.
But you two should go visit her once in a while.
Okay.
But you were really terrific tonight, Conan-kun.
You really surprised me.
It was nothing. I'm always
hearing Uncles deductions, that's all.
Now that's something to be proud of.
Thanks to me, you're learning
detective skills without even trying.
Uncle, you're the one who needs to
learn more about solving mysteries.
Arrest the suspect?
Find them! Find Sato and Takagi!
First, if we're gonna find any witnesses,
We should start investigating at that pub.
Don't... Don't tell me this place is...
You-know-who lives here, too, right?
Next Conan:
Metropolitan Police Officer Love Story 2 (Part One)
Next Conan's hint!
Professor Agasa's new invention
The next chapter is "Love Story 2."
About me and Officer Sato?
I'll rip that hat off your bald head!