Perceiving in a flash.
Once it starts rolling, it won't stop.
This episode is filled with policemen.
The Detective Boys help with the reasoning.
Seeing through the one and only truth...
A child with the intelligence of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Metropolitan Police Detective Love Story. Part 1.
I'm not wrong.
She's discovered your identity.
If you keep hiding it from her, you'll just hurt her more.
You... Why are you telling me this?
I see. You can see into the hearts of the wicked,
But you can't understand a woman's heart, can you?
A woman's heart?
I'm in love with you.
I have been since the first time we met.
Looks like you didn't even notice.
Kamen Yaiba-san.
Cut! Cut!
That was terrible, Conan-kun!
You've gotta act more surprised.
This scene is filled with conflict and emotion.
It's where the spy who betrayed
Kamen Yaiba confesses her love for him.
Geez, I didn't know I needed
acting lessons for the school play.
If that's the case, let's just do a normal story instead.
Like "Momotaro" or the "One-Inch Boy".
I refuse to direct some unrealistic fairy-tale.
Then what do you call Kamen Yaiba?
I'm the one who has to be the evil potato.
Quit your nagging and suck it up!
Yeah!
We're trying to bring out the same
emotions people would have if this were real life.
In that case, let's act out a police story.
C'mon, you know.
Like when a thief runs into an abandoned
building and gets chased down by the cops.
Wait!
Stop!
Put your hands up and don't make a move.
Officer Sato.
Ayumi!
Don't come near me!
Ayumi-chan!
Ayumi!
Back off.
Just back off!
Conan-kun!
Let me go! No!
Let me go! Let me go!
I'm sorry, little girl.
I've done something scary to you.
I'm really sorry.
Damn.
Ayumi!
Conan-kun!
Where'd he go?
I think he ran up to the roof.
Hey! Wait!
W... Whoa!
Sato-san!
Officer Takagi!
Takagi-kun, go around to the front.
Okay.
Hey! What's going on?
What? The criminal you were taking in got away?
Yeah.
We were heading back to HQ
when a bike and truck collided.
And while we were focused on that, he ran away.
He looked so honest. I never imagined he'd run away.
That's terrible!
If he really does get away, it's not like you
can just fill out a report and say you're sorry.
Yes, I know!
18:30.
Recovered the escapee.
Oh, shoot. The handcuff broke.
Man, quit making so much trouble for people.
Come on. Stand up!
No way...
The key! The key! Where's the key?
Not here... Oh, come on!
I must have dropped it somewhere.
Didn't think I'd have to go all out.
Innocent.
I'm innocent!
I didn't kill anyone, Officer!
Hey. Did you hear something weird just now from upstairs?
Must be your imagination. Everything up there's locked up.
Okay, let's finish this up.
Yeah.
Sato-san, where are you?
Sato-san!
That's weird.
Isn't this an art gallery?
Yeah.
Then why isn't there any art? The room's bare.
You're right.
Maybe they're just changing the art around.
Hey! Didn't I tell you guys to go
home because it was dangerous?
Takagi-kun!
Sato-san!
Takagi-kun, I'm here!
How'd it go, Sato-san?
Sato-san...
Over here.
What in the world are you
doing? This is the men's restroom!
What happened to the fugitive?
Well, I caught him...
But there was a little blunder.
What in the world?
You know that both the criminal's hands should be cuffed.
I didn't want him to escape again, so I cuffed him to myself.
Where's the key?
I guess I lost it.
If any of the others sees me
like this, I'll be really embarrassed.
Can you sneak me a spare key?
I can't sneak anything.
When the criminal escaped,
everybody got all anxious about it.
What? That's some nerve you got for a junior officer.
Didn't the criminal originally escape
because you weren't watching him properly?
Yes, ma'am. That's right.
I'm counting on you, Takagi-kun.
Yeah, yeah.
It wasn't me.
I'm not the criminal.
I have no idea how or why,
But when I woke up this morning
Muranishi-san was already died.
He's been saying that for a while now.
It's the truth. Please believe me!
Work with me here, Higashida-san.
The death occurred in her
apartment, in the same building where you live.
Muranishi Masami-san was your superior at work.
She died in the bathroom, which is adjacent to her room.
When her body was discovered,
You were found drunk and asleep on her bed.
The main door was chain locked,
Leaving the room secured.
The main bits of evidence are the fact
that the door was chained from the inside,
And a video cable was found near the
victim's body, with your fingerprints on it.
At work, people often saw
you two arguing with each other.
On the day of the murder, you were seen in a bar
drinking and having a pretty loud disagreement with her.
That's why we concluded that you got came into
her bedroom drunk and used the video cable to kill her.
You probably locked the door
so that she couldn't get away.
After you murdered her, you fell asleep on her bed.
But I don't have any memory of that.
Because you did it after you got drunk.
It's true that I didn't really like her
because she kept complaining about my work.
But I didn't hate her enough to kill her!
So why did you run away?
Because I have somewhere I need to be.
And where would that be?
I received a letter from my daughter...
I haven't seen my daughter since
my ex-wife and I first got divorced...
But she sent me an invitation to her wedding.
I thought that she hated me these 17 years...
How can I not go to her wedding?
It's true. You can go to my room and
check. You'll find my daughter's letter there.
And the airplane ticket, too.
But, still...
This man's not a bad guy!
Oh?
I know because he let me go. He even said he was sorry!
If he were really a bad guy
then he wouldn't have done that.
But, Ayumi...
Say, what time is the flight tomorrow?
It leaves from Narita Airport at 12:30.
Sato-san?
Takagi-kun, can you do everything I tell you to?
What? You can't get a hold of Sato and Takagi?
No, sir. I've been calling their cellphones, but still no luck.
What if they got in an accident along the way?
Hurry and find them! They
should still be in that area somewhere.
Shiratori-kun! We're going, too!
Yes, sir!
Find the real criminal before noon tomorrow?
You mean me?
Yeah, that's right. I'll look after him until then.
It's not like I can move around like this.
Then... I'll go get the key...
We can take him to police station, and then we can both...
No. If you get caught trying to bring back the key...
First the captain will chew you up,
then make you do a bunch of paperwork...
By the time you finish, the flight will have left.
Listen.
We're looking for the real suspect.
Just keep that in mind and find the real criminal.
There's no other way.
Before this man is prosecuted,
We're using our own judgment to check out his alibi,
And there's nothing wrong with that.
But...
The time limit is...
Before this art museum opens tomorrow morning at 10.
If a customer comes into this restroom,
he'll probably call the police immediately.
So until then, I'm trusting you.
How does that work?
Thank you so much.
But, doing this all alone is...
What? You're not alone.
They look like they want to help.
Eh?
Listen. The time limit is tomorrow morning at ten.
You have to find the real suspect
before then to prove this man's innocence.
Don't worry, you can do it.
Believe in yourself.
Hey, what are you laughing at? We've gotta go!
Wait! Isn't Sato-san's direct superior Inspector Megure?
She said all that just to give me confidence.
First he's all excited, and now he's all depressed.
He's weird.
Hey! What are you doing?
These stairs are labeled, "No Entry", aren't they?
There was an emergency...
Yes, we were all chasing a suspect.
What suspect? You're not cops.
Even though it doesn't seem like it, I'm...
Of course, if the police find the two of
us here like this, then the mission is over.
In order for this man to make it to his daughter's
wedding in time, you'll have to investigate alone.
I'm so sorry. We were just pretending to be police men.
Geez.
Is this really okay?
Hmm? What?
That cop doesn't seem too reliable...
Yeah, you're right. He's sweet, but he sometimes ends
up messing up. He's the type you just can't leave alone.
But Takagi-kun works hard to get the job done.
No way...
Besides, the kid's with him.
The kid?
The boy with the glasses.
Somehow, he just gives people confidence.
That was the fifth one.
What's going on?
I told you. They're looking for the
suspect, Officer Sato, and myself.
Officer Takagi, you look like a gangster.
I've got no choice. This is an undercover investigation.
Anyway, that shop is first on our list.
Before Higashida-san went to the
apartment where the crime was committed...
He was at that bar.
Yes, I remember. He got stinking drunk.
He said he'd "set her straight".
But I just can't believe that
Higashida-san turned to violence.
Did he go back alone?
He had a drinking buddy named Kitagawa-san with him...
They both left together.
Look. That man over there.
He works at the same company as Higashida-san.
So this is him.
Kitagawa-san was the first person to discover the victim.
The first one?
Right.
The day after the crime,
Higashida-san and Muranishi-san didn't come to work.
So he asked the building manager to open the
door, and that's when he discovered the dead body.
Money's on the table.
Thanks for coming.
Oh, Kitagawa-san!
I'm with the police. I have a few questions to ask you.
I've told the police all that I know.
My friend killed my boss... It's all been a terrible shock.
Please leave me in peace.
Oh... Right.
That's right.
He already gave
his statement at headquarters.
And the manager here has been questioned loads of times.
Yep. Muranishi-san was a fan of Tokyo Spirits team,
And Higashida-san was anti-Spirits.
Really...?
Hey! What are you kids asking her?
So sorry about that. We'll be leaving now.
Oh, I've got to call home. My mom will be worried.
Me, too.
Aw, man.
There's no way we'll find
the criminal before tomorrow afternoon.
What? Tell everyone that you're all staying with me?
Fine with me. Since you're with Officer
Takagi, I won't have to worry about you.
Tomorrow's Sunday anyway.
So I'll tell everyone's parents that
they'll see you after the big event.
Event? What event?
The time has come for the
world to witness my new invention!
I call it, "Tropical Rainbow".
It's basically a rainbow-colored explosion.
After you wrap things up,
remember to come and have a look.
R-right...
Did Agasa-san say it's all right?
Yeah. He was going on about some
fireworks show tomorrow in Haido city.
Fireworks... Is there really an event like that?
Anyway, next stop is the
crime scene, Muranishi-san's room.
Ah... Yeah.
The police again?
The police that came this
afternoon just left not too long ago...
There was something else we needed to take a look at.
And who are these kids?
Occupational studies.
We have to watch a policeman in action,
and then make a report about it at school.
Ohh. The average "working man"?
I'll return the key after we've finished.
Right, thanks.
Hey!
If you guys touched anything...
Don't worry. Look!
When you bought your hat, we bought these gloves.
Conan-kun told us to.
Really...
Damn!
The suspect, Takagi and Sato...
Just where did they run off to?
They chased the suspect to an
abandoned building in Haido city,
And that's the last we heard from them.
Are you getting a strange feeling about this?
It's not like Sato-san not to check in.
Maybe...
They both were caught by the suspect.
NO!
How dare he!
Dammit. How dare he treat my officers like that...
Oh, Sato-san's...
What, the suspect's got Sato...
He captured Miwa-chan?!
Uh-oh. Am I coming down with something?
I'm sorry. It's my fault that we're caught up like this.
It's all right. We're the ones who
might have chosen the wrong suspect.
And... I'm not doing this for you.
I didn't want to give your
daughter a memory to regret, like me.
I've had to deal with the memory
of losing my father since I was little.
Let's just head on back, guys.
No matter how hard we look, nothing turns up.
The investigators that came earlier went
over this place with a fine-toothed comb.
There are four weird points.
First there's the color of the
futon, pillow, sheets, and curtain.
The utensils in the kitchen are all beige,
But only the bed and curtain are gray.
Come on, that's just a coincidence.
But the beige curtains and
bedsheet are in the wardrobe here.
And the hostess of the bar said that
Munanishi-san loved the color beige.
And that she liked the Tokyo Spirits team.
She also said that Higashida-san knows a
lot about electronics, but hates to take baths.
She said that he gets really sleepy after drinking.
And she said that he's always late for work because of it.
Those things weren't recorded.
When she talked to the police earlier.
People think that if they say something irrelevant
when giving their statement, they might get told off.
So usually they only say the crucial points.
Hearing all that, I can't help
but think that bartender was nosy.
Nosy?
The second thing is why the
calender next to the bed was put away.
Look. This was taken from the closet.
This Tokyo Spirits calendar
matches the faded mark on the wall.
That's probably because the team hasn't
been doing so well recently, so she took it down.
But look here.
The game schedule is marked
down from now until December.
You're right.
Third, the fact that the furniture's been moved around...
The investigators noticed that, too.
They said she must have moved stuff around recently.
But when the wardrobe was moved, this was left under it.
It looks too important to forget
about. Don't you think that's strange?
Isn't this just an ordinary matchbox?
Open it up and see.
There's a piece of paper inside.
This is...
Muranishi-san's marriage application!
I didn't know that she planned on getting married.
But the groom's information is blank.
Yet it's been notarized already.
Fourth thing, the cacti. Since morning
it was raining on the day of the crime.
Would a woman who loved her cacti, just leave
them outside on the veranda on a day like that?
That means someone other than her...
Rearranged the room for some reason.
Oh, this must be the one.
This must be the cactus that the hostess
gave Muranishi-san the evening of the murder.
But some of the needles got broken. How sad.
But what does that prove?
That night, the suspect,
Higashida-san, mistook this as his bedroom.
And he went to sleep an the bed.
Not only the video cord, but the door lock and the chains
were covered with Higashida-san's...
Finger... Prints...
Don't tell me...
Don't tell me this bedroom...
Well, let's shall we have a look?
His apartment is in this building, right?
Let's check it out.
We don't have that much time left.
Yeah...
Let's hurry up and break in.
Into the real suspect's house.
What... What was that just now?
I heard the word... "Bomb".
Damn, we're out of time. Hurry up! Hurry up!
5...
4...
3...
2...
1!
Next Conan:
Metropolitan Police Detective Love Story 2. Part 2.
Next Conan's hint!
Cactus
Next time we finish the love story!
I can't believe Inspector Megure really...
Hey, hey!