Perceived in a flash!
Once it starts rolling, it won't stop.
Today, the Professor reveals the truth and his bomb.
Seeing through the one and only truth,
A child with the intelligence of an adult.
That name is: Detective Conan!
We went to an abandoned
building to practice for our play...
And saw Officer Sato and Takagi
chasing after a handcuffed suspect.
Although the suspect ran into an
art museum, Officer Sato caught him.
But thanks to a little accident, they were stuck there.
The suspect Higashida-san said that he was innocent.
He said he ran away so that he could make it to
his daughter's wedding, which was the next day.
Then, Officer Takagi and we, the Detective
Boys, started our search for the real suspect.
Metropolitan Police Detective Love Story 2. Part 2.
There are four weird points.
First, there's the color of the futon,
bedsheet, pillow and the curtains.
The utensils in the kitchen are all beige and aren't new,
So why is it that only the bed and curtain are gray?
Come on, that's just a coincidence.
But the beige curtains and bedsheet are in the closet there.
Secondly, for some reason, the
calendar has been taken down off the wall.
See? I got this from the closet.
The second thing is why the Tokyo
Spirits calender next to the bed was put away.
That's probably because the team has
been losing recently, so she took it down.
But, look at this.
The game schedule is marked
down from now until December.
You're right.
The third point is, all the furniture has been moved around.
The investigators noticed that, too.
They said she must have moved stuff around recently.
But when the wardrobe was moved, this was
left under it. It looks too important to forget about.
Don't you think it's strange?
Isn't this just a ordinary matchbox?
Open it up and see.
There's a piece of paper inside.
This is... Muranishi-san's marriage application!
I didn't know she planned on getting married.
But the groom's information is blank.
Yet it's been notarized already.
Fourth thing: the cacti. It was
raining on the day of the crime.
Would a woman who loved her cacti
just leave them outside on a day like that?
That means someone other than her...
Rearranged the room for some reason.
Oh, this must be the one.
This must be the cactus that the hostess
gave Muranishi-san the evening of the murder.
But some of the needles got broken. How sad.
Don't tell me...
Don't tell me this bedroom...
Well, wanna have a look?
His apartment is in this building, right?
Let's check it out.
Hey, if you kids sleep out here you'll catch a cold.
Oh, Mr. Manager.
You really surprised me. Did
you keep investigating overnight?
Yes. And thanks to you, we've solved the mystery.
Everything about it.
Thanks for your assistance.
You're welcome.
I'm just glad I was able to help.
Now, we have to figure out how to corner the culprit.
Hey, anybody here?
Hey!
Geez, this makes the fifth time we've searched.
The police just keep asking us.
But it's locked up, so how could anyone get inside?
Hey!
This lock is damaged.
What?
Um... This must be from the police game
those kids were playing with that weird guy.
We have no chance. Even though it's gonna be
bombed, we should put on a new lock just in case.
Right, what's that bomb called again?
What? You already forgot?
Tropical Rainbow!
What? You saw Takagi in Haido City?
Really?
Yes, a young couple here said they
saw someone that looked like Takagi.
How about Sato? Were they together?
Well... The one with him wasn't Sato-san.
He was with a group of kids...
Damn! Why would an officer be fooling around with kids?
That can't be him. Keep searching!
Damn it! Everyone is useless.
Sorry, Inspector Megure...
What is it, Shiratori-kun?
I'm probably way off, but...
Maybe those kids are the Detective
Boys who are always with Mouri-san.
No way!
But if that's true, and Sato-san didn't
call, that would be a good reason why.
Then, where's Sato-kun?
She was probably caught by the suspect.
I knew it.
Hey, guys. If you're sleepy, you can go on home now.
No way!
That's such a childish thing to do!
You kids...
Please let us keep helping.
Don't tell me you're gonna try
and arrest the culprit all by yourself?
I told you, that's what being a police officer is all about.
There's not much time left.
Yeah, let's hurry.
Gotta get to the real criminal's house.
Only five minutes left before the time limit.
I guess they didn't make it.
Don't cry.
Though I can't get you on the plane
in time for your daughter's wedding,
I'll make sure we catch the real
criminal and prove your innocence.
But it sure is strange. The
custodians should at least be working now.
Do you think they're off today?
It can't be. Today is Sunday.
And can't you hear it?
The sound of the customers outside.
They must be waiting in line for the art museum to open.
Oh. It's the policeman from last night.
I'm sorry about yesterday.
I already told you; I've got nothing else to say.
Yes, but I wanted to ask you about the
circumstances of when you discovered the body.
I told you already. Higashida-san and
Muranishi-san didn't come into work.
And no one answered the phone,
either. So I went to their apartments.
I rang the bell, but no one answered.
So I asked the manager to open
Muranishi-san's apartment for me.
But the door was chain-locked, and for some
reason Higashida was lying there on her bed.
I yelled at Higashida to wake him
up and asked him to unlock the chain.
Then, I entered the room with the manager.
And we found Muranishi-san dead in the bathroom.
That's it. End of story.
Wait, Kitagawa-san!
I've said all I'm gonna. So please leave.
Please let me ask you a few more questions.
What?
Don't tell me I'm a suspect now.
No, that's not what I meant.
I suspect you!
You're the culprit, aren't you?
Don't even try to lie.
If you do something bad, someone's gonna find out!
Hey, now...
Don't do it like that. We have to follow routine.
Who the hell are these little brats?
The Detective Boys!
There's no mystery we can't solve!
Umm... This is...
Geez. I don't know what's this is all
about, but give me a break, will ya?
How can I be the culprit in a situation like this?
Then, why did you change the
color of the bedsheet and curtain?
What?
You must be the one.
No one else could have replaced the beige bedsheet
and curtains at Muranishi-san's place with the gray ones.
Hey!
Cut the crap.
If you and these weird little freaks don't leave right now,
I'll sue your ass.
I just asked the department store nearby.
What?
You bought some gray futon covers, sheets, and curtain.
The cashier who checked you out remembered you.
That's because mine were old, so I bought some new ones.
And then I changed my mind, so I threw them away.
How about the calender you took down and the
cacti you moved to the balcony? That was all you, right?
Well, I don't blame you.
Higashida-san was so Anti-Spirits that if his room had
had a team calender and cacti he'd never bought before,
Even drunk like he was, he would have noticed it.
Right. So you removed everything in
Muranishi-san's bedroom that might catch his attention.
Then you changed the color of the curtain and bedding,
as well as the furniture arrangement,
making the bedroom resemble Higashida's.
After you murdered Muranishi-san,
You led a drunken
Higashida-san from the bar to her bedroom.
You created the impression that
He was in his own room.
Then you went to the door and
told Higashida-san to lock the chain.
All you had to do was make sure it was properly locked.
Then he walked back to the bed and went to sleep.
The next day, he and Muranishi-san's
body were found inside a locked room.
That's how it is.
What about the video cord?
The one found around Muranishi-san's neck.
Higashida's fingerprints should have been on it.
Haibara, how'd it go?
Huh?
Just like you thought.
One video cord is missing from the room.
You asked Higashida-san, who's
good with electronics, to help you.
Then you used that cord as a weapon.
And on the day of the crime, you took a day off work.
That afternoon, you went up to
Muranishi-san's apartment via the emergency stairs.
And used the spare key she gave you to get inside.
Then you moved the furniture and the
other items around and waited for her.
That's the evidence.
What evidence? It's ridiculous.
Show me some concrete evidence that I did it.
You don't have any, do you?
That day, I took a day off and didn't see her.
Huh? What happened, sir?
You hurt your thumb.
I wonder what that music's for?
Well, listening to music while waiting isn't too bad.
To all the guests here today.
We have a short amount of time left before we
say goodbye to our 40-year-old Haido Art Museum.
Only 10 minutes left!
Thanks for your hard work!
What... Say goodbye?
Now, please welcome our special guest.
The genius scientist,
Dr. Agasa Hiroshi, will give us a speech.
Please come up to the stage, Professor.
Thank you.
Just as he said,
I'm Agasa Hiroshi.
The "Tropical Rainbow" that I've created
Is a bomb that allows us to send
this old art museum off with a blast.
What?! What did he just say?
I'm pretty sure he said, "bomb"...
Wa-Wait... You have to be kidding me!
Hey, hey. Since you're wearing a band-aid on
your thumb, you must have hurt it somehow, right?
So what if it is?
Take these brats and get out of here.
Excuse me.
Hey, what are you doing?
I knew it.
How did you get that wound on your thumb?
Uh...
When the police examine your wound against the cacti
found at the scene of the crime, they'll know everything.
That after you killed Muranishi-san you
were the one that shifted the cacti to the balcony
It's time for you to tell the truth.
That night, the hostess at the bar
gave the cactus to Muranishi-san.
Since you swore you didn't see her,
how could the cactus carry your blood?
What'd you say? Takagi just left the crime scene?
Yes, sir. After he inspected the place, he headed to Kitagawa-san's
house, who's the person who first found the body.
Got it.
He's supposed to be chasing
the suspect. What's he up to now?
Anyway, let's go and check for ourselves.
Only three minutes left until the explosion.
The one who presses the
switch will of course be Dr. Agasa!
Hello? Hello?
Just great. The battery's dead.
How about your gun? If you
fire, someone's bound to notice.
I spent two shots on the pump,
one on the lock, and two on the door.
I fired all five rounds of them.
Why didn't you leave at least one?
Because you were running away!
Where in the world is Takagi-kun?
Huh, the phone's off.
What's with Sato-san?
It's after 10AM now.
Surely the art museum people found her by now.
Yeah. Let's hurry over there anyway.
Takagi, what are you doing?
Inspector Megure!
I found the real criminal.
Forget about that...
What? The real criminal?
Yes, sir. Kitagawa-san was being pressed
into marriage by Muranishi-san, so he killed her.
He also set a trap to make us believe his
colleague, Higashida-san, was the actual offender.
He didn't deny any of this.
Inspector, please go to the police station
now and revoke Higashida-san's charges.
Um... Sure.
So? What about Sato-san?
She's with Higashida-san inside
the Haido Art Museum right now.
Don't joke around.
By now that place is...
Huh?
It's just about time, everyone.
Come on, let's do a final countdown!
What? People are still inside the building?
That's impossible.
Hello? Hello?
What's wrong? Answer me!
Shit. There's no time! Go faster!
Faster! Faster!
Okay, ready?
10...
9...
8...
7...
6...
5...
4...
3...
2...
1!
Hey, Agasa-san!
Looks like we made it.
All right, now you're free.
Where is Takagi-kun?
He's probably...
Sato-san!
Takagi-kun!
Sato-san, I did it!
I... Sato-san...
The toilet!! Where's the toilet?
I've been holding it since last night,
and the water's cut off in that toilet.
Takagi-kun, hurry up and tell me where one is! Now!
The-There should be one right around the corner.
Sato-san.
Detective Takagi.
Yes?
Sato-san was crying, wasn't she?
Takagi...
Yes?
What did you do to Miwa-chan?
Huh? What are you saying?
Nothing...
Sato-san!!
The marriage application form
was found inside the matchbox.
It was hidden underneath the matches.
Both of them have a spare key to each other's places.
I guess Muranishi-san was waiting for
Kitagawa-san to have smoke at her place,
Use the matches and get a big surprise.
Isn't that right, Conan-kun?
So that means that Takagi-kun
Spent the whole night going over the case again.
There's no one to blame.
When the body was discovered,
All the evidence found at the scene of the crime
was deliberately planted to point at Higashida-san.
But little things started to add up, once we
decided that Higashida-san wasn't the murderer.
That's what was different.
At least, that's what Officer Takagi said.
He sure has a way with words.
Got that right.
Thank goodness.
Higashida-san got on the plane on time.
That's true.
But I got scolded big time by Inspector Megure.
"Can't you trust us?!"
Um... Can I ask you a question?
Oh?
Do you...
Have feelings for...
Inspector Megure?
Oh, no. How'd you know?
I really like him.
Is that so?
Because he's just like my father.
Eh... Your father?
Yep. My father.
My father was also a police officer.
Though he died on duty while
I was still in elementary school.
I've never been able to forget
How he had the same swagger as Inspector Megure's.
Is that so?
What now? You think I have a father complex?
No. Well, I'll go let Dad...
I mean, the Inspector, get mad at me, then.
The day after that, the art museum
was finally blown up in a heroic blast.
The Tropical Rainbow was a big hit.
And our class play changed
from Kamen Yaiba into a police story.
Father!!
What a terrible incident.
This is the tragedy that happens
between a loving father and daughter.
Father!!
That's how I'd end up if Ran ever found out my secret.
Cause of death?
Seems to be from a scratch on
the ear done with a poisoned pin.
Oh.
I get it.
That's how you could establish
an alibi and murder Kiyoumi-san.
Next Conan:
The Silent Kanjo Line.
Next Conan's hint!
Pink ballpoint pen
The next stage is the Kanjo train line in Yamanote.
What? A lymph node?