A BAARO FANSUB
"Pull!"
As bright as a spark,
with a penetratingly precise wit.
Once he gets started, you can't stop him!
Today, we visit a five-story pagoda
deep in the mountains.
Its legendary power leads to an impossible crime!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
The Terrifying Legend of the Five-Story Pagoda
(Part 1)
Izu, Shizuoka Prefecture
Genkai Temple Gate
This is so beautiful! This is a great change.
Yeah, and it's all thanks to you for winning this prize in the contest.
But you're the one who solved the puzzle, Conan-kun.
It was unbelievably easy.
Dad!
Let's go!
I hate it here—this place is just depressing!
These free trips are really lousy!
What are you on about?
You're the one who got all excited when you first heard about this free trip!
Go on without me.
I'll just go to back to the hotel and soak in the bath.
Excuse me, but smoking isn't allowed on temple grounds.
Shigekichi Okabe (55)
Temple Employee
Oh, sorry.
My apologies.
No worries.
Still, it's true this place might be somewhat boring for tourists.
That's not true! You don't see sights like this in the city.
It cleanses my soul.
How nice of you. You're young, but admirable.
If you want, I can give you a tour of the temple.
Really? Could you?
I'll pass.
Don't be rude, Dad!
Let's go!
This temple was built 400 years ago.
400 years ago? It's very old.
Due to its age, there are many historical sites here.
For example, an old well near the pagoda was used well until the middle of the Edo period.
What made them stop using it?
It suddenly went dry.
Legend says that a young heartbroken woman cried for three days in front of the well,
and when her tears dried, the water in the well filled her eyes and dried.
Man, talk about nonsense...
There's a frightening legend behind this pagoda.
What legend?
In the beginning of the Edo period,
there was a young monk
who the head priest picked as his successor for this temple, but...
He fell in love with a girl from the village, broke his vows, left the temple, and ran away to marry her.
But supposedly due to a curse, the monk was taken away by a goshawk
and was found dead later on, hanging from the pagoda.
How horrible!
There's more. Midway through the Edo period,
a ruthless priest sold the temple's furniture to have money and used the money for liquor.
One day, he disappeared.
A few days later, he was found dead,
hanging from the pagoda.
Since then, it's been said that anyone who breaks the temple's vows will be cursed.
Hey, don't make that scary face.
A ghost!
Tankai-sama!
Don't be scared. He's the head priest.
The head priest?
So you're bringing a family here now? What are you looking for this time?!
Tankai (64)
Genkai Temple Head Priest
Please, wait. They're just tourists.
They look suspicious. I don't trust them!
Don't bring strangers here without my permission!
But the tourists are what make the temple...
Nonsense!
Remember that people will desecrate the temple for that very reason!
But that's...
But soon, punishment shall befall the unbeliever...
The punishment of the temple's curse.
Umm, did something happen?
To be honest, a tour company took over this property
and they want to build a theme park.
KEEP OUT
Then the area's going to change?
Yes.
Yes. The head priest is opposing it, saying he was tricked.
He's bitter even towards tourists now.
But he has some nerve, scaring people like that!
Let's get out of here.
Wait, Dad!
Sorry, my dad's a bit short-tempered...
Don't apologise, it's all my fault...
By the way, your father wouldn't happen to be Kogoro Mouri-san?
Yeah, he's a detective...
Oh! As I figured, he's that famous great detective!
Now I have a nice story to tell my grandson!
It's an honor. Thank you for inviting us to dinner.
The honor is ours.
Yosuke Kajimura (43)
Oda Tours Director
Hotel Oda Manager
Our hotel just opened, so having a famous person such as yourself staying here is great publicity.
I'm at your service if I'm needed!
You certainly have a beautiful hotel here!
Hideaki Oda (56)
President of Oda Tours
You like it?
The theme park that I proposed building will be finished next year.
This place will become even more enjoyable!
Really? It must be costing you a lot of money.
Yes, well, about 8 billion yen.
But once it's finished,  I'm expecting to make over 10 billion yen annually.
Amazing...
Oh, I apologise for my rudeness.
I am the hotel's general manager.
Don't be impertinent, Kajimura!
You were careless. How did you not realize that the great detective Kogoro Mouri-san
was staying here until Okabe told you?!
I hope you learn from this.
Yes. I'm terribly sorry.
Weren't you going to Tokyo tonight on a business trip?
Should you really be wasting time here?
Right.
Well then, Mouri-sama, please enjoy your stay.
He's totally useless.
Oh, sorry. I sometimes forget myself.
You were pretty harsh...
I always get like that when it comes to business.
Is that a diamond on your tie pin?
Oh, that's no big deal.
It's only about five carats.
Five carats? It's huge!
Stop it, Dad! You're embarassing me!
Don't worry, young lady.
Your father's just acting naturally.
That's natural?
Sir, your cigar.
Hey! Where's the receipt?
Sorry!
Geez. I can write it off as company expenses.
Do you always carry so much money with you?
This? This is just petty change.
I hate credit cards.
Shunkai (26)
Tankai's Son
Look at yourself, enjoying a meal...
You're a disgrace.
If it isn't the heir to the Genkai Temple.
Did you finish your training at the head temple yet?
My father's ignorant about financial affairs, so you managed to deceive him.
But you won't get away with this!
I came back to the temple to make sure of that!
Hey, hey, watch what you're saying.
You and my father have carefully discussed the subject.
Enough!
You told my father he should sign over the temple's deed to Oda Tours temporarily
to raise funds for the preservation of the temple's environment.
He trusted your advice!
But now he's ready to take you to court!
Is that all you have to say?
What?
I'm entertaining my guests right now.
If you want to tell me anything else, come to my office tomorrow.
If you think this is the last you'll hear of me, you're sadly mistaken.
Let me go!
Sorry for the interruptions. This place is like a mad house.
So you're having problems with the people at the temple?
It's nothing.
They're suspicious of the development plans,
and some of them are protesting, saying we'll destroy the temple's atmosphere and whatnot.
They're going to gain from the tourism business too,
but they're a bunch of idiots.
Ran-neechan, didn't they say a curse would fall on those who harm the temple?
This isn't the time for that!
I already know about that legend.
Many people warned me about it.
But that can be used to draw in tourists, too.
It's a matter of how one looks at things.
This guy's a shark...
Yes, Mouri Detective Agency...
It's me, Okabe! I'm the one who showed you around the temple yesterday!
It's terrible! The curse, it came true!
What? The curse?
Please come to the temple, right away!
Hey, hold on!
Mouri-sensei! This way, hurry!
Hold on! I want an explanation!
The terrifying curse came true!
What curse? He's just reciting the morning prayers.
Chōka (Morning Prayers)
Not that. Look over there!
Oda-san was...!
It's the curse!
The crime lab's done with their investigation,
so the corpse is going to be lowered now.
Detective Yokomizo
Shizuoka Prefectural Police
How does it look?
The victim was found with the rope tied to the railing on one end,
and the other end was swung around the edge of the roof and around his neck.
He was tentatively identified as Hideaki Oda, the manager of a tourism company.
A private detective who knew him is going up to make a positive ID.
A detective? Who is he?
It's me, Detective Yokomizo.
It's Mouri-san himself! It's been a while.
What are you doing here?
I just happened to be here.
To get straight to the point, what do you think of this case?
From the evidence, it looks like a suicide, but...
Well, the circunstances are strange, but it's definitely not murder.
What makes you say that?
First, Oda-san must have weighed about 100 kg.
He is very heavy,
so a normal person wouldn't be able to carry him all the way up there!
And even if the killer managed to carry him up,
the stairwell is too narrow for more than one adult to pass.
It would be possible to drag him up, but in that case, his clothes would get torn,
and the body would get bruised.
And I didn't notice any of those just now.
I see. You deduced quite a lot already!
But why would he have chosen this place?
A little bit more, a little bit more!
Okay, stop.
This mark is fresh. How did it get here?
The rope's new, but it's frayed in some spots...
What?
Hey...
How are we getting him down? He doesn't reach the railing!
That's impossible.
If his feet can't reach the railing, then...
Hey, what are you doing here, kid? Get down!
I was looking for the toilet, and got lost... Looks like it's not here.
How strange. Where could it be?
Who's the kid?
Beats me.
According to the crime lab,
there wasn't much dust inside the pagoda,
so they couldn't find the victim's footprints.
We had the town doctor do an autopsy, and he didn't find any external injuries.
The cause of death was thus determined to be suffocation due to pressure on the neck.
Therefore, he died from being hung here...
The estimated time of death is between 3 and 4 AM.
Mr. Oda was using a suite in his hotel as an office and home,
but the receptionist says he saw Mr. Oda exit the building at about 2:30 AM.
Judging by the time, I think it's safe to assume he came straight here.
Any will?
We haven't found any yet.
President!
President, why did you kill yourself?
You should have waited a little more. Just a little more...
Excuse me, but who are you?
I'm Hotel Oda's general manager.
My name is Kajimura.
It seems you weren't here last night?
Indeed. I had a sudden business trip.
Do you know any reason why he'd commit suicide?
The truth is, the purpose of my business trip was to raise funds.
If I failed, the checks the company wrote this month would bounce.
I wasn't the only one—the president was worried about it, too...
But he was carrying a lot of money last night...
The president was a very proud man, so he would never show weakness to anyone.
He kept putting on a bold front.
But yesterday, when the temple people threatened to take him to court,
he looked extremely worried.
Oh?
He doesn't have his wallet!
The wallet?
We didn't find any in his possession.
Doesn't it look weird to you?
If Oda-san didn't change his clothes after he had dinner with us,
why did the wallet that he carried last night disappear?
Idiot! Who would have thought of going out with so much money when committing suicide?
Stop butting your nose around the scene. I keep having to tell you this!
But his tie pin's gone, too!
Are you okay? You can't interfere with the police work...
Mouri-san, what did he mean about the pin?
Oda-san had one on last night.
It was a five-carat diamond tie pin that really stood out.
Well, it would appear that it's gone missing.
Which means he could've been robbed!
Well, even if he was robbed,
he was on his way to commit suicide, so he'd probably give up his possessions easily.
So this doesn't disprove the suicide theory.
If he'd been strangled,
he'd have struggled trying to free himself, and scratch his own throat with his fingernails.
But there are no traces of that!
And even if this was a murder,
how would the killer be able to hang the victim from the pagoda?
Aside from suicide, it's physically impossible!
Well, if there was a killer here,
then it'd be that curse.
It is the curse!
Heaven punished the unbeliever!
I am Detective Yokomizo of the Shizuoka Prefectural Police.
May I ask who you are?
Isn't it obvious?
I'm this temple's head priest, Tankai.
I am his son, Shunkai.
I'm Okabe, a temple employee.
Can you all tell me where you were and what you were doing yesterday between 3 and 4 AM?
What do you mean?
Wasn't this a suicide?
We haven't come to any conclusion yet.
And since some of Oda-san's valuables are missing...
What?!
Are you accusing us, servants of Buddha, of being vulgar thieves?!
No, of course not, but we need your alibis for our records...
You'd probably like it if I said I was meeting with that no-good liar,
but I was in the main hall chanting at the time.
Chanting? You were chanting at night?
I had a premonition that the curse would come true.
The... curse?
What about you, Shunkai-san?
I was asleep—I got up at 5.
Then Okabe came to tell me that Oda was dead.
I was so shocked that I called Mouri-sensei right away.
I see. Why did you call Mouri-san first instead of the police?
This man is Oda's spy.
He's the one who introduced me to Oda in the first place.
Tankai-sama, Oda told me he wanted to help the temple by increasing tourists!
He... He lied to me too!
You too?
It looks like he fooled the head priest here and got the temple's deed.
So three people hated Oda-san!
So what if we did?
That private detective just said you can't disprove the suicide theory.
And if it's a suicide, then there's no killer, is there?
We haven't concluded it as a suicide yet...
Then make a decision already, and get off my property!
I can't stand having these sacred grounds trampled by those who are impure!
Oda-san's wallet and tie pin are indeed missing,
but everything seems to be pointing to a suicide.
But something doesn't fit.
His elbow's dirty.
Grass? Did he fall and hit his elbow?
There's dirt on his heels!
Why would there be dirt there?
Hold on!
If you look closer, you can see the rope is charred!
Maybe...
Found it! There's his tie pin!
Now I'm sure.
This is the true crime scene!
If my deduction is right, then Oda-san didn't kill himself, he was murdered!
And the one who did it was him, the one who said that back then!
NEXT EPISODE
How could that be?
If he stood on the railing and his neck didn't reach the rope, then he couldn't have committed suicide!
Let's just say for the sake of argument that it was a murder.
How would the killer hang him with a rope that was 50 cm too short?
You're right!
This side was tied to the railing...
But why did the killer use an artillery loop?
Next Conan:
The Terrifying Legend of the Five-Story Pagoda
(Part 2)
Next Conan's Hint: Wallet!
Look forward to the next episode!
Next time, it's part two!
The truth behind the legend might be even scarier!
Please, no...