As bright as a spark,
with a penetratingly precise wit.
Once he gets started, you can't stop him!
Today we solve the mystery of the legend!
The trick and the evidence
are beyond your imagination!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
We came to an old temple with a five-story pagoda while on vacation.
But development of a tourist attraction has brought trouble with the tour company.
And the next morning, the president of the tour company, Hideaki Oda,
was found hanging from the pagoda.
Exactly like the legend surrounding the pagoda...
It's the curse!
Now I'm sure.
This is the true crime scene!
If my deduction is right,
then Oda-san didn't kill himself.
He was murdered!
And the one who did it was him,
the one who said that back then!
Hey! What are you doing here?!
Isn't that tie pin over there Oda-san's?
What?
How about it, Mouri-san? Is it Oda-san's tie pin?
Yes, most likely. Tie pins with diamonds aren't very common.
Kajimura-san, I'd like you to look at this too.
Yosuke Kajimura (43)
Oda Tours Director
Hotel Oda Manager
Yes, there's no mistake.
This belongs to the president.
There, you see?! And you accused us of being thieves!
Tankai (64)
Genkai Temple Head Priest
Jukichi Okabe (55)
Temple Employee
Shunkai (26)
Tankai's Son
His wallet is probably around here somewhere too...
How about doing a thorough search?
Now we know Oda-san wasn't robbed.
His tie pin probably fell when he hanged himself.
But Mouri-san, the pagoda's over 10 meters from here.
Don't you think it's a bit too far to fall?
It could've happened like this.
Oda-san was deciding whether
to kill himself here or not,
and he didn't realize it fell off.
But tie pins don't fall off so easily!
Excuse me!
There was a grass stain on Oda-san's elbow.
So what?
Wasn't the tie pin found here?
That's it! So the stain's from the grass around here!
Mouri-san, I'm positive Oda-san struggled with someone here and fell!
And another thing...
When they were taking the body down,
the rope was too short,
and Oda-san's feet didn't reach the railing.
Hey, men!
When you were lowering the body,
did his feet reach the railing?
No, sir! It was about 50 centimeters short!
How can it be?
If he stood on the railing and
his neck didn't reach the rope,
he couldn't have committed suicide!
Mouri-san! How do you explain this?
Don't worry about it. It doesn't mean a thing.
What do you mean?
After a lot of deliberation, Oda-san
climbed the pagoda to kill himself.
The rope may have been 50 centimeters
short, but there was no turning back!
In other words, he jumped to the rope
and put it over his head!
But there are so many circumstances
indicating it was murder!
Let's just say for the sake of
argument that it was a murder.
The killer would have to carry
the hefty, unconscious Oda-san
up the narrow stairway, only wide enough for one person, and drag the body!
But there was no indication of this
on either the body or the pagoda!
And how would the killer hang Oda-san
with a rope that was 50 cm too short?
That's true!
The murder theory is starting
to sound far-fetched...
That's right!
Unless it was suicide, there's no way
he could've hung from the pagoda!
It looks like you're showing
everyone how foolish you are!
You're nothing but a mere human.
You'll never be able to solve
the mysteries of heaven's wrath!
Give up and leave this place at once!
It's true, there are many unanswered questions...
but there's not enough evidence to prove
this was a murder made to look like a suicide.
But this is definitely murder.
The problem is, how did the killer
hang him from the roof of the pagoda?
Unless I can solve this trick,
this case will be classified as a suicide!
This side was tied to the railing.
But why did the killer use an artillery loop?
That's it!
That's how he did it!
The fog is finally starting to clear!
Using this method, it's possible to tie the rope to the railing!
Hey, kid! You're not supposed to touch the things around here!
I'm sorry!
If my theory is correct, then that thing should be around here.
There it is!
With this method, Oda-san's death
can be made to look like suicide!
There's a fresh scratch on it.
Curse, you say?
You thought up one fantastic trick,
using the legend as your guide!
But now for the evidence!
I've got to find proof he's the murderer!
This was a strange suicide, but it's settled now!
Are you sure?
Something about it still bothers me.
Why are you so stubborn?
Fine, go ahead and write on your report, "Death by Curse".
Y-You've got to be kidding!
If I do that, I'll be mocked to death!
Excuse me...
Would it be all right if I returned to the hotel now?
I'm sure the employees are shaken up by this...
Let's see... I suppose it'll be all right.
But to be on the safe side,
give me your contact number.
I'll be at the hotel, so...
Look at all that money!
Thank you very much, boy.
Here, you can reach me here.
I'll do that.
Kajimura-san, you sure have a lot of money on you.
It couldn't be Oda-san's, could it?
Of course not! His wallet is a different color!
This money is for the payment I have to
make to one of the hotel's suppliers today!
It was just a joke, a joke!
You scared me.
Hey! Now that Oda's dead, the plans for
that theme park are dead too, aren't they?
Y-Yeah. If construction isn't stopped right
away, our company will go bankrupt.
I'm sure the deed to the temple
will be returned to you.
What? Really?!
Yes. The president gave me
the deed to hold on to.
I think it's best if I gave it back to you now...
Isn't that wonderful, Tankai-sama?
Kajimura-san, you're a very understanding man.
I was wrong about you!
That's very flattering...
As for the deed, I'm sure it was just a
misunderstanding between the two of you.
In lieu of Oda's last act of generosity,
I will recite a prayer for him.
Now that my mind's at ease, I can go back
to the head temple and resume training.
If I leave now, I'll get there by evening.
I'll start cleaning the pagoda.
I've found it!
The undeniable, solid proof!
He's the murderer after all!
Detective Yokomizo...
What do we do now?
M-Mouri-san...
This is definitely a suicide.
Yes, I see... Since you're so sure about it...
I was forced out of bed so early this morning. I'm so tired...
I'm going to the hotel and getting some sleep.
Huh? I'm so sleepy all of a sudden...
Now to put this button speaker
on the old man's forehead.
I have no choice.
Alright, this is a suicide case!
We're going back to the station!
Just one moment!
Detective Yokomizo, you are absolutely hopeless.
A-Are you talking about me?
You were being given so many hints,
didn't you realize that?
This was no suicide, it was a murder!
I knew it!
But Mouri-san, why didn't you tell us earlier?
Because I wanted you to
solve it and get the credit!
I didn't realize that...
Forgive me for being so dense!
It's okay.
Now I want you to pay close attention
to my mystery-solving show.
Now, Detective Yokomizo,
I would like to conduct an experiment.
May I enlist the aid of your officers?
Of course you may!
Men! Get ready!
Yes, sir!
First, we'll put a bag weighing
the same as Oda-san on the grass.
Tie a rope around the neck of the bag,
take the rope up to the fifth tier of the pagoda
and drape it over the edge of the roof.
Then you pass it through the railing
until it reaches the ground,
and tie it to the scrap metal
left on the old unused well.
And to make one side of the
scrap metal easier to drop,
it is placed atop a steel rod.
Here you are!
Now, Detective Yokomizo,
pull hard on that string!
I-It's hanging! Just like Oda-san was!
What do you think?
This is the identity of your so-called curse!
The rope was charred because it rubbed
against the edge of the roof, causing friction!
Although the rope was brand-new,
it was frayed because of the friction!
And since we found the tie pin
over there in the grass,
I assume that's where it happened!
But how did the killer get the
rope around Oda-san's neck?
Oda-san would have put up a fight,
but examination of the body
showed no such marks!
Yes. That's a very good question.
Let me explain things in the order they happened.
First, the killer called Oda-san to meet him here.
Then, when he saw the opportunity,
he put the noose around Oda-san's neck,
and pulled the string at the same time,
dropping the scrap metal into the well.
Before Oda-san was pulled up,
the rope around his neck would come off,
so the killer grabbed his legs, causing him to fall.
Since it was dark, even a slim man
would be able to topple a large man
like Oda-san who's caught off his guard.
That's when the grass stain got on his elbow.
That's also when the tie pin fell.
Oda-san had no time to undo the rope, and was pulled up.
I'm positive Oda-san was tripped.
Otherwise, there's no way he'd get dirt on the heels of his shoes.
I get it!
No...
Wait a minute, Mouri-san!
Are you saying more than one killer was involved?
It seems you've come across that dilemma, Detective Yokomizo.
After all, Oda-san is a heavy 100 kg!
If the killer tried to tie the rope
to the railing all by himself,
he wouldn't be able to wind the rope
around his hand—only squeeze it!
The moment the rope was cut,
it would be pulled out of his hand!
It's not possible for him to tie the rope to the railing all by himself!
Oh, but it is possible.
Even if the killer was alone.
That's ridiculous!
Exactly how was it done?
The killer used an artillery loop on the railing.
Artillery loop?
It makes a loop with the rope.
I've given instructions to the officer on the pagoda. Have him start.
Hey! Cut the rope and tie it to the railing!
Yes, sir!
First, he needs to pull the artillery loop in.
Then, pass a stick into the loop,
making a stopper.
Then cut the rope on the outside,
pull the cut end through the loop and tie it.
Pull the stick and the ruse is complete!
Detective Yokomizo!
The rope is tied to the railing!
He did it all by himself...
All that remains is to collect
the rope that has fallen,
and throw it into the old well!
And this ends my explanation of how
a legend was used to cover up a murder.
The only mistake the killer made
was the 50 cm difference between
Oda-san's feet and the railing,
because that's what made me
suspect it wasn't suicide.
The only one capable of rigging all of this...
is someone who is familiar with the temple!
Hold on there! Are you insinuating
that one of us is the killer?!
That's right.
The man who used this trick and killed Oda-san...
is you, Kajimura-san!
W-What are you talking about, Mouri-san?!
I don't know very much about this temple!
You are the general manager of the Hotel Oda,
but you are also an executive of Oda Tours.
It's easy for you to get the blueprint to this
place—just say it's for the construction.
You calculated the height of the pagoda,
the distance to the well and its depth.
And wasn't it you who told the construction
workers to put the scrap metal near the well?
So you could use it in your scheme.
Y-Yes, I may have given the orders!
But if I did, it was due to
some work-related matter!
Mouri-san, you too are aware that I was on
a business trip last night. I wasn't even here!
Then how did you know about Shunkai-san
and Oda-san's argument last night?
When you came here today, you said:
But last night, when you threatened to
take him to court, he seemed very upset.
Shunkai-san came back last
night right after you left.
But how did you know about that?
W-Well...
I had a call.
The president called me on my
mobile phone at the hotel in Tokyo...
No, you're lying!
You heard their conversation
right here on these grounds!
When you called Oda-san to meet
you here so you could kill him!
Enough of this foolishness!
All you have are accusations! Show me
some proof that I was here last night!
You have the evidence on you!
Irrefutable evidence!
A-Are you sure, Mouri-san?
Yes. Look inside his wallet.
May I?
If you're talking about the
president's fingerprints on the bills,
that won't be proof—
he gave me the money himself!
Mouri-san, what am I looking for?
It should be stuck between the bills...
A receipt.
A receipt?
Let's see... It's a receipt from the Hotel Oda...
September 12, 7:40 PM, for cigars.
That's right. We saw Oda-san get that receipt
last night while we were having dinner!
You left after that, and if you
hadn't seen him since then,
tell us, how did the receipt
Oda-san got end up in your wallet?
I'm pretty sure that after you killed Oda-san,
you saw his wallet lying in the grass,
so you kept the money as cash earned.
But you didn't notice the receipt
stuck between the bills!
If you check the receipt,
you'll find Oda-san's fingerprints on it!
What have you got to say, Kajimura-san?!
Are you still going to deny it?!
How stupid. What a silly thing to get caught by.
What was your motive?
Tax evasion.
When the company began
having financial difficulties,
he told me to file a fake financial report.
Sure, I profited from the scheme too.
But then I realized he was only letting me profit
because he eventually intended to
make me take the fall for everything...
So you killed him.
Yes.
Before he chopped me off like some lizard's tail,
after I'd worked myself
to the bone for the company...
What a bummer. I thought we
were going to enjoy ourselves.
Why is it that every time you're with us,
Dad, we get involved in a case?
How would I know?
Dad, maybe you're cursed?
The temple's right here—
why don't we have you exorcised?
T-That's stupid! I'm a private detective!
I'm supposed to be involved
with cases! That's what feeds us!
Trouble is my business!
Cases are supposed to follow
a famous detective around!
Dad!
He's right, he's never lacking trouble...
W-What is this?!
If the killer came in through the waterway...
then the room should be sopping wet!
I see! So that's why that person did that!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Blowfish milt
The next episode's stage is Ryusui-tei!
A restaurant that sells nagashi somen?
Huh?