As bright as a spark,
with a penetratingly precise wit.
Once he gets started, you can't stop him!
Today's setting is a strange restaurant!
A crime flows in on the water!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Created by
Gosho Aoyama
"Detective Conan"
Serialized in Shogakukan's
"Weekly Shonen Sunday"
Planning
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Character Design
Masatomo Sudo
Art Director
Yukihiro Shibutani
Art Design
Hiroyuki Mitsumoto
Director of Photography
Takehisa Ogawa
Sound Director
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
Music Producer
Hiroki Horio
(PolyGram)
Music
Katsuo Ono
Opening Theme
"giri-giri chop"
Performed by
Lyrics
Music
Arrangement
Koshi Inaba
Tak Matsumoto
Tak Matsumoto & Koshi Inaba
(Rooms Records)
Editor
Teramitsu Okada
Story Editor
Junichi Iioka
Color Key
Reiko Hirayama
Executive Producer
Hiroaki Kobayashi
Planning Support
Toyohiko Okuyama
Mitome Asai
Chief Director
Kenji Kodama
Director
Yasuichiro Yamamoto
Producers
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Masahito Yoshioka
(Tokyo Movie)
Ryusui-tei
("The Flowing Water Pavilion")
Geez. It's still 30 minutes until our reservation!
But this is a very popular place. If we're late, they'll cancel our reservation.
I'm tired of waiting and I'm getting hungry.
Alright, #4, sake is ready!
Got it!
OK!
A restaurant where the food is served by boat...
No wonder it's popular.
Do you like it?
There's a bigger boat too.
What happens to the boat once it gets to the room?
Kyoko Anzai
Cashier
The customer takes the dishes off the boat,
then pushes a button in the room and it goes back automatically.
That's neat!
Excuse me.
Yes?
We have reservations.
Kaneda-sama, you reserved room 8, right?
Hey, Kaneda...
Keizo Kaneda (29)
Jomon University
Assistant Professor of Physics
Ryuichi Arai (29)
Jomon University
Physics Instructor
Not me... There must be a mistake!
Hey! Kaneda-kun and Arai-kun!
You're late! I was getting tired of waiting.
Sorry. Kaneda was late.
Go on, apologize.
This wasn't my idea.
Come on! This is to celebrate your promotion to assistant professor,
the Professor's treat!
Just because we were hired the same time doesn't mean we're friends!
Starting today, address me as Assistant Professor Kaneda, understand?!
And you're my assistant, Arai-kun.
Out of my way.
You, what's the most expensive dish you have?
It's...blowfish milt...
Then bring us three of those.
You don't mind, do you, Professor?
Uh, no, it's fine with me!
Nobuo Iwama (48)
Jomon University
Physics Professor
Tonight's your night...
We'll have three orders of blowfish milt.
Yes, right away.
Let's go inside.
Did you see that? That Kaneda's a real stinker.
I wonder why Prof. Iwama always orders so much food?
Maybe he likes a full table.
But he usually leaves without eating much.
I'm dying of hunger!
Those men are next door...
Here it comes!
What a huge boat!
Look at the food! I won't be able to...
Drat. It wasn't ours.
Professor, this is a lot of food!
It's a celebration.
By the way, I wonder what's keeping Kaneda.
He probably went to the john. He'll be back soon.
"Room 2"
Delicious!
Conan-kun, do you like the sashimi?
Hey, where'd it go?
I dropped my contact lens!
Oh no, now I've done it!
Ah, there it is. What a relief.
7:50 PM
For a professor, he's quite a scatterbrain...
8:00 PM
Boy, that was the best!
If there were geisha here, it'd be heaven!
Geez, Dad!
There's a child present, you know.
It was just a joke, a joke.
Huh?
Hey, Ran, we're out of sake!
Order me another!
One is enough!
We're going to have a delicious dinner now!
It's not just her personality.
Now she's even beginning to sound like her mother Eri.
Somebody come quick!
What's going on?
What happened?
T-The customer...
That's...!
Kaneda-kun!
He's dead.
This is a murder! Notify the police at once!
R-Right!
Prof. Iwama! What happened?
K-Kaneda-kun is dead in this room!
Everyone, there's just been a murder!
Until the police arrive, nobody is to leave their room!
The police will probably want to question everyone,
so your cooperation will be appreciated!
Since he fell at this angle,
I guess Kaneda-san, who was sitting at the far end of the table,
greeted the killer, and was stabbed in the chest while facing him.
Then he fell onto the table.
If the killer came here by the waterway,
this room should be sopping wet.
But it's not.
What is this black stuff on his thumb?
This smell is...!
How many times do I have to tell you not to wander around the crime scene?!
The victim is Keizo Kaneda-san, age 29,
assistant professor of physics at Jomon University.
He was stabbed through the heart with a dagger and died instantly.
The estimated time of death is 7:50 PM.
Also, we have confirmed the alibis of all the restaurant employees.
This is Prof. Iwama, and Mr. Arai is an instructor.
Both men work with the victim at the university.
We were celebrating Kaneda-kun's promotion to assistant professor tonight.
I thought he was in the bathroom.
Who would've thought something like this was possible...
And a certain party just happened to be on the scene.
Yes! The famous private detective, Kogoro Mouri, is here, Inspector!
Anyway, Kyoko Anzai-san, you were the first to discover the body?
Yes.
The customer went into the room, but never placed an order,
so I went in to check on him, and that's how I found him.
But why was he in Room 8?
Didn't he say he didn't make that reservation?
That's why I called out to him when he started to head for that room.
But he said he was meeting someone there.
So he was meeting someone secretly...
That person must have killed him.
Did you see anyone other than Kaneda-san enter the room?
No, no one...
You're positive?
Yes. I was standing at the register and looking out at the garden.
The front door is the only entrance,
and everyone has to cross the bridge to get to their rooms.
Then how did the killer get into the room?
Inspector, from the waterway!
It was designed to go past each room,
so you can get to the room by using it!
I see. So you're saying this is an inside job.
Alright, Takagi-kun!
Ask all the customers if they saw someone using the waterway.
Yes, sir!
"Room 4"
We were looking at the waterway a lot,
but we didn't see anyone on it.
"Room 5"
No, no one like that.
I didn't see anyone either.
"Room 6"
No idea.
No one went by.
"Room 7"
If anyone went by, we would've noticed.
Only boats went by.
No one saw anything?!
No. All the other rooms were parties of 4 or more,
but no one saw anything other than boats go past.
Maybe the killer went underwater?
No. The water's only about 50 cm deep.
It's not possible to swim underwater.
Besides, if the killer went underwater, the room would be sopping wet.
Did you say something?
Just talking to myself...
Either way, since coming in from the outside is impossible,
it must be an inside job.
We've got to confirm everyone's alibi.
Iwama-san, where were you at about 7:50?
I never left our room, Room 3.
Isn't that about the time you were shouting?
Yes, that's right!
When I was looking for my contact lens, I knocked some dishes over.
After that, I saw the screen close in your room,
so your alibi is solid.
Arai-san, you came back to the restaurant after the murder.
After Kaneda left,
the professor asked me to buy him a pack of cigarettes,
so I went to the convenience store.
Um, I told him where to go.
We didn't have the brand he wanted at our register.
It took me about 10 minutes to walk there.
I have a receipt.
The time on the receipt is 7:52 PM.
Which means these two men have perfect alibis!
The killer must be one of the other customers!
No.
With the other parties of 4 or more,
the killer would have to fool the others and Anzai-san to get to that room, so it's impossible.
These two are the only ones who were able to be alone
and commit the crime.
Takagi-kun!
Let's split up and verify the other customers' alibis.
Understood.
Hey, miss, I want to see the boats.
Not now, Conan-kun! It's a bad time.
It's all right. I have nothing to do now.
Thank you so much.
See, this is it.
Is the door always locked?
Yes, that's right.
We don't want just anyone going in and out of here.
I'm the only employee with a key!
Here we are, go on...
5 boats altogether...
And one of them is huge...
This is the same stuff that was on Kaneda-san's finger!
But he wasn't there when the food got to their room.
Was the whiskey and ice on this boat just now?
Yes.
The reservation specifically stated the big boat was to be used.
The food was to be served at 7:30 and the whiskey at 8:00.
A small motor and sensor.
There's a lot of space inside.
So all that's left is the alibi.
Thanks, miss!
"Room 3"
Huh?
There's one wrapper missing...
This is...
I see!
So that's why that person did that.
I found it! A tiny hole and a wet spot...
That person's alibi has just been broken!
On top of that, I've got undeniable evidence!
Hey, Uncle...
Go away! You're bothering me!
I found something really weird.
Something weird?
What? I can't hear you!
Inspector, all the customers in Room 7 have alibis.
Er, how much longer do we have to stay?
Yes, you're right...
I suppose you two can go.
No. It's too early.
Actually, I know how the killer got to Room 8.
You do?!
Why don't you explain?
We were right. The killer did use the waterway.
Come on now.
Er, Mouri-san, all the witnesses agree that there were only boats on the waterway.
That's right. The killer used a boat.
A boat?
A small person could hide in the big boat. There is enough room.
First, the killer requested the large boat be used to serve their complete meal.
He takes the food off, removes the boards, and gets in.
The boat returns to the dock by sensor.
Before it gets there, he uses his foot to turn off the sensor.
The boat's motor shuts off,
and it reaches Room 8.
Kaneda-san must have been really surprised at first!
But he wasn't worried.
After all, he would never suspect
a friend would come to kill him.
The killer used this element of surprise...
and killed him.
Then, so that no one would think
he came in through the waterway,
the killer made Kaneda-san face the doorway.
I-I see.
But then, how did the killer
get back to his own room?
It's simple.
He got back into the boat and switched the sensor back on.
The boat automatically goes back to the dock.
All he has to do now is wait.
As directed, the boat would carry their drinks to the room at 8:00.
But unfortunately for the killer,
I noticed something.
W-What was that?
The waterline.
There was only that whiskey set on the boat.
yet the waterline was extremely high.
What it proves is that the killer had been in the boat.
W-Wait a minute...
The only one who could have remained in the room alone and who was a friend...
That's right.
The killer is Prof. Iwama!
It could only have been you!
P-Professor?!
You probably told Kaneda-san
that you wanted to speak to him
in private in another room
and had him reserve Room 8.
When the food arrived, you sent
Arai-san out to buy your cigarettes,
deliberately asking for a brand
they don't sell at the register
so that he'd have to go to a convenience store.
Hold it right there, Mouri-san!
You yourself testified that I was in
Room 3 at the time of the crime!
With that alibi, how could
I have killed Kaneda-kun?!
You have a tape recorder, don't you?
Of course I do! It's a small one I carry around in my bag for meetings!
Even if I could use it to tape voices and sounds,
how would I close the sliding door?
How about by using a rubber band, a pin, a chopstick wrapper and ice?
First, you used the pin to attach the rubber band to the sliding door and its frame.
Then you stuffed the chopstick wrapper into the sliding door on the other side,
and pinned one end down.
Then you pulled the door with the rubber band attached to the wrapper
and pinned it through the wrapper.
For the finishing touch, you took ice from the food
and put it on the wrapper circle.
The ice melted, making the paper wrapper soft, and when it broke,
the rubber band snapped back
and closed the door!
I-I see!
When you returned to the room, Iwama-san,
you got rid of the rubber band and pins and erased the tape.
And if you threw the wrapper into the waterway,
there'd be no evidence left.
That's right, there's no evidence!
If you're accusing me of killing Kaneda-kun,
show me the proof, the proof!
Arai-san.
When you took the food off the boat,
did you spill the sauce for the blowfish milt?
Y-Yes, I did.
On the boat's boards...
Iwama-san.
When Anzai-san screamed and you came out of the room,
you had your jacket on, didn't you?
No one would bother to put their jacket on in an emergency.
But you did, because the sauce got on your shirt when you got into the boat, isn't that right?
Iwama-san. Will you remove your jacket?
I do have a sauce stain on it.
But I got it when I spilled the sauce while looking for my contact lens!
Did you really?
Kaneda-san left the room before the food arrived,
but he had some sauce on his thumb.
I wonder when he got it...?
I-It can't be!
That's right.
When you stabbed him, he grabbed you there!
Right on that stain on your shirt!
Which means Kaneda-san's fingerprints are on your shirt!
Kaneda-kun heard that in the past, I had put my name on a student's thesis paper
and passed it off as my own.
He threatened to make it public
if I didn't recommend him for the assistant professor's position.
Furthermore, he wanted me to give him 5,000,000 yen!
I couldn't take any more of it!
The blowfish milt was an unexpected order.
If he hadn't ordered it, I would have gotten away with it!
Remember Ryusui-tei?
Since the murder, they've gotten popular again.
Hey, Dad, take us somewhere again.
Sure, as long as there are geisha there.
How about if I serve you then?
N-No, no thank you...
She's scary.
That's right. This was Shin'ichi's first case.
Shin'ichi Kudo, detective.
Next Conan Special:
Next Conan's Hint: Medicine for Airsickness
Next time, a special!
It's 1 hour long!
He hasn't been around in so long, I better greet him—HI-YAH!