As bright as a spark,
with a penetratingly precise wit.
Once he's on a roll, there's no stopping him!
Today's a special — Conan's first case back when he was Shin'ichi.
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
daitai don'na zasshi o mekuttatte dame
It's useless no matter what magazine I flip through
tameiki dechauwa
I let out a sigh
boku ni niau fuku nanka wa arya shinai no yo
There's no clothes that suit me
seikimatsu no ryūkōshoku
That's the fashions and colours of the 90s
zembu wa omae nya awaserarenai yo
None of them match with you at all
gakkari sasete gomen ne nante ne
Just kidding, sorry for letting you down
giri-giri gake no ue o yuku yō ni
On the edge, like walking along a cliff
fura-fura shitatte ii ja nai ka yo
It doesn't matter even if I sway about
soredemo mae ni iku shika nain dakara
As all I can do is still just move ahead
daijōbu boku no baai wa
I'm fine with it at least
giri-giri ja nai to boku dame nanda yo
If I'm not on the edge, I'm useless
onegai samui me de mitsumenaide
Don't look at me with that cold gaze
jibun no pace de yarasete yo
Let me work at my own pace
ja nai to sugu ni tsubureru
Otherwise, I'll crash and burn out!
giri-giri gake no ue o yuku yō ni
On the edge, like walking along a cliff
fura-fura shitatte ii ja nai ka yo
It doesn't matter even if I sway about
soredemo mae ni iku shika nain dakara
As all I can do is still just move ahead
daijōbu boku no baai wa
I'm fine with it at least
The Flying
Locked Room
SHIN'ICHI KUDŌ'S FIRST CASE
The Flying
Locked Room
SHIN'ICHI KUDŌ'S FIRST CASE
The Flying
Locked Room
SHIN'ICHI KUDŌ'S FIRST CASE
The Flying
Locked Room
SHIN'ICHI KUDŌ'S FIRST CASE
The Flying
Locked Room
SHIN'ICHI KUDŌ'S FIRST CASE
The Flying
Locked Room
SHIN'ICHI KUDŌ'S FIRST CASE
The Flying
Locked Room
SHIN'ICHI KUDŌ'S FIRST CASE
The Flying
Locked Room
SHIN'ICHI KUDŌ'S FIRST CASE
Tōkyō International Airport
Hey, there it is!
The plane we're gonna be riding!
Wow, it's so big!
A Boeing 747.
It's a jumbo jet, 70.7 metres long!
Sheesh.
Kogorō Mouri, private eye, babysitting brats on a trip to Okinawa.
You sure have some nerve.
Weren't you the one who went all ‘Wait for me, my cute seaside angels’ last night?
That was before I knew I had to babysit a bunch of brats.
Come on!
The reason we're even here is because
Dr Agasa won this trip on the Internet!
You should be grateful that you can come along!
Yeah, yeah...
And how come I can't see our lucky doctor yet?
Now that you mention it...
The doc's not coming.
I just called him. He told me he came
down with a cold and can't come.
What?
But it's nothing serious.
Though he asked for lots of souvenirs.
What about Haibara-san?
She's going to pass as well
to look after the doc.
I see.
Then let's buy her a lot of souvenirs!
Wow, the houses keep getting smaller!
Take a look, Conan-kun!
He's asleep.
Shh...
He was up all night reading.
What's so funny?
Oh, I was just remembering the flight I took last year.
Back then, Shin'ichi also fell
asleep right after we took off.
Oh, that...
You and that detective kid ran off to LA
when I was away on a trip that I won at the neighbourhood drawing.
How many times do I have to tell you?
We just went to visit his parents!
Normally, teenage kids don't go on overseas trips together.
Well, his parents were the ones who sent me the ticket!
Hey, back then, he didn't try anything... funny, did he?
What do you mean by ‘funny’?
W-Well, like...
I mean...
H-How do I put this...
Hey! Sit down, brats!
Really...
Umm, excuse me...
Huh?
Ya talkin' to me?
Could you put out that cigarette?
This is a non-smoking section.
Tsuneo Ukai (47)
Executive
You're causing trouble
for the rest of us.
If you want to smoke,
there's an area in the back.
Kazuhiro Ōtaka (29)
Photographer
Oh, my bad.
I'll try to be more thoughtful next time.
Tsugumi Amano (27)
Photographer
Please knock it off, Kazuhiro.
What's with you?
Are ya seriously scolding your boyfriend who's gonna be stinkin' rich soon?
Kazuhiro...
Lighten up some!
That American newspaper said they'll give me a whole lotta green for these negatives, remember?
If those negatives are the real deal.
Huh?
I don't know if those actually are scandalous shots of a powerful American senator or whatever.
Chizuru Tachikawa (29)
Photographer
But if you've got the wrong man,
this'll just be a bad joke.
Don't make me laugh!
I've already faxed 'em two of the shots to confirm it for me.
That's fine and all, but just don't
forget that we're on vacation!
This deal with your shots comes second.
I know!
Wait 'til ya get a load of our surfing skills.
Right, Saginuma?
Noboru Saginuma (30)
Photographer
What's with him? He's already asleep.
Well, guess I'll catch a nap too.
Good night.
Edward Crowe (51)
Freelance Journalist
May I help you, young lady?
I'm sorry...
I'm feeling airsick.
Do you have any airsickness pills?
Sure. Just a moment, please.
Excuse me, sir. May I help you?
Oh, no. I'm not too fond of planes.
I just feel uncomfortable sitting still.
Oh, right. Could you do me a little favour?
Certainly. What is it?
H-Hey, are you all right?
I feel sick. The stewardess went to get me some medicine...
Did you take the airsick pills I gave you?
Yeah.
That's odd. They seem to be
working fine on Saginuma-kun.
Want to switch seats?
Sitting by the window might make you feel better.
Huh?
Well...
Oh, she's the one who needed the medicine.
Here you are. The medicine and some water.
Thank you.
Here's your medicine.
I wonder where Ōtaka-kun went.
He got up a while ago and went somewhere.
Maybe he's also feeling sick and went to the toilet.
Hey, you! Hey!
Excuse me, is something bothering you?
I've been knocking on the door,
but the guy inside won't answer!
Sir? Madam?
Excuse the intrusion.
If you're not feeling well...
What was that scream?
I think it came from the back?
May I have your attention, please?
We have a passenger who has fallen ill.
If there is a doctor or nurse on board,
please report to your nearest flight attendant.
Excuse me.
Yes?
I'm Megure from the MPD.
Is there really a sick person aboard?
Well, actually...
Hey, I saw it!
Someone died!
For real?
Yeah! He's in the toilet in the back!
Hey, wake up! This is terrible!
No way...
Geez, where did he wander off to?
Oh? If it isn't Ran-kun. Right?
Off on vacation during the school break?
Pretty much.
But I heard that somebody died.
Now, now. Just leave everything to the police.
Nobody has disturbed the scene, right?
Well, some strange boy did.
A strange boy?
The cause of death was most likely
suffocation by damage to the cervical cord.
The murder weapon is a pointed object, similar to an ice pick.
The victim may have already been unconscious from inhaling some kind of chemical.
Just who would do such a thing?
I don't have enough information for that yet.
But there's no need to worry.
The murderer is still in this big tin can
that's flying above the Pacific Ocean.
I won't let that person get away.
Hey, just who are you?
That's right.
That was the first page in his career.
Shin'ichi Kudō, detective.
This was Shin'ichi's first case.
Detective Conan Episode 162
‘The Flying Locked Room: Shin'ichi Kudō's First Case!’
Broadcast September 27, 1999
Based on manga volume #21, files 4-8
Subtitled by The Moonlighters
irc://irc.hoshinet.org/the-moonlighters
Translation: Tohma-kun, Miyaki
Song translations: bluesun
Timing: SakoeraTyan
Editing: Puto, SakoeraTyan
Encoding: Licca
This is a V0 release — it hasn't gone through a full TLC or QC
K-Kudō? Are you Yūsaku-kun's...
Long time no see, Inspector Megure.
Oh! You're his son, Shin'ichi-kun!
You're the spitting image of your dad in the old days!
I haven't seen you since
you were in the sixth grade.
But man, you've grown so tall!
But you've got no business here!
You're still in high school, aren't you?
You can't just meddle with a crime scene!
Excuse me. Could you borrow a camera from someone?
I need to take pictures of the scene.
Well, if you need pictures,
that boy already took some.
About sixty, I believe. I borrowed the camera from a passenger.
And...
He told us to keep an eye on his actions.
And he didn't do anything suspicious, like trying to hide something or wipe something off.
But if you move the body, you'll destroy the stiffening of the muscles,
making it harder to determine
the estimated time of death.
Judging from the livor mortis and the
fact that his chin was already stiffening.
I'd say he's been dead for an hour or two.
There are three things that struck me as being just plain odd.
First of all, even though there were spots of
blood on the wall where the body was leaning,
there wasn't any blood on the body.
Secondly, there's a strange scratch at
the lower right of the fatal wound.
And last but not least, the inside of his
trousers' left pocket was soaking wet.
Though his hands were completely dry.
And even if you shove a wet hand into your pocket, it wouldn't get that wet.
Which means that somebody
must've soaked it for a reason.
Argh! Stay out of this!
You're supposed to leave this to the police!
Excuse me, but could you get the man sleeping in the seat next to mine?
He's also a cop.
Yes, sir.
Hey, you!
What do you mean, ‘detective’?
You're just a regular high schooler.
Can you blame me?
They wouldn't let me get near the body otherwise.
You should've told me where you were going!
I was worried sick about you!
But you were sleeping so peacefully with that dopey look on your face.
What do you mean by dopey look?
Like this!
Inspector?
You're late, Takagi-kun!
A murder case?
Indeed.
The cause of death was most likely
suffocation by damage to the cervical cord.
The murder weapon is a pointed object, similar to an ice pick.
Judging from the livor mortis and rigor mortis, he died one or two hours ago.
Hmm? There's an empty bottle and a handkerchief in here.
It looks like the killer soaked the handkerchief in something like chloroform, carried it around in a bottle
and knocked the victim out with it before killing him.
Yeah.
Excuse me. We'd like to store the evidence.
Could I have a plastic bag or something?
Umm, is something the matter?
Oh, it's nothing.
It's just that everything you just said has been exactly the same as what that boy said.
We were astonished.
‘That boy’?
Take a look. The one over there with the black pullover.
Who is he?
A friend's son.
His dad's a mystery writer who used to help me whenever I couldn't figure out a case.
When he was still little, his dad used to bring him along to crime scenes.
But I never would've thought he'd pick up detection skills like that.
That sounds pretty neat!
You fool!
An amateur's still an amateur!
He's just a teenager who got big ideas from
reading too many mysteries and medical books!
At any rate, let's look for potential witnesses!
We're dealing with four suspects here.
Only four people, apart from the victim, went to the toilet at the key time.
SMOKING AREA
TOILETS
My seat's at the very end of the row.
I had my eyes open the whole night, and
nobody went to the smoking area behind it.
There's no mistake.
You had your eyes open?
You were awake all night?
Yeah, I couldn't fall asleep.
Huh, how come?
Didn't you fall asleep the
moment you got on the plane?
Ah, is that so?
Oh, boy! Falling asleep early and then waking up in the middle of the night, just like a baby.
You really expected me to fall asleep with you right next to me?
I'm not that mature yet.
Then could you identify
those four people for us?
O-Oh, yes.
Let's see, the four people were...
This woman.
And the woman next to her.
Also, the man sitting across the aisle.
And the foreigner in the seat in front is the last one.
They're all seated close together.
Yes.
H-Hey, what's this?
What's going on?
Kazuhiro...
Kazuhiro!
No way...
Tsugumi...
But why did this happen to Ōtaka-kun?
That's what we're trying to figure out.
Those negatives could be a motive, right?
Negatives?
I saw him showing them off to the others.
He claimed he'd earn big money by selling them to some newspaper.
Don't tell me that they're gone.
Yeah, he didn't have any on him.
No way...
So the murderer must be someone who was aware of those negatives.
Anybody in our business would've known.
He offered to sell them to plenty of newspapers!
So, Inspector.
Ōtaka was stabbed in the back of the head, right?
Yes.
Then the killer must've been a pro.
Those two are just photographers.
Don't you think it's a bit off base to suspect us?
No, it could've been done by anyone with an anaesthetic weapon and basic medical knowledge.
Yes, even a woman.
Well, for now, let's hear you all
out about your trips to the toilet.
I went to the toilet because I wasn't feeling well.
But I'm certain that Kazuhiro was still there when I got back to my seat.
At that time, I asked the stewardess to bring me some medicine.
And that's why I still remember.
Is that true?
Yes. He still seemed to be asleep, back then.
I saw that from down the aisle.
It indeed looked as if she was asking for some medicine.
I went to the toilet right after that.
I think I was there for about five minutes.
Down the aisle?
Isn't your seat across from them?
I was walking around since I don't like sitting for long.
Then when did the victim leave his seat?
By the time I brought her the medicine
and water, he had already left his seat.
But I'm fairly certain that I got back in less than a minute.
I went to the bathroom about twenty
minutes after Tsugumi got her medicine.
I went to see how Ōtaka-kun was doing
because he had been away for quite a while.
But he was still alive then.
Well, when I knocked on this door and asked wheter he was doing fine, he knocked back.
I-Is that true?
But how did you know
which one he was in?
I knew.
I checked all the other ones
and they were all unoccupied.
So he's the only one left.
When did you go to the toilet?
I don't remember when I did, unfortunately.
He says he doesn't remember when he went.
I guess we can't blame him.
What's wrong?
That foreigner uses a really strong cologne.
Hey! How many more useless questions will you ask?
Whoever has the murder weapon must be the culprit, right?
Wouldn't it be faster to just perform a body check on those four and check their luggage?
Anyway, since I never went to the toilet and was asleep the whole time,
it's got nothing to do with me.
You're lying!
You also left your seat, didn't you?
What?
Your seat's right behind the victim's, right?
What are you talking about?
Remember how I said the victim was still
asleep in his seat before I went to the toilet?
I swear that he wasn't there at the moment.
Hey, that's just crazy talk, mister!
Only you and the other three went to the toilet!
That's what he testified!
Right, kid?
Well, yes...
Hey, are you really sure?
Come to think of it, I was
distracted for a moment.
Anyhow, I must ask all five of you
to get bodychecked in the lavatory and have your baggage searched.
What?!
You couldn't find a weapon on them or in their bags?
Yes, nobody had anything
similar to an ice pick on them.
We have also searched all
possible spots on the plane.
But nothing was found.
Hey, are you sure they were the only ones who went to the lavatory?
W-Well, Shin'ichi?
Shin'ichi!
Interesting, isn't it?
If the murder weapon couldn't be found, then that must mean
that the murderer is probably still carrying it.
And that must be the culprit's trump card.
And I'll find that trump card.
Before this iron bird rests its wings.
Detective Conan Episode 162
‘The Flying Locked Room: Shin'ichi Kudō's First Case!’
Broadcast September 27, 1999
Based on manga volume #21, files 4-8
Subtitled by The Moonlighters
irc://irc.hoshinet.org/the-moonlighters
Translation: Tohma-kun, Miyaki
Song translations: bluesun
Timing: SakoeraTyan
Editing: Puto, SakoeraTyan
Encoding: Licca
This is a V0 release — it hasn't gone through a full TLC or QC
What?!
Search them again?
Do you want us to do a full search of the five suspects and their belongings once more?
Is that what you want, Shin'ichi-kun?
Yes.
Since we can't find the
weapon on board the plane,
the murderer might still be
carrying it, Inspector Megure.
First up, Tachikawa-san's baggage.
Passport, purse, handkerchief,
makeup kit, tissues, boarding pass,
a pair of sunglasses, camera,
notebook, and a ballpoint pen.
I don't think any of this could be a potential murder weapon.
About that ballpoint pen...
Did you look inside it?
Yes, of course we did.
Okay, next up is Amano-san!
Yes.
Passport, wallet, handkerchief,
knit hat, boarding pass,
camera, makeup kit, sewing kit and some medicine for airsickness.
The only edged tools here are the small
scissors and needle in the sewing kit.
It seems like a far stretch to think someone could kill with these.
Okay, next up is Ukai-san!
Okay.
Passport, boarding pass, wallet, handkerchief,
electric razor, towel and some shaving cream.
Let's see. Next up is Edward-san.
Let us check your belongings, just in case.
Well, it appears you have to.
He doesn't mind.
Go ahead.
That's strange.
The cologne is the most strong around his neck.
Maybe he has none on his wrists.
Passport, wallet, handkerchief, boarding pass,
towel, newspaper, two paperback books, glasses case, sewing kit
and a checkbook from the
American National Bank.
Excuse me, Edward-san.
What's this checkbook...
Oh, wait a sec...
Mr Edward, I'd like to ask you a few questions
about the checkbook in your briefcase.
Yes, it's for my job.
I was to buy some art object
at the auction in Japan.
But nothing caught my eyes.
He intended to buy an art
object at an auction in Japan,
but he couldn't find anything to his interest.
I see...
Only one left.
Here!
I'm the last one, right?
Passport, wallet, handkerchief, camera, some negatives,
wristwatch, cigarettes, lighter, boarding pass and medicine for airsickness.
Quite a lot of medicine you've got here.
I easily get airsick.
Chizuru and Tsugumi lent me some, too.
Right?
Yes.
Mind if I look at those negatives real quick?
Go ahead.
H-Hey!
The man in these photographs...
It's the American senator Dickson-san, right?
Y-You're right!
He's with a woman...
Hey, that's enough, okay?
Hold it!
That sounds just like Ōtaka-kun's negatives.
J-Just like his? Don't tell me...
And here they are in your luggage.
H-Hey, hold on a sec!
T-These are my negatives!
I was at that hotel with Ōtaka, taking the same pictures.
But Ōtaka's...
But Ōtaka's were better than mine.
Mine weren't so good.
But I was gonna try sell 'em anyway to some newspaper office in Los Angeles.
But if you want to blame the murder
on me, then go find the weapon first!
Now, now. I'll be happy
to talk after the body check.
Now then, I'd like everyone to enter
the toilet, one at a time, as before.
A stewardess will be checking the woman,
while the men will be checked by us.
So this is Ōtaka-san's seat.
According to the seat numbers on the boarding passes,
Ōtaka
Saginuma-san was behind him,
and in front of him sat Edward-san.
Saginuma
Ōtaka
Edward
Amano-san sat to his right, and next to her was Tachikawa-san.
Amano
Tachikawa
And across the aisle to his left sat Ukai-san.
Ukai
Th—
This is a fragment of a film negative.
What's it doing in the seat
next to Saginuma-san's?
Hey, Shin'ichi.
They just finished the body check.
But it looks like nobody had a weapon.
That means the only place left is...
You see now? We didn't have any weapon!
I had to strip buck naked twice!
I've had enough!
W-What do we do, Inspector Megure?
We've searched every possible place.
No, there's still one more place.
There's a place we haven't searched yet.
The luggage of the victim, Ōtaka-san.
Detective Conan Episode 162
‘The Flying Locked Room: Shin'ichi Kudō's First Case!’
Broadcast September 27, 1999
Based on manga volume #21, files 4-8
Subtitled by The Moonlighters
irc://irc.hoshinet.org/the-moonlighters
Translation: Tohma-kun, Miyaki
Song translations: bluesun
Timing: SakoeraTyan
Editing: Puto, SakoeraTyan
Encoding: Licca
This is a V0 release — it hasn't gone through a full TLC or QC
Which one belongs to Ōtaka-san?
Umm...
The one behind that black bag.
Is something wrong?
No.
I just remembered something unusual he told me.
Something unusual...?
A week ago, he forgot his bag in the studio, and somebody tore it to shreds.
That's why he had to buy...
...a new one for this trip.
Maybe somebody thought the
negatives might've been inside it.
Passport, camera, film, a pair of
sunglasses, three packs of cigarettes,
wallet, towel, two magazines,
boarding pass, and wristwatch.
Nothing like this looks like
the murder weapon to me.
Shin'ichi...
Seriously?
Oh?
‘Kazuhiro Ōtaka’.
The same Ōtaka-san who won the Nichiuri Shimbun Photo Awards three years ago?
Yes, that was him.
The same Kazuhiro Ōtaka.
I knew it.
What's that, Takagi-kun?
Oh, you know...
That photograph of a mother caught in a fire handing her baby to a fireman.
So what?
What does that currently matter?
Are we cleared of the charges now?
Or not? Well, which is it?
B-But you people were the only ones who went
to the toilet around the time of the murder...
...according to this boy.
I bet the young detective simply fell asleep and missed a couple of people.
It certainly seems like you've read lots of books and did lots of studying.
But this is reality.
Not some fictional story.
Children should behave and just go back to their seat, and take a nap.
Hey, Shin'ichi.
Aren't you gonna stand up to him?
What's with this case?
We can't find the murder weapon.
And their stories just don't add up.
Don't you think it's about time to confess already?
Huh?
You're the murderer, am I right?
Hey, hey...
I think it's pretty obvious that you're
the only one among us who's lying.
I was watching...
When this lady asked for some medicine.
You claimed you were in your
seat back then, but that's a lie!
Stop talking nonsense!
I-It's not nonsense.
It's true that... back then...
That stewardess...
She also must've seen it.
Or so he says.
Is that true?
Yes.
That gentleman was wandering
around the cabin, so I stopped him.
He then complained about someone who
was smoking in the non-smoking section.
And was this person in his seat back then?
Umm, no.
I don't think he was.
Hey, come on! What're you talking about?!
You were the one who brought the medicine, right?
Umm, yes.
Y-You saw me asleep in my seat, didn't you?
Umm, well...
I don't remember clearly.
What?!
Excuse me.
Is it true that when you brought the medicine...
That's what happened, right?
Yes... Yes, you're absolutely right.
I thought I was just imagining things.
I knew it.
There's no mistake.
That's the killer.
All testimonies except the killer's...
The negative fragement in the seat...
The unusual bloodstain in the toilet...
And why the victim's pockets were wet.
It all fits.
But why...
But why did we not find the weapon on the killer?
Could it be...
That it couldn't be thrown away?
Something that'd lead us
immediately to that person.
Wait a sec.
Back then that person...
Come here, Shin'ichi!
Inspector Megure is looking for you!
He wanted to ask you wheter or not you remember anyone else who went to the toilet.
Ah, more importantly, Ran, you're...
...in high school, aren't you?
Of course I am.
Then, lemme ask you something...
W-Wh-Wha-Wha...
Answer already!
It's embarrassing for me too, you know.
Yeah, that's right...
Most of them are like that now.
I see.
So that's how it is.
J-Just what do you mean by ‘I see’?
I've finally figured it out.
The trump card that the killer used to finish off the victim.
At any rate...
The only one of you who has
made any suspicious moves...
...is you, Saginuma-san!
Hey, hey...
You're mistaken, Inspector Megure!
He is not the killer.
That man never went near the crime scene,
so there's a 0% chance that he's the killer.
Hey, hey...
Well, look at that.
I told you I wasn't involved with any of this.
No.
You are involved in this case.
Saginuma-san...
You were being used by someone...
By one of those four people who isn't telling the truth.
I'm talking about the killer.
That reminds me, Inspector...
The one who claims to have gone to the toilet to check on the victim, knocked on the door,
and that then someone knocked back was Tachikawa-san.
She lied?
H-Hold on now!
No.
She didn't lie.
There really was someone inside the toilet room...
Together with a body.
Edward-san, that was you, right?
H-Hey, are you sure?
While looking for the negatives he put his hand inside Ōtaka-san's pocket,
and realised that some of the cologne from his wrists got on the victim's trousers.
So he quickly washed the cologne off his hands,
and wiped that distinctive scent out of the pocket with a wet handkerchief.
Him not having any cologne on his wrists is the proof.
That doesn't really classify as proof.
Besides, the questioning would have to be done in English.
No, he can actually speak Japanese.
Isn't that right, Edward-san?
The boy's telling the truth.
He...
He spoke...
...in Japanese!
Of course he can.
He wanted to buy those negatives with that National Bank check.
Buy them?
Indeed.
Senator Dickson, the man in those
scandalous photos, requested me to.
So you're the one who killed Ōtaka?!
No, he didn't do it.
Because when he entered the toilet, Ōtaka-san was already a dead man.
What'd you say?
Isn't that right, Edward-san?
Yes, when I heard that he went to the toilet...
I realised that it was my opportunity to make a deal with him.
But when I got no reply after knocking on the door, I forced myself in.
And there he was... Dead.
Of course I didn't get my hands on the negatives.
So, the one who knocked back were...
That was me.
Hey, don't be fooled!
He's just playing along with the kid's guess.
Guess?
Not at all.
There was blood on the toilet's wall.
But there wasn't any on the victim's back
even though that he was leaning there.
That indicates that someone else
must've moved the body later on.
Someone who found the body without notifying anyone.
The only reason I could think of to move the body would be to look for the negatives.
Unable to find it, he searched inside the victim's pocket.
And the only person who would do that,
must have been someone who couldn't see what the victim was doing.
That person would be Edward-san!
I... I see!
Then, who's the murderer?
We have now ruled out Edward-san, and the
one who knocked on the door, Tachikawa-san.
Which means that Ukai-san and
Amano-san are the only suspects left.
Here's an important part.
When Amano-san asked a
stewardess for some medicine,
there was nobody sitting in Saginuma-san's
seat — the one behind the victim's seat.
That's what Ukai-san had testified.
That is no mistake.
That's why I kept telling you that I was asleep in my seat the whole time.
That's right, Saginuma-san was
sleeping in his seat the whole time.
But the killer put a knit hat and an eye mask on him.
What'd you say?
But wait, doesn't that match...
Indeed, it matches what
Ōtaka-san wore while sleeping.
After killing Ōtaka-san, instead of returning to their own seat,
the killer sat next to Saginuma-san while being
dressed like Ōtaka-san and called the stewardess.
That way it'd seem like Ōtaka-san was still alive at that moment.
H-Hey, hold on.
Y-You don't mean...?
Indeed.
The one who killed Ōtaka-san and used Saginuma-san to create a fake alibi is...
Detective Conan Episode 162
‘The Flying Locked Room: Shin'ichi Kudō's First Case!’
Broadcast September 27, 1999
Based on manga volume #21, files 4-8
Subtitled by The Moonlighters
irc://irc.hoshinet.org/the-moonlighters
Translation: Tohma-kun, Miyaki
Song translations: bluesun
Timing: SakoeraTyan
Editing: Puto, SakoeraTyan
Encoding: Licca
This is a V0 release — it hasn't gone through a full TLC or QC
Tsugumi Amano-san, it's you!
H-Hey, you're kidding, right?
Tsugumi...
Well, we can't blame the stewardess
for her mistake, because it was so dark,
and most of his face was covered up.
Tsugumi-san went back to her own seat when the stewardess was getting the medicine,
and woke up Tachikawa-san by coughing loudly.
All to make her notice that Ōtaka-san wasn't in his seat.
Thus making Tachikawa-san and the stewardess think that Ōtaka-san just went to the toilet.
I-In that case, the empty seat I saw...
You must've seen the empty seat behind Sazanuma-san.
But she wouldn't be able to pull off that trick if the
seat next to Saginuma-san was to be occupied.
If she ordered an extra ticket without
cancelling it, the seat would remain empty.
If she gave Saginuma-san sleeping pills instead
of airsick pills, then he wouldn't wake up easily.
There was a knit hat in her luggage.
And she was aware of Ōtaka-san's habit of wearing an eye mask when sleeping.
But what if the stewardess noticed Tachikawa-san wasn't sitting next to her?
Something like that can easily be camouflaged by putting a blanket over your luggage.
The negatives were cut to pieces with the sewing kit's scissors and flushed down the toilet.
All to make it look like that the killer was after the negatives
to draw away attention from her and her friends.
I found a piece of the negative on the seat next to Saginuma-san's
which must've stuck to her
clothes and fell down there.
Check it out!
Yes, sir.
This is what must have happened...
She waited until Tachikawa-san fell asleep,
and told Ōtaka-san that she wanted to talk and told him to wait in the toilet.
She then took her drugged handkerchief in
a bottle and weapon, and went to the toilet.
Right after opening the door, she pressed the handkerchief into his face to knock him out,
and stabbed him in the cervical cord.
Now she had to cut up and flush away the negatives,
lock the door from the outside, and set up her trick so that it seems Ōtaka-san still was alive
when she returned from the toilet.
Her alibi was now established.
But what if someone going to the toilet saw her leaving the scene?
I'm guessing that she left the door unlocked during the murder.
So even if someone wanted to use the toilet,
she could easily keep the door closed because of it being so narrow.
The person outside would realise that it's occupied and just go to another toilet.
Hey, hold it!
If you're going to accuse Tsugumi then you better show us some proof!
Hey...
I have the weapon and proof.
As a matter of fact, she still has it on her.
What're you blabbering about? You forgot that she went through two body checks?
It's something that can bypass a search.
It also can get past metal detectors.
But only women have it.
O-Only women have it?
As if something that convenient exists, you silly.
D-Don't tell me, Tsugumi, that you...
What I'm talking about, Tsugumi-san,
is the metal wire in the right
side of the bra you're wearing.
It's impossible for a woman to
kill someone with such a thing.
No, if you sharpen one edge and stab the back of the neck with full power,
and penetrate about 5 to 6 centimetres, it'll reach the cervical cord.
It's possible for a woman.
There's a peculiar scratch mark left near the fatal injury on his neck. That's the proof.
It must've been left there when the other end of the wire scratched the neck.
Tsugumi-san didn't get rid of the weapon because if it'd be discovered at the scene,
we'd figure out that the woman with
a missing wire in her bra would be the killer.
I get it! Let's just have her go
through one more body check.
I can't, Saginuma-san.
Because then they'd find it.
T-Tsugumi?
That's right.
I killed Kazuhiro.
Because of the photo that made him win the
Nichiuri Shimbun Photo Award three years ago.
What're you saying? Wasn't that photo what brought you two together?
That's right. He caught my interest because of it.
I was amazed that someone was able to capture the horror of the fire
that took my brother's life, on film.
Then why?
That wasn't the only photo he took.
I found dozens of photos in his room!
Some from when the smoke started to rise from the flat building,
and even panoramic shots from before the fire even started!
D-Did Ōtaka-kun...
...start that fire?
Exactly! He even boasted about it when I confronted him with the photos!
You don't wait for perfect
moments. You make them.
...he said.
But...
I'm upset.
I was confident in where I hid the weapon.
You raised your arm.
When you were about to get his bag from the luggage rack,
your right arm stopped and then you used your left arm instead.
That gave you away.
The sharpened edge of the wire must've
pricked you, which is what made you stop.
F-From that?
From just that?
It has long been an axiom of mine that the little things are infinitely the most important.
That little gesture you made just struck me as odd.
Her arm... Did you notice it, Inspector?
No, not at all.
By the way, Inspector...
Why are you going to LA?
I'm on my way to pick up a Japanese criminal who's on the international list from the LAPD.
I see.
I get it now.
That's why he asked me that.
Free Magic, in its true form
Free Magic hontō no tokoro
Free Magic, what is this thing called love?
Free Magic ai-tte nan na no sa
Even if you're blindly searching through darkness for warmth
tsumetai kurayami no naka de nukumori o tesaguri shite'ru
Someday you'll surely find a miracle
itsuka wa kitto kiseki mo okoru darō
Free Magic, if love were to take form, it'd be round like an egg
Free Magic kitto ai ga aru nara maarui katachi
Free Magic, so right now, speak your first cry in these hands
Free Magic ima kono te no naka ubugoe agete
Even with faked bravery you can still be reckless
karagenki demo mada-mada mucha shite
Free Magic, you may not have much courage now
Free Magic wazuka na yūki
Free Magic, but I'll gather and raise it
Free Magic atsumete sodachimashō
But you know...
‘Could you show me your bra?’
‘There's a wire in it, isn't there?’
Who asks a woman such a thing?
Don't you know that's
sexual harassment, Shin'ichi?
Hey, hey...
Don't tell me Ran's dreaming about that case.
Hey, Ran! What's the meaning of this?
That creep did try something, didn't he?
Hey, wake up!
I wonder what's she dreaming about.
I dreamt about stuffing myself with eel on rice.
Sir, we're about to land. Please return to your seat.
Idiot! How can I stay calm when my daughter's virtue is endangered!
But, sir!
Hey, what's sexual harassment?
sekuhara
It's gotta mean a dessert stomach.
betsubara
I don't understand a thing.
But...
I'm so excited!
The less I understand of it, the more it goes wild...
My uncontrollable curiosity!
The Secret of the Moon, Star and Sun
(Part I)
On the next Conan: ‘The Secret of the Moon, Star and Sun (Part I)’.
Next Conan's Hint: ¥1 coin!
Look forward to the next episode!
The next episode is on the 11th of October!
Hey, Ran, when're you gonna
dream about me again?