Shines with a flash, and pierces with a shatter, you can't stop it once it begins to move!
Today's episode is about a treasure hunt on a normal autumn day.
The Detective Boys must figure out the whole 'answer' to the hunt.
Though I may look like a child my brain is that of an adult.
My name is Meitantei Conan!
The Secret of the Moon, Sun, and Stars
(Part One)
The secret of the Moon, Sun, and Stars! (Part One)
The Secret of the Moon, Sun, and Stars
(Part One)
Say professor,
Is there really treasure at that place where we're going to?
Yeah, of course.
But you'll have to use your own heads to try and find it.
YAY!
Only us, the detective boys will be looking for it!
Then all of treasure will belong to us!
Hey, professor.
Eh? What?
The treasure that you're talking about,
don't tell me that it's those bunch of toys that you made me buy.
Shh! Don't let them hear that!
You're always like that, no wonder Haibara didn't wanna come.
But lately, you've been acting so generous.
Since you've also recently bought that new car.
Maybe, you're trying to rob a bank with all this stuff?
Don't be stupid! How can I possibly do that?
It's actually because of this.
The Masked Yaiber?
Some friend's office wanted me to help them.
To help them start off their new business, in exchange for some cash.
And what might this be?
A Masked Yaiber voice changer.
Surprised, huh?
The professor gave us all one of those this morning.
The masked yaiber voice changer.
Yaiber voice changer?
You can record your own voice then change it into a completely different voice.
It's a new Masked Yaiber product.
Then it's just the same as my voice-changing bowtie...
What's wrong? You never did admire my inventions.
That product is now available worldwide.
Wow! What a big house.!
Is this place really Agasa's uncle's house?
Yes it is. My uncle's name was Agasa Kurisuke.
He was known around here for being a very rich man.
Fifty years ago, he hid a bunch of treasure,
but not long after that, he passed away.
That's why I brought you guys here,
so that you Detective Boys can help me find the treasure.
To the looks of it then, there is treasure here!
Yeah. It doesn't seem that Agasa came here earlier and hide the treasure after all.
Didn't I say? Agasa's not the type to trick kids.
Right, Professor?
Uh... of course.
Heh heh...no one's stupid here.
Let's start searching in this room!
Yeah!
Huh?
Heh-henn..
Here?
There doesn't seem to be anything in here..
There's nothing in here either.
Say professor.
Is your uncle that man in that painting?
Huh? Yeah that's him.
I see.
Your uncle sure seemed rich..
Eh?
Just look at that fireplace behind him, it's
exactly the same as the one over there.
So in other words, he hired someone
over to paint that painting.
He had enough to get that done,
so he had to be a rich guy.
Yeah, I heard that a year before my uncle had died,
he hired someone to paint the picture.
The lady behind him is?
She is my uncle's sister, who took care of him
She was my uncle's most trusted person.
I think that she was teaching in an elementry school.
After my uncle died, she left this
place and went back home.
So no one had come to this house
for the past 50 years.
But there are lots of things there,
all the silverware and books..
Since uncle's belongings were here within
the fifty years later after he died,
no one touched any of it.
So that's why all his belongings are still left here.
But they have decided to tear
down this place next month.
I see.
So that's why you wanted to come to
this dust-filled house with the kids,
before they tear it down, you wanted
them to play your treasure hunt.
Exactly.
Where is the treasure?
Hey. Make sure you don't mess any of the things here.
But-
Be careful, and just keep searching and
you will discover something interesting.
That's right, for example, underneath my foot,
there is some weird writing...
What?
Eh?
Wow! You're right!
Mo-za-ri-sa-wa-so-de-ru.
What is this?
Is it English?
No, that's not it. It's in Arabian.
It's not that easy...
Even for Shinichi.
Eh?
Where did Shinichi go?
Did Shinichi..
Looking at things, seems like I've even
got Shinichi, confused with my riddle.
Huh?
Well, I'm not surprised.
I spent three whole days planning it out.
Oh, if you're talking about the
thing which you've hidden..
I already found it underneath
the bed in the other room.
Huh?!
I didn't open and look at the treasure just yet.
Since it's just too easy..
I put a piece of cloth over it and
pushed it in a little more.
Well, good work...
Why you...
But I'm still thinking about this place,
since I've stumbled upon another mystery.
Another mystery?
Yeah.
Professor, what do you think about this?
Huh? Let me see.
Why, if's just an ordinary one yen.
I found it underneath the bed.
Then maybe I was the one who dropped it.
No, that's not it...
That coin has been completely covered with dust
And it doesn't seem that it has
been rolling around either.
The first time that this one yen was released was,
approximately in 1455, which makes
this coin 40 years old.
And it was already lying in this place, not
to mention it's covered with dust..so..
Can it be?!
Someone came and just broke into the house?!
No, they didn't just come here,
they actually lived here forawhile,
and they were a very sensitive old man.
Hmm...sensitive old man.
Hey hey, what exactly are you mumbling about?
I don't get it at all.
Why don't you take out a one yen,
and compare it with the one you're lookiing at?
Wha? Compare?
How is it different?
What?!
That yen is way smaller than the one I took out!
And it's so thin! It's smaller than mine by a whole circle.
I'm thinking that,that yen was an original...
the person cut the coin with a knife, making it smaller.
That person's hand-works are very well done.
See? Even that word "country" has changed.
I'm not sure if that person did it on purpose or if he accidently did it.
But I don't know why they used the old version of "country".
though since it's like that, they must be an old person.
But how did you know that the person lived here? They didn't do anything.
Nope. There's no doubt that they did do something.
And they did it while reading too.
Reading?
There are fragments of coin material within this book...
And a piece of white hair.
There couldn't have been someone who within this short period of time
who could have done that to the coin.
So we can only guess that person was living here at that time.
Oh, I see.
But why?
Who knows.
Maybe to just kill the time.
Wasn't there only one person who was living here?
There should have also been some kids.
I just discovered this..
Proof that kids have been living here.
Look at the bottom of this flower vase.
Bottom?
This is...
It was drawn by kids.
I also found something like that.
Me too!
What?!
Look, there's some on the bottom of this candlestick!
There's some of this plate too!
It must have been done by a really naughty kid.
We should quickly go and try to figure out the mystery on the floor.
That's weird..
Uncle didn't have any kids.
and moresoever, what about that mysterious old man?
Why did he bring children?
Professor, do you know about the "The Dancing Boy"?
Dancing Boy?
You're talking about that code from Holmes' books?
About that stick-figure's mysterious dance pattern?
I still remember that drawing of the mysterious dance
Ar-are you saying that this is the same as that?
There's no doubt about it.
The flower vase, the candle and this plate.
If I compare them,
the three symbols to the right are the same.
So in otherwords, those three symbols are required in the code.
That's right. It's a code
What happened? You seem happy.
Did you already figured out what the code means?
Nope. I don't get it at all.
The mystery of the old man, and the mystery of that one yen.
I'm actually quite excited.
The more I don'tunderstand, the more excited I get.
I just can't face this mystery and be calm.
A detective's blood boils unstoppingly...huh?
Speaking of this, I think I've seen those,
Symbols somewhere before.
What? For real, professor?
Where? Where did you see it, professor?!
Calm down.
Hey Conan!
Come and think about this too with us, would you!
About the code that was written on the floor.
Stop being lazy!
O-oh. That?
Mo-za-ri-sa-wa-so-de-ru
I don't understand what that is,
but these kinds of codes are usually
written having the letters shifted either one before or after the actual letter.
So just try shifting the letters back one and reading it
Ya-zi-ru-si Wo-ta-do-re
Follow the arrow!
Alright! Let's go and follow the arrow!
Yeah!
Wait-wait a minute.
What? What is it?!
When we first entered this room,
didn't we see an arrow?
We did?
I don't see one.
Just look at that clock over there.
Wha?
Clock?
What's wrong with that clock?
Haven't you noticed that there's something oddly strange about both arrows pointing at 6 o'clock?
How is it odd?
The arms of that clock just seems to have broken down.
Look at it again carefully.
On a normal clock if it was 6:30 then the two arms should be seperated and not together at that point.
But look at that, both arms of the clock are overlapped.
That proves that someone has played around with the arms of the clock,
probably the same person who hid the treasure here.
So in other words, the arms of that clock's the arrow
which the code was talking about?
Right.
Then let's check out what's underneath the clock!
There's a pile of cards here.
Look at that Ace of Spades in the middle of the pile.
Who knows why that card is pinned down to the table?
You're right.
Ah! I get it, the A is the arrow.
Hmm, what is it pointing at.? That chess set!
Look at that.
See how the chess pieces are arranged?
The way they are arranged?
If you look at them carefully, you'll see an arrow!
Wow, you're right!
The pieces have been glued to the board too.
There's no doubt about it.
Then next is...that room over there!
Hey, I don't see an arrow in this room.
The person who hid the treasure,
had the most difficulty in this room.
Wha?
If you look on top of this table over here,
there are three odd markings.
That's the proof that something has been placed on this table.
Something?
Ah! Can it be...
This toy airplane on the ground?
Right. Place that to the markings on the table.
Okay.
Ah! The bed!
The plane is pointing towards the bed!
So the treasure is in this bed after all!
Wow! Seems like there's something under this bed!
That must be the treasure!
But that's weird.
The airplane that I've placed on the table,
I don't remember having it fall down onto the ground.
Wha?
Hurry and open it! Hurry!
What?!
That's so cruel..
They used a knife and recked all of these.
Yeah.
The person who hid the treasure,
just wanted to scare us.
No. The professor wouldn't do such a thing.
Pr-professor?
So you're sayng that these toys were hidden here by the professor?
He wanted to create a little hunting game for you guys.
So after the professor hid the toys,
Someone came here while we were still driving here and did this?
Right. I'm guessing that whoever did it must have seen a little of the code which the professor wrote on the floor,
and found the treasure.
But when he realized that the treasure was actually toys,
he got mad and wrecked everything with his knife.
The airplane that the professor had put on the table,
mūst have fallen onto the floor at that time.
But who would come here?
I'm not sure, but that person should have just been passing along.
He was curious so he came in...or maybe..
he purposely came in here, to search for something.
What was he looking for?
Maybe it has something to do with those symbols.
Symbols?
Those symbols that you discovered.
The symbols of the sun, moon and stars.
So you're saying that those symbols were a code?
Most likely.
Let's see,
Maybe there really is actual treasure in this house.
Ah professor, what did the police say?
They said that this was most likely done by a thief.
They'll come and investigate tomorrow. So it'll be best if you guys leave everything as it is right now.
Everything would be best that way.
That's right. Even though that code is very mysterious,
I wouldn't want to do anything to the scene.
Hey! What are you guys doing?
You still need to ask?
We're going to look for more of those symbols, and then find the real treasure.
Don't be stupid! The criminal might be somewhere near here!
Conan-kun, I found another!
There's the same symbols on this card!
You serious?
Look.
Alright. Ayumi and I will be a group,
Genta and Mitsuhiko, you guys be the second group, let's go search for more.
Yeah!
Geez.
Wha?
Maybe it was just me.
Conan-kun, I found another one!
There's none here.
None here either.
So now, we have found a total of seven different codes.
On a card, a French đictionary, a record, an airplane, awine glass, a painting, and this doll.
Now that I think about it, I've heard my aunt say that when my uncle was still alive, he really treasured that doll.
And the three which we've found earlier.
A plate, a candlestick, and a flower vase. So a total of 10 objects.
But after having gathered all these objects,
we still don't understand.
Yeah. If only the code would be longer, and more similar to regular writing, that'd make things easier.
Like for an example, maybe having the code written a diary or maybe a letter of some sort.
Letter?
Oh yeah! Now I remember!
There was a letter!
Wha?
Didn't I mention?
That I've seen that code somewhere before?
A while ago, my aunt showed me.
But I completely forgot.
Are you talking about that lady in the painting?
That person who you said had onced worked as a teacher?
Yeah. That's right. That happened around five or six years ago.
She had recieved a letter every year for ten years that didn't have a sender's name on it.
But the address and name on the letter was to her.
Since it was so strange, my aunt had let me see it. I still remember that the content of the letter was written entirely using hiragana.
"How do you do?" "God bless." Etc.
Maybe one of her students sent it to her?
No. Since all of the letters within the ten years that have been sent were only written using hiragana.
That's indeed strange.
What was special about that letter and the code?
The code was drawn everywhere,
starting from the four corners of that hiragana letter.
Just like a fancy pattern.
So what did the letter mean?
I really didn't know, so I went to ask that person,
your da...no, err... my good neighbor,
who worked as an author.
Dad saw it?!
Though even that author didn't even know that letter had meant.
At first, he didn't seem to happy about it,
but once he saw the letter, he seemed really excited.
He took the letter with him back to his place,
and came back out within a few minutes
and told me that,
"give these letters back to your aunt for me,
this is just too exciting.
Professor, you're just like the sun.
You always turn my horrible mood around."
What did that letter say?!
I have no idea.
My guess is that it must have been the answer to the code.
What?
That's right. That author had figured that out that,
the code was also written in hiragana.
Hiragana?
Are you for real, Conan?
Yeah. The letter was written using hiragana,
so you just needed to use hiragana, to read the symbols of the four corners.
I see.
Judging by the code on the letter and the painting, should be the same person who did all this.
But why does that person need to write that code, to my aunt?
That person probably didn't want other people do know besides her.
For example, if he was being chased by someone at that time.
Oh yeah, my aunt had said that
there was often a strange person who'd go and steal her mail
I'm guessing that person is the same criminal who did that to the toys.
So there really is a secret within this house.
Hey, is there really actual treasure here?
What? There's nothing here.
There's those symbols again, on the ground.
Wait! If I put them in order then... that would mean...
A SK-SKE-SKELETON!
Take this!
Next episode,
The Secret of the Moon, Sun and Stars! (Part Two)
Next Conan's Hint!
A 20-dollar bill.
Next time, it will be decoded finally.
Now I got it!
Huh?
I got it!