Shines with a flash, and pierces with a shatter, you can't stop it once it begins to move!
Today's case is a treasure hunt.
A small hint turns out to be big.
Seeing the one and only truth,
I look like a child but have mind of an adult,
My name is Meitantei Conan!
After helping a toy manufacturing company,
Professor Agasa received a sum of money, and took Genta and the others on a treasure hunt.
We arrived at the villa where the Professor's uncle lived.
However, it's been fifty years since Agasa's Uncle died,
but we've found some things to suggest that someone had been living inside the house.
Underneath objects such as vases and plates,
we found engraved symbols of the sun, moon, and the stars.
The toys hidden by the professor for the treasure hunt were discovered
completely destroyed, most likely by that same someone.
There's a big secret hidden within this villa.
As we searched the villa, we discovered nine things engraved with the secret code:
a card,
a French dictionary,
a record,
an airplane,
a wine glass,
a portrait,
and lastly, a mechanical doll.
Also, Professor Agasa remembered seeing the same Symbols, on letters that he received from his aunt.
The interesting thing is, the Professor showed those letters to a mystery novelist, my father.
Yes, he understood it too.
That the code is written in.
Hiragana!
Oh?
Hiragana?
Are you sure Conan?
Yes, it looks like the one who sent those letters.
And the one who wrote the secret code, are indeed the same person.
But then, why did that man write to my aunt in a secret code?
Besides your aunt, is there anyone else who had access to those cards?
Now that you mention it, my aunt mentioned that Someone weird was checking the mailbox.
That person was most likely the culprit who destroyed the toys.
As I thought, something interesting is happening inside this place.
The Secret of the Moon, Sun, and Stars
(Part Two)
The Secret of the Moon, Sun, and Stars (Part Two)
But how did you know the code was in hiragana?
What are you saying?
It's really easy to see when you know where to look.
Huh?
For example, the black sun, the white sun, moon and stars.
As well as the black moon and stars.
Forms change.
But the one black sun does not change.
In hiragana, what's the only character that stands by itself?
The one that stands by itself.
The only one?
I've got it.
It's gotta be "n", right?
That's right!
So the black sun stands for "n".
The second clue is all the engraved lines have one thing in common... The last 3 signs are the same.
They certainly have a special meaning.
I see what you mean.
Then we have another clue, The little black and white dots on the right side of some symbols.
Even though I don't yet know the meaning of the black dot on the bottom right side,
the probability that the black and white dots on the upper right side
stand for the hiragana's daku-ten and the handaku-ten is very high.
Hey, daku-ten and handaku-ten, what are they?
Didn't we learn this at school?
Daku-ten are the symbols that turn the sounds "k","t","s" into "g","d" and "z".
They're called ten-ten as well.
Handaku-ten are the signs that turn "h" in "p", like "pa", "pi", "pu", "pe" and "po".
So if we use the hiragana tables, we can find the matching signs for the code.
For example, the white moon without a dot, one with a white dot, and one with a black dot,
We can easily understand that the first stands for "h"
the second for the "b" sounds, and the last for the "p" sounds.
I see!
We can determine what it stands for, if we use the dakuten and the handakuten!
Okay, if we use that as a base, the code written on that glass is...
If we look at the first part, third sound is "n" and the forth begins with "p"...
What words do we have like that...
pantei (panties),
heapin (hairpin), perikan (pelican),
Hanpan (Ham Bread),
meronpan (Melon bread), karepan (Curry bread),
pasokon (Computer), Nippon (Japan), ran...
toranpu (playing card)...
Card! It stands for card!
That's it! That's gotta be what's written!
But wait... then that means...
Let's see, the code on candle stand would mean...
"Pu" for the first sound, "ra" for the 4th, and the third sound begins,
with a "p"... pu... pu... ra.
Puropera (propeller)!
Yeah! The propeller!
But wait, if that black moon stands for "ro", then that means.
propeller... ro... ro.
Miro (look at)?
Puropera wo miro (look at the propeller)?!
There's something written on the plane's propeller!
You're right!
There's a dot for the dakuten on the code, so.
The second sound is "bu", and the thirds is "ra".
bu ra wo miro...
bu ra...
a-bu-ra-e...
Look at the oil painting!
That means the portrait, right?
I see, it's all clear now!
The code is asking us to look at different things inside the mansion.
It means that the code was made up for a special purpose.
In other words, it must've been created to hide something.
And that thing, must be very important!
A... A treasure!
Alright, then to get it we just have to crack the code!
Yay!
Hey,
Do you really think that there's really a treasure hidden here?
Well, I'm not sure.
But I'm sure that something is hidden here.
Hmm...
So on the plate it's written.
The 3rd sound is n, the second is begins with either "b", "z", "g" or "d".
eto... ka-bi-n
Kabin (vase)!
The vase!
That one on the dictionary ends with "nro".
eto... n-ro
...da... danro...
The Fireplace!
Then on the mechanical doll, we have...
wa-i-n-gu-ra-su.
It's the wine glass!
Uh... Conan-kun?
Up until now we've figured out 17 symbols,
and I can deduce the rest, so...
What are you writing?
Hey everyone, look.
This is the full translation of the code.
Woah, cool!
If you look, it's easy to understand.
That the suns, stars, and moons, stand for A I U E O.
Then all we have to do is follow the hiragana order to understand it.
For example, if you remove one part of the suns and the stars,
the same with the moons, and you keep removing one after the other, turning clockwise.
They will match the hiragana table.
Then all we have to do is to complete the table.
Oh, I see now.
So if I translate the whole code we have something like.
This.
Look at the vase.
Look at the candle stand.
Look at the propeller.
Look at the oil painting.
Look at the record.
Look at the mechanical doll.
Look at the wine glass.
Look at the card.
Look at the dictionary.
Look at the fireplace.
The fireplace!
So the treasure's gotta be there!
I don't see anything like a treasure...
There!
There's another message.
Really?
Ayumi-chan, bring me what I wrote earlier!
Okay.
Here you go, Conan-kun.
So... the code is...
Hey, what's written there?
Yeah, please tell us.
Conan-kun!
Tell us.
Plate.
Eh?
Look at the plate.
Ehh?
Wait, by plate they mean the plate we already.
What a pile of rubbish.
So the code was fake after all.
No way.
It looks like it was a lousy joke.
A joke? No way!
People don't build such a good secret code for a joke.
But...
Did I mistranslate it?
No, It cant be that.
But then.
What did I miss?
What's the true purpose of the code?
It can't be helped.
Before the police come, let's clean that place and replace the objects where we found them, okay?
Yeah.
Hmmm.
The plate... was up there.
Wait...
If I change that and begin with the vase.
"sa", "ka, "ro", "ku", "are", "ni", "wa", "to", "fu", "ga".
No, that leads nowhere.
The vase was here.
Wait. What if I write it in romaji?
The candle stand was on the fireplace.
Nope, that doesn't work either.
Hey, Professor, where was that plane?
Oh, it was near the vase I just put over there.
Near the vase, near the vase...
Hmm, if I try to write it in English?
Wait, could it be French... or German maybe...
Darn, it leads nowhere no matter how I change it.
Doll, doll.
Heh?
Hey!
Do something too!
You're staying still in the center of that room, doing nothing.
Hey Professor.
Did you say that the card was in this room too?
Hmm? Yeah.
It was there, just under the clock,
I took it from there.
So that means that all the things with the code were in this room.
Wait!
If I follow the order of those items.
We start with the plate,
the vase,
the candle stand,
the propeller,
the oil painting,
the record,
the doll,
the wine glass,
the card,
the French dictionary,
the fireplace,
and the plate again.
They all converge to the center of the room!
That's why Ayumi chan keeps passing near me.
But that's strange, there's nothing on the floor,
and it looks like nothing has been on the floor for a long time.
Then if it's not on the floor.
There! At the base of the chandelier!
Professor, pull me up!
Huh?
Quickly!
Oh, okay.
Okay.
Eh... What's that noise?
Wha... what's happening?
On the second floor, It sounds like something fell down.
Let's see...
So, the room just above the one we were in...
This room.
What happened, Conan?
Oh, there's a stair case in the room...
So, that's what the point was!
The code was pointing at the chandelier in the middle of the ceiling...
In other words, at this secret staircase.
My uncle loved mechanisms like that.
But really, to do such a thing.
Maybe there's still a treasure there!
Yeah, something is hidden up there.
Alright, let's hurry!
Err, What's with this room?
It's all dark.
We can't see a thing.
Wait a second... Here.
Those are tiny parts of a 1 yen coin and... a tube of oil paint.
Look, there's something on the desk.
Is it the treasure?
Hey, what happened?
S-s-s-s...
What? Talk clearly!
A skeleton!
What?!
Who is it?
He's the one I mentioned earlier.
The one who used to hide here.
He's the one who whittled the one yen coin and made up the code.
Could it be... was he killed?
No, it looks like he was alive when he was writing a letter to your aunt.
It seems he had a weak heart.
But why was he living here?
The only ones who ever lived here were my aunt and uncle.
No, there was someone else.
Before your uncle died, someone came here.
Before my uncle died?
Oh! That painter.
Yes, the portrait of your aunt and uncle near the fireplace...
He's the one who painted it.
I'm sure he became aware of this secret place, when he stayed here to paint...
Yes, but why did he stay hidden here?
And why did he keep sending postcards to my aunt?
The reason must be this.
Huh?
What is this?
This is a...
20 dollar bill plate?! Counterfeit money?!
Yeah, I'm sure he was asked by someone to counterfeit money.
But he changed his mind and had to disappear and hide from that someone.
That's why he hid here.
He stayed here because he was ashamed of what he did.
And he wrote to your aunt in code, because he wanted her to know of this secret place.
But then, the person who checked my aunt's mailbox...
Yeah, that's probably the one who asked the man to make the counterfeits...
and the one who destroyed the toys, too.
Congratulations.
Indeed, I kept an eye on that old man.
Because I knew he was going to find the thing I was looking for.
But when I looked inside the box, there were only toys.
Too bad.
I searched this mansion for a long time,
I searched it all, but I never thought of a secret hidden room...
Thanks, kids.
Don't move!
Unless you want to see someone die.
Besides, if you'd used your head, you wouldn't have gotten involved in the first place.
Damn it.
The young lady over there,
Yeah, you.
Grab the plate from the old geezer, and give it to me.
Here you go...
There, you're a good girl.
Come a little closer and I'll give you a nice reward...
You brat!
I'm gonna beat you to a pulp!
Just wait a second.
I'll give it to you right away...
Mister Okuda Tomoaki.
Huh?
How do you know my name?!
Well, I asked that man.
He can't talk anymore!
Are you sure? If you listen closely, you might hear the voice of his ghost.
Ha ha ha... Brat, there's no such thing as...
Okuda Tomoaki...
Let me keep my promise, and give this back to you.
Catch this!
Conan-kun.
Let's run away.
Huh?
Yes, or the ghost might come back!
Oh, you're talking about that voice?
It was only this.
Masked Yaiba voice changer!
I recorded my voice when I said his name, slowed and then amplified it.
But how did you know his name?
Oh, that was written in code in the letter on his desk.
It said "The one who coerced me into this was Okuda Tomoaki".
Ah, so that's why he was writing her letters.
He wanted to thank her for letting him stay here...
What happened to your aunt?
She died last year. She was 76.
Looks like I'm the last one now.
We'll never know, but maybe there was more than a simple "thank you" in there.
Two hours later, the police came and Okuda Tomoaki was arrested.
And we were finally able to go home.
But I still don't understand.
Huh?
You know, those words your father said.
"For sure, Professor Agasa, you're a real sunshine!"
And since that time, he keeps calling me "Professor Sunshine".
Oh, that.
It's just a play on words...
A play on words?
If you write your name with the code.
Huh?
A - GA - SA
See, you only use suns to write it.
Oh, I see now.
That's kinda neat,
I am Professor Sunshine!
What? There's someone there!
Who?!
There was someone here.
That means... that we are not alone...
Just... to keep us silent...
I can't accept it!
Conan-kun!
Run, Mitsuhiko!
Next Conan:
The Case of Disappearing Detective Boys
Next Conan's HINT!
A bunch of puppets.
Next time, your gonna see the Detective Club's great skill.
I'm really excited!