As bright as a spark,
with a sharp and precise wit.
Once he gets going,
you can't stop him!
Today, the Detective Boys
are at a training camp!
Ayumi and Genta
have vanished!
He sees the single truth
for what it is,
and looks like a kid
but has the mind of an adult!
His name?
Detective Conan!
The Case of the Detective Boys' Disappearance
Serial lodge attacker...
Both hosts and guests
are victimized...
How scary...
Then again, it's just a simple
brainless robbery case.
There's no need to bring
in a famous detective.
Sheesh, dad...
By the way, I haven't seen Conan around.
Is he still crashed out?
Oh, Conan-kun's at a training camp
with the neighborhood kids' club.
What's that?
The kids' club's going to be
putting on a puppet show.
Puppet show?
Wait, training camp?
Yeah. They're at a lodge
on the Kirigaoka Plateau.
He'll be there rehearsing
with the other kids.
Oh, so he's with that
kiddie detective club.
But will they be all right?
How so?
The lodge attacker that was in the papers.
Oh, don't worry about it.
Yoko Okino - Last Concert of 1999 - Friday Dec. 31, Beika Dome
That's somewhere totally different.
But the Kirigaoka Plateau is famous for
the really thick fog that rolls in at night, isn't it?
Yeah.
What if they get lost?
Kirigaoka Plateau - Sasayuki Village
They've got at least one
grown-up with them, don't they?
Yeah, someone from the 3rd Ward
named Kaifu-san.
Hajime Kaifu (28)
Apparently back when he was in school,
he used to do puppet shows.
And this time he's helping the kids' club
with the script and the—
Sheesh, dad.
Er... "That's odd.
Another person vanished."
Wait, wait!
And Then There Was Only You
Genta-kun, you're not putting
any emotion into that line!
R-Really?
Alright, Genta-kun,
do it again!
"That's odd.
Another person vanished!"
So, next is Ayumi-chan's line.
Um... "Just what could
be going on here?"
Ugh. That Mitsuhiko's acting
like such a bigshot.
Next, that's you, Conan-kun.
Ah, er... "The killer
has to be in here."
Here I am, a high-schooler,
doing a puppet show...
I wish I hadn't come,
like Haibara...
I'm not into that kind of stuff.
Geez. I envy her character.
That won't do, Conan-kun.
You're playing a detective.
You need to put more force into the lines.
Be more dignified about it.
Right, Kaifu-sensei?
You don't need the sensei bit,
Mitsuhiko-kun.
This is my first time
doing this too.
But after all,
Conan-kun's role is...
Yeah. That's true.
Conan-kun,
give it another try.
Right.
"The killer has to be in here!"
The movement of the puppet
isn't quite right...
Geez. What's Mitsuhiko
all gung-ho about?
That Kaifu-san moved in near
Mitsuhiko-kun not too long ago,
and they really hit it off.
He even let him help write the story.
But wasn't this...
"And Then There Were None."
It's obviously named after the famous novel
by Agatha Christie, the Queen of Mystery.
I know it!
People are invited to this island,
and they get killed off
one by one, right?
Whatever, I'm starving.
Sheesh, Genta-kun...
Alright.
Let's call it quits for now.
We can take an hour for dinner,
and then try again.
Right!
Get the puppets together
so they don't get lost.
Right!
All right!
Time to eat! Time to eat!
Eel on rice!
Oh, Genta-kun...
Good work, Conan-kun.
Oh, geez...
'Scuse me...
But we're not there yet.
We need some intensive practice.
Intensive practice! Intensive practice!
Oh, geez.
That's some fog...
Well, it is called Kirigaoka Plateau.
Fog Hill
I'm stuffed! No good,
I can't move an inch!
Everyone, break for 30 minutes
and then let's get back to practice!
More practice?
Give us a break, Mitsuhiko!
There's going to be a
late-night snack, Genta-kun.
I'll do it!
I'll do it! Let's go!
Everyone...
Has anyone seen the teacher?
What's wrong?
It's strange...
He's nowhere to be found,
and it's already time to get back to practice...
Come to think of it,
the Third Ward guys ain't here either.
You're right!
Where could they have gone?
This isn't good...
Say. Have you seen them?
I thought so...
The Third Ward kids' puppets are gone!
You're right!
Teacher's is gone too.
Oh geez.
This is just like...
The Third Ward guys probably
took it with them.
But where?
I dunno,
maybe they went home?
This late?
In this fog?
Someone's outside!
No good. I can't see
a thing in this fog...
There's no doubt about it.
Somebody was definitely here.
Those kids are gone too!
W-What?!
T-The puppets vanished too!
The only ones left are ours!
Damn it!
This is some sick joke.
It's just like
"And Then There Were None"...
T-That's the story the
puppet show was based on...
Yeah...
In the original story,
the characters are killed one at a time,
and the figures are lost
as each one is killed...
K-Killed...
You can't be serious!
Then all the vanished kids are...
Oh, no!
Get it together!
We don't know that for sure yet!
The back door!
The fog's thick here too!
Footprints! They must be
the kids' footprints!
There's another pair,
adult footprints...
W-Whose are they?
The guy outside the window earlier?
No. They're a different size
and type from those prints...
Then, who...
The manager said this was the only lodge
anyone was staying at,
which... means...
I don't know. But something's definitely
going on at the cottages in the fog.
I got it!
Got what?
It's the work of that lodge attacker!
Lodge attacker? You mean
the one who was in the news?
Exactly.
No doubt about it!
He's got everyone locked up somewhere,
while he's planning to hit
all the other nearby lodges!
I-I see...
Alright, in that case, we, the Detective Boys,
are gonna nab that lodge attacker!
Agreed! Once again,
the Detective Boys move into action!
Good idea! Let's do it!
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
Oh, it's nothing...
But if it is the lodge attacker,
never mind the kids,
why did he take the puppets too?
This is full of things
that make no sense. Geez.
Anyway, we should probably
call the police for now...
After that it won't be too late
for the Detective Boys to get inv—
Huh?
W-What's up, Conan?
Y-You can't get a hold of them?
Yeah, there's no dial tone...
This means we're completely
trapped here in the fog...
What now, Conan-kun?
There ought to be someone in
the caretaker's office at the bottom of the hill.
Are you going there?
Yeah.
That's weird. I could've sworn there were
a flashlight and candles in there...
Yeah. When we got here, we checked
the emergency exits and saw them.
They ain't there?
Nope. Looks like someone took them.
Someone? Who?
Seriously, Genta-kun?
Who would it be but the lodge attacker?
No. We can't confirm that yet.
But if we just tried to get
to the next lodge, we'd get lost...
For now, let's look for clues
here in this lodge.
We won't find much.
Let's go, Conan-kun!
Ayumi-chan, stay here
with Genta-kun.
What am I gonna do
with those kids?
Genta, look after Ayumi-chan!
O-Okay.
Be careful, Conan-kun...
Mitsuhiko-kun...
Leave it to us!
Oh, geez...
I suppose this is Kaifu-san
and the others' room...
Let's go in.
What's this?
Looks like a map of the area.
Some of the lodges
are marked here and there.
What's this supposed to mean?
That's...
What's that?
Don't tell me...
Oh, no!
Kaifu-sensei is...
Genta!
Ayumi-chan!
Huh?
Genta! Ayumi!
Where are you?!
T-That's...!
What's wrong? Conan-k—
Oh, no...
The only ones left are ours...
I got it... I know...
The... teacher...
Kaifu-sensei is the lodge attacker!
The map and the toolbox are proof!
In order to attack
the Kirigaoka lodges,
he used this puppet play
practice as cover...
He even tricked us!
I can't let him get away with this!
Hold on a sec, Mitsuhiko.
Not only the kids,
but even the puppets disappeared.
This doesn't look like just
an attack on the lodge...
You're overthinking this, Conan-kun!
First of all, isn't Kaifu-sensei
the only one who can take the puppets out?
Well, yeah, but...
Anyway, we need to look for
Genta, Ayumi and the others.
That's right!
And catch the attacker!
With our own hands!
The closest lodge was
in this direction, right?
Yeah.
What's that? That's too close
to be the next lodge.
Still, let's check it out.
It's the others!
Kaifu...
Yikes!
He... He really did...
Huh?
Where'd they go?
We're going in. Hurry.
Looks like nobody's here...
No good...
I'll check the upstairs.
Conan-kun...
Stay here!
Please be quick...
Conan-kun!
Mitsuhiko!
What?
Conan-kun!
What's going on?!
What are you doing?!
Conan-kun!
R-Run! Run, Mitsuhiko!
C-Conan-kun...
Conan-kun?
This can't be happening...
Even Conan-kun...
Now, "And Then There Was Only You"...
Mitsuhiko-kun...
No... No!
Someone...
Anyone... Help!
Help, anyone! Help!
There's no use running away,
Mitsuhiko-kun...
Come with me, Mitsuhiko-kun.
Stay away, stay away!
Don't be so selfish,
Mitsuhiko-kun...
Now...
Hurry!
Uh oh, uh oh!
Oh no, oh no!
Thanks...
Conan-kun...
Everyone?
Then this is...
Sorry about that,
Mitsuhiko-kun.
Actually, we were doing some intensive
rehearsal for the puppet show.
I had them come to
this lodge one by one...
No way!
You never told me anything!
Sorry about that. I was going to
tell you four, but it slipped my mind.
So what were the pliers and
screwdrivers in your room for?
Oh, I thought I'd build
a simple puppet stage.
I wanted to put you all in the
atmosphere of the drama right away.
So, what about the map?
Of course, it was so we wouldn't
get lost on our way here.
I heard the fog was
incredibly thick around here.
So that's how it was?
The puppets that disappeared
were used to practice, of course.
You were shocked,
weren't you, Mitsuhiko?
Oh, you were scared to death too,
Genta-kun.
I wasn't really...
But when we were
doing voice practice,
you thought we looked
like we were tied up.
But that's really how it looked!
Right, Conan-kun?
Sorry, Mitsuhiko.
In the end even I scared you...
Actually, at that time...
Run, Mitsuhiko!
Calm down, Conan-kun!
You guys!
So that's what
this was all about...
Looks like Mitsuhiko-kun's
the only one left.
Everyone, go back
to your practice.
Wait!
He was being a hotshot
all day today.
Let's scare him a bit.
Isn't that a bit much?
But it might be good
practice for the play.
Oh geez.
They're really going all-in.
Not you too, Ayumi-chan...
What a shock!
Say, Kaifu-san.
Why did you go so far
as to cut the phone lines?
What are you talking about?
It wasn't you?
What do you mean?
If it wasn't you, then who was it?
D-Don't tell me...
Mitsuhiko!
Let's go!
The real lodge attacker!
You saw me!
No! Help!
Mitsuhiko!
Help me!
Conan-kun! Everyone!
S-So... The one who cut the phone lines
and stole the flashlights... It was...
Yes. It was all...
The work of the
real lodge attacker...
Stand back!
You don't care
what happens to him?
Don't worry about me, guys!
Get him!
M-Mitsuhiko!
You're a nuisance!
Shut your mouth!
You little...
Get him!
Yeah!
We did it!
That was close!
That was dangerous.
Safe...
Conan-kun,
close your eyes for a sec.
Close them tight.
Sorry about earlier,
Mitsuhiko-kun.
I've changed my mind...
I'm so happy!
Mitsuhiko! Damn you,
you're gonna pay for that!
Cut it out, Genta-kun...
Three days later, the city's kid's club opened,
and we performed our puppet show.
The outcome was, of course, a huge success!
K-Karakuri Pass...
Spider House?
A thumbtack?
The surface is rusty,
but the pin's still clean...
But Dad said not to leave the room.
Hey, old man! Wake up!
Ran's in danger!
The Mystery of the Spider House of Tottori
(The Case)
Next Conan's Hint: Number of fish
Next time, we're in Tottori
and Heiji takes the stage!
Huh? Heiji Tottori?
Heiji Hattori.