As bright as a spark, with a penetratingly precise wit.
Once he gets started, you can't stop him!
Today's setting is Karakuri Pass.
A spider's thread eerily tangles in the case.
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Tottori Prefecture - Karakuri Pass
That's weird...
I've got the feelin' we've been goin' around in circles.
Hey, Heiji...
Are you sure we're not lost?
I haven't seen any people or cars for hours,
and we can't call for help 'cause I forgot my cell phone,
and to top it off, the bike's outta gas.
We should've taken a taxi after all.
Shut up!
If it's the map of this area, just leave it to me...
Aren't you the one who forced your way onto the back of my bike?!
But what're we gonna do?
Takeda-san said in his letter that he wanted you to get to his place tonight, right?
Yeah, that's right.
He sent me this weird letter about a case, plus some money.
But he forgot to include his phone number,
so now I've gotta go return the cash in person.
Figgered I could crack the case, too,
but it's gettin' dark already.
Looks like we're gonna have to camp out...
C-Camp out?
No way! We're in the middle of the forest without a tent or even any blankets.
What if we end up catching a cold?
If we wear all the clothes we brought and huddle together,
we'll manage for a night.
I-If we huddle together...
Don't ya dare take advantage of me while I'm asleep.
That's what I should be sayin'!
Now, now, no need to start a fight.
Kazuha, let's pretend we didn't see him, and just move on. Okay?
G-Gotcha.
Ah, wait a second!
It's just a joke... a joke!
Robert Taylor (26)
Photographer
I'm Robert Taylor, an American!
I'm a photographer who's in love with the beauty of the Japanese countryside.
I was just snapping a few shots. This forest brings back memories.
I haven't been here since I visited Takeda-san...
Takeda? You know him?
Yes. I was just on my way to his house.
Hey, just like us!
Can you show us the way then?
Well, it just happened that I got a little carried away enjoying the scenery.
Don't tell me you're lost.
But aren't you going to Takeda-san's house too?
Looks like we're campin' after all.
No way in hell!
No choice. We're all on our own here...
Hey! Hold it!
I said hold it, didn't I?!
They stopped.
What do you think you're doing, punk?!
Ah, I'm sorry.
I never thought I'd actually hit ya...
It's you!
Oh, if it isn't Hattori-kun!
Which means...
I had a bad feeling about this trip.
What's that?
You've received a request on the case,
and you're on your way to Takeda-san's place too?
Yes.
But unlike you, I got a formal request.
The sender is Nobukazu Takeda-san, the head of the Takeda family.
I've received the nice amount of 500,000 yen in advance.
Then why'd I get this letter here?
Maybe there's another family around here called Takeda?
Hey, let me see that.
Sure.
Let's see...
"Come to the Takeda house at Karakuri Pass before the sun sets next Saturday."
"If not, another living puppet will become a victim of the spider."
Victim of the spider?
That's about us, all right.
We've been havin' them unruly events for a while now,
so everybody 'round these parts calls our place...
Yūzō Takeda (35)
3rd son of Takeda family
The Spider House of Karakuri Pass.
They say not to go near it if ya value yer life.
K-Karakuri Pass...
Spider House!
Misa-san passed away three years ago?
W-Why?
Yōko Takeda (33)
Ryūji Takeda's wife
Two or three days after you left,
she was found hanging on the second floor of the puppet shed.
Was it a suicide?
Yes.
And a few days later, my sister-in-law was found hanged in the same place as Misa's mother.
B-But why?
Well, I don't know.
And that's not all.
T-There's more?
Yes.
Just the other day,
Negishi-san, a man my brother-in-law used to know,
was similarly found hanging in the shed.
It quietly happened while everyone was out for the day.
Did he come here often?
Yes.
My brother-in-law makes puppets,
and Negishi-san was in charge of shipping and selling them.
It's about that Negishi-san.
The mystery Brother wants you to solve.
Dear...
Ryūji Takeda (38)
2nd son of Takeda family
I'm Ryūji Takeda, second son in the family.
You two don't have much of an accent.
Yes.
That's because we live in Tokyo.
We came back on vacation,
but when Negishi-san died,
my big brother asked me to stay around
until the detective showed up.
Oh, Detective Mouri.
Nobukazu Takeda (45)
Eldest son of Takeda family - Master puppet maker
I'm Nobukazu Takeda, your client.
Sorry for draggin' you out to the mountains like this.
Not at all.
I'll be honest with ya, Detective.
I've got a hunch that Negishi-san was killed by one of my folks here.
That's the situation...
If you find out who the murderer is, tell only me who he is!
And are those four all your children?
I thought you only had two kids with ya.
Oh, well, you see...
Excuse me, Nobukazu-san.
Long time no see.
Oh, Robert-kun!
It sure has been a while.
I haven't seen ya since summer vacation three years ago.
I came to see you to thank you for last time, but...
Well, come in!
Your good friends Sae and Emi have just come home too.
Oh, there you are!
Oh, Sae-chan! Emi-chan!
You've grown so much!
Murderer.
Emi Takeda (9)
Ryūji & Yōko's daughter
(younger sister)
Sae Takeda (9)
Ryūji & Yōko's daughter
(older sister)
He's come for his next victim.
He sure has.
How scary...
Real scary...
You two! What are you saying?!
Eek! Mom's scary too!
I'm sorry about that...
Oh, it's nothing.
Chie Takeda (71)
Mother of the Takeda brothers
Hey, Mother...
Why do Emi and I have only half a fish each?
Why?
I'm sorry...
We're two short because we only bought enough for the guests we knew were coming.
Please bear with it...
Ah, then, have this...
What's the matter, Kazuha?
I'll eat yer fish if yer not gonna.
You punk.
Delicious...
Huh? Where are you taking that?
Miyuki Shiotani (26)
Maid
To the mistress.
After the incident with Negishi-san,
she locked herself in her room, sayin' she was scared of the curse.
So I take her meals to her.
I see.
Alright!
I'd better go finish up the puppet I'm makin'!
Well then, Mouri-san...
Yes?
I hope I can hear your deduction tomorrow.
Okie-dokie!
Well then, relax and enjoy yourself.
Hey, Yūzō...
Don't you need to help Big Brother with his work?
What's the hurry?
Just one more drink.
Excuse me, may I borrow your car?
I'd like to go and visit Misa-san's grave...
At this hour?
Yes.
I should be able to see the moon and stars between the hills on the way there.
The moon and stars, huh?
Can I join ya?
Of course.
Hey, Ran-chan, wanna tag along?
Sure, sure.
Hey, Ran-neechan...
You want to come too, Conan-kun?
Take this along with you. You'd be in trouble if something happened.
Here.
If something happened?
Take it along, take it along!
I don't know what it is, but that kid is showing first-class jealousy!
Idiot! That's not it...
See ya later!
My dear.
I'm going to take a bath with the children.
Don't forget to keep the
bath fire going for me.
Okay.
Those two are suspicious, aren't they...
You're right.
Hey, Big Brother!
Big Brother!
Yūzō, what's the matter?
I can't find Big Brother!
He's not in the workshop or anywhere else!
What?!
What's that?!
What about the shed?
Did you look in the warehouse?
I looked in both places, but he wasn't there.
How about the second floor of the warehouse?
No, I haven't checked yet.
That's strange. The window on the second floor of the warehouse is open.
Ever since two people committed suicide there, nobody's gone near it.
The stairs are over there!
Hey!
It won't open! It's locked from inside!
Somebody, bring an axe or something!
Sure.
T-This is...?!
Brother...
Brother!
H-Hurry, call an ambulance!
Y-Yes!
That's not what you need.
You've gotta call the police, not an ambulance.
He's already cold...
I'm guessin' he's been dead for about an hour.
W...
What are you talking about?!
Don't come in!
This may be the site of a murder...
M-Murder?!
I got a letter...
A mysterious letter sayin' that if I didn't come here,
"another living puppet will become a victim of the spider."
"Another" means this has happened before!
I was hopin' to prevent another murder
an' crack the case,
but the killer got the better of me.
W-Who are you, anyway?
A pretty famous detective in the Kansai area.
D-Detective?
Well, I think I've heard about you...
They say there's a mighty smart kid detective down in Osaka...
But, is it alright? That kid is in the room too...
Oh, don't mind him! He's like an assistant.
A thumbtack?
The surface is rusty, but the pin's still clean...
Like it just fell out of something.
But what's it doing here?
Look, just hurry up and call the cops!
Y-Yes!
But if this is a murder, how did the murderer escape?
It must be that small window...
The killer must've used a rope or somethin'.
That's impossible.
You can see that window's barely big enough for a kid to fit through.
What?!
Wait a sec! We had to break into this room
'cause it was locked from the inside, right?
But the only escape route is too small for anybody to get through!
Then this is a locked-room murder.
It was the mistress.
The spider mistress used her six long legs to climb the warehouse wall,
and from the window, she strangled Nobukazu with her thread...
She wanted to get even with Nobukazu for building the shed here...
Frightening, frightening...
You too, detective. If you keep calling it a murder,
the Spider Mistress is gonna curse you too.
What's the Spider Mistress?
It's an old folktale in these parts.
A long time ago, a beautiful woman lived in this mountain pass
and asked questions of all the travellers who came by.
"Do you think there's a heaven?" "Would you like to go there?"
All the travellers were taken by the strange beauty of the woman.
When they answered "yes",
they disappeared into the depths of the forest and were never seen again.
One puppet maker heard of the rumor,
and put a human-sized mechanical puppet on the mountain path. Then he hid and watched.
As expected, the woman appeared and asked her questions.
When the puppet didn't answer,
the woman became angry.
Showing her true identity as a giant spider, she attacked the puppet.
Seeing this, the puppet maker shot the spider with flaming arrows.
The giant spider, engulfed in flames, escaped into the forest.
The puppet maker followed it
and found it burnt to death in its nest, along with its baby spiders.
The village people, fearing the spider's curse,
built a small shrine on that nest, calling it the "Spider Mistress".
And they came to call this pass "Karakuri Pass".
That's just an old fairy tale! Where's the curse come in?
This shed is built where that shrine used to be.
T-The shrine was torn down?
Yeah.
Father was a master puppet maker, and after Brother took after him,
he built this shed against the wishes of the villagers.
It was three years after the shed went up that his daughter, Misa-chan,
and his wife, Kinuyo-san,
hanged themselves there.
By the time we found them, they were in a miserable state, covered in cobwebs.
Then three years later, the other day,
Negishi-san died in the same shed, this time covered with string.
String?
His arms and legs were covered with the strings we use for the puppets.
Just like our big brother...
They look like cobwebs, don't they?
I see. That's why it's called the Spider House of Karakuri Pass.
Yeah. Somebody's usin' that old story to get away with murder.
Come to think of it, grave where Robert and the others went
is around the place where the Spider Mistress was supposed to appear.
Could it be...?!
Making Ran take that mobile phone was the right thing to do after all.
Damn, someone's on the house phone...
Hey, old man!
Lemme use your mobile!
Old man!
Here!
The mobile phone I borrowed. Who are you going to call?
Kazuha!
K-K-Kazuha, you're back...
What's the matter? You're out of breath...
I just told them an old ghost story about the place you went.
They turned pale and ran out after you.
Oh, you were worried about me?
Idiot! That's not it!
It started raining, so we cut our trip short.
This area gets a lot of landslides.
What's all the noise about, dear?
Well, actually...
What?! Nobukazu-san has died?!
On the second floor of the same shed?
Is that really true, dear?
Yeah. And the door was locked.
And the police?
Miyuki-san is calling them now.
I-It's terrible!
There's been a landslide and the police can't come until tomorrow!
Can't help it...
Robert-han, mind if I borrow your camera?
Go right ahead.
What're you gonna do with his camera?
What else? We're gonna do the investigation!
We can't wait until daybreak!
Who's "we"?
Who else is there? Me an' the old man, right?
Whatever. I'd like everybody to stay in their rooms until the police arrive tomorrow!
Don't wander off or mess with anything!
Huh? That's strange...
What's the matter?
My phone strap with the little mascot on it is gone.
I'm sure it was still there when I got in the car...
Maybe it's still in the car?
I'll look for it tomorrow, I guess...
Wanna go out an' look now?
Yūzō-san left the car keys that he had lent to Robert
and I have a pen-light.
But dad said not to leave the room.
It wouldn't hurt to just take a peek.
How is it? Is it there?
Doesn't look like it...
I probably dropped somewhere in the mountains... Darn...
Maybe it was when you first got in the car.
Remember, you dropped your phone and picked it up in a hurry.
It was probably then.
Was that mascot that important?
It was that Kudō-kun who bought that mascot, wasn't it?
It's no good trying to hide it! It's written all over your face!
Boy, I envy that guy Kudō-kun!
You think about him so much. Where has he gone?
If I were a man, I'd take you away from a cold guy like him!
Shin'ichi isn't my guy! And he isn't cold!
He always seems to be watching over me.
Is he here?
Nope... It just feel that way, somehow.
If I'm not mistaken, it was in this area where Robert parked the car
and we came running over.
Yeah... Ryūji-san called out to us.
I dropped my phone when I turned around.
Oh no! The battery's dyin'!
There's some batteries in my CD player, so I'll go get them!
She's really a nice girl...
Oh, geez. Leaving a nice girl like that alone...
That guy Kudō... Where could he be roaming around?
Huh? What's this? This white ball.
It's come after all...
It sure has...
We saw it, didn't we?
We did, we did... The spider's thread...
It's frightening, isn't it...
Frightening, frightening...
Hey, what's that sound?!
Shh! It's the stairs!
Heavy feet... It's not Ran...
Who could it be...
Kazuha! Where are you?!
Kazuha!!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Misa & Sae & Emi
Next time is the shocking Suspicion Part!
So that's where it was!
What was?
My mascot.