As bright as a spark, with a penetratingly precise wit.
Once he gets started, you can't stop him!
The case at the Spider House becomes more complicated.
Ran and Kazuha are in a dangerous situation!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
We were called out to the Takeda home at Karakuri Pass in Tottori Prefecture.
Heiji Hattori and Kazuha Tōyama got lost in the forest.
and met up with a foreigner by the name of Robert Taylor.
We happened to pass by and find out that we had all been called out to the Takeda home
to solve the mystery of the curse at the "Spider House of Karakuri Pass".
On the night we arrive, Nobukazu-san, the eldest son of the Takeda family,
committed suicide on the second floor of the puppet warehouse.
Then someone suspicious appeared behind Kazuha...
Mystery of the Spider House of Tottori (The Suspicion)
I'm sorry, Kazuha-chan! I found the mascot I was looking for!
It was caught on the lid of the CD player...
Kazuha-chan? Where are you?
Kazuha-chan's penlight...
Kazuha-chan...
Kazuha-chan? Kazuha-chan!
Hey, check this out!
Looks like he's been hit on the back of the head with something!
What?!
Then, the killer hit him, and...
Yeah. The estimated time of death is about 9:00 PM,
just around the time Nobukazu-san left the living room.
At that time, he had already been called out by the killer.
The killer met Nobukazu-san here and hit him on the head,
knocking him unconscious, then strung him up by the neck.
Yeah. Then he tangled the body up in strings
to make it look like the "Spider Mistress" curse.
But I still don't get it...
How did the killer escape from the room after committing the crime?
Nobukazu-san's sandals and flashlight scattered on the floor also bother me.
It's also strange that there's no dust on the shelves and floor.
The room was supposed to have been left alone for three years.
Hey, kid.
Oh, that small window...
It's just about big enough for a kid to get through.
You think it's important? Was it left open for a reason?
No... I thought I heard...
Ran's voice just outside the window.
And Kazuha-neechan's voice too...
Idiot. Those two are probably in their room, fast asleep.
Hey, what was that sound?
The stairs!
Someone's coming up the stairs!
Heavy feet... It's not Ran...
Who'd be coming here?
Never mind...
Let's meet him in person and ask what the reason is.
Oh, it's the housekeeper.
What's the matter?
I thought you'd be hungry, so I brought you some rice balls and tea.
Oh, this looks delicious.
Kazuha-chan? Are you here?
If you're here, answer me!
Kazuha-chan!
So you were friends with Misa Takeda-san, the girl who died three years ago?
Yeah. We were nurses at the same hospital.
But the work was too hard for me, and I quit...
I became a housekeeper here through Misa's introduction.
Thanks.
Misa was a really nice girl, always attentive and kind...
But why?
Why does a person like that have to commit suicide?
Just maybe... it could be because of that...
Misa's father, Nobukazu-san, came home from the hospital for some reason.
He grabbed his wife, Kinuyo-san, and was very angry.
He said, "You really deceived me for the past 20 years!"
Deceived him? About what?
Well, I have no idea...
And that's when Misa got badly hurt.
Badly hurt?
Yeah.
Misa went between them to stop the fight, but Nobukazu-san pushed her away.
She hit her head on a pillar, and had to have seven stitches in her forehead.
Misa became gloomy, and rested from work at the hospital...
until she met Robert.
Robert?
Yeah.
The day of a landslide three years ago, Misa happened on him.
He was caught in a landslide while taking pictures, and was badly hurt.
Unfortunately, the hospital rooms were full that day.
Misa had no choice, so she had him treated at the hospital
and brought him here and took care of him.
In the beginning, she had a hard time taking care of him.
The inside of Robert's mouth was cut up from the landslide,
so he couldn't speak well.
Robert could speak Japanese, but it seems he couldn't read or write it,
and the conversation with Misa took place on paper with Roman letters.
But when Robert got better and was able to talk,
they seemed to be enjoying things.
They told all sorts of jokes...
"Japanese foods are delicious, especially on rainy days,
dirt and sand are excellent"
"I'm a prince of a certain country, and I came to find a bride who is like light"
By the time Robert's wounds had healed and a farewell party was to be held,
Ryūji-san and his family were home, and he became friends with them too.
Misa also became bright again.
But that makes it more confusing...
Wasn't it two or three days after Robert went home that Misa-san committed suicide?
I don't really know,
but after Robert went home, Misa became gloomy again.
She suddenly disappeared, and everyone thought she ran away from home.
Yūzō-san is the one who found Misa dead on the second floor of the warehouse.
And several days later,
her mother, Kinuyo-san, also committed suicide in the warehouse...
After the two died, was there anybody who had a change in attitude?
Well...
Nobukazu-san came to the funeral without tears or sad expression,
but on the other hand, Ryūji-san was the one who was a big problem.
He cried in a voice so loud it echoed throughout the neighborhood.
The others would be Sae-chan and Emi-chan...
Oh, those twins...
The two of them were such good friends with Robert,
but two years ago, when they came back to visit,
they suddenly started saying something strange.
It was Robert...
Robert is the one who killed Misa-neechan...
Isn't it terrible...
Terrible, terrible...
But why did the children say something like that?
I don't know...
Negishi-san, who came to pick up the dolls, was also surprised.
Because after they talked to him, they suddenly started saying those things.
What did they talk about?
Well...
Negishi-san said they only asked him his name.
That's the Negishi-san who died in the shed the other day...
Everyone was out to attend to the neighborhood gathering.
Yōko-san came home ahead of the others to prepare dinner and found him in the shed.
Weren't you around then?
I was with Nobukazu-san, buying groceries at the supermarket for dinner.
With Nobukazu-san?
Yeah.
After his wife died, Nobukazu-san took over the household finances.
By the way, the rope used to hang Nobukazu-san, and the string around him,
can they be found in this warehouse?
Yes, for the string...
there's a lot of it because it's used to make the marionettes.
The ropes are in the shed. Would you like to go and see them?
Gee, it's raining hard.
Hey, Kudō, do you know who the killer is?
Nope... Not who the killer is, or the locked room trick...
Not a single lead...
After Nobukazu-san left the living room,
Robert went to the shed to get the car, and left with Ran and Kazuha.
He didn't go near the warehouse even once. It couldn't be him.
Yōko-san, who was in the bath with the twins,
and the housekeeper who was cleaning up in the living room with us,
and the old lady who was in her room, are also clear.
Yeah.
The only ones who could have done anything are Ryūji-san, the one making the bath...
and Yūzō-san, who was looking all over the house for Nobukazu-san.
But something bugs me.
Something...
The string, right?
Right, right. That's it.
Why did the killer have to use the string to make it look like a curse?
It was a locked room.
If he didn't do that, we would have thought it was a suicide.
And that request letter that was sent to you also bothers me.
Yeah.
If it was sent by the killer...
Is he taking me lightly and challenging me?
There's something fishy about this case.
Let's see, the rope...
Is somebody there?
R-Ran?!
What? Kazuha's missing?!
Really?!
Yeah... Only her penlight was on the ground...
I thought someone carried her off and panicked...
Anyway, let's split up and look for her!
Kazuha! Where are you?!
Hey!
Kazuha-chan!
Hey, have you found her?
No... She's nowhere to be seen!
What's the matter, Hattori?!
The door to the warehouse...
I thought I closed it, but it's open!
T-This is...
K...
Kazuha!
Hey! Hang in there, Kazuha!
Kazuha! Kazuha!
Hey! Kazuha!
Heiji...
Kazuha!
W-What... happened to me?
I remember... waiting for Ran-chan in front of the warehouse...
I suddenly felt faint...
Be quiet! I'll cut you loose right now!
K-Kazuha-chan!
No need to worry.
Looks like you were just hanging with the strings.
I'm sorry! I'm so sorry, Kazuha-chan!
I didn't search hard enough, and got you into this terrible situation.
Then... The mascot...
I'm sorry... I found it...
It was caught on the lid of my CD player.
I'm so sorry... If I'd taken a closer look...
I'm glad you found it. Don't lose it again.
Hey, Hattori...
Yeah, I know.
Old man, please take care of Kazuha.
What?
Don't you get it?
The killer tried to use our blind spot by hanging Kazuha up
in the warehouse we were in a while ago.
After leaving, the killer brought Kazuha here, and wrapped her in the strings.
Then all that remained was to put that rope around her neck,
and the curse would be completed.
There's only one reason the killer had to stop.
The killer noticed my footsteps when I ran over here, and left in a hurry.
Which means the killer is still here, in the warehouse!
Hey, Kudō. Are my deductions wrong?
Nope. Not at all.
Then, let's take a look at the killer's face!
Hey, is he around?
No...
That's strange. It hasn't been 3 minutes since we came to this warehouse.
We were guarding the entrance on the first floor, so there's nowhere to hide!
The only place to escape would be that tiny window.
Is it really possible?
Is there a way to get out through there in such a short time?
This time that girl from Osaka was attacked?!
B-By who?
I dunno!
Kazuha is resting in the room right now, but she may remember in time...
...one of the faces among you!
One reason we had you gather here
was to prevent any more murders from taking place.
The other was to confirm your alibis!
Alibis? We were asleep in our rooms all this time.
It's the same for me.
I was in my room too, but I wasn't asleep...
Where were you? I didn't see you when we were searching.
I was searching outside the house.
In other words, nobody has an alibi.
Y-You're kidding...
Hey, Yūzō-san's not around...
Yūzō? Wouldn't he be in the workshop?
Oh, me?
I was here working the whole time.
I was putting the finishing touches on the doll Brother had to complete by tomorrow.
You can make dolls too?
Three years ago, my company went bankrupt, and I came back home.
Brother taught me all sorts of things and let me do the simple constructions.
Three years ago... That's the time of that incident.
Yeah. I came home just after Robert left.
But I wasn't allowed to make fixtures or do repairs.
Brother's marionettes cost ¥1,000,000 apiece, and he charged ¥700,000 for repairs.
He sold them for ¥1,000,000 and repaired them for ¥700,000?!
Can he do business like that?
Yeah.
Seems like there are some people who request repairs more than ten times.
He charged quite a bit for the marionettes.
With the money he made, he often went abroad with Negishi-san to play.
After leaving the sales to Negishi-san, the dolls began to command high prices.
Hey, what's that big doll?
Oh, that's the marionette of the "spider empress".
When Father was alive, dolls of that size were used at every festival
to do plays of the "spider empress".
But the number of people able to handle dolls that big gradually disappeared,
and they quit doing it.
What are those boxes that are stacked up?
Oh, those are the dolls that Negishi-san was supposed to take that day.
After Negishi-san died, Brother realized he was one doll short.
The customer called directly and he had to make one more.
Anyway,
please stay in the room everyone is gathered in.
It's dangerous to be by yourself.
Yeah.
Alright, now's our chance.
The repair fees for the dolls are extremely high.
Despite the price, there are customers who request repairs more than 10 times.
A simple puppet that's expensive means
what's inside is probably...
narcotics!
As for the marionettes,
you can only put the narcotics in the head, so the price is cheaper.
I've got it!
Now I know why Nobukazu-san called a detective
to find out who the killer was.
A large part of the entire picture has come into view.
What's left that we don't know is the locked room trick
and why Kazuha was attacked.
Sae? Emi?
What is it? What's the matter?
The two daughters I brought to the restroom aren't here!
What's that?!
- Mother...
You worried me!
Didn't I tell you to wait in front of the restroom when you were through?
But there was a smell!
There sure was! A funny smell!
It's probably the spider children burning in the furnace!
They're burning!
Grandmother said so, didn't she...
She did! She did!
Furnace?
It's true, there's something strange burning in here...
Hey, come to think of it... What was the meaning of that?
You said it, didn't you? You called Robert "murderer"...
The day Robert was leaving,
Misa-neechan told us to go and ask him what his feelings were,
so we went to the bus stop!
We asked him, "How do you feel about Misa-neechan?"
Then Robert wrote a terrible thing down on paper!
- Didn't he?
Terrible thing?
- He wrote, "die!"
Die?
It's terrible!
Terrible, terrible...
Don't let it bother you.
The children probably saw wrong.
I shouldn't have shown that business card.
Business card?
Let's see, I'm sure I have it here...
Here it is!
They found this name card inside the wallet and made a lot of noise.
They asked, "Who did you get this from?" "Where is this person?"
Hey, look at this!
I got it out somehow!
Hey, this is...
Don't tell me...
Isn't that a stun gun?!
Kazuha!
Oh, Heiji! I feel much better now.
Take off your clothes!
Just let me see!
What're you doing?!
Hey, Conan-kun!
Why am I the only one to get hit?!
Well, I'm a kid.
It's here.
Small burn marks on her back...
So she was knocked out with a stun gun.
And? Did she say anything else?
She didn't see the killer,
but she said she found a strange ball in front of the warehouse.
Ball?
She said it was a ball about this small.
BB shot!
That's it!
I never thought of that!
If that's so...
That thing...
Should be somewhere...
In this room!
I found it! Hattori, it's here!
The marks of a thumbtack!
I found it too!
Strange string with loops on the beam ends!
It's just as we thought, isn't it?
Yeah.
There's no mistake... That person is the killer!
The killer didn't need to escape from here!
T-That's crazy!
It was to avenge Misa-san, who committed suicide in this warehouse three years ago!
M-Misa-chan's revenge?
There's only one person who could have done it without anyone noticing!
And that's you!
Mystery of the Spider House of Tottori (Case Closed)
Next Conan's Hint: Roman letters
Next time, the solution at last!
Next time, it'll be the killer who gets caught in the web!
I see!