[ Misa -> Sae -> Emi ]
[Misa]
[Sae]
[Emi]
[11:10]
[ED]
[NEP]
Flowing water has no form.
A blowing wind can't be seen.
All cases can be freely deduced!
The mystery of Trick Ridge is coming to an end!
Heiji and I solve the mystery perfectly!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Hattori and Kazuha are called out to the Takeda home
on Trick Ridge in Tottori Prefecture.
The two get lost
and meet up with a foreigner by the name of Robert Taylor.
We were also called out to the Takeda home
and accidentally met up with them on the way there.
We were called to solve the mystery of the curse of the "Spider Mansion of Trick Ridge".
On the night of our arrival,
Nobukazu-san, the eldest son of the Takeda family,
committed suicide on the second floor of the warehouse.
In addition, Kazuha was attacked
and found tangled in strings in the same warehouse!
T-This is...
Kazuha!
Business card?
Here it is!
I got it out somehow!
Hey, this is...
Don't tell me...
Isn't that a stun gun?!
She didn't see the killer,
but she said she found a strange ball in front of the warehouse.
Ball?
She said it was a ball about this small.
(BB shot!)
(That's it!)
(I never thought of that!)
(If that's so...)
I found it! Hattori, it's here!
I found it too!
Strange string with loops on the beam ends!
Yeah.
(There's no mistake... That person is the killer!)
[Mystery of the Spider Mansion of Tottori (Case Closed)]
He figured out who the killer is?
D-Did Mouri-san really say that?
That's right.
He said for everyone to gather on the second floor of the warehouse.
Ah...
He also said to bring that big doll in the workshop too.
And also, it would help if there is some spare gasoline.
Oh, geez. What's that kid from Osaka up to?
Bringing the corpse down without permission...
Did he really say to wait here?
That's right.
Here it comes...
Oh, you're all here.
Well, let me start
to tell you about the many incidents
that have happened here at the Takedas' home.
H-Hold up, Mouri-san...
When we found Brother, the door was locked from the inside.
There's only that one small window,
barely large enough for a child to get through...
I don't think it's a curse,
but if you say there's a killer,
will you first explain
how the killer escaped from this room?
If there is a way like that,
I'm the one who'd like to know how it was done.
Yes...
The killer had no need to escape from here.
That's because when Nobukazu-san was killed,
the killer wasn't in this room!
N-No way!
Then how did he do it?
The strings used for the puppets!
The killer used puppet strings, ropes and thumbtacks
to commit this locked room murder!
The setup is simple.
First, the rope is set up so that the loop closes when it is pulled,
and it is tied to the beam.
Then with small loops made on both ends of the string,
the loop of the rope is pulled to four corners,
and fixed to the small window with thumbtacks.
Another long string is attached to the base of the loop of that rope.
It is put over the beam in the center of the room,
and leads out the small window.
And the setup is complete.
Look!
Like this.
L-Little boy...
All that remains is to call Nobukazu-san out here,
make him look out the window,
and pull the string.
The loop of the rope closes, and killing Nobukazu-san is possible.
But why did Brother lock the door?
A-And...
Anyone would think it strange if he was told by the person he was waiting for
to look out the window...
He locked the door
because it was something important and he didn't want to be seen.
He looked out the window because he probably heard a sound.
A sound?
Yes.
The killer fired BB shot at the window with an airgun
so that Nobukazu-san would look out the window.
It was to take revenge
for Misa-san, who committed suicide here three years ago.
R-Revenge for Misa-chan?
Yes.
The killer probably thought
that Nobukazu, having found out that Misa-san wasn't his real daughter,
went hard on her, and forced her to commit suicide.
N-Not his real daughter?
W-What do you mean?
Isn't that right, Ryūji-san?
D-Dear?
I'm sorry, Yōko...
I knew I had to tell you sooner or later...
But Misa...
That child...
is the daughter made between
Brother's wife, Kinuyo-san, and me!
Y-You're joking, aren't you? Dear?
It's true.
It was before I met you...
Kinuyo-san was told at the hospital that Brother could not have children.
And she pleaded with me in tears...
"He wants a child", she said... "Please make his dream come true"...
That was the first and last time...
Brother and I have the same blood type,
so he wouldn't have found out.
Until three years ago,
when the doctor at the hospital slipped his mouth...
Misa ended up committing suicide,
and Kinuyo-san, feeling responsible, followed her...
It's... It's all because I listened to her plead...
Dear...
But how did you know I was Misa's father?
Kinuyo-san and I didn't tell anyone...
Her name.
Misa-san and the daughters of you and Yōko-san,
Sae-chan and Emi-chan, resemble each other
and form a circle...
I recognized that and knew...
You secretly made the names of your daughters have a relation to one another.
It also seems like you were unusually upset
at Misa-san and Kinuyo-san's funerals...
But Mother named all the daughters...
I knew!
I named the three to form a circle for you.
Don't take an old person for a fool!
When Kinuyo-san came home from the hospital with the baby...
I knew right away from the way you two acted.
But I didn't think you'd take revenge for the daughter's suicide
that Nobukazu was responsible for...
making it look like the curse of the spider empress!
You're disgusting!
Mother, you're wrong!
I didn't kill Brother!
Ryūji-san isn't the killer.
I said it, didn't I?
The killer fired an airgun at the window,
and when Nobukazu-san looked out the window, the string was pulled
and he was killed.
Even if it was a locked room,
if someone made movements in front of the warehouse like that,
he'd immediately be suspicious.
The way this setup was done,
there would have to be superhuman strength used
or the rate of failure would be very high.
To make it successful,
you would need the strength
to pull the thumbtacks on all four corners off at once.
There's only one person who could have done that
without being noticed by anyone!
You!
There's only one person who could have done that
without being noticed by anyone!
You!
You used the car to visit the grave with the girls...
Robert-san!
You're the only one who could've done it!
After dinner,
when you were going out to visit the grave,
you parked the car in front of the warehouse
and waited for the girls to come running over to the waiting car.
You could have shot at the warehouse window from the driver's seat.
And beforehand, you could have lead the string out the window
if you tied it to the car before dinner.
All you would have to do is drive the car off.
You'd be able to pull with great strength.
The string that was left on the car
was retrieved in the mountains when you stopped to look at the scenery,
and was thrown away somewhere along with the airgun.
Please wait a minute!
Yes, I'm definitely the one who moved the car,
but it could've been someone else who tied the string to the car!
Besides, I haven't been here for three years. I just got here today!
I completely forgot where the house was, and got lost.
From the time I got here to the time we went to visit the grave,
I was with you almost the whole time.
I wouldn't have time to rig something like that...
Wrong.
It hasn't been three years since you visited.
It was only a few days.
That's right.
You killed Negishi-san and rigged this setup on that day.
W-What?!
That's why only Negishi-san was killed in the shed.
He avoided this room that was rigged with the setup.
He called the high school detective from Osaka with a strange request letter.
He made the meeting on the road look accidental
to make it look like he hadn't been here for three years.
No one would suspect someone who was lost
and picked by an Osaka detective on the road
to have something like this set up beforehand.
B-But why kill Negishi-san?
Well, I don't know that yet.
but I know for sure that Robert-san found out
about Misa-san's suicide and the narcotics at that time.
N-Narcotics?
Right.
Nobukazu-san worked with Negishi-san
stuffing the dolls with narcotics
and selling them at a high price.
Brother dealing narcotics?!
That can't be true!
If you don't believe me,
check the dolls in the workshop later.
The dolls are filled with narcotics.
And after killing Negishi-san,
Robert stole one of the narcotic-stuffed dolls that he was planning to take with him.
The next day, he made the plans to call Nobukazu-san out to this room.
"If you're interested in narcotics, I've got some good drugs. Wanna make a deal?"
That's probably what he said on the phone.
Nobukazu-san suspected someone in the family of killing Negishi-san and stealing the drugs,
and he jumped at the phone call!
He was called out to this room, where the trap was set
and he was murdered.
Am I wrong?
Stop!
You don't have proof and you're making false accusations!
And you're forgetting something important!
Explain the mystery of why Nobukazu-san was tangled in the strings!
Was he really?
Yeah.
Hey, old man! I'm ready!
Right, right!
I completely forgot about it until you mentioned it...
that thing about Nobukazu-san being tangled in the strings.
That setup has been taken care of.
Hasn't it, Conan?
Look. It was dark and you probably didn't see it,
but strings are attached to the rope that's tied to the beam!
Proof rather than discussion... Let's actually try it.
Then, Yūzō-san...
Stick the head of the doll you have out the window.
Sure.
Like that.
Just like how Nobukazu-san looked out the window.
Robert confirmed the situation and then moved the car away.
The string tied to the car is pulled,
and the thumbtacks come loose.
As the rope choked Nobukazu-san, it pulled in the opposite direction,
and the back of Nobukazu-san's head bangs against the beam.
The string is pulled more, and it snaps.
Nobukazu-san's body dives into a sea of strings
and tangles from the ceiling, as if tangled in a spider's threads!
The question, Robert-san, is...
How did you know that Nobukazu-san's body was tangled in strings?
The only ones among you who knew about it
were Ryūji-san, Yūzō-san, Chie-san and Miyuki-san, the four who came to the crime scene.
Of course, those four were told not to tell anyone about the crime scene.
And one more person...
in other words...
the one who rigged the setup to kill Nobukazu-san!
Robert...
How...
How did you know?
It sounds funny!
You kept everyone from talking and waited for me to make the slip!
The number of fish.
The fish we had for dinner...
The unexpected guests were supposed to be the three of us—me, Kazuha and you.
But she was short only two fish.
That means that you were an expected guest that someone had already invited.
At first, I thought that you and Yōko-san, who bought the fish, were suspicious.
But hearing that Nobukazu-san handled all the money,
the only suspicious one left was you.
I sensed something was going to happen.
Nothing had happened yet,
so I let Kazuha go to visit the grave with you.
But Nobukazu-san was murdered, and I panicked.
If you were the killer, you might have run off with Kazuha to find Ran.
You dangled Kazuha in the strings on the first floor of the warehouse
but didn't kill her, to make it look like a curse,
and to create an illusion to make us think that there is a way to escape from this room.
Of course, there's also the reason that Kazuha found the BB shot...
B-But why? Why even Negishi-san?
Several days ago, when I came by here, he said this...
>If it's Misa-chan you're looking for, she committed suicide after you left.
>Nobukazu was picking on her anyway.
>Well, it can't be helped. She wasn't his real daughter.
>A girl like that... Nobody'd marry her anyway.
>There'd be nothing good even if she were living.
With eyes that were high on drugs...
He laughed and told me that!
I desperately learned to read and write Japanese
because she wasn't good at English...
I was finally able to come and meet her...
I looked forward to seeing her smiling face...
But don't you think you overdid it, putting Kazuha in that situation?
I didn't care who got hurt, or who suspected me!
Even everyone in this household, who let her die!
Hey, I didn't plan on telling you, but I'll tell you anyway!
When Misa-san was in an unstable state of mind,
when she was conversing with you in roman-Japanese,
(Stop, Hattori!)
The real reason she committed suicide was...
maybe... just maybe...
"Shine" ?
That's right.
S-H-I-N-E is "shine".
It means to be bright.
Maybe for Robert, Misa-san was a bright light.
Light?
Come to think of it, Robert said
he wanted a bride that was like a light...
We've got to apologize to Robert!
Apologize?
Because it was the same as the letters from Uncle Negishi's name...
so we thought Robert wrote a terrible thing and gave it to Misa-neechan.
We thought he wrote "die" (shine)...
Morning came, and Robert was taken away by the Tottori Prefectural Police.
In the police car,
Robert repeated the same words over and over again...
"Why wasn't I Japanese?"
"Why wasn't she American?"
Like a broken puppet,
he repeated over and over again...
Hey...
Why did Robert go off with the police?
Why? Why?
But the killer is the spider empress...
We saw it!
Before we went to take a bath,
we saw that long spider's thread coming out of the warehouse window!
Oh, that's probably...
No.
It's the doing of the spider empress.
Robert just went back to his country. There's nothing to worry about.
You're right!
Yeah!
Hey, Granny, tell us a story again!
How about The White Rabbit of Inaba?
We've heard that one before!
(It's Grandma, after all...)
How pretty!
What's that?
(Drowning?)
In other words, due to some sort of accident,
she wasn't able to escape from the shell.
(No. This isn't an accident!)
(It's premeditated murder!)
Next Conan: The Kiss of Venus
Next Conan's Hint: Cosmetics
コナン「次回は」
蘭「水もしたたるいい女～」
コナン「の事件！」