Just as water flows without shape,
and wind blows without form,
no case can stop you from deducing the truth!
Venus born from a big shell,
But, behind the beauty lies a horrible trick!
Seeing through the one and only truth,
he looks like a child, but his mind is of an adult.
His name?
Detective Conan!
The Venus' Kiss
THE VENUS' KISS
Beika City Aquarium
Wow!
Such amazing facilities!
Yeah, true.
Hey, hey Dad!
There... Look, look!
Isn't that where the show will take place?
Wow...
Hey, hey, don't you think that's just beautiful?
To think that a woman is going to come out of that shell!
But even so...
Isn't there too many people?
Let's just head home.
How can you say that?!
After all, we got invited here by one of your fans.
Mouri-san,
Sorry to keep you waiting.
I am in charge of the costumes' performance technology.
My name is Hayashi.
Hayashi Masato (40)
Ah, thank you for inviting us over.
And, the lady is...?
She's the main actress of our show...
Oosawa Michiko (25)
I'm Oosawa Michiko.
I have been a huge fan of Mouri-san for quite some time now...
And I wanted you to come see our show.
Ah, don't embarrass me...
I've been looking forward to watch your show too!
Hey hey, didn't you say you wanted to go home already?
Um, excuse me, how long can you hold your breath underwater?
How straightforward can you get?
Ah... sorry...
Well... You see... She's really been looking forward to seeing your show.
Oh, really?
Let me see...
Maybe about 4 minutes.
If you're that interested,
Would you like me to show you around the backstage?
Yes!
Then, come this way please.
Well, this is the control room.
All the lights and music used for the show...
as well as the operation of machines are all done here.
This is the employees' locker room.
And this is the make-up room.
Oosawa-san and the other actresses put on their make-up and change costumes here.
And then, that door at the end of the corridor.
That's a waiting room for the actors awaiting their turn... and behind that,
there is a hatch that connects to the inside of the shell in aquarium, that you just saw.
Oh...
Wait a second, Hayashi-san.
Please don't explain so much of the behind the scenes.
You're spoiling the mystery of my show!
Oh, well, I didn't mean to do so.
Ah! Murakawa-kun!
Let me introduce him.
This is the head of the staff, Murakawa-kun.
Murakawa Yasuyuki (44)
He has over twenty years of experience.
Hello.
And this person here is Minegishi Yuriko-san.
Minegishi Yuriko (30)
Hi.
She counts as another Venus in this group.
Oh...
Minegishi-san,
Have you not changed yet?
You're the first one to perform, you know!
Yes, I know.
Don't you see I was on my way in doing so?
Jeez!
She has no professionalism in her at all!
Not even when there are guests in here.
Besides,
The only Venus we need here is me,
don't you think so, Mouri-san?
A-Ahh...
Well, it's about time for me to start getting ready too.
Please take your time and enjoy the show.
Ahh... She sure is some woman.
Her father is the President of the Oosawa Constructions.
Oosawa Constructions...
You mean the one-man managed company?
Yeah, he was involved in the construction of this aquarium,
but now he has started to get involved in the management side as well.
That's why his daughter acts the way she does.
I see...
Well, it's about time I go to check out the equipments.
Ah! Sorry to have stopped you.
It's okay, I'll be leaving now.
Let us return to the audience seats now.
You guys can go first.
That guy just dropped a towel.
I'll hand it to him.
Conan-kun!
Uncle!
You dropped this.
Ah, thank you. Sorry, but my hands are busy right now.
Can you place it on the shelf over there?
Sure.
Do you always do an inspection?
Yes, people's lives depend on it.
Your work must be tough.
What are these buttons for?
The red one above is a switch that stops the water flow,
and the blue one below is a switch that lets the stored water flow out.
Eh? So you can control the water flow from here?
The water flow is controlled by the guys up there, at the control room.
However, if something happens out there, you will be drowned unless you are able to stop the water from here.
Oh yeah...
Okay, that should do it.
Little kid, you should return to the audience now.
The show is about to begin.
Yes...
Wow, so many people in the audience.
It's starting now.
So pretty.
How can they train those fish so well?
It's a smelling bag.
Eh?
Look! It seems she is clutching something in her right hand.
The fish are following the smell from that bag.
Wow...
I'm so excited, it is Oosawa-san's turn.
Wha... What the...
Eh?!
The victim is Oosawa Michiko-san, Age 25.
She is the main actress in the underwater show.
And Mouri-kun just happened to be here again?
Yeah... well, we received an invitation.
The cause of death appears to be drowning.
Drowning?
In other words, she was trapped inside that shell,
Unable to escape and eventually drowned.
Hmm, it could be because of a technical malfunction,
but we need to investigate it more.
Her make-up is peeled off...
Inspector, the make-up on her face seems to have been scraped off.
Hey you! Messing around the scene of crime every single time!
He is right.
I guess it could have scraped off when she was drowning.
Then she must have hurt her leg somewhere and drowned, right?
Hmm? Why do you say so, Conan-kun?
Because behind her left kneecap, there is a bandage.
What?
Hey, there is!
Let me see...
Hmm... this is one of those medicine wraps.
Medicine wrap...
Once the actors were in position, they would close the hatch, and that would turn on the light here.
After confirming that the light is on, we would let the water into the shell.
When the shell is about 80% filled, it turns blue and the water stops automatically.
So, was it working as usual, today?
Yes,
Me and the other staff members were controlling everything from this room.
There's no doubt about that.
Does the lady often used to have medicine wraps while swimming?
Eh?
It's you again! My patience has a limit, you know?
Excuse me...
Did Oosawa-san have a medicine wrap on her?
Yes, at the back of her left knee.
What is it?
She had once hurt her left leg before, and almost drowned back then.
Did she mention anything on it today?
No. If she had said her leg was hurt, the show would have been canceled.
She might have been trying to hide her pain because of her strong professionalism.
So you mean...
While she was standing for her turn, her leg must have started to pain, and so she drowned.
It's hard to believe this for a swimming professional...
but it's not impossible.
Yes...
If there wasn't anything wrong inside the shell, then your deduction is most likely right.
The waterproofing is perfectly fine,
and there doesn't seem to be anything wrong.
So, as long as everything was properly operated,
nothing should've gone wrong.
Yes, even if the control room messes up,
You can just press a button and the water will rush out, and you can escape.
So that means, she was unable to press the button for some reason.
Eh? This is...
Hey, Takagi-san.
Ah, no you can't Conan-kun! You shouldn't be here.
What is that?
What?
This is.
Foundation.
Why is it at this place?
So before Oosawa performed,
She was putting on make-up in the make-up and changing room?
Yes, exactly.
It is worth mentioning that she was very concerned about what the audience thought of her.
So, she would always double check her own clothes and make-up, just before the performance.
Did you, Minegishi-san, come out of the shell after going in once?
What are you talking about?
Didn't you just say that her death was an accident?
Once Minegishi-san was ready, we immediately let the water in from the control room.
So, I'm sure she couldn't come out.
I see...
Then how about you two?
We were both operating from the control room.
During the show I went to the restroom once.
Hmm?
Conan!
What are you doing here?
Hey ma'm, whose lipstick is this?
That's Oosawa-san's.
She didn't even clean up properly before leaving...
Looks like she was in a rush.
Oosawa-san was always so meticulous.
It's very unusual to see her so careless.
Hey, it looks like something dropped.
It's the cover of a medicine wrap.
It might be that her leg suddenly started hurting, and she panicked.
I wish she would have told us at least.
That's...
That's how it is! I got it now!
This wasn't an accident, it's a planned murder!
And...
The culprit is...
Oh, Inspector Megure!
Takagi-kun, how was it?
The position of the shell and the controls in the control room,
All seem to be normal.
Just to be sure, I am thinking of having him test run it.
Hmm...
Then there is the mechanism under the shell,
where, in this one place, there was a foundation stain.
It matched with the part of Ms. Oosawa's cheek that had scraped off.
I see...
Looks like it came off while she was struggling with the pain in her leg.
It looks like this was an unfortunate accident.
Hmm.
Everything's all ready here, we can start anytime.
Please begin.
Okay, let's begin.
Okay.
The lock's on.
Okay, I'm letting the water in!
Okay.
The water's in. So far no abnormalities.
Okay,
Try testing the emergency drainage device when you can.
Okay.
What? What happened?
That's the emergency bell.
The water inside has stopped, meaning that something has happened.
I see...
How is it?
No problems; the water's stopped already.
Now it's draining.
Okay, then just continue let it fill the tank.
Looks like there wasn't any problems.
Now all we have to do is wait for the water to fill up, and open the shell.
It's your turn now, uncle.
Water filling complete. Water level's all normal.
Okay, now it'll open the shell, so come up here.
Thanks for your work.
Okay.
It's over, everything is normal.
Thanks for your work. It looks like it really was an accident.
Please wait, Inspector.
Ah, it's that pose!
This really wasn't an accident. It's a well planned murder.
Ah?!
What are you talking about, Mouri-kun?
I just figured it out...
Who the murderer is, and the subtle trick they used.
Trick?
What do you mean, murderer?
At first, I had deduced that, Oosawa-san must have suffered pain in her leg
while she was inside the shell, and thus drowned...
But as the test before just proved,
the emergency drainage switch inside of the shell works fine.
For Oosawa-san, who could hold her breath underwater up to 4 minutes,
It is hard to imagine that she drowned without having the time to press the button.
What's more... She had a pro's personality,
who was always conscious of the audience.
Would she really put on a medicine wrap during the performance?
I thought something was a bit funny too.
What do you mean?
In the past, when she hurt her leg,
she would put on a medicine wrap during practice,
but she hated it during real performances and would take it off.
And besides, when I met her for the first time today,
she was wearing high heels.
Someone with leg pains wouldn't be wearing high heels, I suppose.
But on the body,
there was indeed a medicine wrap on her leg, wasn't there?
That was the act of the culprit.
Ah? Eh?
Then, why would the culprit do that?
As Hayashi-san just said,
Oosawa-san did hurt her left leg in the past.
If a medicine wrap would be found on the body,
One would naturally lead to think that the death was by drowning.
So, do you mean the culprit was trying to distract us from the truth?!
That's right.
Then when did the culprit put the medicine wrap on her leg?
Before the show began...
The culprit attacked Oosawa-san in the make-up room,
put the wrap on her leg, and carried her to the shell...
Eh?
Then who is the murderer?
At that time, I was performing.
Hayashi-san and I were operating in the control room.
How would I have the time to kill her and move her body inside the shell?
It is true that it requires some time to drown someone to death.
But if you drug her first and then move the body, it wouldn't take long.
For instance, if you say you were going to the restroom,
nobody would be suspicious.
Restroom...
That means...
Yes, the culprit, Murakawa-san,
is you!
No way!
Murakawa-kun?
N-Nonsense!
There's evidence.
Oosawa-san was said to be very meticulous, yet her cosmetics had been left out there...
That's the biggest evidence that she was using them when she was put to sleep.
And then, on the floor of the shell's tank,
A foundation, believed to be hers, was found.
To make sure that the unconscious Oosawa-san would drown, you had to glue her face to the ground.
Had she struggled while drowning, and that's how the spill ended up there...
Isn't it strange that the foundation was found only at one spot on the floor?
I see.
Afterwards... If you flood the shell from this room...
Oosawa-san would swallow the water and drown to death.
Huh...
Those out of whack deductions and circumstantial evidence.
You can't really call that conclusive, can you?
Don't you already have the conclusive evidence on you?
Huh?
On your back...
right by the base of your neck.
Eh?
Excuse me!
A lipstick mark!
T-That's Oosawa-san's...
It probably got there when Oosawa-san was being carried by him.
But what's that mark doing there?
There seems to be have been some stains on the staff sweat shirts too,
and it seems that somebody has tried washing it.
I checked the one hung in the locker room, and I found faint traces of a lipstick mark on it.
But you don't know when this mark was made!
It may have rubbed off when I passed by her through the narrow corridors.
No. That's impossible.
Please take a look closely at the mark.
The mark is upside down!
That's right.
In short, except for when the carried victim was lowered,
there's no other way the lipstick would've gotten there!
Oosawa...
She's a person that deserved to die.
Two years ago... my wife and my child were killed in a hit-and-run car accident.
Don't tell me that the driver was...
Yes... it was her.
When her dad came here, I accidentally overheard their conversation.
She was laughing at how I wasn't aware of anything.
That woman didn't have even a bit of remorse.
Not even a bit.
It's too bad...
Everything was going well thus far...
It can't be helped...
It was a murder case after all.
If a murder occurs, the show can't go on, right?
Besides, I've got to cooperate with the investigation too.
Yeah...
I'll take you to some other place next time.
For example, how about this place?
There's tons of girls in swimsuits.
DAD!
No, wait, the aquarium!
Come on!
Just kidding! Just kidding!
So, let's go home.
I-I think I just sprained my back.
Give me a break...
She sure is an energetic grandmother.
No way, a black out?
Next Conan
The Blind Spot In The Darkness (Part 1)
Next Conan's Hint
Fuse Box
Look forward to the next episode
Next time it is the doctors!
I hate needles.