Just as water flows without shape and wind blows without form,
no case can stop you from deducing the truth!
Today, Kogorō gets a huge scare at a hospital,
and Ran's also acting pretty weird.
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Yeah. I'm gonna be away a little longer...
Geez, what've you been doing?
Everybody at school is worried!
Well, I don't have a choice.
'I'm on a really tough case', right?
Look...
Oh, sorry, Shin'ichi! I have to go or I'll be late.
What?
Bye! It's getting colder, so be careful so you don't catch a cold!
Hey...
I don't know why, but Ran's been acting weird these days.
She's kind of cold over the phone, and she doesn't cry 'Shin'ichi! Shin'ichi!' like she used to.
But the weirdest thing...
Conan-kun, I'm going out for a while.
Dinner's on the table. Warm it up in the microwave before you eat!
Uhh, okay.
...is that she goes out every afternoon and only comes back late at night.
She claims she's got extra training for the karate club tournament.
But it doesn't really fit.
She always looks so... happy.
Then, one day...
What? You've been going to the hospital?
Yeah. We're about to get the results of my tests.
Are you sick, Dad?
Maybe. I've been feeling very tired lately.
You've probably been drinking too much.
Exactly! You didn't have to pick us up from school for this!
It's probably nothing...
The doctor told me on the phone
to bring my closest relatives along.
H-Hey, don't tell me...
Kogorō Mouri-san!
Mouri-san.
You have six months.
I'm very sorry about this,
but you have six months...
How could you do this to me?!
Suddenly telling me that
I only have six months to live!
If I have that serious a disease, you should've told me earlier!
You're a doctor, aren't you?
Serious disease?
What I was trying to say was that you have to refrain from drinking alcohol for six months.
Alcohol?
That's right.
According to your blood test, you've got a case of alcohol-induced cirrhosis of the liver.
Though it's not too serious yet.
Figures.
But you scared me, Dr. Araide!
You made me bring my family and all!
With patients like you, who like to drink so much,
Yoshiteru Araide (51)
Local Practitioner
cooperation from the family is essential.
Just cut down on the amount
you drink each day, and—
No way! I won't let him drink a single drop!
H-Hey!
You've got a phone call from Sugita-san.
She wants you to make a house call.
Not again...
She's one tough patient.
It's just a gastric ulcer,
but she's so worried about it.
Yōko Araide (46)
Yoshiteru's wife
Patient? Yeah, right. More like mistress...
Oh, sorry.
Please wait a moment. I'm sure he'll be off the phone soon.
E-Excuse me.
Could I use your toilet?
The public toilet seems to be broken.
Oh...
Let's see...
On the way, I turned right at the end of the corridor, so...
Here?
That means the examination room must be right up ahead...
This house is so big...
I'm sorry... I wasn't looking...
Oh, no. It was my fault.
Here. That should be all of them.
Ah, thanks.
Er, you are?
I'm Mouri's daughter. He's seeing Dr. Araide.
Oh... Mouri-san...
Tomoaki Araide (25)
Yoshiteru's son / Doctor
I'm the doctor's son, Tomoaki.
I help my father out here at his clinic.
But I'm going off to work at a hospital in Aomori starting next month.
You again!
When are you going to get used to working here?
And after you begged me to hire you as a maid!
I-I'm sorry!
Come on, Dad...
You know getting too riled-up is bad for your heart.
Listen up! Screw up again, and you're fired!
Ugh! I've had enough of this!
Hikaru Yasumoto (22)
Housemaid
Thank you very much!
Remember to stay away from alcohol if you want a long and happy life!
You even have the same name as that other Kogorō Mouri-san...
Haven't you heard of him?
He's a great detective.
Oh, no. You see, that's...
What? You're really him?
That's right!
Oh, when I saw your name, I did wonder, but I didn't expect that you were really him.
You had me fooled completely,
pretending to have no medical knowledge!
Why don't you join me for dinner tonight?
We can exchange ideas about forensic medicine!
Uh-oh!
W-We can't! I've got homework,
and Ran-neechan has karate practice!
Right?
Oh, it's fine. Since they're inviting, we might as well go.
I can skip practice once in a while.
I knew it. Something's wrong.
'Araide Clinic —
Closed for the day'
You graduated at the top of your class at Tohto Medical School, Tomoaki-san?!
Wow!
Isn't that right, Tomoaki-san?
I was lucky, that's all.
Hey, how about you marry my daughter?
Dad!
I think you'd make a fine couple.
Come on, Mother...
Are you all right?
Be careful! The chawanmushi is hot!
I'm sorry...
Oh, that reminds me...
Weren't you going to make arrangements for your class reunion tonight?
You're right! I have to call Masae!
Hey, if you ever think it over, let me know.
We could be like Holmes and Watson!
Together, we can solve any mystery!
I think I'll pass on that.
I'm not sure a detective and a doctor would make a good pair.
The real job of a doctor isn't to find the murderer by performing an autopsy,
but to save the victim from death in the first place.
You've got me there.
I don't know which one would be Holmes though.
Right, Ran-nee...
...chan?
Ran?
I wonder what's taking your husband so long.
His clinic should've closed by now.
He's taking a bath.
That man always takes a bath before dinner.
Mitsu Araide (74)
Tomoaki's Grandmother
He dirties the water for everyone else.
Grandma! Don't talk like that!
Well, traditionally the breadwinner of the family enters the bath first.
Breadwinner, my foot!
He's the one who married into my family, so he's got no right to put on airs!
Grandma!
You're the only blood relation
I've got left in this house!
But you're leaving home next month...
You're practically telling me to die!
Grandma!
Er, what about dinner?
I don't want it!
I have no interest in eating around strangers!
Please don't let her bother you.
Grandma's been in a bad mood since Dad changed the bath and toilet to Western style.
Western style?
Yeah.
She was very annoyed when he replaced our antique cypress bath with a modern tub and shower curtain.
She says it's a dishonour against the house's tradition.
Well, she sure is an energetic old lady.
No way, a blackout?
I think it's just this house.
The lights are on next door.
Are you okay?
Um, I think there's a flashlight
in that drawer over there...
Found it!
I'll go take a look at the circuit breaker!
Will you be all right?
Yeah.
Watch your step, Hikaru-san.
Right.
What? What's going on?
We've got a blackout.
Oh, is it raining?
Sounds like it.
This sucks.
Oh, it's back.
Oh, sorry! I mistook you for Dad...
What's going on?
Oh, Mother...
And about the fee...
Right. I think ¥30,000 is too much...
Are the lights back on?
Silly girl! Can't you see?
I think we should check on Dad in the bath.
I bet he's upset about all the lights going off.
I'm worried about his heart too.
Good point.
I'll go.
I'll go with you!
What caused the blackout, anyway?
Who knows?
It could've been a short-circuit, or too much electricity being used at once.
What is it?
That came from the bathroom!
Dad!
Don't touch him!
If you do, you'll get an electric shock too.
Electric shock?
Hey, don't tell me...
There's an extension cord
connected to this electric razor.
I'll try to resuscitate him.
Mother, go get the drip with the cardiotonic!
Hikaru-san, call an ambulance!
Hurry!
R-Right!
Oh, and call the police, just in case.
O-Okay!
It looks like he was shocked when that electric cord fell in the water.
He could've been using that mirror over the bathtub to shave.
But why would he shave in the bath?
Wait a minute.
Could it be?
I'm sorry to report that Yoshiteru Araide-san has passed away.
He did have a weak heart to begin with...
T-This... This can't be happening...
In what state did you find Yoshiteru-san?
Oh, right.
He was slumped in the bathtub
with his head facing this way.
But why'd he use an electric razor in the bath?
It was a habit of my husband's.
He always did it while keeping his guests waiting...
He even got a mirror that wouldn't fog up.
But wasn't it strange for him to take a bath and keep his guests waiting?
Dad loved taking baths. He always took a bath in the morning and before dinner.
He thought it was important
for doctors to keep clean.
He deserved it!
This was divine retribution
for not listening to Chiaki!
Chiaki decided to punish him from above!
Grandma!
Who's Chiaki?
My mother. She died in a car accident four years ago.
She always told him not to use the electric razor in the bath.
She said it was dangerous to use it with the cord attached.
Then, Yōko-san, you're...
I'm his second wife.
We got married two years ago.
Chiaki and I were in the same
class at nursing school,
and she often talked about him.
Inspector! Take a look!
If you stand up to shave yourself in front of the mirror,
the socket of this extension cord
comes right to the edge of the bathtub.
This sure is risky...
Where were all of you
when the blackout occurred?
In the kitchen.
My mother-in-law wasn't, but I saw her climb up the stairs at the other end of the corridor.
Then Yoshiteru-san was using the electric razor in the bath,
and accidentally pulled the cord into the bathtub, causing a deadly electric shock.
A simple accident.
Right.
Hey! No fooling around!
But I'm so confused, I've got a splitting headache!
Oh? Why?
The man who died was shaving himself standing up,
and Takagi-san was pretending to be him, right?
Then when he felt the shock,
he should've fallen over like Takagi-san,
with his head on this side, right?
But that man's head was facing the other way! Why?
That's true...
That could've been...
Isn't it obvious?
While Yoshiteru-san was shaving himself,
he noticed that the cord was
about to fall into the bath,
so he turned around to pick it up, but ended up pulling it into the bath instead.
Then he happened to touch the handrail, electricity flowed through him with a shock,
and he fell into the bath.
Something like that, anyway.
Not too shabby, old man.
Hey, don't play with that razor, Uncle!
Isn't it an important piece of evidence?
Play? I'm just holding it!
Then was it you, Takagi-san?
Huh? I didn't mess with it.
Then the man from forensics?
I-I just took photos...
Weird. Then who could've played around with it?
What are you talking about?!
The razor's switched off! See?
What's this mean?
Y-Yes, it's strange...
If this man died of an electric shock while shaving, the razor should be on.
Detective Takagi must've pushed the power switch when he fell!
Like this!
Huh? I thought we unplugged that thing!
We did. I'm holding the plug now!
I see! This is a rechargeable shaver!
Then why was it turned off?
Nobody touched it since you found the body, right?
No.
Maybe it's the sound?
Somebody didn't want the sound of the shaver to be heard!
Who didn't want who to hear it?
Beats me! I'm just making guesses!
Maybe somebody wanted to sneak the cord in the tub while Yoshiteru-san was taking his bath
without catching his attention.
You idiot!
If somebody did that, he'd have noticed it even without the noise!
And everybody has an alibi during the blackout.
Come to think of it, when the light came on, it went off again for a moment before coming back.
Hikaru-san, you're the one who reset the breaker, right?
Y-Yes!
Did you by any chance flip it twice?
Oh, I'm sorry!
I thought I might have flipped the wrong switch.
A different breaker shut off,
so I quickly flipped it too.
I-I'm really sorry!
Inspector, the second time the breaker jumped, could it have...
Right.
The killer could create some sort of timer to cause a blackout,
then use the opportunity to sneak into the bathroom and drop the cord into the bathtub.
Then any one of those four...
...could have killed him.
Hey, why are you whispering?
Never mind! I was wondering if we could hear what you were doing during the blackout.
Didn't we just tell you our alibis?
Are you saying there's a murderer among us?
We just want to be sure, that's all!
So you were on the phone the whole time?
Yes.
From before the blackout to the time the lights turned back on,
I was talking on the phone next to the kitchen.
I was talking to my friend Masae about our class reunion.
Oh, and my call waiting went off too.
But the person on the other end just hung up without saying anything.
Takagi! Go check that out!
Yes, sir!
During the blackout, I dug out the torch and handed it to Hikaru-san.
After that, I was in the kitchen the whole time.
Can you prove that?
Er, well...
Tomoaki-san was here the whole time.
From the point when Hikaru-san went to reset the breaker,
I grabbed onto Tomoaki-san the whole time. I was scared!
The whole time?
Why?
I told you, didn't I? I mistook him for Dad.
Next, Mitsu-san. Where were you?
When the lights went off, I'd just finished climbing the stairs.
I groped my way back to my room upstairs.
But when the lights went on, you came back down the stairs to the kitchen.
I felt a presence just as I was about to go to sleep.
Like someone was just outside my room.
You mean...
Someone else may have
been inside the house?
That's what I thought.
I followed the presence downstairs and discovered...
W-What?
It was only the sound of rain.
I see.
And finally, Hikaru-san...
Yes!
I went to reset the circuit breaker.
I'm not used to this house yet,
so I got lost at first.
And you didn't see anyone suspicious?
No. Nobody.
I knew it.
Geez.
I was wondering why you kept touching your arm.
You still put up with everything.
A burn mark?
Excuse me. Can I go down to the clinic to treat her wound?
Sure. But go with the
detective waiting outside.
Want to keep watch, huh?
Oh, and one more thing!
You're the only one who left this house today, from 5 to 7 PM.
Where did you go?
I coach the high school basketball team.
Their coach used to teach me,
but he broke a bone and asked me if I could take over for him until he recovers.
A doctor and a sports coach?
If you don't believe me, ask Ran-san.
The team I'm coaching is at Teitan High School, the same school she goes to.
You know Tabuchi-sensei,
the basketball coach, don't you?
Oh, yes!
Oh, no.
Is that why Ran went out to karate practice at school every evening?
It couldn't be...
It couldn't be!
I knew it.
Could you go take a look at the breaker?
Yes, ma'am!
But why another blackout?
Come to think of it, that man said he was running an experiment in the bath.
Don't tell me that Dad...
You're the killer, aren't you?
On the next Conan: 'The Blind Spot in the Darkness (Part II)'!
Next Conan's Hint: Burn wound!
Next time...
Not good... Ran's feelings are...
Huh? Were you there, Shin'ichi?