Just as water flows without shape and wind blows without form,
no case can stop you from deducing the truth!
People's feelings are the key to solving this case.
I want to find out how Ran really feels!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
kimi to boku to wa betsu no ikimono dakara
We couldn't be less alike
konomi ga chigau aruku hayasa mo
We like different things, walk at different speeds
omoi no tsutaekata mo
and confess our feelings in different ways
iroasete-yuku futari no kioku no naka ima boku-ra wa
Now, sorting through the fading memories of our time together
tesaguri dakedo hoka no dareka o mirai o sagashite-iku
we're blindly searching for someone — for a future
omo'u yori tsuyoku ikite
Be stronger than you ever thought you could be
tokubetsu na ai motomete'ru
Seek out the special one for you
shitataka na hibi ni nayandari
Though some days may not go so well
true heart for mystery eyes
A true heart for your mystery eyes
mō nido to mayowanai yō ni sono ude o hanasanaide
Don't ever let go of my arm, so I never lose you again
kizutsukeau sono toki mo
Even when we may hurt each other...
tada zutto kotae o sagashite mayoikonda toki no naka de
Every time I was lost, simply searching for answers
tsugi no basho e you take your way
You were already moving onward...
dakishimete
Hold onto me...
I feel so all in secret life
For that's my secret life
The old man only has 6 months left to live!
Well, that's what he thought he was hearing.
But he was actually just being told to stay away from alcohol for 6 months.
The doctor, Yoshiteru Araide-san, invited us to stay for dinner at his house.
But after a short blackout, Yoshiteru-san was found dead in the bathtub!
A doctor and a sports coach?
If you don't believe me, ask Ran-san.
The team I'm coaching is at Teitan High School, the same school she goes to.
T-Then...
Ran went out to karate practice every evening to see this guy?!
I see.
Is that right, Ran-kun?
Yes. You can check with the high school as well.
May I go? I've got a burn to treat.
Yes...
Oh, and you need to come to the clinic too, Grandma.
It's no use hiding it!
I noticed you were limping just now,
like something's wrong with your foot.
Foot?
W-What happened to your foot?
While I was coming downstairs in the dark, I stepped on something strange.
May I go help him treat everyone?
Sure, go ahead.
Inspector!
I got a hold of the person that Yōko-san was talking to on the phone when the lights went out.
Oh, and...?
She said that the time it took since Yōko-san told her the lights went out
to the time she reported that the lights went on was about a minute.
I'd like to get Yōko-san to give her side of the story to ensure it matches.
Is that okay?
Yes.
Can I help treat everyone first, though?
Um...
If you don't mind, I can assist the doctor instead.
I'm pretty good at stuff like that.
Okay, you can take over for me.
Her story matches.
The only time they weren't talking
was the six or seven seconds she took to answer the call waiting.
So Yōko-san was on the phone throughout the blackout.
Yeah.
Of course I was!
Say, do you have a floor plan of this house?
Yes. I'll get it.
This is the bathroom where your husband died.
Then we must be here, right? This is the kitchen.
Yes.
Where's the circuit breaker?
You go left from the kitchen and turn left twice, then right once...
It's right here.
Hikaru-san, the maid, left the kitchen to check the breaker
around the time you told Masae-san about the blackout, right?
Yes.
Then it's odd that you were without light for a whole minute.
It looks like it'd take less than 30 seconds to get to the breaker from here.
Hikaru-san has just started working here. She's not used to the house yet.
But when your stepson saw that Hikaru-san'd burnt her arm,
didn't he say something like
‘You still put up with everything'?
Oh, Tomoaki-san took care of Hikaru-san during his clinical training at Tohto Medical School.
Her appendix almost burst because she ignored the pain for too long.
Is that how Hikaru-san ended up here?
Yes.
With my mother-in-law getting on in years,
I can't take care of this household alone,
so I hired her as a live-in maid.
It's embarrassing, really. Chiaki took care of the whole house by herself...
Chiaki?
Oh, Tomoaki-san's late mother...
She died four years ago from a car accident, right?
It seems she was driving drunk.
I still can't believe it — she'd always been a light drinker, since she knew she couldn't hold her alcohol.
By the way, where's your mother-in-law's room?
It's upstairs.
You take the stairs to the left of the kitchen.
It's the first large room.
An old person like her living upstairs?
Yes. She loves the view of the garden from that room.
I gave Hikaru-san the room next door,
so she could help if anything happened.
Inspector, the killer must've tried to call Yōko-san as a distraction.
While she answered the call waiting,
the killer slipped past the kitchen,
entered the bathroom,
and put the cord into the tub.
Don't be stupid. How would she get out?
Oh, right.
What are you whispering about?
Oh, nothing.
Hey!
Why don't you have everybody do what they were doing during the blackout?
You know, that's not a bad idea.
While their memories are still fresh...
I'll go get them!
You're good with the bandages.
Thanks!
I knew a boy who used to get injured all the time, so I got to be an expert.
But that was a long time ago.
Hey!
Geez. The nurse shouldn't get injured.
But it's not serious. We can just wash it and put on a plaster.
Um...
Uh...
What's the matter, Conan-kun?
Er, the Inspector's calling for everybody.
Got it. We'll be right there.
Hikaru-san!
Y-Yes?
Could you hand me a plaster from that cupboard?
Okay!
Silly me...
What am I thinking at a time like this?
Let's see...
The breaker should be at the end of this hallway, to the right.
Aha!
There it is!
Hey, Conan-kun...
Be careful! This is where Hikaru-san dropped the vase!
I helped her pick up the pieces.
I felt so sorry for her.
Yoshiteru-sensei got really mad.
He even threatened to fire her!
Wait a minute. That could mean...
Okay, are you all ready? Let's get started!
Roger. We're ready at the stairs!
I'm in place, in front of the breaker!
Okay, Takagi! Kill the breaker!
Yes, sir!
Hikaru-san, could you go to the breaker?
Y-Yes!
34 seconds.
As I thought, it took less than a minute.
Inspector, look.
If you cross this garden,
you can get to the bathroom without sneaking past Yōko-san on the phone.
Come on, you don't mean...
Yes. There was enough time for her to do it.
H-Hey, wait...
Would you cut it out?!
Haven't we told you?
Everybody in this house had an alibi before the lights went out!
So why keep bugging us about what happened during the blackout?!
We need to...
Wait.
We just had a terrible accident, and you're amusing yourselves with your ugly theories!
Um, er...
Have I done something wrong again?
No, no...
Their alibis...
Only one of those four people has a really solid alibi for the time of the murder.
Of the remaining three, one is very suspicious.
A fragment of something!
Is this red mark blood?
And what's this weird thing stuck to it?
Could this be...
I knew it.
So that's how it happened!
Which means that there's only one person who could have been the killer!
Ten seconds, round trip.
So she did have the opportunity.
Then, the thing that we were concerned about...
Yup. It's not even an issue...
Hey! Don't tell me, it's come?
Yes. A light bulb just went on in my head.
I know the truth behind the case.
If you could take me to the bathroom, I'll explain everything.
My back hurts a bit, so it'd help.
Hey, hey.
What? He wants to take a bath?
Mouri-san said that?
He got wet in the rain,
and he wants to see if you can really get an electric shock by using that razor in the bath.
Where's the Inspector and the others?
The detectives said they
were leaving for the day.
No way! What a shame!
What do you mean?
'Cause Uncle Kogorō said that once he gets out of the bath,
he'll put on a deduction show for everybody!
Did Mouri-san really say that?
He's figured out who the killer is!
The killer? But didn't my husband die in an accident?
Oh, I dunno...
But he said he wants to have a bath and collect his thoughts first, so he might be a while.
It's been 20 minutes...
Mouri-san's taking a while.
I've had enough of that toothbrush moustache guy!
Now, now...
Hey...
You know...
Oh, no. Another blackout?
Hikaru-san. Could you go take a look at the breaker?
Yes, ma'am!
But why another blackout?
Come to think of it, that man said he was running an experiment in the bath.
Don't tell me Dad...
Huh?
That was fast. It's already back.
No, that was too fast.
Detective!
Just as I thought.
You're the killer, aren't you...
Yōko Araide-san?
Yōko and the little boy have run off...
Don't tell me this was a trap?
I-Inspector?
I'm the killer? What are you talking about?
I just came to see if you were okay!
I heard you were experimenting with the razor in the bath!
You wanted it to look that way,
but really, you wanted to kill me because I'd figured out the truth,
then pretend to have discovered my body.
Stop talking nonsense!
You know I was talking on the phone throughout the blackout!
About that blackout.
You created some kind of timer that could
short-circuit the electricity in this house.
You used that penlight to make
your way here in the dark,
then dropped the razor's extension cord into
the tub where your husband was bathing.
That way, when someone reset the breaker, he'd die of an electric shock.
Like I said, I was on the phone with my friend the whole time the lights were out!
So how could I come up here?
It was simple. Anybody could've done it with the phone's cordless handset and a mobile phone!
Unlike the phone in the kitchen,
the handset is cordless.
Additionally, the main phone has
a built-in rechargeable battery
that makes it usable even during blackouts.
As soon as Hikaru-san left the kitchen,
you switched receivers to the cordless handset and went to the bathroom.
You used your mobile's speed dial to phone the house.
Pretending you had someone on call waiting,
you stopped the conversation for a moment,
grabbed the extension cord,
which you'd plugged in beforehand,
and snuck it into the tub while pointing the light at your husband.
You probably told him to be careful to make him grab hold of a handrail.
Then you returned to the kitchen,
still talking on the handset,
switched back to the kitchen phone,
and waited for the lights to turn on.
That's why when Hikaru-san reset the circuit, it tripped again immediately.
When the lights turned back on the first time, your husband,
who was holding the handrail,
was electrocuted, and died instantly.
But anybody could've done that, Mouri-san...
Right.
Your plan was to create
an alibi using the phone,
and also to establish alibis for the others
by blocking the corridor to the bathroom.
But a problem arose.
Because Hikaru-san took an extra
30 seconds to reset the breaker,
her alibi could not be established.
Do you know why she took so long?
It was the chawanmushi.
During the blackout,
Hikaru-san broke one of the chawanmushi dishes in the kitchen.
She held it under her arm and went upstairs to hide it in her room before going to reset the breaker.
Earlier, your husband had threatened to fire her if she made another mistake.
Then, that burn on her arm...
That's what caused her burn and the mark on your mother-in-law's foot.
While leaving her room in the darkness,
she stepped on a shard of the broken dish that Hikaru-san dropped in the corridor.
Hikaru-san's detour added
an extra 30 seconds to her trip,
and during that time,
the old lady was still upstairs.
Tomoaki-san couldn't have left the kitchen,
since Ran was hanging on to him throughout the blackout.
Do you understand now, Yōko-san?
You're the only person who could have committed this crime!
Let me go, Inspector! Let me into the bathroom!
She's currently under investigation!
You framed her, and you call it an investigation?!
Don't make me laugh!
Silly girl.
Did she think we wouldn't notice the missing dish?
If Hikaru-san hadn't done anything,
you would never have suspected me.
No. Even if she didn't hide the dish,
I still would have figured it out.
The hand you held the phone in.
When Hikaru-san left the kitchen, you were holding the phone in your left hand.
But it was in your right hand
when the lights went back on.
It gave me the idea that you might've left the phone at some point.
You went to the bathroom with Hikaru-san when she discovered the body
to make sure she wouldn't touch it and get a shock.
If Conan hadn't stopped Tomoaki-san,
you were going to stop him too.
That's right.
Chiaki told me to take care of Tomoaki-san.
That's right. Four years ago, on the night Chiaki died, she called me and said,
‘Look after Tomoaki for me and make sure he doesn't turn out like my husband'.
At the time, I didn't know what she meant.
But I understood after I married
him and found Chiaki's diary.
I learnt that my husband was a womaniser
who'd chase after any woman he saw.
He was the reason Chiaki began to drink!
He drove her to her death!
Hey!
I'd like to advise you to turn yourself in as soon as possible.
My, how kind of you.
No. I'm not doing this for you.
I'm doing this for Hikaru-san.
You've got no idea, do you?
You may have been the one who set up the murder.
But Hikaru-san triggered it
by resetting the breaker.
Knowing that she killed a man
will scar her for life.
Then the reason you didn't tell anybody the blackout was a fake...
Yes. So Hikaru-san wouldn't figure it out.
I have a suggestion.
Tell the police that you killed your husband by putting him in the bathtub
after drugging him and putting an electric cord connected to a timer in the tub
to give him a fatal electric shock, then removing the timer during the blackout.
Basically, tell them the murder occurred during the first blackout.
Of course, if you confess in court that I asked you to say this,
then it'll get me and the Inspector into trouble too.
No. I'll do as you say.
I don't want to lose my human heart.
Free Magic hontō no tokoro
Free Magic, in its true form
Free Magic ai-tte nan na no sa
Free Magic, what is this thing called love?
tsumetai kurayami no naka de nukumori o tesaguri shite'ru
Even if you're blindly searching through darkness for warmth
itsuka wa kitto kiseki mo okoru darō
Someday you'll surely find a miracle
Free Magic kitto ai ga aru nara maarui katachi
Free Magic, if love were to take form, it'd be round like an egg
Free Magic ima kono te no naka ubugoe agete
Free Magic, so right now, speak your first cry in these hands
karagenki demo mada-mada mucha-shite
Even with faked bravery you can still be reckless
Free Magic wazuka na yūki
Free Magic, you may not have much courage now
Free Magic atsumete sodachimashō
Free Magic, but I'll gather and raise it
Sorry for keeping you here so late.
Oh, no...
I want you to tell your father...
Huh? Me?
No way...
It can't be!
Tell him I spoke too soon back there.
I'm willing to help him if he ever needs me.
What was I thinking?
Um...
I know it's weird to ask you at a time like this, but if it's okay with you...
...can I borrow that hand-knitted sweater you're wearing?
S-Sweater?
‘Kisaki Law Office'
Okay, so this part is like this, and then this part...
Oh, where'd you get that sweater?
I borrowed it off a friend.
I just love the pattern!
That's an Aran pattern. It's difficult, you know.
Oh, that part's not quite right...
Here, let me show you.
Hey, no! I'm going to knit this myself!
Fine. But don't come crying to me if you tangle it up!
If I can't manage it, show me how to do it with another needle!
I've already knitted two sweaters for you!
Sounds like you'd be better off giving a box of cakes rather than a sweater.
It's okay.
He's been working hard lately...
You sound jealous.
Uh, now how did this bit go...
Oh, those sweaters I knitted are in the way. Could you get rid of them for me?
No prob!
A few days later
Hey, did you get it?
Yeah. The doc sent it to me yesterday.
And? Did you try it on?
Yeah. I'm wearing it right now.
Thanks.
What're you laughing about?
Oh, nothing.
I said what're you laughing about?!
It's a secret!
Hey, what was that just now?
Sonoko!
What happened, Sonoko-neechan?!
On the next Conan: 'The Dying Message That Comes Back (Part I)'!
Next Conan's Hint: The sound of fireworks!
Next time, we're at an ice-skating rink!
Ah, out the way, out the way, get out of the way!