Flowing water has no form.
A blowing wind can't be seen.
All cases can be freely deduced!
Sonoko makes an appearance today after a long absence!
A man and a crime at an ice-skating rink!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
There!
And there!
Wow, take a look at all of them!
Look at all those good-looking men!
We've got a big catch!
Hey, Sonoko...
Geez.
Sonoko! What about Kyogoku-san?
Well...
Makoto-san's more like a wounded samurai than a prince.
Anyway, he hasn't gotten in touch with me since we went overseas,
so I'm starting to cool on him.
Talk like that, and his fangirls will kill you.
He's really popular, you know.
Yeah, well, I'm not like you.
I can't just lovingly wait for hubby to return!
I-I'm not waiting for Shin'ichi!
My, my. I never even mentioned Shin'ichi.
Hey!
You chose this skating rink 'cause you two used to play here when you were kids, right?
I don't have any good memories of this place!
Shin'ichi always made fun of my crummy skating!
So he taught you holding your hands, feet and hips, right?
What's with you, Sonoko?
Why are you being so mean today?
I'm just saying, now's your turn to teach somebody else how to skate!
Oh, it's okay. I don't...
Hey. Can he skate?
I don't know.
I've never gone skating with Conan-kun before.
Can you skate, Conan-kun?
Oh, my.
Maybe this is his first time?
Now's my chance to get back at this cheeky brat!
Stop it, Sonoko.
Oh, that Sonoko...
Out of my way!
No!
Move, move!
C-Conan-kun!
Ow...
Chihiro Itami (27)
Daughter of a Corporate Executive
Ouch...
Hey, are you OK?
You OK?
Ow! Help me, Yasuharu!
Oh, geez.
Yasuharu Misawa (29)
Banker
You shouldn't skate so fast if you're that clumsy.
But...
Milk the poor wittle kitten act
while there's still time, Chihiro.
Izumi Sano (28)
Office Worker
Once you turn 30, it won't be cute, even coming from a perky little rich girl like you.
How come you're always so mean to me?
You get on my nerves.
Now, now...
Come on! It's been ages since the clay pigeon shooting club has met!
Yoriko Komatsu (30)
Housewife
Let's not fight!
You do clay pigeon shooting?
What's that?
You know, that sport where you shoot flying discs with a shotgun!
We did a round this morning.
It's a lot more fun with friends.
And we hadn't met since the accident six months ago.
Accident six months ago?
Yeah. You want to hear it, little boy?
It's a strange and scary story...
Stop it.
How dumb are you? Why tell a kid something like that?
And I thought I made it clear that I'd go home the minute you said a word about him.
Kunitomo Oda (29)
Firefighter
Wow! He's so hot!
Another samurai type...
Hey, Oda, are you going home?
I thought we were going drinking!
I'm just going out for a smoke.
Some idiot made me remember something I'd rather not.
What's with him?!
Just because he's cute, he thinks he can talk like that to me!
Well, you shouldn't have brought it up.
It just slipped out!
Where does he get off calling me an idiot?
He's the one you guys should be mad at!
I hate that guy!
He's rude, and he's the odd one out...
Odd one out?
Hey, you've been saying that for a while now.
What do you mean by it?
You still haven't figured it out?
Uh...
I don't know what you're talking about.
Me neither.
Why's he the odd one out?
No way, no way, no way! I can't believe you guys!
Well, hurry up and tell us! You're being a pest!
Forget it!
You're the last person I'd tell!
And you'll probably never figure it out,
since you're not a perky little rich girl!
Where are you going?
The ladies' room!
If you can't figure it out by the time I get back, I'll drop you a hint!
She's so annoying!
So how about it, inquisitive Suzuki Financial Group lady?
Have you figured it out?
Beats me.
Hey, it's getting really crowded here.
They're probably here for the fireworks!
Oh yeah. They do a show every night at 7:00, right?
That's right! From this rink you can see the fireworks go off over the castle!
Ah, you know about it!
We're here for that too!
As usual, I'll pass.
I'll just get coffee.
I've seen this show a hundred times!
Are you leaving too?
I'm a little hungry.
But I'll be back in time for the fireworks, so wait there!
Wait here?
But I've had to go to the ladies' room for a while now...
Go ahead!
We'll be skating here.
If your friends show up,
we'll tell them to gather around.
Sure. Sorry for the bother.
I'll be back in a jiffy, so could you do that for me?
Okay!
Hey! It's already 6:55.
What's taking so long?
The fireworks are about to start!
They're not coming back.
Sorry, Ran. I need to go to the restroom too.
Geez, you're taking too long!
Toilet... toilet...
Hey! What's the matter?
Check it out!
Restroom closed for cleaning. Please
come back later. — Tropical Land
N-No way...
Hold on a sec!
It's a little late to claim the accident was my fault, isn't it?
A-Anyway, even if you hide your face like that,
people will come running as soon as they hear the shot!
You'll get caught in no time!
Unless—
Um, excuse me...
Is this going to take long?
What now?
This is the only restroom you can enter with skates on.
No way!
Hey, the fireworks started!
Hey, can you see them?
For crying out loud.
How beautiful!
It really is.
Especially the ones at the very beginning.
So you changed your mind about watching the show?
Yeah.
I thought it'd be a nice change.
Whew. Made it.
I thought I was gonna miss it.
Hey!
Where's Chihiro and your friend?
Didn't you see them in the restroom?
Maybe I missed them.
The restroom was being cleaned,
so I changed into my shoes and went to a different one.
Come to think of it, Sonoko's sure taking a long time...
Hey, that scream just now...
Sonoko!
Little boy?
What's wrong?
What happened, Sonoko-neechan?
O-O-Over there...
S...
S?
Dad!
Dad! Wake up!
What is it, Ran?
Weren't you gonna watch the fireworks?
There's no time for that!
There's been a murder! A murder! Mur-der!
Somebody was killed in the restroom near the skating rink!
Someone slipped and fell in the restroom near the skating rink?
Geez...
Hey!
Just come with me!
Hurry!
N-No...
Why Chihiro? Why?
Police! Out of the way, please!
Authorized personnel only! Move aside!
How ruthless.
You said it.
Nobody's been in here, right?
Well, when we got here, this boy was inside...
C-Conan-kun!
Don't tell me...
Just another coincidence!
Simmer down, Inspector!
I can't bother with you...
Inspector!
This shotgun looks like the murder weapon!
Okay, let's start by determining the owner of this gun from its registration number...
It's mine.
It's the shotgun I use for clay pigeon shooting.
I thought I put it in a locker with an electronic lock, with all the other guns.
O-Other guns?
Yes.
These three people and I are all members of a shooting club.
Who entered the password for the electronic lock?
I did.
But everybody knows what it is.
Last time we were here, we decided to use 9017.
ku-re-i-na
Sounds like clay friends in Japanese.
kurē nakama
Well, let's check you four out.
The one with gunpowder residue on their body is the killer...
You'll find it on all of us.
We came here after shooting all day.
And maybe the locker just wasn't properly locked.
If that happened, anyone could've gotten in and—
No, that isn't possible.
Have you forgotten?
Gun cases for shotguns are required to look like normal bags,
so people can't figure out what's inside.
Izumi's gun case looks like an ordinary leather bag,
and her shotgun was disassembled.
Only an expert could use it.
I see.
So the only ones who knew where her shotgun was,
and could assemble it,
were you four, correct?
N-No...
All right.
Ask around for any witnesses
who saw a suspicious figure around the lavatory at the time of the crime.
Yes!
Um, excuse me...
I saw!
What?!
I saw the killer come out of the restroom.
Really, Sonoko?
There was a cleaning sign hanging on the door.
I kept knocking on the door,
but nobody answered,
so I kept waiting by the door.
Then the fireworks started, so I left the door alone
and went to the window to watch with everybody else.
And just then...!
I saw a suspicious person in a hooded coat come out of the restroom!
D-Did you see the person's face?
No. It was hidden behind a hood and a scarf.
If the killer used a coat like that as a disguise
and used the sound of the fireworks to hide the gunshot,
this is a premeditated crime!
We'll need to question each of you separately.
I'd like to know whose idea it was
to come to this amusement park.
H-Hey!
We all decided together!
Now, now, save it for the interrogation.
No, you don't have to bother with that.
I had a hunch the moment
I saw the scene of the crime,
but now that I've heard Sonoko-kun's story, I'm convinced.
The killer who shot Itami-san is...
Izumi Sano-san,
it was you!
Hey, that's not funny! What are you talking about?!
There are three things that point to you being the killer.
First, the crime took place in the ladies' room.
The killer hung the sign on the door
to keep other people away,
then walked in after the victim.
Which means it was a woman!
Then there's your relationship with the victim.
I've been told the two of you
fought like cats and dogs.
So what?
That doesn't mean I'd kill her!
The decisive proof...
is the bloodstain left on the wall
next to the corpse's head.
Bloodstain?
To you, it might just look like a mark
left by the victim's struggles.
But I can clearly see it...
as a dying message left by the victim as she passed away!
S for Sano!
I asked all of your names before
the Inspector came, didn't I?
You're the only one whose name begins
with an S, Sano-san!
Isn't that right?
I don't think so!
Why not?
As you can tell by examining the body,
the victim was shot in the chest and died instantly.
It wasn't possible for her to write something with her own blood after she was shot.
Good point...
And a man could have called the victim here by telling her one of the women wanted to see her.
Then he could've entered in disguise.
Then that S is...
That's right.
Somebody left it there on purpose to incriminate Sano-san.
The shotgun is hers too, as you'll recall.
But this still seems fishy.
Sonoko-san knocked on the door just before the crime was committed, right?
If the killer was aiming the gun at the victim and waiting for the fireworks to appear,
why didn't the victim scream for help?
The killer was probably hiding in the next stall or something until the fireworks went up.
What's this?
There's something wet on here!
Look, on the tip of the gun.
I-It's saliva!
I get it!
The killer pushed the muzzle into the victim's mouth
to shut her up until the fireworks started!
Then just as the fireworks went off, the killer lowered the gun to the victim's chest and...
Then...
It couldn't have been any of us!
We were all at the skating rink
when the fireworks started.
Isn't that right, Ran-chan?
Yeah.
Were they really there from the start?
It only takes 30 seconds to get from the restroom to the skating rink.
But when the first firework went off, those three all ran up!
It was less than 10 seconds between the first one and the second.
Where were you at that time?
I was smoking on a bench by the skating rink, with my back to the fireworks.
The only one without an alibi.
But we've still got no proof.
And we don't know his relationship with the victim.
But at least you know she didn't like the cold, huh?
Look!
She had her hand in her pocket,
even when she was about to be shot!
A cellular phone?
But there's nothing on the display.
She must've been shot before she could call the police.
Why don't you press redial?
You can find the last person she phoned, right?
R-Right...
Let's see...
KIX?
And 8 pound signs where the phone number usually appears.
She probably tried to call for help,
but was too panicked to dial just by touch.
KIX...
KIX?
Wait, I've seen this somewhere before...
S-Suicide?
B-But that was an accident, wasn't it?
It's a lie that she always uses to get herself out of trouble!
KIX...
The actual dying message left by the victim?!
So the killer...
...is none other than you!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint, Sonoko!: Five Yen Coin
Next episode, Sonoko-neechan receives a call!
Make sure you don't get the wrong number!