Flowing water has no form.
A blowing wind can't be seen.
All cases can be freely deduced!
A very strange message!
Crush the trick and identify the killer!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
We went to the ice-skating rink at Tropical Land with Sonoko,
who, as usual, was hunting for a boyfriend.
While skating, we met a group of five friends who were part of a clay shooting club.
While we were waiting to watch the fireworks together,
we heard a scream from Sonoko, who was in the restroom.
When I went to see what's going on, what awaited me was...
...the body of Chihiro Itami, with a shot in the chest from a shotgun.
From the S written in blood next to the victim's body,
the old man deduced that the killer had to be
the only person in the group whose name starts with S, Izumi Sano-san, but...
I don't think so!
Why not?
As you can tell by examining the body,
the victim was shot in the chest and died instantly.
It wasn't possible for her to write something with her own blood after she was shot.
Afterwards, we discovered,
along with the last number Chihiro tried to call on her cell phone,
the letters KIX.
KIX?
Wait, I've seen this somewhere before...
KIX...
Where have I...
Hey, Mr. Detective...
May we at least change into our shoes?
We came straight from the skating rink.
As long as you take a detective along.
But come right back.
Hey, Chiba-kun, will you please escort them?
Yes, sir!
Come on, don't cry, Yoriko-san.
But Chihiro... Chihiro...
Yoriko Komatsu (30)
Housewife
Izumi Sano (28)
Office Worker
Kunitomo Oda (29)
Firefighter
Yasuharu Misawa (29)
Banker
Hey, Yoriko.
I'm sure the police will find the killer.
Idiot...
Huh?
That's the same kind of phone the victim had, isn't it, Sonoko-neechan?
Don't tell me this kid thinks I'm the killer.
No! I just want to see your phone!
Here.
Geez, Conan-kun. You shouldn't be fooling around with it!
By the way, Sonoko-neechan, was it really the sound of a firework you heard?
Well, yeah! A whistle, and then an explosion...
Hey, Sonoko, you replaced your phone?
Something like that...
Locker Room
I've figured out the trick.
But anybody could have done it.
Maybe there's something in that weird comment...
Yoriko-san, pull yourself together.
Sorry. It just reminds me of the accident.
Yoriko-san...
You were lucky, Izumi.
You weren't there when it happened.
I was sick with a cold, okay?
It's not like I was lucky.
As of today, I'm quitting the club.
It's like we've been cursed.
I don't want to die like Narita-kun, with a gun suddenly going off.
Hey, enough small talk. Let's head back.
R-Right.
I see. So that's it.
That's why he's the odd one out!
But I still don't have proof.
That message isn't enough to pin the crime on one person...
Two dark red dots...
Could it be?
Huh? What is it?
Conan-kun?
No way...
No way!
Hey!
I found it!
This is it!
I've found it! This is solid proof!
This proof will help me corner the culprit!
What are you doing here?
Honestly! This is a crime scene, not a playground!
Inspector Megure!
We found a coat that looks like the one the killer was wearing
in a trash bin between the restroom and the skating rink!
Good. See if Sonoko-kun, who witnessed the killer, recognizes it!
Yes, sir!
Oh... Excuse me!
Where are you going?
We're going to return our skates.
You can question us after that, right?
Remember, we've all got alibis. We were all watching the fireworks when it happened.
That's right...
Except Oda, who doesn't like fireworks.
I'm so glad I decided to watch them.
Otherwise, I'd be a suspect too.
Izumi!
Well, it's true, isn't it?
Okay, time to knock the old man out with a tranquilizer dart...
Let's end the meaningless probe.
It's time to clear everything up.
After all, the answer's simple!
Has he really...
Have you figured out who it is?
Yes. And this time I'm certain!
The person who waited for Chihiro-san in the restroom
and killed her with the shotgun...
was you, Kunitomo Oda-san!
It was you, wasn't it?
No way!
Hey, wait a minute! I...
You were up against the wrong man!
You may have tried to fake a dying message in your victim's blood,
but you couldn't fool me!
You were fooled big time.
You wrote that yourself after you killed her!
Nobody can write a letter on the wall after being shot through the chest.
And something Izumi Sano-san said
just now cleared everything up for me.
You tried to frame Sano-san, who you knew usually didn't watch the fireworks,
by committing the murder at the time the fireworks went up.
You used her gun for the crime and wrote the letter S on the wall in blood!
But unfortunately for you, she decided to watch the fireworks after all,
leaving you as the only one without an alibi, and your plan collaps—
Ah, ha-hi-hu-he-ho...
Right. As I was saying,
the killer wanted to make everyone suspect Oda-san,
and take the real culprit off the list of suspects.
That was the killer's true aim.
S-So just who was the killer?!
The one who killed Chihiro Itami-san, excluding Oda-san...
One of the members of the clay shooting club...
It was you!
The one who killed Chihiro Itami-san, excluding Oda-san,
one of the members of the clay shooting club...
It was you,
Izumi Sano-san!
I-Izumi?
That's right.
You used your own gun and wrote your
own initial on the wall to mislead us.
We were supposed to reason that
no killer would leave her own gun
and write her own initials
at the scene of the crime!
Taking advantage of this psychology, you set a trap.
You shot Chihiro in the chest rather than the head
to make the letter written in blood seem more plausible.
A person shot in the head
couldn't write a letter on the wall.
What are you talking about?
I was watching the fireworks with Ran-chan
from the very beginning, remember?
If the crime was committed when the fireworks went up, there's no way I could've done it!
That's if the murder was really committed when the fireworks went up.
Oh, come on!
Sonoko-chan already said the killer was still in the restroom when the fireworks began!
No.
What Sonoko-kun heard was the gunshot, not the fireworks.
Don't be silly!
Nobody would mistake a gunshot for a firework going off.
Boom!
Well, doesn't it sound just like a firework?
Er, yes...
B-But how did you do that?
With this!
A... five-yen coin?
If you put it against your lips and whistle,
it makes the sound louder and huskier,
like the whistle when a firework goes up!
Come to think of it, it did sound like that...
Isn't that right, Uncle?
Normally you wouldn't confuse a gunshot with a firework.
But if the gunshot was paired with that whistle at a time when people were expecting fireworks,
it'd be an easy mistake to make.
As proof, Sonoko-kun said she heard only one explosion.
The fireworks show here starts with a sequence of three fireworks, in red, blue and yellow.
Isn't that right, Sonoko-neechan?
Yeah...
But how did the killer know Sonoko-kun would be standing outside the restroom?
There were two or three other people there.
This is the only restroom you can enter with skates on.
She assumed that after she put the sign on the door, some people would wait outside.
Here's what happened: Sano-san asked Chihiro-san to meet her in this restroom.
She hung the cleaning sign on the door,
locked it, left to get her shotgun,
then came back to the restroom where Chihiro-san was waiting.
She pointed the gun at her,
waited until a minute or two before the fireworks show,
whistled through the five-yen coin, and shot her.
Then she used the blood to write her own initial on the wall.
Then she ran back to the skating rink
before the real fireworks began!
It was all to frame Oda-san,
who wouldn't have an alibi,
since he'd gone off on his own.
Hey... Is this true, Izumi?
Izumi?
I see... I guess I could have committed the crime that way.
But why me?
The other three could've used the same trick!
Izumi!
I don't know who you are,
but I won't take these false accusations!
KIX.
Do you know what that is?
It's the gibberish Chihiro typed into her cell phone, isn't it?
No. It's not gibberish.
While you had the gun in her mouth,
she typed a message into her phone from inside her pocket,
then kept pressing the Send button,
in the hope that whoever was on her redial would get the message!
Aha!
So that's why the area where the phone number appears was filled with pound signs!
If you keep pressing Send on this phone, it turns into a pound sign.
T-Then the word on the screen is...
The actual dying message left by the victim!
Well, so what?
Are you saying KIX is my name?
I've been told that Chihiro-san told all of you...
that Oda-san was the odd one out in your group.
W-What's that got to do with anything?
The victim is Itami-san.
The two people behind you are
Komatsu-san and Misawa-san.
And your full name is Izumi Sano.
Get it now?
Then let me put it this way.
Your friend, who died in an accident six months ago...
His name was Narita-san, wasn't it?
Wait...
I-I got it! Airports!
Apart from Oda-san, everybody's name is the location of an airport!
But I can't recall any airport called Sano, can you?
No...
And what does any of this have to do with KIX?
That's right.
KIX is the three-letter code to Kansai International Airport!
It's in Izumisano City in Osaka.
Now do you understand,
Izumi Sano-san?
B-But...
The real killer could've left that message to incriminate me!
Then if I show you this, it may convince you.
Check the bloodstain on the floor near the victim's left toe.
What?
Bloodstain?
T-This is...
When Sano-san wrote the letter on the wall,
she accidentally stepped in blood
with the blade of her skate.
She left some blood in the corridor when she escaped.
She hasn't realized...
There are traces of Chihiro-san's blood on the blade of her skate!
I-Izumi...
I see. Names of airports, huh?
It's just the kind of thing a pampered girl like her,
who travels the world on her parents' dime, would think of.
Izumi... You really killed Chihiro?
But... But why?
Narita-kun.
Narita?
Yes.
I just wanted to get back at Chihiro
for driving Narita-kun to suicide.
S-Suicide?
But that was an accident...
Chihiro had dumped him that day.
He pulled the trigger himself.
Everyone thought he had an accident
while he was cleaning his gun.
I told him she wasn't worth it,
but he was devastated.
But why kill her?
If that was all there was to it, I could've handled it.
But then there was the cheating.
Cheating?!
Yes. While I was sick in bed, Narita-kun called.
He said, It's over... We've both been betrayed...
Chihiro and Oda are seeing each other...
He was so broken up.
But Oda was going out with you back then!
That's right!
And he knew Narita-kun's feelings,
but he went ahead and made
fools of us with Chihiro!
That's not true!
It was just one of her lies to make Narita jealous!
Then why didn't you tell that to Narita-kun?
He said he asked you about it,
but you brushed him off!
Yeah, I'm sorry, but I wasn't paying attention to Narita that day.
I was too worried about you and your illness.
Maybe you should've killed me instead...
We'll hear the rest at the station.
Hey...
Can you wait for me?
No matter how long it takes...
And how far I may go...
Don't worry. I'm a pretty stubborn guy.
Thanks...
Hey...
Can you wait for me?
No matter how long it takes...
And how far I may go...
You sound like a tired old man.
What? You have no idea how I feel!
Hey, a phone call.
Yes? Hello?
Seattle International Karate Championship
I won, Sonoko-san! I won the winter tournament!
I never thought I'd meet so many tough oppo—
You idiot!
You stupid, stupid idiot!
Why didn't you call me earlier? I sent you my phone number two months ago!
I'm sorry... I didn't want to call for no reason...
Oh, geez...
By the way, Sonoko-san, I heard there's a flu bug going around Japan.
Don't go out in those short skirts.
I'm not! I'm wearing something really long today...
I knew it! Sonoko got another cell phone
to keep in touch with Kyogoku-san!
Yeah.
A cell phone just for two...
How nice...
A few days later,
I sent Ran a cell phone as a thank-you gift for the sweater.
She was a little suspicious at first,
but I think she kind of liked it.
Well, I guess that's that...
Hey!
Don't play games with me!
You meant Saizo Kano, didn't you?!
It's impossible! He'd never let that happen...
Hattori! Where are you?!
That's impossible...
Next Conan Special: