Flowing water has no form.
A blowing wind can't be seen.
All cases can be freely deduced!
Happy New Year, everyone!
And to kick off the new millennium, a two-hour special!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
It's the bottom of the ninth, the score's 3-2 with Chunichi leading by a point.
Ace relief pitcher Komatsu is on the mound with 2 outs and runner Oh on second...
Hey, did you kill him?
Yeah.
Four shots to the chest. He's as good as dead.
Saizo Kano, the Phantom Schemer, at the bottom of the sea.
The current's strong around here.
Before he can float to the surface, he'll be fish food.
But did we have to kill him?
You kidding?!
He went chicken after we killed that bank teller!
He was gonna rat us all out!
And the cops know our faces.
Never mind him, what are we gonna do with the dough?
He's right.
Out of the 400 million yen, the cops have the serial numbers for 300 million, right?
Don't worry.
We've taken care of the big problem.
Now all we have to do is bide our time.
Here.
A little gift from your old pals.
No hard feelings...
Boss.
I got it! A record!
What?
The answer has got to be a record!
What are you talking about anyway?
This, here!
See!
What!
Look at this.
Special announcement?
What's this?
"Something important most people in Japan had during the Showa era..."
"Do you still have it with you?"
"The first ten people who bring this valuable but increasingly obsolete item..."
The next part! Read the next part!
Good grief, don't bother me.
"...are invited to a free Ogasawara dolphin tour, three days and two nights"?
Let's try bringing in a record! We can still make it!
Conan-kun, you'd like to see dolphins, right?
Don't you, Conan-kun?
S-Sure...
Come on, please?
We don't have anything to do this long weekend anyway.
Geez. Forget about it! This tour sounds fishy.
And your answer's wrong, too!
If it was records, they wouldn't have written "people in Japan".
Well, what is it, then?
You dummy.
"Samurai spirit", that's what modern Japanese people are lacking!
How are you going to bring something like that down there?
Besides, I've never had samurai spirit, and I doubt I ever will!
Maybe yo-yos... bell-bottoms...
What about kombucha?
Designer clothes... Nintendo...
I know! How about the frill-necked lizard?
That was a popular pet back in the day.
What's that?
Hey...
The answer... might just be...
Yes, that's correct!
Please board the cruiser.
All right!
Yay! You were right, Conan-kun!
Just a lucky guess.
Next, please!
I'm so glad I hung onto those old bills!
Hurry up and hide it!
You'll give away the answer.
You're so stingy, Uncle.
Don't worry.
It's not something people can get their hands on that easily.
No way! It's not this? Unbelievable!
Nope!
He was right...
Next, please!
Wait!
Wow, this is real fancy.
I'm so excited!
Congratulations!
This is a pamphlet for today's tour.
Oh, thanks.
Uh, what number are we?
There's 3 in your party, so not counting the boy,
there's 1 more opening on the tour.
Gee... We just made it, huh?
How lucky!
That's right, the maximum number for the tour was 10.
But this sure is a huge ship for such a small group.
Conan-kun, we're going!
R-Right!
Wow!
It's like a hotel!
We'll be riding this to Ogasawara? Not bad!
Congratulations!
Thank you.
Three guests? Are you a family?
Sort of.
Then you'll have room 110. It's a double.
May I ask you a question?
Where's Masaru Furukawa-san, the organizer of the tour?
Excuse me?
I wanted to thank him for giving me the opportunity to sail on this fantastic ship!
Actually, we haven't met him either.
You haven't met him?
No...
He reserved the ship over the phone and told us how to select the passengers.
The charter fee was paid by bank transfer.
But I'm sure he'll be waiting for us at Ogasawara.
Oh, I see.
By the way, may I please have your names?
Of course.
My name is Kogoro Mouri.
A former detective with the Metropolitan Police Department,
and now a famous private eye.
Right?
P-Police Superintendent Samezaki!
Hey, I'm nobody's superintendent now.
Toji Samezaki (62)
Former Superintendent, Homicide Department
I'm just an old fogey. Retired two years back.
Hey, long time no see!
Is that you, Ran-chan?
You're all grown up and pretty as a picture!
But what brings you here?
Oh, I just wanted to look at the sea.
After all, today's a special day!
A special day?
Guess you've forgotten since you quit the force ten years ago.
By the way, how's your pretty wife doing?
You're not still separated, I hope...
As a matter of fact, I am.
It's okay. Just forget about her.
Dad!
Uh...excuse me.
What is it?
Teruyoshi Kameda (45)
Passenger
N-No... Never mind.
A seal?
You dropped this.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you very much!
Huh? Oh, y-you're welcome.
Why are you thanking him? You picked it up!
It's okay. Never mind.
Yo.
W-What is it? Are you talking to me?
Korehisa Kanie (46)
Passenger
I've been waiting for you.
How about it? Let's go have a drink over there.
Sir! Allow me to carry those!
No thanks, I'm fine!
Are you alone, sir?
Yes.
Not counting the little boy, he's the tenth person here.
That's the last one!
Then we can get the ship moving!
We're already behind schedule.
Not yet! There's that old man who came at the beginning.
He left to go get something he forgot, but hasn't come back yet.
Oh, him?
He just dropped by to tell me he was going to take a nap until dinner,
so he didn't want to be disturbed.
Huh? When did he get back?
At any rate, we've got ten winners,
so please send the rest of the crowd home.
Alright! I'll go!
Now then, sir, you'll be in room 107.
Thanks.
You there.
Haven't I seen you before?
N-No... You must be mistaken.
Minoru Ebina (42)
Passenger
I've never seen you before.
Did you find someone on the wanted list, Superintendent Samezaki?
Thanks to you people, Mouri-sama,
I'm certain we'll have a safe journey.
After all, he's a former police officer
and you're a private investigator.
There's three of you on board!
Three?
There's someone besides us?
Yes, another detective.
But it's not anyone who looks the part.
Thank you all for joining us today on the S.S. Symphony.
We are now leaving the dock.
We are scheduled to arrive in Ogasawara tomorrow morning,
so relax and have a pleasant journey!
I'm the king of the world!
She said she wanted to do that once in her life.
She's been watching too many movies.
If the ship sinks, that won't be funny.
Now, now.
Sadao Kujirai (50)
Passenger
The mighty ocean glowing in the sunset...
With that view in front of you,
I understand why you'd want to shout.
That felt good!
The sea certainly is wonderful.
It is! It helps you forget all your troubles!
Yes... The sea covers everything for you.
Your sad memories, your uncertain future...
Nagisa Isogai (27)
Passenger
Even... dead bodies.
Dead bodies?
Oh, I'm sorry, I shouldn't have said such a horrible thing.
I lost my father at sea a long time ago.
I can't help thinking of it.
I'm sorry to hear that.
We've all got to thank this Furukawa person for organizing the tour.
I know who he is!
Remember that seal I picked up?
That's when I saw the letters "Furukawa".
You saw too, right, Conan-kun?
Yeah.
So that's why you thanked him.
That's right!
So you see...
That guy from earlier with the seal must be Furukawa-san!
I bet he's going to surprise everyone
by revealing his identity at dinner tonight!
That's strange...
I overheard his name, and I think it was Kameda.
You're kidding...
Hey, Mouri! They're announcing dinner!
Ah, right!
So you're the famous Sleeping Kogoro?
That's me!
What an honor!
I think I'm gonna rest up in my room.
You still get seasick easily, don't you?
May I pour you more wine?
Please.
It feels kind of lonely, our little group
wandering around this huge ship.
I agree with you.
Including the two people resting in their rooms,
there are only eleven passengers on board.
That's if you include me!
And those two are the detective and the old man?
Yes.
I passed the old man in the corridor.
He was a mighty quiet fellow. Who is he?
An oceanographer, I've heard.
Let's see, his name is...
Saizo Kano-sama.
Saizo Kano?!
What room's he in?
Room 101...
Where have I heard that name "Saizo Kano" before?
You idiot! Have you forgotten?!
He's the mastermind behind the 400 million yen robbery we investigated together!
Saizo Kano, the Phantom Schemer!
Saizo Kano
You have the master key, don't you?!
Yes!
All right?
If it is him, he may be armed.
As soon as you open the door, get out of the way!
Y-Yes, sir.
Don't worry. Please calm down.
I-It's open.
Let's go!
What is this?
Strange.
It's like no one's even been in here.
Are you sure this is the room?
Yes! There's no mistake!
Damn it!
I'll look on the lower deck!
Mouri, you check the upper!
Y-Yes, sir!
Hello?
Where are you?
I know you're in here!
I got your letter...
Hey...
If he's not in his room, maybe he's on the deck?
Who's in the room next door, 102?
That's the other detective's room.
But he hasn't come out since getting on board.
Sounds fishy.
Excuse me, sir, may I come in?
Sir?
Here, let me do it.
Hey, you! I know you're in there!
Answer me! Hey!
Guess we have no other choice...
Will you unlock this door too?
Shut up, already!
Don'tcha mess with me, punks!
Huh? Old man...
What're you guys doin' here?
That's what I'd like to ask you!
Phantom Schemer?
Come to think of it, my pop told me about a guy like that when I was a kid.
His real name's Saizo Kano.
He was the mastermind behind a 400 million yen heist robbery 20 years ago.
His plans were flawless.
The job went off without a hitch, and he had no trouble shaking off the police.
So people called him the Phantom Schemer.
He was a lone wolf who changed gangs for every heist.
He made it a point not to harm anyone while committing his crimes.
But then during that big robbery 20 years ago, someone got killed.
After that, he disappeared into thin air.
And that guy was sleeping in the room next to me?
Yeah, but it was empty when we entered.
Samezaki-san's looking for him now.
Weird.
My pop told me he died a long time ago.
I thought his jacket washed up on a beach, all bloody and full of bullet holes.
He's not dead.
That jacket was a decoy to fool the police.
He wasn't the kind of guy who'd die that easily, kid.
I figured he'd be halfway around the world, counting money with his cronies.
Imagine finding him here.
But the statute of limitations for that case ran out five years ago,
so even if we find him...
Are ya senile, old man?
The statue of limitations for murder is 15 years,
but it's 20 years for a civil case!
If those guys're caught, they're gonna have to return the money!
Right. We can't nab Kano on the murder,
but his three cronies still have some time left.
If we can get Kano to tell us their whereabouts,
we might just get that money back.
As a matter of fact, they might all be on this ship.
Then we'll just call the police once we get to Ogasawara!
They can't get away while we're at sea!
You fool! There's no time!
Didn't I tell you today was special?
Tomorrow's the 20th anniversary of that robbery.
At midnight, those crooks will no longer be fugitives.
Then we've only got two more hours...
The statute of limitations will run out for them...
Huh? If it isn't Hattori-kun!
Yo, long time no see!
What's going on?
I didn't know you were on this ship too!
Yeah. I was sleeping peacefully in my cabin,
when this old guy came banging on my door and woke me up.
So, is Kazuha-chan with you?
Geez, do you have to ask about her?
She's got her life, and I got mine, right?
We're not as close as you two!
"You two"?
Er, I just meant you're such a loving family!
Don't get personal!
Samezaki-san, did you find that Phantom what's-his-name?
Nah. Mouri and I are gonna look around a little more.
Then we'll be waiting in the restaurant downstairs.
H-Hang on! We've gotta help them out.
What? You want me to wait on my own
while a dangerous criminal's lurking about?
N-No...
All right, then! I'll be waiting for you, dad!
OK!
I'll be waiting...
I'll be waiting, dad...
Something wrong, Superintendent?
Oh, no, nothing...
Then let's start from the top and work down.
Yeah.
But I'm kind of surprised.
I never knew you liked dolphins, Hattori-kun!
Rolwins?
Didn't you answer the ad
in the newspaper to get here?
Nope! No way!
I'm here 'cause I got a weird letter!
A weird letter?
Yeah. Last week I got a letter telling me
to come to Ogasawara for a case.
They enclosed 100,000 yen as an advance.
100,000 yen?
Yeah. But it was really fishy.
All the bills were the old design,
and there was no return address.
What about a name?
It said "Masaru Furukawa".
Furukawa?!
What? You know the guy?
What are you talking about? That Furukawa person planned this whole tour!
Really? I didn't know that.
The letter said I'd be able to get on the ship
if I showed one of the bills at the harbor.
So, you were invited on board
as a detective, Heiji-niichan?
I never accept cash for a case.
I just came here to return the money.
It kinda raised my curiosity though.
But talk about a coincidence!
I can't believe we're all on the same ship!
Actually, when I got to Haneda, I tried to call Kudo...
Er, I mean, old man Mouri.
But no one picked up the phone.
You must've called us right after we left.
But here we are anyway...
Like they say, wolves attract wolves,
and detectives attract detectives!
Right, kid?
Oh, are you the other detective?
You're a lot younger than I thought.
Well, yeah!
So, have they found this Saizo Kano person?
No... Looks like they're still looking for him.
Yo.
You want to use this?
T-T-Thanks, I appreciate it...
No problem, just ask.
Hey, why don't we all play some poker?
We can go to the lounge over there.
Good idea, but what about cards?
Don't worry, I brought a deck with me.
Hey, how about you guys?
You don't have anything to do, do you?
Find him?
No, I didn't...
Where the hell'd that guy disappear to?
Damn... Less than an hour left...
Mouri...
Yes?
I'm not going to give up.
Not until the very last second...
I'm going to get him!
Superintendent Samezaki!
Let's search one more time!
You're right.
Let's search this ship from top to bottom, Mouri, one more time!
Roger!
Tada!
Full house!
Good grief, you won again...
Alright! Alright!
After the next game, whoever has the lowest score will change places with Kujirai-san.
Excuse me, do you know what time it is?
Yeah, it's five minutes to midnight.
You seem awfully worried about the time. Is anything wrong?
It's just an important day for me tomorrow.
There, two-pair, aces and nines!
I'm the loser...
Alright, Kujirai-san's up next.
Alright now, miss, be gentle with me.
Hey, by "important day", do you mean...
The day your lover died?
That cocktail.
It's a Bloody Mary, isn't it?
The day you lost your beloved princess, or something...
Oh, no... Nothing like that.
Dad!
Did you catch him?
He's nowhere to be found...
Huh? Where's the old cop?
He's going to keep looking until time runs out.
Would you like something to drink?
Sure... Water, please.
Coming right up.
Well, I'm calling it quits soon.
I'll call it a day too.
M-Me too.
All right then, after we're done, I'll fix the cards and bring them to your room later.
I'd appreciate that.
How much for my drinks?
Lets see... you had two martinis...
I'll pay my bill too.
H-Huh? My wallet...
Could this be yours?
Why, yes, it is!
I found it out in the corridor, so I picked it up.
Hey, I didn't take anything out...
I-I'm sorry, I just wanted to check...
Are you going to bed too, Kujirai-san?
No, just to the bathroom. Let's take a break.
I'll be right back.
Out of time.
Now I'll never close that old case.
'Course, I retired from the force two years ago, so I never really had the right...
Superintendent...
Can I still get a drink?
Sure, no problem.
Give me a beer.
Yes, sir.
You did your best, Superintendent.
Mouri...
All right, Mouri, let's drink up!
Sure! I'm with you all the way!
It's on me!
Gee, that's generous of you!
I know the old man was in charge of the case,
but don't you think he's a bit obsessed?
But just like always—
What was that sound?
It was outside... Somewhere on the upper deck!
A gunshot?!
Mouri! What's the time?
12:08!
The flag...
The flag's on fire!
Hey, what was that?
I heard a firecracker or something.
Hey, Kudo, do you think this is just some prank?
No. Look at that, Hattori.
What?!
What is this?
"My phantom shall rise from the dead with the help of Poseidon"
There's somethin' written on this 10,000 yen note!
Don't touch the knife!
Who're you talking to? I'm no amateur!
Excuse me, go get me a plastic bag.
Yes, sir!
Do you always carry those things around?
Old habits die hard.
What's written on it?
"My phantom shall rise from the dead
with the help of Poseidon."
K-Kujirai-san?
H-He's alive...
I knew it... He's...
He's...
He's alive!
What now?
Captain! Explosion on the stern!
Stop all engines! Extinguish the flames!
Stop all engines!
What happened?
There was an explosion at the stern this time!
What's on fire?
This is the box the emergency escape ladder is kept in.
But why...would anyone do this...
A body!
Somebody's being burned!
Damn. It's burnt to a crisp.
There's no way we can identify the body
or work out the time of death.
This could even be Saizo Kano.
We sure can't find him anywhere else.
We've got to investigate further.
Isn't this Kanie-san?
L-Look.
The wristwatch he's wearing.
I think that's the gold watch he was wearing when I asked him for the time.
Now that you mention it...
It's scorched badly, but this sweater does look like his.
And these look like his pants.
Oh, no...
Why would anyone do this to Kanie-san?
Funny, isn't it?
F-Funny?
Just look at him, looks how he's posed...
His upper body and his arm are raised.
It almost looks like he's trying
to sit up and show us the watch.
Oh, this is just...
It's heat rigor.
Burnt bodies, you see...
The skeletal muscles react to the
heat and contract with thermocoagulation,
Heat rigor
which causes heat rigor.
There are more muscles to bend the
arms and legs than to stretch 'em out.
So the joints start to bend,
and the body winds up lookin' like a boxer in the ring.
All burnt bodies move into that shape.
Is that so?
Move importantly, the problem is the watchband.
Watchband? What's wrong with the watchband?
Look at the strap. It's all loose.
That doesn't mean anything.
See the can near the victim's feet?
That explosion was probably set off
with the gasoline in this can...
The explosion was powerful
enough to destroy the can.
It probably blew the watch loose.
You're probably right...
It must've also blown off the
vinyl sheet covering the box.
Vinyl sheet?
Yeah. When the Superintendent and I came
here looking for Kano, it was on the box.
Just like that one.
And then? You did look inside the box, didn't you?
No. As you can see, the box is
tied securely from the outside,
so I didn't think anyone could hide inside.
No one could have been in that box then anyway.
When I got back to the lounge,
Kanie-san was still there.
Hey, Mouri.
Who's that smart-aleck kid?
His name's Heiji Hattori.
His father's the chief of the Osaka police department.
Oh, so he's Heizo's kid? No wonder he knows his stuff.
You know the chief of police?
Sure. We used to face off in kendo tournaments.
I was no match for him, though.
Hey, Hattori.
Check out this weird stuff on the guy's face.
Weird stuff?
This is...
Ain't this silicone?
Yeah, polydimethylsiloxane.
Otherwise known as silicone.
It's warped from the heat,
but this stuff's used in plastic surgery a lot
to heighten the bridge of the nose.
That means... This stiff changed his face...
Yeah. I'm pretty sure he did.
E-Er, excuse me...
We'll cover him with this.
If he changed his face, that means...
Yeah. He could have been one
of the four members of the gang
that stole the 400 million yen.
If that body really is Kanie-san,
there's a good chance his pal
Kameda-san was also part of the gang.
Two buddies with face lifts,
meeting again after all this time...
I bet the third member...
is that guy sweatin' bullets in the back of the crowd.
Says his name's Kujirai.
You may be right.
He acted suspicious when he borrowed
that match from Kanie-san too.
Another thing's buggin' me.
That guy shouted somethin' funny back on the deck.
H-He's alive...
I knew it... He's... alive...!
He was freakin' out over that ¥10,000 bill
that was pinned to the deck with a knife.
Written on the bill were these words:
"My phantom shall rise from the dead
with the help of Poseidon."
The "phantom" must be Saizo Kano,
the Phantom Schemer.
And if he's risin' from the dead, he musta been killed!
I'm guessing he was killed by his
three henchmen from the bank robbery.
And now an old man shows up,
claiming to be Saizo Kano.
But I don't get it.
I ain't just talkin' about who this
old man who vanished really is.
But why'd all three guys from the robbery
have to be on the same ship
on the day the statute of limitations was set to run out?
Then there's that weird newspaper ad.
And I wonder about that Masaru
Furukawa person who put out that ad.
Could it be the real name of one
of the three gang members, or...
At any rate, that guy holds the key to this case.
I'll bet he's got a lot hidden
up his sleeve, don'tcha think?
Yeah.
What? You don't remember?!
But we heard you say it on the upper deck!
You said, "I knew it, he's alive!"
D-Did I say that?
Don't mess with me!
Come on, 'fess up.
You were talking about Saizo Kano, weren't you?
I-I don't know... I don't know anything...
I really don't know...
This is going nowhere fast.
Superintendent!
I've questioned all the ship's staff!
So, how'd it go?
All their alibis are perfect.
At the time of the explosion, excluding us passengers,
all the crew members, including the
captain, were always working in a group.
We heard something that sounded like a gunshot,
and the explosion occurred
just as we rushed to the upper deck.
The fire must have been lit by
the one person who wasn't there.
And that's Saizo Kano, the only guy who was missing.
Wasn't there someone else?
You know...
That Kameda man who went back to his room
because he wasn't feeling well.
I haven't seen him since.
Come to think of it...
Hurry down to his room and bring him here!
Y-Yes, sir!
Hey, I'll go with ya!
Me too!
H-Hey!
Wait for me!
I'm going with you!
Yes. I understand.
I'll see you there then.
Got it.
Continue on to Ogasawara!
Aren't we turning back, Captain?
No, they're sending a helicopter out
first thing in the morning.
Our ship is loaded with cargo they need on the island.
As soon as they're ready, the coast guard will also send a boat out.
Until help arrives, those detectives
will have to do their best.
Start engines! Raise speed to 20 knots!
Start engines! Start engines!
Kameda-san!
This could be a problem.
Go borrow the master key again.
Oh? It's not locked.
Kameda-san? I'm coming in!
What's this?
He doesn't seem to be in.
Then we'd better tell Samezaki-san...
Right, Hattori-kun?
Hey, where'd you go off to?
Hattori-kun? Conan-kun!
So? Ya find anythin'?
Yeah, in the engine room below us.
The cartridge case from a bullet,
some slight traces of blood,
and this mysterious letter.
I found a suspicious piece of paper too.
It was crumpled up and thrown away.
Where'd you find it?
You know the restroom at the
entrance to the restaurant?
It was in the trash can inside.
The trash can in the restroom?
And then? What does the letter say?
"I'll be waiting for you in the engine room. Masaru Furukawa."
Masaru Furukawa again...
Blood stains and an empty cartridge case...
There it is. One shot to the temple.
There's no doubt about it, it's a gunshot wound.
I bet the victim was lured to the engine room by the letter,
shot in the head, then stuffed into the box.
Well, that sounds about right anyway.
What about that piece of paper you found?
It was probably written on the
same word processor as your letter.
"See you on the stern. Masaru Furukawa."
This is proof that someone
lured that Kujirai guy out there.
How do you know it was Kujirai-san?
Two of the crew saw him.
He was standin' out there a little
after midnight, lookin' pale.
They heard him shout, "Hey, I'm here!"
When they tried to talk to him, he got real panicky.
Please don't tell anybody I was here!
After saying that, he hightailed it
back to the restaurant.
The crewmen hung around for a while
to see if somebody else was gonna appear,
but nobody showed.
They were about to return to duty when they heard that gunshot on the upper deck.
Was the box on fire yet?
Of course not!
And we haven't found any kind
of incendiary device, either.
So the killer fired the gun out on
the deck, and set the flag on fire.
Then while everybody was out on the deck,
he snuck down here and lit the box on fire.
If that's so, Kujirai-san's behavior makes sense.
Yeah. Bet he figgered he coulda been the one burned to death.
Then the only question is
how the killed made it down here so quickly
after firing the gun, with no one seeing him.
Well, I got a pretty good idea who the killer is.
We'll work out the rest soon enough.
You've figured it out too?
I knew you'd done it!
Wanna see if we're on the same page?
First there's the old man claiming to be Saizo Kano.
According to you, he got off the ship,
but later he was suddenly back on board,
even though nobody saw him.
That was set up by the killer as...
A fake!
That leaves only two possible culprits.
Right. The important clue is...
the fact that the corpse's elbows
were right in front of his face,
and that his knees were completely bent.
The killer musta pushed the corpse down and
raised the arms up when stuffin' it into the box.
There's only one person who'd need to do that.
But that's just a red herring.
The real killer is hiding somewhere on the ship, playing dead.
What're you talkin' about?
Look! This watch is solid proof that—
What are you talking about?
That's the killer's trump card...
How interesting.
It's been a while since we've disagreed on a case.
Yeah. The last time was when we first met.
All right then.
Let's find out whose deduction is right!
Shall we make a contest of this?
Hey! Wait!
Oh, yeah...
And fix that watch for me, will ya?
You want me to get this scorched watch running again?
No, no!
I'm just askin' ya to put it back where it was!
Oh, right.
What?! Kameda wasn't in his room?
No...
We've been looking for him, but...
You idiot! People don't just vanish into thin air!
Move aside! I'll look for him!
Er, I guess I'd better pick up the search...
So I'd like all of you to stay here a little longer.
No way.
You're just a private eye, and that guy's retired.
What right do you have to keep us here?
B-But...
I'm sorry, but I'm going to rest in my room.
Me too.
M-Me three...
H-Hey! It's dangerous out there!
Don't sweat it.
We can take care of ourselves.
Right?
Y-Yeah.
It's gotta be somewhere!
If my deductions are correct,
he's gotta be hiding somewhere...
Don't tell me...!
A good place to hide?
You know one, don't you?
Someplace that's usually off-limits,
or can't normally be seen...
Geez! Quit sneaking off! There's a murderer on board!
Huh?
Where's Hattori-kun?
Haven't you seen him?
We were wrong!
Kudo and I were both wrong!
Captain!
The ship's route is clear for the next 30 km!
All right.
Raise speed to 293 points!
30 knots!
Speed to 30 knots!
Then who is it?
Who's the killer?
Hey, didn't you just hear a strange water noise?
Strange water noise?
Probably just a bonito jumping.
I know I heard it!
A strange water sound, like something fell into the water!
Like I said, it was just a fish jumping!
Lots of bonito and flying fish around these parts...
Hey, have you seen the guy with the Kansai accent?
Kansai accent?
Oh, he came here to borrow a flashlight.
Flashlight?!
That means there's a good chance he went
out on the deck to look for something!
Then that water sound was...
Don't tell me...!
Hey!
No way! Not him, of all people...
There's no way he...
Hattori!
Hey!
Are you there?!
Answer me!
Hey!
Hattori...
It can't be true... It can't!
Hattori!
Hey!
Hey, now!
You've got to be careful!
You could've fallen overboard...
B-But...
That's right, little boy.
The waves of the open sea...
devour men whole.
You'd never survive.
Conan-kun!
What are you doing?
Well, Heiji-niichan's...
Him again?
He's prolly off somewhere sniffing around for clues.
That's right!
Don't worry. I'm sure he'll turn up sooner or later.
Y-Yoshimi...
Er, uh...
You just...sounded like someone I knew, that's all.
Never mind that, what's going on here?
What are you three doing here?
We were helping her look for something...
Look for something?
My pendant.
When I was getting ready for bed,
I noticed it was missing.
I went out to look for it, and these men happened by.
They seemed to have time on their hands,
so I asked them to help me.
Three heads are better than one, after all.
Are you talking about this locket with the photo?
I found it on the bow of the ship.
The clasp was undone.
Yes, this is it. Thanks.
I must've dropped it when I was there this evening.
So, Nagisa-san, the girl in the photo is you,
and the man holding you is your father?
Yeah.
Geez. Why didn't you give it back to her earlier?
Well...
I didn't know whose it was.
There's a hole over the dad's face!
After all, it could have been
someone else holding his daughter.
I was going to ask about it at dinner, but I forgot.
Sorry... I shouldn't have mentioned the hole.
Don't worry. That photo's over 20 years old.
It's all I have left...
of my father's mementos.
What the hell were you guys thinking?!
There's a murderer somwehere on board! Don't wander off!
Toji Samezaki (62)
Former Superintendent
Homicide Department
Mouri! Why'd you let them out of the restaurant?!
Er... They said they were going
straight to their rooms...
That's right! You've got right to order us around!
Besides, I don't want to hang around with the group...
Nagisa Isogai (27)
Passenger
or with some hysterical old man!
S-Say what?!
If it's dangerous to be alone,
I'd rather lock myself in my room with
these kids so we can play cards all night!
Right?
E-Er, well...
Sadao Kujirai (50)
Passenger
Minoru Ebina (42)
I agree that it's dangerous to be alone.
We should probably all stick together.
Anyway, you were looking for
Kameda-san. Did you find him?
Nah, he's still missing. Along with Kano.
Have you seen Hattori-kun?
Oh geez, Heizo's son's missing too?!
Damn it, what the hell's going on on this ship?!
Anyway, from now on, I want
all of you to stay together!
The killer could be out there
somewhere, or he could be one of us!
He could be lying in wait for
one of us to wander off alone!
He's right.
When we heard the first gunshot,
Samezaki-san was with us in the restaurant,
and Kujirai-san had just come back from the restroom.
Just as we got to the upper deck,
there was an explosion on the stern,
incinerating the box with the body.
Nobody went missing when we went up on deck,
so Ebina-san and Isogai-san
couldn't have set the fire either.
We still haven't identified the body.
But the only people who could have
lit the fire were Kameda-san, Kanie-san,
and the old man claiming to be Saizo Kano.
They were the only three who weren't with us.
But something's bugging me.
Everyone here's giving off weird vibes.
Even Samezaki-san keeps
getting worked up over nothing.
What happened?
What happened in that case 20 years ago?
Hang on, I'm going to the bathroom!
Damn, if Hattori were here, he could
ask the old man about the case!
Where's he gone?!
Agasa Residence
Hello?
Oh, what's up?
The 400 million yen robbery from 20 years ago?
We were just watching a special on that case!
The statute of limitations is about to run out,
so last night they did a big program on it.
I taped it because I thought you'd
like to see it when you got back.
Did they say anything about the perpetrators?
Let me see, I'm sure they did...
They showed photos of the ringleader, Saizo Kano,
but they only had composite sketches
of the other three, and no names.
Did they say anything about Kano being dead?
Yes. A jacket with bullet holes and
his blood washed up on a beach,
so the police concluded that his
accomplices killed him after a falling-out.
But how did they know it was Kano's jacket?
They found something in the inside pocket.
Something he always carried with him...
A picture of him holding his daughter.
What?!
What a sad case.
One of the robbers panicked
when the burglar alarm went off
and started shooting at random.
A stray bullet happened to hit and kill
a young bank teller named Samezaki.
Who did you say was shot?
A bank teller. Her name was Yoshimi Samezaki-san.
Poor thing, she was still so young...
Yoshimi Samezaki?!
It couldn't be..
It's too much of a coincidence.
Why are there so many people
connected to that case here on this ship?
And who is Masaru Furukawa,
the person who organized this tour?
"Masaru Furukawa"
Who could he be?
W-What was that sound?
I have to go now!
Call me if you think of something!
Hey, wait!
Where'd that sound come from?
The stern, I think...
All right then, I'll take the perp from
the left, you go around from the right!
Got it!
C-Conan-kun!
N-No one's here...
That's impossible! Look around!
Right!
Where are you, Hattori?
Why aren't you here?
You should've come running
as soon as those shots rang out!
What's the matter with you, Hattori?!
Superintendent!
Do you suppose he went this way back inside?
It's Kano.
It's got to be Kano!
He's trying to confuse us by firing wildly!
But what for?
I-It's me...
He... He's trying to kill me...
I... I d-don't want to die...
I don't... want to die yet!
Please! You've got to help me!
I'll tell you everything I know!
Yes. That's right.
I was in Saizo Kano's gang, the one that
committed the robbery 20 years ago.
I came aboard this ship
because the three of us wanted to
celebrate escaping arrest for 20 years.
One of the others sent me a letter.
He said once the ship set sail, we'd be safe until
the statute of limitations ran out at midnight.
He enclosed an old 10,000 yen bill.
But we hadn't met in years,
and we'd all changed our faces and our names, so I didn't even recognize them.
At least, not until Kanie-san spoke to me.
He said that Kameda-san was
the other member of the gang.
So, who's trying to kill you?
W-Well... I don't know...
You're lying. It's Saizo Kano,
the guy you betrayed, isn't it?
It can't be him! One of the others
shot him to death 20 years ago!
Then it's probably one of the others.
He wants all the money for himself!
You haven't spent the dough yet, have you?
That's what I thought at first.
But something's strange.
It just doesn't make sense!
What was that?!
Everybody down!
Are you alright? Kujirai!
Where? Where were you shot?!
Don't move!
Y-You've been shot!
Damn, where'd the shot come from?!
Hey, kid! Keep your head down!
Somebody's out there!
Look! At the bow of the ship!
Damn you! I'm not letting you get away this time!
S-Superintendent!
Hey! You're cornered!
Drop your gun and surrender!
Do you hear me, Kano?
You are Saizo Kano, aren't you?!
Come on! Say something!
Kanie!
T-That's impossible!
One shot in the temple.
Quick death.
Yeah.
The body's still warm,
and the blood hasn't fully congealed.
There are burn marks around the bullet wound, so the gun was pressed to his head.
When we heard the gunshot, everyone
except Kanie was in the restaurant.
The only plausible explanation is
that Kanie shot himself in the head.
See if this fits.
Kanie was lurking around the bow of the ship.
When he heard his old crony spill the
beans about the case 20 years ago,
he tried to kill him, but didn't succeed.
Realizing he was trapped,
he gave up and killed himself.
What an idiot.
H-Hang on.
Isn't this a little fishy?
The burnt body we found at the stern was
wearing Kanie-san's clothes and wristwatch.
So who was it, really?
Probably Kameda, the other
member who vanished off the ship.
Or Saizo Kano.
Whoever it is, Kanie here's the one who killed him.
He probably planned to fake his own death
by disguising the body and burning it.
The problem is how Kanie was able
to hide here without being spotted.
Hey, what's this?
There's something funny tied behind the man's back!
This is...
A rope ladder!
It's a great place to hide when you're playing hide and seek!
I see. Kanie hid from us by hanging from this ladder.
There are rope marks on the arms
and legs. Looks like you're right.
But I don't get it.
Why'd he go to the trouble of faking
his death and then hide out here?
It could be...
He planned to appear before someone he wanted to kill,
to make them freeze in fear.
That's all I can think of.
But who was Kanie trying to kill, that he
had to go through so much trouble?!
Kujirai, who just got shot, was one
of his old buddies, wasn't he?!
Yeah, you're right...
Geez, you're losing a lot of blood.
The bullet must've nicked an artery.
He needs medical attention right away.
Ran-chan's just gone to get the first-aid kit.
But you're pretty lucky.
You just damaged your suit and your arm.
Hey, Mouri! I found it!
Here's the bullet hole.
Looks like Kanie definitely fired
from the bow through this window.
Now...all we have to do is find the bullet,
which is embedded here somewhere...
Er...
Is this what you're looking for?
Yes, no doubt about it, this is it!
Quite a marksman.
He barely grazed his target,
but he shot a handgun from quite a distance.
Have you forgotten?
One of the men in Kano's gang was
supposed to be an expert with firearms!
Oh, yeah.
We got as far as finding out that he might've been in some country's foreign legion,
but that was about it.
Yeah, that must've been Kanie.
Dad!
Ah, you brought the first-aid kit.
We've got to stop the bleeding.
Huh? Where's Conan-kun?
Huh? Isn't he around?
The boy with the Kansai accent?
He came to borrow a flashlight, but never came back.
He hasn't come to the bridge either.
That's strange. Where's he gone?
Hey, could you look inside everybody's rooms?
Sure, but I don't think you'll find him.
That's right. When we were looking for
that Kameda person with Samezaki-san,
we searched all the rooms then.
Did you find any signs of his room being searched?
He's a detective.
No, nothing like that.
Aside from Kameda-san's room,
every room was locked.
Come to think of it, there is
one room we didn't search!
Oh, yeah, the neat freak...
It was Ebina-san's room, the guy with the glasses.
All we found was a suitcase in the middle of his room.
There wasn't so much as a wrinkle on the bedsheets.
It was like he hadn't even unpacked, right?
Yeah.
Hey! Could you show me that room?
There's something Uncle Mouri wanted me to check!
Conan-kun?
Conan-kun!
Hey, little boy, did Detective Mouri really ask you to do this?
You bet! He also said to keep it a secret!
Let's go back in. That body's giving me the creeps.
Yeah... You're right.
You hurry back too, little boy!
Right!
Even if the killer's offed himself now,
this trip sure has been a disaster.
I bet Furukawa-san, whoever he is,
can't wait for our ship to get to Ogasawara...
Masaru Furukawa...
The man who planned this tour...
All the mysteries start here.
If the killer was Kanie-san, and this
Masaru Furukawa was Kanie-san all along,
this case almost makes sense.
But I still can't explain...
the watch the corpse was wearing.
And there's that "Furukawa" seal
that Kameda-san had.
Damn it. If only I could figure out
who this Masaru Furukawa is...
Er, excuse me...
Have you seen a boy with glasses?
Don't tell me...
Masaru Furukawa is...
A scorch mark?
And some paint has chipped off, too...
Maybe...
Conan-kun!
Another one!
And here!
I get it!
That's how the killer controlled the time and everyone's movements!
And that's why he hired Hattori as a detective!
But why Hattori?
I'm sure he's famous in the Kansai region, but...
Why hire a private detective all the way from Osaka?
Sheesh, do you know how much you make me
worry when you keep going off by yourself?
I-I was just about to go back. T-That's why I...
Please...
Don't leave me alone.
Conan-kun, you know what a scaredy-cat I am.
If you're not around, I'll have to
search this creepy ship all by myself!
I-I'm sorry...
By the way, where'd you get this tennis ball?
I found it under the table while I was
looking for you in the restaurant.
I asked around, but no one knows who it belongs to.
Did Mr. Samezaki say something when he saw it?
No...
I haven't seen him since he went up to the bow with Dad.
But I heard them shouting.
Sounds like they found an old
bullet wound on Kanie-san's body.
Hey, what did everybody do the first time
Uncle Mouri and the others left the restaurant
the first time to look for this Kano person?
They all left, one by one.
By the time I got back to the restaurant with
you and Hattori-kun, they'd all come back.
I see.
I've figured it all out.
The truth behind this bizarre case!
All I need now is the proof.
Oh, excuse me.
We're looking for a guy with a Kansai accent.
That kid asked us the same thing earlier.
We've been looking for him too,
but so far, nothing...
Sorry, Doc.
I'm kinda busy right now.
I'll call back later.
What?!
Anyway, we'll get the entire crew to search the ship again.
I'd appreciate that.
Sheesh... What are you doing here?
Oh, nothing...
Really, where did he go?
Who?
Huh? Who?
Hattori-kun, of course!
Oh, Heiji-niichan?
He's probably swimming with the fishies somewhere.
Mouri.
Could this mean that...
Yup. I think—
Dad?
Uncle? What's wrong?
Uncle?
What're you doing?
Dad?
Ran! I want you to get everybody out here!
I've solved the case.
Go on, hurry!
What?
Is that true? You've solved the case?
Yes. I've figured everything out.
All the facts of this case.
You're not going to just tell us
that Kanie was the perp, are you?
No. The killer is Kanie-san.
As you said, Superintendent,
he faked his death and went into hiding,
looking for an opportunity to kill...
You, Kujirai-san!
Then who was the burned corpse?
It was Kameda-san.
First, Kanie-san lured Kameda-san out and shot him.
Then he put him in the emergency ladder box,
and went back to join the others.
Then he set the flag on the upper deck on fire.
Then when everyone ran up to
the deck, he set fire to the box.
The reason why he didn't dress Kameda-san
as soon as he was put in the box
was because he was waiting for the superintendent
to give up looking for the old man named Kano.
It takes a long time to dress someone,
and he couldn't risk being seen by the superintendent.
The proof is the way the victim's
arms were up beside his face!
If you raise the arms when
putting the body into the box,
it's still easy to dress the body
even after rigor mortis sets in.
The strap of the watch was loose,
probably because it didn't fit Kameda-san's wrist.
Just before lighting the box on fire,
Kanie-san called Kujirai-san out to the stern,
hoping to pin the crime on him.
After all, the person closest to the scene
of the crime is usually the first suspect.
But why?
Why did he have to fake his own death?
To frighten his next target, Kujirai-san.
Who wouldn't be terrified by the sudden appearance of the man he betrayed 20 years ago?
Betrayed?
That's right. The old man claiming to be Kano was another illusion created to cause fear.
Look at the scar on Kanie-san's body!
That old bullet wound proves everything!
Y-You don't mean...
That's right!
This was the man thought to have been killed 20 years ago, the Phantom Schemer...
Saizo Kano himself!
You're lying...
You're lying!
That's not true at all!
It's not true...
This man couldn't possibly be Saizo Kano...
Because Kano is...
Kano is...
My father!
Y-Your father?
That's right.
Saizo Kano, the Phantom Schemer, is my real father.
I joined this tour to look for him.
It was rumored that he was killed 20 years ago by his accomplices,
but I thought that maybe he was still alive...
But I couldn't find him on board.
He probably had plastic surgery and changed his identity.
Who do you think I am?
Even if his features changed,
I'd never mistake my father for another man!
And he would have shown some sign that he recognized me too...
Even though it's been 20 years since we saw each other...
That's exactly what I wanted to hear.
Sorry to deceive you, Nagisa-san.
I suspected as much, but I wanted to make sure.
So I could upset the killer's plan.
Plan?
Yes...
The killer make it look like Kanie-san killed Kameda-san,
dressed him in his clothes and set him on fire.
This would make us think he faked his death.
He created the illusion that he was firing a gun around the ship to distract us.
Finally, he made us think that Kanie-san committed suicide
after shooting Kujirai-san, one of the other members of his old gang.
He wanted it to look like Kanie-san was actually Saizo Kano,
and that this murder on the ocean was revenge for the gang's betrayal 20 years ago.
Then... you mean... the killer is...
That's right. It's someone else.
And he's right here!
No way!
Hey, now! What are you talking about, Mouri?
You know the facts!
At the time of that explosion at the stern,
all the passengers were on the upper deck!
And everyone on the crew has an alibi.
You even said there'd have to be some kind of automatic incendiary device.
I found it!
I found the incendiary device.
You found it? In there?
He used a cigarette.
The culprit poured gasoline into the box with the body,
then placed a lit cigarette under the lid of the box,
and tied it in place with string.
In about ten minutes, the string burned through,
making the cigarette fall into
the box and light the gasoline.
But then...
How do you explain the four gunshots we heard at the stern,
and then two more at the bow?
All the passengers were around back then too.
Another cigarette.
I suspect the killer stuck a lit cigarette and
a firecracker together onto the handrail.
After the firecracker exploded,
the evidence fell into the sea.
As proof, there are scorch marks
and chipped paint on the handrails!
The same trick was used for the gunshots
we heard before we found the burning flag.
The culprit soaked the flag in gasoline
and left a lit cigarette nearby.
It's a trick anyone could've pulled off
with just a pack of cigarettes.
Then who is it?
Who's the real killer?!
I-It's...
It's too late!
What?!
There was an explosion in the rear!
Stop all engines! All stations check for damage!
Right!
Lower deck! Any damage?
No damage!
No need to worry.
A bomb just exploded about 100 meters behind the ship.
100 meters?
Was that a bomb?
Just to be on the safe side,
I put it on a life raft,
and had the raft tied with a rope to the handrail on the stern
so it'd drift away from the ship.
Ebina-san.
That was the end of the bomb in your suitcase!
Suitcase?
H-How did you know about that?
A tidy room without even a wrinkle on the bed,
a suitcase that hadn't been opened,
and your constant fretting over the time.
Very suspicious.
You probably prepared the bomb a while ago to kill
the gang responsible for the robbery 20 years ago,
and avenge the death of your old colleague.
Colleague?
He counted bills with the technique of a bank teller.
And I heard him mutter the name
of the teller who was killed in the robbery.
Yoshimi Samezaki-san's name...
She wasn't just my co-worker.
She was... She was the most important thing in the world to me...
You don't mean you're...
You're the guy who broke down
in tears at my daughter's funeral...
That's right!
After the funeral, I quit the bank,
and drifted from job to job ever since,
looking for the killers,
even after the statute of limitations for her murder ran out!
I see... So it was you...
You're the special person Yoshimi asked me to meet...
If... If only...
You'd come to the bank on time as you promised...
She... She wouldn't have...
I'm sorry.
One of my officers was stabbed that day,
and I was at the hospital when I got the news.
You also saw that ad in the paper and joined the tour.
Yes...I thought this might be it...
If my hunch was wrong, I figured I'd just toss the trunk into the sea before the bomb went off...
So it was you!
You're the killer who's been picking off the gang members!
N-No! It wasn't me!
All I brought on board was the bomb!
I didn't know anything about any guns!
It's true! You have to believe me!
Don't worry.
I know you're not the killer.
As I said before, to make it seem
like Kanie-san was the killer,
the real killer set up this whole scenario
to look like Saizo Kano's revenge.
He disguised himself as an old man to board the ship,
left to remove the disguise, then boarded as himself,
to make us think Saizo Kano was on board.
He left that bill with the mysterious message pointing to Kano on the deck.
It was all to make us think it was Kano trying to terrorize the people who betrayed him.
Even the bullet wound on Kanie-san's body
was used to make us think he was Kano,
shot by his gang 20 years ago!
Then what is that wound?
Probably a souvenir from his time in the military.
We believed the gang included
an ex-soldier, remember?
And he was one of the accomplices...
That means...!
Right.
The only person who could have come up with a plan like this
was somebody who already knew there was
an old bullet wound on Kanie-san's body.
You don't mean...
Kujirai-san, you were a member of the gang!
Only you could have done it!
T-That's insane!
You waited for Kameda-san to leave the restaurant after getting your note,
then you mentioned Saizo Kano's name to us.
In the excitement, you went down to the engine room,
where you had told Kameda-san to wait, and shot him.
Then you hid his body in the box at the stern.
The engine room?
Yes. I've already found blood stains, an empty shell casing,
and the letter he used to lure Kameda-san into the engine's room.
He must've slipped the note
under the door and into the room.
Kujirai-san came back to the restaurant,
waited for the superintendent to give up the search for Kano,
then left to meet with Kanie-san.
They probably met in the restroom next door.
Then he knocked Kanie-san out with a drug,
stole his clothes and wristwatch,
dressed Kameda-san's body
and set up the cigarette device.
He raised his voice, attracting the staff's attention,
so he'd have witnesses to attest
that the box wasn't on fire yet,
and so he could claim he'd just been called to that spot.
He left the note in the restroom trash can,
pretending to be afraid after hearing Kano's name
so that Kanie-san would approach him.
He must've intended to claim that
the note was hidden in the matchbook.
He lured you out to make us believe
that Kanie-san was the mastermind.
He created the cigarette setup with the flag
before he changed the clothes on the body.
That way, when we heard the explosion,
he could run up with everyone else.
We would be his alibi.
He moved the sleeping Kanie-san
from the restroom to the bow
while we were all focused on
the burning body at the stern.
Then he watched our movements,
and after some time had passed,
he placed another device at the stern.
After hearing the sound, while we went running,
he went back to the bow,
pulled Kanie-san up, shot him,
then shot himself in the arm,
letting the bullet pass through the window into the restaurant.
Then he set two more of his cigarettes, and was good to go.
He just had to gather everyone together on
the stern, claiming to make a confession,
and wait for the firecracker to pop.
By falling down at the same time as the noise,
he made it look like he'd been shot
by someone standing at the bow!
W-Wait a second, Mouri!
I was with him and took a look at his wound right after he fell!
If he'd shot himself earlier, there'd be more blood.
He used a tennis ball!
By holding a tennis ball tightly under his arm,
he put pressure on his artery,
and stopped the blood flow!
When the firecracker went off, he dropped it.
Ran found the ball under the table in the restaurant.
He must've thrown it away while everyone
was distracted by the second explosion.
But why didn't he kill Kanie-san when
he dragged him down to the bow?
Because the trick would seem fishy
if Kanie-san appeared to commit suicide
right after the first body was found.
He wanted us to believe that Kanie-san had dressed the body.
The raised arms of the body and the loose watch strap
were red herrings used to create the illusion.
That's also why he hired Heiji Hattori,
a private detective from Osaka.
When we showed up, Kujirai-san
decided to use us as his patsies instead.
You got a detective from Osaka
because you live in the area, right?
People from Kanto don't say "fix" when talking
about putting playing cards back in a case.
Great... If you just had some proof.
You'll probably find it when you check the area around the shattered glass.
You'll get a luminol reaction.
There'll be just a trace but you'll find some smears from when he wiped
the blood that splattered when he shot himself.
No! It wasn't me!
It's a setup! Somebody's trying to set me up!
Why, you!
How dare you?!
The stars...are so beautiful...
What?
Hey! What's that?
A strange star approaching from portside!
What's that?
It's...
Hattori-kun!
That's right.
He can testify that you attacked him
and threw him overboard
when he found Kanie-san hanging from the bow!
You can't talk your way out of this one, can you, Kujirai-san?
But how did you know Kanie wasn't the killer?
The watch.
From the moment I noticed that the corpse was wearing a right-handed watch on its left hand,
I took Kanie-san off my list of suspects.
You tried to make him look like you,
but you were made a big mistake
by putting the watch on wrong.
Laid low by your buddy's fancy watch.
By the way, Kujirai-san is the one
who put the ad in the paper.
20 years ago, he must have promised the other members
that he'd contact them under the name "Masaru Furukawa"
on the day their statute of limitations expired.
The three members gathered here
to get their hands on the money.
They couldn't spend it for 20 years,
so they left it in a safe-deposit box.
Back then, to get into such a box in a Japanese bank,
you needed a key, a signature and a seal.
They split the three among themselves,
so that when they had changed their faces, they
could use them as a sign when they met in 20 years.
Kujirai-san was in charge of the signature.
When he saw Kameda-san and Kanie-san
flashing the seal and the key around,
he identified them as his former partners,
and put his plan into action.
I see.
He was going to kill them, steal the key and seal,
and keep all the money for himself.
What an idiot.
Just when your statute of limitation expired,
you had to pull off another murder.
I wanted to win...
Against Saizo Kano, and his perfect plans.
I wanted to beat the Phantom Schemer,
who used to tell me my plans were a joke!
But why?
Why are there so many people
connected to the case on board?
I never said anything about Kano in the ad...
Don't you know the significance
of "Masaru Furukawa"?
Kano had us use that name all the time.
He said there were just a few strokes,
so it was easy to remember.
We were to use it when we
needed to contact each other.
I didn't think it meant anything...
Are you kidding?
"Masaru Furukawa"
Turn "Masaru Furukawa" sideways!
The kanji spell "Saizo Kano"!
"Saizo Kano"
That's why I came.
Dad's name appearing on the day the statute of limitations ran out...
I wasn't sure, but I had a hunch...
"Masaru Furukawa" was Kano's alias!
He created it with wordplay!
No... It can't be...
You were no match for him.
For the last 20 years,
you've always been in Kano's clutches.
What? You fell into the sea?!
No way!
I'm not kiddin'!
The guy clocked me from behind and knocked me in!
Didn't ya miss me? You're cold!
I'm glad you're okay.
I had to tread water 'til those fishermen saved me.
I had a heck of a time, ya know.
I had to take all my clothes off,
then tried to signal the ship with a flashlight...
I can't believe ya didn't notice!
You... took your clothes off?
'Course! Wet clothes're heavy
'cause they soak up so much water!
If I hadn't shed the extra weight, I'd be on the bottom of the sea right now.
The only thing I kept on was my pants,
and this. Found it in my pocket.
This good-luck charm...
Who knows if this thing actually helped?
W-What're you staring at me for?
Come on, don't play dumb!
You were looking at Kazuha-chan's good-luck charm gave you all dreamy-eyed...
No way!
I was just wonderin' if I should throw this unlucky thing away!
I'm only keepin' it 'cause I don't wanna get cursed or nothin'!
Then you shouldn't have forgotten it...
Three people turned themselves in,
saying they committed the murder?
Accomplices?
There's only one victim, but there are
three people saying they killed him.
Very interesting.
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: A head as hard as rock
The next case is super-unique!
You burned the mochi, Conan-kun!
Right...
Look forward to this year too!