Just as water flows without shape,
and wind blows without form,
no case can stop you from deducing the truth!
Today is a surprising murder.
Using one's head and heart to solve the mystery,
Seeing through the one and only truth,
he looks like a child, but his mind is of an adult.
His name?
Detective Conan!
true
heart
for
mys
tery
eyes
take
your
feel
so
all
in
se
cret
life
**EpisodeMainTitle**
So what is it...
that you want to borrow the mind of the great detective Mouri Kogorou?
If it is just a silly case, treating me just a lunch wont do.
Wai-wai-wait Mouri-san,
Your voice is too loud.
Will a chief inspector come to you if it was just a silly case?
Moreover, all the way from Shizuoka, all by himself.
Actually, Mouri-san...
It's about-
Something up with that man?
No, no...
It's actually a very confidential matter so...
Mouri-san, it's about the Komiyama Taiji case.
Komiyama?
Oh! That famous actor!
So Komiyama... did something happen to him?
Huh? He was killed three days ago, didn't you know?
K-KILLED?
You really didn't know?
This case was a very incomprehensible one indeed.
No matter how much you investigated, you couldn't get any suspects?
Just the opposite.
Opposite?
There are three people who
claim that they have killed him.
What!?
Hmm...
Only one victim, but three persons have turned themselves in as the culprit.
This is interesting.
The Man Who Was Killed Four Times
There are three who claim to be the murderer...
Were they working together?
If that was the case, things would've been easy.
Let's hear the details.
Sure.
The incident happened three days ago.
On the last day, the victim had a stage performance,
and two hours before the performance began...
Komiyama.
####Signs#####
######Cards#####
Are you asleep, Komiyama?
m 0 0 l 0 -15 l 36 -15 l 36 0
Hideo Tsuda (55)
(Actor)
******1******
F1
m 0 0 l 0 -15 l 36 -15 l 36 0
Hey, I'm coming in.
m 0 0 l 0 -15 l 36 -15 l 36 0
Whoa!
K-
Komiyama!
The victim is Komiyama Taiji, 58.
m 0 0 l 0 -15 l 36 -15 l 36 0
Taiji Komiyama (58)
(Actor)
The estimated time of death is about two hours before the body was found.
Traces of a wound by the strike of a blunt object were found on the back of his head.
We suspected that it might have been a murder,
So we immediately sent the body for autopsy.
We also went on to question these three people for testimony.
These three were the other performers...?
Yes.
The room where Komiyama was found, is at a corner, not easily accessible to outsiders.
At the time of the estimated death,
only three of them were in that area,
as confirmed by the security guards.
I see.
Kazumata Kengo-san wanted to play the role that Komiyama had been playing for the past twenty years.
Niikura Yumiko-san was being afflicted by Komiyama-san, who was pressing her to go out with him.
Hoshino Haruyuki-san had feelings towards Yumiko-san,
And so he had bitterness towards Komiyama.
Anyways,
So we brought in the three of them for questioning,
And then...
m 0 0 l 0 -15 l 36 -15 l 36 0
Kengo Katsumata
(Actor)
I'm very sorry, I killed Komiyama-san.
Huh?
That time, suddenly,
Komiyama-san burst into my dressing room, yelling.
He seemed to be a bit unsteady,
as though he was drunk.
W-What's the matter, Komiyama-san?
What are you reading just now?
W-What are you...
Just hand it over.
You were reading it again, huh?
Listen, Katsumata.
This script was written for me to do it!
I'll never give this role to a
lowlife like you, even if I die!
In other words, I'll bring this with me to my grave!
You are worthless.
I thought I had to do something about the body, so I dragged him over to his own room.
I thought that if I left his body there, it would look like his wife killed him.
His wife?
Yes, everyone knew that things weren't going too well between Komiyama-san and his wife.
She came to the dressing room yesterday, and they had a big fight.
I see.
Damn it.
But, why did Komiyama-san suddenly come into the room yelling like that...
It was then...
Wh-What did you say?
Like I just told you, I killed
Komiyama with my own hands!
m 0 0 l 0 -15 l 36 -15 l 36 0
Kengo Katsumata
(Actor)
m 0 0 l 0 -15 l 36 -15 l 36 0
What are you doing, bursting in here like this?!
Remember this well...
Niikura Yumiko is mine!
Do you even think I'm going to give her over to you?
Shrimp!
I thought it wasn't a good idea to leave the body in my dressing room.
So instead, I moved Komiyama's body to his own dressing room the moment the theater was empty.
But inspector,
If I think of it now, it was really a pointless action.
Even if I get arrested, I won't regret anything.
With these hands I rescued her,
Yumiko,
from that lewd poisonous insect.
What's more...
What did you just say?
m 0 0 l 0 -15 l 36 -15 l 36 0
Yumiko Niikura
(Actress)
Komiyama-san had suddenly entered my room and...
m 0 0 l 0 -15 l 36 -15 l 36 0
Please stop Komiyama-san.
Why do you run?
We're going to be acting on the same stage.
I'm just trying to be friendly with you, Yumiko!
No!
I don't know how Komiyama-san's body was found in his room.
But the one who killed Komiyama-san was me.
I'm very sorry.
On further investigation,
We found traces of impact on the victim's head from all three vases in their rooms.
Anyway, we've made all the arrangements for your stay. Please think this thoroughly before dawn tomorrow,
and give one of your famous deductions to us.
Mouri-san.
Wh-What the heck is this?
The investigation documents.
Eeek! There's this much?
Yes.
Ahh, I see.
Huh?
Isn't it a bit strange... this picture?
What's so strange about it, huh?
That hurt!
This isn't for a child to see!
But if you hit someone on the head,
won't he be holding his head like this?
But the person in that picture is holding his chest...
I wonder why.
I guess it is a bit strange.
The direct cause of death was his heart.
Heart?
After the autopsy,
the wound on the back of his head was not that serious,
but it seems that he had heart problems.
According to the director, who found Komiyama's body,
he had a heart attack the morning he died...
and could somehow hold it down using the medicine he had.
So it seems, in this case,
after being hit on the head
his heart must have received a big shock,
and caused his death.
It seems to be like that.
But why didn't he take the medicine at that time?
You idiot.
He must have had no time to take it.
Maybe, he would have taken it, if the medicine container wasn't empty.
Empty?
If he had taken it, I'm pretty sure he would have survived.
That means, it must have been empty from the start.
This doesn't make any sense!
Excuse me, Mouri-san.
It's a call from the station, please excuse me for a while.
The medicine that's critical to one's life.
Will anyone not notice that it had run out?
But in reality it was indeed empty.
The only thing I can think of...
What! That's impossible!
But sir... even if you ask...
Yes...
If that was the case,
Why didn't the victim call for help?
The chances are one out of three.
If I just think it over the night, it's no problem!
I'm very sorry.
Huh? What is it all of a sudden?
We lost the time for you to think this over the night.
Huh?
Now we need you to give your deduction as soon as we reach the scene.
As soon as I reach there?!
Hey hey, what are you going to do, uncle?
m 0 0 l 0 -15 l 36 -15 l 36 0
Shizouka Citizenship Hall
So, l have reached the scene.
Hey, Inspector Yokomizo.
Oh, hello ma'am.
m 0 0 l 0 -15 l 36 -15 l 36 0
Atsuko Komiyama (36)
Taiji's wife
When are you going to return everything to us?
Uh, your belongings is evidence after all.
We cannot return them until the case is solved.
Then hurry up and solve it.
Huh, who was that?
The victim's wife, Atsuko-san,
and the director, Tsuda-san.
She looks pretty angry.
Heh heh, she only wants the items we are keeping down at the station.
Hey, isn't that the person who found Komiyama-san's body?
Yeah.
I thought so.
Wait, where are you going Conan-kun?
Just to the bathroom.
Wait...
Oh yeah, I've to go to the bathroom too...
But, Mouri-san,
The bathroom is the other way.
Oh is it?
The morning of the murder?
Yeah, I was told to ask you about it by Detective Mouri.
Komiyama-san had a heart attack that morning too, right?
Yeah, it was when he was talking to me at the hotel cafe room...
You're telling me, I should quit acting?
I'm telling you this as a friend.
Continuing in the condition you're in, it is like suicide!
What will be left of me if you take away acting?
Komiyama,
What's wrong, Komiyama?
Should I call your wife?
She will be in her room, right?
All I have to do is eat the medicine and it will be okay...
Just one of these.
After he took the medicine,
It looked like the attack faded immediately.
I see, I've figured it out:
how the victim was killed,
and furthermore, who the real culprit is!
Hello, I'm Detective Mouri Kogorou from Tokyo, who was brought over by Inspector Yokomizo.
I have something I would like for you to check immediately.
Damn it.
You gotta be kidding me!
I was asked to lend my wisdom at a personal level.
You asked me for it!
Yes, you're exactly right.
I don't know how our chief heard about this.
I'm very sorry.
May I please ask you for it soon?
No you may not.
Please, somehow.
Our boss is really looking forward to this.
To be able to hear the great
detective's deductions in person!
That's your problem!
Besides, you said that tomorrow will be fine as well, didn't you?
What's up uncle?
It's not good to keep everyone waiting.
If you can't solve it, maybe you should just go and apologize.
Right?
You idiot.
There's no case this Mouri Kogorou can't solve.
Alright, let's do it.
No rehearsal, it's show time!
I'm the renowned Detective Mouri Kogorou.
Uhh
Today, I am going to tell you about the Komiyama Taiji murder case.
But firstly, I would like to tell you about why l chose to be a detective.
Never mind the formalities!
Who among the three, is the real murderer?
Huh, uh, the real murderer?
The real murderer is...
Uhh, hmm, it's...
How should I say it...
I can't watch dad like this...
The real killer probably is...
I guess there won't even be the usual stupid deductions...
I was hoping that it would buy some time.
I've got no choice.
Now it's time to see the true strength of the detective, sir!
Yeah.
I've finally figured it out, Inspector Yokomizo...
who the real murderer is.
If it was exactly as the three suspects say it was...
the victim, Komiyama Taiji,
would have been killed three times.
He entered each of your rooms one after another.
But the problem is in the order.
Katsumata Kengo-san said it happened like this...
That time, suddenly,
Komiyama-san burst into my dressing room, yelling.
He seemed to be a bit unsteady, as though he was drunk.
That's correct.
But I doubt that with the bad heart Komiyama has,
he would drink to a point where he would be unsteady...
and that too, on the day of his performance.
That's true.
Then why was he unsteady?
It was probably because he was already hit by someone else.
Now, according to Hoshino Haruyuki-san's explanation,
What are you doing, bursting in here like this?!
Remember this well...
Niikura Yumiko is mine.
Yes...
However, Komiyama acts weird here as well.
To suddenly burst into the room and yell at you about Niikura Yumiko-san,
There must have been some trigger before that.
That's right, Niikura Yumiko-san.
He went to you and was rejected.
You understand now, right?
First Komiyama went to Niikura Yumiko-san's room.
Then he was hit on the back of his head.
Thinking she had killed the man,
Yumiko-san ran from the scene.
But after a while,
Komiyama regained consciousness.
That means...
He was just unconscious.
Then with those feet,
he went to Hoshino-san's room,
believing that the reason Yumiko-san kept rejecting him
was because of Hoshino-san.
Once more, Komiyama was hit on the head.
But I suppose he had a pretty hard head.
He recovered from it again.
What a hardheaded individual!
Indeed.
But Komiyama, not learning his lesson, went on his way again,
To take out the rage of being hit twice, on someone.
So that's why he came to my place like that.
So then it was Katsumata-san?
Like I said, it was me from the start.
No, don't underestimate Komiyama.
What do you mean?
When his body was discovered,
Komiyama was holding his chest,
even though he was supposed to have been dragged by Katsumata-san.
But, if you drag someone, their hands would be spread out instead.
Then why were his hands on his chest when we found him?
There's only one answer.
Komiyama regained consciousness for the third time.
It was after all this that, Komiyama had the heart attack that took his life.
I get it! When he realized it, his medicine container was empty.
Do you really think someone won't realize that they have run out of such an important medicine?
Moreover, he already took his
medicine that morning as well.
No way that he would not notice it!
But, in reality...
Someone took the medicine from that container.
But the victim always hung the
medicine container around his neck.
Is there anyone who can access that...?
There is one person.
After the earlier heart attack,
to wash away the sweat on his body,
Komiyama probably took a shower, right?
Madam?
He must have taken the medicine off from his neck to prevent it from getting wet.
From the situation I guess that I am the most suspicious.
But Detective, you have no evidence, do you?
...that I emptied that man's medicine container?
He may have really forgotten about them.
I never said you emptied it.
If it was really empty,
Komiyama would have sought help from someone.
But he did not.
There was probably a different medicine in the container.
Just one.
Naturally, without suspecting anything, Komiyama-san took it.
And as expected, his attack did not stop, and finally, while struggling, he passed away.
This is Yokomizo.
Stomach medicine?
What do you mean?
I'll know if l ask Mouri-san?
Hmm, stomach medicine, huh?
Heh heh.
The medicine that l always take.
What is this all about?
I had Komiyama's medicine container checked out,
to see whether there was any unnatural substance in it.
So the last medicine Komiyama took was...
Stomach medicine?
Oh, it's over.
If you guys didn't hit him so much,
it would have ended with a simple heart attack.
The police wouldn't have come to investigate so much.
And of course,
neither would have that detective over there.
OCR Efforts
Yakubo
Lady Zeline
Riku, Zill
Translation Sources
KnKF Subs
UTB Subs
Catalan Dubs
Translation Checkers
Yakubo
Lady Zeline
Spimer
Quality Checker
racer21
Raw Source
Reghost-Fabrebatalla18
Typesetting & Timing
Mando387
Yakubo
Karaoke
MisakiTaro
Scradow
Wow, just like the rumors.
That was excellent.
Thank you very much.
But for the contents of the container... when did you call to check that?
That was uhhh...
It was, uhh...
That is of course...
Classified.
Hehe, you don't know it either...
Gin's, you say?!
Oh no, they found it!
Probably Apotoxin 4869,
The drug.
Reunion with the Black Organization
(Part Haibara)
Next Conan
Reunion with the Black Organization (Part Haibara)
Next Conan's Hint
Transmitter.
m 150 411 l 549 411 548 459 150 461
Look forward to the next episode
The next episode will finally feature the Black Organization!
Conan-kun, don't drink alcohol though!
Okay...