Flowing water has no form.
A blowing wind can't be seen.
All cases can be freely deduced!
Today, it's those guys at last!
I'll expose the black conspiracy!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a child
but has the mind of an adult.
His name: Detective Conan!
Let's hurry home and play more soccer.
Yeah, let's do that!
I'm the captain!
Eh? You again?
Hey, did you watch yesterday's match?
Wasn't it awesome?
Yeah. You mean Hide's overhead kick, right?
The time for games is over.
That goal was a real work of art.
Hide's so cool!
Now, wake up from your dream and celebrate our reunion!
In pure blood red, like the color of your favorite rose.
Eh...? Sherry!
A bad dream...
Haibara-san!
Here's the MO disc I borrowed from you.
Please tell the doctor that this game was even better than we hoped.
Sure, I'll tell him.
The boss character was a bit lame, though.
But it was still better than the one in the previous game.
Oh! Look, look!
Look, snow's falling! Snow!
Really?!
Snow...
Let's celebrate our reunion!
In pure blood red, like the color of your favorite rose.
Eh...? Sherry!
Hey, come look out of the window at the snow with us, Haibara-san.
Don't touch me.
Haibara-san?
Is something wrong?
I'm tired of this place already.
So much that I wish I could just disappear from here.
Well, one of these days, I probably will.
Haibara-san, are you transferring to another school?
Could it be that someone's bullying you?
I'll take care of that guy!
So please don't say you're leaving us!
I was just joking! Don't take me so seriously.
I've got a bit of a cold, so I'm just in a bad mood. Don't worry about it.
Oh, just a cold.
They say people aren't quite themselves when they get sick...
Now, now, if you got a cold, you need to go to the nurse's office!
I did it!
What a face!
Now you've done it, Mitsuhiko!
Wait!
"I shouldn't be in this place."
"To avoid getting these kids involved,"
"I have to disappear from this place as soon as possible."
That's the kind of nonsense you're thinking right now, right?
It'll be fine.
The idea that someone would shrink from a drug is just absurd. Nobody would believe it.
The thought wouldn't cross their minds.
You just have to keep acting as a child, and you won't get found out.
Until the time comes...
Don't worry.
If something bad happens, I'll figure something out.
Later!
See you tomorrow!
Bye-bye!
Yeah!
Kudo-kun, you still don't know a thing.
You can't handle something like them by yourself.
Once you let your guard down, it's all over. The Organization won't let us get away.
Right. Maybe, just like in my dream,
even now, somewhere in this city,
they're watching us...
What? Is there something wrong with that black Porsche?
A Porsche 356A.
A 50-year-old classic car.
The driver doesn't seem to be in it.
I've only seen them on TV and in books,
but I guess some people actually drive old cars like these.
Gin...
Gin's favorite car is one of these.
Did you say Gin?!
That's right.
Even in my dream he came out of this car...
Hey, what are you—?
Doc?
Bring what I'm gonna tell you, and come to the corner of Block 4!
I'll explain later! Just hurry!
Hey!
Did you bring them with you?!
Yeah. A wire hanger and a pair of pliers.
What do you need them for?
Wait!
To open an old car, all you have to do is this...
Kudo-kun?
What are you planning to do?
I'm planting a transceiver inside the car.
But we're not even sure this is their car!
What's up?
Across the street.
Across the street?
Gin! Vodka!
Asshole!
The snow's unusually trampled around the car.
Some civilians probably came and looked at it.
Your car is quite rare after all, Bro.
"The German Rainfrog."
It sure became famous.
Bingo.
I never thought I'd find them here.
I'm glad I did, Gin!
This time, I won't let them get away.
Keep going straight.
Try to keep some distance from them.
It's useless.
Even if you figure out where they are, there's nothing you can do in that body.
Don't you understand...
how stupid you're acting right now?!
Shut up! Just shut the hell up!
A phone?
Yeah, it's me.
How are things on your side?
What? He still hasn't shown up?
Don't worry.
The target's sure to show his face at the Haido City Hotel at 6 PM.
He has no idea it'll be his own farewell party.
Target? Farewell party?
Either way, our superior ordered us to kill him before he rats us out.
Feel free to use that drug if you want.
Drug?
Don't mess it up, Pisco.
Pisco?
That codename sounds familiar.
I haven't met him, though.
Pisco...
Haido City Hotel...
A reddish brown hair?
Bro, what's wrong?
What's that?
It's probably a transceiver.
Not good! It's been discovered!
W-What did you say?
I never thought you'd be the one to approach me first.
I welcome you, Sherry!
What are you thinking of doing? The situation got a bit more complicated.
Without the transceiver, it's impossible to keep following them.
Besides that, the chewing gum you used to place the bug in their car is now in their hands.
If they analyze that...
Don't worry about that.
I removed my toothmarks,
and the only thing they can figure out with the saliva is the blood type.
I also wiped off all the fingerprints inside the car.
Then you should turn onto a side street
and leave their car alone.
As it is, it's too risky to go down a street their car is on.
Yeah. I'll stop chasing them.
But I don't intend to run away.
Haido City Hotel.
That's where that Pisco guy is planning to off someone.
Anyway, I'm gonna go to that hotel to try to prevent that murder from happening.
My, what a strong sense of justice you have.
But sorry to say,
I have no interest in such abstract things as justice.
And I don't think we could do anything,
even if we did deliberately go to a place that is so dangerous.
Yeah. I was thinking the same all along.
It would be dangerous for you to be seen there,
since they know what you looked like as a child.
So stay in the car with the doc and wait for me.
Even though it's the worst scenario, I have to try and get that drug.
That drug?
Gin said it on the phone.
"Feel free to use that drug if you want."
Probably... Apoptoxin 4869.
The same poison that shrunk us.
Yeah, that's right. Sherry.
The woman who betrayed the organization should be headed your way.
If you don't know what she looks like,
look her up in the organization's database.
After we check that she hasn't planted any more transceivers,
we'll meet up with you.
Absolutely. She'll be there.
Since I mentioned that drug.
Of course, whether or not to use the Incomplete Detective is up to you.
Anyway, as soon as you see her, catch her and bring her head down to the ground.
Ah, there won't be any problem.
Even if there's nothing below her neck.
Sheesh... I thought you had no interest in things like this.
I can't help it. I'm the one who made that drug.
I just don't want you to call me a murderer anymore.
Be careful.
They'll suspect that the one who planted those devices is coming here.
And if they find out you're involved...
It's all right.
Didn't you already erase all the evidence in the car?
They'll think it's either a prank, or that someone who's against the Organization did it.
More importantly, are you sure this is their meeting place?
Yeah.
Gin said it's a farewell party.
Pisco and his target should both be here by now.
Well, that's enough chit-chat. Let's go in.
Damn. It's a mourning party, so lots of people are wearing black.
Everybody's starting to look suspicious.
Sherry...
Sherry!
What's wrong, little girl? Did you get separated from your parents?
Yeah. We're looking for them now.
Let's go, Hana-chan.
What's wrong with you? This isn't like you.
Weren't you the one who chose to come along?
I had a nightmare...
A nightmare?
On my way home, Gin saw me.
He chased me into an alley...
And you were the first one he shot.
And each time I heard his pistol fire, one by one, everybody else...
Yeah, just because they were involved with me...
Maybe if the Organization had killed me back there,
it would have been for the best...
Did you know? Nobody'll ever discover your identity if you wear those.
Even Clark Kent would be surprised.
Oh? Then, having taken off the glasses, are you Superman?
I can't fly, though.
Well, it's better than nothing.
Thanks.
You're really not that cute.
But, bro...
Will that woman really come?
Yeah.
That's the kind of woman she is.
She'll definitely come to stop us.
But she doesn't know we'll be there waiting for her.
And if, by some chance, she doesn't come?
We know she's hiding somewhere in the vicinity of the Beika district.
Once we get a general idea of her hiding place, she'll be no trouble to hunt.
Since the scent of a traitor can't be erased.
It's a big mourning party.
There's big stars everywhere.
A novelist who won the prestigious Naomoto Prize...
The owner of a pro baseball team...
A capable music producer...
A popular actress from America...
A famous university professor...
And here there's a big fish in finances.
Well, then? Did you figure out who Pisco's target is?
Yeah.
Gin mentioned on the phone that the target would arrive at 6 PM,
and that he might be arrested by the police tomorrow,
so it can only be that man at the entrance, who's surrounded by reporters.
I see.
So that's the lawyer who the papers say might be getting rich off bribes?
He said to shut him up before catching him.
Wouldn't that mean he's also part of the organization?
Who knows?
But we'll know when they catch him.
Please answer more clearly.
Excuse me.
Inspector Megure?
I called him from the restroom with my voice changed.
I told him someone here wants to murder that lawyer.
So what are you gonna do now... Pisco-san?
In this situation, with the target under police surveillance, a murder is impossible.
Before he tries to complete the mission the organization sent him on,
I'll put him to sleep with this tranquilizer gun.
Well then, everyone.
Allow me to present you with a slide show
of Director Sakamaki's memories.
A slide show?
Now, everyone, do any of you know when and where this photo was taken?
Wait. That lawyer's gone already.
What?!
Hey, hurry up and find him.
Yes, sir.
Damn, where is he? Where did he run off to?!
Yes. This is Director Sakamaki's masterpiece that won many awards.
The place where he filmed "The Rainbow Handkerchief."
A precious shot from before the Director's hair started looking lonely!
How is it?
We still haven't found him.
Look more carefully!
Yes.
Now let's look at the next photo.
Oh? This looks like the studio cafeteria's staff.
You probably all know this well, but Director Sakamaki was a big fan of soba.
The filming for Rainbow Handkerchief occured in Shinshu,
so every day he walked to a different soba restaurant and had lunch there.
When the filming ended, he boasted that all the soba restaurants in Shinshu were his.
Ok, let's move on to the next slide.
A flash?
No matter how precious this photo is, you wouldn't be able to see it if you used a flash.
What?
What was that sound just now?!
Above?
What?!
What was that sound just now?!
Hey, what's wrong?
What was that sound?
Hurry up and turn on the lights!
What in the world is going on?
A handkerchief?
NEXT EPISODE
They're here. One of the seven I chose...
is the one called Pisco.
Haibara, this is bad! They're coming!
Hey!
Haibara!
Next Conan:
"Reunion with the Black Organization (Conan)"
Next Conan's Hint: Handkerchief
Look forward to the next episode!
Next time, Haibara's in trouble!
But the one who needs to watch out is you.
Me?
Wrong.