Flowing water has no form.
A blowing wind can't be seen.
All cases can be freely deduced!
Danger is approaching, Haibara, Conan!
Even the cast is getting insanely large!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a child
but has the mind of an adult.
His name: Detective Conan!
On the way home from school,
Haibara and I saw a car belonging to Gin, one of the men in black.
I set up a bug in his car, and we followed him.
But Gin found the bug, and figured out that Haibara was still alive.
By intercepting his conversation,
we found out about their murder plans,
so we went to a party at Haido City Hotel being held in memory of a film director.
Wait. That lawyer's gone already.
What?!
What the...?!
A handkerchief?
T-The chandelier...?
What's wrong?
T-That's...!
What's happened?
I don't know...
Something happened, didn't it?
Yeah.
Just what is going on?
Hey! Would someone mind giving me an explanation?
Everyone, calm down.
I'm Megure, from the Metro Police.
That's new. For once you police arrived quickly.
We got a tip that there was going to be a murder tonight,
and that someone was planning to kill this Nomiguchi person.
Isn't that right, Takagi-kun?
It's no good.
He's already stopped breathing.
I see...
Tell police headquarters right away.
Right.
He's the killer.
A partner of the men in black who shrunk me.
Codename Pisco.
He's still somewhere in this hall.
I see.
So you were the ones closest to
Mr. Nomiguchi when the chandelier fell?
Yes.
Did you see anyone suspicious at the time?
We didn't have time for that.
I was almost turned into a pencil board too!
Look. The chandelier scratched my suit like this.
I never saw any suspicious characters.
I see.
Inspector, she says she didn't see anyone of the sort, either.
It was an accident, an accident!
The chandelier's chains were old, and broke.
The lawyer just happened to be under it.
But there was a message saying there'd be a murder tonight, right?
What are you going to do about that?
Before you go investigating us, I'd like a full description of the informer.
Maybe the informer is the killer.
The voice was altered by a machine, so we don't even know if it was a man or a woman.
Then it was probably a prank.
Mr. Nomiguchi was weakened by his medical condition.
Right, right.
The accident just happened to overlap with the prank.
The heavens smote him.
You can't do bad things, eh?
How can you eat at a time like this?
An insignificant lad like yourself should keep his mouth shut.
Hey! Someone call the chef!
What's wrong? Was there a cockroach in it or something?
You're eating at a time like this,
so the heavens smote you too.
What did you say?!
Now, now, keep it down.
This is... a piece of the chandelier's chain?
Why was it in a place like that?
Anyway...
Mr. Nomiguchi died when he was crushed by the falling chandelier, right?
To murder someone that way, you'd have to set a trap on the chandelier,
lure him underneath it when the lights were turned off,
and then activate the trap, right?
Yet, looking at the fallen chandelier and the ceiling it hung from,
I can see no such thing.
Therefore, murder is impossible.
Now that you understand, could you release us already?
It's true.
Dropping a chandelier on a targeted individual in the darkness,
without some sort of trap, would be impossible.
Yet, he did just that.
But how?
Hey, where are we going?
We're running away.
Staying here and wasting time is too dangerous.
And how will you explain us being here if Inspector Megure or the others spot us?
You only have one clue—the piece of chain you picked up earlier.
Not even you could figure out who the killer is from just that.
What if I have two?
It fell after the chandelier, but before the lights were turned back on.
This handkerchief.
What about it?
It's not like it has the killer's name written on it.
Look at its corner.
It says "Director Sakamaki's Mourning Party", right?
Its owner probably received it at the front door.
Just look around at the guests.
See, that man holding the glass,
the overweight woman next to him,
and the elderly man with the mustache in the back.
They all have this handkerchief, but in different colors.
What are you saying?
Likely, due to Director Sakamaki's number one hit, "The Rainbow Handkerchief",
handkerchiefs in seven different colors were given to the guests.
In other words, if we ask at the front desk,
we can reduce the number of suspects to those that received a purple handkerchief.
But is there really any connection between that and the murder?
Yeah. I don't yet know how it was used,
or even if it belonged to the killer.
However, there is a non-zero probability of it being related to the case.
Right?
Hey, officer!
We can go to the bathroom, right?
Sure.
What's wrong with you all?
Did Mr. Nomiguchi really pass away?
We heard it was an accident.
How about it?
We'll explain it later, so please everyone, back away.
Wait! Please answer us!
The people we gave purple handkerchiefs to?
Yeah! I picked one up,
so I want to return it to him.
They were going to use the handkerchiefs later for something, weren't they?
Yeah. At the end of the party, we were going to choose a color,
and someone with that color handkerchief would be chosen to say a few words.
Then tell me their names. I'll look for someone who doesn't have one.
What should we do, Inspector?
If we keep holding them in, it'll turn into a panic!
However you look at it, it doesn't look like anything but an accident.
For now, let's get out of here.
Right.
I got it, little boy.
The guests who were given purple handkerchiefs are these seven.
Here.
Thank you.
I see. So it was one of those seven.
I'm not certain, but it's likely that among those seven
is one of them, Pisco.
Hey, they're coming out!
Excuse me, when the accident happened,
were you nearby?
I don't know! Now outta my way!
Tell us the details of the accident.
Talk to the police about that!
Damn. Let's go back to the doc's car for a bit.
Haibara.
Hey, Haibara?
Where are you? Answer me!
Wai—
Hey, where are you?
Answer me!
Haibara!
Haibara-san...
Wake up! Haibara-san!
Haibara-san!
What's wrong?
We're in class right now.
Could it be because of your cold?
You really should go rest in the nurse's office...
A dream...
That's it... That's it, isn't it?
Randomly meeting them in town is just too good to be true.
I've been having dreams like this a lot lately...
Maybe I'm just exhausted...
Haibara!
Answer me, Haibara!
Who...?
Hey, Haibara!
Who's there?
Haibara!
Who's there?!
Kudo-kun...?
Haibara? Is that you, Haibara?
Where...?
I'm in the doc's car in front of the hotel.
I'm speaking to you through the microphone and speaker in the glasses.
What happened to me?
That's what I want to know!
What happened in the hallway, in front of the party room?
In front of the party room?
Oh, back then I got engulfed by a wave of people,
and got separated from you.
Then someone came from behind me and...
Someone came from behind you and...?
Somebody made me sniff some drug,
and now I'm being confined in some winecellar.
Hey... By "somebody", you mean...?
Yeah.
Likely the Organization member who managed to commit murder in front of the police.
Pisco.
What?!
He's not there, is he? I mean, right next to you?
No.
Whoever he is, he's not here now.
But the door is locked tightly.
The only thing around is a large cardboard box and cart for carrying goods
and an employee boiler suit.
Boiler suit?
Yeah.
Likely, after making me sniff the drug, he must have taken me to the restroom or something,
changed into this previously prepared boiler suit, then stuffed me in the box and brought me here.
It was probably ready in case the attempt on that lawyer's life failed.
He'd have lured the lawyer to the restroom and killed him, then brought him here.
Whatever. Just hurry and find a way out of there, and find our next move.
Are you ready, Kudo-kun? Listen well.
In the Apoptoxin 4869 that regressed us to childhood, the "apo" stands for "apoptosis".
In other words, programmed cell destruction.
Yes.
Cells have a mechanism that forces them to self-destruct,
and we live because they receive a signal limiting that process.
Hey, Haibara...
However, this drug doesn't just activate apoptosis.
It also contains a telomerase, and increases a cell's reproductive ability.
Stop it, Haibara! I'll listen to as much as you want about that once you get out of there!
Shut up and listen!
I'll never... never be able to exchange words with you ever again.
What?
Don't you get it?
They held me here despite being in my shrunken figure.
Even if I were to escape from here, they'd find me in no more than two days.
If that happens, the doctor who protected me, and all others who were involved with me
would be killed to preserve their secrecy.
You get it?
No matter if I die here or if I escape,
I've already been forced into a state where I can no longer come into contact with any of you.
Haibara...
Therefore, I'm going to tell you all I can remember about the drug, as long as I'm here.
Tada! Dr. Agasa's Great Adventure II!
Hey... what was that just now?
Oh, it's the doctor's game that Tsuburaya-kun returned to me at school.
They were probably checking the MO disc in my pocket.
There's a cell phone attached to the PC, which means...
I knew it.
They were analyzing my face.
Hey, you aren't tied up?
That's why I'm in such a hurry.
They won't leave me for long without tying me down.
No, he won't be able to come back for a while.
After you disappeared, I called the inspector right away,
and told him to not let the guests with purple handkerchiefs leave the Haido City Hotel,
with Shin'ichi Kudo's voice.
That you aren't tied up, and that they left a PC connected to a cell phone,
likely means that the person who confined you
tried to leave the hotel for a bit in order to complete some sort of objective,
when they were stopped by the officers at the exit, and made to undergo police questioning.
Also, there's a good chance
that they're in a state where they can't communicate with the outside world.
It's already been almost an hour since you vanished,
so it would be unthinkable for neither him or his colleagues to not have come there.
He's there. One of the seven I chose...
the one who did the assassination and confined you...
is the one called Pisco!
Then this place is still somewhere in the Haido City Hotel?
Yeah, probably.
If I can prove the murder before he contacts his companions, and reveal him to the police,
then your secret will remain intact.
At best, the inspector can hold those seven for another hour or so.
Anyway, I'm going to the hotel's front desk
to ask them if there's any infrequently used winecellar in the hotel,
and I'll go and save you.
If I say there's a girl locked in there...
Idiot.
I told you what'd happen to those involved with me.
Don't complain to me, whatever happens to the staff members who help me escape.
Then find some way to get out of there by yourself.
In the meantime, I'll find Pisco out from those seven people.
That's really easy to say and all,
but there's no escape route in this room!
The only thing here is an old chimney.
Can you climb up that chimney?
No, it's too big to climb up.
If I weren't in this body, it looks like I could barely manage it by stretching my arms and legs.
Isn't there some sort of rope?
Not sure. Do they keep ropes in a winecellar?
If it's a winecellar, does it mean it has a wide variety of alcoholic drinks?
It looks like they took an old room that had fallen into disuse,
and turned it into a winecellar where they stored alcoholic beverages from around the world.
Is there baigar there?
Baigar?
Yeah. It's a strong liquor from China.
I know that, but...
Just look around for it.
Let's see if there's some.
But what do you want that for?
How's your cold?
You said you had a cold in the morning, right?
Your topic seems to jump all over the place.
Whatever. Just tell me how you're doing.
After my sleeping on the floor, I think my fever went up.
I see.
Oh?
You sound quite happy about it.
Yeah.
I found the baigar.
But what am I supposed to do with this liquor?
I'm going to get you out of that room.
By casting the ultimate magic spell on you.
This was the scene inside the hotel, right after the accident.
Even now, many people are still being questioned in a nearby room.
However, those individuals' names have yet to be released.
That is all. This is being broadcast live from the scene.
From that news report, I figured out the rough location of the seven right after the murder.
But this alone...
Hey, do you know how to spell "Hercule Poirot"?
What the heck are you doing? Did you drink the baigar already?
Yeah, I drank it.
I don't know what you're planning, but I feel even worse now.
Either way, tell me how to spell Poirot's name.
"H-E-R-C-U-L-E P-O-I-R-O-T", but...
What do you want to know that for?
I wanted to transfer the drug's data from the Organization's computer to the doctor's MO disc,
but I got stuck on the password.
...R-O-T.
It's no good. It's not Poirot.
Why did you think the password might be "Poirot"?
The people in the Organization called the drug by a name during its prototype phase,
They gave it the serial number 4869/shiyaroku after Sherlock.
They called it the "Incomplete Detective".
So I've been trying the names of great detectives as they popped into my head.
But I guess it's not going to be that easy.
"Shelling Ford".
The spelling is "S-H-E-L-L-I-N-G F-O-R-D".
Was there such a detective?
Just try it and see.
S-H-E-L-L-I-N-G F-O-R-D.
It opened! How come?
"Shelling Ford" was...
...a temporary name that Conan Doyle gave to his detective before naming him Sherlock.
In other words, it's the prototype of the Great Detective.
That's kind of clever for the Organization.
Anyway, we're running out of time.
Doesn't your body feel odd?
How could it not, after you had me down liquor like that?
Either way, I'll drop the drug's data on this MO disc and hide it in this winecellar.
You'll come get it later, right? After the Organization takes me away...
Hey!
S-Shin'ichi! Look!
It's them. Could Pisco have gotten through to them?
No, that can't be! The Inspector said he'd call me before releasing those seven!
No way!
Could there be a tracking device in the PC Haibara's using?
I get it. They called him and there was no answer, so they used the tracking device to get here!
Haibara, this is bad!
They're coming! For now, go hide in the chimney or something!
Hey, what's wrong?
Hey!
Inspector! It's Kudo!
Men dressed in black?
NEXT EPISODE
Pisco's not here.
A burn mark.
That means this chain...
I see. That's how it was!
I missed you...
Sherry!
Haibara!
Next Conan: "Reunion with the Black Organization (Case Closed)"
Next Conan's Hint: Fluorescent Paint
Look forward to the next episode!
Next time, an amazing development!
When you're not feeling well, it's not good to drink too much.