Flowing water has no form.
A blowing wind can't be seen.
All cases can be freely deduced!
Unbelievable dramatic developments!
The secrets of the Organization have come into sight!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a child
but has the mind of an adult.
His name: Detective Conan!
On the way home from school,
Haibara and I saw a car belonging to Gin, one of the men in black.
I set up a bug in his car, and we followed him.
But Gin found the bug,
and figured out that Haibara was still alive.
By intercepting his conversation,
we found out about their murder plans,
so we went to a party at Haido City Hotel being held in memory of a film director.
While slides were being shown in the hall,
a chandelier fell from the ceiling,
landing on top of Mr. Nomiguchi and killing him.
Also, someone kidnapped Haibara,
and locked her inside a wine cellar inside the hotel.
Are you ready, Kudo-kun? Listen well.
In the Apoptoxin 4869 that regressed us to childhood, the "apo" stands for "apoptosis".
In other words, programmed cell destruction.
Yes.
Cells have a mechanism that forces them to self-destruct,
and we live because they receive a signal limiting that process.
Hey, Haibara...
However, this drug doesn't just activate apoptosis.
It also contains a telomerase, and increases a cell's reproductive ability.
Stop it, Haibara! I'll listen to as much as you want about that once you get out of there!
Shut up and listen!
I'll never... never be able to exchange words with you ever again.
What?
Either way, I'll drop the drug's data on this MO disc,
and hide it in this wine cellar.
You'll come get it later, right?
After the Organization takes me away...
H-Hey!
S-Shin'ichi! Look!
It's them. Could Pisco have gotten through to them?
No, that can't be!
The Inspector said he'd call me before releasing those seven!
Haibara, this is bad! They're coming!
For now, go hide in the chimney or something!
Hey, what's wrong?
Hey!
Inspector! It's Kudo!
Men dressed in black?
Pisco's not here.
He was supposed to contact us 30 minutes after finishing off the target, but he didn't.
So we came here thanks to the tracking device, and the PC's here, but not him.
Just where'd he disappear to?
And what's the deal with this wine cellar?
Pisco probably prepared this room just in case.
If he'd failed in the party room, he'd probably kill him elsewhere, and bring him here afterwards.
Either way, we shouldn't stick around too long, Bro.
I suppose.
Hey, did they leave?
Yeah.
And uh... your clothes?
Pervert.
I'm wearing the boiler suit that was left in the wine cellar.
Of course, I have the MO disc with the copy of the drug's data, too.
But I'm surprised. That baigar liquor...
I wonder if it has some enzyme that speeds up cellular metabolism or something.
Don't get too relieved. It's only temporary.
Get out of that chimney before you turn back into a child.
Got it.
Now I look like Cordelia coming out of that well.
I feel like I'm going to faint.
By the way, have you figured out who Pisco is?
No, not yet.
There isn't enough information.
Look at this, Shin'ichi. The early edition of tomorrow's paper is on the Internet.
I already saw it, but...
No, look at the Entertainment page!
They say a photographer in the room took it right before the incident.
Isn't that two of those seven people?
Wait! Maybe...
A burn mark...
That means this chain...
I see.
That's how it was...
I'm out.
Good job, Ai-kun.
Do you know where you are right now?
Looks like I'm on a rooftop.
Rather, isn't Kudo-kun there?
No.
He was just talking to Inspector Megure, but he panicked and went into the hotel.
Panicked?
Well, don't worry.
He figured out who Pisco is.
He left a message for you: "I'll come get you soon, so just be patient and wait there."
That's fine.
As much as I try, my body just can't move.
I missed you... Sherry!
G-Gin...
Look at that. It's pretty, isn't it?
The white snow falling down,
as if dancing through the darkness,
painted by the scarlet color of fresh blood.
The glasses and boiler suit you wore to trick us
aren't a very attractive outfit to die in.
But this is an excellent place for a traitor to die.
Don't you agree, Sherry?
I'm surprised you knew I'd be coming out of this chimney.
It was this hair.
I found this reddish-brown hair of yours near the chimney.
I don't know if you were captured by Pisco,
or snuck into that wine cellar when he was out.
But I could hear them.
Your quivering sighs, coming from the chimney...
I could have killed you inside that dirty chimney,
but I thought I could at least
let your death flower bloom.
Oh my. I guess I should thank you.
For waiting for me in this cold.
I'll ask you while those lips still move.
How did you disappear from the Organization's gas room?
Eh? A wine cellar?
Yeah. I think it has a big chimney in it.
Do we even have a room like that in this hotel?
Maybe it's in the old building that's going to be rebuilt?
Old building?
Yeah. I heard they were using a room somewhere as a temporary storage room.
Storage... that's it!
Hey! Little boy!
Most likely, Pisco's on his way there right now!
If he meets up with those two, they'll figure out that Haibara shrunk with that drug!
Damn! If only the inspector could've held them for five more minutes.
What?! Haibara was shot?!
Yeah, on a roof somewhere. Hurry and g—
Hey, doc! Doc!
Damn, the battery must've died.
Haibara!
Bro, this girl's not gonna talk.
I guess there's nothing we can do.
Let's send her to meet her sister,
whom we sent first.
A needle?
Bro!
The chimney!
Get into the chimney!
Who the hell are you?!
Hurry!
Bro? What's wrong, Bro?
Oh, amazing!
You were still a baby, so you probably don't remember anymore,
but I was very close to your parents, who were scientists.
I was told a lot about the drug being developed.
Who...
But I had no clue that you managed to take it to this point.
Your parents, who died in that accident,
would've been very happy.
Who are you?
But this is an order, so don't blame me,
Shiho-chan.
Hold it right there!
Masuyama-san.
Or should I call you Pisco?
W-Who are you?!
You might think you skillfully dropped the chandelier
on Mr. Nomiguchi's head to make it look accidental,
but things never go that smoothly.
You dropped it, right?
With a silencer-equipped handgun.
Your target was the fluorescent substance you painted on beforehand.
Once the lights go out in the room from the slideshow, that light will shine through.
Of course, if you'd fired at it directly, there'd be a spark from your gun,
which would be noticed by the people around you.
But if you cover the silencer with a handkerchief,
the handkerchief will fly off with the bullet and hide the spark.
The reason you used the handkerchief from Director Sakamaki's mourning party
was because it'd be hard to trace even if it was found later on.
But unfortunately,
of the guests who received that purple handkerchief, most went home already,
leaving only seven suspects.
Tawara-san and Chris-san, being directly under the chandelier with no way to aim, are clear.
Mihei-san, who spat out the chain piece that became evidence from his mouth,
and Mugikura-san, who'd been watched by the guests on-stage, didn't do it either.
Tarumi-san and Nanjō-san, who were embracing each other right before the incident, are also clear.
In other words, the only one
who could have committed this crime
was you, Masuyama-san!
Over there!
And the reason Mr. Nomiguchi went under the chandelier
was because you put fluorescent material on the floor there, too.
You probably told him you could give him
a chance to avoid being arrested,
and to wait for you at the glowing place
once the lights went out.
Isn't that right, Pisco-san?
A speaker?
W-Who are you?!
Just what are you?!
Conan Edogawa. A detective.
D-Detective?
Could it be that you were the one giving out orders to the police during their investigation?
You and the two above will be caught by the police sooner or later.
Before that, could you tell me?
Why did you have that purple handkerchief during the investigation?
That's why the Inspector had to release you.
Could that handkerchief have been...
There are things in this world that you don't need to know.
And look at the situation.
You won't be able to call the police.
You should take a closer look.
At your feet.
Spirytus.
A strong liquor, with 96% alcohol.
You know what happens if you smoke
near that much alcohol, right?
A fire has broken out in room 404
of the old building.
I repeat, a fire has broken out
in room 404 of the old building.
What?!
Let's go check it out!
Hey, brat, where are you?!
Come out, damn it!
Where are you?!
There you are.
What's the meaning of this, Gin?!
It seems you messed up, Pisco.
Why didn't you immediately kill that photographer or get rid of the film?
Photographer? What are you talking about?
The front page of the early edition of tomorrow's paper has been swapped out for a photo of you.
It shows you holding your gun to the ceiling.
Don't do it! If you kill me, you'll never find Sherry!
I have a general idea of her whereabouts.
And if you kill me, who served that person for so many years, then your standing will...
Sorry.
This was a direct order from that person.
Wha—?!
Thanks to the power of the Organization,
you rose up in the world.
You've probably seen more than enough good dreams.
Maybe you can continue to dream more in the other world.
What?! Gin executed Pisco?!
Yeah. I was listening to the conversation through the glasses Ai-kun forgot in the chimney.
But I think he ran away through the chimney right after killing Pisco.
That's strange. How can he move after I shot him with the tranquilizer gun?
I thought a huge guy like him wouldn't be able to get away from the police, once put to sleep.
I'm also worried about how well they read Haibara's movements.
It seems like they knew she was going to the party.
Could they really tell it was her just from one strand of hair?
Hey, Haibara?
When you were in the Organization, were you...
Well, did they find out?
That my body shrunk.
No, I don't think they know. Don't worry.
So, what are you planning to do now?
Well...
Now that they know that I'm in this city,
I can't stay with you guys any longer.
And the MO disc in that boiler suit
is probably burnt up by now.
There's no reason for me to stay here anymore.
Don't worry. I'll leave first thing tomorrow.
Hey, hey, you can't do that in your condition.
All right, then everything's fine.
You're not going to search this city for that woman?
Yeah. I'm a shogun who doesn't do useless things.
She's probably long gone by now, with that man who came to save her.
She's not a stupid enough woman
to stay in a city where we saw her face.
My, it looks like you're quite caught up with that girl.
Sorry, Vermouth.
We called a lady like you to help that old geezer,
and got you into such a mess.
Really, to think I even gave him that handkerchief before he went into questioning.
You were right to kill him.
But don't you wonder
about the man with that girl?
Yeah, the man who is embraced by that woman.
I'd love to see his face.
Yes... His face, contorted in terror,
at the moment of death...
Are you going back to America?
No, I'm going to take a break
from being an actress.
I plan to relax in Japan for a while.
There's something I'm involved in.
Anyway, Inspector, please keep it a secret
that I was involved in this case.
I can, but...
Just what were you up to?
The family of the victim,
Mr. Nomiguchi, has all disappeared.
President Masuyama's home was burned down.
I have no idea what's what...
I can't say anything right now.
When I've figured things out, I'll be back in touch.
H-Hey! Kudo-kun!
Yes.
Everything suspicious goes up in smoke.
That's their MO.
Do you understand?
If anyone figures out who we really are...
Yeah. I'm well aware.
I have to take them down.
NEXT EPISODE
W-What?
T-This is...!
Strange.
What does this mean?
Did he injure himself in the restroom?
But why...?
Doc!
This is a murder case.
NEXT EPISODE
W-What did you say?!
Next Conan: "The Truck that Crashed into a Coffee Shop Case"
Next Conan's Hint: Bus schedule
Next time, it's the Detective Boys
after a long while!
Look forward to the next episode!
Ah, then I can take a rest.
Hey, help us out.