Flowing water has no form.
A blowing wind can't be seen.
All cases can be freely deduced!
Today, we're at a coffee shop by a road on a hill.
Was it an accident or a case that came flying in?
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Created by
Gosho Aoyama
"Detective Conan"
Serialized in Shogakukan's
'Weekly Shonen Sunday'
Planning
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Character Design
Masatomo Sudo
Art Director
Yukihiro Shibutani
Director of Photography
Takahisa Ogawa
Sound Director
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
Music
Katsuo Ono
Opening Theme
"Mysterious Eyes"
Performed by
Lyrics
Music
Arrangement
GARNET CROW
Nana Azuki
Yuri Nakamura
Hirohito Furui
Editor
Teramitsu Okada
Story Editor
Jun'ichi Iioka
Color Key
Reiko Hirayama
Executive Producer
Hiroaki Kobayashi
Planning Support
Toyohiko Okuyama
Mitome Asai
Chief Director
Kenji Kodama
Director
Yasuichiro Yamamoto
Producers
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Masahito Yoshioka
(Tokyo Movie)
I can't walk another step.
Hey, hang in there!
Just a little further...
According to Doc's map, it's right around this curve coming up.
You can do it, Genta-kun!
Hey, maybe taking the bus would've been faster!
No way!
We're going to be treated to lunch,
so if we take the bus it would render everything meaningless!
You mean you just wanted to save bus fare?!
What a tight-fisted brat.
Um... It's supposed to be around here...
Hey, Mitsuhiko, isn't that it?
"P-e-a-c-h S-u-n-d-a-y..."
This is the place after all.
Mitsuhiko-kun, you can read English?
I'm bilingual.
C'mon, let's go inside. I'm starved.
Yes, let's!
Welcome!
Uh, we...
Detective Boys, right?
You're going to meet with Dr. Agasa here, right?
This way please.
- Right.
- Right!
I'm starved.
Hi there, welcome to our shop.
Dr. Agasa called me about you.
He said he'll be a little late, so eat anything you like.
That looks yummy!
Hey, Genta-kun, ladies first!
O-Of course! Here you go.
Thanks.
Let's see...
Welcome.
My name is Ohara. I have a reservation.
Oh, please come this way.
They say the house specialty is great, it's the peach sundae.
It's the owner's original.
I'll have that, then!
Me too!
What would you like, Conan-kun?
The same as the rest of you is fine.
So, four peach sundaes please!
Okay.
That looks yummy!
- It's really yummy!
- It sure is!
Aren't you gonna eat, Conan-kun?
I'll take it, then!
Genta-kun!
It would be a waste if the ice cream were to melt...
What's that? Leaflets again?
It's a rush job.
Kazuo Ohara (52)
Ohara Design — President
They're going to be passing it out at the shopping center  this coming Sunday.
You should just refuse such a cheap-paying job.
Toru Aida (35)
Ohara Design — Designer
I can't do that!
This is the kind of job that leads to a stable income! Right?
That's right.
Will you think about the you-know-what?
No matter how many times you ask me,
my answer will not change.
Is it money you want?
If so, I'll increase the amount...
I don't think you can,
with what work you're doing now.
Maybe not just yet,
but I promise that someday I'll...
There you go again!
Can't you do something about it?
Talk about persistent.
I don't want to spend the rest of my life making leaflets!
Working with you is ruining my talent!
Take it easy.
I'll bet you don't have any on the pamphlets
of the resort hotel that I'm asking you to work on this time.
Yeah, as for that, I'll take the job as pay!
You can't handle it anyway if I leave, can you?
What?!
But I promise to finish these leaflets before I leave.
Let's get started. You're in a hurry, right?
I'm going to the restroom.
It was delicious!
Both of them?!
No way!
Mitsuhiko, what's your second recommendation?
You'll get a stomach-ache if you eat too much.
I'll be fine.
I told you so.
I-I gotta go to the restroom.
Genta, someone's in the restroom right now!
Huh? Somebody's inside!
That was good!
It's indeed worth recommending.
Hey, Genta, someone was inside, right?
Yeah...
I don't know who's in there,
but he doesn't answer when I knock!
- I'm gonna explode...
- Oh, he just came out.
Really?
Ah, a customer...
Yay, I'm saved!
If you're ordering seconds, get me some too!
Huh?
He's using his right hand this time...
He's ambidextrous.
Welcome.
Oh, Dr. Agasa!
Sorry I'm late.
We're all digging in.
Oh, eat all you like.
I won the raffle at the shopping center!
Alright then, I'll take...
a hot fudge sundae, custard à la mode
and strawberry shortcake!
How's your stomach?
Fine, just fine.
Look at that bus!
I wonder what it is. It's beautiful!
It really is!
I think I dropped my lighter. I'll go check.
I want it done by sundown. I'm counting on you.
Yeah, yeah.
Hey, Conan-kun, whatcha having?
Oh, I'll have coffee.
Coffee?
Uh, well, I mean...
W-What the?!
That's...!
Which means that you just happened to leave your seat, so you were spared?
Yes. I just happened to go to the restroom to look for my lighter.
Thank goodness you were spared...
Oh, you're the president of Ohara Design.
The office is located at the top of the hill, isn't it?
Saito-san!
I found the driver of the truck!
Okay, I'll be right there!
Did you park your car part-way up the hill, like this,
and make your delivery?
I'm sorry, I usually park on a flat place uphill,
Jiro Kobayashi (25)
Express Delivery Driver
but that car was parked here today,
so I had no choice but to park in front of it.
But I made sure my emergency brake was engaged,
and had the gear in reverse just to be safe!
Saito-san, I went to the site right away
and checked the driver's seat, but the emergency brake was disengaged!
That's impossible! Please check more carefully!
I know I pulled my emergency brake and engaged it!
Of course he's lying!
Aida-kun was...
Aida-kun was my precious right-hand man!
Without him, my company is finished!
Oh, no! Did someone die?
President!
Segawa-kun!
What are you doing in a place like this?!
Michiko Segawa (46)
Ohara Design — Clerk
If we don't deposit the money today,
they're going to stop shipment of the goods!
I know...
But this is no time for something that...
Aida-kun passed away...
He was in an accident...
O-Oh, no...
Strange. What could that mean?
H-Hey, Conan!
Conan-kun?!
Hey! This place is off-limits!
I forgot something in the restroom!
He was licking his finger when he first came out of the restroom.
I wonder if he got hurt in the restroom?
But why?
Blood stains?
These are traces of a hand touching the frame from outside!
I see.
The blood got here when he came back from outside.
That's why there was no answer when Genta knocked.
Ohara-san wasn't in the restroom then.
He hurt his left hand when he was outside.
That's why he held the pencil in his right after coming back...
But where did he go,
and what was he trying to do?
Before the accident, Ohara-san
seemed very concerned about the time.
Did he have to go out at a certain time?
Time...
Hey, Conan, where did you go?
I just went to get something I forgot.
Does anyone remember at what time the accident occurred?
About 2:10, right after Dr. Agasa got here.
2:10...
There's one at 2:07...
Is something wrong?
Well...
I wonder what route the bus that left here just before the accident took?
I think it should be coming back soon.
It's supposed to make a circuit from the complex back to the shopping center.
Why was that bus stopped?
This is the end of the line,
so the buses take a break for 5 to 10
minutes to get back on schedule.
What is it?
Do we have a case?
No fair, Conan! You're always hogging the clues!
He's right!
Hey, I'd like to ask you kids some questions too,
so come here, will you?
Okay!
Piano wire?
Aha! I've figured it out!
This is a homicide!
And the killer is...
I'm sure it's him!
Uh, officer.
Yes?
I have some urgent business to attend to,
so I'd like to be excused for a while.
We can't allow that.
I have to go make a bank transfer to one of my clients.
30 minutes—no, 20 minutes, please.
Has he been questioned?
Yes, briefly.
I guess you can go, then.
Thank you so much.
Not good.
If he's released, he'll go and get rid of all the evidence!
Doc!
This is a homicide!
W-What did you say?
Move your lips like always for me!
R-Right.
Wait just a minute!
Who, me?
Yes. I can't have you leave just yet.
What are you talking about?
This is a murder case!
Who are you?
My name is Agasa.
Will outsiders stay out of this?!
Hold it. Let's at least hear him out.
Agasa-san, do you have a lead?
I not only have a lead, I have proof.
Ohara-san...
I have proof that you are the killer!
D-Don't be ridiculous!
No matter how you look at it, this is an accident caused by the carelessness of the driver
whose truck crashed into the shop!
T-That's not true!
Let us hear, Agasa-san.
Very well. Then first, let me explain the trick.
Nonsense.
I'm a busy man! I don't have time
to waste listening to a made-up story!
Ohara-san!
It'll just be a short while, so let's hear him out.
Please continue.
Ohara-san, you parked your car
at the top of the hill
where the delivery truck always parks.
Then you asked Aida-san to come with you
to the coffee shop at the bottom of the hill.
And then you made him sit by the window,
so that he couldn't see the slope from his side.
Isn't that right?
No!
I didn't make him sit by the window so that he couldn't see the slope!
The place he sat just happened to be by the window!
I see.
Then you left a while later,
in the middle of negotiation,
pretending to go to the restroom.
I wasn't pretending! I really went to the restroom!
That's strange.
Genta-kun here says he kept knocking on the door, but you didn't answer.
That's right! My stomach was so sore, I thought I'd die!
T-That's because...
Back then, you snuck out of the restroom window,
and went over to the delivery truck.
You placed a wooden wedge that you had set up beforehand
in front of the front tires of the truck.
That's ridiculous.
Why would I do something like that?
It was a trick to make it look like you weren't committing the crime!
You attached piano wire to the wooden wedge,
and then tied it to the back of the bus
which was parked there for time adjustment.
Then you shifted the gear of the delivery truck to neutral,
and released the emergency brake.
You then returned to the coffee shop as if nothing had happened.
When the time came
and the bus started to move,
the wedge would come off.
That way, the delivery truck would roll down the hill all by itself!
All you had to do next was to wait for the bus to pass the coffee shop
and get out of the way...
by pretending to go to the restroom to look for your lighter!
I see!
The thing that was shimmering at the back of the bus
was the piano wire!
Right. And that wedge is right here!
You mean this?
Here.
Oh, right.
It's just a plain piece of wood...
The wooden wedge is dragged along by the bus,
and shatters as it bounces on the pavement.
That's what's left of the wedge.
The car, which was accelerating because the road was on a hill,
crashed into the window of the coffee shop,
and burst inside, just as you had planned!
Aida-san was hit and killed by the truck from behind.
Let's say... Let's say the trick is as you said.
But do you have proof that I did it?
Proof? I sure do.
This was your mistake: you hurt your finger tying the piano wire to the bus.
My hand got stuck on the restroom doorknob!
The delivery truck can be operated one-handed,
so you didn't leave any blood stains there.
But when you re-entered through the restroom window,
you touched it and left blood stains on it!
There's some blood on the inside of the restroom window.
After returning from the restroom,
you continued making arrangements.
But since you hurt your left hand,
you held the pencil in your right hand.
Conan witnessed you licking your left hand occasionally.
Isn't that right, Conan?
Yes, I hurt my finger.
But like I just said, I scratched it on the doorknob.
Can something like that be considered proof?
Can it, officer?
H-He's right...
Shut up!
Anyway, if you insist I'm the killer,
show me concrete evidence!
Hey, what's this?
There's a glove with a strange pattern in the car!
What is the meaning of this, Ohara-san?
If the piano wire on the bus is checked,
your blood should also be detected on it.
The blood stains from your wound in the restroom
and the blood stains on the glove in the car should match exactly!
The blood stain on the frame of the restroom window
shows that you held the frame from outside.
Furthermore, your blood stains are also on the piano wire tied to the bus...
How are you going to explain all this?
How about it, Ohara-san?
Yes. I did him in.
That guy...
Aida dared to forget everything I did for him until now,
and betrayed me by saying he was going to quit working for me...
If he were to quit, my company would go bankrupt...
If it were going to go bankrupt anyway,
I figured I should kill him
and make it look like an accident,
and at least get a hold of his
life insurance money as compensation.
To tell the truth, I hadn't made my mind up until we were at the coffee shop...
But he had the nerve to say he was going to take away a big job that I found as retirement pay!
W-What a thing to do...
I'm very sorry...
"Peach Sunday — Renovated and Reopening"
Thank you so much, Agasa-san.
Thanks to you, my innocence has been proven.
No problem, no big thing, I can handle things like this with my hands tied behind my back!
I am the one who taught the famous high-school detective Shin'ichi Kudo
the skills of being a detective, after all!
Really?!
Geez. You sure can talk.
Oh well.
Wow!
It's dated 10 years ago?
This is 10 years before Misaki-san got married!
Oh no!
Could there be more than one killer?
What is this a piece of?
Just as I thought... This is...!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Bust
Next time, a dignified tale!
kakuchō/hanashi
Big stomachs roaming free?
ikakuchō
hanashigai
Sounds great!