Flowing water has no form.
A blowing wind can't be seen.
All cases can be freely deduced!
A visitor from France!
Murderous intent harmonizes with the melody of the piano!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
The Kana Amusement Group
is a very big company.
Yoshinori Kana (35)
What would the chairman of such a company want to talk to me about?
Well, we're going to be making a CD
for Gerard Tenma at our company.
And we're going to be holding a private party upon the signing of the contract...
How nice! Tenma-san is finally going to make his debut in Japan?
Do you know him?
Of course!
He's a mysterious Japanese singer who is the talk of the French world of chanson!
No one knows anything about his personal history, isn't that right?
I'm amazed that you know.
Ever since the day we decided on the date of the party,
eerie things have been happening around his wife Misaki.
Eerie things?
Repeated phone calls,
with no one on the other end...
A bouquet of roses from an unknown sender...
And also...
This letter.
Blackmail...
"Those who do not realize my love will surely fall to the pits of hell..."
We got the other one yesterday.
"The curtains will be opened to commence the party of revenge.
Enjoy a party of terror to your heart's content..."
The party will be held in three days.
We can't cancel it now,
but I'm worried about my wife...
Do you have any idea who this may be?
We are carrying out the contract process in secret.
Therefore, the only ones who know that there is going to be a party
are my wife and I, and the other four who are scheduled to attend.
Three Days Later
"You left me behind all alone,
but I still have not forgotten you."
"My eyes are always on you."
"I hear your voice and I am just so delighted."
What on earth is that?
Oh, come on!
It's the Japanese lyrics to Tenma-san's
"The Red Nocturne of Love"!
Hm... "I'll send you a flower a day..."
"A red rose, a marigold, a lobelia,
a bright red dahlia, and a love song..."
"You are forever mine."
I wonder what she likes about a song like this?
I'm so happy that I'm going to get to see Tenma-san.
This is work now, remember?
We're supposed to be members of the Morita family, a friend of the chairman, understand?
Right, right.
I can't have them finding out that I'm a top-notch detective.
Don't worry. You don't look like one.
Sheesh. You two better behave yourselves!
I should be the one saying that!
Wow!
Going from the gate to the entrance of the house by car
is like what I've seen in foreign movies!
This is really some house.
They must be millionaires!
Hey, doesn't it look like a castle that you see in horror movies?
Oh no, thunder!
And it was such a fine day until just a while ago...
Didn't you want to see Gerard?
Being scared is another thing!
You are Morita-sama, correct?
Yes, I'm Morita.
Welcome.
Please come in.
Morita-san! We've been waiting for you.
Thank you for inviting us.
Welcome. Thank you for coming.
She's my secretary.
Masayo Tokudaiji (24)
Secretary
I'm Masayo Tokudaiji.
How do you do?
It's nice to meet you.
This is the reception room.
Oh, well, well.
The artwork here is also fantastic!
It's all my wife's taste.
Come this way, please.
Uh, may I take a look around your residence before doing so?
Oh, sure.
Tokudaiji-kun.
Please show them around.
Yes, sir.
No.
I'll show them around.
She's my wife, Misaki.
She's the president of the company group,
Kana Music Publishing.
Misaki Kana (32)
How do you do?
Shall we go?
Oh, yes.
Please prepare things in the kitchen, Masayo-san.
Your wife doesn't like me, does she?
Hey...
This is the room right above the large reception hall.
Beyond it is the piano room.
Oh, how wonderful.
You even have a spiral corridor in the house...
This sword...
Hey, runt!
Don't lay a finger on it!
It's not all that fragile.
Although it's just a decoration,
it's made of the same materials
and in the same way as the real thing.
In other words, it is the real thing?
The room next to the piano room is mine.
Come this way, please.
This room also looks very nice.
Is this a picture of your wedding?
How beautiful!
It was taken ten years ago today, in Fiji...
How nice...
We belonged to the same music club in our university days.
We went steady for a year, and then got married.
My, how I envy you.
H-Hello?
W-Who is it?
Who is it?!
The person hung up...
Hello?
They hung up...
Does this kind of thing happen often?
Yes...
In a hoarse, male voice,
things like "mon amie" and "je t'aime" are whispered.
And when I answer, the phone is hung up immediately.
You have no idea who it is?
Actually, that's not all.
Together with a letter, I got this...
Was this taken without you being aware?
This is what I found together with the bunch of marigolds I found at the front door this morning.
This seems to have been taken yesterday...
I'm scared because I feel like someone's always watching me...
After the rose is the marigold...
Always watching...
Worry no more.
I, Kogoro Mouri, will protect you,
Misaki-san, with my life.
Chairman, the guests have arrived.
I'll be right there.
I'm sorry to have kept you waiting.
Thank you so much for coming.
Brother, this is Gerard Tenma-san's manager.
Michel Anglade (40)
Manager
I'm Michel. Nice to meet you.
This is my older brother
Yoshinori Kana, and his wife Misaki.
How do you do?
Thank you for coming.
Where is Tenma-san?
I'm sorry. He had some other work to attend to,
so he'll be here about 30 minutes late.
Brother, who are they?
He's an old friend of mine, Morita-san.
Those are his children, Ran-san and Conan-kun.
Morita-san, this is my younger brother Hideki.
Hideki Kana (30)
He is the vice-president of Kana Music Publishing.
Brother, may I have a word with you?
What is it?
Excuse us.
Please come this way and have a seat.
Oh, what delicious-looking dishes!
Don't forget why we're here.
Why did you invite outsiders here?!
This is an important time when we have to sign a contract with Gerard.
Contract?
You leave for France on your own and suddenly bring Gerard along...
Thinking of the company, I don't see anything wrong in what I did.
For the company?
I guess so, because if this doesn't work out,
you can't make yourself look good to Misaki.
W-What are you talking about?!
I hear you've been persistently hitting on Misaki.
Who told you such a thing?!
What about you and Tokudaiji-kun?!
The rumor's going around all over the company!
Don't be ridiculous! There is nothing going on between her and me!
Anyway, I'm going to make this contract go through, no matter what it takes!
It's about time for Gerard to arrive.
I'll go wait for him by the front door.
Then, me too.
But first, I need to use the men's room.
Please get the next dish ready.
Yes, ma'am.
You don't have anything to drink, Morita-san.
I'll go get you some.
Oh, thank you very much.
Will you excuse me while I go fix my make-up?
Don't drink too much, Dad.
I know, I know.
Hey...
Don't you have to go guard Misaki-san?
That's right, Dad! You've got work to do!
I couldn't possibly go into a room where a lady is fixing her make-up.
Ran, you go.
Good point.
The power went out!
Lightning hit somewhere...
This is bad.
Upstairs?
Oh, no!
Help!
The door's locked!
Out of the way!
Help!
Hold it!
Misaki-san!
Where'd he go?!
Dammit. Where'd it go?
Misaki-san...
What's the matter? Are you all right?
Somebody switched off the breaker.
Misaki!
What's the matter?
S-Somebody suddenly attacked me...
T-That's...!
No!
Lobelia!
Just as I thought, this is...
Ran-neechan, flowers by that name come up in that song too, don't they?
That song?
You mean "The Red Nocturne of Love"?
Rose, marigold, lobelia...
Which means that all the flowers that the person had sent up to now are...
"My eyes are always on you.
I hear your voice and I am just so delighted."
Are you saying that someone is threatening Misaki
according to the lyrics of Gerard Tenma?
Threatening?!
It means that someone is stalking your beautiful wife.
Although I know we are all in the midst of a party,
I'd like to question all of you.
Are you the one who turned off the breaker?
Yes. On my way here, the breaker at the top of the stairs...
Where were you at that time, Hideki-san?
Morita-san, who are you?
I'm sorry, I'm not actually Morita, but Kogoro Mouri, a detective.
Kogoro... Mouri?
That famous...?
That is correct.
Misaki-san, you locked the door, didn't you?
Yes.
Just as I was about to fix my make-up,
the lights went out and I was attacked from behind.
You didn't see the attacker's face?
No, I didn't.
I did.
I couldn't see very clearly...
but he was wearing a cape, and had a facial expression...
He looked like a foreigner.
Like a foreigner?
Me? Why me?
Pardon me, but where were you at that time?
I went to the front door to meet Gerard.
The lights went out and I came inside because it started to rain.
I saw Hideki-san, and heard a voice scream, "Help!"
We came here together.
Will you cut it out?
Michel-san is an important guest!
Gerard!
He looks like the attacker...
Let me introduce you.
This is our main guest tonight, Gerard Tenma-san.
Gerard Tenma (34)
Chanson singer
There seemed to be no one downstairs, so I...
We had a little incident here.
May I speak to you downstairs?
Please come with me too, everyone.
The door of the room was locked.
Which means the attacker was already in the room.
Everyone who left the large reception hall beforehand had the chance.
So, who switched the breaker off?
Could there be more than one attacker?
Huh?
What is this a piece of?
The crack is still new...
There's more small debris nearby.
Here?
No, the size is different.
What is this a trace of?
Where were you all when the incident occurred?
I was in the restroom.
I panicked when the lights went out.
I was in the kitchen checking on the cake the mistress had baked.
Tenma-san, you were drenched, weren't you?
That's because I got out of the taxi by the gate.
Is that true?
Well, why don't we take a break then?
Excuse me.
Oh, no! Conan-kun...
That kid again...
Are you all right?
Dear, can you go get medicine from my room?
Sure.
The picture that was taken last night was...
Huh?
They seem to have struggled pretty hard...
Misaki-san and Gerard Tenma!
This is dated ten years ago...
two weeks before Misaki-san got married!
Hey!
Conan-kun, Dad's going to scold you again!
What's that?
Uh, er, well, this is...
Show it to me!
No! Don't!
What's the matter?
Oh no!
What is the meaning of this?!
Did you have a relationship with Misaki in the past?!
Now what do I do?
Brother, what a rude thing to say!
Hideki!
Don't tell me you knew about it!
W-Why would I do such a thing?!
Stop it!
Misaki...
Dear...
It's true that before I married you, I was dating him.
His real name is Jun'ya Tenma-san, and I used to go with him.
He was a nameless musician back then.
But on a certain day ten years ago, he suddenly disappeared.
Isn't that right?
When I saw the papers for Gerard Tenma that we were going to sign a contract with,
I was surprised to find that such a coincidence existed...
It's been a long time, Tenma-san.
Yeah.
Ma'am, I have a gift for you.
It's hand-made wine, something that you cannot get in Japan.
I would like to taste the wine...
There doesn't seem to be anything wrong with it...
Let's have juice.
Now, let's all have a toast.
Cheers!
She's still on her guard, after all.
Yes, this sure is good wine!
Oh, excuse me!
No problem.
Oh, yes! I was baking a cake.
Masayo-san, will you go to the basement in the yard and get me the silver tea set?
Yes.
I will serve you all a special hand-made cake I made.
Please wait a moment.
As one of the conditions of having your company publish "The Red Nocturne of Love",
I have slightly changed the lyrics and made a new arrangement.
A new arrangement?
Gerard insisted on doing so.
I found this bunch of flowers at the entrance...
Dahlias...
In the language of flowers... Betrayal.
Betrayal?
Thank you for waiting.
It's secret, everyone.
Tenma-san, won't you play your music for us?
After all, you're here in person...
Sure.
You attacked Misaki, didn't you?
Not that again.
Who else could've done it?!
I have to make preparations, so please leave me alone.
Are you running away?!
Would you cut it out?!
They seem to be having an argument...
Let's go check on them.
That's Tenma-san's voice!
What happened?
N-No! I didn't do it!
Gerard!
T-This is...?!
"The Red Nocturne of Love"!
Mr. Tenma wrote this song for Misaki-san ten years ago!
Is this blood?
No, it's not...
He's the one who attacked Misaki-san!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Wine
Look forward to the next episode!
Next time, the solution!
Cha-ri-ra-ri-ra-rin!
What's that?
It's the sound of a case being solved.
I see.