Flowing water has no form.
A blowing wind can't be seen.
All cases can be freely deduced!
The language of flowers has a deep meaning.
Songs and murderous intent cross the barriers of time.
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
We got a request for a job from Yoshinori Kana, chairman of the Kana Amusement Group.
He asked us to attend a party
and protect his wife, Misaki-san, who was being stalked by someone.
There was a blackout during the party,
and Misaki-san was attacked in her room.
Suspicion fell on Gerard Tenma, the main guest of the party.
However, Gerard Tenma himself was murdered.
The murder weapon is the knight's sword.
A tuning fork, used to tune the piano...
I wonder what this scratch is...
And what is the piano stool doing over there?
It's stuck under the large sofa.
You stay put!
Everyone, please move over to the waiting room,
so that we can keep the crime scene as is.
Gerard...
Yoshinori-san, are you the one
who killed Mr. Tenma?
N-No! It wasn't me!
I was in the waiting room! Right here!
Tenma ignored me and went into the piano room alone!
When I had no choice and was about to sit in the chair,
I heard a thump and a scream,
and when I went to look...
I found Tenma dead!
But at that time, everyone else was in the large reception room downstairs.
That's right, Brother!
Of all things, how could you...?!
I told you, I didn't do it!
You didn't like the fact that I decided on this whole thing by myself in the first place!
So when you found out that Sis and Tenma used to go with each other in the past,
you were enraged, weren't you?!
W-Well, that's...
So, the Kana family is finished...
It's too bad, chairman...
I wonder who will take over the Kana Amusement Group now?
I'm innocent!
And, did you see the killer?
Well...
When I got there, there was
already no one there...
Hey...
When Misaki-san led us in there,
the piano lid was closed, wasn't it?
I wonder if Gerard-san opened it...
No... In a room of this size, you can hear the piano well enough without opening the lid.
Gerard would never open it.
Come to think of it...
The top lid of the piano was open even before Tenma came into the room!
Which means that...
the killer could have opened the lid of the piano beforehand to block our view...
The only way out of this room is through the waiting room.
One of the windows was open,
but below it is just a large drop to the sea.
Even if the killer were to jump in,
it would be difficult to avoid the rocks.
Huh?
There's a scratch on the window frame too...
It looks like a scratch from a string or something that scraped it...
It's the same as when Misaki-san was attacked!
If a rope were used, you could escape either up or down.
Well, that is a reasonable possibility...
But could someone flee that quickly?
A scratch made by the tip of the sword cutting through the floor, perpendicular...
This means...
Maybe...
Let's position you all back where you were at the time of the crime.
Let's all go to the next room.
The small chandelier on this side
is positioned higher than the big one over there.
When we were brought in here,
I'm sure it was positioned lower.
Huh?
There's another scratch here.
It looks like the one by the window.
So this is the chain that moves the chandelier up and down.
I guess it's easy to roll it up.
Only this box has no dust on it.
"The Red Nocturne of Love"...
This song is a gift that Mr. Tenma dedicated to Misaki-san ten years ago!
Wait a sec...
What does this mean?
What's that?
On the piano...
Is this blood?
No, it's not...
Inside the piano too?
Detective Kobayashi...
What is it, Conan-kun?
Lend me your ear, please.
The inspector said that?
To look for a bust of Beethoven?
Is it really in the sea?
Good luck.
At any rate, I'll have to have you come to the station with me.
I didn't do it!
How many times do I have to tell you
to make you believe me?
Misaki! Help me!
Dear...
If this piece fits into that part...
Just as I thought!
This is the debris from the decoration up there!
Only that person could have committed the murder!
I'll take care of the company, Brother.
You're already thinking of selling a memorial CD of Gerard Tenma, aren't you?
How dare you!
That's the one who attacked Misaki-san!
Inspector Megure...
Like you said, this bust of Beethoven was found on the beach!
I never asked you to do such a thing.
Uh oh.
Hey, what's this?
There's a scratch below the railing
that seems to have been made by scraping a thin string or wire on it...
Huh?
What's this?
What's this string called?
Isn't this the string you use when you go fishing?
It's called fishing line.
Inspector, there was fishing line
and this stick on that bust...
What did you say?!
I see!
The scratch on the railing was made by the fishing line scraping against it!
Good, old man, just like that!
But why Beethoven?
Hey, there's Beethoven-san in this picture too!
What's this?
That was a picture that was secretly taken last night of this room.
This is just about there...
Oh, the statue of Beethoven isn't here?
Aha, I've figured out the caped phantom's trick!
What?!
Right. The bust of Beethoven belongs in this room!
If this trick was used...
Don't you think that beam fits the length of the stick?
Hey!
Doesn't the piece that was found
fit right into the crack over there?
Right.
Let's try it from the balcony on the other side.
Misaki-san, would you please lend us a fishing pole if you have one?
S-Sure.
The eaves stick out more than the railing,
but if a fishing pole was used, it's simple.
The end of the string was tied in a loop, with a weight on the other end.
Then, the string was pulled under the railing...
Detective Kobayashi.
Please put your finger through the loop in the fishing line and hold it in place.
Sure.
May I borrow your coat, Inspector?
So now, we're all set.
Detective Kobayashi.
Struggle with the phantom,
and let your hand go on my mark.
Then pull the string.
All right.
Let's begin.
Ah, help!
Now! Pull the string!
Let the string go!
This is fantastic! It's perfect!
Hey! My coat!
That movement just now was exactly the same as Misaki-san's attacker...
Then...
You don't mean... it was you?
In a dark room, it looked like the caped phantom fled.
In other words, the victim and the attacker are one and the same.
The killer switches off the breaker in the corridor,
goes back to her room right away,
locks the door and screams.
Isn't that right, Misaki-san?
Misaki?
Perfect, just as would be expected of a famous detective.
However, all the pranks and threats I have received until now
are a matter of fact.
I wanted you to believe me, so I put on an act...
I see...
But this is not directly connected to the murder of Mr. Tenma.
Yoshinori-san.
Please come with me to the station.
Fine.
This is not looking good.
What was that?
The piano room?
Conan, what's up?!
Where are you?!
What is it now?
Inspector Megure.
Please don't take him yet.
What?
Oh, that thing's happened?
Yes, I've finally figured it out, Inspector.
Please look at the sword scratch on the floor.
The angle of the scratch indicates
that it fell perpendicularly.
The result of the investigation shows likewise.
And the railing of the spiral corridor by the window.
The scratch left on the tuning fork
that Mr. Tenma was holding...
If we connect all the traces left behind,
we will discover a certain horrible trap.
There is a chandelier right above the scratch on the floor.
That is, in fact, the last point
that connects all the traces.
Y-You don't mean...
I do.
The sword that was suspended from that chandelier
fell straight down, pierced Mr. Tenma,
and left a perpendicular scratch on the floor.
O-Oh, no...
But, Mouri-kun,
even if he conveniently stood right under the place where the sword descended,
wouldn't he have been stabbed in the head or the shoulder?
However, Mr. Tenma was lying on his stomach.
No such thing could be done!
The answer to that mystery is the tuning fork.
Tuning fork?
And the piano bench.
The space between the piano and the bench is only enough for one person.
That was the trap.
When Mr. Tenma came up
to the keys of the piano to play,
the bench was overturned beside the piano.
He also found the tuning fork used to tune the piano on the floor.
Well, Mr. Tenma would naturally go to pick it up.
And if so, he would turn his back to the sword.
And the tuning fork that he picked up is the very thing that made the sword come falling.
What do you mean?
This horrible trick...
It was set up by placing a long string through the middle of the sword's handle,
then gathering both sides of the string,
pulling them through the metal structure of the chandelier
using the railing of the spiral corridor as support.
One side was wound once around the large sofa,
then the tip of the string was attached to the tuning fork.
The other end of the string was left outside the window,
with a weight attached to it.
After that, Mr. Tenma pulled the tuning fork out from under the chair.
The string that was attached to the tuning fork was released by the weight of the sword,
and the heavy sword probably came falling in an instant.
On the other hand, the fishing line that was holding the sword in place
was pulled by the weight suspended outside the window
and dropped into the ocean below.
I see.
So, who set all this up?
Please recall...
The trick using the fishing line...
The method of throwing the evidence into the sea by using a heavy weight...
It is exactly like the one used with the caped phantom that was just demonstrated, is it not?
Misaki?
Yes. The killer is you, Misaki-san!
After we all drank the wine,
you pretended to go to the kitchen,
but you set your trap up here, didn't you?
By raising the chandelier to the very top,
you made it harder to spot the sword,
as well as increased its killing power, right?
I thought you were a great detective,
but I guess I was wrong.
Do you have proof that I did it?
I'd like you to take a look at the lid on top of the piano, and the stains inside it.
This is... wine?
Judging from the place where it is spilled,
it must have dripped when she opened the lid.
The one who spilled the wine is the killer!
How can you be so sure?
Because the wine is what Michel-san brought from France,
and one that is not sold in Japan.
Yes. This is unmistakably the wine that I brought.
We were all drinking that wine.
Misaki-san is the only one who didn't drink it.
When I bumped into her and spilled the wine,
the wine that was probably left in the gap of her brooch
spilled out when she opened the lid on top of the piano.
You not only made it look like you were attacked by Mr. Tenma,
you set it up so that the picture of you two in the past would be found,
and tried to frame Yoshinori,
who you figured would get angry and kill Mr. Tenma, isn't that right?
Misaki, is that true?
How are you going to explain
the stalker incidents before all this?
She probably acted it out herself.
The prank call that came a while ago
was probably made by Misaki-san herself from her cellular phone.
Why would she want to kill Tenma-san?
The date of that picture
of Mr. Tenma and Misaki-san
was only two weeks before her marriage, wasn't it?
T-That's ridiculous!
And "The Red Nocturne of Love" was a song that was written for you, ten years ago.
Vraiment?
At first glance, the song appears to be a love song.
But in the language of flowers,
Red Rose —
Burning Passion
red roses symbolize burning passion,
Marigold —
Hopelessness
marigolds symbolize hopelessness,
lobelias malice,
Lobelia —
Malice
and dahlias betrayal.
Dahlia —
Betrayal
In other words, this was a song of hate, written for someone who had betrayed one's lover!
Is that true, Misaki-san?
Yes.
That day, ten years ago,
he insisted on not leaving me,
so I called him out to a nearby beach
and pushed him off a cliff.
Then you married Yoshinori.
However, Mr. Tenma miraculously survived,
went overseas, and adopted a French name.
When you found out Gerard Tenma's true identity,
you figured you had no choice but to kill Mr. Tenma again,
in order to keep your previous crime from being revealed!
But why did you try to frame Yoshinori as the killer?
It was Masayo-san's fault!
If I got caught, my husband and the company would be taken away!
But a man in prison can't be taken away from me.
I was planning to take over the company until he returned...
Misaki...
When Tenma-san's body wasn't found ten years ago,
I was always afraid that he might still be alive.
Because I also knew the meaning of that song.
Well, the fact is, whenever Gerard sang that song at his concerts,
he would whisper the following phrase without fail.
Pour compenser ton cœur blessé.
In French, those words mean
"To compensate your wounded heart."
The new arrangement had new lyrics,
but most probably...
Yes! Except for red roses,
the flowers have all been changed
to hyacinth, laurel and olive!
The flowers stand for sadness, peace and glory...
I see.
Mr. Tenma, having realized that he had harassed Misaki-san into trying to kill him,
continued singing this song with feelings of compensation,
and probably deliberately decided
to sign a contract with the Kana Group.
Yes. He once fell into the pit of grief,
but he no longer hated Misaki-san,
and having achieved success and happiness himself,
he probably wanted her to hear
the real "Red Nocturne of Love".
That's right!
Ever since then, I've been super-interested in the language of flowers.
Talk to you later, Sonoko. Bye-bye!
Welcome back.
Here. I saw this at the flower shop, so I bought it.
You bought that for me, Conan-kun?
Thanks!
Wow, what pretty peach blossoms!
Hmm, this flower stands for...
"To be unrivaled in the world..."
Hey, Conan-kun, what do you mean by this?
Uh, well, you see...
Just what do you mean,
"to be unrivaled in the world"?!
Exactly that.
Hurry!
Let's get outside before they get into the elevator!
No use running away!
What I want to say is...
that you are an impostor!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Alphabet
Look forward to the next episode!
Next time, a nine-story apartment building!
Where the Detective Boys play a big part!
So where do I come in?