Flowing water has no form.
A blowing wind can't be seen.
All cases can be freely deduced!
Today's point is a shopping receipt!
A small piece of paper says a lot!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Hey, hey, how about it, Mitsuhiko?
Yaiba Kick!
Damn, I lost!
My turn next!
How long are you guys gonna keep this up?
There, Ayumi! Go for it!
Yaiba Kick! Take that!
A Dangerous Recipe
Basement Floor 1, Food Checkout
An ice cream cone after a battle is the best!
You can say that again!
You should've played too, Conan-kun.
Maybe next time.
It sure is crowded, isn't it?
It's already past 4:00,
so they're all here to buy things for dinner.
Dinner... I wonder what we're having tonight.
I hope it's eel on rice.
I got it!
Why don't we play a menu deduction game?
A menu deduction game?
What's that?
Well, it goes like this.
We deduce what the shoppers are having for dinner
by looking at the receipts they leave behind.
Alright?
Okay, here goes.
Potatoes, onions, half a dozen keiran...
Keiran? What's that?
Eggs. Chicken eggs.
Next...
Ground beef, bread crumbs...
And the answer is?
I got it! It's a croquette!
But you also need flour to make it, don't you?
Maybe she's already got the flour.
Oh, I see.
It's my turn next.
Uh...
Chicken thighs, ketchup, green peas,
tomato, lettuce and celery...
Chicken rice!
With a garden salad.
Alright, my turn next!
Oh, there's a bunch of 'em...
Okay, here goes!
Uh...
Potatoes, onions, beef, flour, sugar.
The answer is...
Meat and potatoes? No...
Cream stew or gratin?
But usually you'd use salt and pepper, not sugar.
Maybe the sugar is for something else?
The person doesn't have to be buying ingredients just for tonight's dinner, right?
I see, that's true too.
Then, here's the next one!
P-P-Petit knife...
Cutting board, grater, handy gloves...
Food container... Dust pan...
Isn't that the receipt for a different section?
But what's this thing called "petit knife"?
It's a small knife.
Something like a knife for cutting fruit.
What about handy gloves, then?
Gloves used when cooking?
Do you wear gloves when cooking?
Oh, I get it!
That person probably just moved in,
and is going to start cooking tonight!
That's why the shopper bought
a knife and cutting board too!
The grater's going to be used for grating onions!
Those are some pretty good deductions.
The dustpan's gonna be used for cleaning!
Obviously.
I wonder if she's a young woman?
It could be a man, too...
Uh, the third one is...
Oh, it's a Kamen Yaiba color ball!
Huh, maybe there's a kid?
The fourth one is...
Size 2 batteries, handle light...
What's a handle light?
I think it's a light that you attach
to the handlebars on a bicycle?
The items are not all food, are they?
The fifth one is...
This one's from another store.
Satoshi Kobayashi Drug Store...
That's the drug store next door.
The name of the drug store changed recently, didn't it?
Never mind that, what's on the list?
Uh, clo...clono...clonin?
Clonin?
Genta, show me that!
And the receipt from the food products section that you read at the beginning.
W-What's with you, Conan?!
Hurry, give it to me!
What's the matter, Conan-kun?
He's right... Clonin...
Just what is that thing called clonin?
It's a colorless or whitish crystalline substance,
usually used to sterilize or disinfect the skin.
There is another way this substance is used...
Another way?
Clonin has a very high toxicity...
I-It's poisonous?
Well, usually it's used to make bait to get rid of moles.
The ingredients for making that mole bait are on this receipt—
potatoes, onions, beef, flour and sugar.
Then maybe the shopper bought them to get rid of moles?
Genta, do you think there are moles in a city like this?
Ah, right.
Maybe we see mice sometimes, but...
Then maybe it is gonna be used
as a skin disinfectant after all.
The potatoes and onions are
going to be make stew or gratin.
Well, I guess so...
Conan-kun!
If it bothers you so much,
why don't you ask the employees here?
Yeah, you're right.
Hm...
3:20 PM...
It was bought only an hour ago.
The person in charge is Masako Arai-san.
Thank you for waiting.
I remember that person very well.
All right!
He was about 20 years old.
At first I thought we were out of what he wanted,
so I told him it'll come in tomorrow.
But he insisted he needed it today...
How did he act?
Well, he seemed sort of jittery,
and didn't look all that calm.
Do you remember his face?
The color of his hair?
Was he fat like me?
Please tell us!
Hey...
Height, about 170 cm...
Light hair and wearing glasses...
Skinny and wearing a dark shirt...
The question is why he bought clonin...
Yeah. If he used it to disinfect his skin,
it bothers me that he didn't seem calm.
Hey...
What happens if a person eats the mole bait?
It won't kill the person,
but it will probably paralyze the body, making it unable to move.
Unable to move?
I got it!
The guy was trying to make mole bait!
He was going to make someone eat them
and then kidnap the person!
Kidnap?!
If so, it makes sense why he bought the ingredients
to make mole bait, despite no moles!
Anyway, let's find out who this man is!
I don't remember. There were a lot of shoppers...
This is the one.
Petit knife, 1980 yen.
It's small, but it's enough to cut potatoes and onions.
The cutting board is plastic and is also the smallest one they have.
The grater is also plastic.
Everything looks like something a man who doesn't usually cook rushed to buy.
Hey, here's the 120 yen gloves!
Very thin gloves made of polyethylene...
If these are used to make mole bait, no fingerprints would be left behind.
Disposables...
But it's more than enough to carry the mole bait.
This has the longest and narrowest handle.
But what does a dustpan
have to do with mole bait?
I...can't tell either.
Come to think of it, a guy like that could have bought it...
Do you have any idea who he is?
No...
Did you know, this ball glows in the dark?
It's made with fluorescent paint.
What does this have to do with the mole bait?
We didn't notice anybody like that buying it, did we?
And we were playing a video game right behind here, too...
Ah, this handle light...
I remember it well, because it's a new item that just came out three days ago.
Here.
This is an important piece of evidence!
Was the person who bought it...
about 170 cm tall and...
skinny, wearing a dark shirt,
with light hair and glasses?
Oh, you know a lot.
He also bought batteries.
But I have no idea who he is or where he lives.
Understood. We'll buy that.
Are you gonna put that on your bike too, Conan?
If you are, you gotta buy batteries too.
I'm not going to use it.
We'll use it as a clue to find the man.
But how, without even knowing his name or address?
No, we've got a clue.
The sixth receipt.
Come to think of it, we haven't looked at the sixth receipt yet.
It's a receipt from a convenience store.
Utopia, at Beika Park.
What was bought was a vinyl umbrella.
The time was 2:50 PM.
2:50?
That's about the time we were at the Beika Library.
Yeah, and there was a sudden rainstorm.
200 meters from this shop is a bus stop for the Beika Station bus.
The man probably took that bus.
I think he walked from where
he lives toward Beika Station.
But since it suddenly started raining,
he went into this store and
bought himself the vinyl umbrella.
Which means where that man lives
is near this convenience store,
in the other direction from the bus stop,
too far to go back to look for an umbrella.
Judging from the fact that he
bought a knife and cutting board,
he probably doesn't live with his family,
but rather, alone, in an apartment or condo.
I see!
It's very likely a man who lives by himself
frequents the convenience store!
Maybe we'll be able to find out
who he is or where he lives!
Okay, let's go to that store!
The man said he had to have the clonin by today.
If he plans to prepare the mole bait
today and make someone eat it...
We've gotta hurry, there's no time to lose!
This way!
A man with light hair, wearing glasses,
about 20 years old, about 170 cm tall...
We have a lot of customers like that.
He bought a large vinyl umbrella at about 2:50 PM...
Maybe it could be him...
You know him?!
He comes here every so often.
Do you know his name or address?
No...
But I think he lives nearby,
because he comes here wearing sandals most of the time.
We couldn't find out who he is or where he lives after all...
We've got no choice but to split up and look for him.
L-Look for him? How?
The bicycle!
Bicycle?!
The man didn't go shopping with his bicycle,
because it wasn't equipped with a basket to carry his things in.
And I'm positive that the guy's bicycle has a brand-new handle light just like this on it!
I see! So we're going to look for a bicycle without a basket
that has a brand-new handle light attached to it parked in the nearby apartments!
Yeah.
Take this, Genta, so you don't make a mistake.
Alright!
Ayumi-chan and Mitsuhiko, take these.
Right.
Listen.
Like I said before, the man's house is near here in the other direction from the bus stop.
He lives far enough away that it's too much trouble to go back home for his umbrella.
If you find him, report in on your Detective Badges!
See ya!
Conan-kun!
The bus stop's this way!
Where the heck is he going?
I'm sure Conan-kun has something in mind.
Let's go ahead and look for the guy.
He probably went to buy the handle light today,
because he's planning to use his bike tonight.
We've got to be ready for that too!
But I wonder what he's gonna use the dustpan and ball for?
Found it!
Testing microphone, testing microphone.
Detective Boys, Detective Boys!
I found the bicycle in question!
Report to the scene on the double!
Good work, Genta!
Genta-kun!
So you found it!
Only Conan hasn't shown up yet...
You went back to get your skateboard?
Yeah.
So he lives here...
But I wonder which apartment he lives in...
Let's hide and watch.
He should be coming out.
Yeah!
Somebody came out!
About 170 cm tall, skinny, wearing a dark shirt...
Light hair and glasses!
Is it him?
Wait!
It's definitely him.
Alright!
Yikes!
Me too!
Oh, geez.
Hang on tight!
Conan-kun, he's pulling away from us.
At this rate, we'll lose him!
Can't you speed up a bit more?!
You guys are too heavy!
He's gone...
We've lost him after all...
He got off his bike here, which means...
It's most likely that he went into one of the houses nearby.
Should we check the houses one by one?
I-I don't wanna go in this alley!
There's a house with a big yard, and a big dog that barks a lot!
A dog?
Don't tell me...
Did you know, this ball glows in the dark?
This has the longest and narrowest handle.
Don't do it.
What you are about to do is a crime, you know.
No use running away!
Your name is Murakami, isn't it?
We know where you live too!
What?!
What's that?
Well, Murakami-san?
Still gonna run?
Genta, take off your shoe!
Your shoe!
Take this!
My shoe...
After that, the neighbors called the police, who arrived quickly.
Murakami was arrested.
To think he was going to give the mole bait to that dog...
I heard on the phone from the Beika Town police detective
that the guy was saying he was going to kill that dog one of these days.
Every day when he went out for a walk along his favorite path,
that dog would bark ferociously at him.
That dog really does bark a lot.
He learned how to make mole bait from a book,
and yesterday afternoon, when he passed by the house,
he happened to find out that the whole family was out on an overnight trip.
He suddenly decided to carry out his plan.
He was going to feed the dog the mole bait,
and after it became unable to move, he was going to hit it with the stick and kill it.
The menu game that we decided to play
end up saving that dog's life, didn't it?
Yeah.
Let's do it again! I brought the receipts!
Don't pick stuff like that up!
Okay, here goes!
Sashimi, mayonnaise, cup noodles...
I feel sick.
NEXT EPISODE
"The cursed mask will sip blood tonight..."
Jofre's masks are gone!
This is a declaration that a murder will be committed,
from the messenger of the cursed masks!
Next Conan Special:
The Cursed Mask Smiles Coldly