Flowing water has no form.
A blowing wind can't be seen.
All cases can be freely deduced!
Today is a special with cursed masks!
A mysterious room and an eerie smile!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Dad, drive careful, will you?
She's right.
Remember, you're going to be performing on a charity show held for children
who have lost their families in car accidents next week, Uncle.
If you get into an accident in a place like this,
we couldn't face up to Beniko Suo-san, the hostess who chose you as a guest!
I know!
Suo-san invited us to a party today too.
If I get in an accident, I'll miss out on all the good food!
Hey...
That Suo-san used to be a famous singer, didn't she?
Yeah.
She used to a big star. They called her the Canary of the Orient.
But nowadays she's so busy being the president
of a show-biz promotion company called Kurenai Promotion
that she's hardly ever on stage anymore.
Oh, geez.
That was dangerous!
Why is this tree lying in the middle of the road like this?
Hey, there's something posted on it.
What's this?
Don't take part in the charity party held by Beniko Suo. You'll regret it.
The Messenger of the Cursed Masks.
Oh, no...
What's that supposed to mean?
The Messenger of the Cursed Masks...
What a mansion...
This is some mansion, isn't it?
Huh? That's...
Masanori Katagiri, the photographer...
You mean the one who travels around the world taking pictures of beautiful landscapes?
Masanori Katagiri (45)
Photographer
Mamoru Matsudaira (24)
Pro Baseball Player
The King of Home Runs, baseball player Mamoru Matsudaira?!
Huh? And you're that famous detective...
Kogoro Mouri-san, aren't you?
Yes.
Are you guests on next week's charity show too?
Wow, what a beauty!
She's Haruka Nagara-san.
You mean the tarot card reader who's all the rage on TV and in the magazines?
You know her too?
Whenever I step up to the plate, I read her predictions
and put on gloves that match her lucky color of the day!
And that's how you became the King of Home Runs?
This is...
What seems to be the matter?
Haruka Nagara (25)
Tarot Card Reader
I feel something ominous about this mansion...
I feel that there is going to be a great disaster...
W-What an eerie thing to say...
Well, rather than talk out here,
shouldn't we ask to be let in?
Y-You're right...
But which door do we use to get into the mansion?
There are two entrances...
Thank you all for coming.
Oh, so that side's the entrance.
Huh? What's going on here?
Honami Shimogasa (21)
Suo House Maid
Mouri-sama and his party, please enter from this side—the east entrance.
Only us?
Minaho Shimogasa (21)
Suo House Maid
Katagiri-sama, Matsudaira-sama and Nagara-sama,
please enter from this side—the west entrance.
Why are we going in separately?
The inside of this mansion is divided into west and east.
Those who will be spending the night in the rooms on the west side,
enter from the west entrance.
Those who will be spending the night in the rooms on the east side,
enter from the east entrance.
It is a tradition practiced here.
What a strange place.
If we don't stick to traditional practices in this mansion...
Grave misfortune will befall us.
Misfortune?
What makes you say that?
Because this is the place where...
- ...the cursed masks reside.
Cursed masks?
It's a mask!
There's one here too.
Suo-sensei likes to collect masks.
This way, please.
This one's a cat mask...
Your luggage has already been brought here,
so please wait in the mask room.
Mask room?
This room.
Huh? Mouri-san?
I see.
E
2ND FLOOR
W
MASK ROOM
This room connects the east and west wings of the mansion.
Wow, this is fantastic!
There are so many masks...
Look at all this...
What's this?
A remote control?
W-What the...?
What the heck is this?!
W-What's with all these masks?!
What is all this?
What are all these masks?
These are called the masks of Jofre...
Y-You are...
Beniko Suo (63)
Singer ∙ President of Kurenai Promotion
Beniko Suo-san?
Thank you so much, everyone, for coming.
Kazuyo Inaba (40)
Suo's Secretary
How do you like my precious collection?
Uh, yes, well, I guess you could say...
You just mentioned the masks of Jofre,
but are you referring to the masks covering the side wall?
Yes, it is said that the Spanish sculptor,
Jofre Gonzales, made them just before he died.
These are the two hundred masks that he made.
They are also called the Cursed Masks.
Cursed Masks?!
Uh, what are these cursed masks all about?
Jofre Gonzales is a sculptor of tragedy.
Although overflowing with talent,
trapped by the jealousy of his brother,
his fame, glory and estate were all taken away from him.
Jofre, who became very wary of people,
began making masks as if obsessed.
After finishing his two-hundredth mask, he killed himself.
The masks were scattered upon his body and splattered with blood,
as if they had sucked the blood from him while he was still alive.
Since then, Jofre's reputation was restored,
and his masks were handed down to various people.
But many who owned the masks seem to have died tragically.
An English bank president fell off his horse
the following day after getting hold of one of the masks, and died.
A French jeweler was attacked by robbers and killed...
And with the passing of time, these masks became known
as the cursed masks that sip the blood of their owners,
and were feared by people.
Are you all right, owning all two hundred of those masks?
No need to worry.
I had a master spiritualist seal the curse in.
It's starting to get more and more occult around here...
But, Suo-san,
the evil will of a living person may be even more frightening than a curse.
Oh, what do you mean?
Well, on our way here, our path was blocked by a fallen tree,
and we found this pinned to the tree.
Mouri-san! I received a similar letter three days ago!
I got one too!
Same here.
What?!
It seems to be more than just a prank...
It seems that the office also sent me a strange letter.
Toya, you're late!
Toya Aikawa (26)
Rock Singer
I'm right in the midst of a nationwide tour.
Sorry I'm late.
Who is he?
Oh, Conan-kun, don't you know him?
He's the popular #1 rock singer Toya Aikawa-san.
You received a strange letter?
The name of the sender is not written.
The way the name of the addressee is written is also odd.
It seems a ruler was used so that the handwriting cannot be identified.
May I open it?
Yes, please do.
This is...
The cursed masks will sip blood tonight.
The Messenger of the Cursed Masks...
Suo-san, you should call the police...
There's nothing to worry about.
Ever since I've started the charity show, I've been bothered by pranks like these.
Yes, this stew is very delicious indeed!
East Wing, First Floor
Dining Room
This wine sure is good too!
Top class!
Ladies and gentlemen, I am greatly thankful
that you have all graciously accepted to appear as guests
on the charity show that I will be hosting.
Suo-san, may I ask you a question?
What is it?
How did you come across the idea of saving children
whose parents who have become victims of traffic accidents?
I started this charity about 15 years ago.
But to tell the truth, my manager caused a hit-and-run accident.
A hit-and-run?
Yes. Ever since then,
I could not stand being indifferent to traffic accidents.
There are people saying that she's a publicity seeker,
but it's really nothing like that.
Um... What happened to the manager after the incident?
She committed suicide.
That manager happened to be my mother.
Your mother?
Since I lost my father at a young age,
after my mother died, I was sent around to my relatives' homes.
I really had it tough.
But, Suo-sensei here helped me in every way she could.
I'm what I am today thanks to her.
Toya's mother was more a cherished friend of mine than a manager.
There are many at Kurenai Promotion
who have lost their families in traffic accidents.
Sensei is putting a lot of effort in helping the children
of traffic accident victims become independent.
What a touching story!
I'll cooperate as much as I can at your charity show next week!
Same here.
Actually, I lost my wife in a car accident 20 years ago.
I'm sure that my wife in heaven is happy
that I'm going to be taking part in Suo-san's charity show too.
West Wing, Third Floor
Suo's Living Room
Hey, I'd like you to investigate something for me, Mouri-san.
Yes, I know.
You'd like me to figure out the one who sent out those letters, right?
No.
Well, I wonder if you can check in detail
on the traffic accident that took Katagiri-san's wife.
Katagiri-san's...?
May I ask you why?
There is something that bothers me...
Would 2 million yen be enough to do it?
2 million yen?!
I'd be more than glad to!
You're pretty good, King of Home Runs!
It's just luck!
Conan-kun, you play very well.
Mouri-san, this year is a good year for you to begin something new.
Something new?
Why then, Mouri-san, how about making a debut as a singer from our company?
I'm sure it'll make a great hit if it is sung by
the modern-day great detective, Mouri-san!
I guess I'll sing you a song then!
- We're sorry...
Everyone, when the clock strikes midnight,
we have a tradition of locking the door of the mask room.
When the door is locked,
we will not be able to pass back and forth between the east and west wings.
Therefore, we would like you to go into your rooms before that.
No way...
Midnight is still too early to close up...
Is there a reason for locking the doors at midnight?
The masks of Jofre like pranks
and begin playing on their own come midnight.
Therefore, we must lock the door and keep them confined.
T-That's ridiculous!
It's true.
Come morning, the masks are tilted unnaturally...
...or down on the floor.
This has happened many times now.
- Now, please go into your rooms, everyone.
Can this story get any more occult?
East Wing, Second Floor
Guest Room
Ugh, his snoring is so loud, I can't sleep...
An extension phone...
Who are you?!
The Messenger of the Cursed Masks...
Messenger of the Cursed Masks?!
Gimme that!
Hey!
The cursed masks thirst for blood.
Who will be the sacrifice?
What?!
You'd better hurry before it's too late.
That bastard!
It's locked!
Ran, Conan, wake Honami-san up and bring the key to this room!
Right!
It's locked...
The call a while ago was from an extension.
The person is in the mansion!
Dad!
Honami-san, the key!
R-Right!
O-Oh, no!
The masks of Jofre are gone!
What is the meaning of this?
What was that just now?!
It came from above!
Above? That's Suo-san's bedroom!
You can't go that way!
In order to get to her room, you have to take the stairs on the west side!
This door is locked too...
I'll wake Minaho and make her open the door!
Hey, what on earth is this racket about?
In the middle of the night...
The masks of Jofre are...?
What the heck is going on?!
Suo-san! Suo-san!
This door is locked too!
Break that glass!
Mouri-san, what are you going to do?
Did something happen to Suo-san?
Hey, how's Sensei?
Looks like she's hurt. She's bleeding badly!
The masks of Jofre are scattered all over the room!
The masks of Jofre?!
Is there any other way in?
There's another door over there!
That door's no good!
It's been sealed off for quite a while already!
I'll go in through there and check out the inside!
I guess there is no other choice.
Dad! Here you go!
We're counting on you.
The door is looked, all right...
Two locks!
Hurry and go check on Suo-san!
How is it?!
No good... We're too late...
Son of a...
Sensei!
Don't come in! Please stay here!
Her throat slashed with one stroke...
How cruel...
D-Don't tell me, Mouri-san...
Was this a murder?!
It can't be!
The door was locked, wasn't it?!
From the looks of the corpse, suicide is impossible.
But...
My curse has been fulfilled...
What was that?
This is a declaration that a murder will be committed,
from the Messenger of the Cursed Masks!
It's a curse!
The curse of the masks!
She was cursed to death by the masks!
Suo-san was cursed to death by the masks?
That's ridiculous!
But the crime scene is a locked room.
How did the murderer manage to kill Suo-san?!
Messenger of the Cursed Masks?
Why didn't you report it to the police when you first found this letter?
Well, the victim, Suo-san mentioned that she had been receiving
similar pranks for some time, and not to worry about it...
So, these are the cursed masks...
Yes.
We heard a groan and a loud crash.
It could've been the sound of the killer scattering the masks.
You said that this door was locked from inside?
Yes, that's why I broke the glass above the door, made Conan go inside
and verified Suo-san's death.
The door was definitely locked.
Both locks.
Two locks?
Yes.
Suo-san always locked both locks on her door.
First...
this lock...
and then this padlock.
Why did the victim have two locks on her door?
Well, according to her secretary, Inaba-san...
when Suo-san went to have the curse of the masks sealed in by a spiritualist,
she was told to do several things.
One of them was to put two locks on the bedroom door.
A spiritualist, eh...
Which means that the victim herself opened the door and let the victim in?
Well, it doesn't seem like it.
It seems that Suo-san was suffering from insomnia lately,
and was taking sleeping pills.
That's why there were no traces of the victim struggling?
If the victim locked the door as usual, took sleeping pills and went to bed,
how did the killer get into the room?
What is this door?
There is a bedroom next door too,
but that door seems to have been closed off for many years.
It seems to be nailed shut,
and there are no signs of it having been opened.
The railing above the door, can that bar be removed?
I checked on it, but it couldn't.
The space between the bars is about 5 or 6 centimeters,
so not even an arm can go through.
How about that window on the other side?
That window is fixed on.
There is nothing out of the ordinary about it.
If so, how and where did the killer go in and out of this room?
The only door that could be opened and shut was locked from the inside.
The door to the bedroom next door is nailed and sealed.
The space between the bars above it
is so narrow that not even an arm can get through.
The windows are both fixed on,
and there seems to be nothing wrong with them.
It's also impossible for the victim herself to have opened the door
and let the killer in, because she was under the effect of sleeping pills.
The room is a locked room, with no way in or out.
I wonder if Suo-san really took the sleeping pills herself?
If she didn't take them herself, who would make her...
Huh? Wait a sec...
I've got it, Inspector!
What? Really?!
The killer met Suo-san in the middle of the night,
made her drink something with a sleeping pill in it,
and put her to sleep...
Then, the killer carried Suo-san to her bed and killed her there!
I see!
And, how did the killer lock the door when leaving the room?
W-Well...
I haven't figured that out yet...
Yeah.
Only half of the locked room mystery can be explained.
The door is the only possible way that the killer could've entered,
but how did the killer lock the door from the outside?
If the lock were just a handle that could be turned,
then using a string or something could unlock it.
But the problem is the padlock.
In order to lock this, the door has to be closed first.
Then the door and the metal piece on the door frame have to be matched.
Only after doing that can the pole be stuck into the two metal fixtures.
I don't think it's possible to do all this from outside the door.
What kind of trick did the killer use?
No matter what trick the killer used,
why didn't the killer make it look like a suicide
after doing all this to kill her?
The killer called our room just before the murder was committed.
As if to let us know beforehand that murder was going to take place...
This knife seems to be the murder weapon.
This is what was decorated in the room of the masks.
It was poked into the bed pole, but there's something odd...
As you can see, its handle is also smeared with blood.
It sure is odd...
If the killer is holding the handle, there should be no blood there...
Speaking of blood,
there were masks among the masks that were scattered on the floor
with blood splattered on them too.
This was found on the bed.
It seems to have been splattered with blood at close range.
I think that the killer was wearing this mask when committing the murder.
If so, there may be some traces of the killer left...
Are there other masks that have been splattered with blood?
Yes, but it's quite strange.
All the other masks had blood only around the mouth.
Actually, there's a frightening story about the masks of Jofre,
saying they suck the very life out of their owners.
Don't be silly.
Could the killer have scattered the masks
to confuse investigations with occult stories?
That's most likely...
I wonder if that's the only reason why the killer scattered the masks?
No, I'm sure there's some other reason.
If I could only figure that out...
Inspector!
Oh, Kobayashi-kun, how was it?
We checked everywhere around the mansion,
but perhaps because of the snow that has accumulated,
there is no sign of the killer having gone in or out!
Which means that the killer is...
Someone inside the mansion!
Aside from Mouri-san and his family, those who were in this mansion are
photographer Masanori Katagiri-san,
pro baseball player Mamoru Matsudaira-san,
popular fortune-teller Haruka Nagara-san,
rock singer Toya Aikawa-san,
the victim's secretary, Kazuyo Inaba-san,
and the twin maids, Minaho and Honami Shimogasa-san.
That makes seven people.
We can narrow down the suspects a bit more.
What do you mean?
2ND FLOOR
W
E
MASK ROOM
You can't get to Suo-san's bedroom on the third floor
without using the stairs in the west wing.
At the time of the incident,
the doors leading to the east and west wings were both locked.
This has already been verified.
In other words,
you couldn't pass from the east wing to the west wing at that time.
Which means that the killer is someone
who was in the west wing of the mansion?
Who were in what rooms?
E
1ST FLOOR
W
First, on the first floor of the east wing were Aikawa-san and Honami-san.
In the west wing were Inaba-san and Minaho-san.
On the second floor of the east wing were the three of us.
2ND FLOOR
In the west wing were Katagiri-san, Matsudaira-san and Haruka-san.
I see... There are five suspects.
Katagiri-san, Matsudaira-san, Nagara-san,
Inaba-san and Minaho-san.
Yes, the messenger of the cursed masks
is one of those five!
Everyone,
I hate to have to do this, knowing how tired you all must be,
but I'd like to ask you a few questions.
The incident occurred in the early morning, at around 2:30.
Please tell me, in order, what you were doing at that time.
First, Honami-san?
I was fast asleep in my room until Ran came to wake me.
You got the key and headed for the second floor?
Where do you keep the key?
On the kitchen wall next to this dining room.
So anybody could take it and use it at will?
But the key was definitely there at that time...
Ran-kun?
Yes?
She's right.
Are there any spare keys?
They are old keys, so we can't make spares.
When we unlocked the door and went into the mask room,
we noticed that the masks of Jofre were gone.
That was when we heard the groan and loud noise from the third floor.
Yes, and while we were waking Minaho-san on the extension phone,
Aikawa-san came along.
I was sleeping in my room on the first floor too.
I realized that they had come to wake Honami,
but I didn't think it was a big deal.
Then it started getting noisy,
so I went to the second floor to check things out.
I was awakened by Honami on the extension phone,
took the key and went to the second floor.
I was also sleeping in my room,
but as it started to get noisy outside, I got up
and went out into the corridor just as Minaho-san had come up the stairs.
Same with me.
Me too.
Inaba-san, I heard that you did not appear at the time the corpse was found?
I had too much wine to drink last night and was totally passed out.
So, you didn't notice all the racket going on?
N-No...
Oh, Katagiri-san, have you ever met Suo-san before?
No, I met her for the first time yesterday.
Why?
Suo-san asked me to check on the accident that took your wife's life 20 years ago.
Suo-san did? Why?
Do you have any idea why?
No, I don't.
Suo-san asked the old man to check on the accident that took Katagiri-san's wife's life?
Why would she want to check on a traffic accident that happened 20 years ago?
Your mother got into a car accident twenty years ago too, didn't she, Aikawa-san?
Yeah, that's right.
Don't tell me...
Katagiri-san?!
Will you tell us about the accident that took your wife's life?
You'll find out sooner or later even if I didn't tell you.
Yes, my wife was the victim of the car accident that Aikawa-san's mother had caused.
N-No way...
Didn't you know about it, Aikawa-san?
No... because I was still only six years old.
But, how is that traffic accident connected to today's murder case?
The police think that the murderer is among us, isn't that right?
No way! Is that true, Inspector?
Oh, no, not really...
I recall that it had stopped snowing after 12:00.
I'll bet you couldn't find traces of the killer on the snow.
Is she right, Inspector?
It can't be helped.
Yes, it's true that there are no signs of the killer having entered or left the mansion.
Oh, no!
You mean the killer is among us?
Moreover, since the mask room was locked,
the killer has to be one of the five who were in the west wing!
In other words, Katagiri-san, Haruka-san, Inaba-san, Matsudaira-san or Minaho-san.
Huh? Wait a sec... That was a strange remark.
Why did he say that?
But it's difficult to single out the suspect.
I think there is a way.
Don't tell me that you're going to find the killer using your cards?
From the looks of the scene of the crime,
the killer probably was splattered by a lot of blood.
Although it is possible to avoid blood on the face by wearing the mask,
it would not be as easy to remove the blood from the hair and body.
I see! The killer is someone who had time to wipe the splattered blood off!
W-What? Are you saying that I'm the killer?
The only person who had time to wipe blood off
is you, because you weren't at the scene where the body was found.
You've got to be kidding!
Why would I have to kill Suo-san?!
Hey, you!
Cut out your nonsense!
Please calm down!
You fraud fortune-teller!
That's it! That's what happened!
I was completely deceived by the trap that the killer had set!
But now, this farce is over!
I've figured out the curse of the masks!
Huh? What's up, Conan-kun?
Uncle Mouri says he has a favor to ask you.
What? What is it?!
On the chest over there. Take a look at it!
Oh well...
There's nothing here.
Leave the rest to me, old man.
So this is the bedroom next door...
A bedroom that looks just like Suo-san's was right next door.
Correct. This room, with the same layout as the crime scene,
is what helped solve the mystery of the locked doors
as well as reveal the identity of the killer.
You mean Inaba-san is not the killer?
I've been saying that I'm not!
Have you solved the mystery of the locked doors?
Yes, I've figured everything out.
So who is the killer?
The killer who killed Beniko Suo-san in a locked room,
the Messenger of the Cursed Masks is...
...you!
The Messenger of the Cursed Masks is...
Toya Aikawa-san!
No way...
Unbelievable...
What on earth are you talking about, Mouri-san?
How could I, who was in the east wing of the mansion,
have gone to Sensei's bedroom?
Yes, it's true that you could not go to Suo-san's bedroom.
In order to prove that,
you called us on the extension phone just before you committed the murder.
But, if he couldn't go to her bedroom, how could he have committed the crime?
I've been suspicious from the time the body was found.
I kept wondering why the killer, despite committing the crime behind a locked door,
didn't make her death look like a suicide.
It was because he couldn't.
Aikawa-san killed Suo-san without entering her bedroom at all!
W-What?!
Without going into her bedroom?
That's impossible...
It's possible, with the help of the cursed masks.
D-Don't tell me that you really believe in things such as curses?
No. But the masks of Jofre are indeed the key to committing this locked-room murder.
I will replay that method here.
Detective Takagi!
Yes, sir!
I borrowed a knife that is similar to the murder weapon.
There is a rubber rope attached through the hole at the rear end of the handle.
Next, the mask.
The rubber rope is passed through both eyes of all the masks,
and the rubber rope attached to the knife is passed through the mouth hole of all the masks.
After all of us went to bed, Aikawa-san
went to the kitchen to get the key to enter the mask room.
He stole the masks of Jofre and a knife,
then locked the door and returned the key to the kitchen.
He brought the masks and knife into this room,
and carried on with the rubber rope trick.
He dropped the masks and the knife
into Suo-san's bedroom through the space between the railing.
The size of the space is 5×5 centimeters.
A thin mask would easily slide through.
Can you really solve the mystery of the locked door doing something like this?
Well, please watch.
This is the last mask!
After placing all the masks inside the room,
he pulled the rubber rope towards himself.
Now, everyone, since one mask is 15 millimeters thick,
if 200 are piled up one on top of another,
the pile would be 3 meters.
The position of the neck of the victim asleep in bed
was about 3.5 meters from the railing.
So then what?
This is...!
From the edge of the knife to the victim's throat is only 10 centimeters.
All he had left to do now was to push the masks out using a ruler or something.
By using the stairs that only the people in the east wing of the mansion can climb,
Aikawa-san killed Suo-san without setting foot into her room at all.
I see! One of the masks was badly covered blood
because it was the mask on the very top, right?
The reason why several masks had blood by the mouth,
was because Suo-san's splattered on them.
Finally, he severs the rubber rope that was passed through the eyes
of the masks and the handle of the knife.
This is...!
There's your locked-room murder.
It's all rubbish! Just where do you have the proof that I used that trick?!
Aikawa-san, you're acting in bad faith.
Haven't you realized that you've already confessed that you are the killer?
What? What do you mean?!
While you were being questioned a while ago, you said,
I noticed that the kids came to wake Honami up.
Yeah, because I was in my room on the first floor then!
When you said, those kids, who besides Ran were you referring to?
Who else but the kid named Conan?
Huh, how strange.
I didn't say a word back then.
How did you know I was with her?
T-That's because...
Right, I opened the door a bit and looked out.
That's why I know that you were with her!
Really?
Really!
Then it's even stranger.
Because I didn't go with Ran-neechan.
I went to check if the doors around the house were locked!
O-Oh, no...
Is that true?!
Yes.
I went to Honami-san's room alone.
I did tell Ran and Conan to go get Honami-san back then.
You thought the two of them went to Honami-san's room together,
because when you heard me say that, you were on the third floor, right?
Just because of something like that, you figured...!
Toya! After all Sensei did for you, how could you?!
Shut up! After all she did for me?
You've got to be kidding!
That lady blamed the hit-and-run accident that she caused on my mother,
and made it look as if she committed suicide!
Is that true?
It's true! But I only found out about it two months ago.
I was cleaning out my mother's belongings,
when a letter fell out from behind the cover of her diary
and the truth about the incident was written in it!
That's a lie! It's all rubbish!
No, it's not! Mother had an alibi!
The accident occurred on the night of October 31!
October 31...
Toya-san's birthday...
Right! Mother was with me all day!
Which means that the one who hit my wife and ran...
...was Suo?
Moreover, she didn't even know that your wife
was the victim of a traffic accident, Katagiri-san!
I guess she asked me to investigate on the case
after she heard Katagiri-san talk about it at dinner.
Sensei is a fine person who has been hosting charity shows for 15 years!
What a laugh!
That lady embezzled the money that was raised to fatten her own pocket!
That's a lie! Sensei would never do any such thing!
You also got part of the cash, didn't you!
Don't talk as if you know nothing!
I wanted to keep Katagiri-san from participating in this corrupt charity
no matter what...
That lady...
Beniko Suo was a devil wearing the mask of someone practicing good will!
To think that I felt grateful for her having saved me, all these years...
I... I...!
It could be that Aikawa-san was possessed by the curse of the masks.
Curses are only superstitions!
A curse! This is a curse!
That's no curse, old man. You're just a klutz.
That sounded like...
A gunshot?!
What's this?
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Rain shower
The next episode airs April 10!
Next week is the movie, The Last Wizard of the Century!
Don't miss it!