Just as water flows without shape,
and wind blows without form,
no case can stop you from deducing the truth!
Be it the world of TV, movies, and even books,
famous detectives are everywhere!
Seeing through the one and only truth,
he looks like a child, but his mind is of an adult.
His name: The real,
Detective Conan.
true
heart
for
mys
tery
eyes
take
your
feel
so
all
in
se
cret
life
Ouch, I bit my tongue.
Be careful, dad!
They said it is a very famous lodge secluded from any population.
Of course it's going to be hard to get to!
There, I see it now.
Hey dad, this road is actually paved.
Are you sure that we weren't suppose to come from this road to begin with?
Oh look, there's an archery range too!
You're trying to change the topic.
m 0 0 l 0 -15 l 36 -15 l 36 0
Archery Ground
up here
I figured.
Watch out!
I'm so sorry!
I missed completely!
Is anyone hurt?
You!
Oh, you...
You're the famous detective, Mouri Kogorou-sensei, aren't you?
Yeah, umm, haha...
You know me very well.
Are you going to that lodge as well?
You too?
Yes.
That means, the two famous detectives will finally get to meet each other.
THE MURDERED FAMOUS DETECTIVE
(PART ONE)
The Murdered Famous Detective (Part l)
What is this, isn't anybody on duty?
Excuse me...
What is that sound?
Those were gunshots.
The forest around here are hunting grounds.
This is Mouri-san, I presume?
m 0 0 l 0 -15 l 36 -15 l 36 0
Sorry to have kept you waiting,
I'm the only one working today.
Dad,
We drove right through the forest today,
don't you think it was dangerous?
Really?
Although the hunting areas are marked clearly with signs and fenced around,
there's always the danger of misfires.
Hehehe.
We have already had the blessing of such an experience,
only it was by an arrow.
Welcome back.
Here is your key.
What's up with him?
You should have your dinner outside, at our Special Garden Restaurant.
Dinner is outside?
Please go take a look.
Wow, this is beautiful.
Wow, Ran-neechan, this is indeed awesome.
There's a stream down right below!
Be careful, Conan-kun.
Huh, rain?
Hey hey, if it starts raining like this,
we won't be able to eat in their Special Garden Restaurant.
Y-You are...
Correct,
Jack The Ripper, the 5th generation.
Who's there?!
You are...
Right,
Urban Hunter.
Sabao Banai at your service!
Are you watching this crap again?
C'mon, it was finally getting to the best part.
Heh, he's no real detective,
Real cases don't get solved so easily, week after week like that!
My apologies,
for being so lucky.
Urban Hunter.
Sabao Banai at your service!
He's real!
He plays Sabao Banai,
Sunaoka Kazuyoshi, an actor.
I'm his manager, Tanigawa.
Apologies for the earlier incident.
You're the real famous detective, Mouri Kogorou-san, right?
It's an honour to meet you.
To tell you the truth, l am a big fan of Sunaoka-san as well.
Can I have your autograph later?
He's all talk.
Well, well, thank you...
Just in case,
here's my card if you would like.
m 0 0 l 0 -15 l 36 -15 l 36 0
It is such an honor to share the same table with Detective Mouri.
The honour is all mine, to be able to meet such a famous actor.
Are you doing your shootings over here?
Shhh!
The truth is, I came here to protect you, as part of a top-secret mission!
We've come here for the show-making meeting and to get along and relax!
m 0 0 l 0 -15 l 36 -15 l 36 0
But the fact that the famed star Sunaoka-san would come along as well, was something only we knew!
Your team work is pretty good indeed!
Today, Sunaoka-san and I went out to enjoy some hunting this afternoon.
Despite waiting all the way till the rain stopped, we couldn't catch anything.
m 0 0 l 0 -15 l 36 -15 l 36 0
Jeez, I can't believe how anyone can shoot live animals.
That's why I chose archery instead,
Ah!
However, I almost got a person hit...
Oh, yeah.
We were about to become the prey.
What was that about...?
By the way, what were you doing?
You don't look like you've gotten rid of your stress.
m 0 0 l 0 -15 l 36 -15 l 36 0
That is because I stayed in my room thinking about the plot for our next show.
That person looks scary, doesn't he?
And...
Did you think up any good ideas, sensei?
Sunaoka-chan...
Lately, the audience are able to solve the cases before I do.
This just won't do!
Sunaoka-san,
Do you ever consider how hard writers work to accommodate you?
Now, now...
We're here to work something out to make the show more interesting!
Let's discuss something helpful.
That's easy for you to say.
All you're concerned about is the money.
I know all about it...
how you've been pocketing some of the production budget for yourself.
What are you talking about?
That's just a foolish rumor!
Come now, everyone...
Huh...
They sure don't get along well.
Sunaoka-chan,
You drank too much.
Let's go back to your room.
What?
I want to talk a bit more with Mouri-san.
And you, always acting like you're the boss...
but that won't be for long.
A major production company has offered me a huge contract fee to sign up with them.
What are you talking about?
Didn't we discuss about that already?
In any case,
Please go to your room and get some sleep.
If I, the biggest star in your production, were to quit,
you'd probably be unable to even stay in the business.
Well, great detective, perhaps some other time.
If you got something against me,
I'll quit anytime you want, Tahara-sensei.
If Sunaoka-chan was to quit,
the entire series will go down the drain.
President Tanigawa, please do something.
I guess TV and reality are different after all.
Yeah, they are.
Sorry about that.
Sunaoka-chan is actually very hard working.
He's very serious about making the show a success!
He just got a bit drunk tonight.
Please forgive him.
It's okay, keep up your good work.
Thank you.
Now shall we continue our drinks?
Why is it empty?
Oh, let me go get some more.
Thanks.
Here, your keys.
Aah, I think said too much.
I'm sorry.
Good night.
Uh... President...
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Thanks a lot.
It was worth the wait.
These are for you two.
Sorry for the trouble.
Thank you.
Not at all.
Here, Mouri-san.
Thank you.
His mood has suddenly got better after Sunaoka-san left.
You should drink too, Tahara-san.
Okay.
Oh, excuse me for a second.
What's up?
I just had an idea of an interesting trick!
I better write it down before I forget.
Scriptwriter is a really busy job.
Here, Mouri-san.
Cheers.
Nagatsuka-san,
There is a phone for you from Tokyo, at the front desk.
It's 8 o'clock, who could it be at this hour...
Excuse me for a while.
What a drag... I ended up all alone.
Why don't you guys join me with juice.
Dad,
I think you've had enough!
Hello, this is Mouri Kogorou speaking.
Well, how about we have some detective talk in my room?
Oh, Sunaoka-san.
Huh, hold on for a second.
What's that?
Uh, hello? Sunaoka-san?
Jeez.
What's wrong, dad?
It's Sunaoka-san.
He asked me if I wanted to go to his room,
then cut off all of a sudden.
A gunshot..?!
It sounded like it came from across the valley!
What could anyone be shooting at a time like this?
It's dangerous, so you guys go back inside.
Oh, Tanigawa-san.
What happened?
Did you just hear that gunshot?
So it really was a gunshot!
Sunaoka-chan would be already in bed.
Sunaoka-chan's room's window,
There's a hole in it.
Looks like it was by a bullet!
What did you say?
Uncle, the key!
Oh yeah, you're right!
Owner, please bring the master key and come to Sunaoka-san's room.
Sure...
Did something happen?
Sunaoka-chan, wake up!
Is there no response?
No.
He never gets up when he falls asleep while drunk.
Mouri-san,
I brought the key.
Sunaoka-san, I'm opening the door.
What just happened?
Why would anyone kill Sunaoka-chan?
Mouri-san, long time no see.
Hello, Inspector Yokomizo.
Take a look.
Listen everyone,
Please wait at the lobby downstairs.
Later on, we'll ask you for the facts.
That person...
He sure says some harsh things when he's drunk,
but it's nothing anyone would want to kill him for!
Oh...What do l do now?
I'm going to have to answer for all this.
Just when they decided to extend the series...
Everyone,
I understand how you must feel...
but the forensics need to start working now.
By the looks of it, the only wound is the bullet shot on his forehead.
Yes, that's what killed him.
From the fact that there is no burn mark,
and no gunpowder on the wound either,
it appears that the shot came from some distance away.
This hole here is,
about the same height as of Sunaoka-san's forehead when he's standing.
Moreover, Sunaoka-san was,
most likely shot when he was standing at the window looking outside.
That means, the culprit must have fired the gun from...
During the time of the crime,
we heard a shot being fired from across the valley.
Let's go have a look.
Huh? What's this?
Among the broken glass shards,
there are some plant fibers as well?
Conan!
Always fooling around the scene!
Come here!
He's gotten quicker at getting away.
To get to the other side of the valley,
this bridge is the only way that's close to the lodge.
Please come only five at a time.
This is quite some distance away from the lodge.
Yeah.
Now, if we keep going for about ten minutes, we should be across from the lodge.
We're here.
Good grief!
That took us 30 minutes.
But at a place like this,
The problem is the culprit's get-away route.
Who... Who's there?
Sorry.
R..R..Ran!
What are you doing at a place like this?!
It's because,
Conan-kun dashed out of the lodge all of a sudden.
I followed him since I got worried.
Then why were you hiding at a place like that!
Well,
Conan-kun was...
Huh,
Conan-kun?
Conan!
Yes...
Look, I found the gun.
Conan-kun...
Arghhhh!
Dad?
This-
This little brat...
Here!
Get him tied up somewhere!
You shouldn't do that, Conan-kun.
Sorry.
There's the bullet, too.
There seems to be no doubt that this was the weapon.
The culprit must have aimed at Sunaoka-san who was standing at that window over there.
Go give the rifle and the bullet to the investigators immediately.
Sir!
What's this?
The bottom side of the rifle isn't wet.
Take a picture of this.
Mouri-san,
When did the rain stop around here?
Let me see...
I think it was over before it got dark outside.
But then,
why isn't the bottom side of the rifle wet?
Never mind that, Inspector Yokomizo.
After shooting Sunaoka-san, the culprit must have escaped through this road.
Better set up a roadblock before it is too late.
Oh, you're right!
Eh? That's strange...
Hey, when we were coming up here,
we saw no footprints on the mountain road, right?
Yeah right.
It was slippery from the rain.
The mountain road was scary,
so I kept my head down and followed Conan's footprints.
There's no mistake.
Then maybe the killer took this road.
There are no footprints on this side as well.
What!
What is really going on?
Mouri-san!
Take a look at this.
There is a rope tied to this tree.
The culprit probably used this rope to go down,
and escape by that stream.
The current is rapid,
So they probably came from the upstream with a rubber boat.
Tying the boat to the shore and climbing up this rocky cliff,
the culprit must've waited for Sunaoka-san to show up on the window on the opposite side.
And then...
Sunaoka-san was sniped.
Then the culprit used the rope to slide down to the stream,
and went downstream using a boat.
Oh no!
Set up roadblocks in the downstream area as well!
No.
From the garden restaurant,
it is easy to notice someone
climbing up and down this cliff.
And who would snipe from a rocky cliff with no place to hide?
Besides, it's impossible
not to be seen by us, who came running in
right after the shot was heard.
That means...
Conan-kun.
Just as I thought,
The rope is soaked.
Conan-kun!
Oh, you're not supposed to run around.
Okay.
You two, we're going back.
Don't blame me if you run around too much and get lost.
Oh, wait up.
So when the gunshot was heard,
What was everyone doing and where?
I had received a call from Tokyo,
and was busy on the phone at the front desk.
So I didn't even hear the sound.
We have already confirmed this from the caller.
And for the phone, did you use
the one at the front desk?
Yes, but not the public one, the lodge's private one.
It has a cord.
Yes.
We receive outside calls with that phone.
And my cellphone's battery was already dead.
I see.
And Tahara-san?
I was writing down ideas for the script at the garden restaurant.
I was so concentrated, I didn't react to the gunshot at first.
By the time I looked up with Mouri-san and the others, there was nobody to be seen.
The time we had heard the gunfire was
a little while after Nagatsuka-san received the phone call,
which was around 8:00pm.
When Mouri-san came to get the master key at the front desk,
I was just getting off the phone.
I'm sure you can track the time of the call if you check the phone records, right?
Haha, everyone here,
is a mystery specialist!
So the questioning goes so quick and easy.
And Tanigawa-san, you were?
I...
After taking Sunaoka to his room,
I went to my room to take a shower.
When I got out of the shower,
I heard a sound,
but I didn't realize it was something dangerous.
Then it got noisy outside,
so l went to check things out at the balcony.
I never thought Sunaoka-chan would be shot.
I'm sorry.
Akashi-san, where were you?
I was washing the dishes in the kitchen.
The ventilation fan was on,
and maybe because I am used to the gunfire of the workplace, I didn't notice it at all.
True.
It would be physically impossible for anyone in the lodge to fire the gun.
The only guests in this lodge, besides us, are those three.
Although it was kept secret that Sunaoka-san was here,
it wouldn't be too difficult to find that out.
However,
if the culprit was to come from the outside to kill Sunaoka-san,
they could've rather killed him at the hunting grounds and made it look like a misfire.
Then there are numerous ways with better getaway routes.
There's no point in using a boat and a rope to escape,
from a place that can be easily
spotted from the garden restaurant.
That was just a fake evidence for sure.
There can be only one reason to go through all that trouble.
The culprit wanted an alibi.
Which means,
the culprit has to be someone from this lodge.
That's right.
One,
among these three,
must be the culprit!
There is always an exit in every maze!
This impossible crime...
in behalf of the killed famous detective,
I vow to solve it!
heart
heart
wait
ing
for
a
I
chance
wait
ing
for
a
chance
NEXT EPISODE
I've not pocketed anything
from the budget for myself!
Well, the investigation will clear that up.
Do you mean the culprit might be one of us?
You're the most suspicious one, Tanigawa-san!
What!
It means what I had found
mixed with the glass shards,
must have come from...
Just as I thought.
THE MURDERED FAMOUS DETECTIVE
(PART TWO)
Next Conan:
The Murdered Famous Detective (Part 2)
Next Conan's Hint:
Bullet.
Next episode will be the revelation!
Leave it to the real detective.
It's not uncle, by the way.