Just as flowing water has no form,
and the breeze is invisible,
deductions take all shapes and styles in each and every case to be solved.
The case where a detective is the victim
Shin-ichi solves the case sharply
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult, no case is left unsolved
when Detective Conan comes to the scene.
We come to this villa on an overnight trip
& meet Kazuyoshi Sunaoka
who plays a famous detective
in the popular TV series "Urban Hunter"
& other staff members working on the series
But
behind the scenes of the show
relations between these people are very hostile...
and then with a single gunshot
Mr. Sunaoka is killed by an unknown assailant!!
after firing from the rocks across the valley
the killer climbed down the rope
& used a boat to escape,
that's what was believed.
It takes 30 minutes to get to the other side
so no one from the villa could have possibly committed the crime!
But the killer is one of those 3
I know I'm right!
MURDER OF THE FAMOUS DETECTIVE
(PART 2)
Yes, Mr. Sunaoka's killer
I believe, went down to the stream
& escaped.
I've just issued an all points bulletion
& we are searching
but I must ask all of you once more
to go over the details of what happened
In the morning,
I was in Mr. Tahara's room going over the scenarios...
Then in the afternoon, I went to the hunting in the woods with Mr. Sunaoka,
Atsuaki Nagatsuka (40)
Producer
we got back at about 6:30
then joined everyone for dinner right after that
After talking with Mr. Nagatsuka,
Toshiaki Tahara (35)
Scenario Writer
I stayed in my room until the evening writing...
Mr. Sunaoka called me to his room in the morning
Noe Tanigawa (27)
Sunaoka's manager
& he told me about switching agencies...
we had a little argument...
I see... an argument you say?
Y-Yes...
I was on the archery grounds in the afternoon.
I ran into Mr. Mouri & his family there...
I got back here after 6
then joined the others
Uh huh...
Me? I was busy working, of course...
I'm alone today so I was very busy,
I don't remember all the details though...
Yusaku Akashi (60)
Sansou's Innkeeper
Hmm...
Come on, it's your bedtime Conan
Oh, but I want to listen a little more...
No! Dad'll scold you again
I know, but it's too early for bed...
I'm sure dad'll be at it all night
You'd better not get in his way so just go to sleep
Oh alright...
I'll go to sleep so you can go now
No way, I'm staying right here until you're asleep
Alright then, now for after dinner
It was about 7:50 when Mr. Sunaoka left the restaurant with Ms. Tanigawa
Right after that, Mr. Tahara went to the kitchen to get more drinks
At 8 sharp, Mr. Nagatsuka got a call from the station and went to the front desk...
and right after that,
I got a call from Mr. Sunaoka
he abruptly ended the conversation & that's when we heard the gunshot
Ms. Tanigawa, who had been taking a shower came out to the veranda
and discovered the bullet hole in Mr. Sunaoka's window
We went to get Mr. Akashi at the front desk &
got the master key to unlock the door
At 8:05, we discovered the body
Which means Mr. Sunaoka was killed between 8 & 8:05...
Conan?
Ha... he fell asleep unusually fast tonight.
Good night...
Phew, I thought she'd never leave
I'd like to go over in more detail what you were all doing before & after the murder
Why bother, you know it was somebody from the outside, don't you...
Well, we still must clarify what the victim was doing
Mr. Sunaoka was alone in his room locked from the inside.
How would we know what he was doing.
Yes well... that is true...
We don't even have time to mourn him!
Give us a break!
Excuse me for saying this
but it seems you 3 had some bad feelings toward Mr. Sunaoka
What was that?!
Are you implying 1 of us killed him?
Not really, this is all part of the investigation.
Mr. Sunaoka seemed very picky about the scenarios, isn't that right, Mr. Tahara?
Lately, the viewers solve the crime before I do. That won't do
Mr. Sunaoka, put yourself in my shoes,
I have to write scenarios to fit your personality
I was only being honest
And as for you,
Mr. Nagatsuka the producer...
I know all about it. I hear you're pocketing some of the production fees
How dare you! That's a lie!
It-It really was a lie!
Well, an investigation will clear that up
Uh, why, of course!
Now for Ms. Tanigawa,
Mr. Sunaoka talked about switching agencies, didn't he?
I'm the biggest star your agency's got,
if you lose me, you probably won't be able to stay in the business, huh.
Well Mr. Detective, I'll catch you later
On top of that, you're the only one without a witness to verify your alibi
How can you say that!
You all saw me in my room from the garden restaurant, didn't you?
Yes, but it was after the gunshot...
another thing, the rest of you also had an opportunity to contact the shooter
This is crazy!
But then you can never tell about Ms. Tanigawa!
What do you mean by that!?
Didn't lover boy dump you?
Mr. Nagatsuka!
Don't be ridiculous!
Now now everybody just calm down
Detective Yokomizo!
The findings regarding the rifle are back!
Oh!
The rifle was one of those kept in the hunting management office,
the rope also came from there!
The markings on the bullet taken from the victim & the ones from the rifle
were a perfect match...!
Oh! And what is this?
A hole was opened in bottom of the bullet
& the tip's been sharpened...
What was the purpose for this...?
...It certainly doesn't make sense does it
There's spiral grooves inside the hole...
It's like a screw
C-Conan...
Why you, you're supposed to be sleeping!
I got up because I was so thirsty...
Alright already, go get some water & then go back to bed!
Okay...
Oh, I almost forgot!
Hey, Uncle Kogoro
Yeah, what is it now?
What did Mr. Sunaoka say on the telephone?
that is none of your business
Aw but those were the last words of
Mr. Sunaoka the big star weren't they?
Oh, so you're one of those low brows?
He asked me to come to his room to talk detective talk!
But then he said "Hey what's that" & seemed surprised & hung up
I knew it...
Since the rifle markings match,
it means what I found mixed in with the pieces of glass...
Where'd it come from...
Which one?
It's so heavy
I knew it! Just as I thought...
Yes! Now I know how the trick was worked!
What's this mark on the floor...
I concentrated so hard on the pieces of glass I didn't notice it before...
Could it be...
I knew it... there's one here too! which means...
The real weapon should be behind this door...
And! The person staying in that room is also the killer!
The rifle markings matched, you don't need us here anymore, do you
Ah...
Excuse me officer
What is it kid?
I have something to tell you
Eh? Room 304?
Sh, Detective Yokomizo said to do a secret search,
here's the master key
Hurry, OK?
Oh, sure...
Then we'll be going back to our rooms now
Oh alright!
Shall we continue this at 8 tomorrow morning then?
That's so early!
But I guess it's OK
Thank you for your time
Mr. Mouri, why don't you get some rest
We're going to go join the search downstream, excuse us.
Good luck...
Wait just a minute!
You three over there... and
Detective Yokomizo, hear me out first
Ah! That's the pose!
So it's hit you, didn't it!
Yes, it finally hit me
Yes, but it doesn't seem like a job for "Sleeping Kogoro" this time...
You're wrong about that. After all,
The killer is one of those three!
What!
What was that!
I understand, Mr. Mouri!
Alright you 3, why don't you have a seat on the sofa once more?
At the first, it appeared to be an obvious case
where the murderer was someone from the outside...
But why did the murderer leave the rifle behind?
The murderer could have tossed it into the stream or hidden it in the woods
Another thing, both the rifle & the rope
the murderer used to get down to the stream,
why were these things wet by the rain?
Yes! It rained in the evening!
The rifle was left about 8pm, it shouldn't be wet, it is strange.
The reason for that is, both the rifle & rope were planted there before the rain
In fact, it was dry under some parts of the rifle
That proves the rifle was left there before it rained in the evening
...which means the rifle was what actually the murder weapon
But the markings matched, didn't they?
Before I explain that,
why do you suppose the murderer went through all that trouble?
Making it appear like he was shot from across valley...
Even if the murderer was an outsider,
all the murderer had to do was prove he or she never came close to the villa
There was absolutely no reason to plant fake evidence
The murderer is someone who needed an alibi,
that's why the scene had to be across the valley...
That's right...
the murderer is one of you three!
Ho, hold on just a minute.
We're not magicians, how did we shoot him without using the rifle!
That's right! You haven't been making any sense at all!
And now I'll go into the details of how Mr. Sunaoka was actually killed
This is ridiculous...
First, the killer takes the master key from the front desk when no one is around
and sneaks into
Mr. Sunaoka's room on the 3rd floor
then props up the mattress against the window.
Mattress?
What's a mattress got to do with anything?
The killer then went to the hunting ground management office & stole the rifle & rope
then the killer went to the rocky area across the valley &
shot at the window in Mr. Sunaoka's room
The killer then left the rifle there & tied the rope to the tree
and made it look like the escape was by water
The killer then snuck back into Mr.Sunaoka's room &
removed the bullet shot into the mattress.
After replacing the mattress,
the killer removed all the broken pieces of glass &
hid the hole by drawing the curtains
Detective Yokomizo!
The bullet removed from the body had some work done to it, didn't it?
Yes!
The killer went back to his or her own room
& dug a hole into the end of the bullet which the killer took out of the mattress
Tools were used to drill the screw threads
& the tip was sharpened with a file
Then something the killer had prepared earlier, was screwed into the bullet
And now we have a new deadly weapon with the same markings as the rifle!
After the preparations had been made,
the killer went to the garden restaurant for dinner
when Mr. Sunaoka went back to his room
the killer made up some sort of excuse & got into his room
And pierced Mr. Sunaoka
in the forehead, from the front!
Pierced!?
Are you saying the weapon was a knife or arrow?
An arrow!?
After killing Mr. Sunaoka,
the killer moved the body to make it look like the shot came from the window
& opened the curtains
then rescattered the pieces of glass around
& removed the tip of the arrow from Mr. Sunaoka's forehead
Then left without a snag
Why Mr. Mouri, you should become a scenario writer!
That was a brilliant story!
No, I don't have the talent to become a writer.
All the evidence the killer left behind showed me the truth
I'm just the messenger
For instance, along with the pieces of glass from the window,
I found some coconut fibers
They were from the mattress.
It probably fell out when the bullet was dug out
The killer didn't notice them & gathered them up along with the glass
I see!
After that, the killer hid the real weapon
& then went to another location so as not to under suspicion
& called me on my cellular...
The killer probably saw the number
on the business card
I handed out during dinner
Mr. Mouri, you yourself said the caller was Mr. Sunaoka...
On the phone, Mr. Sunaoka said
"How about it? Why don't you come up to my room & we'll talk detective"
then "Huh?
Hold on a second, what is that?"
Well people, does that sound familiar to anyone?
Yes, that's it. That's the dialogue he said on tonight's show!!
Are you sure?
Yes, I'm positive!
I taped it, why don't you see for yourself?
Yes, I'll do that
It was the opening scene but please fast forward it
That's it!
How about it? Why don't you come up to my room & we'll talk detective?
Huh? Hold on for a second, what is that?
I see... the killer recorded this line previously
& played it back to
Mr. Mouri on the phone, right?
Then Mr. Sunaoka was already dead when the call was made?
Yes... he was already killed...
The only one without an alibi for that time is...
Detective Yokomizo!
As you ordered, I searched room 304
& look at what I found!
That's a bowgun!
And I found an arrow with blood on it!
So this is the murder weapon!?
And there are screw threads on the arrow head
Mr. Mouri! It's exactly like you said!
I'm sure the killer intended to take them home & destroy them
O-Officer, did you just say room #304?
You mean...
That's right... the killer was staying in room 304
Toshiaki Tahara, it's you!
I don't believe it!
Mr. Tahara, a little past 7:50,
you left the room saying you were going to get more drinks
but you went to Mr.Sunaoka's room
& killed him
About 8, you came back looking as if nothing happened
You deliberately sat far away
so you call me without being seen
then you threw something, possibly a firecracker into the valley
to make us think a shot was fired
Some detective you are!
Just because the murder weapon was in my room
doesn't mean it belongs to me.
I'm being set up by the real killer!
Unfortunately for you, I have more proof
What was that?!
It's your shoes
You see the scratches on the floor?
Excuse me, would you mind taking your shoes off?
There's pieces of glass stuck in the sole!
Could they be from the pieces scattered around the body?
I'm sure no one else besides us went near the body
So how could be these pieces of glass get under your shoes...
You were so preoccupied with what you had to do,
you didn't realize you had stepped on them. You were too caught up
You win...
Mr. Tahara!
Why did you do such a thing!?
Humph! He was also criticizing & making fun of the scenarios I wrote,
if the ratings were bad, he blamed me...
I couldn't forgive that Sunaoka for that!
I wanted to show everyone, the producers, the actors & the police
yes, & I even the most famous detective that I could commit the perfect crime...
And the victim, of course Bannai
Kujirao Sunaoka was the only choice...
How about the lead in our next series!
The title is "Kogoro the Famous Detective"!
Will you do it?
The ratings are guaranteed to be high, you'll be a famous star in no time!
That does sound good
Let's get going!!
What!?
Mr. Mouri!
Ran, we'll want you too...!
I want a chance to be a star!
What was that sound?
She's been shot in the forehead!
You saw a bluish-white flash of light?
Bluish-white light
what could it have been...?
I've got it!
A MYSTERIOUS GUNSHOT
ECHOES IN THE DARKNESS
Next Conan's Hint
Black tea
TODO