Just as flowing water has no
form, and the breeze is invisible
Deductions take all shapes and styles
in each and every case to be solved.
Today, we must all
change out way of thinking
What should be on, isn't...
He sees through to the one & only truth
A child in appearance
With the I.Q. of an adult
No case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan
A MYSTERIOUS GUNSHOT
ECHO IN THE DARKNESS
So many handsome actors star in
those Monday night mystery shows...
I'm so excited, I wonder what
kind of stories we'll get to hear
Good grief!
Just because our client's the president
of some company produces movies,
This kid insisted on tagging along...
I think I already told you but my job
is to protect the client's mother!
I know that
But she was injured when she was
attacked 3 days ago, wasn't she?
Is being the president of a finance
company such a dangerous job?
Well, I've heard she can be pretty vicious
So that means she's got
a lot of enemies, right?
I guess you could say that
Yes?
My name is Kogoro Mouri,
I'm a private investigator...
I have a 7'o clock appointment
to see Ms. Etsuko Furukawa
Yes, you're expected. I'll unlock
the gate now. Please come in...
This way...
Conan? We're going
Oh, OK!!
Please have some coffee...
I'm terribly sorry about this,
Ms. Furukawa is usually punctual...
Azusa Machida
Furukawa Family Maid
No, don't be bothered
Excuse me...
Yes?
If it's alright with you, while we're waiting,
Could we watch the television?
I'm sorry. That TV's been on
the brink since this morning
Nothing shows on the screen
I see...
Idiot, you have some
nerve asking like that
But...
Excuse me Miss,
But the window on the far left on the
2nd floor facing the street was open...
That room belongs to
the owner of this place
Mrs. Katsue Furukawa, president
of the Furukawa Finance
Pardon me for asking, but who are you?
Kohji Furukawa...
I'm her son
That window is always open at
this time of day to air out the room.
Kohji Furukawa
Eldest Son Unemployed
Isn't that right, Azusa?
Y, yes...
You're that detective my
sister hired, aren't you?
I pity you
She's just going to use you...
Use me? You say...
I'm sure that's her now
Yes?
It's me, Etsuko.
Etsuko Furukawa
Eldest Daughter TV Producer
I'm late. Hurry & let me in
Yes, right away
Mr. Mouri, I'm terribly sorry
I had some last minute
businesss to take care of
Kohji...
Hi sis, long time no see...
What are you doing here?
Didn't mom ban you from this
house the last time you were here?
Aw shut up, this is MY house.
And by the way, what's with that watch?
Eh?!
You said digitals were cheap stuff and
you wouldn't be caught dead with one
Oh I get it!
You had to pawn that Swiss watch you
were so proud of to pay for your debts.
That's none of your business!
By the way, Kohji
I'll bet you're here to get mom to
pay off your debts again, aren't you?
Shut up!
And what about you sis, hiring a
private detective to butter mom up?
It's so obvious
How dare you!
Things seem pretty messy around here
Sort of...
Miss Etsuko's company is on
the verge of bankruptcy
And it seems Mr. Kohji has
a lot of gambling debts
And some mobsters after him
But their mother Katsue
has a lot of money...
Unfortunately, Mrs. Furukawa
never lends money to those
She feels cannot repay her,
regardless if they're her children.
In the past though, she did lend Kohji
A lot of money but it got out of and
So she finally banned
him from the house...
Azusa, what is wrong with you!
Yes, what is it?
What are you telling them?!
I'm going to get mother!
She's alseep in her room, isn't she?
Yes, she is...
Hey Azusa!
Instead of doing everything
my sister tells you,
You should go out with me sometime!
If I ask, I can get mom to forget
about all the money you owe her!
Kohji! If you have nothing better to do,
Why don't you go out and
buy something to give mom?
Let's go Azusa
Y, yes!
Rats!
Uh, about Azusa's debts...
Huh? Oh, I heard she made a
stain on mom's Persian rug today
Just for that, she's not
getting a bonus this year
And since that wasn't enough, mom
made her write an IOU for the rest
It's happened several times before,
One of these days, I'm sure
she's going to blow up
Oh well, I guess I'll go and buy mom
a little something...
I just hate taking sis's advice though...
What's with this family...
Mother
Mother, wake up
That's odd...
She usually gets up right away
It's locked...
Maybe she took some of the sleeping
pills the doctor prescribed and fell asleep
But it's still so early...
And it certainly is hot...
It is?
I'm sweating...
Oh my goodness...
What was that sound?
Mother! Mother!
Mother, open this door!
Is something wrong?
Mr. Mouri, something's wrong
It came from mom's room...
Sis!
Didn't you hear a weird
sound from mom's room?
I heard a gunshot in mom's room!!
It's locked. Do you have a spare key?
The key was a special order
item and mom has the only one
There's no other choice, we've
got to break the door down
Right!
One, two!
It's so dark you can't see a thing...
Where's the light swtich?
On the wall to your left...
M, mother?!
Mother!?
You mustn't go in there!
B, but!
This is a murder! We have to
preserve the crime scene!
Mother...
Ran, call the police
Alright
She's been shot in the forehead
She died instantaneously...
There're no signs of a struggle...
Huh?
Footprints lead to the window...
The killer must've used that ladder...
But the position of the body...
Why you! How many times do
I have to repeat myself?!
I'm sorry!
Huh?
Come on and get out of here!
Ouch, ouch...
The victim is Katsue Furukawa,
64 years old, president
of a finance company
The footprints around the body match
those we found around the ladder outside
I see
The victim was attacked just
3 days earlier.
Maybe it was the same assailant...
Oh officer
Eh?
If someone you didn't know
came in through the window,
Wouldn't you run for the door?
You little brat!
I told you to stay out of this!!
No, Conan's right
Huh?
Since the body was near the window
We can assume the victim noticed the
intruder and approached the window...
Which means the intruder was
probably someone the victim knew!
Let's question everyone who was
in the house when the murder occurred
Yes sir
About when you discovered the body,
Ms. Etsuko Furukawa and
Ms. Azusa Machida, you two
went to the victim's room
on the 2nd floor to wake her up
And heard the gunshot...
So Mr. Mouri and Mr. Kohji Furukawa
Broke the door down and
then discovered the body...
Am I correct so far?
Yes
When you heard the gunshot, did you
notice anything out of the ordinary?
I'm very certain it was when
Miss Etsuko bent down
To pick up the handkerchief she dropped,
that's when we heard the gunshot...
What about after the gunshot?
No, nothing...
Inspector, just a moment!
How long are you going to keep us here?!
That's right!
It's obvious she was killed by the same
person who attacked her 3 days ago!
Put out an all points bulletin, do something!
That's already been
taken care of. However,
Judging from the position of the body,
There's a good chance
she knew her killer!
She knew the killer...
Are we suspects?!
I left this morning and
haven't been in mom's room!
Inspector Megure...
Hmm, thank you
Azusa Machida...
Y, yes...
It seems the victim
treated you quite badly...
According to your neighbor, you
were complaining about it this evening
You said, "I'll get back at her for this!"
Yes, I did...
Azusa, you didn't...
Oh-oh, you finally lost your temper, huh...
No, you're wrong. I didn't do it!
It's true, I did say that...
but let me explain...
I spilled some tea in the
madam's room this evening...
I wiped everything that got wet
The clock, the remote control
for the television, even the rug!
But madam insisted I stained the rug
And she said she wasn't going
to give me a bonus this year
Then on top of that, she made me
write an IOU...
And that's why I said what I did...
But like I said before,
when the gunshot went off,
I was outside the door with Ms. Etsuko
Is that correct?
Yes
Which means you two have an alibi...
And Mr. Furukawa, where were you then?
Eh?!
That's a good question, Kohji.
As soon as your sister and Azusa
went upstairs, you left the living room
After the gunshot, you took some time
before joining us upstairs didn't you...
Ho, hold on just one minute
I didn't kill her
Then where were you?
I, I was going to go buy mom a gift...
And just as I was going out the gate,
I heard a strange sound so I rushed back
Which means you have no alibi...
Th, that's...
Why don't we just talk
about this a little more
The way things stand now,
Kohji does seem the most suspicious...
But something just doesn't seem right...
Huh?
Mr. Tome!
Huh? Hey, there you are kid!
Are you here to help
that famous detective again?
Yeah, sort of
He told me to ask you if
there was a cassette radio
Or something with a timer in the room
Aha...
I get it, if you set the timer, you
can pre-set the gunshot, right?
Unfortunately, we didn't
find anything like that,
The TV's an old model and it
doesn't have a timer either...
I was wrong...
Thank you, Mr. Tome
OK!!
Good hunting, little detective!
I was so sure there was a
trick behind to that gunshot...
A blue-white light?!
What nonsense are you talking about...
It's true!
Just before the gunshot, I
happened to look up at mom's room
And her room was lit up with a blue-white
light but it got dark right after that again
You've got to believe me!!
A blue-white light...
But Mr. Tome just told me...
What's going on here...
I've got it!
You can do it that way!
That's why that thing was there
Hello
Yes, I see...
Thank you very much!
I knew it!
You're smart to pick up on that kid...
That struck me as strange too...
Now I've got all the evidence...
That person is the killer!!
Hey, Conan!
Good grief, where's this solid
proof you were talking about!
Ulp?!
Here it comes...
It's happening again...
I'm counting on you, old man!
Mouri!
Is it true, you know who the killer is?
Hey Mouri...
What the?! Oh, I know that look!!
Yes Inspector Megure,
I've figured everything out
Have everyone come
here to this room please
You've got it!
So everyone's present?
First of all Inspector Megure,
judging from the position of the body,
You've deducted the victim
knew the killer, didn't you?
Yes
But when we broke the door down and
entered the room, the lights were all off!
What? Then how did the
victim see the killer's face...
Wait...
You don't mean?!
That's right.
Mrs. Furukawa was killed earlier in the
day, while there was still sunlight!!
Are you sure?!
B, but what about the
gunshot we all heard?
That gunshot was staged by
the killer to be used as an alibi
The killer took the remote
control for the television
And switched it on
later to play the television
But Mouri,
Doesn't that mean the killer
had to have prior knowledge
Of the exact time the gunshot
would be heard on television?
How could anyone...
Oh!!
Uh, sis...
That's right, there's only one person here
Who would know the exact time
A gunshot would be
heard on the television...
The gunshot was heard at about 7:30.
7:29 and 32 seconds to be exact
It's the exact time a gun is shot in a show
Ms. Furukawa's company produces
Yes, Ms. Etsuko Furukawa,
you are the murderer!!
The crime probably took place like this...
In the evening,
Ms. Furukawa climbed
in through the window...
Her mother sees her and
goes to the window
And is shot by a gun with a silencer
Ms. Furukawa then changed her
clothes and came to meet with us
Acting as if nothing had happened
Then calculating the time,
She took Azusa,
who would act as her witness,
Upstairs and deliberately
dropped her handkerchief
Then pretends to pick it up as
she presses the remote control button!
Did I made any mistakes anywhere?
I see...
So the blue-white light Kohji was
talking about was from the television...
If even a second was off from the timing
of switching the remote control on,
Other noises would have been heard
and the trick wouldn't have worked
That's why you wore a digital
watch today, isn't that right?
And it was also you who broke
the TV in living room, wasn't it?
When the gunshot was heard
upstairs, it would've been suspicious
If the same sound came from the
television downstairs, wouldn't it?
C, can you prove any of this?!
Do you have any proof I did it?!
Of course I do!
When the body was found,
you pretended to cry and crouched down
When no one was looking, you took the
remote control out. Then slid it on the rug
And returned it
under the table, didn't you?
But you put a little too
much strength into it,
it was supposed to look
like it fell from the table
But it slid under the legs instead
Your fingerprints were
on that remote control
Of course they would be!
I go in and out of this
room practically every day!
But earlier you said you left the room
this morning and never returned...
I was talking about today. But I was
in here yesterday and the day before too!
Oh really...
By the way, Azusa
Y, yes?!
What did you do with the remote
control when you spilled the tea?
I told you, the tea spilled on it
So I wiped it clean...
You're lying!
I bet you forgot to wipe it!!
I did not! I wiped it absolutely clean!!
Oh brother, this argument
is getting us nowhere...
Tome! Please explain to everyone!
Yes sir!
Can I begin?
Anytime
Ahem!
We found two sets of fingerprints
on the remote control found on the scene!
One! The left hand print
of Ms. Etsuko Furukawa
Including the thumb to
baby finger and palm print
Second! The left hand print
of Ms. Azusa Machida
Including the thumb to
baby finger and palm print
See, what did I tell you!
YOUR prints are on it too!
B, but I...
Is that all, Mr. Tome?
That's all
Then that settles it...
Wh, what do you mean by that...
Azusa didn't forget to
wipe the remote control
B, but just now...
Something was missing!
If she had forgotten
to wipe the remote control,
something else had to be on it...
Katsue Furukawa's fingerprints,
it was her room
& since she's always handling
the remote control,
her prints should have been on it!!
.....It was all her fault...
...She knew
I was having financial problems
but she wouldn't lend me a single cent...
Yet she'd pay off
all of Kohji's gambling debts...
It was always that way!!
It was always Kohji this, Kohji that...
she pampered him because
she gave birth to him in her later years...
Kohji was everything...
Sis...
Miss Furukawa...
It's not that
I don't understand how you feel...
I do, but
....think about it
You've just committed a murder!
You've killed your own mother!
...I want you to think deeply
about what you did!!
There, that should do it!
It works!
Thank you so much!
Aw, it was nothing...
He may not look it
but Mr. Takagi's a video freak!
He's goes to rent videos every night,
he's addicted,
Gunshots?!
L, look out!!
I've got a case to solve...
somebody tell him it's already over!!
Y, you've.....
You've got to be kidding!
I'm not going to bathe
with Conan, no way!!
Something's come over Ran...
I wonder if she suspects who I really am?
Genta, what's wrong?
PERILOUS RETURN-
DETECTIVES IN THE CAVE