The ultimate series starts today!
We'll start by beating these guys.
Seeing through to the one and only truth,
He looks like a child but has the mind of an adult.
His name is: Detective Conan!
Not just once, but twice! Who was it that saved my life again?
Oh, unnamed knight with your black cloak, if you will grant me my wish...
Please take off that dark mask and show me your true face!
If that is what the princess wishes, I shall show you my sorrowful face under this moonlight!
Dad, do it properly!
There isn't much time left until the festival.
Dummy, how can I do this properly with all of these cheesy lines?
Who in the world would write such a melodramatic script?
Sonoko, it was Sonoko!
She said the "Black Cloaked Knight" was made in Shinichi's image.
That woman.
Hey, wait a minute!
It says here that the knight and princess will exchange a warm kiss!
W-What?!
It's just pretend, don't worry.
Hey Ran-neechan, who's going to play the part of the knight?
Ah, so you want to know, Conan-kun?
A little...
It's probably just some young male student.
It's someone you both know very well.
We wet him by chance on a case, Araide-sensei!
All the guys were too shy, so we asked Araide-sensei when he just happened to come in for a checkup!
When he was a student he was very good at doing a lot of lead roles in plays.
Things like, emphasizing a line and handling a woman...
Hey, that's not right, not at all!
Don't do it, Ran-neechan!
Just kidding. The only thing we asked Or. Araide to do was direct.
Sonoko says she'll dress up as a wan and do what she can!
What?
Mow stupid.
Look at the time! I have practice, I heed to take a quick shower and get to bed.
Our shower is broken.
I wanted to take one too!
Then why don't you two go to the public baths?
But I think today is a holiday!
Then how about the Professor's shower?
I was just thinking of going there to talk to him about our weekend camping trip.
Really? I'll go!
I'll get clothes to change into.
Me too!
Geez, go in together so you won't be a bother and come right home, okay?
Are you joking?!
Why should I take a shower together with Conan-kun?!
You know, it's not good to teach those type of things to children.
Right, Conan-kun?
R-Right...
Desperate Revival: Cavern of the Detective Boys
Something is odd about Ran.
What do you mean?
I sense it sometimes.
Ran's attitude towards me isn't right for a first grade elementary school kid, it's more like...
Hey, hey, Shinichi!
You know, it's probably just me!
Or maybe she knows...
Your true identity.
A-Ai-kun!
I have something to do in the basement until morning, so... don't bother me, okay?
Hey, if it's as Ai-kun said...
Idiot then why doesn't she tell me?
Someone like Ran would...
What, something about me?
Oh, it's nothing!
Where's Ai-chan?
Ai-kun is in the basement * *
I'll go greet her!
Ran-neechan!
Wait!
Hello, Ar-chan...
Hello, Ai-chan...
Hey, why don't you at least answer?
It's alright, Professor. I wouldn't want to be a bother.
See you later, Ai-chan!
Maybe I'm... running away?
That's outrageous.
"In this world...", shall we go again?
Ready and...
Hey Professor, about the talk we had earlier...
If I could, in this world,
Grasp your love.
Just in case, can you wake me something for it?
Another invention?
Watching the dancing lights, I shall not forget.
Maybe something like a robot that looks like me and can move and talk?
If I could do something like that, I would be a billionaire by now!
Ah, the mystery is getting solved.
I suppose you're right.
Alright the tent is finished!
You didn't forget the tent today.
Ai-kun and I will make a cooking fire, why don't you guys go get some firewood?
Yeah!
Dinner! Dinner!
Barbi-six, Barbi-seven, Barbi-eight, Barbi-nine!
Barbeque!
Hey, I think we have enough.
Let's go back already!
Yeah!
Wait everyone, come here for a second.
I found something interesting!
It's just a cave.
It says "Danger! Do not enter!"
What you should be looking at is this!
The words written on the rock.
(Japanese character "To")
Take your steps towards the path of the dragon,
And you shall be showered by the light of happiness.
Light of happiness?
It means a light full of joy!
Could that mean...
A treasure!
This again?
The curious thing here is the giant hiragana "To" engraved on the rock.
To... Tokujyou unagi rice...?
Topaz?
Tunnel?
(Japanese: "Toneru")
Tokugawa's hidden treasure.
Just kidding.
Hey, hey, you guys!
Come on, just a little while!
Geez...
Geez, this is a huge cave!
It's a limestone cavern.
It's so big inside.
Wm, cigarette?
The filter is still moist.
Is there someone else here?
They're slow. I wonder how far they went?
Maybe they went exploring in the woods.
Especially since they're all just a bunch of curious detectives.
Now professor, hurry back and help we?
Right!
Hey look, there's a light.
Someone's there.
The owner of the cigarette found earlier?
Maybe someone else found the treasure first.
Are you serious?
Hey Genta.
Dawn, if we came here a bit earlier we could've gotten it!
What's wrong, Genta?
A corpse.
Bastard!
Handgun!
Get down!
What's up?
Kids, we were seen by kids!
Hey, hey... their parents aren't with them, are they?
No, just four kids.
Dammit, how unlucky.
When we robbed the bank, our companion's face was seen.
We thought that killing and hiding him here would get rid of any leads. But kids now?
In any case, go find the kids.
Damn, where did they go?
Hey, if you find the kids, what are you going to do with them?
What do you think? We're going to make them sleep for all eternity in this dark cavern.
After placing a hole in their heads, that is.
Anyway, you 50 back to the entrance.
We'll look around here a bit longer.
Right.
Hey Haibara, can you hear we? Haibara!
Haibara, give hie a reply!
Haibara, if you can hear me, give me an answer!
Haibara!
Mow did you live alone for so long with skills like these?
Just leave it.
I wonder what's wrong?
Is her switch not turned on?
Alright, I'll tell them we didn't see anything.
No, you can't do that!
I bet Conan-kun will think of a bright idea for us!
Right, Conan-kun...?
Conan!
Conan-kun...
Conan-kun.
What's with all the blood?
Did the bullet that guy just fired hit you?
Conan-kun, if we don't run soon, those bad people are going to come back!
Wait.
Sooner or later, the Professor and Haibara will come to this cavern.
If they don't know anything when they come in and go to the back of the cave, they'll probably get killed!
We have to tell them first that this cavern is dangerous.
But what can we do?
Even if we leave a note, those guys'll tear it apart if they find it!
I think we should go to the back and use our detective badges to try and establish contact with them.
Fool! If we go any further, our signal won't even reach them.
Then what should we do?
We'll use these homing devices used to track down culprits.
Its back is made like a sticker and there are about 10 of them here.
But how can we... with something like that...?
There's no time to explain.
Hurry up and do as I say.
Damn brats, where did they run off to?
Hey, did you find them?
No, it seems they didn't go to the front.
That's strange, we've searched everywhere around here.
The only place left is the path that leads us even further in.
Then we don't have to chase them.
Those brats are as good as dead.
They say these insides are so full of split paths that many people just get lost in there.
No, we'll chase them.
Just in case.
It's almost certain the brats went further in.
Glasses?
But those glasses could belong to some other guy who got lost in here before!
Fool, look at this.
It's... It's blood!
Yeah, and it's not dry yet.
I see, it won't take long for us to catch up to the kids.
Exactly.
Hey, don't you think it's a bit too late, even for them?
Yeah.
I'm going to take a look around the woods.
Hey, wait up, Ai-kun!
Are, you okay, Conan-kun?
Yeah, I put a huge band-aid on it for now.
But Genta, can't you walk any faster?
They're going to catch up to us.
B-But, wouldn't it hurt if I shook you?
It's all my fault I said a little while wouldn't matter.
If we never entered this cave, Conan-kun wouldn't be like this...
No, it's not your fault Ayumi-chan!
It all started because I found this kind of place!
You idiot I'm the one to blame!
I got excited and then saw the bad guys doing their thing.
You fools.
Because you guys came into this cave,
You have a chance to solve a murder case that might have remained a mystery.
Come on, once we get away from those guys, we're having a barbeque!
Let's stay positive and keep going.
Come here everyone!
The path is split into two.
Yeah.
What should we do?
Alright let's settle this with rock-paper-scissors.
G-Genta, let me borrow your watch light
C'mon, hurry!
Right.
Hey, everyone! Where are you?
Hey, answer me!
Look at this, Professor. It s the branches they gathered for the campfire.
Four piles of sticks are neatly lined up at the entrance.
Then could those kids be...
In this limestone cavern?
Agh, the path split!
Dammit, which way did they go?
Hey I What's that thing?
Something is sparkling.
It's a watch with a light.
They have some pretty cool things.
Then there's no mistake, the brats went this way.
Wait.
That's a trap.
Think carefully.
Even if they are kids, they would notice dropping a shining object.
Also, the belt on the watch is neatly closed.
So they just wanted to make it look like they went that way!
Dammit.
The brats are underestimating us.
This is getting interesting. Now I want to see the faces of those four brats even more.
Yeah, their faces in fear as they beg for their lives.
But are you sure it's okay?
Leaving the watch light at the entrance for this side?
Yeah, they most likely went in the opposite direction.
They pulled off a bank robber/, at least one of them must have some intelligence.
What'll we do if they split into two groups and come to this side too?
They won't.
They know that being alone in a cave like this with no communication would cost them their lives.
Hey, there are fish here!
Hey, do those fish have eyes?
Yes, they do. I believe they're trout.
What, do we get to eat them?
You idiot, were not just running around!
If there are fish with eyes in a cavern like this, then they came here from a nearby river.
So if we go against the flow of water...
We could get to the outside!
Exactly.
These glasses are Kudo-kun's, right?
Yeah, so they're lost somewhere in here.
But why leave them at a place like this?
This is bad, we have to find them immediately.
Mold on.
There are a lot of things scattered around here.
This is my button-sized locator!
Don't touch it. It's in some sort of shape.
Some shape?
If I increase the search area... this is!
(Note: 110 is the emergency phone number in Japan, just like 911 is for the USA and Canada.)
Hey, what's going on, it's a dead end?
Dawn, it's those brats!
They pulled a fast one on us.
Then let's turn back immediately and chase them down!
I'll slaughter them!
It can't be!
Y-You can't be serious!
We can't get out of this place with that!
It looks like the trout really do come from here.
Then were stuck here until we die?
No!
It's still too early to be hopeless.
Look, there are roots on the ceiling.
It's proof that the ground is near. The exit might be closely.
But, I don't see an exit anywhere.
It's an egg!
There's a huge egg here!
It s just an egg-shaped rock on top of a boulder.
Geez, that's boring.
We sure came to a strange place.
Yeah, the path splits into five.
I wonder if one leads to the exit?
That's strange, a rock like this wouldn't just fall on top of a boulder.
Someone placed it there on purpose. But for what?
Look, there are some words engraved on it!
"Those who are lost in the dark,"
'Take your steps towards the path of the dragon."
"Then you shall be showered by the light of happiness/'
Those who are lost in the dark?
It's almost the same as the words engraved on that big rock at the entrance.
B-Bats!
That voice was...
There's mo mistake, it's those brats!
They're close, let's hurry!
Don't move!
Cave bats eat bugs and insects.
Co they're very sensitive to small moving objects.
Don't find those freaky things, Ayumi-chan.
But...
No, it was a big help.
Cave bats only live within a 300 meter radius of a cave entrance.
The exit we're looking for is right in front of our noses.
Really?!
But the problem is, which one of these 5 paths lead to the exit?
From my deduction, the "path of the dragon" is that, but.
Dammit, my eyes are losing focus.
The important keywords are:
The large "To" engraved on the rock at the front of the cave, the "path of the dragon",
And the egg-shaped rock placed on top of the boulder.
To, path of the dragon, egg...
Then let's try each of the 5 paths, in order.
No, you only need to enter one.
The engraved words, "those who are lost in the dark", means people who are lost in this cave.
The light of happiness is the light coming from the exit
That means the rock at the entrance and on that boulder show the way out of this limestone cave.
The exit, the path of the dragon is...
That path is...
Conan-kun?
Conan-kun!
Oh no, there's so much blood coming out!
Footsteps!
Crap, they're cowing!
What should we do?!
Crap, he's coming this way!
You fool, it's already checkmate for you.
What?!
Excuse hie, I have the same blood type as this boy here!
Ran... so you... you really already...
Next Conan:
Desperate Revival: The Wounded Famous Detective!
Next Conan's Mint: Shogi (Japanese Chess)
Next time that person will do something crazy!
I think it's time to wake up from your dream.