Just as flowing water has no form, and the breeze is invisible,
Deductions take all shapes and styles in each and every case to be solved.
The Youth Detective Squad are trapped in the cave
And there's the question of Conan's blood type.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult,
No case is left unsolved with Detective Conan.
We, the Youth Detective Squad, went on a camping trip with Doctor Agasa
And we found a limestone cave!
We quickly decided to go inside and explore it but
we come across some men carrying a dead body
and on top of that, I...
Get down!
got shot and suffered a severe injury...
Footsteps?!
Oh no! Those guys are coming!
What'll we do?!
PERILOUS RETURN-
THE WOUNDED DETECTIVE
Rats! Which one'd they go into?!
Don't worry about it.
One of the kids is hurt, he won't be moving so fast
We'll go after them so you just stand guard here!
OK! I've got you!
Why did we come in a place like this?
It's not my fault!
I thought these were paths so I picked the farthest one,
how did I know they were just holes!
Don't fight,
we've got to find the dragon's path that Conan told us about
or we're going to be killed!
B-By ourselves, without Conan?
You've got to be kidding
I'm not kidding!
He's not budging!
That's strange.
If he'd create a physiological phenomenon,
it'd give us the perfect chance to escape...
We can't wait for that to happen!
Besides, his friends could come back at anytime
We've got to get out of this cave as soon as possible
so we can get Conan to a hospital...
Yes, you're right...
let's look for the dragon's path
Conan said would lead us out!
Let's go
There are 5 openings.
The guard is in front of the rock egg
... and we're right here...
Since this is just a hole & doesn't go anywhere,
the dragon's path must be in one of the other 4 openings...
Right...
The dragon's path... dragon... dragon...
Hey, wait a minute!
The word dragon starts with the letter D doesn't it!
Huh?
D is the fourth letter in the alphabet!
X-DISSOLVE WITHIN CUT 1-2-3
You mean the 4th opening is the dragon's path!
That's right!
The 4th from the entrance
It's the one we're in right now...
You're kidding...
You know, Conan was mumbling something from behind me
Huh?
I'm pretty sure he said the key words were...
[to], [dragon], and [egg]
... something like that...
Why didn't you tell us that earlier!
You idiot!
Huh?
Oh brother... he's coming this way!
Hey!
Didn't I tell you to keep a look out here!
Oh... did you find them?
Those kids...
Nope, the 1st opening was a dead end!
Don't worry about it.
There's 4 more, we'll find them soon enough!
The kids might double back here so keep your eyes open!
OK!
OK now, so the key words are
[to], [dragon] & [egg]...
It doesn't make any sense...
If the dragon were a snake, then eggs would be their favorite food
Snake?
My grandmother who lives in the country told me.
She was born in the year of the snake so she studied them!
Year of the snake?
That's it! I'm sure of it!
[To], [dragon], and [egg] pertain to the Chinese zodiac.
Dragon means year of the dragon, egg means year of the snake!
Yes, but what about [to]?
It probably means year of the tiger (tora) or chicken (tori)
If we put the egg into the snake's position,
the 5 openings and their pertaining zodiac symbols will be like this...
year of the dragon,
which is the dragon's path, is right next to the egg...
But isn't that the opening those killers said was a dead end?!
And besides, I think year of the chicken is better suited for the word egg...
B-But... then the meaning will overlap with the word [to].
Oh, maybe it's pointing to the year of the rabbit.
The character for rabbit looks a lot like the character for egg!
But it's the chicken that lays eggs...
Hmm... I think [to], [dragon], and [egg] aren't referring to the zodiac after all
So the only other common denominator is they're all written in 1 character...
What're you talking about!
Egg is 2 characters, isn't it?
I went to a restaurant close to where I live and I read [tamago yaki] as [ohji yaki]
And everybody, even mom laughed at me, that's why I'll never forget the word!
And tamago is sometimes written as tama no ko too...
You see!
Hey, just wait a minute!
You know, it could be, it just could be, that
it has something to do with "shogi" (chess)
Huh?
[To] is in back of the pawn and
[dragon] is in back of the rook
And just like Genta said,
the character for egg could be
the one he mentioned which would stand for "gyokusho"!
What's gyokusho?
In chess, it's the king the player with the lower score uses!
What I'm saying is, if the egg is referring to the position of the king,
the 5 openings would be ranked according to their proximity to the egg
thus they would be
[kinsho], [ginsho], [keima], [kosha],
the opening in front of the [keima] would be the path of the rook and...
What about the dragon's path?
I'm getting to that!
The opening diagonally in front of it is the way out
But what are we gonna do?
We can't get to that one without passing in front of that man
That is a problem.
The only weapons, if you can call them that,
we have is our watch shaped flashlights and our badges...
Our badges?
If I remember right, Conan...
Listen! I don't know if it'll work but...
Here goes...
Take that!
Do you think you can knock me out with those rocks...
Now! Let's go!
Hey, what's going on?!
It's those kids!
They went into that opening...
I'll teach them!
They won't get away from me!
It's the exit!
Ge, Genta!
Aha, I've got you!
OK you two!
Don't step outside, get back in here!
Come on! Hurry it up!
I'll shoot him in the head if you don't!
That's right, good kiddies
This is the police!
You're completely surrounded!
Throw down your guns and come out with your hands up!
I repeat!
You are completely surrounded!
Rats...
Darn!
You fools! Don't you see what I have?
If you don't me to shoot this kid, you'd better let me through!
You idiot...
I've already read your next move...
What?
Play it smart...
That's how the 3 robbers were caught and our cave exploration came to an end
It was Doctor Agasa and Haibara that notified the police.
They figured we'd be heading for the cave's exit
so they talked to the local people and found out about this exit
And they'd just arrived to stake it out
According to this local man,
that mysterious sign has been around for ages
And no one knows for sure who wrote it...
My consciousness started to slip as I listened to the conversation
And I was taken to the Beika General Hospital
What?! Surgery???
Wasn't it just a scratch?
Well... uh, er... you see... um...
He was shot
What?
The bullet passed through the abdomen on the left side
but there was a lot of bleeding and there's a possibility of kidney damage
He's in a very serious condition...
Conan!
Conan, hang in there!
You'll be fine in a little while!
Doctor, we have a problem!
The previous patient we operated on has this boy's blood type
And we used up almost all the blood we had in stock!
Are you sure?!
Even if we call the blood bank now, we'll never get it in time!
Excuse me...
You can use my blood...
He and I have the same blood type!
Hey, now, how do you know that?
Oh, but you'd better check to make sure
Hurry then, let's get you tested
Yes ma'am!
Ran....I knew it...
So you did know after all...
Shinichi...
Well, it looks like I'm still alive
Ouch....boy this pain doesn't give up... and neither do I...
Ran...
You owe her your life!
She gave you 400 cc of her own blood and on top of that,
she stayed up all night watching you
Good grief
You're lucky you and Ran just happened to have the same blood type
If you had a rare blood type, you wouldn't be here today
You'd be in the next world!
Excuse me... you can use my blood...
He and I have the same blood type!
No, it wasn't a guess...
Ran knew for sure...
She knew my blood type...
She knows who I am...
Hey!
Huh?
Ran gave you a whole lot of her blood.
You'd get better fast or I'm going to get you!
Oh, yessir!
10 Days Later
Are you sure?
Yes! There was no damage to any major organ and he's healing very well,
at this rate, he'll be able to check out in 2 or 3 days, I'm sure of it.
That's wonderful
One thing though....after the operation, his resistance is low
And it appears he has an infection in his upper respiratory tract...
An upper respiratory tract infection?
Don't worry, it's just a cold
See! Didn't I tell you this game's neat?
It's really popular at school!
There, go there!
Go left there!
That's enough
Play time is over!
Aw shucks!
The patient is to return straight to his room!
As for you kids, it's getting late so go on home!
Aw gee
Sorry guys...
Rats!
See you Conan!
Bye bye
See you!
We'll see you at school!
They said you could leave in 2 or 3 days,
our school's having the school festival then
3 days from today, that's the day we have our play
What are you going to do?
You can't pick him up... you'll be busy all morning!
Don't worry! I'll ask dad to do it
By the way, did you get a hold of "you know who"?
Who's that?
Shinichi of course!
If he finds out you're playing the lead,
I'm sure he'll come flying
He won't come...
Besides... it doesn't matter to me anyway...
I'll be happy just having Conan get better and coming to see the play...
Eh???
You will come, won't you
Oh... sure...
What is this???
You two're acting so lovey-dovey!
Ran, don't tell me you're switching from Shinichi to this kid?
Don't be silly! That's ridiculous!
Hey, hey!
Sonoko, what happened to your wrist...
You mean this?
I sprained it during rehearsal, that's why I can't play the knight's part...
But you're lucky someone that nice offered to take your place
Who's that?
You know, Mr. Arade, the teacher I told you about!
I hate to admit but he's awfully good at it too!
And that love scene with Ran is something!
Sonoko!
Heh... I see...
And if Ran can keep a cool head in front of all those people, the play'll be perfect!
Don't worry!
The cooler in the gym is broken and it'll be like a sauna inside,
besides, there wasn't much of a crowd last year either...
I'll bet that scrawny guy planned things to work out this way
Didn't you know, things will be different this year!
The drama club is putting up a stand in the gym, they're going to sell cold drinks!
Oh no, I don't believe it!
What in the world were you thinking of?!
Why'd you go and buy lilies!
Why don't you just shut up!
Flowers are flowers, what's the difference?!
Aren't those voices coming from your room, Conan?
You're right...
That voice, it couldn't be...
You dope! Lilies have a strong smell, some people don't like them!
You don't buy them for people in the hospital!
Why didn't you tell me that before!
You ninny!
Heiji, Kazuha, I didn't expect you.
Yo! I heard the kid got hurt bad so we hopped on a plane after school got out
So how are you?
Fine! He's healing very well, they said he'll be able to leave in 2 or 3 days!
I'm glad to hear that
Never mind that! I brought you some great flowers to send you off with!
What's that supposed to mean?
You have some nerve!
Will you girls go with Kazuha so she doesn't get lost?!
Why of course
And?
So what's the real reason you came here?
You hurt my feelings, I came all this way just to see how you're doing
I was shot in the stomach too, we've got things in common
I'm asking you again...
What is so important you had to come all this way and with flowers even
Heh, I guess I can't fool you, huh
Truth is, I got a call from an old guy named Agasa, last night...
Eh?
He wanted to talk to me about you
About me?
I don't know what's going on but, Kudo...
You...
It seems that girlie's starting to get suspicious about who you really are!
Humph!
No she's not suspicious!
She already knows!
Eh? You're kidding, you told her?
Do you think I'm crazy?!
Then you and that old man could be wrong about the whole thing!
You're so scared she'll find out, your imagination got the best of you!
No, there's been a lot of signs she knows
And unless I can come up with another me, I don't think I can fool her...
But I don't understand,
if she knows,
why doesn't she just tell me...
Hmm...
You haven't changed, you can read other people's minds
But you don't have the slightest idea what's going on with yourself
If that girl knows and she's not saying it,
then there's only 1 reason why
She's waiting!
She wants to hear it from you personally!
I guess you have to prepare for the worst and tell her everything,
about the so called group of men in black
and about the potion that made you shrink, don't you think so?
You've got to be kidding...
Do you expect me to tell her all that? She's a kind person.
She listens to everyone's problems, worries for them, and cries for them
How can I do that to her?
But then again,
I don't think I can keep lying to her,
not after seeing how strained she was...
I really want to tell her everything and get it off my chest but...
Hattori, listen...
What would you do...
What do you think is right?
Hey Heiji!
Heiji!
Huh?
On the last day of the school fest, you know the play Ran's in...
It's on a Sunday, so you'll come with me won't you?
Unless I can come up with another me,
I don't think I can fool her...
Sorry but I can't go
But why not?
I have something to do that day.
I can't get out of it.
It's important...
Listen Shinichi
You must never tell anyone about this!
And that includes Ran!
If that girl knows but isn't saying anything
Then there's only 1 reason why!
You understand, don't you?
We can't let anyone know about us...
She's waiting...
She wants you to tell her personally...
Don't leave me!
I guess I've got to tell her!
На...
Haibara...?!
PERILOUS RETURN-
SHINICHI IS BACK