Just as flowing water has no form, and the breeze is invisible
Deductions take all shapes and styles in each and every case to be solved
A gun is between Conan and Ai
While Ran is putting on quite a performance with a certain someone
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult
No case is left unsolved with Detective Conan
We, the Youth Detective Squad, go on a camping trip with Doctor Agasa
And find a limestone cave in the forest
We immediately decide to go in and explore it
But inside the cave, we come across a gang of bank robbers
who are trying to hide the body of one of their partners
And of all the bad luck,
I am shot and seriously injured
But thanks to the good work of the Youth Detective Squad,
We escaped and the robbers were arrested
I was quickly taken to the hospital and thanks to Ran, whose blood they used
For my transfusion, I pulled through.
But how did she know my blood type?
He and I have the same blood type!
Ran was very certain...
She knew what blood type I had...
She knows who I am...
And just when I figured the only option
I had was to tell Ran the whole truth...
Ai comes along and points a gun at me!
PERILOUS RETURN-
THE THIRD CHOICE
Ha...
Haibara...?!
Sorry about this...
I guess there was still some bad blood flowing through me
What?!
Oh... didn't you know?
My cover's been blown...
By those men in black, as you call them...
Want to know how?
It was that incident at the Haido City Hotel
I never dreamed it would happen...
Who would have thought there was another man there besides Pisco...
What he told them made the organization suspect the potion turned me into a child
And they found out where I was and contacted me this morning...
I thought they'd kill me off right there
But they said that if I returned to the organization,
They'd overlook the fact I betrayed them...
They want me to get back to developing the Apotoxin 4869, that's their objective!
So that's it...
That's why you're here to kill me, because I know about your organization...
That's right...
That's what they told me I had to do if I want to go back!
Of course, your parents and your detective friend in Osaka
Will also be killed tomorrow!
I'm sorry about this...
But Doctor Agasa's been taken hostage...
This is the only thing I can do to save him!
But you can also thank me...
You won't have to see your parents or your friend get killed...
Because I'm going to kill you first...
What'd you think?
What the...?
What if there really was someone like that at the hotel...
And what if they did find me and take the doctor hostage?
I'd do just what I just did, you know...
But then it's a sure bet they'll kill anyone and everyone I came in contact with,
No doubt about that...
Hey...
What are you trying to get at...
I came here to make things clear to you...
Make what clear?
If you let your feelings get the best of you
And you tell her about the organization...
I want you to know that she'll certainly be one of those the organization gets rid of!
By "her"...
Do you mean Ran?
That's right...
I'm almost positive she knows who you are...
And you're thinking you can't fool her this time...
So you're thinking of telling her all about the potion and the organization
And get everything off of your chest...!
Why are you so surprised?
Anyone could tell by looking at you now!
If I can see through you, she probably can too...
She might just be thinking,
"He's going to tell me any day now...
Oh come on...
You have 3 choices!
3?
The first is, leave things as is, don't tell her anything and keep your distance
Second, you cast your fates to the wind and tell her everything...
Or your third choice which is...
Shuffle Romance
Good grief, I don't believe this...
Why are there so many people out there? And we're up next too!
That's because they've heard good things about it!
After all, it's being billed as the best love romance
Surpassing even Romeo and Juliet!
Raaan!
Kazuha!
I decided to come after all!
Heiji said I shouldn't since
I'd only be imposing, though...
You mean Heiji didn't come with you?
Oh shucks and I have a secret crush on him too...
Eh?!
She's just joking!
Sonoko's crazy about another tall, dark boy...! Aren't you!
Well excuse me for liking them tall and dark...
And where's Shinichi?
I didn't invite him...
For the love of...
You invite old friends and people from your neighborhood
But you don't invite your
"honey, I don't understand you
Oh I get it...
I'm not the only one you invited today...
Why Conan, I'm glad you could make it!
He's still got a cold so I told to him stay at home and rest but he refused to listen
He said he promised to come so nothing could stop him
How are you?
Do you feel OK?
I'm fine
Don't push yourself just for me
Ran, may I speak to you?
It's about the cue to the last dialogue...
Be right there...
He's nice looking...
Is he by chance her partner in the play?
That's right! Don't you think they make a nice couple?
Well I'll be going to my seat now...
OK...
Don't get nervous!
Good luck!
Oh no, it's 15 minutes before stage time!
We've got to change into our costumes!
Uh huh...
Sorry it took so long...
What took you so long, I'm dying of thirst
Youta Mitani
Security
Sorry about that but the concession was pretty crowded...
Mai Kougami
I have to go to the restroom, could you take these?
Are you going from now?
Then you'd better hurry Mai!
Yumemi Noda
Travel Agent
I think it's about to start...
Really?
I have less than a minute left, I better hurry!
Hurry back!
Let's see, Mai has an iced coffee and...
Mine's orange juice
Orange juice, and...
Here
Thank you
Kohei, you're having iced coffee, aren't you?
Yeah...
Mine's the oolong tea!
Kouhei Kamata
Huh?
I-I don't believe it!
It's her...!
Ayako Ninakawa
Huh?!
What's wrong?
Nothing... don't worry about it...
The B group of the junior class will now perform Shuffle Romance"...
I hope you all enjoy the play...
Ah...
Omniscient and omnipotent God Zeus!
Why do you subject me to such cruelty...?
Or are you telling me to resign myself to this marriage that I do not wish?!
That's the way, show us your stuff!
Eh heh, that's my daughter up there
Oh how embarrassing,
I want to change my seat...
Sir! It's the first climatic scene!
Hurry and get up there, stand by... for...
Uh...
Wh... who are you ruffians?
Do you realize this is
Princess Heart's carriage?
Her father is the Duke Bridge!
Of course we know that!
Our orders are to kill the princess so the wedding doesn't take place!
To our empire, it is more convenient for the Duke and the King to remain at odds
It is to our benefit...
Get out of the way!
Come!
Ran, give him a karate chop!
Take those guys out!
Huh?
Raven feathers...?
It can't be...!
Ugh!
A black knight...?!
Ooo he's so handsome
Damn! Let's get out of here!
You've saved me not once but twice...
Who and what might you be...?
I am but a lowly knight dressed in black, my lady...
If you would grant me my wish...
Please remove that dark mask that you're wearing
And show me your face...!
Eh...?!
What...?!
Oh Ran, you're so lucky...
Mr. Arade...
This wasn't in the script...
Why that animal
What's he doing to my young daughter, she's still a child!
I'll teach you!
Don't go up there sir! Don't interupt them!
This is the best part!
Eh...?
Psst, Sonoko...
What am I supposed to do?
What...?!
What do you mean keep going...
Are you sure about this?
Oh, could you by chance, be Spade...
The man my father slashed between the eyes then threw out of our courtyard...
No one dreamt you were the prince of Trump empire...
If you haven't forgotten the promise we made when we were but children...
Please...
Plant a kiss upon my lips in proof...
Why you idiot!
What are you saying! Ran!
The deceased is
Kohei Kamata, 27 years old...
He's a doctor at the Beika General Hospital?
Yes...
You say he collapsed while watching the play, is that right?
It seemed as if he was suddenly overcome with pain
Then he just collapsed
Could he have collapsed after drinking the contents of this cup?
I don't know
I was concentrating on the play...
There isn't much left inside...
At approximately what time did Mr. Kamata collapse?
Let's see...
The play started a little after 2, so...
I believe it was about 2:40...
Ra, Ran?!
You see
We heard the scream during the climatic scene in the first half of the play...
Isn't that right, Mr. Arade!
Mr. Arade...?
Oh I get it!
This is Ran's high school and it's their school festival!
Which means, hey!
That fellow must also be here
Huh...?
Are you looking for somebody? Inspector?
I certainly am, you!
You jinx, you!
So you've finally gone and brought bad luck onto your own daughter's school!
And?
You did make sure no one got close to the corpse, didn't you?
Of course, Inspector!
Preserving the scene of the crime is one of the most basic steps in crime solving!
This coroner was the first one to touch the body!
Have you determined the cause of death?
Yes...
I'm certain this was...
It was potassium cyanide
Eh...?!
What?!
I'm sure this guy died after drinking potassium cyanide!
Hey!
I thought you said no one touched the body!
Well, er...
I didn't see anybody...
You fool!
You don't have to touch the body to figure out how he died!
When somebody dies, it's normal for them to take on death's colors...
But this guy's lips and even his nails aren't purple, they're pink!
That's proof he died of potassium cyanide poisoning!
Potassium cyanide is different from other poisons in that,
When you drink it, it destroys the electron transmission in the cells
And the oxygen in the blood gets circulated without being used
That's why the complexion takes on a healthy color...
Also there's the smell of almonds coming out his mouth,
Pointing at potassium cyanide poisoning!
Coroner, is what he said true?
Uh, yes
And there is an almond smell
This boy's right, it's almost certain he died of potassium cyanide poison
Hey, you...
You seem to know a lot about this case...
You weren't anywhere near the victim's chair when it happened, were you?
No way!
I was sitting in the very front row of the block across the aisle from him!
Kamata
Concession Stand
Hmm
The first row of the next block eh...
That's right!
I was sitting 3 seats away from you!
Well, Mouri, is that true?
Uh, you see
I was concentrating on the play so I didn't notice who was sitting in the other seats
Is there anybody else who can prove you were there?
Let's see now...
Uhmm
Just ask him!
I was sitting right next to that kid with the glasses!
Is that right, Conan?
Yeah, I think so...
But still...
I got this funny feeling
I know you from someplace...
Who are you anyway?
Don't tell me you've already forgotten about me?
I'm so disappointed, after all the trouble
I went through to get back here
It's me, Shinichi Kudo!
The kid with the eye glasses called me
That's why I came to see your play, sweetie!
Yes sir! Isn't that right, kid?
Uh...
Aren't you...
Really...
Huh?
Heiji, what're you doing?
Yikes! Kazuha!
I told you not to come here!
You put powder on your face and changed your hair style...
Are you going to put on a kabuki show for us here?
No, you've got everything wrong.
Take a good look!
I'm not Heiji, I'm Shinichi Kudo!
What kind of joke is this anyway!
Aw, I give up!
You're right, it's just a joke!
I thought I'd dress up like Shinichi and surprise everybody
But I guess it didn't work!
Good grief...
Who the heck are you anyway?
One fool's enough and that's Mouri...!
What...?
Oh, uh... it's just a joke...
Rats...
All I wanted to do was pretend to be Shinichi
And sit next to the real mini Shinichi
So that Ran would see us
And maybe she wouldn't be suspicious anymore
My plan was perfect and that darn Kazuha spoiled everything!
Ahem!
At any rate, let's continue the investigation!
And did the deceased
Mr. Kamata buy his own drink?
No, he didn't
I bought the drinks
From that concession...
I bought 4 drinks and took them to my friends who were waiting at their seats...
After that,
I handed the drinks to Mr. Mitani and
I went to the restroom, isn't that right?
Yeah...
So Mr. Mitani, did you give the victim his drink?
No...
Mai asked me to pass out the drinks and...
I'm going to the restroom, could you take these?
Are you going from now?
Then you'd better hurry Mai!
I think it's about to start...
Really?
I have less than a minute left, I'd better hurry!
Hurry back!
Let's see... Mai has an iced coffee and
Mine's orange juice
Orange juice and...
Here
Thank you
Kohei, you're having iced coffee, aren't you?
Yeah
So she was the one who handed him his drink
What's that supposed to mean!
You're the one who picked out which cup was his!
Excuse me but could you tell me what
Mr. Kamata's relationship to you 3 were?
We all graduated from this high school and we were in the same drama club...
And we all coincidentally got jobs in the same company
And it's become a tradition for us to come see the play at the school festival
I can't believe something like this would happen to Kamata...
And he was so excited that his doctrine might finally be recognized...
Yes, that's right...
But Mai, I don't understand why you went to buy 4 drinks all by yourself...
Isn't it pretty hard to carry 4 drinks by yourself?
Well it was crowded so I told the others to go and get the seats...
Kohei came back later and...
Mai, can you manage all those drinks alone?
I'll help you
Oh, thank you
Eh...?
Oh no...?!
Oh, sorry...
I'll wait back at my seat after all
Huh?!
Kohei suddenly got pale and went back to his seat
He got pale?
I wonder what happened?
Maybe it was because he saw me working at the concession...
Ayako, is that you?
Did you graduate from here too?
I knew it!
I knew I recognized you from somewhere...
Do you know her?
Yes...
Her father's the director of the hospital we work in!
Then the person who put the drinks in this group's cups was...
It was me...
I see...
Now we have all the suspects!
Just hold on a minute!
Kohei and I both drank iced coffee!
If I put the poison in his drink,
I'd give him his drink personally so that I wouldn't drink it by mistake!
But if you poisoned both and then just didn't drink your own...
I drank every drop!
Maybe you poured yours down the toilet?
Didn't I tell you I left all the drinks and then went to the restroom?
When I got back, the play had already started and I never left my seat after that!
All I did was pass out the drinks, I didn't have time to put any poison in it!
Neither did I!
But you did have time to open the lid and look inside, didn't you?
We didn't have to open them up!
The contents of each cup was written on the lid...
Besides, the iced coffee had tubs of gum syrup and milk on them...
Then someone could have brought poisoned gum syrup or milk
Then switched them later...
Then he would have died as soon as he drank it!
Potassium cyanide causes instant death!
But Kohei's cup was almost completely empty!
Uh...
It's still not clear what trick the killer used to poison Mr. Kamata's drink, but...
Nonetheless,
It's clear one of you is the killer!
You probably figured it out too, didn't you?
The person who poisoned the drink is more than likely, that person...
No...!
Don't do it!
You're not supposed to be out front
And in the spotlight
That's not allowed...
Don't you understand that...?
PERILOUS RETURN-THE BLACK KNIGHT