Just as flowing water has no form,
and the breeze is invisible,
deductions take all shapes and styles
in each and every case to be solved.
It's what you've all been waiting for,
he makes his appearance
after a long absence!
He sees through the one & only truth.
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
While we were exploring the cave,
we came upon a gang of bank robbers
and I ended up getting shot
Ran's blood was used for the transfusion
which luckily saved my life.
This makes me decide to tell Ran
about everything....
but then Ai points a gun at me...
I came here to make things clear to you...
She'll certainly be one of
those the organization gets rid of
You have 3 choices
The first is leave things as is, don't tell
her any thing & keep your distance
Second, you cast your fates to the wind &
tell her everything
Or your third choice is.....
Later, at Teitan High School
on the day of their school fest,
during the play in the gymnasium,
a murder is committed right
among the audience!
PERILOUS RETURN-THE
BLACK KNIGHT
It's still not clear what trick
the killer used to poison
Mr. Kamata's drink, but...
nonetheless,
it's clear one of you is the killer!!
Isn't that right, Inspector?
Uh, well....
Inspector!
We found unopened tubs of milk &
gum syrup in Mr. Kamata's pocket!
Unopened?!Which could only mean....
Listen, did Mr. Kamata
usually drink his iced coffee black?
No, I'm pretty sure he always used
the milk & gum syrup....
Right?
Yeah, I'm sure he did too
Then why were both unopened!
His drink....
?
There was cola in his cup...
not iced coffee...
Eh?
I thought that he'd come to the
concession to change it if I did that...
I thought he might come to ask me why
I broke off our engagement....
You were engaged?!
Yes...
we intended to get married
after I graduated
...but I started to feel insecure and
I called him last week to break it off...
I've gone to the hospital
but he refused to see me...
Oh, so that's why....
there was cola in mine too...
I almost put this milk & gum syrup in
it, you know...
I'm very sorry...
Well, let's take all their
drinks & the milk & gum
syrup down to the lab &
have it analyzed,
we'll continue this conversation later
Yessir!
Inspector....From the looks of things,
you can't overlook “that" either...
What do you mean?
Suicide!
He must've taken quite a shock being
dumped by a girl 10 years younger
than him,& he might've already
been thinking of suicide
when he runs into her here.
So he decides to kill himself right in her
presence, just out of spite....
And if things worked out right,
she'd become the prime suspect....
I just remembered,
wasn't Kohei looking around
for something on his car's dashboard?
Yeah, he said he was
looking for his driver's license....
Huh? Did you remember something?
No, we all came here in Kohei's car
but I thought he acted a little strange....
Like feeling around his dashboard....
Takagi, have someone take you to
his car & check it out,
we might find something
Yessir!
This way
Hey Kudo....
I guess you've figured it out too,
idn't you?
The person who poisoned the drink was
more than likely, that person...
the lid was off the victim's cup the whole
time and there was cola inside it,
not the iced coffee...
And the strange things that person said...
The trick's been completely blown!!
All we need is the evidence, then our
theory's perfect...
hey...hey...
Hey, wait! Come back!
Heiji and that kid are such good friends...
...Uh huh....
Good grief, what a bummer...
We get caught in a weird case and
the play is called off
and now it's starting to rain
It's put a damper on everything...
isn't that right, sir
There's nothing we can do,
not when something like this happens....
There'll always be a next time, let's just
call it quits for today...
...If that's what you decided...
thank you for your co-operation
Inspector!!
Huh? Oh Takagi
what is it?
We found these on the dashboard of
he victim's car.....
I'm pretty sure it's potassium cyanide....
Good work!
The forensic lab just called me
there was no trace of poison
in any of the drinks...
Th, then you mean....
Yes!
We'll close this as a case of suicide....
Just a minute Inspector!!
Huh?!
!?
This is no suicide...
It's a simple and elementary....
murder!!
No...don't do it...
you're not supposed to stand up front
and be in the spotlight, it's not allowed
don't you understand that?!
...That's right...Mr. Kamata
was poisoned....
right before this stage draped
in darkness...
the killer knew the victim's habit
& used it to commit the murder...
and I am certain the killer still has
the weapon
like the risk I take, the crime was also
bold & brazen....
...that is, if I am correct....
....Wh, who are you...?
It's been a long time,Inspector Megure...
...It's me, Shinichi Kudo...
...Shinichi?....
I don't believe it...it can't be...
Because Shinichi's...
Shinichi's....
This guy's Kudo....and so is that guy....
What's going on here?
...He's such a man....
Yes! That's our hero!!
Eeek, it's Shinichi Kudo!!
Show them what you can do Kudo!!
Kudo! Kudo! Kudo! Kudo!
Shh! Quiet please...
you can celebrate after we
bring the curtain down on this murder...
Shh!
Geez...he's as dramatic as always...
Shinichi...
Are you really Shinichi??
Huh?Silly...
you must still be sleepy....
I have something important
to tell later so don't you go running off...
Eh?
And Hattori...
Uh, yeah....
Do you have any 10 yen coins on you?
Huh? Sure, I think I've got a couple but
what are you going to do with them....!?
Ah ha....I get it now...
OK, can I borrow one for awhile?
Sure thing but it'll cost you....
You'll get it back soon....
Ku, Kudo...you've been away a long time
and I appreciate you trying to help but
There was no trace of poison from the
victim's cup nor his 3 friends'.
On top of that,
the victim drank most of his drink
....no matter how you look at it,
Yes, at first glance it looks like suicide,
and Mr. Kamata took the poison
himself but,
if you use a certain something, murder is
also a possibility.....
A certain something?
That's right....it's a very basic trick....
Using ice....
Did you say ice!?
The poison used was potassium cyanide,
which doesn't dissolve easily
in iced water...
a tiny hole was made in the ice
and the poison was
poured in the center then
a thin piece of ice was
used to plug the hole and refrozen
The ice cube was then put
into the victim's cup,
by the time the ice melts
and the poison seeps out,
Mr. Kamata would have
finished up his drink...
But then there should be some trace of
poison left in his cup....
The lid on the victim's cup...it was off,
wasn't it?
Do you know why?
After he drank the poison, it probably
fell off
when he crushed the cup because of
the pain....
You fool, then why wasn't
the cup crushed!
There's only one reason someone
would take the lid off their cup
after finishing their drink...
The victim didn't drink the poison,
he ATE it!
He ate it?
I get it!!
Inspector, you usually
eat the ice in your drink too!
I see...
someone who knew the victim had this
habit could have poisoned him
and nothing would be left in the cup...
And? So who put the poisoned ice in
the victim's cup?
Mr. Mitani who just handed him the drink
and Miss Noda wouldn't have had
the chance...
Miss Ninakawa who sold the drinks
had the opportunity....
!!
But she deliberately put cola into
the iced coffee he ordered...
She wouldn't poison his drink knowing
he might he ordered...
Besides, there was another person
who ordered iced coffee
so she wouldn't know who would get
poisoned...
There was only a 50% chance of
success, the risks were too high...
So you mean...
That's right...
the person who poisoned Mr. Kamata,
is the one who bought the drinks then
delivered them to everyone...
Mai Kokami
...you're the only one
who could have done it...
Ma, Mai....
You went to the concession
to buy the drinks.
so you had the opportunity
to open the drinks and
drop the poisoned ice cube in pretending
to put milk and gum syrup in it...
Just a minute.
Mai didn't put milk or gum syrup in those
drinks!
She's right, you found the unopened tubs
in Kamata's pocket, didn't you!!
That's because when she dropped
the ice in, she realized it was cola...
if she put the milk and gum syrup in it,
there was the chance
Mr. Kamata wouldn't drink it...
The reason she brought
you the drinks just before
the play was about to begin was so
that he wouldn't bother to go change it....
after all, even if he realized
it wasn't iced coffee,
once the room got dark,
it would be too much of
a bother to get up and
go to the concession....
But how did she go around carrying
the poisoned ice cube?
Yes, the answer to that is this item
that I found
in the trash can outside the restroom
when Officer Takagi left the room....
It's this vinyl pouch....
Get that to the lab, quick!
Yessir!
If you put the poisoned ice cube in here
with a tiny piece of dry ice,
it won't melt for quite a while....
Miss Kokami....
after you handed the poisoned drink
along with the others, you went
to the restroom and
flushed the dry ice down then threw
the pouch in the trash can.....
Well.....have I made a mistake?
......Mai.....
.....My hats off to you Shinichi Kudo
You're as good as I heard......
But have you forgotten?
I also had iced coffee and
I handed it to Mitani
along with the others.
I had no idea which cup
he'd give Kohei, so how
could I poison his drink?
Or are you saying I took a 50/50
chance that he'd get it
and if that's the case, then Ayako also....
No, you were covered 100%.....
Eh?
That's because you
put poisoned ice cubes in both cups....
Th, that's ridiculous! She drank all the
contents of her cup!
That can be accomplished if she
gulped it all down before the ice melted....
But there'd still be traces of
poison in her cup...
and if she tried to get the poisoned
ice cube out,
the others around her would notice.....
Like Mr. Kamata, what if
she put the ice cube in
her mouth pretending to eat it?
What!?
That's right...
then without anyone noticing,
she spit the ice out in her hand & hid in
a certain place...
And I think that
Putting poisoned ice in your mouth
is extremely
dangerous but if the poison is
in the very center,
it is possible in getting the deed done
B, but are you sure it was in her hood....
It's not a lie....
Take a look at this! All the tarnish is
gone from the coin, see how shiny it is
It's proof that it came in contact with
potassium cyanide and oxidation
reduction reaction has occurred!
Oh, I see....
How did you know she put the poisoned
ice cube in the hood?
Oh, well that's.....
Because of the rain....
Eh?
It was raining but
when I went outside to show
the officer to Kohei's car,
I didn't cover my head with the hood,
that's what made you suspicious,
isn't that right?
Yes, I figured you the ice melted,
and you didn't want
the poison all over your head....
So he's right,
Mai, you killed Kamata?
Yes, that's right...
I poisoned him....
He was a disgrace as a doctor!
What do you mean by that?
I'm sure you all know about it.
I'm talking about the doctrine
he was going to present
at the next conference...
Yes....
But there was an unusual patient
in our hospital
who would have overruled his theory...
unfortunately, his condition
turned for the worse and he died...
almost as if an exception to the theory
never existed!
Are you saying Kohei....
Yes...
He gave that patient
the wrong medication,
and made his symptoms worse,
killing him....
Just to protect
his meaningless research...
Phew...
He told me himself last week,
Ayako broke off their engagemen
and he was upset
so I went drinking with him
and he got very drunk....
....He didn't even regret what he did,
instead, he disgustingly blurted out that...
He thought this world was unfair
when a man
who held people's lives in his hands
should be upset over being jilted
by a young girl in her teens
...I was horrified...
Th...that's terrible...
That's why I showed him...
I showed him it was even more unfair
for a man like him to be a doctor...
Then the bottle of poison
in Mr. Kamata's car...
Yes, I put it there....
I hid his driver's license
so he would look for it
and arouse suspicions...
You were lucky weren't you,
Mr. Detective?
That it rained.....
If it didn't,
you wouldn't have any proof I did it
No...
even if it weren't for your hood,
I would have asked the police
to check your clothes anyway.
That's because I already had you pegged
as the killer when I saw that
you had the unopened tubs of milk
and gum syrup in your pocket
Eh?
When you returned from the restroom,
you said the play had already started,
isn't that right?
When the play began
and the lights went out,
you wouldn't have been able to tell
if your drink was cola or iced coffee
even if you took the lid off...
That's what convinced me.
It told me that
you had already opened the lids
and seen that it wasn't iced coffee...
.....
Heh heh...
I give up...
As a fellow alumni of this high school,
I am proud of your brilliance...
We can continue this at the station...
All right...
Mr. Mitani, Miss Noda
and Miss Ninakawa,
I'll need your statements too, could
you please come with me to the station
Yes...
You know Heiji, today,
you seemed to be a mere
assistant to a great magician...
Well that can't be helped.
We're in Tokyo,
I've got to make Kudo look good....
Well, well, well,
you're as dependable as always!!
Oh, please......
But he's not still in
the same league as me...
How about it?
Do you want to sit in on the interrogation,
for old times sake?
No, I'll pass this time....
I have something I need to do...
I see...
And I'd like for you to not let it get out
that I was involved in this case....
That's fine with me, but
you're certainly keeping
a low profile these days....
Let's go, Mohri
Yessir, Inspector!
Hey Kudo....
why didn't you want to watch
the interrogation?
Sorry....
A trick is merely a puzzle
thought up by someone...
all you have to do is
give it enough thought andeventually,
you'll come up with a logical explanation,
but...
!!
!? ....Hey, what's wrong!?
It's very frustrating,
no matter how many times it's explained,
I just don't know the rationalization
behind one human being killing another...
...I can understand the emotion
but I can't accept the action...
it's just beyond me...
ugh....
(Thud!)
Oh no...it's happening already
I thought I'd changed back into
my old self...
I thought it was going to work out...
Here
...This is a test product,
it's a specially mixed antidote
for the Apotoxin 4869...
...What're you going to do?
...It could kill you
if you take it, you know...
Are you willing to give it a try?
Shinichi!?
What's wrong, Shinichi!?
Are you alright?
Does it hurt?
....Ran....
..It's all over
...if I turn back into Conan here...
ugh...
Ran will find out about me...
Oh, ugh...my body...
I can't...move...
(Thud...)
Kudo!
....Shinichi...?
Shinichi?
Shinichi!!!
Uh...
what's this smell....
the school infirmary?
...oh I remember...
I, was carried in here...
It's Ran...
she looks pale...
I can't blame her...
she just saw a person
shrink right in front of her eyes...
Eh?
What's this?
Hey Kudo!!
So you're awake!!
I'm so glad you're awake!!
Don't worry us like that again!
What happened?
Ah....
There he is, it's Shinichi!
I wasn't dreaming!! Hehehe...
he's really come back!!
I hate to say this,
but this doesn't look like
it was a hold-up
Eh!?
Inspector Megure...
Ku, Kudo!!!
PERILOUS RETURN
-SHINICHI IS BACK