Just as flowing water has no form,
and the breeze is invisible,
deductions take all shapes & styles
in each and every case to be solved.
No one knows what will happen with this
couple nor the outcome of this crime
Words are not necessary for
feelings are conveyed.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with
the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left
unsolved with Detective Conan.
While exploring a limestone cave
I am shot by a gang of bank robbers
a blood transfusion from Ran
saves my life.
I have made up my mind
to tell Ran everything
But Ai points a gun at me.....
then, on the day of
Teitan High School's school fest,
during the play in the gymnasium
a murder takes place in the audience!!
Ai mixes up a potion
that restores me to my old body
and I solve the case immediately.
Thankfully, Ran's suspicions
are dispelled.
The next day, I ask Ran
to have dinner with me at the roof top
restaurant in the Beika Center Building
but once again,
we are caught up in another murder case.
I leave Ran waiting
as I go off to investigate
I quickly deduce who the killer is....
I was right, he killed Mr.
Tatsumi after all...
it was Mr. Oba, no doubt about it!!
PERILOUS RETURN-PLACE WHERE
VOWS ARE MADE
I wonder what it is...
what does Shinichi want to tell me...
what could it be...
A proposal, he's going to propose!
Eh?!
I don't believe it, it can't be...
I mean, we're still in high school....
Sigh...
I wish Shinichi'd hurry and come back...
...I'm absolutely sure Mr. Oba
shot Mr. Tatsumi
but I have two unanswered questions...
I can't explain the strange actions
Mr. Tatsumi took in the elevator, and
the lack of powder burns...
seeing how confident he acted, I'm sure
he did something so we wouldn't find any
powder burns on him...
I know, maybe that's how he did it.
Mr. Oba was wearing an animal
costume at the party, wasn't he?
Yes, that's right.
He could have changed his clothes!
Are you sure about that?
Yes,
tonight's party was in part, to celebrate
the unveiling of our new company mascot,
and the character was on stage all night
We were shocked when we found out
Mr. Oba was inside it!
We really were....
I see...
so if he had another set of the
same outfit,
he could have switched it with
the one with the powder burns on them....
But he couldn't have!
Before he changed into his costume,
Mr. Oba handed us his jacket & slacks....
But....
He is suspicious, isn't he....
You shouldn't talk like that!
He worked really hard to make us laugh!
Are you talking about that
character winking?
Sure, it was funny at first...
but that's the only thing he did,
after a while, it got pretty stale...
Excuse me.
If you don't mind, may I take a look at
that costume?
Eh? Why am I perspiring so much....
The design's very surreal, isn't it...
Isn't it adorable?
Who was in charge of the party?
Mr. Oba!
I've got it...
so that's how he did it...
So did you figure it out?
Yes, most of it...
Isn't it getting hot in here?
You must be kidding! It's freezing,
the cooler's on so high...
Eh? Why am I perspiring so much....
Ugh...this..can't ..be..happening...
I don't believe it...
no, not now....
not here...
not on this important day....
darn it all...
Huh?!
Hey, are you alright?
Kudo?
Inspector Megure! We
found no traces of powder on Mr. Oba!
I see...
Then was it a hold up after all....
Alright then, let's ask around if
anyone suspicious was seen going in
or out this building
while the party was in progress!
Wait...
there's no need for that...
Eh?
The killer is already among us...
So, shall we step up to the stage,
where the truth awaits us...
Hey! What's the meaning of this?!
You already checked me out!
They didn't find anything!
So why're you treating me
like i'm the killer!!
Now, just calm down....
You tell them.
Tell them I couldn't have done it!
Yes, I'll swear to it!!
Mr. Oba was with me the whole time!
Naturally, I wasn't with him when he
changed into his costume,
but the dressing room was locked...
besides, there were other people with him
so he couldn't have
slipped out or switched places
with someone else.
Or are you implying that I'm lying?
No...
we don't suspect you of anything...
You believe you were with Mr. Oba
through it all...
even while the murder
was taking place....
Just a second, are you saying I helped
him kill my father?!
No, I'm saying that the murder took
place near you,
it's just that you didn't notice it...
because at the time it happened,
you had your
eyes closed & your back was
to the elevator
that's because you were
kissing Mr. Oba....
They were kissing?!
Kissing...you mean...
That's right...
He cradled your head in his left arm like
this, covering your ears and
while he was kissing you,
he pushed the elevator call button
And as soon as the door opened,
your father was shot...
by Mr. Oba...
But even if he covered her
ears & used a silencer on the gun,
wouldn't she have heard something
when the body fell to the ground?
Yes...
I believe she would have
heard a faint sound
that's why Mr. Oba had the poppers
go off just before the party.
When he moved his arm away
from her ears,
just as the loud party
poppers were going off,
the poppers would have
made her forget about
the faint sound
she had heard previously....
Of course,
he would have made sure the elevator
door closed before he lowered his arm
Humph!
That's a very interesting story
But there's one big hole in your theory,
Mr. Tatsumi left
because he wasn't feeling well
& he got into the elevator going down
so why was he still inside?
You aren't saying that he was waiting
inside for me to kill him, are you?
That's exactly what happened...
he never left,
he was waiting inside all the time.
Waiting for you to come
wearing your costume!
You probably told him
something like this...
"Pretend you've gone home &
change in here,
then you can return to the party &
surprise everyone..."
right?
So what you're saying is, the victim's
clothes were scattered because....
Yes...he was getting ready to change
Now I understand,
the elevator bell won't ring
when the elevator's on hold...
On top of that,
this is the company elevator...
Mr. Oba planned this knowing no one
would use it until the party ended...
What about the powder burns?
If I was the killer, you would have found
traces of it on me
I understand you winked
I beg your pardon?
One of the girls told me,
she said that while you were in
the costume, you kept winking...
that made a light go off in my head.
You weren't winking to make them laugh...
You hid something inside the eye
that's why it wasn't working properly,
isn't that so...
you already wore gloves
on your right hand
& you put a plastic bag over the gun,
closing it with rubber bands,
then you put it in the inside pocket of
your jacket, making it portable
and when the gun is fired,
the powder wouldn't get onto your clothes
& the empty casings
wouldn't fall on the floor
But she was close to him,
wouldn't she have noticed
him taking the gun out....
Of course,
it would have been obvious if things
were like it is now, but...
Please turn off the lights
if the lights were dim like this....
the risk becomes far less...
and if he gives her a pendant,
while they're here
she'll lead him to the restroom
where she'll put the pendant on
& then he can toss the gun down
the dust chute near the rest room
without leaving her side
When Mr. Oba covered
her ears & touched her earring,
his left hand wasn't gloved...
that means, we should find
some very nice prints
from your fingers on this plastic bag!!
Humph, my fingerprints
on the plastic bag?
Of course you'll find them...
after all, I did touch that bag...
along with the other people
who helped me out of the costume!
What?!
Wh, what does that mean?!
Isn't that right, guys?
Yes,
he's right, one of eyes wouldn't close
so I opened it up & that bag was inside...
Mr. Oba said it might be
some important part of the costume
so we should leave it inside....
Hmm...
This is my theory...
Someone who held a grudge against me,
went down to the next floor
& shot Mr. Tatsumi while
Sakurako & I were at the restroom
and then to frame me for it,
the killer put that inside the costume...
it would have been easy since the costume
was in the dressing room until I put it on,
I think my theory sounds
more realistic than your accusation
that I shot him while engaged in
a kiss is absolutely silly....
Hey, Kudo.....
Well mister fresh out of school detective,
do you have anything to say?
You don't seem so cocky now...
what's the matter, run out of ideas?
It doesn't matter,
for every one of your questions
I have a reasonable answer.....
Well mister fresh out of school detective,
do you have anything to say?
You don't seem so cocky now...
What's the matter, run out of ideas?
Pink pearl
....Mr. Oba...
when you....gave her the pendant,
you said this to her, didn't you?
"It's a pink pearl pendant to go with
the earrings you're wearing tonight"....
Yes, but what does that
have to do with anything?
How did you know that?
How did you know
she had pink pearl earrings on?
Humph...
boy you're really grasping for straws
aren't you...asking about that...
It's so obvious.....
She told me
she bought those tonight
on the spur of the moment
just before meeting you here tonight...
which means, you couldn't have seen
them until you saw her here...
And in this spot with
the lights down so low,
those pink pearls look like
mere dark balls....
There's no way you could tell
they were pink....
That's right.........not unless....
you opened this door of light
while you were kissing her!!
Mr. Oba....you couldn't have...
Well, Mr. Oba, why don't you answer me?
Tell us why you opened the door
when you did...
you're asking me why?
the answer is simple...
...Because I made a promise to my father...
that I would avenge his death...
Avenge your father's death?
Yes...my father also
a rather big game company....
that was until 20 years ago
when your father suggested
their companies merge...
he suggested they open an office
in the Beika Center Building...
But he wasn't planning a merger,
he was planning a take over...
all the game creating know-how
my father constructed, was stolen
and all the employees in my father's
company were laid off, one by one...
...and my father...
who was vice president in name only,
was so full of despair, he killed himself...
But papa took such good care of you...
Yes...I think it was because he felt guilty,
that's why he kept promoting me.
Me, the man who planned to kill him,
marry his daughter &
take over the company!
Th, that's so....
It was all a game...
the story line was, the hero uses the
powers of evil to overthrow the demon...
but who would have thought
it would end the same way....
What do you mean by that...?
My father was murdered,
but it was made to look like a suicide...
he was killed 20 years ago, right here
in this very building by Mr. Tatsumi....
but someone saw through the crime....
it was a young man like you,
he figured it out just like you did tonight...
I guess when you borrow the powers
of evil, you have to pay the price...
Yes, that's it! I remember it now!
It was Yusaku!
Yusaku Kudo butted in when we were
investigating the case & he solved it for us!
Oh, you're talking about
that mystery writer....
Which means the son solved the crime
which arose from the crime
committed 20 years ago which
the father solved...
Isn't that ironic...
don't you think, Kudo...huh?
Kudo?
Please...I need a little more time...
She...she's waiting for me...
I can't turn into Conan again now...
Ha, Haibara?!
You...
why....why....
24 minutes over time...
I guess that's the
maximum tolerance level...
I'll consider this a loan...
Conan?
Hey, did you hear?
The murder's been solved!
Eh? Is that true?
You're finally going to get to see him,
aren't you!
See your boyfriend!
For goodness sakes..
he's not my boyfriend...
Eh?
C, Conan?!
Here, take this charge card!
Shinichi told me to give it to you...
Uncle Kogoro told me to come
check up on you & I ran into Shinichi!
Is dad here too?
Yes...he's waiting
in the parking lot downstairs...
Boy, what's taking that kid so long!!
1 whole hour's gone by already!!
I can't wait anymore,
I'm going to go have a look myself...
No, I better just wait....
That wouldn't be adult of me....
Rats....
So where is Shinichi?
Well, uh....
It's like this, he got a call on his cellular,
it was about a case
he worked on recently,
something terrible happened
and so he ran off...
...I see...
Shinichi's stupid, isn't he,
leaving you all alone like this....
...So he left me behind again.....
...uh...you know...
Shinichi told me that....
No! Stop it!!
I don't want to hear it!!
...I don't want to hear it...
no more excuses.....
...Shinichi told me that...
...one day
one day, for sure
he'll come back, even if it kills him...
that's why....
...that's why...
He wants you to wait for him...
that's what he said...
...That's why...that's why...
you're so silly Conan....
you don't have to put on
such a serious face...
It's all that eager beaver detective's fault,
he drops everything & runs off
at the mere mention of a case!
Eager beaver detective.......
Oh, I almost forgot!
Conan, would you like some dessert?
Yeah, sure....
Excuse me, dessert menu please...
Here you go
Of all the...
he has some nerve, asking me
to wait for me, he says!
Who does he think I am, his mother?!
Th...that makes 5 desserts....
But I'd still like to know
what he wanted to talk to me about...
Conan, aren't you curious too?
Eh? Uh... no, not really....
Oh well, since he ran off without telling me,
I guess it wasn't very important...
I just don't understand why he picked
such an expensive restaurant
What a fool...making such a big deal
when he had nothing important to say!
I don't know how to tell her.
I picked this place for good luck
since dad proposed to mom here...
What's taking so long~~~~~!!
Here, look!
The pins on the drum of
this music box are broken...
It looks like it they were
deliberately twisted & broken off
Who's there!!
Haruna, is that you?
What!?
The Entrusted Music Box-Part I