There's no shape to flowing water.
There's no figure to flowing winds.
No matter what the case, the deductions are free.
The melody lingering in her heart,
Brought upon a strange investigation.
Seeing through the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child but the brains of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan.
I, who stumbled onto a case and was wounded,
Managed to recover thanks to Ran donating her blood.
Ran knew about my true identity.
So, with the antidote Haibara made,
I returned to Shin'ichi.
And with Haibara disguised as Conan,
Ran's suspicions had disappeared, but...
Please, let it subside again...
She's... she's waiting for me!
I... can't return to Conan yet...
Ha-Haibara... you... why...?
24 minutes over.
I guess this is within the permitted range.
I'll return this to you, Edogawa-kun.
The Poignant Music Box
(Part One)
The Poignant Music Box. Part 1.
What?
Apotoxin 4869's antidote.
You still have it, right?
Hand it over.
No.
I won't say never, but I can't give it to a deducting
maniac who can't hold himself back.
Sorry, I'll try to stop myself from now on.
I told you, that was only a prototype.
You can't use an underdeveloped medicine for extended periods.
Next time, there is a real possibility that you may die.
I guess with only Paikaru's ingredients,
a full antidote can't be made.
Yeah, at least not without the drug's data.
Well, just be thankful that your identity wasn't revealed.
Dammit!
If I knew something like this would happen,
I would've told Ran what I wanted to say.
Professor!
Conan-kun, are you sure you're not going to come?
It's Haido Avenue's indoor pool.
There are really cool waves.
Sorry, I still have a small cold.
Later then!
Haibara-san's in a good mood.
Something good must've happened.
They served curry at school today, so...
She's not like you, Genta-kun.
You were pretty excited about it, too.
Mouri Detective Agency
I guess this means I have to restart from here.
Ah man, it's already summer.
Note: Spring symbolizes a period of joy and relief from one's troubles.
It doesn't look like spring will come anytime soon.
Translation Note: "Haru yo Koi" means "Come Dear Spring."
This song is... "Haru yo Koi?"
I'm home.
Conan-kun, welcome home.
Oh, you have a son as well?
Oh, he's just a little freeloader that we're looking after.
What's with this music box?
Some areas seem to have notes missing.
This has nothing to do with you.
How old are you young man?
I'm around 7, I guess.
He's only in first grade,
But he always notices little things,
That become the hints to solving cases.
Eh? A little detective.
Oh, should we tell Conan-kun, too?
Maybe he'll find something that would lead us
to the person Haruna-san is looking for.
The person she's looking for?
You see...
Bell buddies are friends that contact each other via pagers,
kind of like instant messenger programs now.
Bell buddy?
The person you're looking for is a bell buddy?
Yes, that's right.
His name is Shuugo-san.
Yuuki Haruna (21)
Fine Arts Major University Student
I met him 3 years ago,
When I became a fine arts student at the university.
I felt lonely because I couldn't make any friends.
So, I just randomly entered a number
on my pocket bell and sent it.
"My name is Haruna,
Would you like to be my friend?" I wrote.
Then to my surprise,
I got a response saying "My first love
was also Haruna. Nice to meet you."
Ever since, we've been bell buddies.
He was like a kind uncle who would listen to your every concern.
If you sent "I wish to see you," in your
pocket bell, then wouldn't he...?
That's not possible.
I have his pocket bell.
It was last Christmas.
It was getting harder and harder to pay
tuition while I was attending school.
I thought about seeing him before I quit school and went home.
I decided to arrange a meeting with Shuugo-san
in front of Shibuya station.
But no matter how long I waited, I didn't see anyone like him.
When I was about to give up...
When I looked inside, this music box
was in it along with his pocket bell.
But how did you know that was his pocket bell?
There was a message on that pocket bell.
"This is a very valuable music box."
"Use it to pay for your schooling and don't
give up on your dreams, Haruna-san."
I can't accept such valuable merchandise.
I thought maybe if I got the music box examined,
I might be able to find its owner and return it to him.
So, I took it to an antique shop.
But the person at the store only said
it was a broken, old, music box.
Also, weird messages have been sent to my pocket bell lately.
Weird messages?
"I have something to ask you."
"Come to the location I tell you now, alone."
Did you go?
No, it was different from the messages
I received from Shuugo-san.
I got scared, so I didn't go.
Then, other messages were sent later that night.
It said "Cat Burglar!" more than 10 times.
Over 10 times?
"Cat Burglar?" Do you have any ideas as to why?
No. I want to ask what the person's intentions
are, but I have no way to reach them.
I thought it might have something to
do with Shuugo-san, so I came here.
And that message is still coming?
No, it continued for some time, but it has stopped now.
Then that means our only lead is this music box.
I don't know what we can get from a music
box that is missing a few notes.
I don't think so.
Look at the broken pins on the drum of the music box.
It doesn't look like they were old and broke off on their own,
But rather they were forcefully removed.
It's true!
Maybe it's some sort of message!
Yeah, the music is "Come, Dear Spring," and the missing
notes are near the end, "Ra, Do, and Ra."
Radora?
It's not a monster you know.
Do you know the lyrics to the missing notes?
The lyrics are "onnmo e-he detai to matte iru," so...
The missing ones are "Mo "De" and "Ru".
Mo De Ru... Model!
The person who had that was a model!
Alright, now that we know that, we can
search the model companies for...
You don't have to.
Wouldn't it be faster if we just go meet the person?
Idiot, we can't do that, so we're...
You know Shuugo-san's pocket bell number, right?
All you have to do is tell officer Takagi the situation.
Then ask him to ask the pocket bell company,
and you'll at least find out his address.
Way to go, Conan-kun!
We found out the address and the phone number!
You might have more potential than Shin'ichi.
Well, it was because of Officer Takagi that we got them.
That was just a misuse of authority.
By the way, Haruna-san, are you sure
they said we can go to their house?
Yes, even though the one who answered
the phone wasn't Shuugo-san.
It seems that everyone in his family
knew that he was into pocket bell.
When I told them that I wish to return
his pocket bell and music box,
They replied, "Please come!"
It must be exciting to find out who Shuugo-san is.
Yes.
Excuse me, I'm Haruna.
Yes, please come in.
Ogata Kazuko (50)
Female Head of the Ogata Family
You weren't coming alone?
Uhh, we're just tagging along... I guess...
Well, we can talk about that later, mother.
Shirou.
The rumored Haruna-san has finally arrived.
Ogata Shirou (22)
Second Son of the Ogata Family
Let's have her rest in the living room.
She was, after all, the pillar of Grandpa's heart.
Grandpa?
Yeah, I guess we should put up some incense.
I-Incense...?
No way...
He passed away?
Yes, he died at the end of last year.
Th-That can't be...
By any chance, was Shuugo-san a model?
Eh?
Guess not...
What about this music box you say you received from my father?
Oh, it's right here.
I heard it was a very valuable music
box, so I would like to return it.
Thanks a lot.
Huh...? This music...
Come, Dear Spring.
Dear.
Note: The Japanese koto is a large string instrument, about six feet long. It is traditionally played on the floor. And it originated in China but, came to Japan in the 7th-8th century.
It's the music that Mother always played on Koto.
Ogata Tsuneo (53)
Kazuko's Husband
Would Mother be the woman in that picture?
Yes, the woman next to Father is my mother,
Haruna, who died 3 years ago.
Haruna!
Three years ago?
Grandpa probably thought of you as Grandma.
He was very happy, saying: "Haruna came back!"
But, excuse my rudeness,
To have a pocket bell at that age, he really is a unique individual.
No, ever since Mother died, Father began
to take walks late into the night.
So we gave him one in case of emergency.
By the way, was there anything inside the music box?
Like what?
You know... like... maybe a...
Stamp, right?
A stamp from a group of four, worth about 200 million yen.
Ogata Minoru (28)
First Son of the Ogata Family
Nii-san!
The reason you came all the way to this house,
Was because the old man told you where
it is and you came to find it, right?
I-I wasn't...
Don't worry, I'll reveal your true intentions.
Please, get very comfortable, Haruna-san.
Geez, please don't take it personally.
His company isn't doing very well, so he's in a bad mood.
Since you came all this way, please stay for dinner.
We would like to hear more about you and Father's memories.
What is this about a 200 million yen stamp?
And what do the missing notes in that music box mean?
What in the world...?
Question after question after question during dinner.
Poor Haruna-san.
To make it worse, it started to rain and it isn't letting up.
But isn't it strange?
Yeah, other than this family's second born,
Shirou-san, everyone else is a bit weird.
That's not what I mean.
Look at the back of Shuugo-san's memoir stone.
The day he died was December 6th.
There's nothing strange about that.
Haruna-san said she received the music box last Christmas.
That means if we believe what Haruna-san says,
Then the one who gave Haruna-san the music box
was someone other than Shuugo-san, right?
Let's forget about the bad things and get some sleep.
Yeah...
Hey, what's wrong, Ran?
An old man with a cane just went left down that hallway.
Who's there!
There's no one here...
But I saw it go left!
The only room to the left is ours...
What's wrong?
Did something happen?
Oh, my daughter says she saw a weird shadow...
Shadow?
I think it was just their imagination.
That's not it!
Come to think of it, the guest that slept
over last time said the same thing.
They thought someone went by their pillows.
Something like this happened before?
Yeah...
But there should only be us in this house.
Where's Nii-san?
Isn't he taking a bath?
Hey hey, now what?
It sounded like a wire on an instrument was cut...
Maybe it's the room with Mother's koto.
Let's take a look.
H-Hey, wait up!
Mi... Minoru...
Nii-san!
Wake up, Minoru!
Minoru... hey Minoru!
Wake up, Nii-san!
Th-That can't be...
What's wrong, Haruna-san?
Haruna-san?
This message...
I've been waiting for you, Haruna.
What?
Then could that shadow of an old man,
And this message be from the deceased Shuugo-san?
You idiot!
Once a person dies, he can't do anything!
If you have time to say stupid things, go call the police.
Th-This might be a murder...!
Hey, hold it.
Don't consider me dead yet.
Minoru.
What happened, Nii-san?
How should I know?
I got hit on the head with something hard all of a sudden.
By something hard, you mean that koto?
Probably.
That's the koto that Grandma treasured!
It wasn't... Haruna-san.
It was you who hit me, wasn't it?
But I...
No!
Because when the loud sound came,
Everyone was together in Ran-neechan's room.
Right?
That's right.
Then who the heck...?
Who? Didn't you see the culprit's face?
What?
Look, your wound is on your forehead.
That means that you were hit from the front, right?
It was too dark to see any faces.
Then that means when you were hit, this room was dark?
Yeah, by the time I noticed anything strange, it was too late.
But isn't that strange?
What's so strange about it?
Onii-san, what were you doing alone in a dark room?
Well?
I was...
Nii-san?
Minoru?
You idiot.
Minoru-san probably felt a presence in this room and came in.
Then, when he was about to turn the light
on, someone hit him with the koto.
Right, Minoru-san?
Yeah...
Then what about the message sent
to Haruna-san's pocket bell, Dad?
Oh, that was probably Haruna-san's friend.
Friend?
Haruna-san probably had an appointment with a friend tonight.
But she had completely forgotten about it and came here.
Meaning, that message was...
From her friend who wanted to say "I've
been waiting for you for a while."
Am I wrong, Haruna-san?
No, I don't remember making a promise like that.
Well, a lot has happened today, so I suppose anyone would forget.
Then what about the shadow of the old man I saw?
That was...
Maybe it was the person who attacked my brother.
But for an elderly man with a cane to hit a person
with that heavy koto and knock him out...
Exactly, even if that elderly man existed,
It is probably impossible for him to knock out Minoru-san.
Ran says that elderly man disappeared just down the hall.
Even if he wanted to run into the room
in the back, Conan and I were there.
Then...
That elderly man was most likely...
Most likely?
Your imagination.
Like the old saying, "The true identity
of a ghost is just a dead tree."
Wait a second, I really did...
You thought you saw a ghost because
you're always so afraid of them.
Dad!
Either way, Madam, please call the police.
It looks like someone other than us was in this house.
Yes!
Was someone hiding here like Uncle said?
If so, what is that person's objective?
From the looks of things, it doesn't look
like it's been searched through.
That means it was a crime committed
specifically against Minoru-san.
But this isn't Minoru-san's room.
I have a good idea why Minoru-san was in this dark room.
But how and when did the culprit know that?
And the koto that was used as the weapon...
Was there a reason behind the culprit
using the koto as the weapon?
Damn it, there's so many things I still don't know.
The shadow of an old man that Ran saw.
Was that really just Ran's imagination?
And finally, one more thing.
That music box with the missing notes.
That music box must be hiding an important secret.
The location of the hidden object that the
people of this house are looking for.
The 200 million yen stamp that Shuugo-san had!
What's this sharp for?
Oh, that's the key signature.
Key signature?
No, I received the music box last Christmas.
That can't be, father died on December 6th last year.
B-But...
Was it the doings of a ghost?
Co-Conan-kun?
The Poignant Music Box
(Part Two)
Next Conan:
The Poignant Music Box (Part 2)
Next Conan's Hint!
Electric Fan.
Next time is my dreaded music tangle!
Secret of my heart!