There's no shape to flowing water.
There's no figure to flowing winds.
No matter what the case, the deductions are free.
A ghost, a pocket bell, stamps, and a music box.
All connect as one as the case is solved!
Seeing through the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child but the brains of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
We took Yuuki Haruna-san's request to return a
music box to a pocket bell friend she lost contact with,
And we came to Ogata Shuugo-san's house.
But Shuugo-san had already passed away.
That night, Ran witnessed the shadow of an old man.
Shuugo-san's grandson, Minoru-san, was attacked by someone.
And a mysterious message was sent to Haruna-san's pocket bell.
I've been waiting for you, Haruna.
The Poignant Music Box
(Part Two)
The Poignant Music Box (Part 2)
There's no trace of anyone sneaking in?
Yes, even though the ground is soft from the rain,
There were no footprints
anywhere that show signs of sneaking in.
Even if the person came in before the
rain, they would've left tracks when they left.
But there weren't any suspicious characters in the house.
The only thing that we thought was
odd was the back door being left open.
Back door?
Oh, the lock on it is broken and it opens by itself with the wind.
That back door is suspicious.
Would you like to check it out yourself?
Even if someone had used the back door,
There should be tracks left on the soft ground, right?
Yes, there aren't any...
If there were footprints here, then what Ran said about
the suspicious shadow wouldn't be just her imagination.
I told you, I really saw it!
Oops.
Could you move your vehicle a bit please?
Sorry, right away.
Anyway, let's summarize the
events then take another look around.
Yes...
Where did the young lady see the suspicious shadow?
Right here.
A shadow of an old man with a
cane went by swiftly in that direction.
Maybe he ran into that room in the back.
No, I was in that room, so that can't be the case.
But I really saw the shadow,
From inside this room.
I saw it as well.
Hey, whose room is on this side?
Oh, that room is for my wife and I.
When the young lady saw the
shadow, were you and your wife in this room?
No, my wife and I were in the kitchen with our son Shirou.
Note: Ita has 2 meanings, 1.Ouch & 2.There he is!
Ita!
You found the culprit?!
"Ouch!", not "There he is!"
I stepped on a hairpin on the tatami.
H-Hairpin?
Stop running around!
And the wounded Minoru-san wasn't in the kitchen at the time?
Yes, I thought Minoru was in the bath...
And what were you three doing in the kitchen?
We were getting yelled at by Shirou.
Saying that it was rude to question
Haruna-san, who finally came, like an interrogation.
Like an interrogation?
Oh, you see, I was a pocket bell buddy
with Shuugo-san, who had passed away,
And they asked a lot about the details of our chats.
Yeah, along with Nii-san, all three of
them, again and again like an interrogation.
I didn't mind.
We spoke of things like how because of
Shuugo-san's influence, I began to collect stamps.
I was able to talk about the memories.
I even asked if I could come again sometime.
So don't worry about it.
Come to think of it, Minoru-san said something about a stamp.
Something about a hand carved stamp worth 200 million yen.
Where is he currently?
Maybe those stamps have something to do with this case.
Oh, Minoru is in his room next door.
It disappeared?
Yeah, even the ones in Grandpa's collection,
those special hand carved stamps are gone.
For us who believed in those stamps and
had been buying them, it was a big deal.
Us?
Yeah, my parents know about this as well.
Excuse me.
Yes?
Is your room next door?
Yeah, that's right.
Then... What about that room back there?
That's Grandpa and Grandma's room.
Is that...?
Hey, boy!
Just as I thought.
It's the room Minoru-san was attacked by the koto in.
That means, the way the rooms are setup is like this.
I've got most of the tricks to this case now.
The only ones left are the shadow Ran saw,
And the music box Haruna-san received
from Shuugo-san with the missing notes.
I did write out the notes based on that music box.
But I don't have a clue to what it is.
Hey, isn't that the music for "Come, Dear Spring"?
What's up?
It's just my homework for music class.
Here, give it to me for a second, I'll draw it out for you.
W-Wait...
Let's see...
Geez...
Ran...
What is it?
N-Nothing.
Here, it's something like this.
She's good.
Hey, Ran-neechan.
What are these three sharps?
Oh, that's the key signature.
Key signature!
I get it!
If something happens, please give us a call again.
Thank you very much.
I guess we still don't know if it was a thief or a ghost.
Yeah...
Excuse me.
Did you see Conan-kun anywhere?
Oh, how simple.
I know everything now.
The ghost commotion that happened in this house,
The different pocket bell partner,
That mysterious music box's meaning,
And the location of the special collection that Shuugo-san hid.
All that's left is to put uncle Kogorou to sleep and...
You, every single time you're running around.
Come on, we're going home.
We're leaving? But I just realized something interesting.
Look at that thing over there.
What is "that thing"?
Move to the right a bit more.
To the right...
Dad?
I see, so it was like that.
Ran, bring everyone to this room.
R-Right!
Oh, before that, borrow a black
sheet of paper, some tape, and scissors.
Hey, you found the thief, right?
Thief? There wasn't anyone like that to begin with.
You're not going to say that it was
Father's ghost that did it, are you?
Of course not.
Everything that happened tonight was,
Planned by one of you.
What?
Although it seems like the ghost thing has happened before.
Before?
The music box Haruna-san received from Shuugo-san.
We've heard about that many times from her.
Two years ago, on Christmas, Grandpa gave it to you, right?
No, I received the music box last Christmas.
Th-That can't be!
Father died on December 6th last year.
H-How can that be...?
Furthermore, Father was in the hospital
since last April, and he could barely move.
Hey hey, what the heck is going on?
It's simple.
Someone pretended to be Shuugo-san and put
the music box next to Haruna-san, who was waiting.
Right, Shirou-san?
Shirou?
Is this true?
Shirou!
Grandpa asked me to,
Saying, "Even after I'm in the hospital, take care of this girl.
She's just like my Haruna, and she is very lonely."
Then does that mean ever since last spring...
Yes, I was the one talking to you in place of my grandfather.
I was planning to tell you everything when I met you on Christmas.
Watching you waiting so anxiously
with the red muffler as your marker,
I couldn't bring myself to tell you.
But how did you know it was me?
I had a suspicion that you were the one
who gave her the music box from the start.
The moment I saw you at the foyer.
You couldn't have...
At that time, you placed your hand
on Haruna-san's shoulder and said,
The rumored Haruna-san finally came.
Let's have her rest in the living room.
We hadn't introduced ourselves yet,
And Ran is roughly the same age.
Even then, you were able to point out
Haruna-san without a second thought.
That was when I thought,
Perhaps you are the one who gave her the music box.
Then you, because I kept
questioning her, you got mad at me and...
N-No!
Ran, turn off the lights.
Eh?
Hurry.
O-Okay.
Co-Conan-kun?
Where are you, Conan-kun?
I'm over here, Ran-neechan.
How'd you get there so fast?
I was here all along.
A "Shouji" is a Japanese paper door
That can't be, because your shadow was just on the shouji.
Look at the window in the hallway.
The hallway window?
What could possibly be here?
Isn't this...
There's a black sheet taped to the window in the shape of you!
Uncle told me to put it up earlier.
Then the shadow of the old man Ran-san saw was...
Correct, what Ran saw was just a shadow.
Tape a cutout of an old man to the hallway window.
If a car comes, the light from the
headlight will come through the open gate,
And portray the shadow of an old
man on the shouji on the opposite side.
Come to think of it, when I saw the
shadow, there was a "shaa" sound.
That was probably a car driving on
the road that is wet from the rain.
I see. If you do that, then you can still
show a shadow of a person without being here.
Shirou, you could have, too.
Well, I was here when you were attacked!
You can do that from this room as well.
By using a simple setup made by some thread and a hairpin.
Setup?
The one who set it up dropped the koto
from the ceiling in your grandfather's room.
It just happened to hit you on your head.
You, Minoru-san, who was trying to
secretly check the koto in that room.
W-Why would I look at the koto?
Probably because, during dinner, you learned that the tune in the music box Haruna-san received from your grandfather,
Was what your grandmother used to love to
play on the koto, "Come, Dear Spring," correct?
You thought that maybe the stamps
were hidden somewhere on the koto.
But even if the koto fell from the
ceiling, it isn't far to someone's head.
So it wouldn't knock a person out, would it?
And if he wanted to check the koto,
wouldn't he have turned the lights on?
But when we ran there, the room was pitch black.
It wasn't that Minoru-san didn't want to turn on the lights,
But rather, he couldn't.
Due to the culprit's set up,
The room was dark, and he didn't
know where the string for the light was.
So with no other alternative, he felt
his way towards the koto on the floor,
And he was planning to take it back to his room.
At that time, hearing the sound of the thread
rubbing against the strings on the koto, he looked up.
And the koto, unluckily, fell on him.
Nii-san?
Yeah, that's right, it's exactly as he said.
But how in the world did the person drop the koto?
It's a simple set up.
First, you get one long thread.
Hang the center of that thread to the light on the ceiling.
Pull it through the koto under its strings.
Then put the koto on a shelf or something temporarily.
Next, take both ends of the thread through the transom,
Through Shirou-san, Minoru-san, and
Ogata-san couple's room, and finally into Ran's room.
Then tie it in a fashion so that the two sides will not tangle,
And position it between the doors with a hairpin.
Next, take the koto off the shelf and let
it hang, then the preparation is complete.
If the door to Ran's room opens even slightly...
The hairpin drops and the koto will fall.
Wait a second, does that mean...?
Correct, the one that caused the ghost commotion
tonight was the one who opened the door at that time...
Kazuko-san, it was you, right?
Mom?
Why?
That was probably because she did not want
Haruna-san to go look for those hand carved stamps.
Kazuko-san probably set this up during dinner.
Probably when she left to prepare the futons.
And upon hearing Ran's scream
when they saw the shadow of the old man,
You ran to this room, and
innocently opened the door to drop the koto.
And while everyone ran to the grandfather's room,
You took down the paper from the window,
Sending that message with your
cell phone to Haruna-san's pocket bell,
I've been waiting for you, Haruna.
And raised the fear level.
To scare Haruna-san enough so that
she won't want to return to this house.
But what happened to that thread used in
the set up that's at least a few meters long?
Mom came right after we arrived at Grandpa's room.
She couldn't have had the time to take the paper off the window and use her cell phone as she rolled the thread back.
There's a very useful item.
Right behind Ran-neechan and the rest of you.
A fan?
Translator Note: Obasan means Aunt
Obasan probably took one side of
the thread and taped it to the fan,
On the back of this fan's blade.
I see, all she has to do is push the switch
and it will automatically gather the thread.
But I can't believe you thought of such
a complex setup when you left your seat.
Of course I can.
I used their pranks when they were kids as a basis for this setup.
Then that shadow of the old man was also...
Oh, that was from me remembering
that the guests that stayed here last time,
Mistook the shadow of the leaves
outside for the shadow of a person.
I got scared of Haruna-san.
She even said that she's collecting stamps,
And said she would love to come back again, so...
And the messages that were sent to
my pocket bell calling me a thief was...?
That was me too, I'm sorry.
But that's horrible, Mom.
To break Grandma's koto just because of that.
Oh, it doesn't matter if that thing breaks.
Hey hey.
The real koto is in storage and I switched it with a cheaper one.
The new kitchen system,
Your new car,
Minoru's computer,
Our finance is burnt up.
I guess we'll have to sell the music box.
But when I got it looked at, they said it was just an ordinary thing.
That's weird, Grandpa said...
"As a thank you to you for being me,
Depending on the person who sees it, I shall
give you this music box that's worth 200 million."
2-200 million?
That music box?
That's just a souvenir Dad bought
at the hot springs a long time ago.
You got played by the old man.
That value isn't in the music box but in the missing notes it holds.
In Japan, there is another way to
represent do-re-mi: The i-ro-ha.
First line: Do re mi fa so ra ti do
Second Line: Ha ni ho he to i ro ha
Right, the missing notes are Ra, Do, and Ra.
If you change that to Iroha representation,
Note: Ihai = An ash box that holds the ashes of the dead individual.
I-Ihai!
That... Can't be.
It can't be.
There it is!
This is it!
It is!
Banzai!
What the...?
Thank you very much.
Now we can pay off all our debt.
It's all thanks to you.
Who in the world are you?
My name is Mouri Kogorou.
Mouri Kogorou... Is that...?
That famous detective?
Yes.
If that was the case, then why didn't you tell us earlier!
If we knew we would have asked you
to help us find the stamps right away!
Minoru wouldn't have had to get hurt too!
Sorry...
This family has a lot of apologizing to do...
Thank you for all your troubles.
No, thank you.
But are you sure it's okay?
Maybe those stamps were what
Shuugo-san wanted to give you alone.
It's fine, I've gotten something that's worth a lot more.
My grandpa's pocket bell.
Haruna-san gave it to me.
She said, "Can I still look to you for courage?"
Thank you very much!
It really is spring.
Spring?
But it's almost summer.
That doesn't matter.
For Shirou-san it's spring.
Come, dear spring.
Hurry and come.
Heh heh, it never comes to me...
Difference in levels?
That little difference in levels
isn't something you put on your mind.
But Sonoko did tell me.
He would also definitely have...
The Invisible Weapon
Next Conan.
The Invisible Weapon.
Ran's First Case!
Next Conan's Hint.
Car.
Next time, Ran-neechan gets sharp!
There's always only one truth!