Flowing water has no form.
A blowing wind can't be seen.
All cases can be freely deduced!
A parent is a parent, but a child is different!
Ran's challenge outdoes Kogoro!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
So hot...
The Akasaka Princess Hotel's a
nice hotel, but this hill's a killer...
You said it.
I'd like to change right away and
jump right into the pool, you know?
Listen, Ran...
I'm gonna catch me a hot guy,
so don't get in my way, got it?
Yeah, yeah, got it.
By the way, have you heard
anything from Shin'ichi-kun?
No, not a word since then...
Is he working on another case?
I just don't understand how anyone
can get so worked up over a case...
Look at that car...
This doesn't look good!
Look out!
I'm so sorry! Are you two all right?!
Y-Yeah...
J-Just barely...
Akasaka Princess Hotel
So, Yoshino-san, you're an
instructor at a flower design school?
Yes. I commute to Shizuoka five days a week.
Shizuoka? That's pretty far, isn't it?
Chie Yoshino (31)
Flower Designer
Actually, I was just on my way to school
when I remembered today was a holiday.
So I called my husband—
he works for an insurance company—
and we made plans to meet here at this hotel.
We were going to have lunch.
I see.
I'm really sorry about what happened.
I got dizzy all of a sudden
and blacked out for a bit.
I've been getting dizzy spells and
splitting headaches a lot lately...
Maybe you're sick?
No... The doctor couldn't find anything wrong.
It's probably the weather. The
temperature's been all over the place lately.
And I guess the fatigue's been building up,
since I have to drive to and
from Shizuoka every day.
As proof, when there's no school,
or when it's cool, even on a weekday,
I feel fine—nothing happens.
Is that so...
Chie!
Sorry for the bother.
Akio Yoshino (33)
Insurance Agent
This is my husband, Akio Yoshino.
Hello.
This is Ran Mouri-san and Sonoko Suzuki-san.
I had another dizzy spell and nearly ran them over.
Again?
Were you two hurt at all?
No, we're fine. But it was a close call.
Your wife was nice enough to treat us to lunch.
I see...
Please accept my apologies.
Anyway, how are you feeling?
I rested for a bit, so now I'm fine.
I see... I'm so relieved.
He seems so nice.
Excuse me, I think we'll be going now.
That's right, you were going
to the pool, weren't you?
All right then.
Where do you two live?
In Beika Town.
Oh, that's not far from us. I live in Haido Town.
We live right near the park.
Please drop by sometime.
Sure.
A bump...
What the?!
Ran, watch your step! There's a bump here.
Hey...
Don't you think it's strange?
What is?
Well, he knew Chie-san just had a dizzy spell, so why didn't he warn her about the bump?
She could've gotten badly hurt
if she tripped and fell!
I don't see why you're making
such a big deal out of it.
But Sonoko warned me about it!
And I know he would have too...
He?
Who are you talking about?
Oh, nothing.
Anyway, I'm worried about that couple.
I think I'll go over to visit
Chie-san and check things out.
And do what?
I want to find out what's causing her to
have those headaches and dizzy spells!
Whatever...
You're not a doctor. Don't stick your
neck out where it doesn't belong.
I'm not stupid, I can figure it out!
Eh, do what you want.
I most certainly will!
Ran's not usually like this.
But she has a point. Something's fishy.
Hey, can I go with you?
You want to come along, Conan-kun?
Then I'll ask Sonoko to come along,
and we'll all go together!
Whatever.
I guess I'll have my rice now.
Get it yourself.
What a grouch.
Yoshino Residence
Wow! This place is super-nice!
The garden's so well cared-for.
Your home's so beautiful.
Thanks.
We just finished building this
place a month and a half ago.
I had a feeling it was new.
A new house, how wonderful...
But dealing with a ¥40,000,000 loan's pretty rough.
That's why we both have to work,
or we'd never make ends meet...
Here you go.
Thanks.
Sorry for barging in on you on your day off.
It's quite all right.
Unfortunately, my husband went out
this morning, so I'm alone today.
Your husband seems so nice.
I suppose so...
He loves cars,
and he's been complaining lately that he hasn't
been able to go out for drives like he used to.
I guess that's why he goes out walking
every morning, to take his mind off it.
And while he's out, I fix breakfast.
That's our daily routine.
Er...
This may be a strange thing to ask,
but why do you go all the way
to Shizuoka to work?
To help pay for the loan.
I used to teach at a design school here in the city,
but my husband told me
about this school in Shizuoka.
The pay was better there.
Oh, I see.
But still, isn't driving there every day pretty hard on you?
Yeah.
If you took the train, you'd at
least be able to get some sleep...
Actually, I enjoy driving.
The entrance to the expressway is nearby.
It's much more convenient when you have a
lot of supplies and large equipment, isn't it?
Yeah.
By the way, have you ever though about insur—
Oh, dear...
I forgot, you're still in high school!
What was that?
I'm terribly sorry.
My husband works for an insurance company,
and I've gotten into the habit of
suggesting people get insurance.
Ah, so you're giving your husband a hand, right?
Something like that.
I felt bad about suggesting it to others, so I just recently raised my policy to ¥100,000,000.
¥100,000,000?!
My husband asked me to...
The monthly payments are very high,
but it's the kind of policy where
after the fixed period has passed,
even if you cancel the policy,
you still get the premium back.
I figured it would make his
job performance look good.
Uh, you're really crazy about him, aren't you?
You think so?
¥100,000,000...
Don't tell me...
But...
Excuse me, but when did you start
having those headaches and dizzy spells?
About a month ago, I guess...
A month ago...
Half a month after the house was built...
Maybe that's what they call
"sick house syndrome"?
Sick house syndrome...
What? "Sick hack"?
Sick House Syndrome
I said "sick house syndrome"!
It's when people get sick from the fumes given off
from the lumber and paint used to build a house.
Sonoko-neechan, I'm sure even
you've heard of formaldehyde...
Formaldehyde
Don't take me for an idiot!
Of course I know about that!
I'm not sure. But I don't think so.
Why not?
The contractor who built this
house is a friend of my husband.
My husband would have told them not
to use anything that was dangerous.
But I still think you should have it checked out!
The contractor could've deceived you...
Hey, Sonoko...
Do you know of any companies that specialize
in checking for contaminated building supplies?
Dad might know.
All right then, let's ask him right away!
Chie-san, I think you should have it
checked, just to be on the safe side.
Y-Yeah...
Ran, you've been acting strange today.
Why did you insist on getting her house checked?
I had my reasons...
Ran-neechan thinks Chie-san's husband Akio-san...
is trying to kill her to collect
on her insurance policy.
Is that true, Ran?
Yeah.
How so?
First, Akio-san gets the contractor to build
the house using dangerous materials,
so that Chie-san starts to become ill...
And then he suggests she take the job
at the design school in Shizuoka.
Why?
Chie-san does as he suggests, and drives to and from work on the expressway every day.
If she were to have a dizzy spell while driving...
Yeah, right.
You're overthinking this, Ran...
First of all, wouldn't the house
make Akio-san sick too?
He lives there too, you know!
But those materials could've been used
only for her room and the kitchen.
Of course, we have no proof.
But as long as the possibility exists,
I thought it was best to check it out.
At this point, we still don't know
if Ran's suspicions are correct.
But something wasn't right.
I couldn't put my finger on it...
This is a device that measures
the amount of formaldehyde.
There's a possibility that different
materials were used in each room,
so I think it's best if we
checked every room to be sure.
Sure. Please do.
All right then, let's begin.
When Chie told me about this, I was shaken.
But then, there is a possibility the
contractor did use those kind of materials,
so I figured it might be best
to have the kitchen checked.
Yeah, you're right.
Well, I'm going for a walk.
I'll pick up some cake on the way back.
That would be nice.
See you later.
He really loves to take walks!
I'm going to take a walk too!
Conan-kun! Don't stay out too long!
Right!
That customer's going to buy it, isn't he?
Yeah. He used to come in
all the time on his days off,
but I think he's made up his mind now.
¥25,000,000?!
Oh geez, is he serious?
We have the results!
Every room shows a level much
lower than 0.08 parts per million,
which is the level the Ministry of Health
and Welfare declared safe four years ago.
Are you sure about that?
Which means...
It means this house is absolutely safe!
What a relief!
I guess it's not "sick house
syndrome" that's making me sick.
You're just tired.
Let's try to get to bed earlier.
Yeah.
I don't get it...
Is something else going on here?
I told you so!
That's what happens when amateurs
try to do a professional's job!
Maybe I have been overthinking this...
You didn't tell them you were the great
Kogoro Mouri's daughter, did you?
Of course not!
Good.
I hope this taught you not to go sticking
your neck into other people's business.
Well?
I understand.
I guess I just can't compete with him...
Conan-kun!
Ran-neechan, I don't think you
made a mistake in your reasoning.
Today, I overheard the salesmen
at the place they sell sports cars.
Akio-san is going to buy a sports
car that costs ¥25,000,000.
¥25,000,000?
Where's he getting the money from?
Chie-san's insurance policy?!
So he is trying to kill Chie-san!
Even after he pays off the loan on the
house, he'll still have ¥60,000,000 left.
But there was no sign that the air
in the house was contaminated...
Maybe he was poisoning her food?
But I think she does all the cooking...
That's right...
What do you think?
How is he doing it?
While I'm sitting here, danger
could be creeping up on Chie-san...
Oh, Shin'ichi, what am I going to do?
Something's bugging me.
And it's been bugging me
ever since Ran told me about it.
What is it, though?
Wait a minute...
Didn't Chie-san say...
That's it! I've figured it out!
You want to know what
Chie-san told me the first time?
Yeah. What did she say about her dizzy spells?
If I recall correctly...
It's probably the weather.
The temperature's been all over the place lately.
And I guess the fatigue's been building up,
since I have to drive to and
from Shizuoka every day.
As proof, when there's no school,
or when it's cool, even on a weekday,
I feel fine—nothing happens.
That's what she said.
Well, if it were something in the house,
then wouldn't the symptoms
be worse on her days off,
when she's at home longer,
instead of when she's out?
You know, you're right.
I think the thing that's giving her headaches
and dizzy spells isn't in the house.
It's somewhere else?
Like, at the design school in Shizuoka?
Someplace between her house and the school...
You don't mean...?
The next morning
I'm going for my walk now.
Is ham and eggs for breakfast okay with you?
Sounds good.
I'll be hungry when I get home, so make a lot!
What are you guys doing here?
Yoshino-san...
What did you just put in your pocket?
It's an air conditioner disinfectant.
See?
I wanted to protect Chie from
cold germs and other bacteria.
Then when the police get here,
you'll show that to them, won't you?
I just called them. I have a friend on the force.
P-Police?
I'm sure Chie-san would never have dreamed that her husband, the man she trusted most,
was spraying an "invisible weapon" into
her car's air conditioner every morning.
That's why Chie-san never got sick
when she didn't drive to work,
or when it was cool enough that she
didn't have to use the air conditioner.
Chie-san!
Dear...
Later, the police investigation
showed that the spray bottle
contained a dilluted organic chlorine solution.
Akio Yoshino had embezzled several million yen from his company, and was trying to cover the loss.
But he also wanted a new sports car,
and that's why he thought up this plan.
That's what his confession stated.
Chie-san sold the house?
Yeah. And along with some
friends and flower shops,
she opened her own flower design company!
Look.
Oh, my!
She's looking great!
"Chie Taniguchi"...
She got a divorce and went
back to her maiden name.
Oh, geez. Women get over things so quickly.
But Ran sure was sharp, getting
suspicious about Akio Yoshino
over a little thing like a bump on the ground.
I'm sure glad things worked out for her.
If you hadn't noticed anything and done what
you did, Chie-san might be dead by now.
Maybe you're getting to be like you-know-who?
No way...
But I guess you could say I wanted
to understand him a little more...
Maybe get to feel closer to him...
I see.
So do you understand
Shin'ichi-kun a little more now?
Not a bit.
Who can understand that mystery geek?
Seriously...
But never mind that.
Let's go eat some cake!
All right!
Well, I guess it's for the best...
Was he trying to damage his own car?
Hey, doesn't the president
have a cell phone with him?
Ran!
Ran-neechan!
Ran-neechan, where are you?!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Open Window
Next time...
Where do you buy a super car? At a supermarket?