Song: Mystery Eyes
Song by: Garnet Crow
There is no shape to flowing water.
The blowing winds can't even be seen.
No matter what the case is, the deductions are free.
The super car, full of adoration.
Not only expensive, but also
causing complicated emotions.
Seeing through the one and only truth,
The appearance of a child but the intellect of an adult.
His name is: Detective Conan.
kimi to boku to ha betsu no ikimono dakara
konomi ga chigau aruku hayasa mo omoi no tsutae kata mo
iroaseteyuku
futari no kioku no naka ima bokura ha
tesaguri dakedo
hoka no dareka wo mirai wo sagashite yuku
omou yori tsuyoku ikite
tokubetsu na ai motometeru
shikana hibi ni nayandari
True heart for mystery eyes
mou nido do mayowanai you ni
sono ude wo hanasanaide
kizutsuke au sono toki mo
tada zutto kotae wo sagashite
mayoi konda toki no naka de
tsugi no basho he
you take your way
dakishimete
I feel so all in secret life
A Super Car's Trap
(Part 1)
A Super Car's Trap (Part 1)
Ahhh! It's so beautiful!
You can see the ocean!
You're right!
Huh? Where's uncle?
That's weird. He was walking with us just a moment ago.
Hey! Stop resting without me!
Winning the 1st place in the city lottery was good,
But getting invited into a hotel where no bus line reaches...
Father!
Father! Hurry up!
What a long way to the hotel.
I thought it was too good to be true.
The 2nd place with the all-you-can-eat
shabushabu would have been better, right?
You're damn right.
Don't ruin my good mood!
Even if you say so... When will we arrive at the hotel?
We'll be there soon, just hold out a bit.
Look! I think that may be the Kirigamini-Hotel?
Please sign in on the registrating card.
Hmm? Mouri...
Hmm?
Ah! It's Mr. Mouri, right? It'll be room 201.
Hey you! It's quite a nice hotel but,
Can't you send out a bus to the
station or do some service like that?
Stop it already, dad!
Suguro Hisashi (28)
Kirigamini Hotel Front Manager
I apologize, but I'll guide you to your room now.
Sorry. Let's go, Conan-ku...?
Huh? Conan-kun? Where are you?
Ahh! Amazing!
Cool!
Conan-kun. What are you doing here?
Always wandering off like that...
Look! It's so amazing! There
are so many historic sport cars.
He's right.
Jaguar XK120
Here is the Jaguar XK120.
The long stretched nose and this beautifully curved fender
are its characteristics. It looks like a real jaguar, doesn't it?
Even nowadays, it's still the
dream of many Jaguar collectors.
And...
Mercedes Benz 300SL Gullwing
This is the Mercedes Benz 300SL Gullwing.
Gullwing means the wings of a seagull.
The sight of the car when its doors are
open is similar to the stretched seagull wings.
You're right.
Oh! Isn't that one over there called a Cadillac?
Cadillac Eldorado
Yes. Cadillac Eldorado a '53 Convertible.
It's really powerful and was
called the ultimate American model.
The production was limited to 500 cars and
disappeared from the showrooms in an instant.
Now, there is even an Eldorado
legend told among the collectors.
You know quite a bit, kid.
This here is the newly built historic car exhibition.
I see.
This hotel's owner is quite a car maniac.
Just for this exhibition, he reconstructed the hotel.
Huh? There's an open spot in the back.
Yes. That space is reserved for
the owner's proud Ferrari Dino.
What? By Ferrari Dino...
You don't mean the 206GT, do you?
That's exactly what I mean.
Wow!
Conan? What kind of a car is it?
Only 152 of them were ever produced, so
it's almost impossible to get one nowadays.
Ferrari Dino 206GT
Dino is the Ferrari's founder, Enzo
Ferrari's only son, Alfreadino's nickname.
He died at age 24.
But the engine he developed
before his death was used in this car.
That's why Enzo Ferrari chose his
beloved son's name as the brand name.
It had such a background to it...
Suguro!
What are you, whose job is at the front desk, doing here?
I'm sorry.
And dear guests,
Kuroiwa Zenkichi (45)
Kirigamini Hotel Manager
This area is prohibited from entering,
until the opening ceremony tomorrow.
We're sorry.
That guest... Could he be...?
Chief, welcome back!
Teraizumi Daigo (60)
Kirigamini Hotel President
This car is more important than my life,
Yet it is still exhausting to drive it all the way from Tokyo.
Chief, we have finished placing the other cars.
I would suggest to place this car now.
Wait, wait! Don't be so hasty.
I want to spend tonight with him, just the two of us.
Once he's on display, I won't be able to
drive him anytime I want as I usually do.
Chief, I wanted to show you this.
Hmm? Detective...?
What the hell? There's only one bed!
Don't act so spoiled. Be happy you even won the lottery.
We can't sleep in a room like this with three people.
Let's ask them to give us another room!
It's okay if we use the sofa.
Selfish old man as usual...
It's okay, let me take care of it.
The opening ceremony will start tomorrow at 3 PM.
So tonight is the last chance.
Exactly. Don't worry.
We'll stick to our plan.
Understood?
Can you come here for a moment, Conan-kun?
Let go of me, Ran!
Please, that's enough, father!
This hotel is almost empty anyways!
I'll definitely make them give us another room!
But, won't they take more
money if we do something like that?
And if you are too loud and
annoying, they might kick you out.
Mr. Mouri.
Threatening letter?
Let's see... "Don't open the exhibition. You'll regret it."
This threatening letter was
sent to our hotel a few days ago.
And we were discussing what to do.
For a threatening letter, it lacks impact.
Probably it's just a prank?
I hope so.
But couldn't you guard me until
the opening ceremony tomorrow?
We would like to assign the
famous detective Mouri Kogorou.
Did you contact the police?
If you accept, I will give you the
pride of this hotel, this suite room.
This suite room? Father?
I understand! I'll accept!
Thank you.
Now, I'm relieved.
Everyone, please just pretend that
you're on a giant cruise and relax.
Miss Ran. How about a drive in my car after dinner?
What? She gets to go on the Dino? Amazing!
Mister? I can also come, right?
Of course, you may!
May I also go, father?
Ah! This steak is really delicious! Great! Really delicious!
Hold back a bit...
This is really good! One more plate!
Oh no! Did it get on your clothes?
No problem, I'll just go change right away.
Father! You're drinking too much!
Chief! It's terrible! The car displayed in the exhibition!
W-What?!
Don't stop me, Don't stop me please!
Please calm down, Mr. Ootake!
You can't!
Don't get in my way! Let me go!
Please let me do what I want!
Stop acting foolish!
Shut up! I'll turn this car into scraps.
Mr. Ootake, you can't.
Wasn't this car like a treasure to you?
Huh?
What? He was trying to destroy his own car?
Mr. Ootake, you really are a pain.
You'll never understand an emotion like this!
What are you talking about?
I'll... I'll crush this exhibition!
This car, '53 El Dorado Convertible was my dream.
Ootake Ichirou (55)
Travel Agency Manager
In order to make that dream a reality, I worked
day and night and finally managed to get this car.
Why did you want to destroy such an important vehicle?
If I must give up this car, then I'd rather destroy it myself.
If you must give it up?
What do you mean?
What do I mean?
If you ask Teraizumi there, you'll understand.
What does this mean, Mr. Teraizumi?
That's a big misunderstanding. Mr.
Ootake, you should thank me, not hate me.
Be thankful!? Nobody is
looking forward to this car exhibition.
Except you!
Exactly. I can understand why Mr.
Ootake would rather destroy his car.
It's true that nobody's looking forward to this exhibition.
Excuse me, but you guys are?
Sagara Shinsuke (37)
Car Repair Factory Manager
I'm Sagara Shinsuke, who was forced to
give up this beloved just like Ootake-san.
Kameoka Jiyouji (40)
Car Realtor Company Manager
I'm Kameoka Jiyouji, ex-owner of that Jaguar.
All three of us here got our beloved car
cheated away by Teraizumi over there.
What are you talking about?
It's your own fault that your car is taken, isn't it?
What do you mean by cheated?
We three have little firms.
I have a travel agency.
I'm a realtor.
And I have an auto bodyshop.
But because of bad economy...
Mr. Teraizumi offered to lend us some
money if we put our cars as collateral.
We accepted, of course.
But that was a trap.
We learned later, that man there
manipulated from the back and took our businesses away.
Finally, when we couldn't pay
back the loan, Teraizumi took our cars.
Teraizumi lent us the money with the intent of
taking our cars away from us since the beginning.
How can you say that?
Do you have any proof that I'm
the reason for your business troubles?
If you got the time to criticize me, I suggest
you think of some ways to return the money.
If you pay me back, I'll return the cars anytime.
Bastard!
Threats won't work on me.
I see, you three sent me that threatening letter.
Threatening letter?
What are you talking about?
Don't lie. I will open this exhibition no matter what.
Mr. Sagara's shoes...
Don't worry. Leave it to me.
The opening is tomorrow at 3pm.
Tonight is our last chance.
Exactly! Don't worry!
We'll stick to our plan.
Understood?
Mr. Sagara, what is your room number?
It's 202.
Is there anything wrong with my room?
Not really,
I was wondering if you could tell me things
about your 300SL tonight because it's really cool.
I can't tonight. I have things to do.
What kind of things?
That's none of your business, is it now?
I suppose...
Room service? I didn't ask for it.
Are you sure this isn't some mistake?
No, it's on the hotel since you're the owner's guests.
Please order anything you want.
Alright! In that case, I'd like a nice bottle of wine.
Dad, no!
Oh, I'm sorry about stains on
your pants earlier at the dinner.
Don't worry. I changed immediately.
Dino's engine...?
You're right, I hear a car's engine, too.
It's Dino... There's no doubt.
Are you sure?
Owner, where are you going at a time like this?
Thanks to those guys, my good
mood is ruined... I'm going for a drive.
Tonight's fog is thick so you should stay in, Mr. Teraizumi.
It's safer on the road than in the hotel with those three.
Please drive carefully.
I know.
Manager, the owner still isn't back.
Geeze, it's nine already,
where in the world did the chief go?
He's still not back?
What a hopeless guy.
But the opening ceremony isn't till 3pm.
You still have enough time, right?
This isn't even a joke anymore.
We still have to exhibit Dino.
And in the afternoon, the
specially invited guests will arrive as well.
But, isn't it strange that he didn't contact us all this time?
Teraizumi is still not back?
Mr. Kameoka and Ootake...
Well, if he had an accident,
today's opening is cancelled, right?
It's God's punishment.
Doesn't the owner have a cell phone?
Right, I've totally forgotten.
Let me talk to him and tell him to stop making us worry.
Hello? Owner?
It's me Mouri, where are you right now?
Where am I? Why is it so dark?
Dark?
Hello? Owner? Owner?
What's up?
Well, he seemed to be in pain and
moaned, "Where am I? It's so dark,"
Then the line went dead.
Dark? It's pure white outside with the fog.
What did he mean by dark then, Mouri-san?
Sir, it's 10 am already. We
need to prepare the ceremony soon.
You're right. Go ahead Suguro.
Yes, sir.
It seems that today's opening is cancelled, cancelled!
It's the God's punishment, that's right!
Man... It's just as the threatening letter said.
Ahhhhhh...
Ran?!
Where are you, Ran-neechan?
Conan-kun, I'm here.
Ran-neechan!
Ran-neechan, what happened? Are you alright?
Yes, I'm ok.
Ran, what happened?
Sorry, I was taking a walk when somebody
suddenly talked to me and I got scared in the fog and all.
You're the guardsman Noda. What are you doing here?
Noda Kazuo (50)
Guardsman
Nothing, I warned that girl because
she was walking toward the cliff in the fog.
Then she just started screaming.
I'm sorry.
You're such a hassle.
A car's coming...
So the owner finally returned.
No no, that's not the owner, it's Mr. Sagara's car.
What's going on, all gathered here?
You were right.
It's amazing how you can tell whose
car it is just by hearing the engine sound!
If it's a regular guest, then I know the sound.
Excuse me, I still have work to do.
Mr. Sagara, where were you last night?
I was out for a drive.
Did you see the owner's car?
No, I didn't. Now, step aside a
little, I'm going to park my car.
Man, it's too late to display Dino in time.
We first have to find out where the owner is.
If we don't find out then we can't do anything.
Hey, Teraizumi is...
Something is wrong with Teraizumi in his car.
What?
Owner!
Mr. Teraizumi!
Owner!?
A doctor, get an ambulance, quick.
It's already too late, he's dead.
The cause of death is Carbon Monoxide-intoxication.
Engine's still running and the car is full of fume.
The exhaust must have backtracked into the car.
This looks like an accident.
The window is slightly opened.
What does it mean?
Why, why the window?
Is this really an accident?
Donna kotoba ni kaete
How can I change my words,
so that you may understand
Kimi ni tsutaerareru darou
Since then numerous seasons
arekara ikutsumo no kisetsu ga
have passed by
toorisugita keredo
But you always smiled beside me
itsumo soba de waratteru
watashi nimo ienai koto ga mada hitotsu dake aru
Even I still have one thing I cannot say
Secret Of My Heart
utagattemo nai ne
I hold no suspicions
itsu datte sukoshi no mirai ga areba
Always as long as there is a little future
shinjitsu wa te ni irerareru hazu
I should be able to find the truth
I can't say mou sukoshi dake
I can't say, Just a little more
I'm waiting for a chance
Next Episode Preview
Let's stop this act of yours, manager.
I know you're happy that the owner died.
I never hated the owner like these people here.
So that car's engine was running?
How did you know that, kid?
Did you ki—...
N-No, it wasn't me.
What's this, it's cut off in a straight line...
A Super Car's Trap
(Part 2)
Next Conan.
A Super Car's Trap (part 2).
Next Conan's Hint.
Coal tar.
Wait in excited anticipation for the next episode
Next episode is the solution.
I wonder if uncle will buy a car too?
A Ferrari or something?
That's not possible...