Song: Mystery Eyes
Song by: Garnet Crow
There's no shape to flowing water.
There's no figure to flowing winds.
No matter what the case, the deductions are free.
Today we solve the mystery of the super car!
I've never seen a trick quite like this one.
Seeing through to the one and only truth,
The appearance of a child but the intellect of an adult.
That name is... Detective Conan.
Because you and I are two different people.
kimi to boku to ha betsu no ikimono dakara
konomi ga chigau aruku hayasa mo omoi no tsutae kata mo
Hobbies, walking speed nor the way we
communicate, our thoughts are different.
iroaseteyuku
Times change.
Amongst the memories of the two, we are.
futari no kioku no naka ima bokura ha
Though troublesome,
tesaguri dakedo
Ever searching for someone else and the future.
hoka no dareka wo mirai wo sagashite yuku
Living stronger than once thought.
omou yori tsuyoku ikite
Seeking a special love.
tokubetsu na ai motometeru
shikana hibi ni nayandari
Getting confused in the tough days.
True heart for mystery eyes
True heart for mystery eyes.
Don't let go of that hand.
mou nido do mayowanai you ni
So that you won't get lost once more.
sono ude wo hanasanaide
Even we hurt each other.
kizutsuke au sono toki mo
Just keep searching for the answers.
tada zutto kotae wo sagashite
mayoi konda toki no naka de
During the times we get lost.
To the next place.
tsugi no basho he
you take your way
You take your way.
dakishimete
Hold me.
I feel so all in secret life
I feel so all in secret life.
After winning a free hotel stay in the
city lottery, we came to Izuku Oogen.
The owner of the hotel is a big car maniac,
And we arrived the day before the
opening of a historic car exhibition.
However, the individuals who gathered,
Were all people who said that they'd
been scammed out of their cars by the owner.
That evening, the owner went driving,
And the following morning was found
dead in the driver's seat of his favorite car.
A Super Car's Trap
(Part 2)
A Super Car's Trap (Part 2)
How is he, doctor?
His cause of death was most likely carbon
monoxide poisoning from the car's exhaust.
Other than that, I don't see any outside injuries.
The time of death, I believe, is
sometime between 9:00 to 10:00am.
Come to think of it, when he
called just past 9:00, he was still alive.
What?
What was he like then?
In a suffocating voice he was yelling,
"Where am I?"
And, "Why is it so dark?"
And things that didn't make any sense.
Perhaps that was due to the effects from his suffocation.
Meaning, he passed away
immediately after the phone call, right?
Hey, Inspector Yokomizo?
That means that Teraizumi-san was here
for quite some time before 9:00am right?
No duh!
By the way, Mouri-san,
About the window by the driver's seat...
Why do you think it's opened slightly?
An act of desperation.
Teraizumi-san was suffocating and must have
opened the window in a last ditch attempt to stay alive.
Then why did he die?
It must have already been too late
by the time he opened the window.
Huh?
What's this?
It's cut off in a straight line.
Now, now. You can't run around in a place like this.
I'm sorry. I was just wondering what this black stain was.
That's coal tar created from the uncondensed car fuel.
That probably dripped from the exhaust pipes.
It happens a lot with old cars like this one.
Wow. Even though it looks sparkling clean, huh?
Yeah. It was wiped so clean that
few fingerprints were found on it.
Hmm?
What is it?
What did you find?
This car seems to have been hit recently.
There was a crack on the left
headlight cover and a thread was stuck inside.
A crack and a thread?
Hello, everyone. Sorry to keep you all waiting.
To start off, who is this
Sagara-san, the first person to find the victim?
That would be me.
Could you tell me the situation at the time?
Sagara Shinsuke (37)
Car Repair Factory Manager
At around 10:00am this
morning, I came back from my drive.
And when I was about to park my car in the
parking lot, I nearly smashed into that Dino.
The fog still hadn't cleared up then.
And when I looked inside the Dino,
Teraizumi was slouched over like that.
Was there anything else out of the ordinary?
Come to think of it, when I came back,
everyone else had gathered together in the parking lot.
Um, that was because of me...
Eh? Ran-san's fault?
That's right. Ran let out a scream,
And surprised everyone, who ran over to her.
The guardsman suddenly called
out to me in the fog. It startled me.
I see...
Now, about the recently deceased Teraizumi-san...
We believe that he came back from his drive
and for some time afterwards, stayed in the car,
And eventually suffocated
from carbon monoxide poisoning.
Does anyone have an idea as to why
he may have remained in his vehicle?
The chief loved that car as though it were his own child.
Kuroiwa Zenkichi (45)
Kirigamine Hotel Manager
Why, just last night...
Chief, we've finished setting up the other cars.
Shall we start on yours as well?
Wait, wait. Don't be so hasty.
I want to spend the night with him, just the two of us.
Once he's on display, I won't be able
to drive him anytime I wish like usual.
So, perhaps he just couldn't leave his
favorite car right even after he returned.
I see. Then he dozed off in his seat, huh?
The chief was so excited about today's exhibition...
It's really too bad.
Let's stop this charade already, Manager.
In reality, you're more than
glad that the owner died, right?
What are you talking about?
I know that you were about to get laid off by the owner.
Laid off?
Is that true?
It is.
But I never hated the chief for that at all.
Unlike these people.
What do you mean by "these people?"
They all had a grudge against the owner.
Especially after getting their favorite cars taken
away as collateral for the money they'd borrowed.
There was a threatening letter, too. Right, uncle?
T-threatening letter?
That was just a prank.
Translator Note: Don't open the exhibition. You'll regret it.
Look.
But if this is the case, then there is a possibility of a murder.
Murder?
How in the world can you use
car exhaust to poison someone?
But Mouri-san...
Hey, Inspector Yokomizo?
The important thing is their
alibis, just as Uncle always says.
Uh... Yeah. That's right, Conan-kun.
How about it, everyone?
Ootake Ichirou (55)
Travel Agency Manager
Kameoka Jyouji (40)
Car Realtor Company Manager
Teraizumi was alive until that
detective there got the call, right?
We were all together with him after that.
Right. The only people that weren't there at the
time were Sagara-san and Suguro-kun over there.
Me? Oh, that can't be.
Suguro Hisashi (28)
Sign Check
The time that I separated from everyone,
Was only for the five minutes between
10:00 and 10:05 in preparation for the ceremony.
Right after that, I heard Ran-san's
scream and ran to the parking lot.
Isn't it impossible to suffocate a
man with gas in just five minutes?
I suppose so.
Sagara-san, you said you went driving, is that right?
Wait, Sagara-san was also the
one who found the owner's body.
Sagara-san, you didn't...
N-no, it wasn't me!
I heard you talking on the balcony yesterday, but...
Don't worry, leave it to me.
The opening ceremony will start tomorrow at 3pm.
So tonight is the last chance.
Exactly. Don't worry about it.
Anyway, we'll stick to the plan. Got it?
Well, Sagara-san?
You see, I went to a friend of mine to borrow money.
Money?
Yes. I was planning to return the
money I'd borrowed and get my car back.
It was boring to just pay back the money,
So I decided to do it just before the
exhibition and embarrass Teraizumi.
That's why I drove all the way to
Tokyo last night to get the money.
If you call my friend, he should be
able to prove my alibi at that time.
It looks like everyone's alibi can be proved.
I guess we can only think of this as an accident.
Excuse me, Inspector.
In honor of the owner's memory,
I'd still like to put Dino up for exhibition.
Well, we're done analyzing the scene now,
So I suppose it's all right.
Thank you very much.
If it wasn't Sagara-san, then who could it be...
Huh, that person last night...
Hey Mr. Manager.
What is it?
Earlier, the analyst person was saying
that there was a crack in the Dino's headlight.
Eh, really?
There wasn't anything like that yesterday.
And if the chief had hit something, he would have
been shouting, "Put it out for repairs!" hysterically.
So that's how it was...
Teraizumi-san hit his car on something when he came back.
But how did the culprit kill Teraizumi-san?
W-what!
Are you sure?
Yes, I looked about the parking lot just before 10:00,
But the owner's car wasn't parked there.
Maybe you missed it because of the fog.
No, I would never mistake owner's car for anything else.
There was another vehicle parked there.
Another car?
Yes. I couldn't see it clearly,
But it was a grayish car.
And it had an engine sound that I'd never heard before.
So it wasn't a regular customer of the hotel.
Then that car's engine was running.
Yes. If it were the owner's car
engine, I could tell right away, so...
Arrgh, what's going on around here?
Inspector Yokomizo.
Please come for a moment.
What is it?
I get it!
Hey, Noda-san, just maybe during that time...
What, Sagara-san is?
Yes. He says that he's returned the money,
so he wants to take his car back right away.
Geez, at a busy time like this...
Let's go.
Little boy, how did you know that?
So, it was like that then?
Yes, it's exactly like you said.
I get it now.
The reason to why the coal
tar was cut off in a straight line,
The identity of the grayish car parked in the parking lot,
And the cracked headlight cover and thread.
All the mysteries are solved!
The culprit is... That person!
Don't do it, Sagara-san.
You can't...
What do you mean I can't?
I returned the money just now.
Either way, I'm going to take what's mine and go home.
Wait a moment, Sagara-san...
What's going on, everyone?
You came at just the right time.
Sagara-san says he's going to get in his
Benz and go home. He just won't listen.
I cannot allow you to do that.
I need you to stay here until this case is settled.
You're saying that this wasn't just an accident?
Yes. It looks like we can no longer say that anymore.
Did you find something?
You see, the guardsman Noda-san says that,
When he looked around 10:00am this morning,
he found a grayish car instead of Teraizumi's vehicle.
What? Then, that means...
Ayeee...
It came, it came, it came!
Are you okay, Uncle?
Mo-Mouri-san!
I've finally got it, Inspector Yokomizo.
From your words just now, everything...
By that you mean...
Teraizumi-san's death was no accident.
It was a planned murder.
Inspector Yokomizo,
Before we start mystery solving, I would
like you to prepare something for me first.
All right.
What do you need?
First, could you get the guardsman, Noda-san?
Hey.
Yes, sir.
And another thing...
A giant plastic sheet.
If possible, something you can put over a car like a cover.
A car cover?
Hey, Suguro-kun,
Weren't you always putting
covers on the cars in the parking lot?
Uh, yes...
Really? Then could we borrow one?
Uh, certainly...
Now that we're all set, shall we begin?
The culprit put Teraizumi-san, who had
returned to the parking lot, to sleep with drugs,
Sat him in Dino's driver's seat,
Then turned on the engine and left it running.
Heh, then that means that it's
impossible for me to have done it.
When I left for Tokyo,
Teraizumi's car still hadn't returned.
You can't confirm that.
What?
No one saw Teraizumi come back.
How can you prove that
Teraizumi wasn't back yet when you left?
What'd you say?
Come now...
I'm sorry for the interruption, Mouri-san,
But the guardsman, Noda-san,
Says that Teraizumi-san's car wasn't in the
parking lot until just before his body was found.
In reality, it was.
When Noda-san checked the parking lot the first time.
But he says that the car there was a gray one...
That was Teraizumi-san's car.
Eh? What?
But Noda-san says the engine sound was different.
Yes.
That wasn't the sound of the chief's Dino.
It was a completely different car.
Okay then, Inspector Yokomizo,
Please turn on Dino's engine as a test.
All right.
Mouri-san, I've turned on the engine.
How is it, Noda-san?
It's definitely different.
It's not the car that was in the parking lot.
Now then, Inspector Yokomizo,
Let's try placing that car cover upon the vehicle.
Eh?
This cover?
Yes.
Ready, Noda-san?
Listen carefully, please.
All right.
This is it. This is the sound, Inspector!
Really!
But why was there a cover on the Dino?
Oh, I get it.
That's why the window was...
Exactly. That's why the window was open.
To lure the exhaust into the vehicle.
After the culprit put Teraizumi-san to sleep,
He lowered the window and covered the car,
To make sure that the exhaust wouldn't
escape, he stuck the cover firmly to the ground.
Everyone, do you all remember?
Teraizumi-san's last words on the phone.
Hello? Owner?
It's me, Mouri.
Where are you right now?
Wh-where am I?
Why is it so dark?
Dark?
I get it! The reason the chief said it was dark,
Was because there was a cover on the car.
Exactly.
Then the exhaust built up inside the cover,
Entered the vehicle from the open window,
And suffocated Teraizumi-san.
The only thing left to do was to take off the cover,
And it would have been a perfect crime.
But here, something the culprit didn't expect happened.
What's this unexpected event?
One is that the covered vehicle was seen by Noda-san,
You going to the parking lot at that time
wasn't part of your schedule, is that correct?
Yes. The manager told me to
check on the owner's car, so...
And the other thing was Ran's scream.
My scream?
Yes. The culprit who was
probably taking the cover off the vehicle,
Heard Ran's scream and panicked,
And forgot to close the window.
Meaning that the culprit is the one that
came last, after hearing Ran's scream.
Suguro-san, YOU!
Su-Suguro-kun...
Hahaha.
Stop joking around.
Why did I become the culprit just
because I came late to the young lady's scream?
Suguro-san, what's with the stain on your pants?
This was because you spilled wine on them last night.
Yes, that's right.
But later that evening when
you delivered us room service...
Oh, I'm so sorry about the spill on your pants earlier.
No. It was no problem at all.
I changed right away.
Why did you change back into your dirty pair again?
That's my choice to make.
On the headlight cover of Teraizumi-san's car,
There was a crack and a thread.
Your pants must have ripped when
you greeted Teraizumi-san's return
And hit it by accident.
No way.
That's just a bunch of stuff you made up!
Noda-san, when you found the unidentified car,
Why didn't you go check it out?
That's because Suguro-kun told me to
go look around the front of the hotel.
That's bullshit!
On the back of Suguro-san's car cover,
Take a look at the area where the muffler is.
There should be a black substance attached there,
One that has been there for some time.
It's there. Just as Mouri-san said, a black stain.
At the scene where the body was found,
There was a tar stain that
flowed from Dino's exhaust pipes.
As though it had been blocked by something,
The stain was cut off in a straight line.
If you analyze it carefully,
The two vehicle's stains should be exactly the same.
How is that, Suguro-san?
Do you still say that you're innocent?
That's right. I'm the one that murdered Teraizumi!
That Dino was originally my car.
Teraizumi scammed me out of it!
You killed him just because of that?
Just because of that?!
Don't put me in the same
group as some fancy free rich boy!
The car I got on the verge of my company's bankruptcy,
Was something I'd sacrificed everything to obtain.
And Teraizumi just...
Donna kotoba ni kaete
How can I change my words,
so that you may understand
Kimi ni tsutaerareru darou
Since then numerous seasons
arekara ikutsumo no kisetsu ga
have passed by
toorisugita keredo
But you always smiled beside me
itsumo soba de waratteru
watashi nimo ienai koto ga mada hitotsu dake aru
Even I still have one thing I cannot say
Secret Of My Heart
utagattemo nai ne
I hold no suspicions
itsu datte sukoshi no mirai ga areba
Always as long as there is a little future
shinjitsu wa te ni irerareru hazu
I should be able to find the truth
I can't say mou sukoshi dake
I can't say, Just a little more
I'm waiting for a chance
The going was fun, but coming back sure is tiring!
Like they say, "The going is
great but the return is fearsome," huh?
I guess the all-you-can-eat hot-pot was better, eh?
Hey, Dad. Maybe we should have
asked Inspector Yokomizo to give us a ride.
Ah!
That bastard...
He could have said something!
Achoo!
A cold, Inspector Yokomizo?
No, I just felt a chill all of a sudden.
Be careful.
Yeah. I've never caught a cold before.
Really?
Achoo!
I'll never help him again!!
Next Episode Preview
Eri is probably flirting with
some young buck somewhere and...
M-Mom!
My father's missing.
He's not in our room or in any of the other three's rooms.
What's going on?
D-Dad!
Kogoro Mouri, Suspect
(Part 1)
Next on Conan: The Suspect is Mouri Kogorou (Part 1)
Chain lock.
Wait in excited anticipation for the next episode.
Next episode is the usual hostile couple.
Dad, you didn't...
You wouldn't!