Song: Mystery Eyes
Song by: Garnet Crow
There's no shape to flowing water.
There's no figure to flowing winds.
No matter what the case is, the deduction is free.
The always clumsy Uncle Mouri.
This time, it's a bit fatal.
Seeing through the one and only truth.
The appearance of a child, but the brains of an adult.
His name is: Detective Conan.
Because you and I are two different people.
kimi to boku to ha betsu no ikimono dakara
konomi ga chigau aruku hayasa mo omoi no tsutae kata mo
Hobbies, walking speed nor the way we
communicate, our thoughts are different.
iroaseteyuku
Times change.
Amongst the memories of the two, we are.
futari no kioku no naka ima bokura ha
Though troublesome,
tesaguri dakedo
Ever searching for someone else and the future.
hoka no dareka wo mirai wo sagashite yuku
Living stronger than once thought.
omou yori tsuyoku ikite
Seeking a special love.
tokubetsu na ai motometeru
shikana hibi ni nayandari
Getting confused in the tough days.
True heart for mystery eyes
True heart for mystery eyes.
Don't let go of that hand.
mou nido do mayowanai you ni
So that you won't get lost once more.
sono ude wo hanasanaide
Even we hurt each other.
kizutsuke au sono toki mo
Just keep searching for the answers.
tada zutto kotae wo sagashite
mayoi konda toki no naka de
During the times we get lost.
To the next place.
tsugi no basho he
you take your way
You take your way.
dakishimete
Hold me.
I feel so all in secret life
I feel so all in secret life.
Suspect, Mouri Kogorou
(Part 1)
Suspect, Mouri Kogorou.
Part 1.
Beautiful, tender, and plenty of them!
Summer is meant for things like these.
What did you do that for?!
What was that, "Let's go to the
Karuizawa's hotel to lay off the heat?"
Bringing the swimsuit only for yourself.
So his goal was the hotel's pool...
H-hey, I wasn't finished with that.
No way.
I won't lend it to some horny old man.
Besides, it was mom who bought me this MD.
H-hey, wait up!
Come on, I've got a lot of stress
from the constant cases every day.
Except I'm letting you get some sleep every time.
Don't you even feel bad for mom?
She won't know.
Maybe she has the hots for some young guy.
Mom!
No way, what are you guys doing here?
I told you, I came to Karuizawa
with my lawyer friends to kill time.
Then what's with that necktie you were buying earlier?
That was just something a friend of mine asked me to do.
So I asked him to help me pick one out.
Right?
Saku Norihumi (35)
Lawyer
Really?
Was it?
I really thought it was a present for me.
H-hey. Saku-kun!
You're not a kid anymore, can't you pick one out yourself?
Gee, sorry?
I see.
Oh, Usui-san.
Usui Ritsuko (32)
Lawyer
Even the number one queen returns to an
ordinary citizen in front of her husband.
She said a queen...
You don't know?
The attitude that won't let anyone ask
her out in any situation in judicial branch.
Her debate skill that even awes the judges.
The nickname that came to be was "The Queen of Lawyers."
Stop it already.
It's only you guys who call me that.
Shiozawa Kenzou (41)
Lawyer
No, the police officers were saying it too.
"If I go against Kisaki-san, it feels like I'm going against
a beautiful queen, 'your excellency,'" they said.
I think I understand...
But the number one female lawyer right now is,
You, who won that rumored case upon its retrial,
And even brought it to the Supreme Court of Justice.
Something like that is meant to be won.
Sorry, a case that was meant to be won,
Mikasa Yuuji (37)
Lawyer
Was lost all as soon as I went on the case...
No... That's not what I meant...
What I mean is that even in winning a case like that once,
I'm still nowhere near the level of the queen.
Stop it already.
But it's to be admired, even
though you are currently separated,
A couple, the female lawyer that has never lost a case,
And the famous detective with no mystery he cannot solve.
I'm just an unknown man with an
arrogant, high-handed queen as a wife.
Then I guess I'm just a stupid woman,
Who chose to run away from a horny
detective who's weak against women as a soulmate.
Geez, acting all tough.
You have a scrapbook of every last
article regarding Mouri-san's cases.
H-hey!
Then it's the same as dad.
Dad is secretly reading all the articles
about the cases mom does overnight.
Right?
Hey, you idiot!
Now, now, since we are all here at Karuizawa,
Let's all have a drink together tonight.
If Eri doesn't mind... I won't mind.
I-I don't really care...
What's this?
Isn't this a good mood?
No way...
I want to be Ritsuko-sensei's cute lil-boyfriend.
H-hold on Mouri-san.
I'm just kidding.
Dad!
Ritsuko-sensei's lil-hand is cute too!
Everything about you is... From this to that...
Mom!
Stupid drunk...
Wait up!
You should know already he
becomes like that when he gets drunk.
And today, you were also with another man...
Happily buying a necktie and stuff...
Yeah, I shouldn't have bothered to buy something like this.
I'm so angry at how soft I've gotten
that I think my head is going to explode.
Then, is that necktie...?
Yeah, that's right.
Tomorrow is our wedding anniversary.
I felt sorry for you.
And I thought I might forgive him
soon, and decided to send him one.
But it's a good thing I chose not to.
Then give it to me!
H-hey!
I'll give it to Dad for you.
Hold it right there!
I guess I'll give it to him myself...
Geez...
Everyone left already?
Even Dad?
He said he's drunk, so he's
going to sleep in a hotel room here.
Mom, it looks like Dad's in his room.
Do your best!
I know...
Yes?
Kisaki-san?
Sorry to bother you so late.
Is my husband over?
I don't think so...
Is that so?
Is something wrong?
My father's missing.
He's not in our rooms or the other three rooms.
Maybe he was taking a walk outside and fell asleep.
He likes the fresh air, so...
Oh, sorry, I'll go outside and take a look.
Sorry to bother you.
Anyhow, let's go and see.
Sorry, Kisaki-san.
I realized, that no matter how hard
I try, I won't be able to surpass you.
In order for me to climb higher than you,
I need you to fall for me.
If others think something
happened between your husband and I,
Your flawless image will begin to sway,
And eventually, you'll have to pass the crown to another.
To this Usui Ritsuko.
Geez, she came again?
She's really stubborn.
Oh, what's up?
Mouri-san's still not back, is that true?
Yeah, I've checked the outside of the hotel, the
rooftop, the stairs, and other numerous places, but...
It's already 2:00am.
That's strange.
They said their rooms are on the
same floor, so he returned with Usui-san.
I see. That means the only place left is...
Just Usui-san's room.
This wasn't here earlier.
Earlier?
We came here earlier too.
But she said he wasn't here.
Of course not.
Those two? They can't be...
Mom, what are you...
Shh, be quiet.
What's that?
There's no mistake, it's that person's cellphone ringer.
No way!
Mikasa-kun, would you go get
the master key from the front desk?
Right!
Here you go.
Thank you.
There's a chain lock.
What's wrong?
H-hey, isn't that Usui-san?!
Sir, please bring the chain cutters immediately!
Get back, we can't wait for something like that!
Hey, Usui-san!
Usui-san!
Hey, what's wrong, hey!
Wait.
She's got no pulse already...
T-that can't be...
Why in the world...
Geez, so noisy over there,
What is it?
Dad!
D-dear?
Why...
There was a chain lock on the door.
And Usui-san's body is on the floor.
And the only person in this locked room was...
Hey, hey, what in the world is...
Wait, don't step there!
The phone cord over there, it's probably the weapon.
W-weapon!
Look, there's a thick mark left on Usui-san's neck, right?
I see, she was strangled to death with the phone cord.
H-hey, why is Ritsuko-sensei...?
Hey, murder?
Who did it?
None other than you!
Why did you kill her?
W-wait, there must be some mistake!
My father can't kill a person.
Right, Mom?
Criminal Law, Article 199.
If one committed a murder,
He will have a life sentence with a minimum of three
years of solitary confinement with no chance of parole,
In the worst case, execution.
R-right...
Mom!
Ran, what are you doing?
Hurry up and call the police.
Hey, hey, hey...
Hmm, so the matter is like this.
Your husband was missing,
And you thought this room was suspicious,
So you called the cellphone in front of the door.
Then, you heard your
husband's phone from inside the room,
And when you opened the
door with the master key to enter,
The chain lock was on,
And you saw this woman on the
floor from the opening of the door.
Yamamura, Inspector
Gunma Kenkei Police Officer
Then breaking the door and gaining
the entrance to the room,
You found the woman was already dead,
And at that time, your husband was sleeping on this bed.
Yes...
Sorry to tell you, but the culprit will become your husband.
But...
Dad, stop being quiet and say something.
Hey, aren't you Mouri Kogorou-san?
Yeah...
How lucky!
If the famous detective such as
yourself is here, then it's no problem!
Please tell me your point of view on this case.
Yeah, why don't you tell him all about the time of the crime?
Mr. Detective who was snoring aloud on this bed.
Husband? You, Mouri-san?
B-but that means...
Then, are you the culprit?
That can't be. What are you going to do?
What about the deduction show of the "Sleeping Kogorou?"
What do I care?!
Inspector Yamamura, shall I escort him to the station
as an important reference personnel for the time being?
Yes, as long as it's alright with Mouri-san.
Dad...
Aw, I wanted to see the deduction show.
Then the attorney would be Eri-san, right?
Attorney?
It's a lawyer who makes sure that the
police don't ask unreasonable questions.
Sorry, but I'll pass.
I don't want to be the lawyer of
someone who's guilty to begin with.
Besides, I don't want to hurt my lossless reputation.
The same goes for me.
If you show your face at the station for no
apparent reason, I won't be too kind about it.
Dad!
Mom!
Then I'll be the attorney.
I can't believe Mouri-san would kill her.
Let's go.
Thank you very much.
Oh, Mikasa-kun and
Shiozawa-san, can you leave for a few moments?
I have something I want to say to the inspector.
Sure, I don't mind.
A talk?
Excuse me, inspector.
Yes?
May I borrow some gloves?
Some gloves?
M-mom, what are you...
The unsettling points are following three.
The first: The phone cord used as the weapon.
If he committed the murder under influence of alcohol,
he would have torn the cord from its socket and used it.
But the phone doesn't look like it's been moved.
And there's no trace of forced
marks on either end of the cord.
The second: That person's cellphone.
The fact that it was placed so close to the door so that its
ringer can be heard from outside seems like it was set-up.
The third: That person's hands.
It's only been about 40 minutes since the last
time we saw her until we found her body here.
If he used the cord to kill her, shouldn't
there be marks left on his hands by the cord?
If he was wearing leather gloves,
then it would be a different story.
But there wasn't anything like that in this room.
I see, now that you mention it...
Then the reason you didn't go
with Dad but chose to stay here was...
You idiot, I've been with him twice longer than you have.
I did get a bit angry at the start,
But I know he's not capable of killing a person.
Then, when Dad told you not
to show your face at the station
He wanted you to stay here and prove his innocence?
Who knows. Maybe he really doesn't want to see my face.
Oh? The memo on the desk, it's been torn out.
Maybe this is that torn memo.
See, it's all crunched up, but there's something written on it.
It's Usui-san's writing.
Hayashi and the number 2?
Maybe it's about the lawyer,
Hayashi, she was to team with soon.
He wanted to talk to her about the rumored case.
The rumored case?
The case that everyone has been talking
about, the recent case on the factory's sewage.
At first, the request came to us, but
neither I nor Shiozawa-san wanted it.
Saku-kun is a specialist in criminal matters,
So Usui-san and Mikasa-kun took the case.
But they lost the first trial,
And at the second trial, they
somehow managed to get back.
But in order to get a definite win, she asked
me to find someone else to replace Mikasa-kun.
So I asked Hayashi-san.
But I haven't told her about Hayashi-san yet.
Also, it's strange since I never told
Hayashi-san that we were staying in this hotel tonight.
He said he heard it from Shiozawa-sama.
Oh I'm sorry, I was the one who
connected Hayashi-sama's call to this room.
What are you doing here without permission?
I had some things that I thought I should tell you, inspector.
Something bothersome?
There were two calls from Hayashi-sama.
The first time it connected fine, but...
The second time, I couldn't get it connected.
So I came over to this room to check things out.
About twice.
Twice!
Yes, at first I rang the bell, but there was no answer,
So I told him that she was probably asleep.
But Hayashi-sama told me that
she might just be in the shower,
So he told me to go and check again.
Then, there was a paper on
the door along with the DND sign.
DND: Do Not Disturb
Paper?
Yes...
It said, "Sorry, I will pay the
money later," which I didn't understand...
Did you tell that to Hayashi-san?
Did you?
Yes, but Hayashi-sama was confused,
And said that all he wanted was to change
the meeting time tomorrow from 2:00 to 4:00.
What does this mean?
The memo in the trash probably meant that
she had an appointment with Hayashi-san at 2:00.
Yes, but the one on the door was
about something completely different.
If Usui-san was already murdered at the
time when the second phone connection failed,
Then the note and the card left on the door the second
time he came here would mean it was the culprit's doing.
But even if the culprit wasn't Uncle,
What could the culprit
accomplish from doing something so stupid?
Donna kotoba ni kaete
How can I change my words,
so that you may understand
Kimi ni tsutaerareru darou
Since then numerous seasons
arekara ikutsumo no kisetsu ga
have passed by
toorisugita keredo
But you always smiled beside me
itsumo soba de waratteru
watashi nimo ienai koto ga mada hitotsu dake aru
Even I still have one thing I cannot say
Secret Of My Heart
utagattemo nai ne
I hold no suspicions
itsu datte sukoshi no mirai ga areba
Always as long as there is a little future
shinjitsu wa te ni irerareru hazu
I should be able to find the truth
I can't say mou sukoshi dake
I can't say, Just a little more
I'm waiting for a chance
Next Episode Preview
Ma'am, I'm sorry to tell you.
But the culprit is none other than your husband!
If I recall... If I recall...
I see, that's why that person left that note.
Other than the fact that you're the culprit,
There is no other reason for you to enter this room.
Suspect, Mouri Kogorou
(Part 2)
Next Conan: Suspect, Mouri Kogorou, Part 2.
Next Conan's Hint.
Hayashi Rice.
Wait in excited anticipation for the next episode.
Next episode, Uncle will be even more cornered.
Mom, help him!
He can do whatever he wants.
The horny old man!