Song: Mystery Eyes
Song by: Garnet Crow
There's no shape to flowing water.
There's no figure to flowing winds.
No matter what the case is, the deductions are free.
Suspect, Uncle, worst case scenario.
The last hope is this person, as predicted.
Seeing through the one and only truth,
The appearance of a child but the brains of an adult,
That name is: Detective Conan.
kimi to boku to ha betsu no ikimono dakara
konomi ga chigau aruku hayasa mo omoi no tsutae kata mo
iroaseteyuku
futari no kioku no naka ima bokura ha
tesaguri dakedo
hoka no dareka wo mirai wo sagashite yuku
omou yori tsuyoku ikite
tokubetsu na ai motometeru
shikana hibi ni nayandari
True heart for mystery eyes
mou nido do mayowanai you ni
sono ude wo hanasanaide
kizutsuke au sono toki mo
tada zutto kotae wo sagashite
mayoi konda toki no naka de
tsugi no basho he
you take your way
dakishimete
I feel so all in secret life
We, who have come to a hotel in Karuizawa,
Came upon Kisaki Eri-san, who
had come with her lawyer friends.
That night, while looking for Uncle,
who had disappeared after he got drunk,
We discovered Usui Ritsuko-san dead in her room.
Furthermore, Uncle was sleeping in that room.
Of course, he was taken to the
station as an important reference.
Us who stayed...
Then the reason you didn't go
with Dad but chose to stay here was...
You idiot, I've been with him twice longer than you have.
I did get a bit angry at the start,
But I know he's not capable of killing a person.
Suspect, Mouri Kogorou
(Part 2)
Suspect, Mouri Kogorou.
Part 2!
"Sorry, I will pay the money later."
That's strange.
Could it be exchange of money between lawyers?
Usui-san, who has been murdered, and
Hayashi-san surely haven't met face to face.
First of all, I never even told her about Hayashi-san,
And there's no way there can
be any money being exchanged.
R-right...
And Hayashi-san, who
decided to help with the court debate,
Wanted to contact Usui-san as soon as possible.
So, he asked his friend Shiozawa-san
where Usui-san was, and gave a call here.
From the memo that was tossed into the trash,
And from the guardsman's testimony, it looks
like they were going to meet tomorrow at 2:00pm.
But we don't know what the one on the door is for.
Huh?
Aren't you the one who was
with Yukiko-san in the last case?
Th-this guy... I thought I saw him somewhere.
Yamamura, Inspector
Gunma Kenkei Police Officer
Gunma Province area's idiot investigator!
What's up, Inspector?
Aren't you stationed at Karuizawa Nagano Province?
Yes, but this place is really close to
Gunma, so we're in charge of the policing.
Oh, you've met Yukiko and this child already?
Yes, it looks like her husband came after, too.
But they pulled me all around the
case, and it was quite exhausting.
Especially this Musu...
Mu... Mu... That tubby Ojii-san was the culprit right?
Uh... Yeah...
Inspector Yamamura.
I-Is that true?
Ma'am, I'm sorry to tell you this,
But the culprit appears to be your husband.
Your husband's fingerprints were found
on the phone cord used as the weapon.
Furthermore, there are witnesses who say they
saw your husband and the victim having a quarrel.
The culprit is undoubtedly your husband!
I told you earlier that there were no
marks left on my husband's hands.
He's a famous detective, furthermore, he's a pro in murders,
He probably came up with some
original way to not leave any traces.
But, just from getting drunk and having a fight?
The true motive is probably his cases.
He, who had crammed every trick
into his head, wanted to try it out himself!
Whoa, how scary!
This is bad.
If I leave things to this idiot,
then Uncle will become the culprit.
Hey Inspector, I found something strange by the door.
Look! Right here there's... Oh?
If you're talking about that thread,
then I've already given it to the CSI.
Thread?
Yes, it was on the floor.
A thin thread about three cm long with a knot tied in it,
Along with the broken piece of the chain lock.
Then, did you get a close look at that piece of the chain?
Yes, I saw it.
Upon the broken piece, there
was a strange mark left behind.
T-then...
Yeah, I've gotten most of the closed room's trick.
T-trick?
But...
Right, the evidence.
The reason behind using the phone cord as the weapon,
Placing Uncle's cellphone by the door,
The reason behind putting up the card on the door,
And I even have an idea of who the culprit is.
But, there's no proof.
Hey, the MD I bought you last time, do you have it here?
Huh? I do, but...
May I borrow it?
I can't focus my thoughts unless I'm listening to music.
And, I still don't get what that note on the door was for.
Huh? There's nothing in this MD.
Really? H-hey! That's the record button!
Oh! Sorry about that.
The MD we have, we use
specifically for recording, so I mistakenly...
Geez...
Mistake?
W-wait a second...
Upon that desk...
There was...
I see, that's why that person left that note.
Hey, you can't stand on chairs with your dirty shoes!
But, I'm hungry.
I thought you were acting like an
adult, but you're still so immature.
But, I'm so hungry.
It can't be helped, can it? I'll
get you some room service later.
H-hey, isn't that...
Oh, Saku-kun.
How did he act at the police station?
Well, it seems like Mouri-san was really drunk,
And he can't even remember why he was in her room.
The police can't even believe it, that the famous
Detective Mouri was the murderer and was stuttering.
Really...
Sorry Kisaki-san, but the culprit can only be Mouri-san.
The room Usui-san was in had the chain
lock on, and therefore was a locked room.
Mouri-san was asleep on the bed in that room also.
The way of the murder is also a problem.
If he had pushed her aside drunkenly and
by chance had killed her by hitting a bad area,
Then it would be considered an accident,
But she was killed from strangulation by the phone cord.
This is a murder no matter how you look at it.
Yes. If it was murder or violence, then he
would be imprisoned for at least 10 years.
If it was a heavy sentence, then it would
even be life imprisonment, or even execution.
H-hey, Mom!
You were saying earlier that the culprit was someone else.
Oh, that? That was just my mistake.
Oh, Kisaki-san, what was it that you wanted me for?
Oh, there was a problem I just couldn't figure out,
So I wanted to hear your opinion on it.
You're a specialist in criminal investigation, right?
So I thought you would know
a lot about these sorts of things.
Come on, let's go.
Kisaki-san!
Mom!
But, what are we going to do about that case?
You know, the one she was in, with the sewage problem.
If you want, I'll take it over.
Well, unlike her, I don't specialize in this.
The most I could do is to keep them from getting buried.
Oh, a phone call. Sorry, but can you go to her room first?
Sure.
Let's see... Her room was...
Geez.
Hey, it's Oji-san.
Huh, it's only you kid?
Yeah, the inspectors went home.
What are you doing here?
Oh, Kisaki-san said she wanted
to talk to me about something, so...
That's probably about the 3cm or so thread and
the broken piece of the chain that was near this door.
Oba-san said, "With that thread, you can
make a locked room even from the outside."
That can't be.
I had to bust through because the chain lock was on.
How can I use a short thread like that to...
What if the chain was cut from the beginning?
If that cut chain's ends were tied by the thread,
And if you put the tied location and the originally cut chain,
At a place where one can not see them from the opening?
Well?
Right. Afterwards, all you have to do is
break the door open violently with a tackle.
The thread will break, and to us outside, it
would seem like the chain lock was on the entire time.
Isn't that right, Saku-kun?
You tampered with the lock, right, Saku-kun?
What are you talking about?
If Mouri-san had woken up in the
room and removed the chain lock,
Then it would become obvious that...
That's why you used the phone cord as
the weapon, so that the phone wouldn't ring.
Placed my husband's cellphone
away from the bed and near the door,
And put the "Please Do Not Disturb"
sign on the outside knob of the door.
It was to prevent anyone from ringing the bell, right?
To prevent waking up my husband who
was sleeping on the bed after he got drunk.
Well, the reason you placed the phone near the door,
Was to make the ringing easier to hear from the outside,
And to let us know that my husband was inside the room.
Then to let us open the door with the master key.
But if I didn't make the call at that time,
You were planning to do so, right?
You are indeed Kisaki-san.
Your words are well thought through.
But in this case, it's best that you don't
get on Mouri-san's side and be his lawyer.
There's no proof that I did it,
And I don't want to leave a
black mark on your undefeated score.
You idiot, the only reason I'm still
undefeated is because my fluke has been continuing.
I feel like I want to lose once to get rid of the pressure.
It's too bad, but it looks like it will still continue,
Because you already confessed that you were
the culprit the moment you stepped into this room.
How did you know that this was her room?
Of course I knew, because in front of
the room, there were Hayashi rice pl...
Oh, what about the Hayashi rice?
T-that's...
Right, probably after you killed Usui-san,
While you were still making the
chain lock's trick, the bell rang.
From the peephole on the door,
you saw the hotel service personnel,
And on the desk was the memo with Hayashi 2 on it.
That's why you got angry, tore the
memo out, and tossed it into the trash, right?
Thinking, "To order Hayashi rice at a time like this."
Then, you left a note on the door
saying, "I will pay for them later,"
To prevent him from ringing the
bell again, along with the DND sign.
Unless that's the case, the words
"Hayashi Rice" would never come from your lips.
I just happened to see the service
personnel that brought the Hayashi rice to her room.
That's why I knew this was her room.
Sorry, but that memo with "Hayashi,"
It really meant a meeting with Hayashi-san at 2:00pm.
You just mistook it with the room
service menu on the table for the Hayashi rice.
U-uh... Did I say Hayashi rice?
I saw the room number and came in.
Oh, so you still haven't noticed?
Look, the chain lock to this room isn't cut.
This was an empty room that I
had asked the hotel to lend us.
Her real room is two rooms down from this one.
Meaning, there would be no reason for you to
have entered this room, unless you were the culprit.
Sorry to lead you into a trap.
Because you were the opponent, I didn't
think that you would go down so easily.
I've just understood for the first time how the
policemen felt that took you as an opponent.
But, how were you planning to make the police believe you?
The only one that saw me go into this room was you.
Your testimony as Mouri-san's family member is...
Oh, I'm not the only one who saw it.
You mean this kid?
It's not just me either.
Right, Inspector?
Yes, I've been watching.
It was as clear as crystal from
this peep hole in the opposite room.
Right, everyone?
Yes, we saw all your movements!
We've even recorded your talk on video.
I... See...
They were all his ideas, though.
And, was the motive her current case?
Yes, that place the factory is influencing is where I grew up,
And I wanted them to win, no matter what.
I was originally planning to put her to sleep at the door,
Lock the room, and make it look like a suicide.
But Mouri-san was sleeping in the room,
And I thought a person who wanted to commit
suicide wouldn't have brought another man to the room,
And eat Hayashi rice together happily.
So I changed it to a murder
and let Mouri-san take the blame.
If, in order to win the case, it became
one of the villagers that killed the lawyer,
Then it wouldn't look good in front of the judges, so...
Well, I was planning on
turning myself in once they had won.
But even if you did turn yourself in,
there's no proof that says you did it.
Oh, that's...
The paint left on that chain that was a bit different, right?
There is only one paint that matches up with that,
And with that as your proof, you were
planning to bring it to the police, right?
But Usui-san only took it as a
job, did you really have to kill her?
If she really took it as a job for her living,
then I wouldn't have done something like that.
When I learned that she was torturing the people of
the village just to raise her reputation and beat you,
I just couldn't forgive her.
To beat me?
Yes, the reason she brought the drunken
Mouri-san to her room was for that as well.
T-that can't be...
To believe the requester and
become his or her lawyer is our job,
But you believe in them too much.
A person has a front and back side that eyes cannot see.
Even I, who has been wanting
you for a long time for myself.
Oh, thank you.
But, I won't be your lawyer just from something like that.
Ah, sorry.
Man, I wanted to show it to you, too!
Your wife's astonishing deduction.
That's what you call "The Sleeping Kogoro's" wife.
The queen of lawyers; it really touched me!
What were you doing at the time?
As requested by her, I placed the bait, Hayashi rice,
And was watching it from the opposite room.
Then, the moment they entered
the hall, I called her cellphone.
And then, and then!
When the culprit entered the room,
I thought, "Wow, I'm glad I became an inspector."
And... Where is she now?
Look, she's over there, at that table.
Dad!
Lucky, now I can stick around for breakfast!
Wait!
That mood just might be...
Sorry Eri, I believed in you, I believed that
you would be able to prove my innocence.
And, uh... I've been growing tired of Ran's cooking.
And, uh... I wanted to try your different taste in cooking.
Uh... Can you come back to me soon?
I can't take it anymore.
You know, today is our anniversary,
And I thought it would be perfect, and...
Hey, are you listening?
Eh?
What is it?
Uhh... Um...
Dad! Mom!
What is it? What were you two talking about?
No, for the Queen of Lawyers, I thought she took
rather long to prove her beloved man's innocence.
(Sai ai: Beloved, Sai yaku: The worst)
Oh, are you sure you didn't
mistake beloved for "The Worst"?
What!?
Well, I hope you learned your lesson
from this and will stop drinking so much,
Mr. Mustached Sexual Harrassment.
W-what did you say!?
Dad!
Oh, and Ran,
I'm going to borrow this disk for a
while; I'm starting to love this song, so...
Later.
Mom!
Hmph, don't ever show your face again!
Dad, you idiot, idiot, idiot!
Donna kotoba ni kaete
How can I change my words,
so that you may understand
Kimi ni tsutaerareru darou
Since then numerous seasons
arekara ikutsumo no kisetsu ga
have passed by
toorisugita keredo
But you always smiled beside me
itsumo soba de waratteru
watashi nimo ienai koto ga mada hitotsu dake aru
Even I still have one thing I cannot say
Secret Of My Heart
utagattemo nai ne
I hold no suspicions
itsu datte sukoshi no mirai ga areba
Always as long as there is a little future
shinjitsu wa te ni irerareru hazu
I should be able to find the truth
I can't say mou sukoshi dake
I can't say, Just a little more
I'm waiting for a chance
Uh... Can you come back to me soon?
I can't take it anymore.
You know, today is our anniversary,
And I thought it would be perfect, and...
Uh... Can you come back to me soon?
Not yet, I won't forgive you for just something like this!
Did I catch a cold?
Doubt it.
Next Episode Preview
Most likely, there was poison in the tea inside of the bottle.
Hey, what's up with this town!?
What happened seven years ago in this town?
What does this all mean?
The 10th Passenger
(Part 1)
Next Conan: The 10th Passenger, Part 1.
Next Conan's Hint: Plastic Bottle.
Wait in excited anticipation for the next episode.
Next time is a bonnet bus!
Oh, that thing tied with a thread that looks delicious!
That's a boneless ham.