Song: Mystery Eyes
Song by: Garnet Crow
There's no shape to flowing water.
There's no figure to flowing wind.
No matter what the case is the deductions are free.
Today is the nostalgic bonnet bus.
Traveling through time, it brings a case.
Seeing through the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child but the brains of an adult...
That name is: Detective Conan!
Because you and I are two different people.
kimi to boku to ha betsu no ikimono dakara
konomi ga chigau aruku hayasa mo omoi no tsutae kata mo
Hobbies, walking speed nor the way we
communicate, our thoughts are different.
iroaseteyuku
Times change.
Amongst the memories of the two, we are.
futari no kioku no naka ima bokura ha
Though troublesome,
tesaguri dakedo
Ever searching for someone else and the future.
hoka no dareka wo mirai wo sagashite yuku
Living stronger than once thought.
omou yori tsuyoku ikite
Seeking a special love.
tokubetsu na ai motometeru
shikana hibi ni nayandari
Getting confused in the tough days.
True heart for mystery eyes
True heart for mystery eyes.
Don't let go of that hand.
mou nido do mayowanai you ni
So that you won't get lost once more.
sono ude wo hanasanaide
Even we hurt each other.
kizutsuke au sono toki mo
Just keep searching for the answers.
tada zutto kotae wo sagashite
mayoi konda toki no naka de
During the times we get lost.
To the next place.
tsugi no basho he
you take your way
You take your way.
dakishimete
Hold me.
I feel so all in secret life
I feel so all in secret life.
The 10th Passenger
(Part 1)
The 10th Passenger. Part 1.
Wow, that feels good.
The air is clean too.
This bus is really nostalgic.
It feels great without the air conditioning on.
Jeez, why do I have to sit on an old bus nowadays?
It's because its old that makes it good.
I didn't even know about it so it's pretty new to me.
So, what was this bus called?
A bonnet bus.
Until about 30 years ago, they were in use all over Japan.
Look, it has a skinny tip.
That's why it's easier for it to
slide past one another on a curve.
That's exactly it.
I'm surprised you knew that.
I read it in a book.
This brat knows a lot of crap that doesn't matter.
No, it's not something that doesn't matter.
Yabe Takurou (32)
For us Kagekura villagers,
The bonnet bus is an important tourist attraction.
Uh, no... I didn't mean that.
I'm Yabe Takurou from Kagekura Village.
Oh, the youth group leader?
Along with the bonnet bus,
enjoy yourself at Kagekura Village.
Everyone, there may not be much in Kagekura Village,
But there is a lot of nature.
Please enjoy your stays!
He's a bright fellow.
Natsume Touko (25)
Bus Guide
Hey, Natsume-kun,
Go and guide me, please.
Oh right, sorry.
Hey, isn't this boulder something that fell from the top?
Wow.
Are you sure we're okay?
That was scary.
A memorial...
Kagekura Village
Hey.
Oh, the seat next to me is open.
Okumura Souchiki (60)
Kagekura Village Deputy Mayor
Hurry up and move.
That's my seat.
Yours...? Does this bus have reserved seating?
Stop it, Okumura-san.
Today's a Sunday.
I know that.
We decided at the village meeting
to give guests the seats on weekends.
Hmph, that was just something you
and the village chief decided on your own.
W-what?!
How interesting, are you going to force me to stop?
If you can, go right ahead.
Move it!
For 40 years, this seat has been mine.
Sorry about that, sir.
Please take another seat.
What the heck is up with this bus?
Hmm, it gets pretty crowded.
For the people of the area, it's not just for tourism,
But it also acts as their feet.
What?!
What's wrong, Okumura-san?
Did something happen?!
W-what is it?
I think someone fell due to illness.
I'll go to the hospital immediately.
Kajita Mamoru (35)
Bus Driver
There's no point.
Does that mean...?
He's already dead.
Most likely, there was poison placed inside the bottle.
Nobody move!
No one is to get off the bus until the police arrive.
Eh... Why?
Wait, you don't have to go that far...
Especially you, Yabe-san.
If this is a murder,
The one who argued with the victim
and sat right behind him is a prime suspect.
M-murder... Who... In the world...
I'm Mouri Kogorou, a municipal detective.
Mouri... That famous...
Then that means this is a big case.
There's no doubt about it.
But who did such a thing?
Thank you for your trouble.
Shinkai Hitoshi Jyunsa (28)
Kagekura Village Substation Officer
I am the Kagekura Village Substation Officer.
I'm very happy to be able to investigate
this case with the famous Detective Mouri.
I see that you're an officer with great potential.
I shall do everything that I can to help.
Thank you very much.
By the way, I heard it was a murder case.
Is that true?
If that is the case, then that means...
Uhh, we'll have to take a closer look before we can...
It's a murder.
Stop sticking your nose where it doesn't belong!
Look at the plastic bottle.
Plastic bottle?
Look, the tea is leaking,
From a hole likely made by a needle.
It is! Could the poison have been injected by a needle then?
Alright, check everyone!
The one with the needle is the culprit!
I don't know...
The windows were open.
If the culprit wanted to toss it, he
or she could've done so whenever.
Also, the culprit could've
been someone that already got off.
There's going to be a storm...
Not just a storm...
It's going to be a war!
What?
A war!?
This is bad!
What should we do?
It's going to rain blood!
Rain blood?
Mouri-san, they found a needle,
From the ditch next to the bus route.
Although there's only a little, they found traces of poison.
And what about fingerprints?
Shinkai Jyunsa.
Inspector Hino.
Hino Shyouhei (41)
Jurisdiction Department, Inspector
I can't have you freely giving out case reports.
This means there weren't any, right?
Fingerprints...
If there were, you'd be asking for
everyone's prints and comparing them.
Y-yes, that's exactly right.
Who are these folks?
This is the famous detective, Mouri Kogorou-san.
They just happened to be on the bus.
Sleeping Kogorou would like to help with the investigation.
How stupid.
Someone's probably solving the
cases for you while you're sleeping.
Heh... He got it right.
Well, do what you want without getting in our way.
What a rude bastard.
Then let's do what we want.
You don't need the Inspector's help to solve this case, right?
Of course!
Just watch, Inspector Hino!
I'll show you!
Mouri-san, I'll help you out as much as I can as well.
I won't forgive him.
To commit a crime in front of me so boldly...
I'll find the culprit myself!
Sorry to tell you,
But until the questioning is over,
I would like you all to stay here.
Well, actually... This is the only
place in the village you can stay anyway.
Oh, Shinkai Jyunsa.
The only place, what a horrible thing to say.
Oh Hostess, I didn't mean...
Komai Kinu (42)
Hostess
I'm just kidding.
Welcome to Komai Inn.
It's a beautiful inn with an old-time charm.
Yeah, wooden structures are great.
Very gentle to people.
Thank you.
This place is a neutral area, so...
Neutral?
You've been saying a lot of stuff that doesn't make sense.
Something about a storm and a war.
Oh... That's...
You will know in time.
But first, please check into your rooms.
Hmm, you can see Mt. Fuji from this village.
This is great!
You're Conan-kun, right?
Is that your room?
Bus Guide Onee-san!
Your room is right beside ours.
Yeah, I can get the best view of Mt. Fuji from this place.
Mouri-san, it's an emergency!
What's up?
You see, the Inspector is at
the station questioning Yabe-san.
Just as I thought.
That man is the prime suspect, right?
Well, I don't know about that...
But the problem is at the place of questioning.
The place?
If it was at the Jurisdiction building, it'd be fine.
But down at the station, the supporting side
and the opposing side came barging in and...
A supporting and opposing side?
Please go home.
We'll do the questioning here!
We can't trust you, give us Yabe!
He's the one that did it!
Hand him over!
That's right!
What are you talking about?
Yabe-kun isn't the culprit!
He's innocent!
Chief, you told Yabe to do it, right?
I'll get you!
Stop it or I'll arrest you all for disturbing the peace!
Stop it, calm down!
Everyone please calm yourselves!
Uncle!
Dad!
Are you alright, Mouri-san?
Stop...
STOP IT!
Yes, the commotion over here
has stopped and everyone left.
Yes.
Thank you for your assistance!
Now it'll be fine.
Mouri-san, the police car with
Yabe-san got to the jurisdiction building safely.
That's fine and dandy, but what's up with this town?
You see, until about a year
ago, stuff like this never happened.
But when we decided at a village meeting to
use the bonnet bus as a way to get tourists,
The supporting side, lead by the village
chief and Yabe-san's tourist development,
And the opposing side, lead by the
deceased Mr. Okumura, began to fight.
That bus was originally used as the villager's feet.
It's a small town and everyone knows everyone else.
So their seats formed naturally and
was thought to be the way it should be.
They decided to open the
seats for tourists on the weekends...
But Mr. Okumura and other
protagonists refused to give up their seats, right?
Yeah, and they became even more opposed to it.
But I never thought it would come down to murder.
Yabe-kun is innocent!
Sorry about earlier, I'm the village chief, Funaki.
I hear that you're a famous detective.
Funaki Takehiko (48)
Kagekura Village, Village Chief
I would like you to take our request.
The one who killed Mr. Okumura is not Yabe-kun!
I don't want to sound rude but
there were many who hated him.
Even on the opposition.
I would like for you to find the real culprit.
But that may still be Yabe-san.
Whatever happens, happens.
Either way, I would like peace to
return to the village as soon as possible.
To think, the horrible memories from seven years
ago have just begun to fade and now this happens.
The memories from seven years ago?
Oh, it's nothing, it's our business.
But, will you take the case for one million?
O-one million!
Whatever the case, I want to stop
this commotion as soon as possible.
Well, I'll leave things to you then.
Alright, let's go do some investigating!
In that case, I'll be your guide.
Excuse me, was Okumura-san, who
passed away, always at that location at that time?
Go home.
I would like to ask you about it...
May I speak to you...
Hey, what's going on in this town?!
In reality, there are more that oppose.
Word probably got out that you took
the chief's side and are on the move.
So...
Damn it, this can't even be considered an investigation.
Ran, take Conan and return to the Inn.
I'll go around a bit more.
Alright.
Oh, you can start supper without me.
Don't wait up.
Hey Mr. Policeman...
What is it, Conan-kun?
Did something happen seven years ago,
In this town?
Oh, you mean what Chief
Funaki was talking about earlier, right?
It was an accident. A bus accident.
A bus accident?
Do you mean that bonnet bus?
But, we repaired the bus.
What was the cause of the accident?
Did someone get hurt or die from it?
Well, I wasn't here seven years ago.
So I don't know many details.
I think about two people died.
What about it?
Nothing, I just wanted to ask.
Hey Shinkai Jyunsa, let's go!
S-sir! I'm coming!
A bus accident seven years ago...
Chief Funaki's agitation...
And his offering of one million...
Something's up.
They look delicious!
I hope they suit your taste.
They're all wild plant dishes.
Onee-san!
Bus Guide Onee-san!
Conan-kun, what are you doing?
Touko-san, are you there?
What's up, Conan-kun?
I have something I want to ask you.
You can't yell like that from here.
Sorry about that.
It's okay.
And what did you wish to ask me?
It's about the bus accident seven years ago.
Sorry Conan-kun, I only started
to work here about half a year ago.
I've heard about the accident, but
I don't know many details about it.
I see...
But I go by there everyday so I
suppose I can't say it has nothing to do with me.
It's the place with the memorial stone.
Oh, that place.
The place with the scary cliff?
I hear that two passengers got drunk and violent.
So the driver got distracted and fell off.
Sorry, my hand slipped.
I'll get a replacement immediately.
Are you hurt?
No, I'm fine.
Touko-san, is something wrong?
No, nothing.
Well, I still have to prepare
supper so I'll see you later, Conan-kun.
Jeez, this isn't funny.
It's not just the opposition.
Even the people on the supporting side won't say a word.
Calm down, Dad. The neighbors will hear you!
Hmph, I don't care.
Besides, this place is neutral.
But why doesn't anyone help us?
From what Shinkai Jyunsa said,
Even if they welcome tourists on the surface,
Inside, they think that we don't pick up our garbage,
We destroy nature,
And won't stop screaming until late into the night.
It really makes you think.
So? I can't even do my work over here!
It's not good if we can't get information.
DAMN IT!
What is it, Dad?
Did your usual sleep kick in?
Um...
He just got drunk and fell asleep.
I know!
Conan-kun, can you tell them to set the sheets?
Oh, and the futons as well.
Hurry up!
Alright.
It's Okami-san.
Where's she going with a bouquet of flowers at this hour?
Conan-kun?
Where did he go?
Conan-kun's shoes are missing.
Did he run out?
I'm sorry.
It's Touko-san.
What does it mean... What?
Where are you Conan-kun?
Kagekura Shrine?
He wouldn't be here... Would he?
Hey! What are you doing?!
Oh, you're Conan-kun!
What are you doing in a place like this?
J-just testing my courage...
Don't scare me like that.
But did something happen?
Yabe-san was released because
there wasn't enough evidence to hold him.
I thought I should tell Mouri-san about it.
That was Chief Funaki's voice!
C-Conan-kun!
What are you doing?
Ran!
Donna kotoba ni kaete
How can I change my words,
so that you may understand
Kimi ni tsutaerareru darou
Since then numerous seasons
arekara ikutsumo no kisetsu ga
have passed by
toorisugita keredo
But you always smiled beside me
itsumo soba de waratteru
watashi nimo ienai koto ga mada hitotsu dake aru
Even I still have one thing I cannot say
Secret Of My Heart
utagattemo nai ne
I hold no suspicions
itsu datte sukoshi no mirai ga areba
Always as long as there is a little future
shinjitsu wa te ni irerareru hazu
I should be able to find the truth
I can't say mou sukoshi dake
I can't say, Just a little more
I'm waiting for a chance
Next Episode Preview
One pierce of the heart. His
death was practically immediate.
Arrest him!
Don't resist!
What happened... On that bus?
What? The murderer is on the bus!?
W-what? The brakes don't work?
Oh, no!
The 10th Passenger
(Part 2)
Next Conan:
The 10th Passenger. Part 2.
Next Conan's Hint!
Bank Book.
Wait in excited anticipation for the next episode.
Next time, lots of mysteries will be solved.
Who's the 10th passenger?
That's next time too...