Song: Mystery Eyes
Song by: Garnet Crow
There's no shape to flowing water.
There's no figure to flowing winds.
No matter what the case the deductions are free.
There's a big commotion in a little village.
The case and the bus are on a rampage.
Seeing through the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child but the brains of an adult...
That name is: Detective Conan!
Because you and I are two different people.
kimi to boku to ha betsu no ikimono dakara
konomi ga chigau aruku hayasa mo omoi no tsutae kata mo
Hobbies, walking speed nor the way we
communicate, our thoughts are different.
iroaseteyuku
Times change.
Amongst the memories of the two, we are.
futari no kioku no naka ima bokura ha
Though troublesome,
tesaguri dakedo
Ever searching for someone else and the future.
hoka no dareka wo mirai wo sagashite yuku
Living stronger than once thought.
omou yori tsuyoku ikite
Seeking a special love.
tokubetsu na ai motometeru
shikana hibi ni nayandari
Getting confused in the tough days.
True heart for mystery eyes
True heart for mystery eyes.
Don't let go of that hand.
mou nido do mayowanai you ni
So that you won't get lost once more.
sono ude wo hanasanaide
Even we hurt each other.
kizutsuke au sono toki mo
Just keep searching for the answers.
tada zutto kotae wo sagashite
mayoi konda toki no naka de
During the times we get lost.
To the next place.
tsugi no basho he
you take your way
You take your way.
dakishimete
Hold me.
I feel so all in secret life
I feel so all in secret life.
Conan, Ran, and Uncle Mouri felt
nostalgic due to the bonnet bus,
And went to Kagekura village for a hiking trip.
But during the bus ride, a murder case erupted.
The victim, Mr. Okumura, was the leader of the people
Who were opposed to use of the
bonnet bus as a tourist attraction.
Because the police made their prime
suspect Yabe-san, who is on the supporter's side,
A quarrel broke out in the village.
Furthermore, the bus accident from seven
years ago appears to be intertwined with it.
At that time, the tourism supporting
head, Funaki-san, was attacked at the shrine,
And there is danger approaching Ran.
The 10th Passenger
(Part 2)
The 10th Passenger. Part 2.
Ran-neechan!
Conan-kun.
Are you okay?
Any injuries?
No, I just got tackled.
But, I think there's someone lying there.
Chief Funaki!
One stab in the heart.
His death was practically immediate.
Ran-neechan, did you see the culprit?
I don't know if he is the culprit or not.
But the person who tackled me was...
What kind of a man was he?
What was he wearing? About how old was he?
It was...
The youth group leader, Yabe-san.
What the hell?!
What?! Yabe killed Chief Funaki?
Uh no, we still don't have any confirmation though...
Take me to his house!
Officer Hitoshi Shinkai (28)
Kagekura Village, Substation Officer
Well, they told me to wait until I received a reply
from the station after they had analyzed the situation.
Listen up!
If anything had gone wrong,
Ran might've ended up like the village chief!
Take me there now!
Hey, Yabe Takurou.
Don't fuck with me!
Wait, we still don't have permission to...
Yabe, don't resist!
Damn, he ran away...
The weekly paper is still in his door.
He probably never came back.
That means after he was released from the station,
He called the village chief out immediately and killed him.
Then he ran away.
It was planned...
Mouri-san...
Alright, seal off the vicinity.
Yes, sir!
A bank book?
200,000 has been deposited
every month for the last two years.
Why isn't it in the mail records,
and why in a bank not in this village?
This money, could it be...?!
The following day, to search for the fleeing Yabe-san,
They decided to comb the mountain.
It looks like we've ended up
in the same place, Mr. Detective.
Hino Shyouhei (41)
Jurisdiction Station, Inspector
Hmph, I don't want to help you.
But I can't leave someone as dangerous as him out there.
I'm participate myself.
The villagers agreed to help with the search,
And the tension between the
two sides is about to reach its peak.
Is the confusion of the villagers what the culprit wants?
Or is there another objective...
First of all, is the culprit really Yabe-san?
If it was a planned murder,
he would have brought his bank book.
There are other things I still don't know.
The terrified expression of the
hostess who dropped her cooking,
And her crying at the memorial stone.
There's also Touko-san, who saw it all.
It looks like the origin of everything
is the bus accident seven years ago.
Damn it, taking my one million I was
supposed to receive from the village chief...
That Yabe, I will catch him!
Hello?
Oh, it's you Shinichi!
It looks like a pretty troublesome case occurred.
Yeah, I need you to look
through articles from seven years ago.
Oh, let me look at the homepages of newspaper agencies.
I found him!
He's over here!
Get back here, I won't let you get away!
Give me back my million yen!
Let's see... Seven years ago... Seven years ago...
Oh, this must be it.
A bus ran off a cliff.
Two passengers were killed, and eight injured.
And do you know the passengers' names?
Yeah, it's the local paper so everyone's names are posted.
First, the injured are...
I've got you, Yabe!
Give it up!
I-i-it wasn't me!
Yabe Takurou (32)
Kagekura Village, Youth Group Leader
I didn't do anything!
The fact that you ran proves that you're the culprit!
Yabe Takurou, you're under arrest for murder!
Eh... What?!
Mr. Okumura wasn't on it?
Yeah, there's no name like that.
Then could Mr. Okumura have been...
And the names of the deceased were...
Tezuka Youichi-san, age 28,
And Noritsubu Kouhei-san, age 55.
Professor, check the family
history for those two immediately.
No, that's not it!
When I went to the shrine, I heard Chief Funaki's scream.
When I hurriedly ran there, your daughter came!
I got scared that I might be arrested if I stayed,
so I ran and accidentally bumped into your daughter.
Enough bullshit!
Then why were you at a place like that?
I was called out by Chief Funaki.
Called out?
To a cold, empty place like that?
Uh... That was because...
You... Do you expect us to believe that
you're innocent when you don't tell us anything?
Isn't that impossible?
What's this?
It's a bank book found in your home.
200,000 yen has been deposited
each month for the past two years.
It's not to a local bank nor mail.
It's a bank that doesn't exist in this village.
That means... It was money that you didn't
want the people of the village to know about, right?
I was giving information.
Information?
You were a spy for the opposition?!
Yes...
I was hired by the opposition leader, Mr. Okumura,
And told everything about Chief
Funaki's thoughts and movements.
But why would Mr. Okumura go that far to...
If new developments were to happen,
Then the village's money
would go into Chief Funaki's pocket.
If that happened,
Certain companies of Mr. Okumura and the
opposition members would get shut down.
So, he wanted to crush the plan beforehand.
That was found out, so you were
called out to the shrine by Chief Funaki.
Yes...
It seems that while I was being transferred,
he saw the bank book in my home.
Meaning, you killed Mr.
Okumura before you were discovered,
And you killed Chief Funaki
because he discovered your secret.
N-no! That's not it!
It wasn't me!
Komai Inn Hostess
Komai Kinu (42)
Can you tell me the story, Hostess?
This serial murder case...
The culprit's motive is not from the opposition of the village,
But rather might be the bus accident from seven years ago.
Seven years ago? That can't be!
If that's the case then the culprit isn't Yabe-san,
Because, seven years ago, he was on that bus.
And Hostess, you too.
What happened...?
On that bus?
Departure, ready!
Bus Guide
Natsume Touko (25)
Kajita Mamoru (35)
Tour Bus Driver
That's the truth behind the bus accident seven years ago.
Just as I thought.
That's why Chief Funaki feared the truth being revealed,
And was willing to pay one million
for Uncle to stop the commotion.
Hello?
I found the family history to the victims of the bus accident.
It was in the family news' article.
Yeah. Yeah.
Eh... What?!
That person?!
Got it, thanks.
Hostess, what time does the bus that
runs at the same time as the accident leave?
The bus should have already left by now.
Oh, no!
Hostess, please catch up to the bus.
I don't want to shift any more blame onto that person.
Please, get there on time!
T-that can't be...
The breaks aren't working!
What?!
You've got to be kidding!
It's all downhill from this point on!
Yabe-san was the culprit?
Yeah, they say he will be
transferred to the station in the afternoon.
Then, your job would be...
Yeah, it's over.
Not only did I not get my one million,
It was completely non profit.
Jeez, that was some hiking...
Hmm, come to think of it, where's Conan-kun?
I see it! It's over there!
Kajita, do something!
I'm already using the engine break.
The wire to the side break is cut!
The break to the bus isn't working!
Hostess, pull the car up alongside the bus.
Eh... What are you planning to do?
I'm going to hop onto the bus.
H-hey, young man!
That's dangerous, stop!
This is the same as seven years ago.
Come to think of it, the faces are the same as well.
I-it couldn't be, must be a coincidence...
No, it's no coincidence.
Conan-kun!
When did you...
I heard from someone,
That seven years ago, all of you were on this bus;
The murdered Chief Funaki,
And even the youth group's Yabe-san,
who was arrested as the culprit,
All together it was 10 people.
You all remember what happened, right?
The hostess of the Kamai Inn, who told me the story,
Was the bus guide at the time.
Come on!
Tezuka Youichi (29)
Komai Kinu (35)
Guest
Bus
Guide
Drink with me.
Help me, someone!
Don't be so hesitant.
Someone stop him!
Please!
Help me!
You! Stop it already!
She's offended by it!
What did you say?
I'm trying to have a little fun here.
Stop bothering me!
The people killed in the accident,
Was the man that harassed her,
And the guest that tried to save her.
The people that were
miraculously saved were eight villagers.
In the end, everyone stayed quiet.
The cause of the accident was
determined to be those two having a violent fight,
Forgetting all about one valiant individual,
And the passengers that watched him die.
You all should know after I said that much...
The culprit for this case...
Is family to that brave individual, Moritsugu Kouhei-san.
The motive is revenge...
Right... Touko-san?
Natsume came from your mother, right?
Your real name is Moritsugu Touko-san.
What, Touko-san is...
That passenger's family?
What?!
The murderer of Mr. Okumura and
Village Chief Funaki-san is on the bus?!
So, who's the real culprit?
I don't know that.
I know that the breaks on the bus
are broken and it's on a rampage.
Hey, call the station immediately!
Yes, sir!
Excuse me, your boy is on that bus as well.
Eh?! Why is Conan-kun...?
Touko-san came to this town to
find the reason for her father's death.
She continued on her
investigation and finally learned the truth,
Most likely from her work companion,
Kajita-san, when he let his guard down.
Ironically, one of the passengers, Yabe-san, was
charged with the murders in the village and was arrested.
Touko-san learned that everyone on that bus
would be on it today for working or shopping,
And tampered with the breaks to kill them all...
At the location of the accident seven years ago.
Memorial Stone
Right, Touko-san?
That can't be...
I don't know what you're talking about.
Acting dumb won't work.
Why are you so calm?
You've taken it to heart already, right?
That you, along with everybody else...
Jeez, what a kid.
Get off Conan-kun.
It should slow down at the next curve slightly.
If you do it right, you'll only get hurt.
Then you confess your crime?
Yes, I confess.
I was the one who murdered Mr. Okumura and Chief Funaki.
I injected poison into Mr.
Okumura's bottle, and then I waited.
And I stabbed Chief Funaki in the dark at the shrine.
That's right, I came back to take
revenge on everyone that was on this bus.
Father was more heroic than the average man.
Helping a person in need came naturally for him.
But that time, if anyone else
would've stood up and helped my father...
Hurry, hurry and jump off!
Conan-kun!
It's already too late.
Even if you let me go,
It wouldn't change the fact
that you killed the wrong person.
The first victim, Mr. Okumura,
wasn't in the accident seven years ago.
What?
That can't be...
As a bus guide who sees him
everyday, you should know his saying.
This seat has been mine for the past 40 years.
If a person who always says that was
asked about what happened seven years ago...
You've asked him, right?
Of course, I confirmed it with him in person.
Seven years ago?
Oh, I was undoubtedly sitting here.
This is MY seat.
He clearly confirmed it.
But that day, Mr. Okumura had a
fever and was sleeping at home.
His name isn't in the papers, either.
N-no way...
I looked at the papers, too...
You were told so confidently
that it made you think it was there.
T-then... The 10th passenger is...
The 10th person passed away two years ago from an illness.
Mr. Okumura had nothing to do with your father's death.
T-that can't...
You forgave the hostess of Kamoi Inn, right?
Right... That person...
I'm sorry...
After seeing that...
I just couldn't lay my hands on her.
Not only the hostess,
But everyone who was involved in that incident,
Has been living with a burden
they could not tell others about.
We're sorry, Touko-chan!
It's all because we didn't have any courage that...
As you can see...
Please forgive us!
If we crash into the accident site like this,
Touko-chan's father might finally be able to rest in peace.
No! Conan-kun has nothing to do with this!
Do something!
That's impossible.
Even if I could make it through the next curve,
I would never be able to make it
through the curve at the scene of the accident.
You can't give up until the end!
There must be some way to stop this!
The ditch!
Drop the wheels into the ditch!
It's no use!
We'll still fly out like this!
Oh yeah, the industrial strength
suspenders the professor invented for me might...
It's no good!
Damn it!
I guess a 10 ton bus is too much!
It stopped...
Conan-kun, who in the world...
I'm just a bothersome detective.
Thank you, little detective.
Stop making us worry so much!
THAT HURT!
Donna kotoba ni kaete
How can I change my words,
so that you may understand
Kimi ni tsutaerareru darou
Since then numerous seasons
arekara ikutsumo no kisetsu ga
have passed by
toorisugita keredo
But you always smiled beside me
itsumo soba de waratteru
watashi nimo ienai koto ga mada hitotsu dake aru
Even I still have one thing I cannot say
Secret Of My Heart
utagattemo nai ne
I hold no suspicions
itsu datte sukoshi no mirai ga areba
Always as long as there is a little future
shinjitsu wa te ni irerareru hazu
I should be able to find the truth
I can't say mou sukoshi dake
I can't say, Just a little more
I'm waiting for a chance
The case was solved.
And now, the bonnet bus is running once more,
Carrying the various memories of individuals.
Calmly through the greens.
Next Episode Preview
Chizuru-san?
Who was she arguing with?
She couldn't be!
Sorry to tell you this but it appears that
it's been some time since she passed away.
No one has entered this room!
I'll keep watch.
Why?
The Black Wings of Icarus
(Part 1)
Next Conan:
The Black Wings of Icarus. Part 1.
Next Conan's Hint!
Lunch Box.
Wait in excited anticipation for the next episode.
Next time is another anime original!
That means the culprit is also original!
Well, duh...