There is no shape to flowing water.
There is no figure to flowing wind.
No matter the case, the deduction is free.
Today's stage is a plateau hotel.
The unwanted guest calls for a case.
Perceiving the one and only truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan.
Excuse me, we would like to get to Hotel Arimori.
Yeah, just go across, and head straight on the road.
Thank you very much.
Dad, I'm surprised you knew about a hotel all the way out here.
It's because this place is known for its great local beer.
Alcohol was his goal again?
Uncle...
That's the place.
We're finally here.
THE BLACK WINGS OF ICARUS
(PART ONE)
Welcome.
I made a reservation, under Mouri.
Arimori Mitsuyuki (32)
Hotel Manager
Mouri Kogorou-sama, I believe?
We've been expecting you.
I am the manager, Arimori.
We're looking forward to our stay.
Please check-in on this card.
Welcome.
Didn't I meet you two...
Shimokasa Minaho (21)
Employee
Shimokasa Honami (21)
On that cursed mask case?
Thank you very much for your help then.
What are you two doing here?
It was a request from a friend of mine.
They've been excited about your arrival as well.
I just hope there aren't any cursed objects here as well...
I made a reservation, under Shiromoto.
Welcome.
Shiromoto-sama...
You must be Shiromoto Hidehiko-sama, correct?
Wasn't the reservation for two?
Yes.
Shiromoto Hidehiko (46)
Businessman
My wife and I.
I'm sure she'll be here soon.
I don't care what the producer's excuse is.
What's this about me having to give up my part all of a sudden?
You're headed this way?
You don't have to come anymore!
Isn't she...
That actress, Bizen Chizuru-san?
Yeah...
Dear, what's the meaning of this?
Bizen Chizuru (30)
Actress - Shiromoto's Wife
I came because I was told this was a beautiful place.
It turns out, you've brought me to the mountains.
I think it's a nice and quiet place.
To think I'll have to see your face and stay here for
the next few days, it's getting on my nerves...
Front Manager, give me a different room from this person.
But, Miss...
Please give the reserved suite to my wife.
I'll take a different room.
Understood.
Well, take care of my things.
Jeez, not even an elevator?
Her image is different from TV and the movies.
Minaho-kun, Honami-kun...
Show them around.
Yes.
Please, this way.
Mouri-sama, would you like to rest at the restaurant?
Restaurant?
At this time, we can offer you cold herbal tea.
How great.
Hey Dad, let's go there.
Yeah, I guess.
Instead of herbal tea, I prefer...
It's such a nice restaurant.
Welcome.
She is our chef.
Simon Shinobu (27)
Hotel Arimori Chef
I'm Shimon Shinobu.
Welcome to our restaurant.
This restaurant's layout and decorations
were designed entirely by her.
Amazing.
I hope you will enjoy the delicious food made
from local ingredients in this relaxing environment.
I can't wait until dinner.
I heard something about a tasty local beer.
We've prepared it, of course.
Shinobu-kun, bring out some herbal tea for the guests.
Okay.
Oh, I'll take the local beer.
Wait until dinner!
So great!
Dad, why don't you stop drinking
so much beer and eat some food?
The soup is really tasty.
I've never had soup as bad as this.
Are you really a chef?
Chizuru, stop it.
You shut up.
Excuse me, but could you tell me how it does not suit your taste?
"How"?
Your customer is saying it's horrible, so
you should at least lower your head!
I apologize.
I'll bring out another soup immediately.
Shinobu-kun...
Manager!
Understood...
That's what she should have done from the start.
I heard of you from my husband.
You're that renowned detective...
Mouri Kogorou-san, I believe?
I'm glad we have met.
I'm glad as well!
I always look forward to hearing stories of your latest exploits.
I'm Chizuru's husband, Shiromoto.
I've come here on vacation after finalizing
the development plan for Vager Land.
Y-You're a businessman, huh?
So the rumors about the development were really true?
At the plateau near by, there are
many rare butterflies and plants.
How do you plan to ensure their safety?
Oh, I'm planning to meet with the locals
at the bottom of the mountain about it.
The locals? So what?
There are always those people who talk
about preserving nature everywhere.
It's all money, all money.
Chizuru, how could you say that?
Oh, did I strike a nerve?
If you want a divorce, I can separate from you.
But...
I wonder if you could afford my compensation?
Chizuru-chan!
Chizuru-chan, please just give up your part this once!
Manager, are you still talking about stupid things like that?
First of all, what's the reason?
Miyabe Kouta (35)
Drama Production Company President
Chizuru-chan, I really can't say here...
Hurry, just say it!
W-Well, actually, the sponsors don't agree with
Chizuru-chan being... Maybe a younger actress...
No, no, no, no!
They won't agree to funding us unless we use Reika-chan, who's at the top of her career from last year's performance.
Reika-chan is one of our actresses as well...
And, if we don't do this movie, it'll
be devastating to our company.
Please understand, Chizuru-chan!
What's...
What's with all your eyes!?
You're all probably thinking that everything would
be better if I disappeared, aren't you!?
Fine, I'll die!
Chizuru-chan!
She's troublesome...
Well, please don't let it bother you.
Hey, is this you, Arimori-san?
Here, in this photo.
That's you in the middle, Arimori-san, and...
Shinobu-san is the one on the right, isn't she?
Yes, that's right.
She and I are old hang gliding friends.
Hang gliding?
A long time ago, we were able to hang glide from a nearby cliff.
Now, it's impossible due to the land development.
That's too bad.
I did it too when I was young.
Who's the man standing next to Arimori-san?
Oh, that's my younger brother.
We flew together often back then.
It's been five years since we've flown, hasn't it?
The hang gliders are just stuffed
in the storage room on the roof.
Conan-kun, let's go to the plateau tomorrow.
It's perfect for the photos you need for your homework.
Uncle is snoring too loud for me to get any sleep...
I think I'll go buy some juice.
I can't reach it!
Enough already!
What did I do?
That doesn't concern me.
Chizuru-san?
Just what's with her?
The Next Morning
9:00 A.M.
Shiromoto-san...
How is Chizuru-san doing?
Sorry about last night.
That's usually what happens, so don't worry about it.
She'll probably...
Um, Chizuru-chan...
N-No, it's nothing at all...
Hey old lady, last night...
What do you mean by "old lady"!?
Please don't let that bother you...
Just what are we gonna do!?
Right now, it's impossible to persuade her.
What do you say we go fish until she cools down?
I start working tomorrow, so I've
been planning to fish all day today.
If you wish, I'll lend you my rod as well.
Well, in that case, I'd be glad to join you.
Dad, let's go to the plateau.
You all can go.
I still have an important mission.
Mission?
First, I watch Okino Youko-chan's new promotional video.
Then, I watch the broadcast of her concert from last month.
Lastly, I will watch a re-run of her drama special!
Dad, what did you come all the way here for?
The re-run of her drama is only playing in this area...
You came all the way out here to watch that?
If you don't mind, I'd like to take you to the top.
That would be great!
Right!
Would you like to go with them, Shinobu-san?
I'll watch the hotel.
But, I still have to prepare everyone's meals...
Oh, just make us bentos for lunch.
We will be leaving as well, so we don't mind bentos.
But I still have to prepare dinner...
Then, how about we barbecue in the yard for dinner?
That will be easy to prepare, right?
My wife was so rude to you last night.
To make up for it, please go stretch your wings today.
If it's only setting it up, we'll do it.
There aren't any new guests arriving today.
Why don't you go along with their suggestion?
Go ahead, go ahead.
In that case, I'll do as you've suggested.
It should be only about 15 minutes to the lake by car.
The Departure
10:00 A.M.
Do you know the way?
Yeah, we'll be fine.
That spot is best right after the sun sets.
Then, I guess we'll be fishing through nightfall.
Have a safe trip.
I'll go check the locks and come in the micro-bus.
I'll catch up, so go ahead without me.
Please hurry.
Yeah.
Chizuru-san would feel better if she came
outside instead of staying in her room.
Mission #1!
Time to watch Youko-chan's new PV and master the lyrics!
Youko-chan!
Mouri-san!
Y-Yes?
I'll leave the master key here with you.
Please take good care of it.
Understood!
Jeez, Dad is hopeless.
Arimori-san still hasn't come?
Oh, there he is.
Arrival at the Plateau
10:50 A.M.
This cool wind feels great.
It's beautiful!
Amazing!
So the sky really is this blue...
I never noticed.
It feels like if I had wings...
I could fly to the sun.
That sounds like something Icarus would say.
Icarus?
It's Greek Mythology.
Icarus, who received wings...
Forgot his father's warning that he shouldn't fly too high...
And flew higher and higher.
He believed he could fly to the sun.
But...
Icarus' wings couldn't bear the heat
when he got too close to the sun.
After his wings burned, Icarus fell
from the sky right to the ground.
It's a sad story.
What a cute butterfly!
Oh, it's a Miyama white butterfly that only exists around here.
The butterfly...
This butterfly can't survive unless the water is clean.
Youko-chan!
Hotel Lobby
12:30 P.M.
Sorry, I forgot my bento.
Is Chizuru still in her room?
Yes.
She has not come down.
I guess I'll go see her.
Lakeside
1:00 P.M.
I wonder if Chizuru-chan's in a better mood yet...
Hotel Lobby
1:30 P.M.
How was your wife?
Well...
It seems as if she's still asleep.
I knocked, but there was no answer.
As someone who also has a tough wife, I know how difficult it is.
Indeed.
Well, I'll be going back to my fishing.
Have a good trip.
Plateau
1:50 P.M.
Out of bounds.
Conan-kun wins.
Let's have lunch.
Oh, it's already this late?
I'll go get the bentos.
Lake
2:15 P.M.
This is a big one!
We've got tons today!
Yes!
Hotel Lobby
2:25 P.M.
Youko-chan, you can't go that way!
So beautiful...
It really is...
The sunset from here is always wonderful.
See, the bright area at the bottom there is Hotel Arimori.
It's that far?
Let's go back now.
All right.
Starting Down the Mountain
6:05 P.M.
What's wrong?
The engine doesn't seem so good.
Go back ahead of me.
All right.
Hotel
7:00 P.M.
We're back.
Jeez, you should have come with us, Dad.
The sunset was wonderful!
Oh, and there was this rare butterfly.
It's said that it doesn't get close to humans, but...
It landed right on Arimori-san's shoulder!
I get it, I get it.
We're back.
We've got tons!
Welcome back.
What's Chizuru up to?
Come to think of it, she never came down.
Never?
Jeez, that troublesome woman.
Mouri-san, may I borrow the master key?
Yeah, sure, sure.
Thank you.
Here, today's catch.
I'll leave the rest to you.
Hello? This is Hotel Arimori.
Oh, Arimori-san?
The car won't start.
Sorry to ask, but could you come here?
All right.
You might need some help, so I'll come too.
Sorry to trouble you, Ran-san.
Mouri-san, there's something wrong with Chizuru-san.
I opened the door with the key, but the door guard is on.
No matter how much I call, there's no answer.
Could it be...
Chizuru-san! Chizuru-san!
Let's break the door down.
Y-Yes!
Body Discovered
7:20 P.M.
Chizuru!
Chizuru-chan!
Mouri-san!
How's Chizuru?
I'm sorry to say, but...
It appears it's been some time since she passed away.
It can't be...
The door guard lock...
These marks are...
Could it be...
As I thought!
Chizuru-san...
Chizuru-san didn't commit suicide!
She was murdered!