Mysterious Eyes
Song by GARNET CROW
There is no shape to flowing water.
There is no figure to flowing wind.
No matter the case, the deduction is free.
Today's stage is a plateau hotel.
The unwanted guest calls for a case.
Perceiving the one and only truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan.
kimi to boku to wa betsu no ikimono dakara
Original Creator
Aoyama Gosho
『Meitantei Conan』
Serialized in Shogakukan's 「Shounen Sunday」
konomi ga chigau aruku hayasa mo omoi no tsutae kata mo
Planning
Suwa Michihiko
(Yomiuri TV)
iro asete yuku futari no kioku no naka ima bokura wa
Character Design
Sudou Masatomo
Art Director
Shibuya Yukihiro
Camera Director
Ogawa Takahisa
Sound Director
Kobayashi Katsuyoshi
tesaguri dakedo hoka no dareka wo mirai wo sagashite yuku
Music
Oono Katsuo
Opening Theme
「Mysterious Eyes」
Performers
Lyrics
Composition
Arrangement
GARNET CROW
AZUKI Nana
Nakamura Yuri
Furui Hirohito
omou yori tsuyoku ikite tokubetsu na ai motometeru
Editing
Ogawa Takahisa
Story Editor
Iioka Junichi
Color Design
Hirade Mayumi
Production Lead
Kobyashi Hiroaki
shitataka na hibi ni nayandari
true heart for mystery eyes
mou nidoto mayowanai you ni sono ude wo hanasanaide
Planning Support
Okuyama Toyohiko
Asai Mitomu
Assistant Director
Satou Masato
Director
Yamamoto Taiichirou
kizutsuke au sono toki mo
tada zutto kotae wo sagashite mayoi konda toki no naka de
Producers
Suwa Michihiko
(Yomiuri TV)
Yoshioka Masahito
(Tokyo Movie)
tsugi no basho e you take your way
dakishimete
I feel so all in secret life
Presented By
Yomiuri TV
Tokyo Movie
Excuse me, we would like to get to Hotel Arimori.
Yeah, just go across, and head straight on the road.
Thank you very much.
Dad, I'm surprised you knew about a hotel all the way out here.
It's because this place is known for its great local beer.
Alcohol was his goal again?
Uncle...
That's the place.
We're finally here.
THE BLACK WINGS OF ICARUS
(PART ONE)
Welcome.
I made a reservation, under Mouri.
Hotel Manager
Arimori Mitsuyuki (32)
Mouri Kogorou-sama, I believe?
We've been expecting you.
I am the manager, Arimori.
We're looking forward to our stay.
Please check-in on this card.
Welcome.
Didn't I meet you two...
Shimokasa Minaho (21)
Employee
Shimokasa Honami (21)
On that cursed mask case?
Thank you very much for your help then.
What are you two doing here?
It was a request from a friend of mine.
They've been excited about your arrival as well.
I just hope there aren't any cursed objects here as well...
I made a reservation, under Shiromoto.
Welcome.
Shiromoto-sama...
You must be Shiromoto Hidehiko-sama, correct?
Wasn't the reservation for two?
Yes.
Businessman
Shiromoto Hidehiko (46)
My wife and I.
I'm sure she'll be here soon.
I don't care what the producer's excuse is.
What's this about me having to give up my part all of a sudden?
You're headed this way?
You don't have to come anymore!
Isn't she...
That actress, Bizen Chizuru-san?
Yeah...
Dear, what's the meaning of this?
Actress · Shiromoto's Wife
Bizen Chizuru (30)
I came because I was told this was a beautiful place.
It turns out, you've brought me to the mountains.
I think it's a nice and quiet place.
To think I'll have to see your face and stay here for
the next few days, it's getting on my nerves...
Front Manager, give me a different room from this person.
But, Miss...
Please give the reserved suite to my wife.
I'll take a different room.
Understood.
Well, take care of my things.
Jeez, not even an elevator?
Her image is different from TV and the movies.
Minaho-kun, Honami-kun...
Show them around.
Yes.
Please, this way.
Mouri-sama, would you like to rest at the restaurant?
Restaurant?
At this time, we can offer you cold herbal tea.
How great.
Hey Dad, let's go there.
Yeah, I guess.
Instead of herbal tea, I prefer...
It's such a nice restaurant.
Welcome.
She is our chef.
Hotel Arimori Chef
Simon Shinobu (27)
I'm Shimon Shinobu.
Welcome to our restaurant.
This restaurant's layout and decorations
were designed entirely by her.
Amazing.
I hope you will enjoy the delicious food made
from local ingredients in this relaxing environment.
I can't wait until dinner.
I heard something about a tasty local beer.
We've prepared it, of course.
Shinobu-kun, bring out some herbal tea for the guests.
Okay.
Oh, I'll take the local beer.
Wait until dinner!
So great!
Dad, why don't you stop drinking
so much beer and eat some food?
The soup is really tasty.
I've never had soup as bad as this.
Are you really a chef?
Chizuru, stop it.
You shut up.
Excuse me, but could you tell me how it does not suit your taste?
"How"?
Your customer is saying it's horrible, so
you should at least lower your head!
I apologize.
I'll bring out another soup immediately.
Shinobu-kun...
Manager!
Understood...
That's what she should have done from the start.
I heard of you from my husband.
You're that renowned detective...
Mouri Kogorou-san, I believe?
I'm glad we have met.
I'm glad as well!
I always look forward to hearing stories of your latest exploits.
I'm Chizuru's husband, Shiromoto.
I've come here on vacation after finalizing
the development plan for Vager Land.
Y-You're a businessman, huh?
So the rumors about the development were really true?
At the plateau near by, there are
many rare butterflies and plants.
How do you plan to ensure their safety?
Oh, I'm planning to meet with the locals
at the bottom of the mountain about it.
The locals? So what?
There are always those people who talk
about preserving nature everywhere.
It's all money, all money.
Chizuru, how could you say that?
Oh, did I strike a nerve?
If you want a divorce, I can separate from you.
But...
I wonder if you could afford my compensation?
Chizuru-chan!
Chizuru-chan, please just give up your part this once!
Manager, are you still talking about stupid things like that?
First of all, what's the reason?
Drama Production Company President
Miyabe Kouta (35)
Chizuru-chan, I really can't say here...
Hurry, just say it!
W-Well, actually, the sponsors don't agree with
Chizuru-chan being... Maybe a younger actress...
No, no, no, no!
They won't agree to funding us unless we use Reika-chan,
who's at the top of her career from last year's performance.
Reika-chan is one of our actresses as well...
And, if we don't do this movie, it'll
be devastating to our company.
Please understand, Chizuru-chan!
What's...
What's with all your eyes!?
You're all probably thinking that everything would
be better if I disappeared, aren't you!?
Fine, I'll die!
Chizuru-chan!
She's troublesome...
Well, please don't let it bother you.
Hey, is this you, Arimori-san?
Here, in this photo.
That's you in the middle, Arimori-san, and...
Shinobu-san is the one on the right, isn't she?
Yes, that's right.
She and I are old hang gliding friends.
Hang gliding?
A long time ago, we were able to hang glide from a nearby cliff.
Now, it's impossible due to the land development.
That's too bad.
I did it too when I was young.
Who's the man standing next to Arimori-san?
Oh, that's my younger brother.
We flew together often back then.
It's been five years since we've flown, hasn't it?
The hang gliders are just stuffed
in the storage room on the roof.
Conan-kun, let's go to the plateau tomorrow.
It's perfect for the photos you need for your homework.
Uncle is snoring too loud for me to get any sleep...
I think I'll go buy some juice.
I can't reach it!
Enough already!
What did I do?
That doesn't concern me.
Chizuru-san?
Just what's with her?
9:00 A.M.
The Next Morning
Shiromoto-san...
How is Chizuru-san doing?
Sorry about last night.
That's usually what happens, so don't worry about it.
She'll probably...
Um, Chizuru-chan...
N-No, it's nothing at all...
Hey old lady, last night...
What do you mean by "old lady"!?
Please don't let that bother you...
Just what are we gonna do!?
Right now, it's impossible to persuade her.
What do you say we go fish until she cools down?
I start working tomorrow, so I've
been planning to fish all day today.
If you wish, I'll lend you my rod as well.
Well, in that case, I'd be glad to join you.
Dad, let's go to the plateau.
You all can go.
I still have an important mission.
Mission?
First, I watch Okino Youko-chan's new promotional video.
Then, I watch the broadcast of her concert from last month.
Lastly, I will watch a re-run of her drama special!
Dad, what did you come all the way here for?
The re-run of her drama is only playing in this area...
You came all the way out here to watch that?
If you don't mind, I'd like to take you to the top.
That would be great!
Right!
Would you like to go with them, Shinobu-san?
I'll watch the hotel.
But, I still have to prepare everyone's meals...
Oh, just make us bentos for lunch.
We will be leaving as well, so we don't mind bentos.
But I still have to prepare dinner...
Then, how about we barbecue in the yard for dinner?
That will be easy to prepare, right?
My wife was so rude to you last night.
To make up for it, please go stretch your wings today.
If it's only setting it up, we'll do it.
There aren't any new guests arriving today.
Why don't you go along with their suggestion?
Go ahead, go ahead.
In that case, I'll do as you've suggested.
It should be only about 15 minutes to the lake by car.
The Departure
10:00 A.M.
Do you know the way?
Yeah, we'll be fine.
That spot is best right after the sun sets.
Then, I guess we'll be fishing through nightfall.
Have a safe trip.
I'll go check the locks and come in the micro-bus.
I'll catch up, so go ahead without me.
Please hurry.
Yeah.
Chizuru-san would feel better if she came
outside instead of staying in her room.
Mission #1!
Time to watch Youko-chan's new PV and master the lyrics!
Youko-chan!
Mouri-san!
Y-Yes?
I'll leave the master key here with you.
Please take good care of it.
Understood!
Jeez, Dad is hopeless.
Arimori-san still hasn't come?
Oh, there he is.
Arrival at the Plateau
10:50 A.M.
This cool wind feels great.
It's beautiful!
Amazing!
So the sky really is this blue...
I never noticed.
It feels like if I had wings...
I could fly to the sun.
That sounds like something Icarus would say.
Icarus?
It's Greek Mythology.
Icarus, who received wings...
Forgot his father's warning that he shouldn't fly too high...
And flew higher and higher.
He believed he could fly to the sun.
But...
Icarus' wings couldn't bear the heat
when he got too close to the sun.
After his wings burned, Icarus fell
from the sky right to the ground.
It's a sad story.
What a cute butterfly!
Oh, it's a Miyama white butterfly that only exists around here.
The butterfly...
This butterfly can't survive unless the water is clean.
Youko-chan!
Hotel Lobby
12:30 P.M.
Sorry, I forgot my bento.
Is Chizuru still in her room?
Yes.
She has not come down.
I guess I'll go see her.
Lakeside
1:00 P.M.
I wonder if Chizuru-chan's in a better mood yet...
Hotel Lobby
1:30 P.M.
How was your wife?
Well...
It seems as if she's still asleep.
I knocked, but there was no answer.
As someone who also has a tough wife, I know how difficult it is.
Indeed.
Well, I'll be going back to my fishing.
Have a good trip.
Plateau
1:50 P.M.
Out of bounds.
Conan-kun wins.
Let's have lunch.
Oh, it's already this late?
I'll go get the bentos.
Lake
2:15 P.M.
This is a big one!
We've got tons today!
Yes!
Hotel Lobby
2:25 P.M.
Youko-chan, you can't go that way!
So beautiful...
It really is...
The sunset from here is always wonderful.
See, the bright area at the bottom there is Hotel Arimori.
It's that far?
Let's go back now.
All right.
Starting Down the Mountain
6:05 P.M.
What's wrong?
The engine doesn't seem so good.
Go back ahead of me.
All right.
Hotel
7:00 P.M.
We're back.
Jeez, you should have come with us, Dad.
The sunset was wonderful!
Oh, and there was this rare butterfly.
It's said that it doesn't get close to humans, but...
It landed right on Arimori-san's shoulder!
I get it, I get it.
We're back.
We've got tons!
Welcome back.
What's Chizuru up to?
Come to think of it, she never came down.
Never?
Jeez, that troublesome woman.
Mouri-san, may I borrow the master key?
Yeah, sure, sure.
Thank you.
Here, today's catch.
I'll leave the rest to you.
Hello? This is Hotel Arimori.
Oh, Arimori-san?
The car won't start.
Sorry to ask, but could you come here?
All right.
You might need some help, so I'll come too.
Sorry to trouble you, Ran-san.
Mouri-san, there's something wrong with Chizuru-san.
I opened the door with the key, but the door guard is on.
No matter how much I call, there's no answer.
Could it be...
Chizuru-san! Chizuru-san!
Let's break the door down.
Y-Yes!
Body Discovered
7:20 P.M.
Chizuru!
Chizuru-chan!
Mouri-san!
How's Chizuru?
I'm sorry to say, but...
It appears it's been some time since she passed away.
It can't be...
The door guard lock...
These marks are...
Could it be...
As I thought!
Chizuru-san...
Chizuru-san didn't commit suicide!
She was murdered!
THE BLACK WINGS OF ICARUS
(PART TWO)
Plateau
8:00 P.M.
Arimori-san?
Arimori-san!
Where is he?
Arimori-san?
I'm over here!
Hotel Manager
Arimori Mitsuyuki (32)
The stars were so beautiful that I got lost in them.
Jeez, Arimori-san...
Hello?
Oh, Minaho-kun?
What'd you say!?
Got it!
I'll be there right away!
Simon Shinobu (27)
Hotel Arimori Chef
Did something happen?
It looks like Chizuru-san passed away...
Let's leave the bus here and get back to the hotel.
Right!
Hotel
8:20 P.M.
The deceased is...
The actress, Bizen Chizuru-san, age thirty.
She was lodging at this hotel with her
husband, Shiromoto Hidehiko-san.
What's the estimated time of death?
The estimated time of death is between 1:30 P.M. and 2:30 P.M.
The cause of death is likely to be
suffocation from a blocked airway.
Mito Kouichi (33)
Nagano Province Detective
At the time that you discovered the body,
is it true that the door guard was active?
Yes, that's why I had no choice but to
break the door open with a tackle.
The windows were locked from the inside as well.
There's no mistake in saying it was a suicide.
But Bizen Chizuru was a famous actress...
Was there any reason for her to commit suicide?
Well, last night there was some trouble.
Trouble?
She was forced to give up a part in
a movie that was promised to her.
It seemed to come as a great shock to her.
I see...
Hey!
Boy, you can't go in!
But...
That brat again...
Why are you running around again?
Because there are some strange marks over here...
Marks?
This is where the door guard's lock was.
There are strange marks on the lock as well.
These could be made after someone from the
outside created this locked room scenario.
What do you mean?
Meaning, after the culprit locked the windows...
They used a screwdriver and removed
the door guard from the wall.
Then, they placed the door guard back
on as they stepped into the hall...
And, from the opening in the door, rescrewed the lock in.
But, it's difficult to do such a demanding task in a
small area, so it's no surprise that the marks are there.
The reason it was displaced with just one tackle...
Must be because the screws weren't completely in.
Hey, Chizuru-san moved this table from
the window and used it as a stool, right?
Yeah, that's right.
Then...
Stop bothering the crime scene people!
Hey, are there prints on toes?
Of course there is!
Look at your own foot...
Oh, wait a second!
Chizuru-san's feet were bear!
Were there any such prints on the table?
There weren't!
What now?
T-That means...
Someone carried Chizuru-san here and hung her.
That means it wasn't suicide, but murder.
Last night, Chizuru-san had a conflict
with someone in the restaurant...
Damn, if only I had saw who it was then...
Are there any other clues?
What's this?
It's like a white powder...
This room is so warm...
Air conditioning!?
Now that I think about it, it was off when we found the body!
Did the culprit go to the trouble of turning it off?
Or maybe...
Regarding the death of Bizen Chizuru-san...
I would like to ask all of you some questions.
You first, Shiromoto-san.
I'm told you were arguing with Chizuru-san over divorce issues?
Businessman
Shiromoto Hidehiko (46)
Yes, her company loans were huge, and...
You're next, Miyabe-san.
I'm told you dropped her as the lead in a movie recently?
Drama Production Company President
Miyabe Kouta (35)
It wasn't my call at all.
The sponsors were the ones who wanted her gone.
I see.
I would like all of you to answer this.
The estimated time of death is between 1:30 P.M. and 2:30 P.M.
Please tell me what you all were doing at that time.
What do you mean by that?
It sounds like you're looking for alibis...
W-Was Chizuru-chan...
From what we found at the scene...
It's very likely that it was a murder.
N-No way...
Shiromoto-san and Miyabe-san, you two
went to a local lake to fish, did you not?
Yeah, right —
That's right.
From when we left at 10:00 AM and returned
to the hotel at 7:00 PM, I was at the lake.
And you, too, Shiromoto-san?
No, I forgot my bento.
I came back to the hotel at 12:30 P.M.
I ate lunch in the lobby with Mouri-san and left at 1:30 P.M.
And, did you see Chizuru-san at that time?
I went to her room to check on her...
But when she didn't answer my knocking, I returned to the lobby.
When Shiromoto-san went back to the hotel...
Weren't you completely alone, Miyabe-san?
T-That's true, but...
I was eating my bento on the lakeside the whole time.
And you two, Arimori-san and Shinobu-san?
We went to the plateau on top of the
mountain with Ran-san and Conan-kun.
We left immediately after Shiromoto-san did...
And arrived there at around 11:00 A.M.
We were there the entire time and
came down the mountain at 6:00 P.M.
It was around 7:00 P.M. when we made it back to the hotel.
And I'm told that Arimori-san remained alone at the plateau?
The micro-bus's engine wasn't doing well, so...
And Arimori-san was at the field when you went to pick him up?
Of course!
There's no mistake, as I was with her.
And Minaho-san and Honami-san?
During the morning, we were cleaning the hotel.
After Shiromoto-sama came back...
We brought out tea to him and Mouri-sama for their lunch.
Afterwards, we had lunch in the office.
At 1:30 P.M., after walking Shiromoto-sama to the door...
We watched television with Mouri-sama until 4:00 P.M.
Afterwards, until everyone returned, we were preparing dinner.
How was Chizuru-san's room when you were cleaning?
We were told by the manager to leave it alone...
So we never went near it.
Mouri-san, you were always here?
Yeah, I was watching TV in the lobby all day.
Excluding when Shiromoto-san
went to check on her at 12:30 P.M...
No one used the staircase in the lobby.
That means the culprit must have entered the
hotel through one of the emergency exits.
What are the emergency exits like?
There's one at the end of every floor's hall.
The doors auto-lock, but can be opened freely from inside.
You can't open it from outside without the master key.
T-That means the culprit is someone from the hotel!
No, I had the master key all day.
The person must have made a spare beforehand.
If that's so, the culprits must be those two!
We didn't do anything!
From 1:30 P.M. until 4:00 P.M., they were watching TV with me.
T-Then, you three must have worked in a group!
What!? That's stupid!
E-Either way...
Since I didn't have the master key, I can't be the culprit.
No, even without the master key...
There's still a way to get in from the emergency exit.
For example, Shiromoto-san...
At 12:30 P.M., when you went to check on Chizuru-san...
You could have opened the emergency exit from inside...
And then placed a small rock to ensure
the door wouldn't completely close.
Then, at 1:30 P.M., you could have
pretended to be going back to the lake...
When you were really going back to the hotel
through the emergency exit to murder Chizuru-san.
N-No way...
This guy's pretty good.
Miyabe-san, if he were working with you, it's
possible for you to have committed the crime.
What are you saying, Detective?
By hiding in Shiromoto-san's car, you
could have returned to the hotel.
Then, you could enter from the emergency
exit that Shiromoto-san opened and...
That's enough already!
You're talking to them like they're the culprits!
Oh, I'm just saying...
What about you all?
What are you saying?
You guys could have had a spare of the master key.
You could secretly come down...
Stop saying such stupid things!
In order to return to the hotel from the plateau or the lake...
You would have to cross the bridge that's under construction.
Earlier, when we checked with the workers...
They said the only car that went back to the
hotel around noon was Shiromoto-san's car.
That means the only ones who could have done it are...
Shiromoto-san...
Miyabe-san...
Minaho-san, Honami-san...
And, Mouri-san.
Me too!?
It's exactly as Detective Mito says...
But something doesn't seem right.
Specifically...
The air conditioning that had stopped...
And that white powder on Chizuru-san's skirt...
What was that?
I see!
Could it be...
This is almost like a runway...
That's...
A rope mark, isn't it?
Officer!
Uncle Mouri told me to ask...
At any rate...
Shiromoto-san...
Miyabe-san...
Minaho-san...
Honami-san...
And Mouri-san...
I would like to ask you more intimate questions at the station.
Hey you, do you know who I am?
Mouri-san, what's wrong?
Please wait.
That's the beginning of "Sleeping Kogorou."
What?
This is the rumored...
Please leave the rest to me.
That means, you know who the culprit is?
That's right.
I know who the culprit is and the trick they used.
Trick?
The culprit has wings.
They are what make this seemingly impossible crime possible...
Those magical wings.
Right...
The culprit...
Is you!
Right...
The culprit is you...
Arimori Mitsuyuki-san!
W-What are you saying?
I was at the plateau with Ran-san the entire time.
That's right!
Arimori-san cannot be the culprit.
Didn't I just tell you?
Arimori-san had a pair of magical wings.
These "magical wings," what are they?
What is that?
Those are the magical wings.
We found it in the storage room on the roof.
It's a hang glider.
What?
Aside from this, there was a rope mark up
there left just above the victim's room.
I see!
Arimori-san used that hang glider...
To fly from the plateau and land on the roof.
He used a rope to descend to the veranda outside her room.
And after he was done...
He flew right back using the hang glider.
What you've said is impossible.
The only time I wasn't with the others was when I got the
bentos from the car, which only took four or five minutes.
It takes at least fifteen minutes to even set up a hang glider.
And about him returning to the hotel...
Judging from the wind direction and
the incline, it's likely not possible.
Mouri-san...
It's exactly as you all have said.
But...
If it was only to strangle Chizuru-san,
it can be done in four or five minutes...
If she was nearby.
What are you talking about?
Chizuru was at the hotel...
I see!
It's the micro-bus, isn't it?
That's right.
First, he separated from Shinobu-san and the others during
the departure by saying he was going to check the locks.
He then went to Chizuru-san's room...
And knocked her out with a stun-gun or something similar.
After putting her and the hang glider in
the micro-bus, he went on to the plateau.
Detective Mito...
When you analyzed the scene, did you
realize that the air conditioning was off?
Yeah.
That means Chizuru-san wasn't in the room after noon, right?
That's exactly it.
And, around 2:00 PM...
Arimori-san seperated from the others to get the bentos.
He returned to the micro-bus and the unconscious Chizuru-san...
And hung her with the rope.
Later, he claimed something was wrong with
the engine so he could stay at the plateau.
Then, he set up the hang glider and flew
from the plateau with Chizuru-san in tow.
Since the roof of the hotel was lit up fairly
well, I doubt he could have lost his way.
After landing on the roof, he descended via rope to the
veranda outside her room, and then hung the body inside.
Afterwards, you set up the door guard
and left the hotel via the emergency exit.
That's foolish.
How did I return to the plateau from there?
That's right.
When Ran-san and I went back, Arimori-san was there!
Could he have used a bike?
The workers on the bridge would have seen him then.
It's impossible to fly back with a hang glider at such
a low angle as this to the top of the mountain.
That's why I said Arimori-san used magic.
Magic that let him get back to the
plateau without anyone seeing him.
Again with things no one can understand...
The seed of his magic is Shinobu-san's car.
By the time Arimori-san called you on his cell phone...
He was already in your car's trunk.
No way...
Arimori-san used Shinobu-san as
his transport without her knowing.
Once the car reached the plateau...
He waited for Ran and Shinobu-san to move away from the car...
And then left the trunk.
Then, acting as if he'd been there all
along, he appeared in front of them.
A-Arimori-san...
T-Those are all just theories!
Don't you have some real proof?
Yes.
Yes, that's right.
Understood.
Mouri-san, we've heard from the autopsy unit.
The white powder on the victim's skirt is
the scale of a Miyama white butterfly.
And now you see...
On the skirt of Chizuru-san, who was
supposedly always at the hotel...
Were traces of a Miyama white butterfly
that only exists on top of the mountain.
As Ran told me...
A butterfly landed on Arimori-san's shoulder and died, didn't it?
That must be when its scale got on his shirt.
And when he put Chizuru-san over
his shoulder without noticing it...
The scale got on her skirt as well.
Why, to Chizuru-san...
Revenge...
For my young brother.
Revenge?
Teruhiko was still at Tokyo University when he met
her, who was just beginning as an actress then.
To my younger brother, she became more and more to him.
But to Chizuru-san...
It was just fun love.
No...
From the start, she only wanted him for his money.
It cost him a lot to keep her around.
Then, as she became wealthier and
wealthier from her drama appearance...
She began to move away from Teruhiko.
To keep Chizuru-san's heart, Teruhiko began
to spend more and more money.
He even sold the hotel, which was obtained
from our father's will, without telling me...
Then, right now, this hotel...
Belongs to someone else.
The reason I remained as manager
was the kindness of the owner.
And what happened to your brother?
After falling into a deep depression, Teruhiko...
Ended up miscalculating on his hang glider, and...
My brother got too close to a sun called Chizuru-san...
Which caused his wings to burn and throw him to the ground.
And then, you held a grudge against Chizuru-san.
Last night, I called Chizuru-san to the restaurant.
Even if it was only one word, I wanted
her to say something to my brother...
But...
Nothing comes to mind when that picture.
How should I know who it is?
I'm the older brother of Arimori Teruhiko
who dated you a long time ago.
My brother died after falling to the ground.
W-What are you trying to say?
I only went out with him because
he wouldn't stop bothering me.
That person liked me on his own...
And he died on his own.
I'm not trying to blame you after this long!
I just want you to visit his grave and say one word to him.
Enough already!
What did I do?
That doesn't concern me.
It was then...
That I decided to Chizuru-san was to be killed.
Do you think your brother is happy now?
Butterflies are said to be the spirits
of those that have passed away.
To me...
It seems it was almost as if your younger brother, in spirit...
Tried to stop you from committing the crime
and rested his wings on your shoulder...
Secret of my heart
Song by Mai Kuraki
Donna kotoba ni kaete
How do I change my words
Kimi ni tsutaerareru darou
So I can convey it to you?
arekara ikutsumo no kisetsu ga
Even though since then, countless seasons
toorisugita keredo
Have passed by
itsumo soba de waratteru
I've always been here smiling at your side
watashi nimo ienai koto ga mada hitotsu dake aru
But I also have just one thing I still can't say
Secret Of My Heart utagattemo nai ne
Secret of my heart There's no doubt, is there?
itsu datte sukoshi no mirai ga areba
That whenever a bit of our future arrives
shinjitsu wa te ni irerareru hazu
We should be able to grasp the truth
I can't say mou sukoshi dake I'm waiting for a chance
I can't say for just a bit longer I'm waiting for a chance
What's taking Dad so long?
Where did he go to buy his takoyaki?
Over there...
Let's have tea sometime!
Let's have tea!
We should have tea!
Come on, with Mouri Kogorou-san!
Dad!
This Icarus...
Is completely hopeless...