There is no shape to flowing water.
There is no figure to flowing wind.
No matter the case, the deduction is free.
Today, the case is solved.
A most unexpected killer, unexpected motive and unexpected trick.
Perceiving the one and only truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan.
We took a summer trip and arrived at Hotel Arimori,
located in the mountains of Nagano.
We ran into business man Mr. Hidehiko Shiromoto and
his wife, actress Chizuru Bizen there.
The following day, Ran, Mr. Arimori and Shinobu went to the highlands,
while Mr. Shiromoto and Mr. Miyabe went out fishing on the lake.
Night falls, and since Chizuru had not come out of her room at all,
we went to her room to check on her...
Chizuru didn't commit suicide...
She was killed by someone!
THE BLACK WINGS OF ICARUS
(PART TWO)
Plateau
8:00 P.M.
Arimori-san?
Arimori-san!
Where is he?
Arimori-san?
I'm over here!
Arimori Mitsuyuki (32)
Hotel Manager
The stars were so beautiful that I got lost in them.
Jeez, Arimori-san...
Hello?
Oh, Minaho-kun?
What'd you say!?
Got it!
I'll be there right away!
Simon Shinobu (27)
Hotel Arimori Chef
Did something happen?
It looks like Chizuru-san passed away...
Let's leave the bus here and get back to the hotel.
Right!
Hotel
8:20 P.M.
The deceased is...
The actress, Bizen Chizuru-san, age thirty.
She was lodging at this hotel with her
husband, Shiromoto Hidehiko-san.
What's the estimated time of death?
The estimated time of death is between 1:30 P.M. and 2:30 P.M.
The cause of death is likely to be
suffocation from a blocked airway.
Mito Kouichi (33)
Nagano Province Detective
At the time that you discovered the body,
is it true that the door guard was active?
Yes, that's why I had no choice but to
break the door open with a tackle.
The windows were locked from the inside as well.
There's no mistake in saying it was a suicide.
But Bizen Chizuru was a famous actress...
Was there any reason for her to commit suicide?
Well, last night there was some trouble.
Trouble?
She was forced to give up a part in
a movie that was promised to her.
It seemed to come as a great shock to her.
I see...
Hey!
Boy, you can't go in!
But...
That brat again...
Why are you running around again?
Because there are some strange marks over here...
Marks?
This is where the door guard's lock was.
There are strange marks on the lock as well.
These could be made after someone from the
outside created this locked room scenario.
What do you mean?
Meaning, after the culprit locked the windows...
They used a screwdriver and removed
the door guard from the wall.
Then, they placed the door guard back
on as they stepped into the hall...
And, from the opening in the door, rescrewed the lock in.
But, it's difficult to do such a demanding task in a
small area, so it's no surprise that the marks are there.
The reason it was displaced with just one tackle...
Must be because the screws weren't completely in.
Hey, Chizuru-san moved this table from
the window and used it as a stool, right?
Yeah, that's right.
Then...
Stop bothering the crime scene people!
Hey, are there prints on toes?
Of course there is!
Look at your own foot...
Oh, wait a second!
Chizuru-san's feet were bear!
Were there any such prints on the table?
There weren't!
What now?
T-That means...
Someone carried Chizuru-san here and hung her.
That means it wasn't suicide, but murder.
Last night, Chizuru-san had a conflict
with someone in the restaurant...
Damn, if only I had saw who it was then...
Are there any other clues?
What's this?
It's like a white powder...
This room is so warm...
Air conditioning!?
Now that I think about it, it was off when we found the body!
Did the culprit go to the trouble of turning it off?
Or maybe...
Regarding the death of Bizen Chizuru-san...
I would like to ask all of you some questions.
You first, Shiromoto-san.
I'm told you were arguing with Chizuru-san over divorce issues?
Shiromoto Hidehiko (46)
Businessman
Yes, her company loans were huge, and...
You're next, Miyabe-san.
I'm told you dropped her as the lead in a movie recently?
Miyabe Kouta (35)
Drama Production Company President
It wasn't my call at all.
The sponsors were the ones who wanted her gone.
I see.
I would like all of you to answer this.
The estimated time of death is between 1:30 P.M. and 2:30 P.M.
Please tell me what you all were doing at that time.
What do you mean by that?
It sounds like you're looking for alibis...
W-Was Chizuru-chan...
From what we found at the scene...
It's very likely that it was a murder.
N-No way...
Shiromoto-san and Miyabe-san, you two
went to a local lake to fish, did you not?
Yeah, right —
That's right.
From when we left at 10:00 AM and returned
to the hotel at 7:00 PM, I was at the lake.
And you, too, Shiromoto-san?
No, I forgot my bento.
I came back to the hotel at 12:30 P.M.
I ate lunch in the lobby with Mouri-san and left at 1:30 P.M.
And, did you see Chizuru-san at that time?
I went to her room to check on her...
But when she didn't answer my knocking, I returned to the lobby.
When Shiromoto-san went back to the hotel...
Weren't you completely alone, Miyabe-san?
T-That's true, but...
I was eating my bento on the lakeside the whole time.
And you two, Arimori-san and Shinobu-san?
We went to the plateau on top of the
mountain with Ran-san and Conan-kun.
We left immediately after Shiromoto-san did...
And arrived there at around 11:00 A.M.
We were there the entire time and
came down the mountain at 6:00 P.M.
It was around 7:00 P.M. when we made it back to the hotel.
And I'm told that Arimori-san remained alone at the plateau?
The micro-bus's engine wasn't doing well, so...
And Arimori-san was at the field when you went to pick him up?
Of course!
There's no mistake, as I was with her.
And Minaho-san and Honami-san?
During the morning, we were cleaning the hotel.
After Shiromoto-sama came back...
We brought out tea to him and Mouri-sama for their lunch.
Afterwards, we had lunch in the office.
At 1:30 P.M., after walking Shiromoto-sama to the door...
We watched television with Mouri-sama until 4:00 P.M.
Afterwards, until everyone returned, we were preparing dinner.
How was Chizuru-san's room when you were cleaning?
We were told by the manager to leave it alone...
So we never went near it.
Mouri-san, you were always here?
Yeah, I was watching TV in the lobby all day.
Excluding when Shiromoto-san
went to check on her at 12:30 P.M...
No one used the staircase in the lobby.
That means the culprit must have entered the
hotel through one of the emergency exits.
What are the emergency exits like?
There's one at the end of every floor's hall.
The doors auto-lock, but can be opened freely from inside.
You can't open it from outside without the master key.
T-That means the culprit is someone from the hotel!
No, I had the master key all day.
The person must have made a spare beforehand.
If that's so, the culprits must be those two!
We didn't do anything!
From 1:30 P.M. until 4:00 P.M., they were watching TV with me.
T-Then, you three must have worked in a group!
What!? That's stupid!
E-Either way...
Since I didn't have the master key, I can't be the culprit.
No, even without the master key...
There's still a way to get in from the emergency exit.
For example, Shiromoto-san...
At 12:30 P.M., when you went to check on Chizuru-san...
You could have opened the emergency exit from inside...
And then placed a small rock to ensure
the door wouldn't completely close.
Then, at 1:30 P.M., you could have
pretended to be going back to the lake...
When you were really going back to the hotel
through the emergency exit to murder Chizuru-san.
N-No way...
This guy's pretty good.
Miyabe-san, if he were working with you, it's
possible for you to have committed the crime.
What are you saying, Detective?
By hiding in Shiromoto-san's car, you
could have returned to the hotel.
Then, you could enter from the emergency
exit that Shiromoto-san opened and...
That's enough already!
You're talking to them like they're the culprits!
Oh, I'm just saying...
What about you all?
What are you saying?
You guys could have had a spare of the master key.
You could secretly come down...
Stop saying such stupid things!
In order to return to the hotel from the plateau or the lake...
You would have to cross the bridge that's under construction.
Earlier, when we checked with the workers...
They said the only car that went back to the
hotel around noon was Shiromoto-san's car.
That means the only ones who could have done it are...
Shiromoto-san...
Miyabe-san...
Minaho-san, Honami-san...
And, Mouri-san.
Me too!?
It's exactly as Detective Mito says...
But something doesn't seem right.
Specifically...
The air conditioning that had stopped...
And that white powder on Chizuru-san's skirt...
What was that?
I see!
Could it be...
This is almost like a runway...
That's...
A rope mark, isn't it?
Officer!
Uncle Mouri told me to ask...
At any rate...
Shiromoto-san...
Miyabe-san...
Minaho-san...
Honami-san...
And Mouri-san...
I would like to ask you more intimate questions at the station.
Hey you, do you know who I am?
Mouri-san, what's wrong?
Please wait.
That's the beginning of "Sleeping Kogorou."
What?
This is the rumored...
Please leave the rest to me.
That means, you know who the culprit is?
That's right.
I know who the culprit is and the trick they used.
Trick?
The culprit has wings.
They are what make this seemingly impossible crime possible...
Those magical wings.
Right...
The culprit...
is you!
Right...
The culprit is you...
Arimori Mitsuyuki-san!
W-What are you saying?
I was at the plateau with Ran-san the entire time.
That's right!
Arimori-san cannot be the culprit.
Didn't I just tell you?
Arimori-san had a pair of magical wings.
These "magical wings," what are they?
What is that?
Those are the magical wings.
We found it in the storage room on the roof.
It's a hang glider.
What?
Aside from this, there was a rope mark up
there left just above the victim's room.
I see!
Arimori-san used that hang glider...
To fly from the plateau and land on the roof.
He used a rope to descend to the veranda outside her room.
And after he was done...
He flew right back using the hang glider.
What you've said is impossible.
The only time I wasn't with the others was when I got the
bentos from the car, which only took four or five minutes.
It takes at least fifteen minutes to even set up a hang glider.
And about him returning to the hotel...
Judging from the wind direction and
the incline, it's likely not possible.
Mouri-san...
It's exactly as you all have said.
But...
If it was only to strangle Chizuru-san,
it can be done in four or five minutes...
If she was nearby.
What are you talking about?
Chizuru was at the hotel...
I see!
It's the micro-bus, isn't it?
That's right.
First, he separated from Shinobu-san and the others during the departure by saying he was going to check the locks.
He then went to Chizuru-san's room...
And knocked her out with a stun-gun or something similar.
After putting her and the hang glider in
the micro-bus, he went on to the plateau.
Detective Mito...
When you analyzed the scene, did you
realize that the air conditioning was off?
Yeah.
That means Chizuru-san wasn't in the room after noon, right?
That's exactly it.
And, around 2:00 PM...
Arimori-san seperated from the others to get the bentos.
He returned to the micro-bus and the unconscious Chizuru-san...
And hung her with the rope.
Later, he claimed something was wrong with
the engine so he could stay at the plateau.
Then, he set up the hang glider and flew
from the plateau with Chizuru-san in tow.
Since the roof of the hotel was lit up fairly
well, I doubt he could have lost his way.
After landing on the roof, he descended via rope to the
veranda outside her room, and then hung the body inside.
Afterwards, you set up the door guard
and left the hotel via the emergency exit.
That's foolish.
How did I return to the plateau from there?
That's right.
When Ran-san and I went back, Arimori-san was there!
Could he have used a bike?
The workers on the bridge would have seen him then.
It's impossible to fly back with a hang glider at such
a low angle as this to the top of the mountain.
That's why I said Arimori-san used magic.
Magic that let him get back to the
plateau without anyone seeing him.
Again with things no one can understand...
The seed of his magic is Shinobu-san's car.
By the time Arimori-san called you on his cell phone...
He was already in your car's trunk.
No way...
Arimori-san used Shinobu-san as
his transport without her knowing.
Once the car reached the plateau...
He waited for Ran and Shinobu-san to move away from the car...
And then left the trunk.
Then, acting as if he'd been there all
along, he appeared in front of them.
A-Arimori-san...
T-Those are all just theories!
Don't you have some real proof?
Yes.
Yes, that's right.
Understood.
Mouri-san, we've heard from the autopsy unit.
The white powder on the victim's skirt is
the scale of a Miyama white butterfly.
And now you see...
On the skirt of Chizuru-san, who was
supposedly always at the hotel...
Were traces of a Miyama white butterfly
that only exists on top of the mountain.
As Ran told me...
A butterfly landed on Arimori-san's shoulder and died, didn't it?
That must be when its scale got on his shirt.
And when he put Chizuru-san over
his shoulder without noticing it...
The scale got on her skirt as well.
Why, to Chizuru-san...
Revenge...
For my young brother.
Revenge?
Teruhiko was still at Tokyo University when he met
her, who was just beginning as an actress then.
To my younger brother, she became more and more to him.
But to Chizuru-san...
It was just fun love.
No...
From the start, she only wanted him for his money.
It cost him a lot to keep her around.
Then, as she became wealthier and
wealthier from her drama appearance...
She began to move away from Teruhiko.
To keep Chizuru-san's heart, Teruhiko began
to spend more and more money.
He even sold the hotel, which was obtained
from our father's will, without telling me...
Then, right now, this hotel...
Belongs to someone else.
The reason I remained as manager
was the kindness of the owner.
And what happened to your brother?
After falling into a deep depression, Teruhiko...
Ended up miscalculating on his hang glider, and...
My brother got too close to a sun called Chizuru-san...
Which caused his wings to burn and throw him to the ground.
And then, you held a grudge against Chizuru-san.
Last night, I called Chizuru-san to the restaurant.
Even if it was only one word, I wanted
her to say something to my brother...
But...
Nothing comes to mind when that picture.
How should I know who it is?
I'm the older brother of Arimori Teruhiko
who dated you a long time ago.
My brother died after falling to the ground.
W-What are you trying to say?
I only went out with him because
he wouldn't stop bothering me.
That person liked me on his own...
And he died on his own.
I'm not trying to blame you after this long!
I just want you to visit his grave and say one word to him.
Enough already!
What did I do?
That doesn't concern me.
It was then...
That I decided to Chizuru-san was to be killed.
Do you think your brother is happy now?
Butterflies are said to be the spirits
of those that have passed away.
To me...
It seems it was almost as if your younger brother, in spirit...
Tried to stop you from committing the crime
and rested his wings on your shoulder...
What's taking Dad so long?
Where did he go to buy his takoyaki?
Over there...
Let's have tea sometime!
Let's have tea!
We should have tea!
Come on, with Mouri Kogorou-san!
Dad!
This Icarus...
is completely hopeless...