Koi wa Thrill, Shock, Suspense
Aiuchi Rina
Koi wa thrill shock suspense
Mienai chikara tayori ni
Kokoro no tobira tozasazu ni tsuyoku tsuyoku
Telling yourself to be tough,
The strong rhythm that provides essence.
The police officers who are always busy,
Good luck to them on love in between cases.
Seeing through the one and only truth,
The appearance of a child but the brains of an adult.
That name is: Detective Conan!
Original Creation
Aoyama Goushou
Meitantei Conan
Serialized in Shogakukan's Weekly Shounen Sunday
Watashi ga kanjiteita
Toge o kimi ni no onaji
Planning
Suwa Michihiko
(Yomiuri Television)
You ni ataeteita no kamo shirenakatta
Character Design
Sudou Masatomo
Art Director
Shibutani Yukihiro
Camera Director
Ogawa Takahisa
Sound Director
Kobayashi Katsuyoshi
Nani ni kokoro o itamete nani ni obieteita no ka
Music
Onno Katsuo
Ki ni mo tomezu motsureteku futari no shinjitsu ni
Opening Theme
Koi wa Thrill, Shock, Suspense
Vocals
Lyrics
Composition
Arrangement
Aiuchi Rina
Ohno Aika
Oshiro Quron
Mukiau no ga kowakatta
Editing
Okada Terumitsu
Story Editor
Iioka Junichi
Color Design
Hiraide Mayumi
Production Chief
Moriwaki Makoto
This love is thrill, shock, suspense
Planning Committee
Tsuzuki Shinichirou
Okuyama Toyohiko
Asai Mitome
Mayoi o aoi kaze ni chirasou toshite
General Director
Kodama Kenji
Director
Yamamoto Yasuichirou
Mo kakaekirezu ni ita yo kono chisana mune ni wa
Kokoro no tobira tozasazu ni
Tsugi e to susumu arata na fuan to
Producers
Suwa Michihiko
(Yomiuri TV)
Yoshioka Masahito
(Tokyo Movie)
Mayoi o kakaeteshimaisou ni natte mo
Presented by
Yomiuri TV
Tokyo Movie
That's a good girl.
Grow, grow bigger and leave
the scars of your flames behind.
One more... One more and this night
before the carnival will be concluded.
It's the beginning of the flames
that will light up this stinkin' town.
The beginning of the beautiful carnival.
Ayumi.
What are you doing?
Mom!
Let's go home.
Okay.
Metropolitan Police Detective Love Story 3
(Part 1)
Metropolitan Police Detective Love Story 3. Part 1!
Police station
I see.
And what did that man's eyes look like?
Hmm, they were like the eyes of a fox,
THIS sharp.
The eyes were slanted.
Then, was he something like this?
Nothing like that.
Really?
You're really bad at drawing.
That's practically a child's doodle.
Isn't there anyone better?
There's nothing I can do!
The one who draws faces,
Tomokawa-san, has a cold and is absent today.
Excuse me.
But Satou-san.
What?
You can't expect to give this
picture to the investigations department.
I do think it has a surreal and noteworthy style though.
So?
Why don't you two draw one instead of me then?
Uhh... N-No, pictures aren't exactly...
My specialty is impressionist painting, so...
H-Hey wait, Shiratori-san?!
Geez, he plays dirty.
Oh, and we aren't even certain that the
man she saw really was the arson culprit.
What's that? Are you trying
to say that Ayumi-chan is lying?
Even if she's a kid, you should still take her seriously.
But you didn't see the man lighting
the fire with your own eyes, right?
There's no mistake.
On these hot days,
A man wearing a long trench coat with leather gloves,
Letting off the scent of lamp oil all
over his pants where he spilled it,
Walking out from a back alley near the
place the fire broke out with a sickening grin,
Wouldn't it be harder to say that he isn't the culprit?
Well?
That's how it was. Right, Ayumi-chan?
Alright, either way, let's go to that back alley.
And analyze the scene of the crime.
Analyzing the scene of the crime?!
Alright!
Then I'll come as well.
Then, we can take my car.
Sure, but I'm going to stop by somewhere first.
It's on the way there so...
Stop by somewhere?
Today is a special day for me.
Special day?
Is it your birthday?
No.
It's the opposite.
Opposite?
I wonder where she's gonna stop at?
A special day, huh...
I see! I remember now!
Today is the day Satou-san's father,
Officer Satou Masayoshi, passed away.
The day her father died on duty.
Oh, really?!
Yeah.
Exactly 18 years ago today.
While chasing a killer robber, at this intersection.
At this intersection?
Right, he got hit by a truck at this intersection.
Unfortunately, there was a heavy
storm that day, and the ambulance was late.
In the ambulance, under the eyes of
Satou-san and her family, he drew his last breath.
That's what Inspector Megure told me.
As I recall, the name of the case is...
Shuushirou.
Yeah, Shuushirou!
It's Shuushirou.
After the officer was hit by the
truck, as the criminal ran away,
He repeatedly called out that mysterious name.
Thus the case was named the "Shuushirou case."
Shuushirou Case
At the time, they even did a house to house search.
But the officer they believed to
have held the key to the case was dead.
So the investigation remained unsolved, and
three years ago the statute of limitations expired.
Well, that's what Uncle Kogorou said.
Oh, I've seen that case a lot
of times on TV, so I know it too.
That was close...
It was a flawless heist, and the only clue left
behind was the security tape of about 10 seconds.
Even how the officer who died on duty managed to
determine who the culprit is, still remains a mystery.
But I never knew that officer was Satou-san's father.
It can't be helped.
Even if the name of the case and the
offender's name remain on the record,
Something like the name of a
officer who died while on a case,
Isn't something anyone remembers
unless they are police officers themselves.
Sa-Satou-san...
Well, we aren't doing this
job to be remembered anyways.
But, didn't that truck driver see the culprit's face?
He said the culprit was wearing a long rain coat,
So he couldn't even tell if it was a male or female.
Even in the image of the security camera, he
was wearing a hat, a mask, sunglasses, and a coat.
But he knew the culprit's name,
That "Shuushirou?"
None of the people who were called with
that name was capable of committing the crime.
Well, I guess it was bound to be unsolved.
If the clues were the security
tape, the rain coat, and "Shuushirou,"
There are four.
The fourth clue is three letters written in
Katakana in his police notebook "ka-n-o."
Kano?
This is the first time I've heard of that.
I hear that the police was trying to keep it classified.
According to reports nationwide, it
appears to have had a lot to do with the case.
And they asked my mother and I so many times if
we have heard of my father saying anything about it.
And?
Not only have I never heard of it,
I have no clue as to what it means.
When I was a kid, I always used to always
think as I stared at those three syllables.
That I would grant any wish of the person
who solves this mystery and catches Shuushirou!
Any...
Wish...
If I get it, would you buy me
a thousand Unajuu rice bowls?
Of course.
I want to live in the castle at Tropical Land.
Then I would like an entrance pass
to the international space station.
Then I would like a name-brand bag.
Would a ticket to the next world cup for me be alright?
S-Sure...
Only these kids take it so realistically that it's scary.
What's up with you two?
Flowers...
It's been quite a while!
Aren't you Miwa-chan?
You've grown up!
You know them?
Yeah, they're members of father's
baseball club from when he was in high school.
This is my father's battery-mate,
the ace, Saruwatari Hiderou-san.
Saruwatari Hiderou (50)
Highschool teacher
Nice to meet you.
Famous for his strong arm and swift legs,
Kano Shyuuji (49)
Italian restaurant manager
Kano Shyuuji-san.
Hello.
The team's dependable slugger,
Financial company president
Inomata Mitsuo (50)
Inomata Mitsuo-san.
And the beautiful manager, Kandori Chyouko-san.
Kandori Chyouko (49)
Boutique owner
Oh stop it, I'm a 50 year-old grandmother now.
What are you all doing here today?
We've decided to all have a drink together.
But first, we came to greet the captain, Satou.
I see.
If we didn't greet him, then
we would have gotten depressed.
We'll be at the usual bar, so you should come to join us!
This is Shiratori.
Oh, Inspector Megure.
Eh, right now?
Right now we're in Haido-city, fourth district.
What, someone spotted a suspicious
character who might be the arson culprit?
Yeah, the location is Shinagawa, sixth district.
While the men on patrol were in the
middle of questioning him, the man fled.
Currently we're in pursuit.
The man's characteristics are...
Long hair with a hat and a grey coat.
He's close to where you guys are.
Leave the kids with Satou-kun, and
you and Takagi-kun go back them up.
That's what he said.
Let's go, Takagi-kun!
R-Right!
What's wrong? Hurry up!
Uhh, Police notebook, handgun and...
Crap! Not good...
Takagi-kun!
I left my handcuffs on the desk at the station.
We don't have time to go back and...
You alright, Takagi-kun?
No problem, as for handcuffs, Shiratori-san still has his.
And according to the magazine
fortune teller, I'm super lucky today.
So even without handcuffs, handling that criminal is...
Dear, be careful, alright?
Don't worry, according to the
fortune teller, I'm super lucky today.
Huh, dad forgot his handcuffs.
What, my husband?!
My husband? By a car...
And where is he right now?
This isn't right. Why...
Dad, you're on the good guy's side.
You're working hard for justice.
Why?!
You idiot. The word "justice" is... The word "justice" is...
Satou-san?
Satou-san!
Are you alright?
Well, we'll be off now.
I'll leave the kids with you.
Eh, wait!
Wait a second, Takagi-kun.
Takagi-kun.
Yes?
They're pretty rusty, these handcuffs.
Since you don't have handcuffs, please take these.
Ah... Alright.
They're a memento of my father.
I broke mine during the Higashida-san
case, so I've been using them for a while.
It should be perfect as a charm.
Cha-Charm...
Didn't your father die while on duty?
Just take them.
Be careful, okay?
Sa-Satou-san!
Takagi-kun!
Ah, y-yes!
Well then...
What's that all about?
Bringing a gun just to catch an arson suspect.
And they're investigators for violent criminals.
Shouldn't arson be investigated by a different division?
A stab victim was found.
Near the 4th combustion site.
It's not positive, but he either witnessed the arson,
Or was stabbed when he tried to stop the culprit,
So that's why we're moving too.
So, don't move away from my side.
Shinagawa Station
Inspector, this is Shiratori.
Just now, we've apprehended the suspicious
character who fled questioning at Shinagawa station.
No, it's not me!
But he's saying that he's not the
arson culprit and just a regular thief.
I get it! That's what it was!
I solved the mystery!
I am lucky today!
Alright, time to give Satou-san a call.
Takagi-kun.
Takagi-kun, where are you calling?
Uhh... Nowhere...
I'm going to the bathroom.
Uh, where was...
Yeah, yeah, this one!
When I was getting Kamen Yaiba
gashapon here, a weird man came out of there.
Hello, this is Satou.
Oh, Takagi-kun, how was that suspicious character?
What?! You know who the
culprit is in the case 18 years ago?
Yes, if my deductions are correct, it's probably...
Please don't be surprised... It probably is...
The culprit was among the people we met today.
That person is...
What is it, Shiratori-san?!
Takagi-kun, there's
something strange about your behavior.
Come on, give me a break...
Yeah. That's right.
I understand everything.
The true meaning of Shuushirou,
And the mystery of Kano,
And how your father was able
to determine who the culprit was.
I got all of it.
Although the statute of limitations has passed already.
So, who is it?
Who's the culprit?
Yes, the culprit is...
Hey! Takagi-kun?
Takagi-kun!
Takagi-kun, Takagi-kun!
What's wrong?! Answer me!
Takagi-kun, answer me!
Takagi-kun, Takagi-kun!
Hello?
Takagi-kun...
Well, I'll leave the rest to you.
Yes, this is Shiratori.
Oh, Satou-san.
I've just sent that suspicious
character to the Shinagawa department.
Eh? Takagi-kun?
Yes, he was with me until 4-5 minutes ago.
Then please send his last known location
and time to the station command center.
Takagi-kun was attacked by someone!
Just now, while on the phone with me.
The attacker might be that
arson culprit as well, so be careful!
Um, Officer Takagi was attacked when he was telling you
about who the culprit in the case 18 years ago was, right?
Then the culprit would be...
That can't be.
That case was prescribed 3 years ago,
And there's no way of knowing if
Takagi-kun's deductions are right or wrong.
Hey, those four we met this afternoon.
They said they were going to go to the usual bar to drink,
Where is it?
Where?
The name of the tavern is Nanamagari.
The location is... In front of Shinagawa station...
In that last call, if Detective Takagi
said that the culprit is in one of those four,
And if one of those four just happened to hear
the phone conversation in front of Shinagawa station,
Then there is a chance that the culprit
attacked Detective Takagi to keep his mouth shut.
In any case, I'm going to Shinagawa station.
So you guys take the train and go home.
Come back to the department tomorrow.
If there's a chance that the one who
attacked Detective Takagi could be the arson culprit,
Then I think there is no other choice but to
bring Yoshida-san, who is the only eye-witness.
But...
I'll do my best!
Me, too!
I'll assist, too!
Geez.
Bulletin from headquarters.
To all officers in the Shinagawa area.
Location: Near Shinagawa station.
Condition: Unknown.
A member of police has been attacked by someone,
Possibly heavily injured.
Immediate investigation is top priority.
I repeat.
Bulletin from headquarters.
To all officers in the Shinagawa area.
Location: Near Shinagawa station.
A lie, it's got to be a lie.
The one was among one of those four...
The one who killed my dad.
That can't be right... Dad?!
Natsu no maboroshi
Garnet Crow
Heya no mado no mukou ni hikouki kumo o nazotte
Beyond the window I see a trace
of clouds made by an airplane
Kyou kenkashita kimi no koto bakari kangaeteta
And realize I can only think about the fight we had today
Sasai na koto de to madotte fuantei de muboubi na
I hesitate with every small thing,
and I'm unreliable and hopeless,
Ano koro no you ni sugu ni denwashite
warai aetara ii no ni ne
Wishing to be able to be like I used to,
and call you right away, laughing
Chika zuite kuru shifuku no toki wa
itami o tomonainagara ashi oto o tateru
I can hear the steps of happiness coming
closer, bringing pain along with it
Kangaesugite fukami ni hamaru kimi no soba ni iru no ni
You are so focused in deep thoughts you
don't realize I'm right beside you
Natsu no maboroshi hitomi tojimete ichiban saishou ni kimi o omoidasu yo
Summer illusions I see, closing my eyes
the first one I remember is you,
Dakedo kimi to ikiteyukitai kara
And it's because I want to live with you by my side
Tomadoinagara demo ii tsunaida te o hanasanaide ne
I don't mind if you hesitate, just never let go of my hand
Next Episode
That person! That's the person!
That's the bad man I saw!
Those kids aren't here!
There, now you can see better, right?
Then does that mean the one
who attacked Takagi-kun was...
DAMN IT!!
Now then, shall we have a drink to celebrate... Kano-san.
Metropolitan Police Detective Love Story 3
(Part 2)
Next Conan!
Metropolitan Police Detective Love Story 3. Part 2!
Next Conan's Hint!
Romaji.
Please anticipate our next episode!
Next time is the solution!
I'm Takagi, I'm a police officer!
I thought you were done for?
Oh yeah... AHHH!!