Koi wa Thrill, Shock, Suspense
Aiuchi Rina
Koi wa thrill shock suspense
Love is a thrill, shock, and suspense,
Mienai chikara tayori ni
Relying on an invisible strength
Kokoro no tobira tozasazu ni tsuyoku tsuyoku
Leaving the door to the heart
open, stronger... stronger...
Telling yourself to be tough,
The strong rhythm that provides essence.
One mystery calls another, arson and robbery.
The two cases connect as one!
Seeing through the one and only truth,
The appearance of a child, but the brains of an adult.
That name is: Detective Conan!
Original Creation
Aoyama Goushou
Meitantei Conan
Serialized in Shogakukan's Weekly Shounen Sunday
Watashi ga kanjiteita
I thought,
Toge o kimi ni no onaji
This disorder I've been feeling in my heart
Planning
Suwa Michihiko
(Yomiuri Television)
You ni ataeteita no kamo shirenakatta
Perhaps you felt the same way
Character Design
Sudou Masatomo
Art Director
Shibutani Yukihiro
Camera Director
Ogawa Takahisa
Sound Director
Kobayashi Katsuyoshi
Nani ni kokoro o itamete nani ni obieteita no ka
Without knowing what hurt, what
did I fear with my heart?
Music
Onno Katsuo
Ki ni mo tomezu motsureteku futari no shinjitsu ni
The confrontation of our tangling truth
Opening Theme
Koi wa Thrill, Shock, Suspense
Vocals
Lyrics
Composition
Arrangement
Aiuchi Rina
Ohno Aika
Oshiro Quron
Mukiau no ga kowakatta
We feared to face
Editing
Okada Terumitsu
Story Editor
Iioka Junichi
Color Design
Hiraide Mayumi
Production Chief
Moriwaki Makoto
This love is thrill, shock, suspense
Planning Committee
Tsuzuki Shinichirou
Okuyama Toyohiko
Asai Mitome
Mayoi o aoi kaze ni chirasou toshite
Even when I tried to toss my confusion to the wind
General Director
Kodama Kenji
Director
Yamamoto Yasuichirou
Mo kakaekirezu ni ita yo kono chisana mune ni wa
I could not hold all of it in this tiny chest
Kokoro no tobira tozasazu ni
Leaving the door to the heart open,
Tsugi e to susumu arata na fuan to
Even if you may have to hold the
new uncertainties and confusion
Producers
Suwa Michihiko
(Yomiuri TV)
Yoshioka Masahito
(Tokyo Movie)
Mayoi o kakaeteshimaisou ni natte mo
That will follow you to the next place
Presented by
Yomiuri TV
Tokyo Movie
Thanks to Ayumi-chan's testimony, who
witnessed the serial arson culprit inside the city,
We began the investigation. We, the
Detective Boys, and both detectives, Takagi and Satou.
That day was also the day Satou-san's
father, Officer Satou Masayoshi, had died on duty,
And the day his school era friends had come together.
Metropolitan Police Detective Love Story 3
(Part 2)
Part 2.
What you doin'?
What's wrong Detective Satou?
You're sweating all over.
This is the tavern, right?
Alright, let's go in!
No, I'm the only one that's going in.
I'll be back soon, so wait here quietly.
Aww man...
What're you doing, Haibara-san?
There's nothing to do while we wait, so I
thought I'd check the places that've been burnt to date.
Hey, does anyone remember which places were burnt?
Oh, I remember!
As I recall, all five were near train stations.
Ikebukuro
Tabata
Asakusabashi
Yotsuya
Shimokitazawa
First one was Ikebukuro, second was
Asakusabashi, third was Tabata, fourth: Shimokitazawa.
Third is Tabata and the fourth is Shimokitazawa.
And the fifth is where
Ayumi-chan witnessed the culprit, Yotsuya!
Even if I connect them with lines, it's just a trapezoid.
There doesn't seem to be a pattern.
From this side it looks like a ladle.
More like a scoop than a ladle.
Scoop?
Maybe this is in the middle of the big dipper?
No, then the scoop handle would go on the left side.
Hey, Conan, why don't you help us a...
Hey, he's gone!
Again?
What? They left?
All four of them together?
Yeah, about fourty minutes ago.
They said something about that arson culprit
being around here, got nervous, and went home.
Hey, do you know what those four
were talking about as they were drinking?
C-Conan-kun...
Oh, bunch of good things happened at the
same time, so they were goin' pretty good.
For Inomata-san, today was his
company's fifteenth anniversary.
Something about it never
being in the red since he started it.
For Kano-san, tomorrow is his 50th birthday.
Apparently, his training in Italy for three years
really paid off and his restaurant is doing great.
Kandori-san's daughter got married to a good
man yesterday and she was all smiley-smiley.
Saruwatari-san's son had his second child this morning.
But because today was the day your
father died, he had a frustrated look on his face.
But the culprit in that case was one horrible guy.
Not only did he get away with fifty million...
He beat a guard to death
with a rifle he hid under his coat.
And to top it off, he even killed an officer.
K-Killed? Didn't he die in an accident?
There was a witness.
He said that he was pushed in front of the truck.
I bet Conan-kun went inside the store.
Running off on his own is his favorite stunt.
You think he's having something to eat inside?
Chicken or shishkabobs or something...
There's only eels and meat on
your mind isn't there, Genta-kun?
If you don't eat vegetables, you'll die early.
Come to think of it, the bad person I saw,
was saying something about one
more and the vegetable would be finished.
Vegetable?
Vegetable, appetizer, and stuff.
Eve?
One more and the eve will be over.
Could... Could this be...
Damn it, what's he eating!
H-Haibara-san?
I'm closing the door.
Uh... alright.
Hey, Haibara, that's no fair!
What're you planning to eat?!
Stay here until I get back.
Aww man...
Why are we the ones who always have to stay behind?
What's wrong?
That person... That's the person!
That's the bad person I saw!
But doesn't that man know a
lot about the details of the case?
You know, like he swung with a rifle.
I didn't know that.
Oh, at the time, the security
camera's tape was played on TV too.
It was too cruel, so it was cut off right away.
But the problem right now is Takagi-kun.
Was he attacked by the culprit from 18 years ago?
Or by the arson suspect? Where do we start looking?
It's Shinagawa.
Haibara?!
The next place the arson culprit will appear is Shinagawa.
Shinagawa?
Look, leaving the first arson location,
Ikebukuro, and the second, Asakusabashi, as it is,
Connect the third, Tabata, and the
fourth, Shimokitazawa, with a line.
Then, connect the fifth, Yotsuya, and then Shinagawa,
Note: Hi (火) is the kanji symbol for fire in Japanese
Fire!
Correct, the arson culprit is cutting a giant
"fire" in stroke order upon the terrain of Tokyo.
Then, the one that attacked Takagi-kun is...
Yes, if the arson culprit thought that he
discovered the location of the next scene,
Then that possibility exists.
Although, if that's the case, then the
next place where the flames will rise,
Just like on the fourth scene,
there should be a body lying nearby.
Everyone!
No way... They're not here, those kids.
Satou-san!
Shiratori-kun, did you see those kids?
No, weren't they with you?
Well you see...
Conan-kun? Conan-kun, can you hear me?
A-Ayumi!?
You idiots! Where the heck are you
guys, and what the heck are you doing?!
Don't shout so loud!
The culprit's gonna hear us!
Culprit?
The man Ayumi-chan saw passed
by the tavern, so we followed him.
We're outside the storage
area at Shinagawa sixth district.
Hey look, he's pouring something on the newspaper.
He hasn't started the fire yet?
This means the person that attacked
Detective Takagi isn't the arson culprit.
Hey, Inspector Shiratori, before you
got separated from Detective Takagi,
Was there any change in the way he acted?
Come to think of it, he was looking up
at the Shinagawa station's station board...
Station board?
I get it! That's how it was!
That's how Detective Takagi got it!
The meaning of Shuushirou,
that Satou-san's father left behind.
The identity of Ka-n-o he left in his notebook,
And how he managed to
determine the culprit with only those leads.
There's no mistake! The culprit is one of those four,
And probably the one who
attacked Detective Takagi as well.
Hey you guys, we're coming there in
Inspector Shiratori's car, so don't move!
Why not in my car?
No, that's not the place you must go.
You have to conclude things from 18 years ago.
Conclude?
Perhaps it isn't over yet.
That's a good girl, grow big.
Are you serious?!
He really lit it!
The hint is the "Na" line in romaji.
Detective Takagi must have realized it
when he saw the station board's romaji.
'Cause it's very simple word magic.
Most likely, the one that knows where
Detective Takagi is, is that person too.
Even if you go now, you
probably won't be able to arrest him.
But he'll probably tell you what really happened.
The truth behind what happened 18 years ago.
Hey, are you sure it's okay?
The fire's growing bigger and bigger.
No problem, Conan-kun should've
called the fire department by now, so...
You sure it's okay not to follow the culprit?
No, Conan-kun told us to stay put!
But hasn't it been over ten minutes since then?
No, I don't think it's been five minutes yet.
It's so dark, I can't see very well.
There, now you can see more clearly, right kids?
Don't worry, I'll line all three of you up together,
As an ornament to the main
event that's going to be starting now.
Huh, Miwako-chan...
Is your work finished?
Yeah, more or less.
But as you can see, we're closing.
Come on, let me have just one drink.
Tomorrow is your long awaited
50th birthday, right, Kano-san?
Sure, but once you hit 50, a birthday isn't much.
Really? You should've been
looking forward to it for some time.
Once 12 PM passes tonight, the prescription of that
Shuushirou case from 18 years ago will be completed.
Now then, shall we have a
drink to celebrate... Kan'o-san?
Damn it, what the heck is going on...
I remember, I got hit by someone from behind and...
I've got to do something about these handcuffs.
Nice! My gun wasn't taken.
Alright, I'll use this to break the handcuff chains and...
Ka-n-o, the three mysterious
syllables left in my father's police notebook.
Written in romaji, it's "KA-N-O."
If you read "O" as part of "N," then you have "Ka-No."
I asked Saruwatari-san and
the others earlier and checked...
That Kan'o was a nickname father
gave you all the while in the baseball club.
But, until I asked them, they just thought they were
strange names he called you like, "Kanno" and "Kao,"
And thought he just didn't know your name.
The reason my father was able to
determine that the culprit was you,
Was because he saw the bank's security tape.
My father always told me,
Saying that it was a strange batting form, but
Kano was the number one batter on the team.
That's not very nice to treat me like
a murderer for something like that.
First of all, that case was prescribed three years ago...
No, not yet. To be precise, there's
still 8 minutes and 17 seconds left.
You should also know.
For if the culprit leaves the country,
That time will not be counted as
time passed for the statute of limitations.
Also, I've already called the
headquarters and they're investigating it.
I also know that you didn't want to
forget what day the prescription was,
So you came back from Italy to Japan to
match that date with your 50th birthday.
Uh-uh, you can't have any until you tell me.
Father said,
"The culprit that's about to confess will
always gulp, then extend their hand to the tea,
And if you give the tea to him at that
point, he will swallow his words with that tea."
I won't let you swallow it, not in this case!
Even if you get so thirsty and your throat dries up.
Ayumi-chan!
NO!
Let me go!
Now you guys, come here quietly and...
Hey, what do you think a ghost of a butt is?
Note: [Bake (化け) - 'ghost'] & [Ketsu (穴) - 'butt'] form [Baketsu (バケツ) meaning 'bucket']
Bu-cket...
Correct.
Heh, it smacked into another dirty thing.
Inspector Shiratori, over here!
Over here, over here!
Hurry!
A canteen with lamp oil and matches.
It looks like it's the real one this time.
But are you sure that warehouse is okay?
It sure is burning.
That warehouse was scheduled to be taken
down next week and there's nothing inside.
Also, the firefighters are
beginning to put the fire out now.
Damn it!
Congratulations, I lost.
I didn't intend to kill him.
You mean my father?
No, the guardsman.
When I tried to push him away, it
must have hit him in the wrong spot.
Then, what about my father?
You pushed him into the intersection, right?
No, I was the one who got pushed.
That was when he saw through everything
and I was being taken down to the police station.
In the rain, as I thought about
what was to come, I got scared,
so I ran out in front of a truck.
Then he... He...
He gave me another chance to start over.
But even if you start over with the money you stole...
No, I didn't touch that money!
It's hidden behind the shrine at my house.
Once the statute of limitations
expired, I was going to return it.
It's true, believe me!
Sure, I believe you.
Chiba-kun, did you catch that?
Yes, clearly.
Get a warrant right away and get all of it.
If the numbers match, then
there is no better evidence than this.
Along with that money, the police will send the
tape of this conversation to the prosecutor by today!
Got it?
Y-Yes!
Hurry, there's only one more day!
One more day?
You didn't know?
You know the day you left
Italy there was a typhoon, right?
Y-Yeah...
That flight was supposed to have arrived at 9:00 PM.
But when it landed late in Narita, it was 12:04 AM.
Meaning the day the statute of limitations
expired was shifted by one day from your plans.
Too bad, isn't it.
Heh, I had a bad feeling.
'Cause the face you had when you came in
here today was exactly the same as his that day.
Even if you didn't confess...
I would have flipped your house
upside down to find that money,
Just to catch you.
But my father was different, he could've
said the criminal's name in the ambulance,
But he believed in you and didn't.
Father said this as you ran from
the intersection: "Turn yourself in."
The bystanders who heard his cut off
words, had mistaken it as "Shuushirou."
Now then, where's Takagi-kun?
In a crumbling warehouse in Shinagawa sixth district.
I was going to report it later...
H-Hey... That's...
A-Are you sure?
Are you sure Takagi-kun is in there?!
If that's the case, then he's probably already...
What are you talking about?!
We can still make it!
Move aside!
Don't, Satou-san!
MOVE!!
Fool...
I started today and was assigned
here. My name is Takagi Wataru.
Umm... Detective Satou...
Sa-Satou-san?
Satou-san!
That fool...
It said that I'm super lucky today.
Takagi, you fool!
Uh... Y-Yes...
Sorry...
T-Takagi...
What are you doing over there?
What am I doing?
I pulled on the bars and they
came off, so I climbed out the window.
After that, I was walking around
and got mistaken for a spectator and...
H-Hey...
Prepare an ambulance!
Hurry!
R-Right!
It's cause you wander around with a wound like this.
Huh, no way! You have your gun!
Why didn't you break the cuff chains with your gun?
He didn't want to break those cuffs.
Those were a memento of
your father, right, Detective Satou?
That's definitely why.
Trying too hard to act cool.
He's the type that will die early.
You idiot...
Natsu no maboroshi
Garnet Crow
Heya no mado no mukou ni hikouki kumo o nazotte
Beyond the window I see a trace
of clouds made by an airplane
Kyou kenkashita kimi no koto bakari kangaeteta
And realize I can only think about the fight we had today
Sasai na koto de to madotte fuantei de muboubi na
I hesitate with every small thing,
and I'm unreliable and hopeless,
Ano koro no you ni sugu ni denwashite
warai aetara ii no ni ne
Wishing to be able to be like I used to,
and call you right away, laughing
Chika zuite kuru shifuku no toki wa
itami o tomonainagara ashi oto o tateru
I can hear the steps of happiness coming
closer, bringing pain along with it
Kangaesugite fukami ni hamaru kimi no soba ni iru no ni
You are so focused in deep thoughts you
don't realize I'm right beside you
Natsu no maboroshi hitomi tojimete ichiban saishou ni kimi o omoidasu yo
Summer illusions I see, closing my eyes
the first one I remember is you,
Dakedo kimi to ikiteyukitai kara
And it's because I want to live with you by my side
Tomadoinagara demo ii tsunaida te o hanasanaide ne
I don't mind if you hesitate, just never let go of my hand
Eh? You don't have to thank me.
No, a promise is a promise!
Well then, how about we go
somewhere together sometime...
That's all you want?
Then next Saturday at 6:00 PM, wait for
me at the front entrance of the stadium.
Sorry! Did I keep you waiting?
Uh, no! I just arrived as well.
Sorry, that arson culprit started his
confession, so I got caught up listening to him.
Let's not talk about work.
Yeah, today is our date, our date!
Eh, yes!
This is Satou, we have Maruhi's little sister in sight.
Alright, continue to watch her.
Don't let her know you're an police officer.
Sir!
Ehm, Satou-san, could it be that this is...?
Come on, let's go, Takagi-kun!
Hey! W-Wait a minute!
SATOU-SAN...
Next Episode
But for the great detective Mouri Kogorou,
Couldn't you have prevented a
murder that happened right in front of you?
Thank you for your help.
I'll take the evidence.
Could it be?!
No, it makes sense if I think of it that way.
Even uncle's deduction was too good...
The Deduction that was Too Good
Next Conan!
Next Conan's Hint!
Cassette Tape
Please anticipate our next episode!
Next time is the number one face off!
I'm gonna go nuts!
Me too!
Eh!?