Song by Rina Aiuchi
Koi wa thrill, shock, suspense
Koi wa Thrill, Shock, Suspense,
Love is a thrill, shock, suspense,
Mienai chikara tayori ni
relying on an invisible strength.
Kokoro no tobira tozasazu ni tsuyoku... tsuyoku...
Leaving the door to the heart open, stronger... stronger...
A brave heart and incredible deductions,
a rhythm that jumps to the truth.
Make sure you listen well today.
It's a unique mystery that you can only find on Conan!
Seeing the one and only truth...
A kid with the intellect of an adult...
His name is... Detective Conan!
Watashi ga kanjiteita
I thought,
Toge okimi ni no onaji You ni ataeteita no kano shirenakatta
this disorder I've been feeling in my heart. Perhaps you felt the same way?
Nani ni kokoro o itamete nani ni obieteita no ka
Without knowing what hurt, what did I fear with my heart?
Ki ni ino tomezu motsureteku futari no shinjitsu ni
The confrontation of our tangling truth
Mukiau no ga kowakatta
We feared to face
This love is Thrill, Shock, Suspense,
Love is a thrill, shock, suspense,
Mayoi o aoi kaze ni chirasou toshite Mo kakaekirezu ni ita yo
Even when I tried to toss my confusion to the wind. I could not hold all of it,
Kono chisana mune ni wa
in this tiny chest.
Kokoro no tobira tozasazu ni
Leaving the door to the heart open.
Tsugi e to susumu arata na fuan to
Even if you may have to hold the new uncertainties and confusion.
Mayoi o kakaeteshimaisou ni natte mo
That will follow you to the next place.
The Deduction That Was Too Good
Beika Street
Hey, Ran... It's this way. This way!
Geez, you always make so much trouble
when you drink too much.
Please, next time don't go to the train station
if you've had too much to drink.
Not this again...
Huh, what's this?
"From 8 PM to 10 PM: Eat and drink as much as you want!"
This is ridiculous!
What the hell are you saying?
I only drank three bottles of beer
and ate five plates of appetizers!
Takayoki Eri (25)
Hey, don't throw things around!
Pick it up!
You want me to pick it up? You pick it up, you imbecile!
What are you doing? You're going to make me fall!
Shut up!
What should we do, Dad?
They'll keep bothering me till I stop them.
D-Dad, I'll go get them to stop.
Don't worry.
They're always fighting like this.
It'll be over soon. Isn't that right?
Looks like we were worried over nothing.
Let's go!
Hey, Dad!
Please wait up!
I'm alright.
Can't you see where you're going?
Later that day, we didn't feel comfortable about
what happened, so we went to check on them.
All evidence points to this being a murder case.
Estimated time of death is between 10 PM and 11 PM.
N-No way...
It's you again!
Actually...
Bad things keep happening around you, Mouri-kun.
Inspector Megure!
It's exactly as Mouri-san said.
According to what the apartment owner said, there was
a quarrel between our victim and another person.
Did he tell you anything about the other person?
Umm, I-I'll ask right away.
But even though you passed by this place,
you couldn't stop this from happening.
I'm really sorry...
Damn, if it weren't for that old geezer, we would've
been able to stop this from happening!
P-Please help me, Mouri-san!
Hiroshi Nakamoto (26)
Takayoki Eri and I used to work together at
Beika University. My name is Nakamoto.
Nakamoto?
What?
It was you!
You're the one who killed Eri, aren't you?
No, that's not true!
Even though the police suspect me, I didn't do it!
Last night, I wasn't even home!
It's the truth!
Hold on, we heard you arguing with him last night.
Now you're telling us that you weren't home?
How do you explain that?
That was on a tape.
That wasn't actually me! He used it to make
people believe that I was in the apartment.
What?
He only did it to make a scene?
Y-Yeah.
After he closed the curtains, he played the tape.
Hey, don't throw things around!
Pick it up!
You want me to pick it up? You pick it up, you imbecile!
He was making it all up?
That's right.
Unfortunately, I don't have an alibi to prove my innocence.
No alibi?
And why would he do this?
So I could hide and spy on our professor,
waiting for the chance to kill him!
What?
He was stealing our research results and claiming
them as his own to gain fame among his peers.
Although we knew what he was doing, there
was nothing we could do about it.
So we... we decided to murder him and
make it look like a random burglary.
B-But I couldn't go through with it because,
when I went to his house, he wasn't there.
I waited for him in his library for a long time,
but eventually gave up and returned home.
I arrived at the professor's house at 10 PM.
By the time I returned, it was 11 PM.
If what you're saying is true, then you couldn't
possibly have committed the crime.
Yesterday was my turn to watch the professor's house,
but it seems that he was eating at a restaurant.
This is really strange...
I don't know why my professor would
lie about being home at that time.
If this goes any further, it's going to become embarrassing!
Surely, the police will use that
to remove you from suspicion.
I heard from the investigators that Detective
Mouri-san was a witness to the crime...
So I decided to look for you. Please help me with this!
It's true I have encountered several similar cases, but—
I knew you wouldn't believe me when I told you, Mouri-san.
I'm sure that if we found the tape, you'd believe me!
Does such a thing even exist?
I couldn't find it back at our apartment, so it's
possible that the murderer took it with him.
If I can't find that tape, then it'll be the end of me.
But how can we find it? I'm sure the murderer
must have dumped it by now.
Hey, Dad, shouldn't we try searching for the tape?
If you are able to solve this case, surely you will improve
the reputation of this agency! Right, Uncle?
Improve our reputation? Yeah! Let's get that tape!
Let's start by searching near the
apartment's entrances and exits.
Now let's try near the train station.
The murderer would have tried to get
rid of the tape as fast as possible.
Hey, you there! Wait a minute.
What the hell are you doing?
Even though he said that the murderer would have
gotten rid of the tape as fast as possible.
Found it!
That's it! It's the tape!
Finding this tape was a piece of cake!
Thank you for helping find this tape!
Officer Takagi?!
We'll be taking this as very important evidence.
That sure is a good thing.
One moment. I'll allow you to take
the tape back to the station.
You want me to pick it up? You pick it up you imbecile!
This is in fact the voice we heard
yesterday. Right, Conan-kun?
So that settles it.
This could prove that Nakamoto-kun was telling the truth.
I'm so glad!
I've finally found someone who believes what I
said. But why would the professor lie like that?
That's true.
That old geezer! If he hadn't lied, I wouldn't
have been suspected in the first place!
That's it!
The professor wants you out of the way!
But why would he do that?
Is it possible that he was claiming
to be at home when he was not?
If that's the case then, it's possible that he's the real culprit.
That is possible.
But.
That's impossible.
Are you suggesting the professor knew in
advance of our plan to spy on his house?
Is it possible that he was eavesdropping on us somehow?
Eavesdropping—
Oh, maybe that's it!
I see, some of the screws are missing from this plug.
It's possible that he was listening in on you.
Ahh, really? Thank you for your effort.
It's true. He was listening in on your phone calls.
It's clear now.
The professor was taking your research results and
claiming them as his own for fame and fortune.
Consequently, he was scared that you
would want to take revenge on him.
That motivated him to monitor your phone calls.
So he was the one who tapped the
line. How'd he do it, though?
It's possible that while he was at the university,
he used a copied key to break in.
That's right!
He had been listening to your phone calls for awhile
and had discovered your plan to kill him.
As a result, he used your own plan against you, twisted
it to fit his means, and created an alibi.
So, last night, while the victim and Nakamoto
were executing their plan,
the professor barged in unexpectedly and murdered him.
Then, he took the tape from the crime scene.
That way, when the body was found, of course
you would be the first person suspected.
Thus, by killing him in a closed room, you would
undoubtedly be accused of the crime.
That was the professor's plan.
He used our own plan against us.
The truth is, is that even with his devilish plan, he
didn't expect to run into the famous Mouri Kogoro.
Hey, hey! Why do you always have to act like that, Uncle?
You always end up being mistaken, waiting
for me to swoop in and save the day.
Why are you so happy? If you had listened to my advice
last night, this murder never would have occurred!
I haven't forgotten.
Ah, I heard from Inspector Megure that you met
an old man with a dog last night on the street.
That's right! Had he not stepped in, things
would have turned out differently!
But still, that man's intentions weren't bad, now were they?
W-What if...
Everything makes sense now!
Uncle might have drank too much,
but he was still doing his job!
Alright. Let's go challenge Inspector Megure
and bet my reputation as a detective!
That's not good.
What? What's not good?
Well, you see, I think we should wait for them to come to us,
to ask us what we were able to figure out, so that
we can help them with their investigation.
You might be right.
I'll go plan a bit before they come.
You're saying a premeditated murder and he has an alibi?
I see. Amazing deduction, Mouri-kun!
Of course it is!
You suspect the real culprit might be
your professor. Right, Nakamoto-san?
No, you don't understand.
My hate towards the professor has nothing to do with this.
Well, we'll be checking that.
Takagi-kun! Get a warrant for the professor's arrest now.
Right!
Please wait a minute, Inspector.
I just thought of another possibility.
I know who the real killer is!
Real killer?
What do you mean, Mouri-kun?
Well, please sit down and make yourself comfortable
so that I may explain everything to you.
Nakamoto-kun's story is nothing but a mere lie.
In other words, there are two people that lied.
The tape, however, remains an unchangeable fact.
While Nakamoto-kun was executing the plan to frame
his college professor, he made a big mistake.
Mistake?
So what you're trying to say is all his previous
statements were meant to deceive us?
That's exactly what I'm saying.
In addition, concerning the tape.
But how can we find it? I'm sure the murderer
must have dumped it by now.
What Nakamoto-kun was doing was misleading
us into searching the trash for his tape.
That, and also...
That old geezer!
If he hadn't lied, I wouldn't have been
suspected in the first place!
So, what Nakamoto-kun said might be true. However...
Is it possible that he was claiming
to be at home when he was not?
With that sentence, he created the
possibility of his professor's guilt.
In addition,
Is it possible that he was eavesdropping on us somehow?
It was, however, impossible to listen
in on their private conversations.
He wanted to lead me into finding some
evidence proving his innocence.
While also placing the professor at the crime
scene at the time of the murder.
He wanted to use this information to
warp my deductions for his own gain.
The fact is, these deductions came from one person,
and one person only. You, Nakamoto-kun!
I see.
Needless to say, the culprit entered the victim's apartment.
Then, as the victim was executing his
charade, someone stabbed him.
It was you!
The culprit was living in the same apartment as the victim.
As a result, he did not need to tap the phone line.
All you had to do was unscrew a couple of screws.
Isn't that right, Nakamoto-kun?
I found it strange since the beginning,
when we found the tape.
If it was really thrown in the garbage after the murder, there
would have been no way to find the tape when we did,
because the cans belong to a fast food restaurant
whose garbage is picked up every morning.
The truth is, the tape wasn't there to begin with.
That tape wasn't thrown away the night before,
you threw it away just before I found it.
If you didn't throw it away then, I couldn't have
found it. Isn't that right, Nakamoto-kun?
What are you saying Mouri-san?
What you're saying is crazy.
It isn't crazy.
I'm sorry, Nakamoto-kun, but I have a witness.
Witness?
Um, Conan-kun asked me to come here.
I was the one who sent him to bring you here.
Well then, let's describe the one who was
playing detective according to his plan.
If he didn't have someone to help him play detective,
he wouldn't have been able to complete his scheme.
That is why he thought of using someone as famous
as I, the Great Detective Mouri Kogoro.
However, he could not leave things to chance.
Thus, he thought of a way to make me willingly talk to him.
How did he do that?
He placed a flier in my mail box with an ad for an
all-you-can-eat food and drink special between 8 and 10 P.M.
I see! He knew Mouri-kun couldn't
resist such a tempting offer.
Thanks to that, he made sure that I would
pass by the victim's apartment.
And according to your timing,
Our victim peeped through the window to make
sure I was there and then acted out his part.
Unfortunately, he had no idea he was getting himself killed.
He was simply trying to make a scene.
But why did you say this lady is a witness?
Because...
Nakamoto-kun, when someone placed
that ad in my mailbox yesterday,
this woman saw who that person was.
Excuse me, Azuha-san, is this the person you
saw put a flier in my mailbox yesterday?
Yes, that's him.
Yesterday, on my way to work, I saw
him place a flier in your mailbox.
I can identify the flier if I see it again.
Of course we'll be examining the flier,
and we will find your fingerprints.
It's unlikely that the owner of that
restaurant sent me this flier
because it was only placed in my mailbox, Nakamoto-kun.
That's quite right. But what led you to suspect me?
It was because of what you said.
Ah, I heard from Inspector Megure that you met
an old man with a dog last night on the street.
Even though I mentioned to the inspector that there
was an old man who had forced me to leave,
I did not mention him having a dog beside him.
You couldn't have known that unless
you were at the crime scene!
That's all?
If I had tried to stop that fight, your
plan would have been ruined.
To prevent this, you intervened, stopping
me from interrupting the imaginary fight.
The man with the dog, that was you.
You deserve the title "Great Detective." And
here I thought detectives were fools.
Natsu no maboroshi
Song by: Garnet Crow
heya no mado no mukou ni hikouki kumo o nazotte
Beyond the windows I see a trace of clouds made by an airplane.
kyou kenkashita kimi no koto bakari kangaeteta
And realize I can only think about the fight we had today.
sasai na koto de to madotte fuantei de uboubi na
I hesitate with every small thing, and I'm unreliable and hopeless.
ano koro no you ni sugu ni denwashite
Wishing to be able to be like I used to,
warai aetara ii no ni ne
and call you right away, laughing.
chika zuite kuru shifuku no toki wa
I can hear the steps of happiness coming closer,
itami o tomonainagara ashi oto tateru
bringing pain along with it.
kangaesugite fukami ni hamaru kimi no soba ni iru no ni
You are so focused in deep thoughts you don't realize I'm right beside you.
natsu no maboroshi hitomi tojimete ichiban saishou ni kimi o omoidasu yo
Summer illusions I see, closing my eyes the first one I remember is you,
dakedo kimi to ikiteyukitai kara
and it's because I want to live with you by my side.
tomadoinagara demo ii tsunaida te o hanasanaide ne
I don't mind if you hesitate, just never let go of my hand.
Nakamoto-kun was planning to take
all the research credit for himself.
His friend was standing in the way of his fame and fortune,
so he tried to get rid of him, and frame the professor for it.
Another advertisement...
What, what?
For three days only, eat and drink as much as you want!
Geez, Dad. You're going to do this again?
Hey, give that back! It'll be terrible if it ends tomorrow.
Didn't I warn you about these bars already?
But I promise I won't do anything stupid again.
Hey, hey. Who does he take us for?