Koi wa Thrill, Shock, Suspense
Aiuchi Rina
Koi wa thrill shock suspense
Mienai chikara tayori ni
Kokoro no tobira tozasazu ni tsuyoku tsuyoku
A strong heart, and deduction power!
The strong rhythm that provides essence.
Today's case and trick is special! The scale is really big.
Seeing through the one and only truth,
The appearance of a child, but the brains of an adult.
That name is: Detective Conan!
Original Creation
Aoyama Goushou
Meitantei Conan
Serialized in Shogakukan's Weekly Shounen Sunday
Watashi ga kanjiteita
Toge o kimi ni no onaji
Planning
Suwa Michihiko
(Yomiuri Television)
You ni ataeteita no kamo shirenakatta
Character Design
Sudou Masatomo
Art Director
Shibutani Yukihiro
Camera Director
Ogawa Takahisa
Sound Director
Kobayashi Katsuyoshi
Nani ni kokoro o itamete nani ni obieteita no ka
Music
Onno Katsuo
Ki ni mo tomezu motsureteku futari no shinjitsu ni
Opening Theme
Koi wa Thrill, Shock, Suspense
Vocals
Lyrics
Composition
Arrangement
Aiuchi Rina
Ohno Aika
Oshiro Quron
Mukiau no ga kowakatta
Editing
Okada Terumitsu
Story Editor
Iioka Junichi
Color Design
Hiraide Mayumi
Production Chief
Moriwaki Makoto
This love is thrill, shock, suspense
Planning Committee
Tsuzuki Shinichirou
Okuyama Toyohiko
Asai Mitome
Mayoi o aoi kaze ni chirasou toshite
General Director
Kodama Kenji
Director
Yamamoto Yasuichirou
Mo kakaekirezu ni ita yo kono chisana mune ni wa
Kokoro no tobira tozasazu ni
Tsugi e to susumu arata na fuan to
Producers
Suwa Michihiko
(Yomiuri TV)
Yoshioka Masahito
(Tokyo Movie)
Mayoi o kakaeteshimaisou ni natte mo
Presented by
Yomiuri TV
Tokyo Movie
The Entrance to the Maze
The Anger of the Colossus
The Entrance to the Maze: The Anger of the Colossus!
Mt. Tenbu
Godess' statue
The Goddess in Mt. Tenbu has been worshipped by
the villagers and protected their peace for many years.
People who offended her ended up dying painfully.
To make a hole in that sacred mountain...
And to pass a ropeway through without
being afraid of the gods is such an evil act.
Without a doubt, they will be punished.
Isn't that the Goddess statue?
It is. You can see that
disrespectful ropeway very well too.
By the way, where are you people going?
Er... Well, we are going to...
That disrespectful ropeway...
Tenbu Station
You are Mouri Kogorou-sama, aren't you?
Yes, I am. How beautiful! Are you the one picking us up?
Yes, I've been waiting for you.
Yoshino Ayaka (23)
Doumoto Tourist Company vice-president's secretary
I am the vice-president's secretary in
Doumoto Tourist Company, Ayaka-san Yoshino.
Sorry for bringing kids too...
I'm Mouri Ran. And this is
Conan-kun, whom we're taking care of.
Hello.
Hello, nice to meet you Conan-kun.
Lively place, isn't it?
Trying to restore the town from tourism.
We are so pleased that the famous detective Mouri
will be joining us for the opening ceremony tomorrow.
What are you saying? It's no problem!
Oh? People who are against the ropeway...
It seems that I wasn't invited just
for the opening ceremony, doesn't it?
Yes... The president will tell you about the problem...
Tenbu mountain ropeway
Your name preceeds you, even to
such small countryside towns like ours.
Special room
Now our opening ceremony will
be that much more memorable.
Doumoto Eizou (65)
Doumoto Tourist Company's president
No, no, I'll be at your service anytime.
To tell you the truth, there's
another reason for inviting you.
Doumoto Yasunori (40)
First son; Doumoto Tourist Company's vice-president
There are many people who are
against the opening of the ropeway.
So it's for the sake of the ceremony?
Exactly. Only shops or people who
benefit from this are happy about it.
Doumoto Junpei (30)
Second son; Import/export trader
My father was rather arrogant and made a lot of enemies.
Therefore, I opened an importing and
exporting business when I was younger.
Didn't you come here to ask our father for
financial help since that business isn't going well?
What?
I'm home! Long time no see, father!
Have you just arrived from Tokyo?
Yeah. This is dad's big event, so I
had to come here no matter what!
Doumoto Rina (24)
First daughter
Hm, how can you say that? You left home
and did whatever you wanted for a year.
I guess you came back to borrow money.
You're so rude! What about you?!
You've been ridiculing the tourist business!
Stop it!
That aside, who is this person?
He is Aoyagi Tesuya-san.
He's a freelance journalist and
wants to report about the ceremony.
I'm Aoyagi.
Aoyagi Tesuya (28)
Freelance journalist
I've heard the entire story up
until the opening from Rina-san.
There seems to have been many
accidents during the tunnel construction.
I see. So you're Aoyagi-san. You're
the one who captured Rina's heart.
Thanks for the phone call.
Hey, what do you mean?
Was their weakness revealed?
Vice-president, how about we let
Mouri-san and the others try out our ropeway?
Oh yes, let's do that.
Shall I show you the great view from the mountain
that we, the Doumoto Tourist Company, are proud of?
Wow!
Great!
Ah, speaking of Uncle...
One sheep, two sheep...
Are you afraid of heights by any chance?
I'm okay, as long as I don't look down...
Wonderful!
It's 3000 meters to the top and
we'll arrive there in about 10 minutes.
What's that?
The promenade.
It's closed to the public until the grand opening, but I
recommend you go up to the summit by the ropeway,
And you can enjoy the scenery of the
forest while walking down the promenade.
So, you dealt with the anti-ropeway
demonstrators by promising them money.
Yes, but we still receive letters and
phone calls asking us to stop the ceremony.
Do you have any idea from who that might be?
It's not just one or two people...
And there's a nun named
Kamiyama Shizuka in a temple nearby.
She's making a fuss that we're making the Goddess mad.
And the local press speculating whether
or not there actually is a curse is a problem.
That ropeway going down on the other side is empty...
Yes, this is called crossing style. When one ropeway
moves, the other moves too. It's similar to a well bucket.
Crossing style
Oh, I see.
What's that?
Ah, those are the 500 disciples of Buddha.
It's a tour within the body of the Goddess statue itself.
A tour inside the body of the Goddess?
You mean that you'll receive a grace from
the Goddess when you pass through her body?
Something like that.
That reminds me... That guy, Aoyagi, he was
saying something about the tunnel construction.
I guess he's trying to make up some
scandal and extort money from us.
But why on earth did my sister tell him about that story?
That story? What is it?
Oh no, it's nothing important.
Some story about our relatives.
This tunnel lasts approximately 30 seconds.
Look, when the ropeway reaches this area,
you can see the upper half of the Goddess' body.
The Goddess was made about 800
years ago by carving the rocky mountain.
Note: The Yoganin-gesture represents the fulfillment of a devotee's wishes.
Additionally, the style of the Goddess putting
her right hand to the front is called Yoganin.
Note: Nyoihouju - The jewel of wish. It's one kind of the houju,
a ball or tear-drop shaped object that is sacred in Japanese Buddhism.
What she's holding in her left hand is called Nyoihouju,
In which she can see disasters and misfortunes.
For the people who wish to see her
up close, we made a viewing platform.
Oh dear, I can somehow
understand why that nun is angry...
The Summit station
Wow, this is such a splendid view!
You don't see this kind of scenery too often.
Looking at this view, it makes me
feel like humans are such tiny things.
But such a tiny human created a tourist place like this.
Oh, this? I made a brooch out of my
mother's jade rosary as a memento.
It's not that. That brooch is beautiful as
well, but I thought you looked like the Goddess.
Me?
Yes, kind and graceful.
Thank you. I'm flattered by such a compliment.
It's not a compliment! Don't you agree, Conan-kun?
Yeah!
Yoshino-kun.
Yes, sir.
Take Mouri-san and the others to the hotel.
How about you?
I will go back after I check the final stages.
See you at the ceremony tomorrow at noon.
So diligent even though he's the vice-president...
Of course, our company depends on him.
Hotel Doumoto.
Kah! Great!
Dad, don't drink too much!
They went to such pains to prepare a
suite like this, I have to drink my fill!
Yeah, it's a really gorgeous room, isn't
it? I wonder if it's alright to stay here...
Don't worry about it, they have plenty of money!
But the 2nd son Junpei-san and the eldest
daughter Rina-san seemed to have financial issues.
Yeah, they did. They didn't seem to get along either...
They're going to argue a lot when it's
time for inheritance. Bloody rain may fall...
Stop it, dad! Don't say such things!
So... Why does the opening ceremony start at noon?
TENBU MOUNTAIN ROPEWAY
Machida Osamu (36)
Tokainippou newspaper reporter
Nakano Yoshihito (28)
Machida-senpai, is it alright that we're relaxing here
rather than gathering information for the newspaper?
Don't be in such a rush. I didn't
come here to write a rubbish article.
Where did Conan go?
He said he was going to the restroom.
Conan-kun, the ceremony's starting soon.
Okay!
The preparation's perfect. Nobody has noticed it.
Hmph, I can't depend on your "perfection."
You can't even deal with the
threats from that hyena, Aoyagi.
But that's...
Don't bother making an excuse! The result is everything.
I can't leave the company to you if you're like that.
President, you should get ready...
Yeah.
Now, the man in charge of opening the ropeway, the
president of Doumoto Tourist Company, Doumoto Eizou,
Will give us a speech for the ropeway opening.
Welcome everyone, to such a memorable day.
By protecting old, cultural heritage and leading tourism
to the 21st century, the Doumoto Tourist Company is...
Damn you!
The people who are attending this
ceremony will suffer divine punishment!
Kamiyama Shizuka (75)
Nun
Idiot! What are you doing? Take the photo!
Oh yeah!
To dig a tunnel in the Holy Goddess is blasphemy!
Shame on you all!
Pass divine judgment onto
the Doumoto Tourist Company!
It seems like we have a uninvited guest.
Don't worry about it.
Newspapers are writing about this like there's a
Goddess' curse, but I will blow away such nonsense.
For that, I asked the well-known
detective Mouri Kogorou to attend the ceremony.
Ah, thank you, thank you. I'm Mouri Kogorou. Thank you!
Machida-senpai, this is great!
Mouri Kogorou is actually here!
Don't you think something's suspicious?
Eh? Is it not really him? A fake?
Don't worry about it.
Why did Doumoto Eizou invite us?
Now, this is the first trip of the Tenbu Mountain ropeway.
The second trip is when the
first ropeway arrives at the summit.
Oh? These two guys are,
Reporters from the Toukainippou newspaper who are
writing bad things about the Doumoto Tourist Company.
Why are they invited for the first
ride rather than other newspapers'?
Fools...
My God...
Look Aoyagi-san, it's a really nice scenery!
What do you think, Machida-san? Why don't
you write something good about us for a change?
Are you going to bribe us? If you do,
we'll write an article about that, too.
That courageous front, I
wonder how long it's going to last.
Look, Machida-senpai! Look at that!
Eh? The 500 disciples of Buddha!
You guys built such a thing regardless of the expenses?
Don't you think we're very faithful?
Perhaps a lot of tourists will come here
to see the Goddess and the 500 disciples.
In other words, we should be thanked
by the Goddess rather than being cursed.
What happened?!
A blackout?
What are you doing to me?!
Someone! Someone get light!
Flash the camera!
Oh yeah.
Aaaaaahh!
Again! Flash!
Er... Yeah!
What?
This is...
I can't believe it...
The president has...
Vanished!
The windows are fixed and don't open.
There are two reporters by the left door.
Ayaka-san is by the right door.
Only a tiny ventilator in the ceiling.
The emergency exit... Hasn't been used yet.
Then, where has he disappeared to?
What is this charm?
Ingaouhou.
Note: Ingaouhou basically means "karma". The term's roots lay in Buddhism.
Ingaouhou?
Receive the punishment of the committed crime?
Father's over there!
What did you say?
That's certainly Doumoto Eizou.
Something seems to be stuck into his chest.
Report this with a cellphone!
There's no reception around here.
There's a phone in the summit station though.
This can't be happening... Such a thing...
There was an accident involving the president!
Call the police immediately and inform
the people at the bottom of the mountain.
Yes, sir.
We'll go down to the Goddess through the promenade.
It's Machida, replace the front page of
the evening paper! The curse has struck!
Doumoto Eizou has been stabbed on the Goddess' hand.
Ayaka-san! What's the matter? Are you okay?
I'm just a bit dizzy. Don't mind
me, please check on the president.
Okay, we'll go on ahead. Let's go Conan-kun!
Yeah.
Mouri-san, the Goddess statue' is just one flight away.
It took 15 minutes to get here.
He has passed away from being stabbed in his heart.
Father!
That can't be! You can't be serious about
the president's death, are you Mouri-san?
I understand how you feel, but
unfortunately he has passed away.
You've got to be kidding...
Thi-This wasn't supposed to happen...
Vice-president! Hang in there!
Ayaka-san, are you okay now?
Yes, I'm okay.
I can't be a good secretary if I
fall apart in a situation like this.
At last!
Hey! It's you!
Mouri-san! Is it you again?!
What? Am I a death god?
Ask the Goddess for cooperation this time.
I didn't mean that, Mouri-san. I mean, I'm
glad that I can hear your great reasoning.
Yokomizo police officer
Shizuoka division
It can't be the curse, can it?
The people were talking about it...
No, it's not. There's a culprit amongst
the people who were on the ropeway.
Really? That means the people over there...
Before Eizou disappeared from the
ropeway, he seemed to be fighting,
And a strange charm was put on the window.
I think the culprit threw Eizou in
the tunnel from the ropeway somehow.
But, nobody got off the
ropeway until they reached the top?
I guess there was an accomplice in the tunnel.
That's impossible.
You! Again you're interfering with the investigation!
Wait a minute, Mouri-san. Conan-kun, what's impossible?
Since it only takes 30 seconds to pass through the tunnel,
Even if there was an accomplice,
Can he move the body to the top of the
Goddess' hand from the tunnel in 30 seconds?
Ayaka-san, is there an elevator or
something from the tunnel to this viewing platform?
There isn't.
But, there's a passage from the tunnel to the stairs
halfway through the platform for repairing purposes.
That's it! The culprit must have used that passage.
But I think even a man would take at least 3
minutes to go from the tunnel to the viewing platform.
3 mi-minutes... Please give me some time.
It was about 30 seconds until we found Eizou on
the Goddess' hand after the blackout on the ropeway.
3 minutes is too long...
No, I think it takes longer.
I doubt Eizou stayed quiet after being kidnapped.
So he must have been killed immediately.
However, if the culprit came to the
platform from the tunnel while carrying the body,
It would take twice the amount of time, about 6 minutes.
No, it would take longer than that.
That's right. What's even stranger than the
victim disappearing from the ropeway is that thing.
It's a curse!
For the body to appear under the Nyoihouju,
It's truly divine judgment for Doumoto
Eizou, who became the reincarnation of greed!
This is definitely very strange to be a murder case...
Could it really be a curse?
Or divine punishment?
Is it the anger of the Goddess' statue?
Officer Yokomizo, the result of the inquest has arrived.
The cause of death was the stab directly to his
heart, and he was most likely killed on the spot.
No fingerprints or other
evidence was found on the dagger.
The estimated time of the death is, as we thought,
immediately after he disappeared from the ropeway.
As we suspected.
Okay. The promenade will be closed off then.
Ask the old woman to go down the mountain.
Yes, sir.
Hey, what's that little shed down there?
That was the place for builders
to rest in during the construction.
We're scheduled to tear it down tomorrow.
Then, the thing coming out of there...
I'm not interfering.
Doumoto Yasunori-san, I've got
something I want you to confirm.
Have you seen this knife before?
This is one of the gilded
daggers from my father's collection.
That means someone stole it.
How was the security?
No, anyone could've taken it out. But the problem is...
What is it?
No, it's nothing...
He's hiding something, but what could it be?
There are 2 points in this case:
First, Doumoto Eizou was being attacked by
someone and disappeared from the ropeway.
And second, the strange charm being put on the window.
So, I think one of you is the culprit.
Now, regarding the motive of the murder,
Who's the person who benefits the most from his death?
If you're talking about his
inheritance, it would probably be us brothers.
No, it's you, Yasunori-san.
Because you will get all the power
to run the Doumoto Tourist Company.
Junpei!
Yasunori-niisan, you may be
glad about our father's death,
Because you don't have to be
lectured about the business anymore.
You guys also have motives, Rina.
Guys... Are you talking about me and Aoyagi-san?
Why me?
You made up a scandal about us
and tried to blackmail our father.
But he ignored you, so that's
why you may have killed our father.
Wait a minute, did you use
that story to blackmail my father?
Aoyagi-san, what is "that story?"
The hard schedule needed to meet the
deadline caused an accident in the tunnel last year.
In the accident, one of the
builders was buried alive and died.
But Doumoto Eizou,
Who was afraid of gaining a bad reputation
from the Mt. Tenbu ropeway incident, ignored it,
And paid his family and the people
involved to keep them quiet about the accident.
I was disappointed with my father and
told you that was the reason why I left home,
And you used it to threaten him?!
Don't get mad, I just inquired about
information regarding the accident.
If you took it as blackmail, then you
must have something you felt guilty about.
You approached me to get the story first.
Because you are a witness.
What a person!
My God, you are some kind of guy to win Rina's favor.
But my father didn't care.
You couldn't get the money you wanted from
father, and you got mad. So that's why you...
I didn't do it!
What about you, Junpei-niisan?
You've been rejected by father
everytime you asked for financial help.
So didn't you lose your temper?
Then how about you?
That's enough! How much more
are you going to disgrace our family?
Machida-san, you were part of
the campaign against the ropeway.
How come Toukainippou managed to get on the
first trial of the ropeway rather than other newspapers?
Only God knows why. We
were wondering about that, too.
The vice-president may know the reason.
Yasunori-san, would you like to tell us?
This was the president's idea.
He wanted to make the people who objected to the
ropeway to understand the good side of its development.
Is that really so?
Or was there another purpose for it?
By the way Machida-san, you two
were standing by the door, weren't you?
Are you saying that we pushed
Doumoto Eizou out of the door?
I think that's impossible.
The door was double-locked on that side and I
had the key, so they couldn't have opened the door.
Which means you could have
opened the door if you wanted to?
No, she couldn't have done that.
Eh?
I doubt that a skinny woman could've moved a man
and pushed him out of the door while he was resisting.
Do you think so? She could try...
I was sitting right by the door
and I didn't hear the door opening.
But the window was fixed, and there's
no sign of using the emergency exit...
So from where...
Anyway, everyone please get off the mountain.
I will ask about more details then.
Yasunori-san, can we use the
special room in the rest house?
Please do.
Don't you think there's something
strange about Yasunori's behavior?
Yeah, he's hiding something.
No, he's hesitating to say something.
What on earth...?
Now that I think about it,
The preparation's perfect. Nobody has noticed it.
That conversation then, and when we discovered Eizou...
You've got to be kidding...
Thi-This wasn't supposed to happen...
He might have been expecting a different outcome.
We came to cover whether there's a curse or not, and
now we've ended up being suspects of a murder case.
Are we being cursed?
No idiot, we're lucky. This is a big scoop.
A different outcome... Perhaps...
Don't you think Yasunori is acting strange?
We have to clear the mystery of how Eizou,
Was found on the hand of the Goddess immediately
after his disappearance from the ropeway, don't we?
That's right, but that's the most important question.
The body can't walk by itself
and climb up the Goddess' statue.
It couldn't be! But, if that's true...
Then that prefabricated house!
Found it!
What's this?
Something is stuck on it.
This is...
A worker's trousers... These are good.
Then...
Good, I can use that mop.
This will do.
Hey! What are you doing here?
You surprised me.
It's not "you surprised me." I get
worried when you suddenly disappear.
I'm sorry. Ah, Ran-neechan.
What?
I'm getting a bit cold. Can I borrow your jacket?
Yeah, that's alright.
Here.
Thank you. I'll wait for you at the bottom.
Conan-kun!
What? Are you gonna leave me here?
Just as I thought.
Yasunori-san, you were sitting next to Eizou.
It was strange that you didn't notice anything.
What are you hiding from us?
No-Nothing.
Are you saying I'm the culprit?
Please show me the evidence if you're saying that I did it.
No, I'm not saying that you're the culprit.
Since this is such a mysterious case, I'm
asking everyone about their situations.
In that case, why don't you ask others?
Ah, of course!
Conan-kun?! How come you got here after me
even though you left the mountain before me?
Why?
Er, I got lost on the way...
Will you let me go?
I don't have a motive to kill Doumoto Eizou.
Ah, since you can't threaten him
anymore, there's nothing to do here, is there?
I can't deal with this family's problems anymore.
What?!
Please calm down. We'll be finished soon.
Officer Yokomizo, how about getting
on the ropeway with everyone here?
On the ropeway?
Hey! Don't say such a thing!
No, we have to! People say that we
should investigate the scene 100 times.
We may find something new.
We're getting on it again?
This case isn't a curse or anything.
The reason why the reporters from the
Toukainippou were chosen to join the first trip,
The trick to Eizou's disappearance,
Yasunori's suspicious behavior,
And the hand from the incinerator.
I'll solve all the mysteries behind the ropeway.
Eh, Mouri-san, could it be?
Shut up! Got a problem?
Not at all. I'm relieved to know that the
great detective is a normal person after all.
Ran-neechan. Look...
Eh? Why do you want me to...
Shh! Uncle said to do it secretly.
Dad said it? I understand.
10 sheep, 11 sheep, 12 sheep...
Uncle, are you chanting a sleeping spell?
Don't talk to me, I'll lose the count!
Okay, I shall make you sleep well.
Aha! It's come!
Mouri-san, are you okay? Ah!
The thing has come, hasn't it?!
Dad!
Take the photo! He became the sleeping Kogorou!
Yes!
Yasunori-san, I've said a lot of rude things,
But I knew from the start that
you didn't kill Doumoto Eizou.
As expected from Mouri-san...
Didn't you make a secret plan with Eizou
to surprise the public at the opening event?
You wanted to clear the rumors about
the Goddess' curse, and at the same time,
It would have made good publicity for the ropeway.
From now, I will re-enact the scene.
What's happened?
This is the same situation back then.
What's he going to do? Stop it!
Ran vanished...
The same situation as my father's case!
How on earth...
Can you do such a thing?
Mouri-san, where has your daughter gone?
Look at the Goddess' statue.
It can't be...
On the hand of the Goddess' statue!
Ran-san! No, that's a doll wearing Ran-san's jacket.
That's right. I made it with a mop and tree branches.
Ran, come out of there.
What?!
Under the seat...
Yasunori-san, you directed this completely
unexpected, but simple play, and Eizou acted it.
Isn't that right?
Yes, it is. I secretly asked a doll maker to
make a fake doll of father out of rubber.
When I walked down the promenade,
After separating from Mouri-san and the
rest, on the day before the opening ceremony,
I stopped at the viewing platform and put the doll
which was prepared beforehand on the Goddess' hand.
You can only see the hand from the
ropeway as it comes out of the tunnel.
So I didn't have to worry about someone noticing it.
Then, you carried out the plan
during the opening ceremony.
Yes, when the ropeway entered the
tunnel, I ripped the cord for the lights.
Note: In Buddhism, "sutra" refers to scriptures as records of the oral teachings of Buddha.
After that, I took out the tape recorder
and started to play the chanting of a sutra.
Father played being threatened and
hid himself in the space under the seat.
Then, I put the charm on the window.
I slapped down Nakano's camera.
The trick may have been
discovered because of the flashlight.
Normally, we keep an emergency kit or
weights for windy days under the seat.
I took them out in advance.
Father jumped off the empty ropeway while
everyone was going down to the viewing platform.
Like that, he went to the platform, then
he threw the doll from the hand to the cliff.
Father, who exchanged places with the doll, was
supposed to welcome you all with a smile and say:
"How about this! There's no
such thing as a curse in the world."
And he was supposed to clear the rumor.
You invited us for that.
No, it's not only for that.
Eizou was going to trick the Toukainippou.
Trick us? What do you mean by that?
Do you know why the opening ceremony started at noon?
Just the organizer's will...
Machida-san, you sent the article at the summit station.
Replace the front page of the
evening paper! The curse has struck!
Doumoto Eizou has been stabbed on the Goddess' hand.
If Eizou wasn't stabbed, could
you have fixed the front page?
The deadline for the evening paper is 1:30PM.
That's right. That means that the
wrong article would have been printed.
The sham by Eizou this time had two purposes,
One was to prove there was no curse and a
loss of Toukainippou's prestige was the other.
That's why he said such a thing that time.
That courageous front, I
wonder how long it's going to last...
What a dirty act...
In this ropeway, there was another
hidden tragedy other than the curse.
The builder's accidental death. I heard that from Rina.
Could you tell us about that, Yasunori-san?
The builder's name was Takahata.
His mother was sick and was indebted
to the Doumoto family for a long time.
So father forced her not to speak
about it with a bit of money in return.
Takahata-san who passed
away... Did he have any other relatives?
I heard that he has a little sister who was taken to
Tokyo by the divorced husband about 10 years ago.
That little sister may be on this ropeway right now.
No way.
But in here...
Yoshino-kun, you can't be...
That's right. The murderer of
Doumoto Eizou is you, Yoshino Ayaka-san!
She killed father?
I can't believe it?
Ayaka-san did it? No way...
This time the culprit had to be someone
who can secretly act together with Eizou,
And someone he wouldn't be cautious around.
Ayaka-san remained at the summit station, claiming
she felt dizzy, and got on the ropeway leading down.
Due to the panic over the president's accident at the
station, no one noticed that you got in the ropeway.
You accompanied the president down to the Goddess'
statue, killed him, and burned the doll in the incinerator.
You watched over the burning and returned to
the viewing platform where everyone else was.
This crime could only be done by someone
who knew Eizou and Yasunori-san's secret.
Ayaka-san, only you could have done that.
Is that so? This is just conjecture.
Yasunori-san, would you open the package next to me?
Yes.
You mean this?
Th-This is...
What is that?!
Could this be the doll's hand?!
This was found in the incinerator.
When Ayaka-san burned the doll, she
dropped something important on top of the hand.
What is that? It looks like a jewel.
No way!
That's right. It's a jade from the
brooch you're wearing on your chest.
If we blow up the group photo we took at the ceremony,
We can prove that there was nothing wrong
with the brooch before we got on the ropeway.
Everything Mouri-san said is true.
Would you mind telling us the reason?
Even after the divorce of our parents, my
brother and I kept in touch and encouraged each other.
When I rushed to the hospital last
year due to my mother's critical condition,
My mother passed away after telling me all about my
brother's death, and her spite towards Doumoto Eizou.
I hid my identity and joined
the Doumoto Tourist Company,
To avenge my dead brother and mother,
who both suffered because of Doumoto Eizou.
Natsu no maboroshi
Garnet Crow
Heya no mado no mukou ni hikouki kumo o nazotte
Beyond the window I see a trace
of clouds made by an airplane
Kyou kenkashita kimi no koto bakari kangaeteta
And realize I can only think about the fight we had today
Sasai na koto de to madotte fuantei de muboubi na
I hesitate with every small thing,
and I'm unreliable and hopeless,
Ano koro no you ni sugu ni denwashite
warai aetara ii no ni ne
Wishing to be able to be like I used to,
and call you right away, laughing
Chika zuite kuru shifuku no toki wa
itami o tomonainagara ashi oto o tateru
I can hear the steps of happiness coming
closer, bringing pain along with it
Kangaesugite fukami ni hamaru kimi no soba ni iru no ni
You are so focused in deep thoughts you
don't realize I'm right beside you
Natsu no maboroshi hitomi tojimete ichiban saishou ni kimi o omoidasu yo
Summer illusions I see, closing my eyes
the first one I remember is you,
Dakedo kimi to ikiteyukitai kara
And it's because I want to live with you by my side
Tomadoinagara demo ii tsunaida te o hanasanaide ne
I don't mind if you hesitate, just never let go of my hand
Ayaka-san... Is such a kind and wonderful person.
The reason why the rumor of the Goddess
statue's curse has been passed down for so long...
May be telling us about the horrible
outcome from making the Goddess angry,
By doing something humans shouldn't do or if
someone commits an unforgivable crime like this case.
Shoot, I fell asleep again!
Hey! Where is everyone?!
Hey, you sleeping Kogorou!
Next Episode
Professor! Call the police and the ambulance!
A cryptogram! We're gonna share this treasure!
Oh no, this could be...
Professor! Call the police now.
They've gone where the culprit, who pushed the car, is.
Mt. Ryujin falling case
Next Conan:
Mt. Ryujin falling case!
Next Conan's hint:
A trace of tire slip.
Please anticipate our next episode!
Next time is my big take!
It's Mitsuhiko's!
No way!