A strong heart and the power of deduction!
A sharp rhythm gets to the root of its true nature.
Today, a mountain road! Drive slowly!
At the bottom of the valley is the scent of a case!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Nishitama-gun, Mt. Ryujin
Tsuzura Ori Pass
("99 Bends")
Wow, amazing!
We've come so far up.
We've still got a long way to go.
We've only come about halfway.
Bleh. You can't be serious!
What's up?
Oh, man...
With all those hard right and left turns, I got dizzy...
Come on, what a sissy.
This place called Tsuzura Ori Pass
has a total of 99 curves, big and small.
Ugh! I feel sick to my stomach just listening to you...
Huh? Where's Mitsuhiko-kun?
Mitsuhiko's reading a book in the car.
Mitsuhiko-kun!
It's really nice out here!
No thanks, I'm reading the best part now!
Um, Doc, Haibara-san didn't come along again.
Oh... Ai-kun was saying she had something to do...
I know, Doc!
It went like this, right?
"I'm not interested in camps..."
"Snuff, snuff, snuff..."
You're really good, Genta-kun. That's a perfect impression!
Bullseye.
What's that?
Oh, no!
Doc! Get the police and an ambulance!
Okay!
You said you were resting at the scenic spot there,
when you witnessed the car go over the cliff, so you came running over, right?
Yeah.
A dent...
If so...
I'd like to ask you once again...
Did you notice something else suspicious, like a car or a person?
No, nothing at all...
I see...
Oh... I see.
Um, officer...
What is it, sonny?
May I go and take a look at what the men are doing above?
No, no, it's not something for a child to watch!
I think they're almost finished up there anyway...
It should be okay.
But...
But, sonny,
make sure you don't get in the way of their work when you watch them!
Yes, sir!
Hey, Mitsuhiko,
don't we have to go too?
Conan's going to go off on his own like always you know!
Oh... who cares, let him do what he pleases...
We've got something better here!
Something better?
Okay, here!
Okay!
Uh... 16.33 meters.
16.33...
There...
It's a piece of polish that rubbed off!
Really?!
Look, it's dark blue!
Dark blue...
W-Which means...
Yeah!
So that's what happened!
We came all the way out here to have a picnic and
get messed up in an accident like this...
It's no accident...
What do you mean, "it's no accident"?
Didn't the officer there ask you if you saw any other cars?
Yeah...
That car fell over because it was pushed from behind by another car.
What?!
That car had a dent in the rear,
an indication of it having been hit from behind.
Besides,
the paint that seemed to have rubbed off from the other car was also found.
Moreover,
the car that hit from behind most likely did so deliberately.
T-then it's homicide.
Yeah...
Don't we have to cooperate with the police?
It'll be fine, after all they've got so much evidence.
But, all they've got is rubbed off paint and a dent in the rear...
The Japanese police is usually very efficient.
So long as a piece of rubbed off paint is found,
from the color and substance they can figure out the model of the car too.
Then, all they have to do is
go asking around for details to get to the one who did it.
I see...
Mitsuhiko,
what do you mean by something better?
Shh! Quiet! Conan-kun will hear you!
This is it, Genta-kun!
What is this?
It's a code!
A code?!
Shh!
I picked it up near the site of the accident just a while ago.
Then, shouldn't you have told the police about it?
But, what we saw was just an accident, wasn't it?
It's hard to believe that a code has anything to do with it.
Right...
Codes are usually used for figuring out where treasures are hidden, aren't they?
Right, exactly!
Treasure, eh...
So, take a good look at this!
See, on the very top, in the square, the equation 100-1 is written.
Okay Genta-kun, what is 100-1?
Nnnn... nine... ninety-nine?
Right.
Is there something that crosses your mind when you think of the number 99?
99... 99...
9, 9...
911! Ambulance!
Nope!
Whatever gave you the idea of calling 911 at this point?!
First aid bandage then?
I got it!
The Tsuzura Ori Pass, right?!
Doc just explained that there is a succession of 99 hairpin curves, didn't he?!
Correct!
Which means that this code indicates
a place somewhere in the Tsuzura Ori Pass area.
And, did you figune out where it is, Mitsuhiko?
No, but this code sure looks familiar...
Where did you see it, Mitsuhiko-kun?
Hey you guys!
What's with all the racket?
Um, it's nothing!
Right, right, we're not talking about any codes.
Codes?!
Oh, uh...
Well, the novel that I was reading you see...
Some codes came out... They're too easy for you, so...
Oh, for children's stuff...
Good gracious...
Okay then, you guys,
Doc and I are going fishing,
don't forget to chop the firewood.
Okay!
Bye.
Here goes!
Mitsuhiko, did you really figure it out?!
It was in the book that I was reading!
Really?!
This!
What is this?
The keyboard of a computer?
Yes.
Numbers are written in numerical order from the top left.
and they correspond to the same hiragana keys!
For instance,
1 and 4 equals the hiragana "ta".
2 and 7 equals "to" and so forth.
All right!
Let's try it!
Genta, please read the number codes.
Okay!
0 and 4,
2 and 3,
3 and 8...
0 and 4 equals... "u".
2 and 3 equals "se".
3 and 8 equals "tsu"...
"A right turn"!
But...
What is this mark supposed to mean?
Maybe this is the shape of the road?
Right! You're probably right!
That's why the first code can be deciphered as
"Turn right at the intersection!
You're fantastic, Mitsuhiko-kun!
Let's continue!
I'll write it down!
There, it's done!
Please read it.
I'll follow along on the map.
Okay!
Turn right at the intersection after passing Tsuzura Ori Pass.
Turn right at the forked road,
then turn left at the next fork.
Cross two bridges,
turn left after the 2nd bridge and jackpot!
Okay, it's over here!
The pension house is over here, so it's pretty close!
Let's go check it out!
Maybe we'll find the treasure!
I'm sure Conan-kun will be vexed.
We're here.
Hey, are you guys upstairs?!
We've had a big catch!
Hey...
What's this?
Hey, bad news.
The kids are nowhere in sight!
What?!
Hey, Mitsuhiko...
Are we there yet?
We've only got a little more to go, so hang in there, Genta-kun.
We're crossing the 2nd bridge now.
After we turn right at the next fork, we'll get there!
We've still got that much more to go.
Hang in there, Genta-kun!
If we find the treasure, you'll get a luxurious serving of eels over rice!!
Eels over rice...
Okay, if we find the treasure, I'll eat all the eels over rice I can eat!
Let's go, Mitsuhiko, for 100,000 eels over rice!
Yes, let's do it!
Shoot! This could be...
Hmm?! Did you figure it out?
Doc, call the police right away!
What?!
They went to the hideout of the one who pushed the car over just a while ago!
So this was the code they were talking about in the car a while ago...
Darn!
We did it! We've finally come, Genta-kun!
It's over there!
Hey, Mitsuhiko,
are you sure this is the right place?
It doesn't look like it has anything to do with a treasure, does it?
What a thing to say!
We came exactly where the code said to go, so it's gotta be right!
Besides, it's places like this where treasures are usually hidden.
Okay, let's go inside then.
Yes, thank you!
The police will rush over to the site immediately!
Let's hurry on over too!
Okay!
It seems that nobody is in...
Hey, Mitsuhiko, where's the treasure?!
The building farthest beyond...
Look!
That building over there is the only one capable of being locked.
I'm sure its there!
Let's check it out!
T-this is...
Wow!
Wow, look at all those foreign car models!
Hey, Mitsuhiko,
there's no treasure anywhere, though...
Hmm... strange...
Hey, you two...
There's something funny about this car...
See...
It has no license plate.
You're right...
Hey, Mitsuhiko.
There's none on this one too!
Maybe they're all stolen cars.
I'm sure they're planning to sell them off to some foreign country.
We've come to the hideout of car smugglers!
Exactly!
You're the brats that were at the site of the the accident...
Who cares!
Where's the guy with the mustache and the other kid?
Just who are you referring to?
Don't you play dumb with me!
What was that sound?
The sound of gunfire!
What?!
Hurry up will you, Doc?
I know!
I'll ask you once more.
Where's the guy with the mustache and the other kid?
I-I have no idea what you're talking about
What?!
Hey, Mitsuhiko...
Mitsuhiko-kun...
No, I can't get Conan-kun and Doc involved in something
I got mixed up in because of my own actions!
He's right...
Yeah...
Oh... you must really want to die.
It's me.
Sorry, I've only got 5 for now.
Sada chickened out and rode off with one.
Yeah, I took care of that.
I hit him from behind at the ridge, and he fell head first all the way down.
I'm no goof...
I'll scrap the car before the police get to it.
Once it's scrapped, there's no proof.
That's...
Hey, what's with you guys?
What's with you?!
Swinging a rifle around towards children!
Doc!
You're the one who was at the scene of the accident...
Phooey, there couldn't be better timing... You saved me time looking for you!
No use, mister.
See, you hear it, don't you?
The sound of police car sirens...
What?!
They're coming here...
to arrest you, mister!
What?!
All right!
Hey, hey, officers...
What's with all the racket?
Before we hear you out, give us that gun of yours.
Oh, you mean this gun?
I was only trying to scare the kids because they trespassed on my property.
I see...
By the way, is that your car?
Yeah, that's right. Anything wrong?
Well, a car happened to go over the cliff at Tsuzura Ori Pass...
and it seems that a car of the same model as yours pushed that car over from behind.
Your car has a dent too, and it looks like it struck something...
What?! Are you suspecting me of something?!
There are several hundreds of cars like this, aren't there?!
Just how many of those hundreds do you think happened to be at the scene of the accident?
And where were you, may I ask, at that time?
Sorry... that was an accident...
Since the scenery was so beautiful,
I took my eyes of the road...
And the next thing I knew, crash!
He's lying, officer!
Shut up, stay out of this, brat!
No, I'm not shutting up!
You just said on the phone, that you struck the car and pushed it over the cliff!
I heard you say so too!
Me too!
Hey officer, are you going to believe what those brats say?!
For one, how could I push a car over a cliff by crashing into it from behind at such a sharp curve?
You did exactly that!
You succeeded perfectly!
Old man! Quit your gibberish!
Do have proof, or what? Proof!
Of course there's proof.
In the foreground of the curve where that car fell over,
there were two pairs of tire marks,
that were left behind when the car was hit from behind.
In other words, you collided twice!
So what?!
I wasn't looking at the road and I collided twice!
Well, there is a possibility too, however...
Do you know the space between the tires of the car that fell over?
Yes, 16.33 meters.
And, at what speed were you going at on that road?
Just about 30 km/h!
Well, I guess so...
The fact that you were going at 30 km/h means
you were going at about 8.3 meters per second.
In order to leave skid marks at a spacing of 16.33 meters,
it would take you approximately 2 seconds.
After colliding into the car in question, the first time, for a period of 2 seconds,
you never steered to avoid another collision,
nor did you step on the brakes.
Rather, you collided again!
If this is not called colliding deliberately, what else would you call it?
So... if you have anything more you want to say,
we'll hear you out at the station.
Darn!
Um, officer...
There are luxurious cars without license plates in the building beyond.
I'm sure those cars are all stolen!
Good work, all of you!
But listen,
don't ever do something dangerous like this again!
Y-Y-Yes sir!
Darn. I just don't seem to have the knack for chopping firewood.
Darn, darn it!
Hey, we need more firewood!
Hey, Conan-kun, why don't you help us a bit on this side too?
No way!
It's your own fault for loafing around without chopping firewood like you should've been,
serves you right.
Yes, yes, all right.
One "yes" is enough!
Yes!
I hope they learn their lesson and quit doing dangerous things.
How disappointing though.
What is?
Conan-kun deciphered that code in no time at all!
You were fantastic too, Mitsuhiko-kun!
Not only did you figure out the code, you also were right about the smugglers.
Oh. I just thought so because it was in the book I was reading!
Wow, just great. Maybe I should look through it too...
Oh, we got just the thing for you, Genta-kun!
"Children's Lunch Murder Case" is the title of it.
What a funny title!
I would rather have eels over rice than a children's lunch.
Hey, haven't you guys learned your lesson or what?!
How nice and bitter!
This is indeed what you call the world of wabisabi!
Huh?
I wonder what's up?
Why is she looking around like that?
Are you saying that the master is afraid of a monster?
I wonder if there really is such a thing as a monster?
D-Don't be ridiculous! No way such a thing exists!
T-The master is...
The Five-Colored Legendary Water Palace
(Part 1)
Next Conan's Hint: Hanging Scroll
Next time, a hard to understand anime original!
nankai
You won't get it, no matter how many times you watch.