Koi wa thrill, shock, suspense
Song by Rina Aiuchi
KOI WA THRILL, SHOCK, SUSPENSE
LOVE IS A THRILL, SHOCK, SUSPENSE
MIENAI CHIKARA TAYORI NI
RELYING ON UNSEEN FORCES...
KOKORO NO TOBIRA TOZASAZU NI TSUYOKU... TSUYOKU...
POWERFULLY WITHOUT LOCKING UP THE HEART'S DOOR... POWERFULLY...
A courageous heart and deduction power!
The rhythm that leads us to the truth!
A strange detached room in the legendary pond
As the water changes, the waterwheel turns!
Recognizing that one truth
a child with the mind of an adult
His name is Detective Conan!
WATASHI GA KANJITEITA
MAYBE I WAS GIVING YOU PAIN
TOGE OKIMI NI NO ONAJI
YOU NI ATAETEITA NO KANO SHIRENAKATTA
SIMILAR TO WHAT I'VE FELT, AND WITHOUT THINKING
NANI NI KOKORO WO ITAMETE NANI NI OBIETEITA NO KA
KI NI INO TOMEZU MOTSURETEKU FUTARI NO SHINJITSU NI
ABOUT WHAT GAVE ME PAIN, WHAT I FEARED
Opening Theme
「Koi wa thrill, shock, suspense」
MUKIAU NO GA KOWAKATTA
I FEARED FACING THE COMPLICATED TRUTH
THIS LOVE IS A THRILL, SHOCK, SUSPENSE
THIS LOVE IS THRILL, SHOCK, SUSPENSE
MAYOI WO AOI KAZE NI CHIRASOU TOSHITE MO KAKAEKIREZU NI ITA YO
EVEN IF I TRY TO SCATTER DOUBT IN THE BLUE WINDS
KONO CHISANA MUNE NI WA
I WAS UNABLE TO CARRY THE BURDEN WITH THIS SMALL CHEST
KOKORO NO TOBIRA TOZASAZU NI
WITHOUT LOCKING UP THE HEART'S DOOR
TSUGI E TO SUSUMU ARATA NA FUAN TO
EVEN IF I MUST CARRY MORE ANXIETY AND DOUBT
MAYOI WO KAKAETESHIMAISOU NI NATTE MO
AS I CONTINUE ON
Mouri-sama, as in the famous detective?
Well, yes...
Shirou Suzuki from the Suzuki Financial Company
said that someone would come in place of him
but to think it was you!
Please go easy on me!
Wow, a tea ceremony's headmaster's home!
What a beautiful mansion!
Tea ceremonies... so formal
Why did I come?
Conan! Come on!
Yes!
I guess I should get ready.
The Water Palace of Five Colors
(Part One)
Oh my gosh!
So pretty!
Enchanting! What a fascinating view!
I wonder why it shines in a yellow color?
Yeah.
Is this your first time looking at a pond?
At this time of year,
the water shines in five colors
depending on which lay the sun is facing.
I see.
That's why this place is called the Water Palace of Five Colors.
Yes.
And who are you?
Oh, pardon me.
These are my students.
Antique Dealer
Morio Yakura (42)
The antique dealer, Yakura-san.
Yukari Mimura (33)
Company President
And a manager of a company, Mimura-san.
N-nice to meet you.
This is the famous detective, Kogoro Mouri, and his family.
Oh!
The famous one!
It is an honor to meet you.
Housekeeper
Yoshiko Hanasaki (40)
Well, now that we're all here,
I'll call Master.
Uh... Master?
The headmaster of the tea ceremony.
This is exciting.
I wonder if the hard-to-please headmaster
will welcome even a famous detective?
That's why I didn't want to be a substitute!
Sorry! Sonoko asked me to.
Huh?
That's the housekeeper.
Which would mean...
That's where the headmaster is.
Hey,
Is the building in the middle of the pond, the tea room?
Eh?
Oh yeah...
It's simple and artistic.
It's like a wabi-sabi world!
That's definitely the tea room!
Yes. That's true.
It's built in the middle of the pond that changes colors.
It's called "Five Colors."
It's a tea room that was built for a break from everyday business.
Oh, it's called "Five Colors."
It's a nice tea room.
Hey, Ryoichi.
He is the headmaster's son.
Ryoichi Aonogi (28)
Headmaster's son
Mouri-san,
welcome.
Oh, you've already heard?
Why don't you tell the famous detective about the demon as well?
Demon?
What's that?
Well...
it's like the superstition of this pond.
Please do not talk about that. I only came here to say hello.
So if you'll excuse me,
I'll be going now.
Geez, Mimura-san
Don't make fun of Ryoichi.
Well, let's talk about this over there while we drink hot water.
They say it was during the end of the Edo period.
Fresh, clean, cold water sprang out from the pond.
It was even bigger than it is now.
A beautiful girl appeared by the pond.
As she played her flute, the color of the pond changed.
She entertained the people who came.
One day,
a rich merchant became interested in the girl,
and built a mansion near the pond.
She accepted his proposal of marriage with two conditions:
that the pond belonged to her, and no one was ever to go in it.
Yet, the merchant broke his promise,
and made a bedroom in the middle of the pond.
In addition,
he became angry at his wife who pressed
him to clear the room away immediately.
He killed her.
And drowned her in the pond.
However, one night
the boa that appeared from the lake attacked the merchant.
It was the girl,
The demon who lived in the pond.
Terribly wounded and with great difficulty,
the merchant went in the bedroom.
In the bedroom, there were talismans.
He was safe.
Still, the demon waited for him to come out.
He got tired and hung himself.
They say the reason why the colors change,
is because the demon takes the girl's
appearance and plays the flute.
It's hard to believe that there's such a horrible
legend in such a beautiful pond...
Everyone,
Sorry to make you wait.
Please come to the tea room.
Ryoichi-san isn't coming?
Even though he's the headmaster's only son,
he's not interested in tea ceremonies.
That's a difficulty.
And I haven't greeted the headmaster yet...
I'm very sorry, please forgive me.
Master rarely comes out these days.
He won't ever cross this bridge alone.
Master,
I've brought the guests.
Master?
Maybe he was eaten by the demon?
What are you doing!?
I-It appeared!
You!
Spying on people!
It's rude!
What do you think this sacred place is!?
Go!
Hurry and get out!
Master, please calm down.
It's our guest, Mouri-sama.
What?
Guest?
The substitute?
Geez...
Huh?
There's a waterwheel over there.
Hey, is that waterwheel a decoration?
It gives water to the river.
It's electrically-powered.
With the timer, it should turn at the decided time.
At one time, it was famous for tea water.
But after this tea room was made, the amount of water just...
Shh! Mimura-san, Master will hear you!
You came all the way here.
I'm sorry about my rude behavior earlier.
Please stay all day.
Thank you for inviting us.
Oh dear...
Talismans...
They're all over the place.
They are scared of the demon in the pond.
Master,
Did you see what I told Hanasaki-san to give to you?
An owner of Kyushu's ceramics factory gave it to
me, which was passed down many generations.
Ryouzou Aono (65)
Tea Ceremony Headmaster
It's impressive that you got such a thing,
But you are an antique dealer after all.
Let's use the teacup at tonight's tea ceremony.
Thank you very much.
The tea ceremony will be even better with the teacup.
I deserve it, after all, this is my last tea ceremony.
What do you mean, "last"!?
Mouri-san, I got the best, old sake.
Would you like to try?
Y-Yes...
Hanasaki, prepare the sake.
Master!
The last tea...?
What does that mean?
My leg's asleep...
Dad, it's embarrassing!
I'm going to get ready for the tea ceremony tonight.
No one is to come near the tea room.
I understand.
Mimura-san!
Where are you going?
I have a small errand to run.
What do you mean?
I'll be right back!
She is selfish!
Master is going to host the ceremony.
Oh, Yakura-san
The bath is ready.
Sorry to make you do that all the time.
Whoa! The pond's color changed!
The sun's reflection is gone and you can
see inside the pond. It looks green.
It'll turn red when the sun sets.
Hanasaki-san, why are these fishing rods...!?
T-That's...
Master told me to burn them...
Oh... As I thought...
You mustn't, Ryoichi-san!
Ryoichi, guests are watching.
Until tonight's tea ceremony is over, you should wait.
I know.
I'm just going to put these away.
Fishing is Ryoichi's only hobby.
Master can do such harsh things...
But yelling all of the sudden and burning the
fishing rods, instead of hard to please...
he's more like...
Last year, when the tea room was completed, his wife died.
His wife believed in the legend,
and she was against building the tea room.
It's a similar story.
Well, yes...
Between us pupils, there have been rumors where
some have seen the demon's shadow.
I see.
In other words, the headmaster is afraid of the
demon, which makes him hard to please.
No,
He says it's a stupid superstition and laughs it off.
I'm going to go get the hot water ready.
Well then. I'm going to go take a bath.
Please excuse me.
I wonder if there are really demons.
N-Nonsense...
W-Who's there?
Hey, you're...
Are you bored?
Yeah.
Did you catch that big fish?
Yeah, that's right.
Conan-kun!
I was wondering where you were...
Oh..
Sorry.
Well,
Let's eat some snacks in the guest room.
Yeeees!
Hey, Conan!
Where were you?
He was in Ryoichi-san's room.
There's a giant fish print hung in his room!
Ryoichi is amazing.
Sometimes he invites me to go night fishing with
him, but I can never be as good as him...
The security sensor. Looks like someone is here.
Huh?
I wonder what's wrong.
She's looking around restlessly.
Huh?
Whoa, it's red!
It's so bright, I can't see.
It's four o'clock.
At around this time, the sun makes a diffused reflection.
Oh, it's so hot!
Hanasaki-san, do you have a cold drink?
Mimura-san, where were you?
What? It's none of your business.
Her kimono is a mess and she's sweating a lot.
She must have really been in a rush.
Mimura-san!
That was rude!
You were invited!
Hmph!
What's with the arrogant attitude?
This is Master's tea ceremony!
To sneak out in the middle is...
Now now, both of you, calm down.
Aren't we talking about the last tea ceremony?
Exactly!
You were looking forward to his retirement!
What is that supposed to mean, Mimura-san!?
Don't assume things!
Now now...
Yes yes, I was wrong.
This sucks. Even the pond looks heated.
What is it?
That's... the headmaster...
Dad!
What is this blood?
It's no use, it's locked.
Are there any other entrances?
One to the water room in the back.
Ryoichi!
The water room is locked too!
We have no other choice but to break in then.
Move!
Master!
It's no use,
He's dead.
Dad...
It's the legend!
Just like the legend! Master was killed by the demon!
Dad...
Thank you.
Hey, it's Conan!
Inspector Yokomizo?
Which means Mouri-san is here, too?
Yeah.
He's over there.
Hey! Mouri-san!
I'm happy to see you again!
I'm not happy at all to see you.
You don't have to be so embarrassed!
Inspector Yokomizo!
I collected all of the information.
The entrance was locked from the inside.
And the screen was slightly open, but there were bars.
And on the east side, there was a water room, but it was also locked.
It was a locked room.
The estimated time of death was 3:30 to 4:00 PM.
The body was bleeding, but he died from the
pressure on his neck and it being choked.
It's suicide, huh?
Look at this blood.
The headmaster cut his wrists on the
veranda to commit suicide at first,
But he was unsuccessful so he hung himself in the tea room.
That would explain the trail of blood
from here to inside the tea room.
If he was unsuccessful at the veranda and committed suicide in the
tea room, then I don't think he would be able to lock the doors.
The waterwheel is turning.
So narrow!
A pinhole on the inside of the entrance door...
The cut end of the rope is strange...
Looks like it was cut halfway by a sharp object,
and then the other half was ripped off.
The scroll is spread out.
He was probably getting ready for tonight's tea ceremony.
While he was preparing, he suddenly chose death.
That's probably what happened.
He wasn't finished writing.
Hm?
This stuff is wood pieces?
Even on the tatami mat...
I see!
It's the beam that the rope was hung from!
Eh? There's no mark, though...
I can't see very well...
Y-yo, Conan!
Since when did you...
Don't bother us!
Can I have a piggy-back ride?
What!?
Go away, you little...
I knew it!
There's a mark where the rope wasn't!
And it's new!
Uh-ahh!
A-ahh!! U-Uncle!
Do what you want!
Killed by the legendary demon!?
Everyone, do you really think that we police are going to believe it?
W-We're positive!
The blood marks on the veranda and the
way he died is all similar to the legend!
Even if there was no demon, he died just like in the legend,
which would mean that he was killed by the demon, right?
We shouldn't have made this tea room.
Right after it was made, the wife died because
of a heart attack, and now, the headmaster...
It's definitely the demon!
Which means...
He was mentally stressed out, so he definitely committed suicide.
Yes.
No, that's wrong.
This isn't a suicide.
It's a murder!
One of these people used a clever trick to kill the
headmaster and made it look like a suicide!
Who is it?
The real demon who blames it on a demon!
Natsu no Maboroshi
Song by Garnet Crow
HEYA NO MADO NO MUKOU NI HIKOUKI KUMO WO NAZOTTE
TRACING THE AIRPLANE CLOUDS BEYOND THE WINDOW
KYOU KENKASHITA KIMI NO KOTO BAKARI KANGAETETA
THINKING ABOUT YOU, WHO I HAD A FIGHT WITH TODAY
SASAI NA KOTA DE TO MADOTTE FUANTEI DE MUBOUBI NA
HESITATING AT THE SMALLEST THINGS, BEING UNSTABLE AND RISKY
ANO KORO NO YOU NI SUGU NI DENWASHITE
WISHING THAT I CAN CALL YOU RIGHT AWAY
WARAI AETARA II NO NI NE
AND LAUGH TOGETHER LIKE WE USED TO
CHIKA ZUITE KURU SHIFUKU NO TOKI WA
THE HAPPINESS THAT IS COMING NEAR
ITAMI WO TOMONAINAGARA ASHI OTO WO TATERU
BRINGS ALONG PAIN, AS IT MAKES NOISES, AS IT WALKS
KANGAESUGITE FUKAMI NI HAMARU
KIMI NO SOBA NI IRU NO NI
I'M NEAR YOU WHEN YOU ARE THINKING DEEPLY
Ending Theme
「Natsu no Maboroshi」
NATSU NO MABOROSHI HITOMI TOJIMETE
ICHIBAN SAISHOU NI KIMI WO OMOIDASU YO
SUMMER'S ILLUSION, CLOSING MY EYES, I THINK ABOUT YOU FIRST
DAKEDO KIMI TO IKITEYUKITAI KARA
BUT I WANT TO KEEP ON LIVING WITH YOU
TOMADOINAGARA DEMO II TSUNAIDA TE WO HANASANAIDE NE
HESITATING IS OKAY, BUT DON'T LET GO OF MY HAND