Koi wa thrill, shock, suspense
Song by Rina Aiuchi
KOI WA THRILL, SHOCK, SUSPENSE
MIENAI CHIKARA TAYORI NI
KOKORO NO TOBIRA TOZASAZU NI TSUYOKU... TSUYOKU...
A courageous heart and deduction power!
The rhythm that leads us to the truth!
A pond that changes color with time...
Dyed red, the case is solved!
Recognizing that one truth, a child with the mind of an adult...
His name is Detective Conan!
WATASHI GA KANJITEITA
TOGE OKIMI NI NO ONAJI
YOU NI ATAETEITA NO KANO SHIRENAKATTA
NANI NI KOKORO WO ITAMETE NANI NI OBIETEITA NO KA
KI NI INO TOMEZU MOTSURETEKU FUTARI NO SHINJITSU NI
Opening Theme
「Koi wa thrill, shock, suspense」
MUKIAU NO GA KOWAKATTA
THIS LOVE IS A THRILL, SHOCK, SUSPENSE
MAYOI WO AOI KAZE NI CHIRASOU TOSHITE MO KAKAEKIREZU NI ITA YO
KONO CHISANA MUNE NI WA
KOKORO NO TOBIRA TOZASAZU NI
TSUGI E TO SUSUMU ARATA NA FUAN TO
MAYOI WO KAKAETESHIMAISOU NI NATTE MO
We came as the substitutes for Sonoko
and her father, the Suzuki president,
and decided to attend a tea meeting at the Aonogi house.
At the backyard of the mansion, there
was a pond that shined in five colors.
And there was a bridge which led to the tea room.
While we were enjoying the pond's colors,
something unusual happened...
The headmaster died in the tea room, the same way as the legend.
No, that's wrong.
This isn't a suicide.
It's a murder!
Someone here used a clever trick to kill the
headmaster and made it look like a suicide!
Who on earth is it?
The real demon who blames it on a demon.
The Water Palace of Five Colors
(Part 2)
Well, then!
When all of you gathered in this room after four o'clock,
you saw the headmaster's body from this veranda, right?
Antique Dealer
Morio Yakura (42)
Yes. The pond was turning red.
And then, Ryoichi-kun checked the time on his watch.
Yes. It was exactly four o'clock.
Ryoichi Aonogi (28)
Headmaster's Son
At that time, I looked in the tea room,
but my father's body was not there.
Yoshiko Hanasaki (40)
Housekeeper
Yukari Mimura (33)
Company President
Afterwards, Mimura-san came back and
we discovered the body immediately.
Where was everyone at that time?
I was in the bath for thirty minutes.
I had some stuff to do so I went out for a bit.
Where did you go?
It's my personal matter. I don't need to answer that.
What about you, Hanasaki-san?
Getting ready for tonight in the kitchen and entertaining the guests.
Ryoichi-san, where were you?
I went in and out of the guest room.
I heard the headmaster burned your precious fishing rods?
T-That is...
What exactly happened?
Actually, I was told to participate in tonight's tea ceremony.
What he was planning to do was...
...to make me the next headmaster.
But you don't know anything about tea ceremonies!
You're kidding, right? I can't believe Master
would say something like that now.
So, Ryoichi-san. Did you accept?
Of course not, I refused.
Which means the headmaster burned your fishing
rods because you wouldn't listen to him,
and you hated the headmaster for that.
W-Wait!
Inspector Yokomizo.
When the headmaster died, everyone, including
Ryoichi-san, was in this room.
That's true.
Even if someone went out to murder him,
we probably would have seen them.
I was sitting on that chair the whole time,
but there was no one heading towards the tea room.
Which means... they all have perfect alibis.
And I wonder what Mimura-san brought from outside...
She was glancing around nervously, but she
probably didn't have the time to hide it.
Which would mean...
That!
I knew it. Just as I thought!
May I have a cup of water? Oh, sorry I'm so thirsty.
Here you are.
Thank you.
I'm going to make tea for everyone anyway.
Hey, Hanasaki-san?
Oh, little boy.
Why won't Ryoichi-san, the only son, succeed to the headmaster?
W-Well...
You're only a kid. It's none of your business.
But that's true. Why?
I didn't want to become like my father.
He was arrogant, and my mother had
to go through many hardships.
But the position for headmaster has been passed down for many
generations, so naturally, wouldn't he want his son to succeed?
If you become headmaster, you can make speeches
and teach classes to earn lots of money.
Teacups that have been passed down for many
generations also belong to the headmaster.
My father was only interested in that!
If you take over, you can still live the same life after you retire, right?
I didn't like that side of my father. Hanasaki-san, I'll help.
Ah, thank you.
If you were that miserable, you should've left the house.
H-Hey!
Yes. Well, I was out for a long time.
I made him come back because I couldn't
take care of the master by myself.
I see.
We made a deal, so I didn't have to succeed to the headmaster.
My father didn't have anyone to reply on accounting,
so he said if I did that, it was okay.
I see... But then he brought the subject back up?
Accounting... You know how much money
the Aonogi household has, right?
Hey!
Is that true?
If the headmaster died while the next headmaster
was undecided, you would take over.
And then the headmaster's position and you would become free.
What was the real reason you came back home?
Pardon me! Master was in an unhealthy
state! He's worried about his father!
Whatever. Thank you, Hanasaki-san. Then, I'll take this.
In other words, the headmaster, who's afraid of the demon,
shut himself up in the tea room with talismans.
And he didn't like others going near the room.
Yes. For that, we've set up security sensors.
So there's a very small chance that an outsider can get in.
That's true. Around the tea room is a lake...
If someone crossed this bridge, someone
would have noticed from here.
How did the culprit...?
What?
You're giving expensive ceramics and trying
to act innocent. Master is not that dumb.
Look who's talking!
You have an eye on being the headmaster.
You're investing money to the point where
your company is not doing well!
Wait a minute. We're only asking about his personality.
What is this teacup? Hanasaki-san, there's a crack in it.
I'm terribly sorry.
You were probably too worried about the appearance
and didn't even bother to look at the other side, right?
Worried about the appearance!?
Now now, everyone's upset right now, so...
Really? Hanasaki-san, aren't you happy that Master is dead?
He made his wife, who loved you dearly,
suffer and have a shorter life.
That is not true!
Hanasaki-san did her very best for Father.
Oh. You two didn't lead Master to commit suicide
by scaring him with those legends?
W-What are you saying!?
How awful!
Hanasaki-san!
Hanasaki-san.
I don't bear a grudge...
Don't worry about it. It's a common thing
for Mimura-san to say things like that.
Is this the wife?
She looks very kind.
She was a very kind person.
Just looking at her picture cheers me up.
That's why there are so many pictures of her.
She didn't blame me even if I hated tea ceremonies.
She would even come fishing with me.
This knot...!
Found it. Looks like someone forced their way here.
If my deductions are correct...
Just as I thought.
So then the culprit would have to be that person who
was acting awkwardly when the body was found.
There should be some evidence that the culprit left behind.
That's...!
I found it!
The frozen evidence!
Well, thank you everyone.
Then we can go home now, right?
Yes. It's probably a suicide.
Crap!
Geez.
Conan, we're going home.
Where's Uncle?
He should be coming down right now.
I'm done~. Well, I should go home.
Sounds great! After one nap.
All we have to do now is wait for the inquest's results.
Yes.
Inspector!! Uncle says, "Are you letting
the culprit leave right in front of you?"
Culprit!?
Dad figured it out!
What does this mean, Mouri-san?
You actually realized it, right, Inspector Yokomizo?
The headmaster did not commit suicide; he was murdered.
Will you please explain it?
It's a good thing the famous detective
is here. It's a good way to kill time.
Well, let's make this up to the point.
While the pond was turning red, there was
a crime that none of you were aware of.
But when the body was discovered, everyone was in this room!
How do you explain that?
Yes.
While the culprit was in this room,
he hung the headmaster from the beam in the tea room...
...using one rope.
What did you say!?
R-Rope?
Like the legend of this pond, the culprit stabbed
the headmaster at the veranda of the tea room,
and strangled him from behind to kill him.
Then he hung the rope which was hidden
somewhere in the room on the beam,
and made a knot that would tighten in one pull.
He tied one end around the headmaster's neck,
and the other around the pillar, then out the window.
He tied that rope to another rope which he had tied beforehand
on the waterwheel that was hidden beneath the water.
He then could prepare for the time trick. Finally, on the entrance
door, he created a spring with thumbtacks and rubber bands.
He pulled it, used the hook to hang the scroll as a
stopper, and used the scroll to uphold the door.
After setting up a locked-room murder, the culprit left the scene.
Oh yeah, there was a pinhole on the inner side of the entrance door.
What?
Afterwards, the culprit came back to this room and made an alibi.
How creepy! Is that true?
Around 4:00, the pond turned red,
and the waterwheel started turning.
And then the rope winded. The body
was dragged into the tea room.
The body hit the scroll near the door, causing
the scroll to fall and the door to shut.
The panel became locked in the post's hole. After the
body was pulled up to the beam, the rope tightened.
A cut that was measured beforehand ripped. The
rope was dragged outside by the waterwheel.
While we were shocked to find the body,
the cuplrit pretended to put the door aside and
took off the rubber bands and thumbtacks.
I see. That's possible!
When the waterwheel turns,
the sun made a diffused reflection which
makes the rope harder to see.
The culprit used this for the crime.
But how did the murderer go in the tea room?
Through the bridge that we were looking at.
Weren't you the one who said that no
one went to the tea room, Mouri-san?
"You were too concerned about the front,
so you didn't look at the other side."
Isn't that what you said, Mimura-san?
Eh? Yes...
Exactly that.
The culprit used that blind spot.
While he left us gazing at the pond, he boldly went
to the tea room... underneath the bridge.
W-What?
He hid in the shrubs beside the pond and crept under the bridge.
Then, he swam to the tea room underneath the bridge.
After that, he came up in front of the entrance door on the veranda.
He then lured the headmaster out of the
room and stabbed him with a knife.
So Mouri-san, who is the culprit?
The culprit was acting very strangely around
the time when the headmaster was killed.
Mimura-san, that's you. Saying that you went out!
What? Are you saying I'm the culprit?
You'll explain to us this time, right?
Where were you?
I only went to get this!
Isn't that an expensive teacup?
How did you know?
You knew that the headmaster was going to retire tonight.
Weren't you afraid that Yakura-san might become headmaster?
So you hurried to go buy an expensive teacup
that was better than Yakura-san's.
Isn't that right, Mimura-san?
Well, most of the money here goes
to me if I become the headmaster.
I got a little greedy.
It's probably the truth.
If she went out and sneaked back in, the alarm would go off.
When Mimura-san came, Hanasaki-san went
out and escorted her up the stairs, right?
Unfortunately, there was no time for
Mimura-san to go near the tea room.
Which means Mimura-san is not the culprit.
Then who is it?
The culprit knew that no one would go near the headmaster,
who was busy setting up for tonight's ceremony.
He hung the headmaster's neck in a special way.
A Cleat Hitch knot. Fishermen use it when they moor the boat.
Fishing?
It wasn't me!
Yeah, it's not you.
After all, the culprit swam underneath the bridge.
I see! He must have been wet! Hair and body!
To trick us, he took a bath after he committed the crime.
Yes. The culprit is you, Yakura-san!
When we all gathered in this room, you were harshly blaming
Mimura-san, to the point where we had to stop you.
It was probably because you didn't want us
to see the moment the body was lifted.
That's why you were so serious!
After that, all you had to do was wait
for someone to notice the body.
No! Those are guesses! You don't have any proof!
Admit your crime already. You left proof for us. On the bridge!
Mouri-san! The thing you asked for was there!
What is it?
It was under the bridge!
Handprints! What is this black thing?
It's the moss in the pond.
I thought that if someone passed there...
...there would be some marks.
There were so many handprints.
I think we may be able to get fingerprints!
The investigators are searching!
Excuse me, Yakura-san, but may we have your fingerprints?
I thought it was a perfect plan...
You admit it?
That man was the worst!
He told you that you were going to be the next
headmaster and you believed him, right?
It's not like that!
Together, we made fake expensive ceramics and sold them.
No way...
You didn't know? We've been doing it for over ten years.
But he started believing that his wife's
death and the demon were related.
He changed. He was planning to officially make Ryoichi headmaster.
You wanted to stop him before he made an official announcement.
It's because he made that kind of tea room...
Look! It turned out to be exactly like the legend!
Natsu no Maboroshi
Song by Garnet Crow
HEYA NO MADO NO MUKOU NI HIKOUKI KUMO WO NAZOTTE
TRACING THE AIRPLANE CLOUDS BEYOND THE WINDOW
KYOU KENKASHITA KIMI NO KOTO BAKARI KANGAETETA
THINKING ABOUT YOU, WHO I HAD A FIGHT WITH TODAY
SASAI NA KOTA DE TO MADOTTE FUANTEI DE MUBOUBI NA
HESITATING AT THE SMALLEST THINGS, BEING UNSTABLE AND RISKY
ANO KORO NO YOU NI SUGU NI DENWASHITE
WISHING THAT I CAN CALL YOU RIGHT AWAY
WARAI AETARA II NO NI NE
AND LAUGH TOGETHER LIKE WE USED TO
CHIKA ZUITE KURU SHIFUKU NO TOKI WA
THE HAPPINESS THAT IS COMING NEAR
ITAMI WO TOMONAINAGARA ASHI OTO WO TATERU
BRINGS ALONG PAIN, AS IT MAKES NOISES, AS IT WALKS
KANGAESUGITE FUKAMI NI HAMARU
KIMI NO SOBA NI IRU NO NI
I'M NEAR YOU WHEN YOU ARE THINKING DEEPLY
Ending Theme
「Natsu no Maboroshi」
NATSU NO MABOROSHI HITOMI TOJIMETE
ICHIBAN SAISHOU NI KIMI WO OMOIDASU YO
SUMMER'S ILLUSION, CLOSING MY EYES, I THINK ABOUT YOU FIRST
DAKEDO KIMI TO IKITEYUKITAI KARA
BUT I WANT TO KEEP ON LIVING WITH YOU
TOMADOINAGARA DEMO II TSUNAIDA TE WO HANASANAIDE NE
HESITATING IS OKAY, BUT DON'T LET GO OF MY HAND
It's already night.
If you want, I can drop you off at a station or a hot springs resort.
Oh, thank you!
But even though the crime was based off of the legend,
I almost thought there was actually a demon!
Well, it was back then, so there was
probably a big snake. It's nothing.
If it pops out, we'll just catch it and make
snake skin! What are you doing?
What are you guys doing?
T-That...
A boa!
Hey hey, you said it wasn't a big deal...