Koi wa thrill, shock, suspense
Song by Rina Aiuchi
KOI WA THRILL, SHOCK, SUSPENSE
LOVE IS A THRILL, SHOCK, SUSPENSE
MIENAI CHIKARA TAYORI NI
RELYING ON UNSEEN FORCES...
KOKORO NO TOBIRA TOZASAZU NI TSUYOKU... TSUYOKU...
POWERFULLY WITHOUT LOCKING UP THE HEART'S DOOR... POWERFULLY...
A courageous heart and deduction power!
The rhythm that leads us to the truth!
The Matsutake is an expensive, delicious, and very rare mushroom found in Asia.
The Matsutake picking Detective Boys.
Be careful of the bad hunter!
Recognizing that one truth,
A child with the mind of an adult,
His name is Detective Conan!
WATASHI GA KANJITEITA
MAYBE I WAS GIVING YOU PAIN
TOGE OKIMI NI NO ONAJI
YOU NI ATAETEITA NO KANO SHIRENAKATTA
SIMILAR TO WHAT I'VE FELT, AND WITHOUT THINKING
NANI NI KOKORO WO ITAMETE NANI NI OBIETEITA NO KA
KI NI INO TOMEZU MOTSURETEKU FUTARI NO SHINJITSU NI
ABOUT WHAT GAVE ME PAIN, WHAT I FEARED
Opening Theme
「Koi wa thrill, shock, suspense」
MUKIAU NO GA KOWAKATTA
I FEARED FACING THE COMPLICATED TRUTH
THIS LOVE IS A THRILL, SHOCK, SUSPENSE
THIS LOVE IS THRILL, SHOCK, SUSPENSE
MAYOI WO AOI KAZE NI CHIRASOU TOSHITE MO KAKAEKIREZU NI ITA YO
EVEN IF I TRY TO SCATTER DOUBT IN THE BLUE WINDS
KONO CHISANA MUNE NI WA
I WAS UNABLE TO CARRY THE BURDEN WITH THIS SMALL CHEST
KOKORO NO TOBIRA TOZASAZU NI
WITHOUT LOCKING UP THE HEART'S DOOR
TSUGI E TO SUSUMU ARATA NA FUAN TO
EVEN IF I MUST CARRY MORE ANXIETY AND DOUBT
MAYOI WO KAKAETESHIMAISOU NI NATTE MO
AS I CONTINUE ON
Mushrooms, Bears, and the Detective Boys
(Part One)
Mushrooms, Bears, and the Detective Boys...
Part One!
Is everyone ready?
Although we're here to pick Matsutake mushrooms,
don't go wild picking them.
There's a limit of three per adult and two per child.
When you're done, the hotel will cook them for you.
Yes!!!
Ah, also, pay attention to the metal fences
because past them is hunting area.
Don't go there!
Hunting area?
There are bears there.
B-bears?!
But it's okay.
Over on this side, there aren't any, so you can relax.
Hey, hey, what kind of place are we
picking Matsutake mushrooms?
Geez!
That guy at the hotel said that we'd find a lot here!
There aren't any here! Damn it!
Hey, hey.
But Genta-kun, weren't you the one that
wanted to pick Matsutake mushrooms?
I really wanted to go pick apples.
It's because Matsutake mushrooms are the kings of fall food.
And they're also much more rare and expensive than apples!
Oh?
Apples are the fruits that Adam and Eve ate,
and were banished by God from the Garden
of Eden because of this prohibited food,
which can analyze good and evil.
Isn't it more mysterious than the Matsutake mushroom?
Since it analyzes good and evil, Genta-kun
needs to eat a lot more of these!
Shut up!
It's the old testament, right?
Well, the fruit is an apple only because of popular belief.
What's wrong, Mitsuhiko?
What's with the weird look?
I'm not making a weird face!
I was just looking at her.
By her, do you mean Haibara?
Yes.
Haibara-san's words are harsh,
but she's really pleasant, smart, and mature.
Don't you think she's mysterious?
B-but, just because, it's not like...
Well, Mitsuhiko,
I won't say anything mean, but don't choose her.
She'll be too difficult to deal with.
Hey, come here, come here!
This is a Matsutake mushroom, isn't it?
This mushroom is only found in Asia.
That's a Tengutake, a poisonous mushroom.
Ah, I can't do this anymore!
There aren't any hints and the Matsutake
mushrooms are too hard to find!
There are hints.
Just look at the surroundings!
The needles on the pine trees have
become a yellow-green, right?
Matsutake mushrooms grow near the roots of
red pine trees to get nutrition from them.
This means the trees will decay and
the needles will change color.
Also, for the Matsutake to grow well, there
has to be good soil, water, and wind.
Given that information, if we look carefully here...
Look, we found the culprit!
Where? Where? Where is it?
This is one big Matsutake!
Delicious...
We finally got our first one!
Everyone, look over here!
There are lots of red pine trees with yellow-green needles!
Really?
All right! I'm going to find some, too!
Needles are a yellow-green color, under the red pine tree...
I've found the culprit, Matsutake-san, see?
Hey, I've found one too!
It looks like Matsutake picking can
be as interesting as a treasure hunt.
I know!
Hey, where did Genta go?
Come to think of it, I haven't seen him for a while.
He's probably going to the bathroom somewhere.
Genta-kun was chugging down a lot of mineral water earlier.
It's not good to get lost somewhere in the forest.
Anyway, let's go back to places we've been already.
Yes.
Genta-kun climbed over the first fence?
R-really?
Yeah.
There's no mistake.
The mud marks on the fence are new, and
the spacing in between them is narrow.
It's proof that a child climbed over.
Plus, I can see many red pine trees with yellow-green
needles just past this first fence.
But, it's too bad.
Genta-kun's detective badge is being repaired right
now, so we can't use your tracking glasses.
Then we have no choice but to look for him.
You guys stay here and I'll...
You're taking the action all for yourself again!
We're going to look for him too! We're worried!
B-b-but, on the other side there's...
In that case, why don't we do this?
Tsuburaya-kun and I will pair up.
You and Yoshida-san pair up, and we'll search separately.
Just in case, if Kojima-kun comes back on his own,
the Professor will be here.
Well?
Isn't this better than you going by yourself?
Y-you have a point, but...
But, be careful, Haibara.
Over two fences, it's hunting area.
Humans have often been mistaken to be wild
animals, and are sometimes shot by hunters.
It isn't rare in Japan.
Oh?
Thank you for worrying about me.
You know what?
Anyway, come back here in one hour.
If you guys can't find him, we'll ask the
hotel staff to help us search for him.
Begin!
Yeah!
Why are you just standing there?
We need to start climbing too.
Yes!
Hey, Genta!!!
Genta-kun, answer us!
Crap, where could that guy have gone?
Genta!
Genta-kun, where are you?
Umm... Can I ask you a question?
What's the relationship between you and Conan-kun?
What do you mean?
I mean, you two often go to a corner,
and talk about things ordinary children don't understand.
It seems you only understand each other...
Like you two are in your own world...
Don't worry about it.
It's not as romantic as you think.
But...
Well, anyway, let's keep moving.
Wait...
What was that sound just now?
It came from the other side of the second fence.
The fence is broken...
Maybe he went through here to the other side.
There's no way, the other side is the hunting area.
If you were to get lost after passing through the first fence,
you wouldn't be able to tell the difference between
the Matsutake picking area and the hunting area.
Wait, hold on a second!
Genta-kun, is that you? Well, we were worried about you!
A b-b-b-bear!
It's okay.
It's only a cub.
Looks like he isn't even a year old.
Cute, isn't he?
Y-you're right.
But be careful. Its mother may be nearby.
Gunfire?!
Could a hunter have shot this cub's mother!?
Ah, don't!
Don't go over there!
Look, it's the hunter!
Could it be that he thinks we're animals?
Hey!
We're humans!
Th-this is...!
This wound...
A gun wound...
Could it be?
Hey!
Don't shoot us!
We're human!
Hey!
Don't you understand?
That hunter is trying to shoot us!
He wants to silence us because he thinks
we saw him murder someone!
Where have you been, Genta!
We were all worried about you!
I'm sorry...
I wanted to get Matsutake for everyone,
and I just kept going farther...
Well, well, at least he returned safely.
Hey, have you contacted Haibara and Mitsuhiko?
You see, I already called them a while back, but...
Geez, now those guys are lost?
Hey, hey, hey.
Mitsuhiko's badge is located in the hunting area.
That's strange.
They should have known not to go there.
Geez.
Let's find them as fast as we can before
it gets dark and return to the hotel!
Yeah!
Hey, hey, it's impossible for me to get through here!
Come on, try harder!
What are you doing?
Yasaka Kiyoshi (41)
Hunter
At a place like this with children.
Two children accidentally wandered in here.
We're looking for them.
Uncle, have you seen a boy and girl around here?
No.
Hey, I found it! Mitsuhiko's detective badge!
Really?!
But, neither of them are here.
Blood?!
Hey! This is a pretty big footprint!
It looks like a bear.
Then they were both eaten by a bear?
I don't think so.
In reality, bears are afraid of people,
and don't think of them as food.
If it's that one, though, the situation is different.
Saika Matasaburou (67)
Hunter
It has a grudge against all humans.
Both of them could have become
another meal before hibernation!
That is the single-eyed giant bear, by the name of Jubei!
N-no way...
I see.
The rumor of that bear is actually true then?
The long trip here was worth it after all.
Don't worry, little girl.
I'll deal with that thing and get revenge for your friends.
Negoru Tomoya (28)
Hunter
What revenge?
We don't even know if they have been attacked for sure!
Anyway, let's help them find the children.
Yeah, we know this area better than they do.
Sorry, little girl.
Hey, Mitsuhiko!
Haibara-san!
It's Conan-kun and the others!
Look, on that side of the forest.
Hey!
Wait.
They're with that hunter we met.
Why are they with him?
He's trying to find us, the witnesses of the murder.
If we go out like this, we will definitely die.
He'll say he mistook us for a bear.
Hey, Haibara!
Where are you, Mitsuhiko?
If you're there, answer!
It's another potato chip!
It's probably something that both of them dropped.
They must have left it here to tell
us which direction they went.
Hey, why don't we just use Conan's glasses
to locate where Haibara's badge is?
No, her badge is on the desk at my house.
I only fixed your badge because I was
testing some different functions out.
I was working on it last night.
No way...
Hey, Professor.
Do you remember the place where we
found Mitsuhiko's badge earlier?
Yeah, by the metal fence with the hole in it.
Then call the people in the hotel, explain the situation
to them, and tell them to call the police.
Police?!
They left traces that they were here, but even after
looking for so long we still can't find them.
Don't you think it's weird?
But aren't they just running from the bear?
No, there was blood near the place where
we found Mitsuhiko's badge.
And there was a new bullet mark
on the tree next to the blood.
Perhaps they aren't actually running from a bear...
Hey, could it be...?
Mitsuhiko-kun and Haibara-san?
Hey! Stop it!
It ran away.
Rabbit-san...?
Did you even think about it?
What if that was one of the children?
My eyes can tell the difference
between an animal and a child.
Even if the legendary Jubei appears,
you don't need to worry.
I'll do a clean shot and get him...
To him this is just like a toy gun.
What?
If you want to keep your life when
you meet Jubei, don't move!
That thing can smell humans from far away,
and will attack anyone without hesitation!
A monster that is 2 meters tall!
I'm the only one that can kill it.
20 years ago, I was the person that shot its eye!
Who is that old man?
He's a famous hunter around here.
I hear he came from the Southeast and
led a mountain running group here.
But after he met Jubei in this mountain,
he decided that he wanted to stay here.
Mountain running group?
He was the boss of a hunting group.
So we can relax if a bear comes out!
Anyway, Professor, make the call.
Ye-yeah.
As I expected, if that hunter sees
us, he'll kill us immediately.
B-but, if we shout really loudly, wait until we're
near them and step out in front of them...
Little Yoshida-san is over there with them.
He can take her hostage and kill all the others.
That person has already murdered one man.
N-no way...
From the way he fired his gun at us,
I think he came up to this mountain with that other
hunter as an excuse to commit his murder.
But don't you need a license to go hunting?
If the body was found in the mountains, wouldn't
they suspect the hunters and their companions?
No, when a license is approved, it stays
approved for a very long time.
Once they get a license, they can
go hunting wherever they want.
In other words, there are no restrictions
as to who comes here.
If the person you kill has a license,
then you will have an alibi.
If the corpse is found, you could
also say another hunter did it.
Then, he saw us when we were at the scene of the crime...
Yes. Now his whole plan is ruined.
He probably wants to kill us now as well.
In that case, instead of leaving these chips so they will
find us, both of us should get out of this forest.
We can't.
Taking action in an unfamiliar forest is very dangerous.
Either way, we can only leave this mountain
once we meet up with the Professor.
But it's okay.
I left the detective badge right by the corpse.
Edogawa-kun will definitely notice it.
Right, I'm sure of it.
Well, why don't we talk about it while we're walking?
Now we need to figure out some way to contact them all.
Also, there's this cub...
who's been following us for some reason.
It would be bad if the hunters meet this cub.
Yes.
This was done by a giant bear.
Using its claws to take off the outside layer,
and then eating the whole inside.
The distance of the marks is wide, and the position is high.
It was something very big.
It was Jubei.
I believe she gave birth to a cub this winter, so
they should be happily together somewhere.
Gave birth?
Isn't Jubei a male?
Don't you know?
The legend states that the mountain god was
always jealous of the mountain goddess.
People tried to avoid the jealousy of
the mountain god while hunting.
So her name was changed to a male name.
Yagyuu Jubei is a famous samurai from the Feudal Era.
It was changed to be like the swordsman, Yagyuu Jubei.
A female bear that's over two meters tall?
That makes me even more eager to see it.
No matter what happens.
Is there something on my face, old man?
Ah, no.
You just said the exact same thing as my friend did.
Hey, did that friend of yours happen
to come with you today?
Because earlier, when you took your camera
out of your pocket, I saw pellets there.
Those were the kind that fire 9 bullets at once, right?
But earlier you only fired one bullet.
I heard that hunters usually don't carry
two different types of bullets.
My friend forgot to take spare bullets
with him to this mountain.
I thought if I met him on the mountain,
I'd pass them on to him.
But will he be okay?
Your friend is still alone on this mountain somewhere, right?
It'll be okay.
He's been up this mountain many times before.
We always split up when we come here to hunt.
Is everything all right, Ayumi-chan?
Yeah, it's nothing!
Hey, we're going!
Yeah.
Hey, Ayumi!
Wait!
We Detective Boys decided to go mushroom
picking in the mountains.
And during it, Genta got lost in the hunting area.
We split into two groups to search for Genta.
And Haibara and Mitsuhiko...
...discovered a dead body, and have become
targets for the dangerous hunter.
We found Genta, and three hunters decided
to help us look for Haibara and Mitsuhiko.
Mushrooms, Bears, and the Detective Boys
(Part Two)
Mushrooms, Bears, and the Detective Boys...
Part Two!
This is our last chip.
We have none left, Haibara-san.
Haibara-san!
What happened?
While we were trying to escape, I twisted my ankle.
I was holding it in earlier.
Please let me see it.
S-sorry...
Wait, your foot is swelling and its purple!
Anyway, I'll help you treat it now.
Bear with it a bit longer.
Treat it?
You brought bandages?
No, but I brought this towel and
a pair of scissors. It'll be okay!
If you use the scissors and cut the towel like this...
Look! It became a long bandage!
First, you need to wrap it around the ankle twice.
Then from the bottom, you have to wrap it around to the top.
Then you pull it tight here, and repeat.
The last thing you need to do is
tie the knot, and you're done!
Wow, that's amazing!
In fact, I sprained my ankle while we were
camping before, and Conan-kun...
C-Conan-kun...
Conan-kun showed this to me.
He knows everything. He's amazing.
He's also a great leader.
I'm not even close to being like him...
How stupid.
The most important thing is that you know this
knowledge and can use it after learning it.
At this moment, you're my outstanding rescuer.
Thanks for your help.
Ah, n-no.
I'm embarrassed by the way you said it!
Anyway, it's dangerous staying here on this mountain.
We should go to the forest and think carefully,
of a way to contact Conan-kun and the others.
Yes, we should.
What did you say?
Is that true?
Yes, near the place where you said, we discovered a corpse.
It was covered with many branches and leaves.
He died due to a gunshot to the abdomen.
Ah, there was also the corpse of a cub buried nearby.
A cub?
Yeah.
The cub corpse was under a big boulder.
Anyway, this mountain is dangerous!
Leave the search of the children to us.
You lot should start heading back now!
Hey, what's going on?
W-well, you see...
A cub!
We thought they found them, but it was only two cubs!
The people in the hotel we're staying
at are helping us search!
What the, you guys scared me.
Well, let's go after them.
After sunset, it'll be difficult to search.
Hey, why didn't you tell them what really happened?
Do you think one of those hunters might be the culprit?
Not just "maybe."
Because, without a doubt, one of those three is the murderer!
What did you say?
He plans to kill Haibara and Mitsuhiko,
who witnessed his murder.
Then why are they helping us look for them?
Once both of them run out of places
to hide, the hunter will shoot them.
He'll just say he mistook them for a bear.
Have you figured out who the culprit is, Shinichi?
No, not yet.
There aren't enough clues.
But don't worry.
Those two will tell us who the culprit is.
They'll tell us in a way only we can understand.
Hey, look, look!
There are a lot of mushrooms here!
Where, where?
What is this?
There are three mushrooms on a branch!
The other four are scattered on the ground.
Shiitake is another mushroom native to East Asia.
On the branch, from top to bottom, are
Tengutake, Matsutake, and Shiitake.
Shimeiji and Hatsutake are also only native to East Asia.
On the ground are three Shimeiji and one Hatsutake.
Hey, do those mushrooms mean something?
I don't know.
Don't move!
But, will they be able to figure it out?
It's okay.
He's really interested in this stuff.
That's the secret code that we worked hard to think of.
It's useless.
It seems like we don't have to worry.
Those guys just really like to pick mushrooms.
Well, let's keep going then.
How strange...
I thought there was a meaning.
Hey, Professor, stay back.
I know who it is.
The one looking for Haibara and Mitsuhiko,
the identity of the culprit.
What did you say?
Get ready!
You're going to fall asleep now, because
of this tranquilizer dart.
What are you doing, Conan?
Ahh, you're in my way!
I was aiming at the culprit!
The culprit?
It's because the murderer is one of those three!
But, how do you know this?
Though Haibara and Mitsuhiko were dropping potato chips
everywhere, in order to show which way they went,
we never actually met up with them, and it
seems like they're still trying to run away.
And also, that hunter's corpse the police
found near the cub's corpse...
Cub's corpse...?
What's Conan-kun doing?
Stun-gun wrist watch.
It seems he has already figured
out our secret mushroom code.
It looks like it, doesn't it?
All right, after he hits the culprit, we should take
this cub and meet up with the Professor.
Yes.
What?
Wh...
Why...?
Hey!
Well, why don't we stop playing tag, Mr. Murderer?
M-murderer?
What?
I can already tell, from the mushrooms, who the culprit is.
Those seven mushrooms represent the seven of us.
The scattered Shimeiji represent us three children.
The Hatsutake is the Professor.
And, the ones on the branch are Tengutake,
Matsutake, and Shiitake,
which represent the three hunters and the
way they carry their guns on their backs.
I see, I get it!
Out of the mushrooms on the branch, only
the Tengutake is a poisonous mushroom!
That means the culprit is the person who
wears his gun on his right shoulder.
Th-that's stupid!
Wrong.
The Tengutake is a poisonous mushroom,
and anyone familiar with ths mountain would know that.
If the culprit found it before anyone else,
wouldn't he just destroy it right away?
Then, which is it?
Look, didn't I say it before?
We were looking for mushrooms,﻿
and pretended they were culprits.
Look, we found the culprit!
It's Matsutake-san!
I see.
Only we would know about that.
Yeah.
That means the culprit the code hints at...
...is you!
Yeah.
That means the culprit the code hints at is you.
Saika Matasaburou-san.
What did you say?!
The police have already found the corpse.
Although we don't have proof, the murdered
victim was probably, skinny Uncle,
your friend who came with you.
While you were committing your murder, Haibara and
Mitsuhiko came by coincidence, and found the corpse.
Saika-san fired his gun at both of them.
And, Haibara thought...
"If this goes on, he'll definitely end up killing us."
Hey, old man!
Hey!
The opposition has a gun!
H-hurry up and use your stun-gun!
He's aiming at something else...
H-hey, Shinichi!
No, this man was never going to kill Haibara and Mitsuhiko.
The real reason this man fired his gun was...
Don't come out!
H-hold on!
Wh-what is that?
Jubei!
Don't run away!
If you try to run away, the bear will
instinctively think you're the prey!
Stare at her, and slowly back away from her!
Jubei! Do you remember me?
Yes, calm your anger and return to the forest!
You need to prepare food for the winter!
Hey, if you don't hurry and go, all the hibernation
places will be taken by other bears!
Hey, Jubei, you need to go!
Jubei...
Haibara, the cub! Let the cub go!
That cub is probably Jubei's son! If he's near you, let him go!
Haibara!
Yes.
Saika-san fired his gun to save
Haibara, Mitsuhiko, and Jubei.
The murdered hunter probably wanted to kill Jubei.
And, trying to stop him, Saika-san shot the hunter.
At that time, Haibara and Mitsuhiko came.
Before Jubei noticed both of them, he fired his gun
at them, in order to make them leave the scene.
On the tree beside the place where we found Mitsuhiko's
badge there were bullet marks, probably made at that time.
Then why didn't he just shout to warn them?
I think you may have noticed earlier, but
bears are actually very intelligent.
If he had yelled at them, it would have seen them.
If he fires his gun at them, both sides would get away.
Isn't that right, Saika-san?
Hey, hey, wait.
Didn't we come here to hunt?
Is there something wrong with trying to kill a bear?
It's also the ferocious beast this
old man always talked about.
Weren't you the one that wounded that bear's eye?
Yeah.
That's right.
Jubei losing an eye was all my fault.
She exchanged one of her eyes to save my life.
E-exchanged?
That happened 20 years ago.
For the spring season bear hunt, I came up this
mountain while it was still covered in snow.
I had slipped while walking around the area, and
fell down 10 meters, breaking both of my legs.
Under the state of my injury, I couldn't even speak.
That was when she appeared in front of my eyes!
Well, I knew she was going to eat me,
so I closed my eyes waiting to die.
But instead, I felt something warm touch my cheeks.
I was panicking, but when I opened my eyes,
she was licking all of my wounds non-stop!
After she finished licking me, she slept next to me.
I thought she'd eat me when she woke up, but instead
she used her black fur to cover me from the cold.
I could tell that she was really kind-hearted.
She eventually made me forget the pain in my legs.
Then, I heard the sound of gunfire!
She had lost one of her eyes, and left my side.
The group of hunters had followed her footsteps,
and thought she was trying to eat me.
That means if it wasn't for Jubei, they would never
have found me, and I would have frozen to death.
After that, I went up the mountain everyday, found Jubei,
and made her go up the mountain
where no one would find her!
Then, could it be that the legend of Jubei you told us was...
That's right.
It's a fake story I made up so that people
would become afraid of Jubei.
But recently, it seems to have had the opposite effect.
A hunter is an animal lover.
I feel sorry for the murdered hunter.
He was hunting the bear, who was the enemy, but was
attacked by the hunter, who was supposed to be his ally.
Bears are talented animals.
I don't think that the bears are enemies.
Only if they are unlucky, they will
be seen and attacked by hunters.
I had to stop that rash hunter. That man
wanted to hurt Jubei for no reason!
What are you talking about?
It's a cheap trick.
That hunter probably used a cheap trick with the cub.
What?
It's just as the boy says.
That man wanted to kill Jubei so badly,
that he killed one of Jubei's children!
He hung the corpse on a tree!
The way that I see it,
murdering a cub just to make its mother come out,
I believe that man was actually...
the only beast that was ever here.
One hour later, we met up with the police
that were investigating on the mountain.
The old hunter was then taken away.
He looked back at Jubei's mountain, with sad, lonely eyes...
Natsu no Maboroshi
Song by Garnet Crow
HEYA NO MADO NO MUKOU NI HIKOUKI KUMO WO NAZOTTE
TRACING THE AIRPLANE CLOUDS BEYOND THE WINDOW
KYOU KENKASHITA KIMI NO KOTO BAKARI KANGAETETA
THINKING ABOUT YOU, WHO I HAD A FIGHT WITH TODAY
SASAI NA KOTA DE TO MADOTTE FUANTEI DE MUBOUBI NA
HESITATING AT THE SMALLEST THINGS, BEING UNSTABLE AND RISKY
ANO KORO NO YOU NI SUGU NI DENWASHITE
WISHING THAT I CAN CALL YOU RIGHT AWAY
WARAI AETARA II NO NI NE
AND LAUGH TOGETHER LIKE WE USED TO
CHIKA ZUITE KURU SHIFUKU NO TOKI WA
THE HAPPINESS THAT IS COMING NEAR
ITAMI WO TOMONAINAGARA ASHI OTO WO TATERU
BRINGS ALONG PAIN, AS IT MAKES NOISES, AS IT WALKS
KANGAESUGITE FUKAMI NI HAMARU
KIMI NO SOBA NI IRU NO NI
I'M NEAR YOU WHEN YOU ARE THINKING DEEPLY
Ending Theme
「Natsu no Maboroshi」
NATSU NO MABOROSHI HITOMI TOJIMETE
ICHIBAN SAISHOU NI KIMI WO OMOIDASU YO
SUMMER'S ILLUSION, CLOSING MY EYES, I THINK ABOUT YOU FIRST
DAKEDO KIMI TO IKITEYUKITAI KARA
BUT I WANT TO KEEP ON LIVING WITH YOU
TOMADOINAGARA DEMO II TSUNAIDA TE WO HANASANAIDE NE
HESITATING IS OKAY, BUT DON'T LET GO OF MY HAND
I see, the cub's grave.
That's how you knew it, right?
Yeah.
At first, I thought Saika-san was trying
to track down Jubei and get rid of her.
I never thought he would bury the
cub and make a tombstone for it.
He even knew that Jubei had given birth to cubs.
He had many chances to kill her.
But, why didn't you hurry up and tell us earlier?
If I did, then Saika-san would have
been arrested by the police,
and Jubei would definitely have been killed.
However, how did you figure out that
Ai-kun was hiding with the cub?
There were cub footprints on a lot of the
chips, so I knew they were together.
Ayumi-chan would often turn around and look behind us,
because you knew the bear was following
the cub's footprints, right?
Bears often have two cubs in one birth.
The cub found dead, and the one that was with Haibara.
My instinct told me that they were her children.
Jubei was angry because her cub was killed.
Saika-san wanted to stop Jubei from attacking Haibara
and Mitsuhiko, who were with the other cub.
That means that old man was more worried
about the bear than us humans.
Yeah, probably.
But you can't help that!
To that Uncle, Jubei was a friend for 20 years...
Oh, is that so?
When an animal lover goes this far, it's rather annoying.
Ah, b-but...
But isn't it great?
The Mother Bear was saved!
I hope they find a nice place in the forest to hibernate!
Yeah, I know!
What are you looking at?
Nothing.
Huh? Isn't that boat strange?
What?
Hey, it's capsized!
This is definitely Tachibana-san.
Huh?
Hey, Officer, wasn't Tachibana-san wearing a life jacket?
That's right, I remember he was wearing one this morning.
Really?
Then, why isn't he wearing one?
The Bay of Revenge
(Part One)
Next Conan...
The Bay of Revenge...
Part One!
Next Conan's Hint...
Tide.