A courageous heart and deduction power!
The rhythm that leads us to the truth!
The Matsutake is an expensive, delicious, and very rare mushroom found in Asia.
The Matsutake picking Detective Boys.
Be careful of the bad hunter!
Recognizing that one truth,
A child with the mind of an adult,
His name is Detective Conan!
Mushrooms, Bears, and the Detective Boys
(Part One)
Mushrooms, Bears, and the Detective Boys...
Part One!
Is everyone ready?
Although we're here to pick Matsutake mushrooms,
don't go wild picking them.
There's a limit of three per adult and two per child.
When you're done, the hotel will cook them for you.
Yes!
Ah, also, pay attention to the metal fences
because past them is hunting area.
Don't go there!
Hunting area?
There are bears there.
B-Bears?!
But it's okay.
Over on this side, there aren't any, so you can relax.
Hey, hey, what kind of place are we
picking Matsutake mushrooms?
Geez!
That guy at the hotel said that we'd find a lot here!
There aren't any here! Damn it!
Hey, hey.
But Genta-kun, weren't you the one that
wanted to pick Matsutake mushrooms?
I really wanted to go pick apples.
It's because Matsutake mushrooms are the kings of fall food.
And they're also much more rare and expensive than apples!
Oh?
Apples are the fruits that Adam and Eve ate,
and were banished by God from the Garden
of Eden because of this prohibited food,
which can analyze good and evil.
Isn't it more mysterious than the Matsutake mushroom?
Since it analyzes good and evil, Genta-kun
needs to eat a lot more of these!
Shut up!
It's the old testament, right?
Well, the fruit is an apple only because of popular belief.
What's wrong, Mitsuhiko?
What's with the weird look?
I'm not making a weird face!
I was just looking at her.
By her, do you mean Haibara?
Yes.
Haibara-san's words are harsh,
but she's really pleasant, smart, and mature.
Don't you think she's mysterious?
B-But, just because, it's not like...
Well, Mitsuhiko,
I won't say anything mean, but don't choose her.
She'll be too difficult to deal with.
Hey, come here, come here!
This is a Matsutake mushroom, isn't it?
This mushroom is only found in Asia.
That's a Tengutake, a poisonous mushroom.
Ah, I can't do this anymore!
There aren't any hints and the Matsutake
mushrooms are too hard to find!
There are hints.
Just look at the surroundings!
The needles on the pine trees have
become a yellow-green, right?
Matsutake mushrooms grow near the roots of
red pine trees to get nutrition from them.
This means the trees will decay and
the needles will change color.
Also, for the Matsutake to grow well, there
has to be good soil, water, and wind.
Given that information, if we look carefully here...
Look, we found the culprit!
Where? Where? Where is it?
This is one big Matsutake!
Delicious...
We finally got our first one!
Everyone, look over here!
There are lots of red pine trees with yellow-green needles!
Really?
All right! I'm going to find some, too!
Needles are a yellow-green color, under the red pine tree...
I've found the culprit, Matsutake-san, see?
Hey, I've found one too!
It looks like Matsutake picking can
be as interesting as a treasure hunt.
I know!
Hey, where did Genta go?
Come to think of it, I haven't seen him for a while.
He's probably going to the bathroom somewhere.
Genta-kun was chugging down a lot of mineral water earlier.
It's not good to get lost somewhere in the forest.
Anyway, let's go back to places we've been already.
Yes.
Genta-kun climbed over the first fence?
R-Really?
Yeah.
There's no mistake.
The mud marks on the fence are new, and
the spacing in between them is narrow.
It's proof that a child climbed over.
Plus, I can see many red pine trees with yellow-green
needles just past this first fence.
But, it's too bad.
Genta-kun's detective badge is being repaired right
now, so we can't use your tracking glasses.
Then we have no choice but to look for him.
You guys stay here and I'll...
You're taking the action all for yourself again!
We're going to look for him too! We're worried!
B-B-But, on the other side there's...
In that case, why don't we do this?
Tsuburaya-kun and I will pair up.
You and Yoshida-san pair up, and we'll search separately.
Just in case, if Kojima-kun comes back on his own,
the Professor will be here.
Well?
Isn't this better than you going by yourself?
Y-You have a point, but...
But, be careful, Haibara.
Over two fences, it's hunting area.
Humans have often been mistaken to be wild
animals, and are sometimes shot by hunters.
It isn't rare in Japan.
Oh?
Thank you for worrying about me.
You know what?
Anyway, come back here in one hour.
If you guys can't find him, we'll ask the
hotel staff to help us search for him.
Begin!
Yeah!
Why are you just standing there?
We need to start climbing too.
Yes!
Hey, Genta!
Genta-kun, answer us!
Crap, where could that guy have gone?
Genta!
Genta-kun, where are you?
Umm... Can I ask you a question?
What's the relationship between you and Conan-kun?
What do you mean?
I mean, you two often go to a corner,
and talk about things ordinary children don't understand.
It seems you only understand each other...
Like you two are in your own world...
Don't worry about it.
It's not as romantic as you think.
But...
Well, anyway, let's keep moving.
Wait...
What was that sound just now?
It came from the other side of the second fence.
The fence is broken...
Maybe he went through here to the other side.
There's no way, the other side is the hunting area.
If you were to get lost after passing through the first fence,
you wouldn't be able to tell the difference between
the Matsutake picking area and the hunting area.
Wait, hold on a second!
Genta-kun, is that you? Well, we were worried about you!
A b-b-b-bear!
It's okay.
It's only a cub.
Looks like he isn't even a year old.
Cute, isn't he?
Y-You're right.
But be careful. Its mother may be nearby.
Gunfire?!
Could a hunter have shot this cub's mother!?
Ah, don't!
Don't go over there!
Look, it's the hunter!
Could it be that he thinks we're animals?
Hey!
We're humans!
Th-This is...!
This wound...
A gun wound...
Could it be?
Hey!
Don't shoot us!
We're human!
Hey!
Don't you understand?
That hunter is trying to shoot us!
He wants to silence us because he thinks
we saw him murder someone!
Where have you been, Genta!
We were all worried about you!
I'm sorry...
I wanted to get Matsutake for everyone,
and I just kept going farther...
Well, well, at least he returned safely.
Hey, have you contacted Haibara and Mitsuhiko?
You see, I already called them a while back, but...
Geez, now those guys are lost?
Hey, hey, hey.
Mitsuhiko's badge is located in the hunting area.
That's strange.
They should have known not to go there.
Geez.
Let's find them as fast as we can before
it gets dark and return to the hotel!
Yeah!
Hey, hey, it's impossible for me to get through here!
Come on, try harder!
What are you doing?
Yasaka Kiyoshi (41)
Hunter
At a place like this with children.
Two children accidentally wandered in here.
We're looking for them.
Uncle, have you seen a boy and girl around here?
No.
Hey, I found it! Mitsuhiko's detective badge!
Really?!
But, neither of them are here.
Blood?!
Hey! This is a pretty big footprint!
It looks like a bear.
Then they were both eaten by a bear?
I don't think so.
In reality, bears are afraid of people,
and don't think of them as food.
If it's that one, though, the situation is different.
Saika Matasaburou (67)
Hunter
It has a grudge against all humans.
Both of them could have become
another meal before hibernation!
That is the single-eyed giant bear, by the name of Jubei!
N-No way...
I see.
The rumor of that bear is actually true then?
The long trip here was worth it after all.
Don't worry, little girl.
I'll deal with that thing and get revenge for your friends.
Negoru Tomoya (28)
Hunter
What revenge?
We don't even know if they have been attacked for sure!
Anyway, let's help them find the children.
Yeah, we know this area better than they do.
Sorry, little girl.
Hey, Mitsuhiko!
Haibara-san!
It's Conan-kun and the others!
Look, on that side of the forest.
Hey!
Wait.
They're with that hunter we met.
Why are they with him?
He's trying to find us, the witnesses of the murder.
If we go out like this, we will definitely die.
He'll say he mistook us for a bear.
Hey, Haibara!
Where are you, Mitsuhiko?
If you're there, answer!
It's another potato chip!
It's probably something that both of them dropped.
They must have left it here to tell
us which direction they went.
Hey, why don't we just use Conan's glasses
to locate where Haibara's badge is?
No, her badge is on the desk at my house.
I only fixed your badge because I was
testing some different functions out.
I was working on it last night.
No way...
Hey, Professor.
Do you remember the place where we
found Mitsuhiko's badge earlier?
Yeah, by the metal fence with the hole in it.
Then call the people in the hotel, explain the situation
to them, and tell them to call the police.
Police?!
They left traces that they were here, but even after
looking for so long we still can't find them.
Don't you think it's weird?
But aren't they just running from the bear?
No, there was blood near the place where
we found Mitsuhiko's badge.
And there was a new bullet mark
on the tree next to the blood.
Perhaps they aren't actually running from a bear...
Hey, could it be...?
Mitsuhiko-kun and Haibara-san?
Hey! Stop it!
It ran away.
Rabbit-san...?
Did you even think about it?
What if that was one of the children?
My eyes can tell the difference
between an animal and a child.
Even if the legendary Jubei appears,
you don't need to worry.
I'll do a clean shot and get him...
To him this is just like a toy gun.
What?
If you want to keep your life when
you meet Jubei, don't move!
That thing can smell humans from far away,
and will attack anyone without hesitation!
A monster that is 2 meters tall!
I'm the only one that can kill it.
20 years ago, I was the person that shot its eye!
Who is that old man?
He's a famous hunter around here.
I hear he came from the Southeast and
led a mountain running group here.
But after he met Jubei in this mountain,
he decided that he wanted to stay here.
Mountain running group?
He was the boss of a hunting group.
So we can relax if a bear comes out!
Anyway, Professor, make the call.
Ye-Yeah.
As I expected, if that hunter sees
us, he'll kill us immediately.
B-But, if we shout really loudly, wait until we're
near them and step out in front of them...
Little Yoshida-san is over there with them.
He can take her hostage and kill all the others.
That person has already murdered one man.
N-No way...
From the way he fired his gun at us,
I think he came up to this mountain with that other
hunter as an excuse to commit his murder.
But don't you need a license to go hunting?
If the body was found in the mountains, wouldn't
they suspect the hunters and their companions?
No, when a license is approved, it stays
approved for a very long time.
Once they get a license, they can
go hunting wherever they want.
In other words, there are no restrictions
as to who comes here.
If the person you kill has a license,
then you will have an alibi.
If the corpse is found, you could
also say another hunter did it.
Then, he saw us when we were at the scene of the crime...
Yes. Now his whole plan is ruined.
He probably wants to kill us now as well.
In that case, instead of leaving these chips so they will
find us, both of us should get out of this forest.
We can't.
Taking action in an unfamiliar forest is very dangerous.
Either way, we can only leave this mountain
once we meet up with the Professor.
But it's okay.
I left the detective badge right by the corpse.
Edogawa-kun will definitely notice it.
Right, I'm sure of it.
Well, why don't we talk about it while we're walking?
Now we need to figure out some way to contact them all.
Also, there's this cub...
who's been following us for some reason.
It would be bad if the hunters meet this cub.
Yes.
This was done by a giant bear.
Using its claws to take off the outside layer,
and then eating the whole inside.
The distance of the marks is wide, and the position is high.
It was something very big.
It was Jubei.
I believe she gave birth to a cub this winter, so
they should be happily together somewhere.
Gave birth?
Isn't Jubei a male?
Don't you know?
The legend states that the mountain god was
always jealous of the mountain goddess.
People tried to avoid the jealousy of
the mountain god while hunting.
So her name was changed to a male name.
Yagyuu Jubei is a famous samurai from the Feudal Era.
It was changed to be like the swordsman, Yagyuu Jubei.
A female bear that's over two meters tall?
That makes me even more eager to see it.
No matter what happens.
Is there something on my face, old man?
Ah, no.
You just said the exact same thing as my friend did.
Hey, did that friend of yours happen
to come with you today?
Because earlier, when you took your camera
out of your pocket, I saw pellets there.
Those were the kind that fire 9 bullets at once, right?
But earlier you only fired one bullet.
I heard that hunters usually don't carry
two different types of bullets.
My friend forgot to take spare bullets
with him to this mountain.
I thought if I met him on the mountain,
I'd pass them on to him.
But will he be okay?
Your friend is still alone on this mountain somewhere, right?
It'll be okay.
He's been up this mountain many times before.
We always split up when we come here to hunt.
Is everything all right, Ayumi-chan?
Yeah, it's nothing!
Hey, we're going!
Yeah.
Hey, Ayumi!
Wait!
TODO: PREVIEW, JOKES