A sound mind gives rise to correct conclusions.
A calm tempo brings swifter truth.
Haibara and Mitsuhiko are in mortal danger!
Will you solve the "mushroom" message?
I see one single truth.
I look like a child, but I have the mind of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
We Detective Boys decided to go mushroom
picking in the mountains.
And during it, Genta got lost in the hunting area.
We split into two groups to search for Genta.
And Haibara and Mitsuhiko...
...discovered a dead body, and have become
targets for the dangerous hunter.
We found Genta, and three hunters decided
to help us look for Haibara and Mitsuhiko.
Mushrooms, Bears, and the Detective Boys
(Part Two)
Mushrooms, Bears, and the Detective Boys...
Part Two!
This is our last chip.
We have none left, Haibara-san.
Haibara-san!
What happened?
While we were trying to escape, I twisted my ankle.
I was holding it in earlier.
Please let me see it.
S-Sorry...
Wait, your foot is swelling and its purple!
Anyway, I'll help you treat it now.
Bear with it a bit longer.
Treat it?
You brought bandages?
No, but I brought this towel and
a pair of scissors. It'll be okay!
If you use the scissors and cut the towel like this...
Look! It became a long bandage!
First, you need to wrap it around the ankle twice.
Then from the bottom, you have to wrap it around to the top.
Then you pull it tight here, and repeat.
The last thing you need to do is
tie the knot, and you're done!
Wow, that's amazing!
In fact, I sprained my ankle while we were
camping before, and Conan-kun...
C-Conan-kun...
Conan-kun showed this to me.
He knows everything. He's amazing.
He's also a great leader.
I'm not even close to being like him...
How stupid.
The most important thing is that you know this
knowledge and can use it after learning it.
At this moment, you're my outstanding rescuer.
Thanks for your help.
Ah, n-no.
I'm embarrassed by the way you said it!
Anyway, it's dangerous staying here on this mountain.
We should go to the forest and think carefully,
of a way to contact Conan-kun and the others.
Yes, we should.
What did you say?
Is that true?
Yes, near the place where you said, we discovered a corpse.
It was covered with many branches and leaves.
He died due to a gunshot to the abdomen.
Ah, there was also the corpse of a cub buried nearby.
A cub?
Yeah.
The cub corpse was under a big boulder.
Anyway, this mountain is dangerous!
Leave the search of the children to us.
You lot should start heading back now!
Hey, what's going on?
W-Well, you see...
A cub!
We thought they found them, but it was only two cubs!
The people in the hotel we're staying
at are helping us search!
What the, you guys scared me.
Well, let's go after them.
After sunset, it'll be difficult to search.
Hey, why didn't you tell them what really happened?
Do you think one of those hunters might be the culprit?
Not just "maybe."
Because, without a doubt, one of those three is the murderer!
What did you say?
He plans to kill Haibara and Mitsuhiko,
who witnessed his murder.
Then why are they helping us look for them?
Once both of them run out of places
to hide, the hunter will shoot them.
He'll just say he mistook them for a bear.
Have you figured out who the culprit is, Shinichi?
No, not yet.
There aren't enough clues.
But don't worry.
Those two will tell us who the culprit is.
They'll tell us in a way only we can understand.
Hey, look, look!
There are a lot of mushrooms here!
Where, where?
What is this?
There are three mushrooms on a branch!
The other four are scattered on the ground.
Shiitake is another mushroom native to East Asia.
On the branch, from top to bottom, are
Tengutake, Matsutake, and Shiitake.
Shimeiji and Hatsutake are also only native to East Asia.
On the ground are three Shimeiji and one Hatsutake.
Hey, do those mushrooms mean something?
I don't know.
Don't move!
But, will they be able to figure it out?
It's okay.
He's really interested in this stuff.
That's the secret code that we worked hard to think of.
It's useless.
It seems like we don't have to worry.
Those guys just really like to pick mushrooms.
Well, let's keep going then.
How strange...
I thought there was a meaning.
Hey, Professor, stay back.
I know who it is.
The one looking for Haibara and Mitsuhiko,
the identity of the culprit.
What did you say?
Get ready!
You're going to fall asleep now, because
of this tranquilizer dart.
What are you doing, Conan?
Ahh, you're in my way!
I was aiming at the culprit!
The culprit?
It's because the murderer is one of those three!
But, how do you know this?
Though Haibara and Mitsuhiko were dropping potato chips everywhere, in order to show which way they went,
we never actually met up with them, and it
seems like they're still trying to run away.
And also, that hunter's corpse the police
found near the cub's corpse...
Cub's corpse...?
What's Conan-kun doing?
Stun-gun wrist watch.
It seems he has already figured
out our secret mushroom code.
It looks like it, doesn't it?
All right, after he hits the culprit, we should take
this cub and meet up with the Professor.
Yes.
What?
Wh...
Why...?
Hey!
Well, why don't we stop playing tag, Mr. Murderer?
M-Murderer?
What?
I can already tell, from the mushrooms, who the culprit is.
Those seven mushrooms represent the seven of us.
The scattered Shimeiji represent us three children.
The Hatsutake is the Professor.
And, the ones on the branch are Tengutake,
Matsutake, and Shiitake,
which represent the three hunters and the
way they carry their guns on their backs.
I see, I get it!
Out of the mushrooms on the branch, only
the Tengutake is a poisonous mushroom!
That means the culprit is the person who
wears his gun on his right shoulder.
Th-That's stupid!
Wrong.
The Tengutake is a poisonous mushroom,
and anyone familiar with ths mountain would know that.
If the culprit found it before anyone else,
wouldn't he just destroy it right away?
Then, which is it?
Look, didn't I say it before?
We were looking for mushrooms,
and pretended they were culprits.
Look, we found the culprit!
It's Matsutake-san!
I see.
Only we would know about that.
Yeah.
That means the culprit the code hints at...
...is you!
Yeah.
That means the culprit the code hints at is you.
Saika Matasaburou-san.
What did you say?!
The police have already found the corpse.
Although we don't have proof, the murdered
victim was probably, skinny Uncle,
your friend who came with you.
While you were committing your murder, Haibara and
Mitsuhiko came by coincidence, and found the corpse.
Saika-san fired his gun at both of them.
And, Haibara thought...
"If this goes on, he'll definitely end up killing us."
Hey, old man!
Hey!
The opposition has a gun!
H-Hurry up and use your stun-gun!
He's aiming at something else...
H-Hey, Shinichi!
No, this man was never going to kill Haibara and Mitsuhiko.
The real reason this man fired his gun was...
Don't come out!
H-Hold on!
Wh-What is that?
Jubei!
Don't run away!
If you try to run away, the bear will
instinctively think you're the prey!
Stare at her, and slowly back away from her!
Jubei! Do you remember me?
Yes, calm your anger and return to the forest!
You need to prepare food for the winter!
Hey, if you don't hurry and go, all the hibernation
places will be taken by other bears!
Hey, Jubei, you need to go!
Jubei...
Haibara, the cub! Let the cub go!
That cub is probably Jubei's son! If he's near you, let him go!
Haibara!
Yes.
Saika-san fired his gun to save
Haibara, Mitsuhiko, and Jubei.
The murdered hunter probably wanted to kill Jubei.
And, trying to stop him, Saika-san shot the hunter.
At that time, Haibara and Mitsuhiko came.
Before Jubei noticed both of them, he fired his gun
at them, in order to make them leave the scene.
On the tree beside the place where we found Mitsuhiko's badge there were bullet marks, probably made at that time.
Then why didn't he just shout to warn them?
I think you may have noticed earlier, but
bears are actually very intelligent.
If he had yelled at them, it would have seen them.
If he fires his gun at them, both sides would get away.
Isn't that right, Saika-san?
Hey, hey, wait.
Didn't we come here to hunt?
Is there something wrong with trying to kill a bear?
It's also the ferocious beast this
old man always talked about.
Weren't you the one that wounded that bear's eye?
Yeah.
That's right.
Jubei losing an eye was all my fault.
She exchanged one of her eyes to save my life.
E-Exchanged?
That happened 20 years ago.
For the spring season bear hunt, I came up this
mountain while it was still covered in snow.
I had slipped while walking around the area, and
fell down 10 meters, breaking both of my legs.
Under the state of my injury, I couldn't even speak.
That was when she appeared in front of my eyes!
Well, I knew she was going to eat me,
so I closed my eyes waiting to die.
But instead, I felt something warm touch my cheeks.
I was panicking, but when I opened my eyes,
she was licking all of my wounds non-stop!
After she finished licking me, she slept next to me.
I thought she'd eat me when she woke up, but instead
she used her black fur to cover me from the cold.
I could tell that she was really kind-hearted.
She eventually made me forget the pain in my legs.
Then, I heard the sound of gunfire!
She had lost one of her eyes, and left my side.
The group of hunters had followed her footsteps,
and thought she was trying to eat me.
That means if it wasn't for Jubei, they would never
have found me, and I would have frozen to death.
After that, I went up the mountain everyday, found Jubei,
and made her go up the mountain
where no one would find her!
Then, could it be that the legend of Jubei you told us was...
That's right.
It's a fake story I made up so that people
would become afraid of Jubei.
But recently, it seems to have had the opposite effect.
A hunter is an animal lover.
I feel sorry for the murdered hunter.
He was hunting the bear, who was the enemy, but was
attacked by the hunter, who was supposed to be his ally.
Bears are talented animals.
I don't think that the bears are enemies.
Only if they are unlucky, they will
be seen and attacked by hunters.
I had to stop that rash hunter. That man
wanted to hurt Jubei for no reason!
What are you talking about?
It's a cheap trick.
That hunter probably used a cheap trick with the cub.
What?
It's just as the boy says.
That man wanted to kill Jubei so badly,
that he killed one of Jubei's children!
He hung the corpse on a tree!
The way that I see it,
murdering a cub just to make its mother come out,
I believe that man was actually...
the only beast that was ever here.
One hour later, we met up with the police
that were investigating on the mountain.
The old hunter was then taken away.
He looked back at Jubei's mountain, with sad, lonely eyes...
I see, the cub's grave.
That's how you knew it, right?
Yeah.
At first, I thought Saika-san was trying
to track down Jubei and get rid of her.
I never thought he would bury the
cub and make a tombstone for it.
He even knew that Jubei had given birth to cubs.
He had many chances to kill her.
But, why didn't you hurry up and tell us earlier?
If I did, then Saika-san would have
been arrested by the police,
and Jubei would definitely have been killed.
However, how did you figure out that
Ai-kun was hiding with the cub?
There were cub footprints on a lot of the
chips, so I knew they were together.
Ayumi-chan would often turn around and look behind us,
because you knew the bear was following
the cub's footprints, right?
Bears often have two cubs in one birth.
The cub found dead, and the one that was with Haibara.
My instinct told me that they were her children.
Jubei was angry because her cub was killed.
Saika-san wanted to stop Jubei from attacking Haibara
and Mitsuhiko, who were with the other cub.
That means that old man was more worried
about the bear than us humans.
Yeah, probably.
But you can't help that!
To that Uncle, Jubei was a friend for 20 years...
Oh, is that so?
When an animal lover goes this far, it's rather annoying.
Ah, b-but...
But isn't it great?
The Mother Bear was saved!
I hope they find a nice place in the forest to hibernate!
Yeah, I know!
What are you looking at?
Nothing.
TODO: PREVIEW
The Mysterious Retro Room Case
Next Conan...
Next Conan's Hint...
Mace spray
TODO: JOKES