Song by Rina Aiuchi
Koi wa thrill, shock, suspense
Koi wa Thrill, Shock, Suspense,
Love is a thrill, shock, suspense,
Mienai chikara tayori ni
relying on an invisible strength.
Kokoro no tobira tozasazu ni tsuyoku... tsuyoku...
Leaving the door to the heart open, stronger... stronger...
With a strong heart and mind,
Today's case is about a room full of mysteries!
Seeing the one and only truth...
A kid with the intellect of an adult...
His name is... Detective Conan!
Watashi ga kanjiteita
I thought,
Toge okimi ni no onaji
this disorder I've been feeling in my heart.
You ni ataeteita no kano shirenakatta
Perhaps you felt the same way?
Nani ni kokoro o itamete nani ni obieteita no ka
Without knowing what hurt, what did I fear with my heart?
Ki ni ino tomezu motsureteku futari no shinjitsu ni
The confrontation of our tangling truth
Mukiau no ga kowakatta
We feared to face
Mayoi o aoi kaze ni chirasou toshite
Even when I tried to toss my confusion to the wind.
Mo kakaekirezu ni ita yo kono chisana mune ni wa
I could not hold all of it in this tiny chest.
Kokoro no tobira tozasazu ni
Leaving the door to the heart open.
Tsugi e to susumu arata na fuan to
Even if you may have to hold the new uncertainties and confusion.
Mayoi o kakaeteshimaisou ni natte mo
That will follow you to the next place.
The Mysterious Retro Room Case
Touto Line
Dad.
Your ticket.
Thanks.
Please, you have to come with us to Dolphinland!
I don't like aquatic shows.
Every man dreams to watch...
...horse racing! After I win, I'll buy a special dinner tonight!
I hope you don't blow all our money there...
Easy, easy.
Ok, see you later.
Hey, what does Naomi want?
She says we should hurry up.
Oh, such beautiful ladies!
By chance, are you Mouri Kogoro-san?
Are you talking about the famous detective?
Yes, that's me!
I can't believe it! I'm your biggest fan!
Kaori, you are so embarrassing.
No, no, she's fine.
We are going to Dolphinland's hotel. Where are you going, Mouri-san?
What a coincidence! I'm going to Dolphinland too!
Weren't you going to the horse races?
Would you like to join us?
Of course!
Alright, let's go!
But we're still waiting for someone...
Kuniko!
Kaori!
I'm sorry! I hope you haven't waited long.
Wow, another hottie!
We still have plenty of time, right?
No, you are late...
We were going to take the 1:20 PM train; we still have ten minutes...
Umm, who's this guy?
This is the famous detective Mouri Kogoro-san.
We just ran into him.
Oh, I see!
We all went to the same university.
Yamamoto Kuniko (27)
Clothing Designer
We had a get-together last week,
but one of our group members was working abroad and couldn't make it.
She arrived yesterday, so the four of us decided to go out for some drinks.
Oobayashi Kaori (27)
Travel Agent
So another beauty is missing?
Indeed. She was the most popular, a true queen.
A queen!? Where is she?
Kaneda Kanami (27)
Housewife
She's already at Dolphinland's hotel.
She's a well-known children's clothing designer.
So we have a designer, a travel agent, and a housewife...
three beautiful and talented ladies!
It's no big deal!
Yeah, I think he's right about you, Kuniko...
What?
It's true. After all, aren't you opening your own clothing boutique soon?
More... or less...
Wow, that's great!
And I'm only a housewife...
But you're a happily married woman!
Yeah, yeah! You look so happy and chubby!
Come on, you know I don't want to be chubby.
Attention! The train to Dolphinland is now arriving.
Here it comes.
Let's go look for this fourth beauty!
The express-train will have us there in no time!
Theme Park Dolphinland
That's the Dolphinland hotel over there.
They just finished remodeling it last month.
Oh, it's done in a retro style.
Yes, it's called the Retro Room.
The Retro Room?
[Note: ryokan is a Japanese-style inn]
Yes, the hotel was originally a famous, traditional
ryokan called Dolphin-Ryokan.
So let's go find Naomi's room.
Sure, sure!
Kuniko, what is Naomi's room number?
Room 503.
Room 503?
Ah, here it is!
We arrived at exactly 2 PM.
Look at this...
Don't tell me Naomi is still sleeping when we're ready to go out.
I cannot believe it.
Naomi? Naomi!
What will we do now?
Oh, the door is unlocked.
Let's go in and see if she is here.
Naomi?
We're coming in!
Dad, you can't go in there. You don't know her.
OK...
What is this?
What happened?
Na-Naomi!
What...
Please, stay calm and don't touch anything.
I said, "Don't touch anything!"
It turned off automatically.
This TV seems to be on a coin-operated timer.
Uhum... Ran, call the police.
OK.
So the body was found by you all,
and, of course, someone else was here by chance...
Mouri-kun, I'll need to talk to you later.
Uh, yeah...
Very well, I will need to question you all
as well. Please wait here for a moment.
Great! I'll be their body guard!
No, I don't think so...
Hey, Chiba-kun!
Yes?
Take charge of these women.
As you wish, sir.
Please come with me.
Hey, Mouri-kun!
Uhh... yes?
What have you found, Takagi-kun?
Oh, Inspector.
Fujimura Naomi (27)
Children's Clothing Designer
The victim was Fujimura Naomi, 27 years old.
She was a children's clothing designer working overseas.
Inspector, I found this in one of the victim's pockets. It's pepper spray.
Huh? Pepper spray?
Maybe she used to carry it because she lived overseas...
There're a lot of sexual predators in America.
Nonsense...
This place is full of old-style furnishings.
That's because it's called the Retro Room, Inspector.
It's a replica of the old ryokan's guest rooms.
That's why this TV is coin-operated.
[Note: 100 Yen is about $1 USD.]
You can watch one hour for 100 yen.
Are you sure the TV turned off when you came into the room?
Yeah, it was 2 PM.
It says here you can only insert one coin at a time.
Instructions
In other words, the TV came on an hour earlier.
What's the time of death?
Between noon and 1 PM.
She was attacked right after turning the TV on.
Hey, this candy is so weird, isn't it?
I have never seen candies like these!
Stop messing around!
So many different old candies... I remember them from when I was a kid.
The hotel usually leaves them in the room as complimentary snacks.
Maybe the killer and the victim were fighting and scattered them around.
There is even ice cream. Too bad it's already melted...
Ice cream?
So, this means she was attacked after turning the
TV on, but before she ate her ice cream, right?
Yeah... What types of ice cream bars are in the fridge?
Yes.
Inspector, these are the ice cream bars inside the fridge.
They all look good to me!
It seems like your hypothesis was right, Mouri-kun.
I know.
No, this ice cream is different.
The victim bought it... or maybe...
Hmm, what's this? Condensation?
Look over here! It's damp on the table!
Damp? Somebody probably just spilled something there.
So, you delivered the dry cleaning to the room before 1 PM, is this correct?
Yes, but I didn't enter because of the "Do Not Disturb"
sign. I just left it hanging on the doorknob.
Did you notice if the door was locked?
Quit being a pest!
No, that's a good question. Did you notice if it was?
I don't know, I didn't try the door.
Inspector! We just found the victim's cellphone under the table!
Very good. Can you find her last call?
Yes.
What? Check this out, Inspector.
November 19th - 1:08 PM
Yamamoto Kuniko
Yamamoto Kuniko. She's one of the ladies who discovered the body.
Look at that, the victim called her at 1:08 PM, right before the murder!
That's when we met Yamamoto-san at the train station.
Really?
Yes, Naomi called saying we should hurry up.
It was 1:08 PM.
November 19th - 1:08 PM
Fujimura Naomi
I see... Where were you at that moment?
In the station, waiting for the train.
We got together at 1 PM. Kanami joined us about 10 minutes later.
We got on the 1:20 PM train and arrived at the hotel around 1:50 PM.
We were outside of Naomi's room at 2 PM.
In other words, these girls have a perfect alibi!
One more thing. Could you please describe the
room when you discovered your friend's body?
Sure.
This is a very well thought-out murder.
If my deduction is right, she is the killer, but I don't have any proof yet...
What was that? Something plastic in her pocket?
I see. The culprit still has the evidence on her. This means she did it!
Thank you very much for your cooperation. You can leave now.
Inspector, I will leave with them...
Dad!
On second thought, I don't think we can leave just yet.
Inspector, this is clearly a premeditated murder.
What?
What do you mean?
I believe the criminal is among us. It's one of these ladies.
What?
I don't believe this.
How can you say the criminal is one of us?
This guy lacks tact sometimes...
First, the pepper spray found in Fujimura-san's pocket had
not been used. This means she knew her attacker.
Second, the room key was on the table...
If it was a burglar, why not lock the door on the way
out? This would delay discovery of the victim.
That's true...
However, if you recall, all of these ladies have
a perfect alibi — they were with you at 1 PM.
Yes, that's true, although the actual time of
death was around 12:20 PM, not 1 PM.
But the TV was on. This means a coin was inserted after 1 PM.
Nobody needs to be here to insert a coin,
they could just use all those candies.
Candies?
OK, explain the trick...
Of course, right now. Conan!
Hai!
Using the ice cream bar and the candy with a string!
Eh? Are you sure?
Here's how it works:
First, you drape the string candy over the coin slot like this.
Next, place the ice cream bar between the
TV controls and the furniture as a bridge.
Finally, put the other end of the string under the ice cream bar.
Do you have a coin, Ran-neechan?
Eh? Hmm...
Here.
Put it into the coin slot.
OK...
Oh, the coin stays there!
After setting this up, the killer left the room.
Over time the ice cream bar melts and falls away, allowing
the thread to slip to the floor and the coin to slip in...
to turn on the TV!
Alright, I get it.
That's why there was candy near the TV — to hide the trick!
Indeed...
Remember the channel knob and table were
damp? It was from the ice cream bar.
Besides, this ice cream bar was a fairly new flavor.
It wouldn't be included with this room's selection.
Naomi could have bought it anytime!
I'm sorry, but the killer did not lock the room just so this trick would work.
What do you mean?
If the killer had locked the door, her friends would not have been
able to open the door and watch the TV turn off automatically.
I see... the trick is meaningless if nobody is here to see it!
What about the sign on the door?
The culprit hung out the sign because the room had to be unlocked...
but nobody was supposed to get in early, or the plan would fail.
Wait a minute! Naomi called me at 1:08 PM!
She's right! If Naomi was killed forty minutes earlier,
she couldn't have made that call, right?
They have a point, Mouri-kun.
The time of their incoming and outgoing calls matches.
There's an easy explanation: the killer used the victim's cellphone.
What are you saying?
But Kuniko was talking with Naomi when—
Impossible!
Exactly. It was impossible for her to talk to Fujimura-san.
That means the killer...
Yamamoto Kuniko-san!
is you!
Kuniko...
No!
After committing the murder, you took Fujimura-san's cellphone...
and went to the station to meet Oobayashi-san and Kaneda-san.
Then, using the cellphone in your pocket, you called your
own phone and pretended to talk with Fujimura-san.
The only thing you had to do was return the phone...
...during the commotion after the body was discovered.
Do you have any proof of all this?
Sure. You still have it with you. Right?
The plastic bag in your pocket.
I don't understand what you mean...
You put Fujimura-san's cellphone in that bag and took it away.
Is this true? Check her.
Yes.
Let me check your pocket, please.
Hey!
Here it is.
Now hold it up to the light and tell us what you see.
Yes.
Several fingerprints are visible...
...and there is a weird vertical pattern.
Yamamoto-san, I must tell you that when I saw your cellphone...
...I noticed something very interesting.
02058252805
To call your number, only the center buttons are necessary.
Hence the vertical pattern as you dialed through the plastic bag.
How do you explain that?
Hey, Chiba! Bring the victim's cellphone!
Yes!
Of course the plastic bag has my fingerprints; it was in my pocket.
Here's the victim's phone.
OK.
It matches perfectly!
I could not forgive Naomi...
Kuniko...
Why, Kuniko?
After graduation we both sought the recommendation for a job in America.
It was with a well-known company, and Naomi, who was
already good, became a successful designer with them.
I was supposed to have been chosen, but Naomi
used her feminine charms on the professor!
I didn't know a thing about it until the professor let
it slip one time when we were having drinks...
But I thought you were opening your own clothing boutique!
I exaggerated a little. The truth is I was fired from my job.
Just because I had a little too much to drink once!
Fired?
Damn her! I was so angry with her. I felt so humiliated by Naomi!
Because she took away my happiness!
That's why...
That's why!
Heya no mado no mukou ni hikouki kumo o nazotte
Beyond the windows I see a trace of clouds made by an airplane.
Kyou kenkashita kimi no koto bakari kangaeteta
And realize I can only think about the fight we had today.
Sasai na koto de to madotte fuantei de uboubi na
I hesitate with every small thing, and I'm unreliable and hopeless.
Ano koro no you ni sugu ni denwashite, Warai aetara ii no ni ne
Wishing to be able to be like I used to, and call you right away, laughing.
Chika zuite kuru shifuku no toki wa itami o tomonainagara ashi oto tateru
I can hear the steps of happiness coming closer, bringing pain along with it.
Kangaesugite fukami ni hamaru kimi no soba ni iru no ni
You are so focused in deep thoughts you don't realize I'm right beside you.
Natsu no maboroshi hitomi tojimete ichiban saishou ni kimi o omoidasu yo
Summer illusions I see, closing my eyes the first one I remember is you,
Dakedo kimi to ikiteyukitai kara
and it's because I want to live with you by my side.
Tomadoinagara demo ii tsunaida te o hanasanaide ne
I don't mind if you hesitate, just never let go of my hand.
What a great show!
For sure, and we got the best seats!
I suppose we are really lucky.
There are only brats here...
OK, the dolphins will now toss the balls to the audience!
Get ready to catch them!
Good job! Even they know you, Uncle!