Koi wa thrill, shock, suspense
Song by Rina Aiuchi
KOI WA THRILL, SHOCK, SUSPENSE
LOVE IS A THRILL, SHOCK, SUSPENSE
MIENAI CHIKARA TAYORI NI
RELYING ON UNSEEN FORCES...
KOKORO NO TOBIRA TOZASAZU NI TSUYOKU... TSUYOKU...
POWERFULLY WITHOUT LOCKING UP THE HEART'S DOOR... POWERFULLY...
A courageous heart and deduction power!
The rhythm that leads us to the truth!
Today is full of suspense!
Two incidents at a farway place!
Recognizing that one truth, a child with the mind of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
WATASHI GA KANJITEITA
MAYBE I WAS GIVING YOU PAIN
TOGE OKIMI NI NO ONAJI
YOU NI ATAETEITA NO KANO SHIRENAKATTA
SIMILAR TO WHAT I'VE FELT, AND WITHOUT THINKING
NANI NI KOKORO WO ITAMETE NANI NI OBIETEITA NO KA
KI NI INO TOMEZU MOTSURETEKU FUTARI NO SHINJITSU NI
ABOUT WHAT GAVE ME PAIN, WHAT I FEARED
Opening Theme
「Koi wa thrill, shock, suspense」
MUKIAU NO GA KOWAKATTA
I FEARED FACING THE COMPLICATED TRUTH
THIS LOVE IS A THRILL, SHOCK, SUSPENSE
THIS LOVE IS THRILL, SHOCK, SUSPENSE
MAYOI WO AOI KAZE NI CHIRASOU TOSHITE MO KAKAEKIREZU NI ITA YO
EVEN IF I TRY TO SCATTER DOUBT IN THE BLUE WINDS
KONO CHISANA MUNE NI WA
I WAS UNABLE TO CARRY THE BURDEN WITH THIS SMALL CHEST
KOKORO NO TOBIRA TOZASAZU NI
WITHOUT LOCKING UP THE HEART'S DOOR
TSUGI E TO SUSUMU ARATA NA FUAN TO
EVEN IF I MUST CARRY MORE ANXIETY AND DOUBT
MAYOI WO KAKAETESHIMAISOU NI NATTE MO
AS I CONTINUE ON
The Bay of Revenge
(Part 1)
What a nice sunset.
I can forget all of today's troubles.
Really!
This almost makes me forget that we rented
a cheap car, and that we're stuck here.
Right, Conan?
What's wrong?
This is my villa's entrance.
Private Property
No Trespassing
It's not a parking lot.
Or is there something I can do for you?
Oh, sorry! While we were on a family trip, our car broke down.
I'm not here to start trouble. I'm Kogoro Mouri.
Oh!
That famous detective, Mouri-san!
Oh, you know me. Indeed, I am Mouri.
Please forgive me.
Lawyer
Tachibana Kensuke (62)
I am a lawyer in Tokyo. My name is Kensuke Tachibana.
Oh!
The one who is always involved in famous cases! The Tachibana-san!
If I remember correctly, he was the lawyer
who would do anything for money.
But it's annoying since there are so many dangerous
cases. Someone is usually after my life.
Ah, this is my secretary, Sakuraba.
Secretary
Sakuraba Yuuichi (29)
I'm Yuuichi Sakuraba.
It is an honor to meet you.
Please look up the phone number of an
auto repair shop and give it to them.
Yes.
Regardless, please stop by the villa. It's
a rare opportunity to hear your stories.
Thank you very much.
Yohan, these are our guests.
How cute!
Yohan
Good boy. Your name is Yohan?
What unique fur! What kind of dog is it?
Actually, I do not know.
This stray dog was found by the caretaker.
He's a watchdog.
Really? That's good, isn't it, Yohan?
Wow!
This accident sure did turn around, huh?
Expensive fish cuisine! And so much of it!
It tastes like heaven.
It's fresh fish.
And Yaeko-san is a really good chef.
Caretaker
Kamei Yaeko (50)
I'm embarrassed that this is peasant food.
Yaeko-san?
Yes?
I'd like some red wine and some risotto to go with it.
Yes, I'll prepare it immediately.
Welcome everyone. I am Tachibana's wife, Yuki.
Tachibana Yuki (43)
Tachibana's Wife
I thought you were sleeping.
I heard Mouri-sama was here, so I regained my appetite.
Would anyone else like wine?
No.
We're drinking sake.
This is hot Japanese white wine!
Corny...
Who could that be?
It's Sugimura-san.
Yes, come in.
Good evening.
What brings you here so late?
I have to talk to Sensei.
Sensei.
We received another letter today at the office.
I thought something happened, so I had to bring this here.
Mouri-san, this is the office's accountant.
I'm Sugimura. By Mouri-san, do you mean...?
Tachibana Law Office Accountant
Sugimura Noriko (48)
That's right. The famous detective, Kogoro Mouri.
Why don't you join us for dinner, Sugimura-san?
Thank you very much.
What!?
You don't have the parts!?
I can't have my car until tomorrow... damn...
Mouri-san!
Why don't you stay tonight?
Ah, well...
Weren't you planning a trip, anyways?
This is Tachibana.
Please repair it properly even if it takes time.
Thank you.
So, Mouri-san? Please make yourself at home.
Okay...
Still, it's amazing.
This is a western-style house made of rocks,
and it even includes a wooden bath.
Lawyers are rich, huh?
Rich bastard. The rumors are true.
What are these numbers!?
Are you stealing our money?
This started happening after I hired you.
You're not watching your wife's spendings.
What would you know about accounting?
I heard your wife was getting revenge on you?
Revenge?
Hurry up and get a divorce,
or give me some of the money you're making behind your back!
Anyhow, do something for the office!
Before you're murdered by TK.
Wow.
But what did she mean by revenge?
And TK is from earlier...
Hey.
Were you able to get information about her?
No, not yet.
God.
That's why you failed your bar examination.
Excuse me? You do not give me enough time to study.
Why must you bring up irrelevant topics?
Don't talk back to me!
No excuse for rudeness, son.
You won't be able to find a job wherever you go!
I'm full.
Yohan, you eat a lot!
Oh, you're already awake?
Good morning.
Were you able to sleep well last night?
Yes, thank you.
I'm going fishing today, so expect a lot of fish!
Sorry.
Sorry for bothering you.
I don't mind.
Relax until your car is repaired.
I enjoy your company.
Sensei, your lunch.
I'll leave everything to you then.
Good-bye!
Yohan's barking.
I wonder what's wrong?
I'm sorry, I haven't taken him on a walk yet.
This morning was a bit hectic because the mistress had to go home.
Darn, and I have to go to Tokyo soon.
Um...
May we walk him?
I'd feel bad if we didn't do anything.
Right, Dad?
I suppose you're right.
I have to go to the auto repair shop anyways.
Really?
It would be a great help if you'd do that for us.
What? This is nothing.
Wait! Yohan!
How long are you going to run!?
Hey!
I'm telling you to stop! I'm tired!
Hey! Break time!
Don't move another step...
You two get along well!
It's not funny.
I'm only doing this because we're staying
at the villa and being taken care of.
Uh? Yohan? What's wrong?
Yohan! Wait!
Where are you going!?
Yohan, do you like boats?
It could be someone he knew.
This looks delicious!
Thank you!
Itadakimasu!
What a splendid view. It feels great!
Huh?
Isn't that boat strange?
It's tilted a lot.
That's—! That's Tachibana-sensei's boat!
What!?
Hey! It's capsized!
Oh no!
Yaeko-san! Please call the police!
Yes!
So, everyone? This is Kensuke Tachibana, correct?
Yes, there's no mistake.
The tide is high, so the investigators are making slow progress.
Chiba Prefecture Police
Officer Inoki (28)
I'm sorry for this unfortunate outcome.
Huh?
Hey, Mr. Officer? Wasn't Tachibana-san wearing a life jacket?
Oh yeah. He was wearing one this morning before he left.
Are you serious?
Then why isn't he wearing one now?
There are people who take it off when it gets hot.
That's why there are many accidents like this.
But it's winter right now. Even if it's mild and temperate here...
If only he was wearing a life jacket...
What a shame. I told him to watch out for the spring tide.
How depressing.
Which means it's not likely that he took the life jacket off himself.
Excuse me. Who are you?
I let Tachibana-san borrow my boat. I'm Inuyama.
Inuyama Hiroshi (70)
Owner of Boat Rental Store
I'm the owner of the boat rental store over there.
Actually, a boat like that was stolen. Can you find it for me?
Is that true?
Yes. The children saw a man wearing a red cap on the boat.
Oh, we saw that too! From over there.
Which direction did it go?
Where is that?
It was the path under the cape, so the cliff blocked our view.
That would be near the accident spot.
Then it's possible that it crashed into Tachibana-san's boat.
But that was two hours before the accident.
But something about that man bothers me.
He could be the man that came to the villa before.
What?
Around two months ago, a man wearing a red
baseball cap paid Mr. Tachibana a visit.
He was arguing with Sensei...
If it's the same man, the reason for stealing the
boat would be to get close to Tachibana-san.
Let's investigate the boat.
That would be helpful.
Officer? What is it? Everyone is not home yet...
The inquest's results came out.
What should we do, Baba-san?
Chiba Prefecture Police
Officer Baba (42)
We'll wait here. I want to observe Mouri-san's deductions as well.
Uh, sure.
You want to observe his deductions?
Mouri-san is famous over here, too.
I've heard that he solves the case while
dancing to Yoko Okino's songs.
Also known as "Dancing Kogoro."
What the heck is that?
Sleeping pills?
Those were detected?
Yes. When he was unconcious, he fell in the ocean and drowned.
Did it seem like Mr. Tachibana was going to commit suicide?
Let's see... suicide...
Suicide? I don't think so. Because...
I'm going fishing today, so expect a lot of fish!
He also said, "Stay and relax. I enjoy your company."
I see. Which means someone led his boat astray.
Yaeko-san. Welcome home.
I'm back. I'm sorry, I will prepare the food immediately.
You are the caretaker? Were you shopping?
Yes. Tonight, the people from the office are gathering here.
I'm sure you are busy, but will you tell us some information?
Sure.
What was the lunch that Mr. Tachibana brought with him?
His lunch was a sandwich and hot coffee.
What was inside the sandwich?
Hamburger patty, pickles, lettuce, onions...
Same results as the investigations.
Which means Mr. Tachibana ate lunch in the afternoon.
And Sakuraba-san was the one who handed him the lunch?
I suddenly had to help the mistress with something very important,
so Sakuraba-san handed him the lunch.
So there are three people who had the
chance to put in sleeping pills...
N-No one would do such a thing!
Sleeping pills? What are you talking about?
You are Sakuraba-san?
Yes.
Are you aware that Mr. Tachibana passed away?
Yes, I heard from the police in the parking lot.
By the way, where were you?
At an office in Tokyo, with Sensei's business...
I heard that Sensei was in a boat that capsized, and he drowned.
What does that have to do with sleeping pills?
There seems to have been someone who
added sleeping pills to his coffee.
No way...
That man with the red baseball cap could have done it.
Oh yeah. There's that possibility as well.
There was also a weird letter. Right, Sakuraba-san?
What weird letter?
Well, Sensei has been receiving threats lately.
Threats? Why didn't you tell us before?
Here it is. All three have the same content.
If you still want your job as a lawyer, prepare 3,000,000 yen. T.K.
This is definitely a threat.
In this diary...
"You are the one who committed the crime, yet you threaten me,
the one who made you innocent. You are a helpless villian!"
Sakuraba-san. Do you have any idea who TK might be?
Well, no...
It doesn't feel right.
According to Tachibana-san's diary,
he knew that TK committed a crime.
However, he acquitted him of the crime.
You did not know about this?
No, I did not. I saw that letter in the office.
Sensei got mad at me, though, and told
me to pretend that I didn't see it.
Hi. The people from the office have arrived.
We will be there shortly.
Tachibana Office Lawyer
Fujisawa Fumio (45)
I came to get Sensei's body, but they wouldn't let me.
Is something wrong?
Well, we wanted to confirm something. Where is his wife?
At her house, with relatives.
Where is Sugi... something?
Sugimura-san.
Since she has her weekends off, she went somewhere.
We can't get in contact with her.
It's here!
T-This is...
A red baseball cap!
Let's tell Officer Baba immediately!
We're sorry to disturb you so early in the morning.
We found something that may be proof.
It's this red baseball cap. Has anyone seen it before?
That was the same color as the one the
person on the boat was wearing!
I see.
What about you, Kamei-san?
Yes, it was like that.
There's a name on this.
Please take a look.
Does the name Kumada ring a bell?
No.
Well?
I don't know.
Hey, Sakuraba. Wasn't Kumada-san Sensei's client five years ago?
During your first year, the trial was being held, right?
Ah, yes. That person.
Was he acquitted?
Yes. It was a disadvantage, but Sensei
was able to prove his innocence.
His name was Tatsu... Tatsuya Kumada, I think.
Tatsuya Kumada?
His initials are...
T.K.!
It's connected with the TK in the threat!
Could this be...?
A man named Kumada threatened Tachibana-san.
But Tachibana-san did not respond.
He may have said something like, "I'll
sue you for blackmailing me!"
While Tachibana-san was fishing, Kumada followed him, fed
him sleeping pills, took off his life jacket, and drowned him.
Very good, Baba-san.
Alright, Inoki-kun! Let's catch him!
Yes.
But it's ironic that he lives 25 minutes away from
the villa. He's more and more suspicious.
Definitely the culprit.
Why are you coming?
Because I'm a witness of the man in the red baseball cap.
How strange. I heard that he works
at night and sleeps during the day.
It's not locked.
What?
Kumada-san, we're coming in.
What is this...?
Kumada, the suspect...
Suicide!?
Natsu no Maboroshi
Song by Garnet Crow
HEYA NO MADO NO MUKOU NI HIKOUKI KUMO WO NAZOTTE
TRACING THE AIRPLANE CLOUDS BEYOND THE WINDOW
KYOU KENKASHITA KIMI NO KOTO BAKARI KANGAETETA
THINKING ABOUT YOU, WHO I HAD A FIGHT WITH TODAY
SASAI NA KOTA DE TO MADOTTE FUANTEI DE MUBOUBI NA
HESITATING AT THE SMALLEST THINGS, BEING UNSTABLE AND RISKY
ANO KORO NO YOU NI SUGU NI DENWASHITE
WISHING THAT I CAN CALL YOU RIGHT AWAY
WARAI AETARA II NO NI NE
AND LAUGH TOGETHER LIKE WE USED TO
CHIKA ZUITE KURU SHIFUKU NO TOKI WA
THE HAPPINESS THAT IS COMING NEAR
ITAMI WO TOMONAINAGARA ASHI OTO WO TATERU
BRINGS ALONG PAIN, AS IT MAKES NOISES, AS IT WALKS
KANGAESUGITE FUKAMI NI HAMARU
KIMI NO SOBA NI IRU NO NI
I'M NEAR YOU WHEN YOU ARE THINKING DEEPLY
Ending Theme
「Natsu no Maboroshi」
NATSU NO MABOROSHI HITOMI TOJIMETE
ICHIBAN SAISHOU NI KIMI WO OMOIDASU YO
SUMMER'S ILLUSION, CLOSING MY EYES, I THINK ABOUT YOU FIRST
DAKEDO KIMI TO IKITEYUKITAI KARA
BUT I WANT TO KEEP ON LIVING WITH YOU
TOMADOINAGARA DEMO II TSUNAIDA TE WO HANASANAIDE NE
HESITATING IS OKAY, BUT DON'T LET GO OF MY HAND