Koi wa thrill, shock, suspense
Song by Rina Aiuchi
KOI WA THRILL, SHOCK, SUSPENSE
LOVE IS A THRILL, SHOCK, SUSPENSE
MIENAI CHIKARA TAYORI NI
RELYING ON UNSEEN FORCES...
KOKORO NO TOBIRA TOZASAZU NI TSUYOKU... TSUYOKU...
POWERFULLY WITHOUT LOCKING UP THE HEART'S DOOR... POWERFULLY...
A courageous heart and deduction power!
The rhythm that leads us to the truth!
Full suspense, part two!
An unexpected culprit!
Recognizing that one truth...
A child with the mind of an adult...
His name is Detective Conan!
WATASHI GA KANJITEITA
MAYBE I WAS GIVING YOU PAIN
TOGE OKIMI NI NO ONAJI
YOU NI ATAETEITA NO KANO SHIRENAKATTA
SIMILAR TO WHAT I'VE FELT, AND WITHOUT THINKING
NANI NI KOKORO WO ITAMETE NANI NI OBIETEITA NO KA
KI NI INO TOMEZU MOTSURETEKU FUTARI NO SHINJITSU NI
ABOUT WHAT GAVE ME PAIN, WHAT I FEARED
Opening Theme
「Koi wa thrill, shock, suspense」
MUKIAU NO GA KOWAKATTA
I FEARED FACING THE COMPLICATED TRUTH
THIS LOVE IS A THRILL, SHOCK, SUSPENSE
THIS LOVE IS THRILL, SHOCK, SUSPENSE
MAYOI WO AOI KAZE NI CHIRASOU TOSHITE MO KAKAEKIREZU NI ITA YO
EVEN IF I TRY TO SCATTER DOUBT IN THE BLUE WINDS
KONO CHISANA MUNE NI WA
I WAS UNABLE TO CARRY THE BURDEN WITH THIS SMALL CHEST
KOKORO NO TOBIRA TOZASAZU NI
WITHOUT LOCKING UP THE HEART'S DOOR
TSUGI E TO SUSUMU ARATA NA FUAN TO
EVEN IF I MUST CARRY MORE ANXIETY AND DOUBT
MAYOI WO KAKAETESHIMAISOU NI NATTE MO
AS I CONTINUE ON
While we were driving near the ocean, our car broke down.
We stayed at lawyer Tachibana's villa for one night.
However, the next day...
Right in front of our eyes...
Mr. Tachibana's boat capsized and he died.
We found out that Mr. Tachibana was killed by someone with
the initials T.K., who had been sending threats to him.
Five years ago, Mr. Tachibana acquitted him of a crime.
We thought he was Tatsuya Kumada,
so we rushed into his apartment.
But what we saw was...
Kumada-san, we're coming in.
W-What is this...?
Kumada, the suspect...
Suicide!?
The Bay of Revenge
(Part 2)
Please stay back.
Okay, stay back!
It seems like he used this chair to commit suicide.
But that's an odd way to hang the rope.
It's tied to the veranda handrail.
Is it because his feet would touch the floor
if the rope was hung from the beam?
Oh yeah, there was a loud noise from the room upstairs.
I heard a thud, as if something fell.
It only happened once, though.
When was that?
I think it was after 7:00 PM.
The estimated time of death is between
6:00 and 7:00, so it makes sense...
Around 7:00?
Ah, I wasn't home. I came home at 7:15.
I see.
But that's weird.
When I came home, I heard the washing
machine from Kumada-san's room.
Are you sure!?
Yes.
Why would someone who is about to
commit suicide wash their clothes?
This is probably...
Hey!
That's dangerous! What are you doing?
Ahh, I'm sorry!
Which boat was Tachibana-san on?
It's the one on the far right.
Can I see it for a second?
Hey, hey, are you investigating the crime?
Uh-huh. I'm a detective.
Thanks for your hard work!
What are these scratches?
Did you find something?
Were these scratches here before?
They're new! That's the first time I've ever seen them.
Tachibana-san or the police probably did it.
Oh man.
The stolen boat was found, but the anchor
was stolen and it's a great deal of trouble!
Anchor?
Yeah.
When you fish, you use it so you won't float away with the tide.
You sink this weight to the bottom of the sea.
He took away the wire from the big boat, too.
It looks just like that.
It still hasn't been found?
It wasn't found anywhere in or near the boat this morning.
That boat's anchor was gone, too.
So that's how it is.
I'm back!
Welcome back.
Conan! Where were you?
You too, Ran.
What were you doing with Sakuraba-san?
Cleaning, of course, cleaning!
Sakuraba-san just came back from walking Yohan.
Sakuraba-san?
What was the case with Tatsuya Kumada five years ago?
Sorry, it's confidential.
What are you saying?
Sugimura-san! Where were you?
Vacation!
I was watching the news and left during the middle.
I see.
So, is the culprit TK?
Yes.
You know Tatsuya Kumada?
Oh, his real name is revealed.
He held a high position in the securities company.
Masahiko Tsuruta, who worked under
him, used the money for his own use.
He was caught, so he committed suicide.
However, from Tsuruta's diary, we found out that
Kumada was the one embezzling the money.
Thus, Kumada was charged for murder.
But the people living under Masahiko Tsuruta's
apartment heard something fall at 10:00 PM.
At that time, Kumada was at a karaoke party.
The alibi was proved, and Kumada was innocent.
Then it's just like this case!
Sugimura-san!
You came three years ago.
How would you know about the case from five years ago?
I was only looking up the threatener,
TK, and a little about Mrs. Tachibana.
I heard it was Sensei's fault your father committed suicide?
You must of hated him, to the point where you wanted to kill him.
What about you?
You are using a lot of the office's money.
After he found out, you killed him.
That's ridiculous!
Yeah.
How was it, Professor?
Ah, I found out where he lived at the time the trial was held.
It's in the same Chiba prefecture.
Masahiko Tsuruta's family consists of his mother,
Tamiko, and his younger brother, Katsuhiko.
Mother and brother?
Grandma!
Do you know Masahiko Tsuruta's house?
Masahiko-chan's house.
It's over there.
But even if you go, no one will be there.
Why?
His mother, Tamiko-san, and his brother, Katsuhiko-chan,
both moved because of that incident.
He went to some school in Germany.
He was an outstanding child.
The house is in a place like this, which is the reason why it won't sell.
They sometimes come to clean the house,
but it's been a year since they last did.
Johann...
I see!
That's how it was!
The same sleeping pill in Tachibana-san
was found in Kumada's blood.
It was also in the whiskey bottle.
We have concluded that he murdered Tachibana-san,
then committed suicide by taking sleeping pills.
Crap, when did he—!?
Shit!
Wait, here, here!
What's in here?
It's this file. What is it?
Oh, it's an account book.
I heard the famous detective's deduction will start?
What are you going to deduce now?
Well, everyone, please take a seat.
I will reveal the truth of Mr. Tachibana and Tatsuya Kumada.
The truth?
I thought it was already solved.
Are you saying the conclusion we drew was wrong?
That's right.
Tatsuya Kumada was murdered by the same
person who murdered Mr. Tachibana.
And the killer is here with us!
What are you talking about!?
Let us discuss that right now.
The same sleeping pill in Mr. Tachibana's
body was found in Kumada-san.
Which means that after the culprit murdered Tachibana-san,
he did the same thing to Kumada-san.
The culprit killed Kumada-san while he was
asleep and made it look like a suicide.
But is there anyone who would have been able to do that?
There were three people.
Yaeko Kamei.
Yuuichi Sakuraba.
And Tachibana-san himself.
But Yaeko-san was there with us when the boat capsized.
So...
W-Wait a minute!
I was at the office in Tokyo when that happened!
No, no.
It doesn't matter where you were when the boat capsized.
Long before Tachibana-san was murdered, the culprit was ready.
All he had to do was wait.
What do you mean, Mouri-san?
Oh yeah!
That person we saw!
The person on the boat with the red cap!
Yes.
That was the murderer.
But that was two hours before the boat capsized.
How did he get the boat to turn over?
If you think about why the culprit did what
they did yesterday, you will understand.
As you're aware, a spring tide occurred yesterday.
Yes, that's true. With the spring tide, it was difficult to investigate.
Don't you get it?
Spring tides exhibit a very large change
in sea level between high and low tides.
That's why the crime was committed yesterday.
Please elaborate.
The guy that we saw in the red baseball cap...
After getting close to Tachibana-san, he
pulled off Tachibana-san's life jacket.
He dropped the anchor that he stole into the ocean.
He then secured a hook that was tied
at the end of the rope onto the boat.
That way, when the high tide comes and the water level rises,
the boat will be pulled by the anchor and will flip over.
After it flipped, the hook came off and
sank to the bottom of the ocean.
Tachibana-san, who fell into the ocean, drowned.
I didn't think of that!
We heard that an anchor was also stolen from the boat rental place.
So, the missing anchor on the stolen boat...
Yes.
That anchor is probably at the bottom of the ocean.
After the incident, the ocean floor should have been investigated.
Yes! I will contact them.
How could someone do something so cruel...
Simple. Pretend it was Jd—.
In order to create an alibi at the time the boat capsized,
he went this far.
Yes.
Thank you.
Mouri-san, the anchor was found.
It was on the ocean floor at the scene of the crime.
We are confirming this information
with the man from the rental store.
And there was a hook at the end of the rope!
Moving on...
After returning to the shore, the culprit left the hat
on the boat to leave suspicions on Kumada.
According to the investigations, that
hat belonged to Kumada himself.
No one else's hairs were detected.
The hat used for disguise was probably something similar.
The real hat was probably something the
culprit took when he met with Kumada.
Kumada and the culprit were acquaintanced.
For proof, the culprit was able to go to his apartment
and feed him whiskey and sleeping pills.
He moved Kumada to the sliding door
and tied a rope around his neck.
Next, he used the railing to tie the rope hung
from the beam, pulling Kumada up.
Afterwards, he tied the rope to the railing, opened
the door, and placed a chair beneath his feet.
That's what happened.
But what about the noise that the people downstairs heard at 7:00?
Everyone has an alibi.
Actually, you don't need an alibi at that time.
What do you mean?
This trick was used five years ago when Tatsuya
Kumada killed Masahiko Tsuruta.
What?
The washing machine that was running after 7:00.
The culprit tied a string around the motor so it would wind up.
He placed a loop around a chair.
Then he set the time on the washing machine to 7:00.
The string would spin with the motor, and thus, the chair would fall.
I'll have people search the washing machine.
That would mean Tachibana-san was murdered at 1:00 PM.
Since Kumada's estimated time of death was from 6:00 to 7:30...
Before 7:00, after 6:00.
The person who doesn't have an alibi at this time is the murderer.
Sakuraba-san, for example.
You left here at 1:00 and came back after 7:00.
Wait a minute!
Many people hated Sensei!
Have you even checked everyone?
Sakuraba-kun.
What did you come to get at the office yesterday?
Right when the boat capsized.
What does that mean?
Well...
I...
Sakuraba-san, it's for these account books, right?
In order to make it look like Sugimura-san stole money
from the office, you were planning to make stuff up.
You!
S-Sorry.
Last night, Sensei and I changed the content of those books.
We were going to blame Sensei's spendings on you.
So I'm relieved that Sensei died...
Sakuraba-kun!
What do you mean you're "relieved"!?
I'm sick of helping Sensei do evil work!
He said, "If you don't listen to me, you won't
be able to become a lawyer in the future!"
He threatened me. I couldn't take it anymore!
Sakuraba-san, tell us the rest at the police station.
No! I didn't do it!
If you resist, we'll arrest you!
Believe me!
I did not kill neither Kumada nor Sensei!
I'm innocent!
Stop it!
It wasn't Sakuraba-san.
I killed them.
No way!
Y-Yaeko-san...
I was waiting for those words.
You can't silently watch others being blamed for your own crime.
You were able to add sleeping pills to Sensei's water bottle.
That day, after we had left, you disguised as
Kumada and left through the back door.
You used a boat to go to Tachibana-san.
Afterwards, you watched Tachibana-san's boat capsize with us.
Later that evening, Yaeko-san went shopping
and parked her car in the parking lot.
She immediately disguised somewhere and
took a train to Kumada's apartment.
Isn't that right?
Look at this.
Conan found this nameplate in Masahiko Tsuruta's yard.
Johann
Yes.
In German, it would be "Yohan."
This is probably the name your son
who graduated in Germany gave.
Isn't that right...
Tamiko Tsuruta?
What?
Then Yaeko-san is...
Yes.
She is Masahiko Tsuruta's mother, who was murdered by Kumada.
I should have realized this earlier.
Yesterday at the cape, Yohan was chasing
after the boat you were on.
Even though you were disguised, Yohan recognized you.
My second son died last year.
Right now, Yohan is my only family.
I lied, saying he was a stray dog, and we started living here.
I fought so many times at court, but no one noticed me.
The court's decision was unfair. I grew old because of that.
And then half a year ago, Kumada finally appeared.
I overheard the washing machine trick.
In jail, Kumada said he would pay any amount of money.
Even though Sensei knew that Kumada murdered Masahiko,
he acquitted Kumada of the crime for money.
That day, I followed Kumada to his apartment.
With his hat that he left, I thought of this crime.
And the threats that looked like they were from Kumada...
you were sending them to Tachibana-san.
Yes.
Since yesterday, I have been so scared.
I'm finally relieved.
You were prepared to be arrested from the beginning.
That's why, despite the fact a detective was
here, you still committed the crime.
Maybe.
I'm sorry for causing trouble.
Natsu no Maboroshi
Song by Garnet Crow
HEYA NO MADO NO MUKOU NI HIKOUKI KUMO WO NAZOTTE
TRACING THE AIRPLANE CLOUDS BEYOND THE WINDOW
KYOU KENKASHITA KIMI NO KOTO BAKARI KANGAETETA
THINKING ABOUT YOU, WHO I HAD A FIGHT WITH TODAY
SASAI NA KOTA DE TO MADOTTE FUANTEI DE MUBOUBI NA
HESITATING AT THE SMALLEST THINGS, BEING UNSTABLE AND RISKY
ANO KORO NO YOU NI SUGU NI DENWASHITE
WISHING THAT I CAN CALL YOU RIGHT AWAY
WARAI AETARA II NO NI NE
AND LAUGH TOGETHER LIKE WE USED TO
CHIKA ZUITE KURU SHIFUKU NO TOKI WA
THE HAPPINESS THAT IS COMING NEAR
ITAMI WO TOMONAINAGARA ASHI OTO WO TATERU
BRINGS ALONG PAIN, AS IT MAKES NOISES, AS IT WALKS
KANGAESUGITE FUKAMI NI HAMARU
KIMI NO SOBA NI IRU NO NI
I'M NEAR YOU WHEN YOU ARE THINKING DEEPLY
Ending Theme
「Natsu no Maboroshi」
NATSU NO MABOROSHI HITOMI TOJIMETE
ICHIBAN SAISHOU NI KIMI WO OMOIDASU YO
SUMMER'S ILLUSION, CLOSING MY EYES, I THINK ABOUT YOU FIRST
DAKEDO KIMI TO IKITEYUKITAI KARA
BUT I WANT TO KEEP ON LIVING WITH YOU
TOMADOINAGARA DEMO II TSUNAIDA TE WO HANASANAIDE NE
HESITATING IS OKAY, BUT DON'T LET GO OF MY HAND
Dad! What the heck?
It was just repaired... that's weird.
When can we go back to Tokyo?
Please!
Just this once!
To Tokyo!
Maybe if you switched places with him, someone will stop.
It's okay.
Let's look at the ocean a little while longer.
Well, I don't mind.
Heeeeeeeey!!
Do something!!