Lying in a strong heart is the power of deduction.
Stepping into the truth with a sharp rhythm!
It's been a while since we heard from the police department.
Excitement builds in an ominous case!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Hello?
It's me.
Sorry for not answering.
My cell phone's battery ran out.
Ah, yeah...
I just got out of the car—I'm in a phone booth now.
Let's see...
I'll be at your place in about half an hour.
Bye, see you soon.
MEGURE'S SEALED SECRET
(PART ONE)
Hey, hey, how's this one?
This is a present for Kyogoku-san, right?
Isn't it a little cute for him?
Guess it is...
If it's him...
This simple one will suit him just fine.
No it won't, it's not hand-knit.
It needs to be hand-knit?
Oops!
Sonoko...
No, I just thought a hand-knit
sweater would feel warm...
Don't tell me, Sonoko!
I unintentionally mentioned it in
the letter I sent him earlier...
"Right now, I'm knitting a sweater for someone I like."
But I never expected it to be so hard.
I see.
So you were going to buy him a hand-knit
sweater from a store and say you knit it.
It can't be helped!
I really don't know how to knit.
Very well.
I admire your bravery in admitting that you
like him, so I'll keep your secret to myself.
Oh, I still haven't told Makoto-san that I like him.
Didn't you say so in the letter?
"I'm knitting for someone I like"?
Stop beating around the bush or Kyogoku-san
might think there's someone else you love.
See, that's the whole point!
Makoto-san will definitely panic a
bit when that comes to mind...
And one day, a package will arrive at his place.
He would think, "What is this, something
from Sonoko-san?" or something like that.
And as he anxiously starts
to open up the package...
"Surprise!"
"The sweater was actually for you! "
What do you think of my marvelous love-love plan?
Even if you say so...
Don't come crying to me if he's not impressed.
But you know...
Makoto-san won't express his feelings, so I don't
know how he actually feels if I don't do this.
I know that he worries about me, but...
I still need the courage to ask him directly,
But Sonoko...
Speaking of which, Ran, do you know?
How Shinichi-kun feels about you?
That's...
Hey...
Hey, hey, hey!
Don't you want to know?
Don't you want to ask him?
Well, don't you?
About that...
I've known him since we were little, so it'd
be a lie to say I don't want to know, but...
But...
"But, but, but, but, but, but, but, but, but...!"
"l want to ask, but I'm afraid to know the answer."
"That's how I feel right now."
I bet you're thinking something dreamy like that!
I'm not!
Excuse me...
May I go to the parking garage and wait with Uncle?
Tell Dad to go ahead and wait in the pasta
house behind this department store, all right?
Hey, hey, how about this one?
Seems I've come across some idle
girl-talk that I shouldn't have...
No, that one's too tasteless!
Isn't it?
Geez...
Why do girls like to spend so much time
shopping and chatting on the phone?
So true...
Wow!
What a beautiful girl!
It's this cold and she's wearing a mini-skirt that short?
How sexy!
There's a ballpoint pen over here.
I think it belonged to that girl.
Oh, a great opportunity!
Ah, wait!
Miss!
I think this belongs to you!
Arrest him!
Right!
Wait, wait, wait!
Disguised in order to investigate the cases of
the women who were attacked this week?
That's right
That's why we asked Detective
Satou to dress that way.
But, the announcements said the
suspect is about 150 cm tall...
A quick look at me will tell you I'm
not the suspect! you're looking for.
Ah, no...
But that attitude you had as you
approached Satou-san was, uhm,...
Should I say "very special"?
I felt I was in danger.
How rude...
But it is tough to investigate.
Yeah, since the only common link between the women
was that they were all wearing fashionable clothes.
Even the crime scenes are different.
Could we see the photos of those three women again?
Yes, Sir.
The first one who was attacked
is named Mizutani Ryouko-san.
One night two weeks ago...
While she,was waiting in her car for the traffic
light to change, another car rear-ended her.
Then, as she left the vehicle to complain,
she was attacked with a metal bat.
The next one to be attacked was Endou Hitomi-san.
Ten nights ago, she was struck by a metal bat as she
was coming out of a public restroom in a park.
Then, we have the one from last
night, Ishiguro Michiko-san.
This time, she was attacked after
coming out of a phone booth,
You said phone booth... Could it be?
Yeah, it was where we subdued you earlier.
Fortunately, the lives of those
three victims aren't in danger.
They just share nothing in common other than
the fashionable garb they were wearing.
The three said they
hadn't made any enemies.
How's that, Mouri-kun?
Think of anything yet?
Well, one thing I noticed is...
One thing you noticed?
All three of them are mixed-race - like
they grew up in a jungle or something.
No matter how you look at it, they
aren't normal Japanese people.
Oh, how cute!
These three ganguro look amazing!
The one in the middle is gonguro, so she's even darker.
This style is called Yamanba, and it's really
fashionable among girls these days.
Yamanba?
No way...
Could it be you don't know, Uncle?
Ridiculous!
Of course, Yamanba!
I know something that obvious.
Huh? Where's Ran-neechan?
Oh, she said she was going to the restroom and
wanted me to meet her at this pasta house.
But, if this was a series of random
attacks, there's nothing we can do...
That's true...
To now, there haven't been any cases like this one.
No, there was one before.
There was a string of female high school
students being run over by cars...
Pretty disturbing cases...
I'm certain it was before I became a police detective...
At any rate, we should get back to investigating.
Yes, sir.
In that case! I'll go back to being a decoy.
No, a decoy is no longer necessary.
Start over and investigate whether or not the three victims had any connection to each other.
Yes, Sir.
Well, Mouri-kun, sorry about what happened.
Hello?
Ah, Ran.
You can't find the exit?
Well, where are you?
The, underground parking garage?
Geez, you have no sense of direction, as usual.
Hey, Sonoko-neechan, about your
ring, necklace, and bracelet...
Don't they look like those worn
by the women in the photos?
Where'd you buy them?
I didn't buy them, they were complimentary gifts
from that department store we just went to.
They're having this Millennium Sale,
and they check your receipt at the exit
For every 10,000 yen you spend, you
get to choose one of the accessories.
Hey, how is it?
They're wearing them.
Although they aren't wearing the entire set, they
each have a piece that matches Sonoko-san.
That means these three...
Are all customers of that department store.
Hey, Sonoko?
What is it?
Answer me...
Hey, Sonoko...
Ran!
Hey, Ran!
What happened, Ran!?
What is it, Ran?
Dad...
Are you OK?
What?
There's a girl whose face is covered in blood!?
The victim is Aizawa Tae-san, 20 years old.
Until one year ago, she worked in this department store.
She's been unemployed since.
So our fourth case is a murder...
It's the same suspect, then?
Yeah.
We never announced the common
characteristics of the victims to the public...
And this is the parking garage of
that same department store.
There's no denying the connection.
In that case, this was done by someone bearing a grudge against this department store.
Tae!
Who's he?
That's the boyfriend.
He claimed to have been waiting
for her in the department store.
His father is the owner of this department store...
Shirakawa Noriyuki (24)
Cook
And he planned to introduce his girlfriend
at the restaurant where he works.
Who's that girl?
She's a waitress who works in the
same restaurant that he does.
Konno Yuri (24)
Waitress
Her name is Konno Yuri-san.
She said they've been friends since college,
and that she sometimes gives him advice.
Advice?
Shirakawa-san's father opposed his
engagement with the deceased Aizawa-san.
By the way, Ran...
Did you notice anyone suspicious
when you found the body?
Nobody suspicious.
The only person I passed by was the guard.
Guard?
It was the guard standing by the entrance when I
came down —
a man who was about 40 years old...
Oh, that would be me.
I left my post in order to head to the restroom, so...
Sadakane Yoshio (43)
Guard
The culprit must have got to her while I wasn't here.
That is, if you aren't really the culprit yourself.
Dad...
If I recall correctly, you worked at a rival
department store until half a year ago.
Could you have arranged with your former employer to
cause a scandal here and send my coustomers his way?
Shirakawa Haruyoshi (53)
Haido Department Store Owner
No way...
Well, at least now Noriyuki can get a new girlfriend.
This time, how about finding
a nice girl with a clean slate?
Dad!
Noriyuki-kun...
Uhm, what did he mean by "clean slate"?
He's probably referring to the automobile accident she
was involved in a year ago, in this parking garage.
Automobile accident?
Yes.
She ran over a little boy, and after
that accident, she gave up her job.
Yumi from the traffic division told me about that.
The boy was waiting in this parking garage for his
mother when he stepped in front of a car and was hit
The driver was going at a slow speed considering
it was the inside of a parking garage, but...
Unfortunately, the boy's vitals were
hit, and he died three days later.
I think the boy's name was Sakurai Akira,
I see.
By the way, Noriyuki-san...
Do you know how tall your father is?
A little over 150 cm.
And the rest of you?
173 cm.
I'm 144 cm.
And I'm 167
Things aren't looking good for the owner.
Yeah.
He would've known when she would be by her car.
I have a question.
Was your father already at the
restaurant when you arrived?
No, he didn't show up on time, so
I asked her to see if he was here.
I see.
Could you be implying that my father is a suspect!?
No, we only asked because the other victims told
us the culprit's height was around 150 cm.
The "other victims"?
Then, as I thought, this is the work of that
serial attacker we've been hearing about?
That is...
What have you done about that?
You even know the culprit's height,
so why can't you catch them?
If you had caught the culprit, Tae wouldn't be dead!
Wait, Noriyuki-kun...
Tae is dead, and it's the fault of the police!
You police are all useless!
That's enough, Noriyuki-kun!
Useless...
Useless
You police are all useless!
Why are you surprised?
I said I was going to play decoy.
Guess...It didn't go smoothly like in the movies...
Inspector Megure!
Inspector!
Are you all right?
Forget it, it's nothing...
My apologies, Inspector.
Noriyuki-kun just went a little overboard.
No, it's fine.
What he said was true.
You know, it might be best for
him to go cool off for a bit...
Understood.
In that case, I'll return to my post.
Keep up the good work.
Say...
Did all three of those ladies attest that
the culprit's height was around 150 cm?
No, only the first and third victims said that.
The second victim was suddenly attacked from behind.
She was unconscious until a passerby found her,
so she didn't catch a glimpse of her assailant.
But, both that did say were certain
that the culprit was about 150 cm.
When we called them down to the
station a few days after the attacks...
Both stated that their attacker was
roughly the same height as they were.
And how tall were those two?
Let's see...
The first was 151 cm, and the third was 153 cm.
We measured them at the station,
so there's no doubt about that.
Hey!
Don't tell a kid too much about that.
Sorry...
Hey, Ran...
Are you sure you didn't see anyone suspicious?
I'm sure of it.
I ran around looking for the exit, after all.
In any case, don't you think something's wrong?
About what?
About that lady there.
Ah, you noticed it too?
You think so too?
Something's weird, but I can't figure out what.
This person... something just isn't right...
Not right?
Speaking of weird, don't you think the
second victim's clothes are weird?
This lady was attacked as she was
leaving a park restroom, right?
Yes, that's right!
We took that picture right after
we arrived at the crime scene.
Look.
The restroom is even in the background.
Since a passerby was the one who found
her, she must have been alone, right?
But if so, why is it she has a
man's coat on her shoulders?
Oh, that's the coat I loaned her at the time.
She seemed to be freezing.
Then, why was she wearing such light
clothes in the middle of the night?
That's true...
She didn't say anything about the
attacker stealing her coat or anything...
Speaking of which, we haven't had time to take her statement since she's still in a state of shock.
Idiot!
Don't you know it's fashionable
for girls not to wear much?
But what she wore was sleeveless.
That'd be too cold for anyone to bear.
Maybe she was somewhere warm and had planned
to go back there after going to the restroom.
Somewhere warm?
Right, right...
Like maybe...
Inside her car.
Her car?
That's right, the first and third victims were
attacked right after they left their cars.
And then, the fourth happened in a parking garage.
These cases all involve cars!
All right!
Takagi-kun, go contact the second
victim immediately to confirm!
Yes, sir!
Does that mean the owner's no longer suspicious?
No, not just yet.
Thanks for your continued perseverance, Detective.
Matsumoto Kiyonaga (54)
Police Headquarters - Superintendent
Superintendent Matsumoto!
Pleasure to see you again...
Hey, Megure...
The press has already started reporting that
this is the beginning of a serial murder spree.
I advise you pull back for now and start
the investigation anew tomorrow.
No, it's just...
He's right, Inspector.
We already know the girls were
in their cars before the attacks.
I'll just disguise as a ganguro
and act as a decoy in my car.
Didn't I tell you!?
No more decoys!
Superintendent.
Please, allow us to investigate just a little longer!
I'm sure we're getting somewhere!
And I have a feeling that the culprit
is still around here somewhere.
If you must
Megure...
Could it be that you're still thinking
back to that case from before?
About what it is you hide away under your hat?
No, that's not it...
Is that so?
Sorry I asked.