Lying in a strong heart is the power of deduction.
Stepping into the truth with a sharp rhythm!
What lies under the hat will now be revealed!
Inspector Megure's incredible past!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
While accompanying Sonoko on her shopping
spree, we came to this department store.
But then, Uncle got involved in
Inspector Megure's sting operation.
The Inspector Was investigating a series
of cases involving bludgeoned women.
Meanwhile, in the department store's underground
parking garage, Ran discovered a woman's body.
Inspector Megure continued his investigation,
but he didn't appear to be his usual self...
Superintendent.
Please, allow us to investigate just a little longer!
I'm sure we're getting somewhere!
And I have a feeling that the culprit
is still around here somewhere.
If you must.
Megure...
Could it be that you're still thinking
back to that case from before?
About what it is you hide away under your hat?
Megure's Sealed Secret
(Part Two)
Hey, Uncle.
Could I borrow your keys?
This case seems like it's gonna take a while, so I'd
like to put my stuff in the car and visit the restroom.
Well, don't be too long.
The store will be closing soon.
Thank you.
Would you take mine too?
Sure.
There it is!
Here, here!
Geez, look at how this other car is parked!
What a strange way to park!
I can't even open the passenger side door like this.
And there.
Inspector, I just heard back from her!
And?
As we thought, she was in her car
before going to the restroom.
I see.
But I still don't understand...
Why is he only after fashionable
young girls who drive cars?
Or is there some other connection?
Something that we overlooked connecting those four...
Restroom Closed
For Cleaning
Please accept our
apologies for the
inconvenience.
Haido
Department Store
Hey, no way!
Here too?
Why don't they wait to clean until after they've closed?
The next restroom is up on the 8th floor.
I have such bad luck with these restrooms.
Thank you for visiting our department store.
We'll be closing soon.
Please come again soon.
No way...
Already?
We'll take the body now.
Hey, her leg slipped out!
Sorry!
Huh?
The shoe doesn't fit?
Hey, Ran-neechan!
Earlier, you said there was
something wrong with that lady!
Could it be...
Yeah, yeah, that's it!
Since it's part of the ganguro fashion,
they shouldn't have been missing!
Then, that means...
Could the culprit be...
Restroom
Wait, don't turn the lights off!
I'm still here!
Hey!
Is anyone there?
What?
Platform boots?
You're saying that Aizawa-san, who was killed in this
parking garage, was actually wearing platform boots?
Yeah—it's part of the ganguro fashion, so
they wouldn't wear low-heeled pumps.
Right, Ran-neechan?
Yeah...
But why would the criminal change the victim's shoes?
He didn't want anyone to figure it out.
That he only goes after women
who drive with platform boots.
What was that!?
Speaking of which, the other three victims
followed the ganguro fashion as well...
In other words, those three must
have had platform boots too?
Right.
Speaking of platform boots...
The primary reason that Aizawa-san
caused that car accident a year ago...
Was due to the fact she was
driving with platform boots on...
Which caused her braking to take longer than usual.
That's what I heard from Yumi.
Is that true?
Yes.
The deceased boy's mother and her ex-husband
argued that that was the cause of the accident, but...
The judge overruled them.
The ex-husband?
Yeah.
They divorced after the husband became an alcoholic.
I think that man's name was...
Sadakane, wasn't it?
Right, right, that was his name.
Hey, hold on a second!
Isn't the guard's name... Sadakane?
Hey, then, could that mean the culprit is...
The security guard?
Takagi, go get information on
that accident from a year ago!
Right!
The rest of you, go find the guard, Sadakane!
Yes, sir!
But, how did you know all that?
It wasn't too difficult.
The culprit only attacked women who drove
while wearing platform boots, right?
From outside the car, the culprit can't see
what kind of shoes they're wearing...
But we know that the victims
shop at this department store.
As such, the only way the culprit would know
is to see them getting in and out of their cars.
That's why it had to be the guard.
However, the victims said the
culprit was about 150 cm tall.
Didn't you hear the guard say he was 167 cm?
You're just playing stupid, aren't you?
The girls only said that the culprit
was the same height as them.
At those times, they were wearing
platform boots over 10 cm thick.
What that really meant was that the
culprit must've been 10 cm taller.
Didn't you already know that?
I see.
We measured their heights at the station.
Since they were coming for a police interview,
they wouldn't wear informal platform boots.
But, if he wanted to kill Aizawa-san...
Why do it in this parking complex rather
than just go straight to her house?
Have you forgotten, Mouri?
The victim was 20 years old, wasn't she?
A year ago when she caused the
accident, she was considered a minor.
Minors cannot have their addresses be
made public according to the law.
Because of that, he waited at this department store
where his son died, hoping she'd return one day.
When she didn't appear, he broke down and began
attacking any woman who drove in platform boots.
Inspector, we got the backstory!
As we thought, the guard is the father of the
boy who died in the accident one year ago.
And?
Where is he at the moment?
About that... his car is still in the
parking garage, but he's missing.
What's wrong, Ran-neechan?
Sonoko hasn't come back yet...
She said she was just going to put her things
in the car and then going to the restroom...
Putting her stuff in the car?
Hey, the shoes Sonoko's wearing...
Hello?
Ah, Ran?
Huh, right now?
I'm still in the department store.
Wait until you hear what happened.
It's so cruel!
Right as I got out of the restroom,
they turned the lights off...
What is it?
Something wrong, Sonoko?
Oh, nope.
It's nothing.
Just thought I heard something weird.
She saw me... She saw me...
She saw my face...
Hey, Sonoko!
Sonoko?
He's made a mistake.
The culprit saw Sonoko-neechan doing
something in the car with the keys in hand!
He mistook her for a driver with platform boots!
What was that?
Where is she right now?
Inside the department store.
Is the line cut?
It's still connected, but...
I can only hear a machine's voice.
A machine's voice?
Please choose your background picture!
Press the button when your pose is ready!
That's a print club machine!
In the department store, do they
have a print club machine?
They do.
There's two on the 10th floor, next
to the stairs for the restaurant...
That's it.
The stores are closed, but
the restaurants are still open.
Sonoko-kun was headed up there to use
the elevator to make her way back down!
All right!
Takagi, get the lights in the building back on!
Megure and Satou, take the elevator
and search from top to bottom.
The others, take the stairs and search bottom to top
in order to secure this girl and seize the culprit!
Yes, sir!
Out of the way!
Move it!
Man, the Inspector seems fired up!
It's no wonder.
This case has reminded him of the
first case he was involved in.
By the way, where's your daughter
and the boy with glasses?
Found it!
This is...
It's Sonoko's cell phone, no mistake!
Since the customers in the restaurants
haven't seen them...
Sonoko-chan must've run into the department stores.
Hey, Takagi, where're the lights?
You girls are demons.
That's right.
You disguise yourselves as cute girls in order to
commit crimes—you're nothing but little demons.
Demons have no right to live!
A blackout?
Damn it!
Why now?
Sonoko?
Sonoko, where are you?
Wait a second.
It sounds like a number of things
are falling simultaneously.
Sand?
Rice?
No, something bigger...
Could it be those little stones you put in a fish tank?
The pet shop is on the 4th floor.
That must mean she's on the 4th floor.
Let's go check.
Restaurant Floor
Books & Beauty, Photos, Denistry
Food, Housewares, CDs, Stationary
Children's Apparel, Clocks, Glasses, Toys
Misses & Plus Site Wornen's Apparel
Forgive me.
I only intended to teach you a little lesson.
But you just had to go and see...
My face.
Sonoko?
That's weird, there's no one in the pet shop.
That's strange...
Nothing's broken and there's nothing on the floor.
Could it have been...
That sound from before...
You just had to see my face!
The Inspector...
Does it...
Feel good?
Hey!
I asked if hurting others feels good to you.
You may think you're punishing evil
and being a bringer of justice, but...
This is just a high school girl who
wanted to put things in a car.
You did this not for the sake of seeking
justice nor for avenging your son.
You did it solely out of rage.
For you it was just a conceited, meaningless
diversion that trifled with people's lives.
Don't you get it!?
I just wanted that woman to apologize...
For her to wear proper shoes and
apologize to my son in heaven...
That's all I wanted...
That really was true in the beginning...
Really...
Sonoko!
Ran!
Are you all right?
You're not hurt?
I was so scared!
Inspector, how did you know they were here?
Well...
I was led here...
By these Go stones.
Inspector, are you all right?
It's nothing to worry about.
It's just my old wound reopening.
An old wound from the past...
Midoridai Police Hospital
He got that wound from a previous case?
Yeah.
Megure hides the scar by wearing that hat.
But for a police officer, a scar is like a badge of honor.
He should be proud.
It was more than twenty years ago.
Right, it was back when Megure
was still a rookie on the force.
You may have heard about it.
The case where someone was
running over high-school girls.
Oh, yes.
The culprit had been bullied by an all-girls gang.
He was running them down in his car at
night, when there was no one around.
He targeted female delinquents
who wore long, tight skirts...
Ones they'd converted from their
school uniforms to be their style.
At first, he only made light contact with them...
But then it escalated and resulted in a fatality.
We warned all students not to wear that style of
skirt, so the case was settled for a while, until...
A high school girl showed up
wanting to be used as a decoy.
She wanted to find her friend's killer at any cost.
Of course we tried to stop her, but it seemed
she despised the police, so she insisted.
With no other choice, I assigned
Megure to keep an eye on her, but...
The culprit tried to run over and kill
both Megure and the girl with his car.
Luckily, Megure remembered the car number, so the
suspect was caught very quickly—but at a high price.
Megure only hit his head, but the girl's
entire body was gravely injured...
By the time we arrived, she was covered
in blood, and barely breathing.
So the reason why the Inspector
has always kept his hat on...
Yeah, that's right.
He doesn't want others to ask him about the scar.
He's always been reminded of that horrible case.
That's why Megure wears that
hat—to seal away that scar.
The scar that symbolizes that tragic memory.
So that's why the Inspector was against using decoys.
He didn't want anyone else to die like that girl...
Hey, hey!
I only said that she was gravely injured!
Not that she died!
In fact, she's Megure's—
Oh, Superintendent Matsumoto!
It's an honor to have you come all the way here.
Megure Midori
Megure's Wife
Shiratori-san and Takagi-san just left a few moments ago.
Oh, they came by as well?
Yeah, they all took a breather from work.
A scar on her forehead?
Don't tell me...
Hey, Midori!
Can you peel this apple for me?
My, he enjoys being spoiled, as always.
Looks like I'll have to toughen him up
so he can return to the force soon!
Yes, if you would, please!
Come to think of it, the Inspector said his wife,
Midori-san, was a delinquent in the past.
Could it be that the real reason he wears that hat...
Is because he doesn't want others to
make fun of how he and his wife met?
Heeey, not done yet?