A museum? Isn't that a bit unusual for him?
Aren't you curious to see what he looks like?
I'm sure he's a beautiful older man!
Like Harrison Ford, John Lennon, or maybe Brad Pitt...
I heard he collects famous jewelry from all over the world and holds exhibitions.
And I hear that you get to see the biggest black pearl in the world.
You mean the Black Star, the black pearl that is said to bring happiness?
Three steel crows in the dark of the night...
And two more beyond that...
Oh, wow.
Kaito Kuroba (17)
They've even got an armored vehicle ready...
That's the police for ya!
They've sure gone all-out!
Don't, Master Kaito...
I have an uncomfortable feeling about this project...
Kōnosuke Jii (61)
If you're cornered like before, and if something should ever happen to you,
I, as your steward, wouldn't be able to apologize to Tōichi-sama before his altar...
Geez.
You're always like this before a big project!
Gimme a break, will you?
Here.
But, Master Kaito...
Besides, tonight I'm not the son of Tōichi Kuroba, the magician whom you served as steward for,
nor am I Kaito, a second-year high school student.
I'm the one who everybody's talking about.
A villain putting on a show.
M-Master Kaito...
SHIN'ICHI KUDŌ VS. KAITŌ KID
GREAT DETECTIVES, ASSEMBLE!
Ekoda High School
Too easy. Way too easy.
The next job is a piece of cake that I could complete with the tip of my pinky...
"Kid garners legions of fangirls!" That's amazing!
Aoko Nakamori (17)
To hell with legions of fangirls!
To me, it's like he's trying to become the biggest loser in the universe!
Oh, calm down.
It's not like that dumb gumshoe of a dad you've got is ever gonna beat him or anything.
After all, he's...
One!
Two!
Three!
An amazing phantom thief that can't be chained!
The final episode of Star Wars's gonna come out before that Inspector even comes near arresting him!
Shut up! Just because you look like Kid and can do some magic, you're always sticking up for him!
He just abandons or returns everything he steals!
That's not being a gentleman—it's just smug!
My.
Akako Koizumi (17)
That's exactly why I like him.
He's charmingly cute, like a mischievous little boy.
Oh, Akako-chan! Akako-chan!
Don't let him deceive you! That guy's nothing but a criminal, and that's all there is to it!
Besides, you saw on the news what Kid's after next, didn't you?
Oh, you mean the old clock tower in front of the station?
Right! That belongs to everyone here in this town!
You'd have to be pretty awful to go and steal something like that!
Yes, I guess so...
B-Besides...
That clock tower is...
Keiko Momoi (17)
But I heard the clock tower was going to be moved somewhere else soon anyway.
It's going to be used as a landmark for some theme park...
Keiko...
Everybody was saying that if it's gotta go, it might as well be taken away by Kid.
Two wrongs don't make a right!
Hey, I don't know what you're up to.
But I really think you should call off the job you're planning to carry out this time.
How many times do I gotta tell you? I'm not Kid!
"When the 20,000th song is sung from the historic tower whence it carries,"
"the demon of light will fly from the east and strike down the sinner in white, for whom the bell tolls disaster."
Is that supposed to be my fortune or something?
It's no mere fortune.
It's a prophecy imparted to me by the devil, Lucifer.
L-Luci—
The day that clock sounds its bell for the 20,000th time is the night
that you warned you'll be carrying out your deed.
Whether or not you believe me is up to you, though!
Clock Tower
Ginzō Nakamori (41)
Metro Police Investigation Division 2 Inspector
All patrol cars and helicopters around the clock tower:
Report any sightings of suspicious people to me immediately!
To the guards in each block of the tower:
Nobody gets through without my explicit approval!
Guard the post that you're assigned to with your entire heart and soul!
But, Inspector Nakamori...
Is Kid really going to show up?
His warning went like this, right?
"On Saturday night, underneath the full moon, I will appear before you at the stroke of midnight"
"to take the towering clock from your side."
"Kaitō Kid."
But you'd need a crane to steal something that big...
You idiot!
If he says he's gonna steal it, he's gonna steal it!
The hands of the clock...
Futoshi Takarada (53)
Clock Tower Owner
50 years ago, as mayor, my father spent a fortune
to have them crafted by a famous clockmaker overseas.
The hour hand of the clock, along with the signature of the designer,
has several large diamonds embedded in it.
It is a highly valued work of art.
I'd bank on those being what he's after.
Why'd you let the owner through?
I'm sorry!
He insisted that he wanted to check out the security conditions himself!
I sure hope you checked thoroughly whether he is really the owner?
Of course.
Whatever you do...
Whatever you do, please protect it!
I inherited this clock tower from my late father,
so please protect it from the clutches of that petty thief and his ridiculous heist notice.
We'll get it done.
I'm counting on you.
By the way, Inspector.
I haven't seen Police Superintendent Hakuba's son Saguru-kun around lately...
He said something about having some unfinished case to take care of and went back to London.
We sure could've used his help.
You idiot!
I'm so sorry!
We can't depend on that costume-wearing freak every freaking time!
Only 28 minutes and 30 seconds until the promised time...
All right...
Well then, Sergeant Yōichi Sensui from Ekoda, 27 and single...
I'm going to borrow your name and face for a while.
Excuse me.
That's an amazing crowd.
Oh, sir! How's everything inside?
Sujio Hosokawa (32)
Subordinate of Takarada
Perfect.
Not even an ant could sneak through.
B-But...
I wonder if everything is okay on the amusement park's side...
They said that if we don't start transportation by tomorrow,
it'll be too late to have the tower ready for opening day,
and they'll have to cancel the purchase!
And if Kid steals the jewels from the hour hand, and he finds out they're—
We're the only ones who know that I sold off the diamonds and switched them for fakes.
Besides, now that everyone knows Kaitō Kid's after it,
its price has jumped high, so it's the best time to sell it!
Whether they find out after the clock tower's moved or not is none of my concern.
Besides, it would never be stolen!
Besides, great and elusive thief he may be,
but how could he ever steal that enormous clock tower in front of all these people?
Stay out, Kid!
Give it to him, Dad!
Hey! Hey, Aoko!
You're the only one rooting against him here!
I know, but...
Oh yeah, Keiko, have you seen Kaito?
No.
He said something about watching a magic show on TV tonight.
Oh...
I guess I'm the only one who remembers something that happened that long ago.
What?!
You saw somebody who looked like Kid while on patrol?!
Yes, sir!
He dropped this suspicious-looking hat and left!
T-This is Kid's silk hat and cape!
Will you wait here a while...
Yes, sir!
Inspector Nakamori, please.
Yes, the silk hat and cape are here.
Yes.
Yes, it seems so.
Okay! I've got approval from the Inspector!
Please go explain the circumstances at the time and the man's features
that you saw directly to the Inspector at the top floor!
Yes, sir!
That was easy!
Without Hakuba around, this is so easy that it ain't even fun!
Here they come, Mistress.
Yes, there's no doubt about it.
It's that helicopter.
He puts out a strong and pure vibe, just like Kuroba-kun.
He has the cunning of the devil, and keen eyes that can see people's hearts for what they are.
Who is he?
Hey, what's going on?!
There's an extra helicopter!
It's another support helicopter sent over by the Police HQ.
Support from HQ?
I don't remember asking for anything like that!
Ah, Kid's silk hat.
Yeah, I was told you'd come.
But please show me your police notebook and license, just to be sure.
Y-Yes, sir.
Please give me your name, age, and date of birth.
Yōichi Sensui, 27 years old.
Born June 2nd.
Okay, good work.
Inspector Nakamori's waiting for you on the top floor.
Yes, sir!
Right, just in case, give me your driver's license number.
Okay.
It's 628605-524810, sir!
I-It's Kaitō Kid!
Get him!
Seriously?!
What?
You found Kid in the building?!
Yes, sir! Groups C and D are in pursuit!
Hey, are you sure he's the real deal?
Yes, it's certain. After he answered his name, age and birth date,
I remembered to ask him for his driver's license number, and voila!
His driver's license number?
Yes.
The boy HQ sent said a disguise expert would probably memorize things normal people wouldn't.
A boy?
I repeat.
Please seal off all entrances and exit the clock tower immediately!
Don't open them until I give the word!
He's just a bird in a cage with his wings clipped now.
This is group D, Nakamura and Kawada. We've lost sight of the target near the 3rd floor toilet!
Please calm down. I'm sure he's still near you.
Has the air vent in one of those toilets been unscrewed?
It has!
Yes, it has!
That's where you'll find him then!
Keep up the pursuit!
Found him!
Hey, hey, hey!
The Inspector's really on the ball today!
Or is somebody helping him out?
But who could it be?
Megure!
So it was you!
What do you think you're doing, bringing a brat in here like this?
I'm the commanding officer here!
You're not even part of this division!
Oh, sorry, sorry.
I promised him I'd let him board this helicopter once.
So I figured I might as well bring him along—
Inspector.
I hate to be rude, but we don't have time to argue.
If you want to catch that thief, please do as I say.
What?!
He's been exposed before pulling off his heist. He'll be unsettled,
since his plan is falling apart.
This is the best chance to make the arrest!
Who are you?!
Who the hell are you?!
Me?
I'm Shin'ichi Kudo.
Shin'ichi Kudō (17)
Detective.
Shin'ichi Kudo?
Oh, I've heard of him.
He's a high school detective who's been solving baffling murder cases, one after another.
Then this isn't your division either!
We're after a phantom thief here!
Inspector.
He's a high school student, he doesn't have a divi—
Either way, this is a job for the police!
An outsider like you should just stay put in that helicopter of yours!
Inspector Nakamori!
Nakamura from Group D, after receiving word from the boy,
discovered Kid disguised as a police officer inside an air vent!
They're still in pursuit!
What?!
This is Nakamura from Group D! It seems the target's trying to exit the ventilation duct!
What should we do?
Don't panic.
Your target's already in your grasp.
Please tell me your present location.
Well...
I've been moving along in the dark, so I'm not sure.
I know I went up one flight of stairs from the 3rd floor, so this is the 4th floor.
No problem.
The exits from all 28 ventilation ducts within the building have already been secured.
Please keep pursuing him.
He has no escape route.
The officers who are blocking the ventilation ducts' exits on the 4th floor should get ready to arrest him!
How dare you order my men around...
This is Nakamura of Group D.
I lost sight of him near the ventilation duct's exit!
What's your present location?
This is...
The corridor to the east on the 4th floor!
The target abandoned his officer disguise and is fleeing down the stairs! Requesting backup!
K-Kaitō Ki—
Good work.
All right! He panicked and ditched his officer disguise!
Officers on the third and fourth floors, don't let him get away!
But how does that boy in the helicopter have so much information about the clock tower's structure?
That's because I sent him the data!
You idiot.
That's strange.
By discarding that disguise in an area full of officers,
he's like a hermit crab disposing of its shell, crawling defenseless across the sea floor.
It makes no sense.
I-It's time, Inspector Nakamori.
Yeah.
I-Inspector!
Smoke came out of the scaffolding!
What?!
Inspector Nakamori!
The clock's hands!
They're gone!
What?! They're gone?!
Amazing! Kid is amazing!
Kid...
Kid, you jerk!
Is something wrong?
It's swaying?
You mean the helicopter's swaying?
No, Inspector.
Oh.
Where are you going, Inspector?
I'm going up to check the clock's engine room!
Excuse me, but could you please bring the helicopter closer to the clock tower?
Damn it, what's going on?!
Anything new?
No.
W-What the...?
Hey, what happened?
A police officer appeared from the ventilation duct and...
What?
He sprayed something weird at us and went out that way.
It can't be.
If he had, he'd be clearly visible from the outside.
Kaitō Kid!
Kid...
It's me, Nakamori! I found Kid! He's—
Inspector Nakamori.
I apologize for not having the time to play with you all.
W-What?!
It would seem you have a Joker in your hand this time.
In my hand?
And if you must call someone here, do so after cracking
the code carved into the center of the clock's face.
Code?
Yes.
I'd appreciate it if you deciphered it before calling anyone.
The clock's face is swaying?
What does this mean, Kudo-kun?
He's lighting up the clock's face along with the smokescreen.
After turning off the light, the clock's face was covered with a giant screen that'd been set up beforehand.
And a film of the clock without its hands was projected onto the screen.
The film is being projected from a projector that's been assembled onto a foothold at the scaffolding.
But that trick's pretty easy to figure out.
Yes. That trick...
...is just a ruse.
He's probably behind the screen right now removing the diamonds embedded onto the hour hand.
Let me borrow this for a bit.
Hey? Who fired?!
Damn!
With the helicopter this close, my hang-glider won't get me anywhere!
Now what?
Now what do I do?
H-Hey, Kudo-kun!
Don't worry.
I won't hit anyone!
That's not the problem, Kudo-kun!
Now for the finale of this magic show. It's time to meet the man behind the curtain!
He's something all right.
He fell onto the crowd along with the screen.
Finding him in that crowd's pretty much impossible.
Megure here.
Hey, Megure!
Did you just shoot at me?!
No, it wasn't me.
By the way, Inspector, did he leave any message with you?
Yeah, he said something about a code.
A code?
I can't make heads or tails of this.
Was this really carved in the center of the clock's face?
Yeah.
Either way, it's important evidence.
We'll have to make them postpone moving the clock tower until the code's deciphered.
I don't need you to tell me that!
All's well that ends well, I guess.
The clock tower's safe, and his heist ended in failure.
I wouldn't go that far, Inspector Megure.
He left a code in the clock's face and left the clock tower for the police to take care of,
stealing away the owner's plans to relocate it .
It says so in the code.
If you change the katakana to romaji, and move the vowels one space each clockwise, you get...
kono kane no ne wa watasenai
"This bell shall not toll for you".
By the way, Inspector Megure, I never did find out the thief's name...
Oh well, who cares?
Are you waiting for someone too?
I'm supposed to meet up with my dad.
But he said he might be busy with work, so we might not be able to go.
Here.
I'm Kaito Kuroba. Nice to meet you!
Kaito!
How would I ever forget that, you dope?
Is something wrong, Master?
All your worrying got me reminiscing, Jii-chan!
That clock tower job was full of close calls.
What did become of that clock tower?
Oh, yeah. You didn't know since you moved.
So they did move it after all.
Three!
Two!
One!
This bell...
The police investigated afterwards and found out that the diamonds were fake,
so the city bought the clock on the cheap.
Okay, time to get going!
The objective is a Big Jewel.
A jewel in the possession of the Suzuki Financial Group, the Black Star!
Master, I know it's too late to stop you.
But as Tōichi-sama always said...
When you face the audience, you step onto a battlefield.
You must never be overconfident or underestimate them,
but see through their hearts and minds instead.
Pay full attention to your hands to utilize all your skills, but maintain your smile and elegance all the while...
And no matter what happens, never forget your poker face, right?
Master...
I'm home!
You got mail.
Oh, what's this? It gives me the creeps.
What is it, Ran?
What's the matter?
Look at this.
It says "Kogoro Mouri-sama" in calligraphic white letters on a black envelope.
Doesn't have a stamp or the name of the sender.
It's probably just some kind of "join us" advertising thing.
You think so?
Let's see.
"In honor of your wisdom, we would like to invite you to a formal gathering."
See, just as I said.
I bet they're just trying to add some class to their party by inviting a Great Detective.
I don't think so.
Because look at this.
It fell out of the envelope. It says "2 million yen", right?
2... million yen?!
Wouldn't it be weird to send something like this just for that?
And they don't even know if you're coming or not.
Hey, Dad.
Isn't the name of the sender somewhere inside?
Huh? What's this?
"The Phantom of the Child Forsaken by God"?
What's that about?
The Phantom of the Child Forsaken by God...
A strong heart's deductive power gets to the true essence of everything with an intense rhythm.
The curtains of the 21st Century open for Conan!
Six detectives follow Kid's trail!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Conan, can you check the tire over on that side?
What's wrong, Dad?
The tire on this side is completely flat.
It's flat?
What a bummer.
There's no spare, either, damn it!
Hey, Uncle.
What is it?
Look at that.
There's a petrol station over there!
Talk about lucky!
There's a Buddha in Hell indeed!
Damn it. Shortcut, my eye!
Why did I listen to that old man at the petrol station?
Hey, Dad.
Is this really the right way?
Of course!
He took me into his stand and sold me this really expensive map 'cause he said it had this area in detail!
If this ain't the right road, that geezer's gonna pay for it!
Looks like we're back on a real road!
Hey, it was a shortcut!
Isn't that it, on the right?
The Sunset Manor we're heading for.
That's a pretty eerie looking building.
Looks more like Castle Dracula than Sunset Manor.
Dad, are we really going in there?
Don't be stupid.
They sent me an invitation to a banquet "in honor of my wisdom"
and a check for two million yen. How could I refuse?
But wasn't the invitation signed with some creepy phrase?
Oh, that child forsaken by God thing.
Don't worry about it.
It's just somebody bluffing nonsense.
I wonder.
Hey, maybe we shouldn't go!
We've already come this far!
But what if Dracula shows up for real?
Don't be ridiculous.
There's no such thing as Dracula in Japan!
If there was anything, it'd be uh...
A mountain witch.
A-A mountain witch!
That's some way to greet a woman on a first meeting.
My apologies.
Granny, what are you doing out in a place like this?
Isn't it obvious?
My sweet little Fiat has broken down.
I've been waiting for someone to pass by.
You're going to the Sunset Manor too, aren't you?
If it's not too much trouble, would you give me a lift?
Yeah, why not?
You can sit in the back.
And while we're at it, would you please move my things from my Fiat into your car?
All right.
Sorry for the bother.
Hey, Dad, are we still going to take long?
It's still gonna take a bit to get there, but why? Is something wrong?
I have to use the toilet!
Oh, geez.
Young lady, I don't mean to intrude.
But the headmaster of my primary school always used to say
that success comes to those who seize the day,
while those who let a golden opportunity pass by will never get a second chance.
So why didn't you go to the lavatory back at the petrol station?
How'd you know that, granny?
That we'd stopped at the petrol station, I mean.
It's pretty easy, little one.
Look at the empty ashtray and the still-new cigarette butts on the floor.
The ashtray was so stuffed that cigarette butts were falling out,
so the gentleman must be a heavy smoker.
But now it's empty.
The only place you could've cleaned it out recently was that petrol station you passed 10 km ago.
A man kind enough to give a strange old lady a lift
would never throw his cigarettes out of the window of his car in front of his daughter.
Who are you, granny?
I'm Furuyo Senma.
Furuyo Senma (63)
Detective
A detective just like you, Mr. Sleeping Kogoro.
Furuyo Senma?
That famous detective who can solve a cases just by sitting down in an armchair?
Oh, flattering an old lady will get you nowhere.
That's her?!
Well, I'll hang on to this ashtray of yours for the moment.
Hey, wait!
Don't smoke in front of me, even after we reach the manor.
I despise cigarette smoke.
Oh, damn it.
There's Sunset Manor up ahead. Step on the gas!
Let's see.
Dad, open the back, please!
Whoa. Up close, it looks even more like a haunted house.
Dad, I'm going inside.
Okay.
Toilet, toilet...
Whoa, check out these fancy cars!
Yeah...
A Benz, a Ferrari and a Porsche.
It's certainly full of dangerous cars.
Isn't that an Alfa Romeo?
That's classy!
Hey!
Hands off my girl!
It took me five years to tame that shrew.
I don't want her to get upset by another man touching her.
Got it, whiskers?
W-Whiskers?
Long time no see, Mogi-chan!
So you were invited too, huh?
Oh, Granny Senma!
Does that mean you were invited too?
Mogi?
Harufumi Mogi (39)
Detective
He's Detective Harufumi Mogi!
Are you all right?
I read in the papers that you'd been shot by the mafia in Chicago last week.
That's old news. I don't think about the past.
You're not still a bachelor, are you?
You're turning 40 in just three days...
I don't think about the future either.
All I need now is a little grub to silence my moaning gut.
Welcome.
Mogi-sama, Mouri-sama and Senma-sama, right?
We've been waiting for you.
Please come in.
This looks like...
...a haunted house, right?
Please put your umbrellas here.
All right.
Hey, you!
Yes, sir!
Please excuse me.
I just went to the kitchen, but...
If I recall correctly, he's...
The gourmet detective.
Shukuzen Ōgami.
What?!
Shukuzen Ōgami (51)
Detective
The cook's fallen ill and can't come in today?!
This isn't what I was promised!
I've come all this way to enjoy a banquet!
I'm very sorry, sir. The ingredients are ready, but...
Then lead me to the kitchen! I'll make the meal!
Gastronomy and murder are the only disciplines that can occupy my prodigious mind!
Geez.
I'm so sorry to have kept you waiting!
What's the meaning of this? Calling four detectives to an old house in the mountains...
Not quite.
We actually invited six detectives altogether.
C'mon now.
You're telling me there are two more?
Yes, a woman and a teenage boy.
A teenage boy? Could it be Shin'ichi?
No way.
It's probably Heiji-niichan.
No. Those two were on the invitation list I received from my master,
but I couldn't get in touch with Kudo-sama,
and Hattori-sama's mother told me he wouldn't be attending
because he has to study for his midterms.
Since those two couldn't come, the master allowed Mouri-sama to bring two members of his family.
So where is this crazy detective lover anyway?
I don't know. I haven't met him in person yet.
But you got the list from him, didn't you?
Yes, when I interviewed for my position as his maid.
But it was a very strange interview.
Strange?
Aki Ishihara (23)
Maid
Yes.
The job paid very well, so there were many applicants.
But when I entered the interview room,
all I found were a PC, a letter instructing me about the banquet, and a list of people to invite.
There was nobody in the room.
So I was left with no choice but to read the papers as instructed on the PC.
Then suddenly I heard a noise, and the words "you're hired" showed up on the screen.
Then you don't even know why you were hired?
No.
But you've talked to him since then, right? You just said you got your master's approval.
Well, all our conversations have been through e-mail on my mobile phone.
This sounds really interesting. The thrill's killing me!
I was already electrified the moment I saw that funny pattern on that door.
It does look pretty strange.
I wonder what it's a pattern of.
Be careful, baby.
If I'm not mistaken, that's probably the remains of an old bloodstain.
No way!
You're joking, aren't you?
No, they're real.
Specifically, a blood spatter that struck the door at an entry angle of roughly 45°.
Not just the door, either.
There are old bloodstains on the wall, streaming downward.
And there are blood droplets on the floor.
And although they were wiped away,
there are bloodstains here and there throughout the whole mansion.
It looks like these bloodstains don't belong to just one or two people.
You are indeed impressive.
Luminol.
Spray it onto blood, and active oxygen inside the blood will oxidize it,
giving off a bluish-purple fluorescent light.
3-aminophtalhydrazide
You make good deductions, former coroner Ikumi Sōda-san.
Ikumi Sōda (29)
Detective
I'm flattered to hear that, kid.
Saguru Hakuba (17)
Detective
I'm Saguru Hakuba.
A pleasure.
Hakuba?
You mean you're Police Superintendent Hakuba's—
Quite so. Police Superintendent Hakuba is indeed my father, Mouri-san.
A falcon?
Oh, I do apologize for startling you.
In the time we've spent together in England, Watson here seems to have picked up a fancy for blood.
"Watson"?
I'm truly glad I came back home, though.
After forty years, I am finally able to step inside the scene of the tragedy
that I had heard of only in frightened whispers.
That's more than enough to arouse my intellectual interest.
Tragedy?
Oh, no.
You're pretty good.
Why, thank you, good sir.
How about this, Mr. Sleeping Kogoro?
All right!
Look, look, I've got a straight!
I win again!
She sure is as strong as ever.
Hold it!
No cheating now, Ran-chan.
See, that Jack on your left.
There's another card stuck to it, see?
Oh, you're right.
I'm sorry, I didn't notice.
But I think they were stuck together this whole time...
What's the matter, Ran?!
There's blood on the playing card!
Oh, my, my! Blood has splattered there too, I see.
Come to think of it, the maid was saying
that the things here are just as they were at the time of the crime.
That practically nothing has been moved.
Then whatever happened happened in this room too?
Thank you all for waiting.
The banquet is ready. My master awaits you in the dining room.
So, the big boss finally makes his appearance...
I can't wait to see him.
I think I lost my appetite.
Here we are.
Please go on inside.
Hey, hey!
What's with the costume?
I think you've been watching too much TV.
Six of the world's most magnificent detectives!
Welcome to the Sunset Manor!
Please have a seat.
Bring out the dishes in the order I instructed.
Oh, yes, sir...
I've invited all of you here to see if you can figure out
where in this house I have hidden my treasure.
It's the entire enormous fortune I've gathered over the years.
Oh, and your lives are at stake.
O-Our lives?!
What was that sound?!
Don't be alarmed.
I've just rid you of your means of escape.
What?!
I'm always getting chased around by the likes of you.
So I thought I'd chase you for a change.
I also destroyed the only bridge,
so even if your cars weren't scrap, you'd have no way out.
As I'm sure you can guess, this house has no phone line, and we're well out of mobile range.
So you can't get any outside help.
Right.
This is a game. I will give half of my treasure to the detective who finds it,
and I'll also show the winner how to leave this mansion.
What do you say?
I say baloney. I don't cozy up to cowards who sneak around in masks!
Come now, you can't play on an empty stomach.
Please enjoy the dinner to your heart's content—your last supper.
It's just a dummy with a speaker in it!
That dirty...
Who...
Who could be behind all this?!
My...
I can't believe a man like you, Mouri-san, would come here not knowing that.
It was written on the invitation, wasn't it?
"The Phantom of the Child Forsaken by God."
A phantom, somebody who appears out of thin air like a ghost...
The word "child" in the sentence was written with the character亻attached to the left.
So it refers to the child of a beast, as this character is used to write words like "pony" and "puppy".
The animal forsaken by God is the goat,
the animal separated from the sheep in the New Testament.
The line is referring to a baby goat.
And in English, a baby goat is called...
A "kid"...
W-What?!
Maybe it'll be clearer if I put it this way.
H-Hey, don't tell me...
Don't tell me...
Right.
That young thief who spirits valuables away like magic.
The mastermind who baffles the police with as many faces and voices as the stars in the sky.
The main dish that all detectives are dying to spear on the end of a fork.
A villain putting on airs that I can't wait to throw in the clink.
And the only person who ever got the best of me.
When the crowds see his white cape fluttering in the night, they all shout...
Kaitō Kid!
Kaitō Kid...
He sure is an honest guy.
The moment his name came up, he gave us a hint about his identity.
It's that cool style of his.
He's here in this mansion... I'm sure of it.
I don't know what you're up to...
But can you fool us all? You're up against seven master sleuths...
Are you saying that Kaitō Kid invited us to this banquet?
It seems that he gathered the six of us here to compete intellectually,
as have a reputation of being good detectives.
At stake are all the treasures he's stolen, and our lives.
He's probably somewhere watching us right now.
I noticed this house was swarming with hidden cameras.
I have brought the hors d'œuvres.
Ah, our so-called last supper.
Excuse me, maid?
Yes?
By any chance did the master tell you to place the food on the table in a certain order?
Why, yes.
I was told to work clockwise from Hakuba-san.
He called this the "last supper", but the game has only just begun. Funny, isn't it?
Come, now. You can't suspect poison. I cooked this myself!
But the forks, knives, spoons, wine glasses and
teacups were all here on the table before we arrived.
And our host chose the seating arrangements.
Saguru Hakuba
Cold-blooded murder isn't his style, but he may have a highly unamusing joke planned for one of us.
I advise all of you to wipe your cups and cutlery with a handkerchief before you eat.
Yeah, I don't like the way this stooge is running the show.
Would you like to do a game of rock, paper, scissors and change seats then?
B-But what if someone ill-fatedly gets the poisoned seat?
That's that, take it as fate, and cry in the coffin.
Oh, no...
This is delicious!
Just as expected of the Gourmet Detective!
You truly are an amazing cook.
I went through a lot of training to satisfy this tongue of mine, so...
Perhaps I was too suspicious.
No.
We can't let our guard down.
Well, people, how do you like the last supper that I prepared for you?
Guess who's back.
I think it's time to tell you why I chose this place for our game. It didn't come cheap.
First, take a look at the plates in front of you.
A bird.
They've all got this creepy logo of a bird with a large beak.
karasu
Isn't this a crow?
Then, could this be...?
Have you figured it out?
That's the millionaire who died a mysterious death a half a century ago.
Ren'ya Karasuma
It's the crest of Ren'ya Karasuma!
R-Ren'ya Karasuma?!
It's not just the flatware. Everything from the doors, flooring and handrails,
down to the chess pieces and the playing cards in the living room,
was specially ordered by Karasuma.
This manor is Karasuma's vacation home.
Or rather, it was a vacation home, until one stormy night 40 years ago,
when this manor house was struck by a blood-chilling tragedy.
You are all fine detectives, so I'm sure you've all noticed the numerous bloodstains.
Right.
It all happened one night 40 years ago, when this house was still beautiful.
Movers and shakers of the business world came here for a private gathering.
It was called a memorial for Ren'ya Karasuma, who had just died at age 99.
But in reality, it was an auction to sell off the priceless art
that Karasuma had collected during his lifetime.
There were over 300 pieces, and the auction was scheduled to continue for three days.
On the second night, that stormy night...
Two men were freezing, and with trembling lips, remarked that they had lost their way in the storm,
and they would like to spend the night until the storm subsided.
At first the auction host was reluctant to let them in,
but the man handed the host over a small parcel in exchange for letting them stay there.
The contents of the parcel seemed to be something like a cigarette,
and the host smoked it as the men instructed him.
Soon he became much friendlier, and let the two men inside.
The other guests who were watching were urged by the two to smoke likewise
and the smoke gradually filled the house.
D-Don't tell me that the parcel was...
Marijuana...
The guests had a enjoyed a merry, boisterous time for a while,
but after a while things began to change.
A man screamed as if he had seen the devil,
carried the item that he had bid for and now owned, and ran...
A woman started crying as if asking someone for forgiveness until her tears dried out.
Yet another man happily stabbed himself in the arm time and again with the pen that he was holding.
Soon people began to fight for the works of art.
They used antique swords from the auction to kill each other.
The elite gathering turned into a vision of hell.
When the nightmare ended, the two men disappeared with the art,
leaving eight dead and
over ten people in a coma.
But why wasn't a case this big made public?
I imagine that gathering included people with powerful relatives and political connections.
I see.
It wasn't clear who killed whom.
They must have thought it would be better to cover it up than to get the police involved.
I bet that was the crooks' plan from the start.
Well, that was certainly pleasant dinner conversation.
Do you understand now why I chose this place?
I want you detectives to reenact the tragedy that occurred here 40 years ago.
That ugly scene of people fighting over the treasure and killing each other.
What foolishness.
I figure it's too cruel to make you all just search blindly all throughout this building,
so let me give you a hint.
H-Hint?
On the night the two travelers looked up at the sky, a demon appeared in the castle,
and the king ran wild with his treasure in hand.
The queen wept for forgiveness, her tears falling into the Holy Grail,
and the knight killed himself with his own sword.
That must be...
It took some time for me to come up with a riddle that fit the tragedy of this mansion.
But don't you think it's perfect for the deadly game you're about to play?
It's absurd.
You can't just order us to kill each other. We have to be willing to play.
You cannot walk out of this game.
After all, you are all under the spell I have cast over you.
Now, the game will start when someone screams.
Don't forget...
The one who finds the treasure must enter the location of the treasure in the computer
that is in the room on the fourth floor in the center tower.
Then I promise to give you half the treasure and tell you the way out of here.
M-Mogi-san!
Mogi-san, are you all right?!
J-Just kidding!
What a bad old man you are, really...
Sorry, sorry...
As a token of my apology, I'm out.
I've got no interest in treasure hunts.
But how do you intend to get out of here?
Don't worry.
We're not castaways on an island, you know.
If I have to, I'll hike all the way down the mountain.
See you all later then, detectives!
Hey, old man, joke's only funny the first time!
22:34 and 51 seconds. Cardio-respiratory arrest confirmed.
There's no chance of resuscitation.
What?!
His lips are pink. No sign of cyanosis.
His breath has the almond scent that indicates cyanide.
Then the tea the old man was drinking had potassium cyanide in it?
No, I'm not getting any redox reaction...
Looks like it wasn't in the tea.
Then, what on earth happened to him?
The die has been thrown!
Please do your best to find the treasure
for the sake of Detective Ōgami, who gave his life
to start this game with a bang...
Cut the bull!
While you are still alive...
A cassette tape...
It looks like it was connected to a timer.
A timer?
Were you given an exact time to bring the food out?
Yes, he had specific times for everything. The hors d'œuvres, soup, main dish, dessert...
Then the killer wasn't spying on us and talking through a microphone.
He was just playing a pre-recorded tape.
But now we know two things.
One, the killer intended to kill Ōgami-san from the start, and two, the killer could be among us.
You think the killer's one of us?
Take that tape for instance.
Any of us could've set the tape recorder up beforehand
and pretended to listen as we all ate dinner.
I guess, but...
And sit in this same dining room as Ōgami-san, without us noticing...
He was made to drink the cyanide and poisoned himself to death.
Right in front of our very eyes.
Judging from the tape,
the killer knew exactly when the victim was going to die.
The problem is that there's no sign of any cyanide compounds in the tea
that he was drinking until just before he died.
The poison could have been on the rim of the cup and not in the tea itself.
I don't think so. I saw him take several sips before he died.
But the killer you're all talking about is Kaitō Kid, right?
I thought he never killed people...
Yes. As far as I know, this is the first case.
Well, we ain't gonna get far just flapping our jaws.
Why don't we take a stroll outside
and see if our cars have really been blown up?
Good idea.
There may be a car that escaped the explosion.
Or the explosion could have been a hoax.
My rental car...
My Ferrari seems to be well-done too.
My Alfa and Ōgami's Porsche are history!
Is that Benz yours, then?
No.
I had my nanny drive me here.
Strange.
I came here in Mouri-san's car.
So whose Benz is that?
I think it's the master's car.
It was already parked here when I came in this morning.
Then somebody else is in this house?
Do you think he blew up my car in the back?
The back? You mean you have a car here?
Yes...
The master told me to park my car in the back.
Is there any shortcut to the back gate?!
Through the enclosed garden...
Go to the back gate by going to the left from the kitchen!
Oh, your car's just fine!
Don't you think this is fishy?
That rat probably just forgot to set a bomb in this one!
Well then, why don't I drive out to see if the bridge is standing?
I'll go with you.
I guess I will too.
Me too.
Now, now, too many captains will sink the ship.
True.
We don't want to end up on a phantom ship while we're looking for the Phantom Thief.
Let's toss a coin to see who goes.
I've got some change with me right here.
My, you're pretty well prepared, little one!
It's a rather primitive method.
I guess we've got no choice.
Whoever gets heads...
...will take the car out to the bridge and check it out.
It's me, Mouri-san and Mogi-chan, right?
Please be careful, Dad!
T-That's...
Don't tell me...
Don't tell me!
Come, let's go back inside!
Come on, let's go!
Oh, okay.
This is terrible.
The bridge is completely wiped out.
Hey, granny Senma!
Turn the headlights up so we can see below!
Okay!
Erm, headlights, headlights...
You think the killer will strike again?
Yup.
It's still too early to end this game.
S-Senma-san!
Senma-san!
Senma-san was murdered?!
Yeah... Looks like the jalopy was set to blow if you fiddled with the headlights.
Oh, no...
If we just sit around, we'll all get killed.
Let's search the house and see if we're really alone!
We girls will search together.
That way we can go to the ladies' room as a group.
Hey.
What happened to the pale kid with the bleached hair?
Beats me.
Maybe he's feeding the falcon that he brought along with him?
Get a load of that fancy-lookin' thing.
I see fresh scratch marks on the edge of this piano.
Probably claw marks from the hawk.
Guess the kid's been doing a little solo investigation.
Hey! There's something stuck between the keys!
Is this the secret code that indicates the location of the treasure that he was talking about?!
But why is it mimeographed on rice paper?
Somebody probably printed a whole lot of these when things like photocopiers didn't exist yet,
and for some reason, distributed it to many people.
In other words, everything he told us about the tragedy from 40 years ago and the secret code
indicating the hidden treasure...
It's all a bunch of baloney.
Hey, the piano's wet.
Come to think of it, yes, it is.
It's that dame's luminol.
Then she was here too.
Hey, whiskers, douse the lights!
Quick!
Where's the maid?
She said she'd be waiting in the hall. Could you go take a look?
Oh, okay.
Ms. Maid?
Ms. Maid?!
Letters written in blood on the piano!
So something really did happen 40 years ago.
I finally got my hands on the trump card that will decipher Karasuma's riddle.
A trump card...
Don't tell me...?!
So it was you after all.
The killer wouldn't risk getting into a car with a bomb in it.
That leaves Ran-san, the maid, you and me—the ones who stayed behind.
Careful where you point that, young man.
I found it under my pillow in my room.
You were planning to pin the crime on me, were you?
Oh, what a coincidence.
I was thinking exactly the same thing.
I made the exact same deduction as you.
A-A gunshot?!
It came from the central tower!
No good...
The bullet's went right through his chest.
Damn it!
The stairs!
S-Somebody's using the stairs!
Damn it!
A PC?
This must be where we're supposed to come if we find the treasure.
S-Sōta-san!
Take a look!
Turn the knob from the inside and a needle pops out!
Any mook who came here to enter their answer
would get a poisoned needle in the palm when they tried to leave.
But where on earth is the killer?!
Cut the act!
There's no way the dame would walk into a trap she set herself.
And I found your daughter and the maid out cold in the hall.
I'm guessin' that gunshot was a red herring.
The only people who could've done this were you and me...
...and it ain't me.
That just leaves you.
The suspects must be punished.
No hard feelings...
Mr. Sleepin' Kogoro.
That's impossible!
As I suspected, not even the greatest detectives can solve this riddle.
My hidden camera! It shut off!
What?!
I have the solution to the riddle.
Somebody is inputting data?!
Who on earth could it be?!
I'd like to tell you in person. Come down to the dining room.
I am the seventh detective.
What?!
I have the solution to the riddle.
I'd like to tell you in person. Come down to the dining room.
I am the seventh detective.
T-This can't be...
All the detectives I invited are dead!
There is no seventh detective!
Who is it? Who could have...
You wouldn't think that somebody who rigged a bomb go a car would drive it, barring suicide.
But I can think of a reason.
That's if you wanted to make people think you died in the explosion.
Isn't that right...
Detective Senma?
That's right. You got out of the car and hid behind a bush just before the explosion.
Then you made your way back here and monitored us
from a room somewhere, using the cameras hidden all over the house.
Don't be silly, child. It's true that I escaped that explosion,
but only because I noticed the bomb at the last minute.
Didn't we toss coins to decide who would ride in the car?
Not really. You knew that you were going to take the car even before the coins were tossed.
You placed a coin with the head facing up on the back of your hand before you tossed the real coin.
You covered your left hand with your right one to hide it,
and pretended to catch the coin that you flicked.
But you actually let the flicked coin drop onto the ground,
and showed the first coin that you'd put on the back of your hand.
No matter how many times we tossed coins, you'd always get heads!
I saw you use a ¥10 coin to test Ōgami-san's tea.
You know a lot of coin tricks, don't you,
Ms. "Phantom of the Child Forsaken by God"?
Are you claiming I'm the host?
The criminal who killed Ōgami-san?
Then, tell me.
How did I make Ōgami-san alone take the cyanide in this dining room,
and just how was I able to predict the time?
There was no poison in his tea.
Mouri-san was sitting in between Ōgami-san and me...
Besides, didn't we do rock, paper, scissors to decide where to sit?
It didn't matter which seats we chose.
Because you put potassium cyanide on everybody's teacup beforehand.
You applied the poison at the spot where the handle meets the cup.
That was exactly where Ōgami-san's right thumb would touch the cup...
including the thumbnail he bites when he's lost in thought.
During the recording, which you made using a voice modulator,
he bit his nail while listening to the riddle about the treasure.
By ordering the maid to bring out the tea just beforehand,
you were able to poison Ōgami-san, and only Ōgami-san,
at the moment you knew he'd be thinking about your riddle.
But I thought we all agreed to wipe off our cups and plates before using them.
Right...
It's awfully careless for Ōgami-san, a famed detective, to have forgotten that.
But if he was your partner in crime and helped you arrange this banquet,
there's nothing strange about him not wiping the cup,
since he never thought he'd be the one killed.
I had my suspicions when I heard the Benz was already parked in front of the house
when the maid arrived.
To leave the Mercedes at this isolated spot, you'd need at least two conspirators:
one to drive the Mercedes here, and one to drive up with a different car and pick the first person up.
By the way, you waited by the side of the road and had us pick you up
so you'd have the chance to tell Detective Mouri not to smoke.
That way, Ōgami-san would be the only one who died.
If Ōgami-san had put a cyanide-coated cigarette in his mouth after grabbing it with his fingertips,
he'd go straight to the afterlife.
You hired the maid because you watched her on a hidden camera during the interview
and noticed that she had a habit of biting her nail too.
and you figured that you could kill her using the same method that you used to kill Ōgami-san.
Right...
You killed Ōgami-san, your accomplice, and made it look as if you'd been killed by someone else,
and tried to psychologically manipulate the other detectives.
Once one of them solved the riddle and found the treasure, you planned to kill the survivors.
Just like Ren'ya Karasuma did forty years ago.
I found the name "Kyōsuke Senma" at the end of the words written in blood on the piano.
That was probably...
That's my father's name.
He was an archaeologist. Forty years ago, he was invited to this house.
A multimillionaire who was over 100 years old
had found a clue leading to a vast fortune left by his mother in a manor he inherited.
He wanted my father to find that treasure before he died of old age.
It was a very well-paid job. My mother and I received large sums of money,
along with a letter from my father, almost every day.
But after six months, the money and letters suddenly stopped coming.
My father, who had never given us his address, vanished forever.
I only found out the truth when I held his last letter, which I had kept as a memento, against a light.
He had written a secret note by poking tiny holes in the paper with a needle.
He recorded the riddle of the treasure and wrote
that many other scholars had been invited to the manor.
He also wrote that Karasuma had begun to kill those scholars one by one,
as a warning to the others...
And that even if he found the treasure, he too would be killed.
Did you tell the police about it?
No, I only found out about the letter written with a needle 20 years later.
Ren'ya had passed on, the Karasuma family had died out, and this house had fallen into other hands.
But two years ago I accidentally let the story slip to Ōgami-san.
He immediately tracked down the house and started to look for the treasure,
but he couldn't solve the riddle.
He had put himself into massive debt to buy the house and was in serious trouble.
So he came up with a plan.
We'll assemble a team of great detectives!
We'll pose as Kaitō Kid as bait to lure them here!
Pretend he's the host of a deadly game!
And during that game, we'll pretend we've both been killed by him!
I know! Why don't we actually kill a maid or something?
Once they think their lives are at stake, they'll put their hearts into it!
Don't worry! Kid will take all the blame!
Then the one who chose that maid was...
Ōgami-san.
He was delighted to come up with a way to kill her based on his own bad habit.
I bet he never imagined he'd die by the same method.
Right. He bit his nails at that time because I'd recorded something he hadn't expected to hear.
He originally planned to kill the maid after dinner.
But why did you kill Ōgami-san?
I realized he was planning to kill me and all the others once the treasure was found.
He was going to make it seem that we'd all gone mad and killed one another using the guns in our rooms.
I had to solve the riddle and stop him at the same time—it was like he was possessed by Karasuma!
So I let the detectives
continue to decipher the code.
But it was the same as 40 years ago...
The riddle can't be solved.
All I did was create another tragedy...
No, I think your father did solve that riddle.
Don't you think it's strange? The only clock in this huge house is the one in the dining room.
So "the night the two travelers looked up at the sky" means midnight,
when the long hand and the short hand of the clock both point up!
Let's try placing the hands at 12.
Now the key to solving this riddle is the word your father wrote in blood, "trump card"!
He was talking about playing cards!
The king, queen and soldier in the riddle stand for the King, Queen and Jack in a deck of cards!
The treasure stands for diamonds, the Holy Grail stands for hearts, and the sword stands for spades.
So "treasure" and "king" means the King of Diamonds!
"Holy Grail" and "queen"
means the Queen of Hearts!
And "sword" and "soldier"
means the Jack of Spades!
First you bring the hands of the clock to 12:00...
Now turn the hands of the clock in the direction the face cards in this house are facing...
13 to the left, 12 to the left and 11 to the right...
The coating came off. There's gold inside.
And it's so heavy...
I get it... This thing is made of solid gold!
My, my...
My father lost his life for a trinket like that, eh?
How anticlimactic...
So, you promised, Senma-san.
Tell me the way out of this place!
There never was a way out.
I always planned to kill myself once the riddle was solved.
Although Ōgami-san did believe me when I told him that I would tell him the way after dinner.
Just as I thought.
Granny Senma...
My best suit... Sheesh...
That's why I objected to this pantomime.
Take your complaints to the little boy.
He's the one who said that she may tell us the way out if a child asked.
You all faked your deaths so I'd talk...
Yeah.
We figured you were planning to kill whoever solved the riddle...
And we had a feeling you wouldn't confess while we were all alive...
And ketchup looks like blood to a camera!
It was my idea to knock out Ran-san and the maid.
This act of bad taste would have been too harsh on the heart of a young dame.
H-How long have you known it was me?
From the time this kid had us choose the coins.
You reached way over to pick up the 10 yen coin at the far end of the hood.
That's when I realized you didn't want anyone else to take the 10 yen coin.
If we'd picked it up with our fingers covered in potassium cyanide,
it'd show a redox reaction and we'd all figure out the trick!
At that point, we all realized you were the culprit and started working together.
I had seen through the trick as soon as I saw Ōgami-san's right thumb nail.
Y-You little brat...
Only problem now is, how do we split from this joint?
What's that sound?
Ah, that's probably the police helicopter I called for.
You what?
I sent Watson with a note to my nanny,
who's waiting in a car at the bottom of the mountain, once the sun came up.
I'm glad that I marked the car with an X so that it'd be able to tell it apart from other cars!
Why didn't you tell us that before?
We wouldn't have had to put on that show...
No. It's not just the sound of the helicopter.
I can hear something crumbling too...
D-Don't tell me...!
So Kaitō Kid was never here after all...
Oh, you wanted him to appear?
Er, no...
Hey, granny.
It was Ōgami's idea to gaslight us, right?
So after you offed him, why'd you go on with his plan and pretend to die?
I wanted you to decipher the riddle my father left for me...
...while I was still alive.
There will never be another time when so many great detectives all come together in one place.
I guess the one possessed by Ren'ya Karasuma was me all along...
G-Granny?!
C-Crap!
Dad!
K-Kaitō Kid?
Say, lady!
Aren't you a little old for this kind of stunt?
Don't be a fool!
I saved you!
What?
Consider it payback for stealing your not-so-good name.
This was the only way you could escape from those two.
Why, that little boy was already aiming at you with that funny watch of his!
So he knew, huh?
The cigarettes.
Kogoro Mouri is a heavy smoker.
But you didn't light up even once after reaching the house, did you?
Who are those kids, anyway?
Sweethearts who I most definitely do not want to have to face, I guess.
How unfortunate.
You came for Karasuma's treasure, didn't you?
Yeah, but I've changed my mind.
That thing's a little too big for a thief's pockets.
The walls are crumbling, and the gold's showin' through.
That clock must have been the switch to peel off the outer wall.
It truly is Karasuma's mansion.
It must be worth a hundred billion yen!
I see...
Sunset means the time when the sky shines gold as the sun goes down.
It's literally a golden manor!
By the way, where's my real dad?
Over here...