Choreography by Miyaji Hirokazu
(TWINSTAR)
Song by Aiuchi Rina
Koi wa Thrill, Shock, Suspense
koi wa thrill, shock, suspense
mienai chikara tayori ni...
kokoro no tobira tozasazu ni tsuyoku... tsuyoku...
A strong heart reinforces reasoning power.
The steady rhythm reveals the truth.
The client is a beautiful woman.
A strange request leads to a case!
Perceiving the one and only truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan.
Original Creator
Aoyama Gosho
『Meitantei Conan』
Serialized in Shogakukan's 「Shounen Sunday」
watashi ga kanjiteita
toge wo kimi nimo onaji
you ni ataeteita no kamoshirenakatta
Planning
Suwa Michihiko
(Yomiuri TV)
Character Design
Sudou Masatomo
Art Director
Shibuya Yukihiro
nani ni kokoro wo itamete nani ni obieteita no ka
Camera Director
Ogawa Takahisa
Sound Director
Kobayashi Katsuyoshi
Music
Oono Katsuo
ki nimo tomezu motsureteyuku futari no shinjitsu ni
Opening Theme
「Koi wa Thrill, Shock, Suspense」
Performer
Lyrics
Composition
Arrangement
Aiuchi Rina
Oono Aika
Ojiro Kyuuryuu
mukiau no ga kowakatta
Editing
Ogawa Takahisa
Story Editor
Iioka Junichi
Color Design
Hirade Mayumi
Production Lead
Kobyashi Hiroaki
This love is thrill, shock, suspense
Planning Support
Tsuzuki Shinichirou
Okuyama Toyohiko
Asai Mitomu
mayoi wo aoi kaze ni chirasou toshitemo kakaekirezu ni ita yo
General Director
Kodama Kenji
Director
Yamamoto Taiichirou
kono chiisa na mune ni wa
kokoro no tobira tozasazu ni
tsugi e to susumu arata na fuan to
Producers
Suwa Michihiko
(Yomiuri TV)
Yoshioka Masahito
(Tokyo Movie)
mayoi wo kakaeteshimaisou ni nattemo
Presented By
Yomiuri TV
Tokyo Movie
THE CLIENT FULL OF LIES
(PART ONE)
You're looking for someone?
Yes, I really must see him.
Sorry, but I'm a little tied up...
Is there anything that can be done?
The truth is, I'm actually near your office already.
If it's OK, I'd like to at least talk...
Lightning!
Lightning has come flying through!
The winner is Lightning!
With that amazing come-from-behind
victory, the final race is over!
Lost again!
Hello?
Mouri-san?
Didn't I just say I was busy!?
Oh, I mean, discussing it would be just fine...
Yes, I'll see you soon.
Do your work already...
Dad!
I know...
Hey, what kind of person called just then?
It was some older woman.
She said she's coming over now.
She'll be like...
"Please help me find my long lost first love!"
She'll definitely be like that...
Come in!
I'm Ikenami, who just called a moment ago.
I apologize for intruding on you so suddenly...
Ikenami Shizuka
Client
My friend claimed that if I asked Mouri-san
for help, we could find him easily.
I very much so hope you'll help me.
Please, come sit down.
She's such a beauty...
Excuse me.
Huh?
Where did Dad go?
My apologies for having you wait...
Madamosielle.
I was busy reviewing some elementary murder case files.
Now, now, please have a seat on the sofa.
Perhaps we may rest your heart before discussing this matter.
Ran?
What about some drinks?
Yes...
It's begun again...
You're looking for a classmate from middle school?
Yes.
We were both involved in kendo as well.
Shouldn't there be an address in the yearbook?
Since he moved before graduation, the
information supplied for him was minimal.
I-It's a man?
I have a photograph from back then.
I'm looking for the one in the center holding the gold cup.
His name is Shibata Shirou.
Could this cute girl next to him be...
I'm afraid that would be me.
This photograph is already thirty years old.
T-Thirty years old!?
That means you're over forty years old?
Yes.
I turn forty-two this year.
But, since this photograph was taken
when he was in the seventh grade...
He's probably a bit taller now.
Can I get a list of hobbies?
Yes...
Let's see, he likes...
No.
I mean yours.
I've always...
Really liked knitting, so I make a lot of sweaters.
That's a perfect hobby!
My mother likes to knit as well!
And you're probably a great cook as well, right?
No, I'm not good at it at all.
I ended up doing this while trying last night.
Well, what does that matter?
Women with weaknesses are more attractive anyway.
Right! Right!
Just like Mom, right?
But, I really have a lot of weaknesses.
That's probably why I'm still single at this age.
You're single!?
It's hard to believe men haven't noticed
such a beautiful and honorable woman.
They must all be blind!
You're really great.
It's just like the person who split from
my mother, what were they thinking?
Hey now...
Excuse me.
Is something wrong?
Do you have a cold?
No, my throat just isn't well right now.
I'm allergic to dust.
I'm sorry.
I was just cleaning, so there's dust everywhere.
Then, we can go elsewhere.
I'm sorry for being troublesome.
A photograph?
You mean...
The reason you want to find this
Shibata-san is to ask for that photograph?
Yes.
The photograph was taken when we were
in eighth grade, on the summer fair day.
It was just a picture of me holding
the championship plaque.
My grandmother accidentally threw
the award away a few days ago...
So I thought about it and was reminded of that photograph.
But, why does Shibata-san have the photograph?
I was using it as a bookmark while reading a
book I borrowed from him and forgot about it.
By the time I realized it, he was already gone.
Then...
You don't want to find him because he's your first love, right?
Right...
And?
Do you have any other information?
Let's see...
Mouri-san, what would you like?
I'll take coffee.
Iced lemon tea for me.
I want...
Reiko.
"Reiko"?
Who is that?
Oh, no...
That's just what he used to call me.
He used to say there was a character named Reiko in the
book he let me borrow that had a personality like mine.
And what will you have, Conan-kun?
Iced coffee for me!
I'll take that as well.
Coming right up.
This definitely isn't enough...
With only his name, age, and a thirty
year old photograph to go on...
Um...
Perhaps I should have used that person's brilliant mind.
That person?
I've heard others mention him...
That high school detective...
They say Kudou Shinichi comes and
goes from your detective agency often.
Shinichi?
Isn't that right, boy?
No, no, that brat won't come.
He only gives us a stupid call every now and then.
I didn't know they were so stupid...
But really...
What if this was noticed...
By them already?
Could they have already deduced this?
Hey, Conan-kun.
What do you think, Conan-kun?
Weren't you about to say something?
What's the point in asking this brat?
But sometimes he notices interesting
things that no one else does.
Oh, nothing really.
I was just thinking...
Since this guy is holding the cup,
he must have got first place, right?
Yeah.
If he was already this good in seventh grade...
He must have attended some sort of recorded
competition at some point, even if he had problems.
But, I don't really get it.
Seriously?
There was a person who participated named Shibata Shirou?
Yes!
Yeah.
Did you find him?
They say he always participates and is usually in the lead.
Right now, he's a physical education
teacher at Shizouka High School.
He lives together with his wife at an apartment building.
I'll go call for a rent-a-car now.
Isn't it great that we've found him?
Yeah, it really is.
Found him...
We've already found who she was looking for, but...
What confuses me is...
This woman full of lies.
She lied about everything she said.
Just what does she want?
Could she be...
Hiding her identity?
Hey, hey, or could she be...
Could this woman be...
Thank you.
It's all thanks to you, boy.
Guess no one's in...
Since it's Sunday, they may have gone out.
Well then, let's head out and come back later.
Hey, wait.
Yoshikawa Takezou (47)
Friend of Shibata Shirou
Are you looking for Shibata-san by any chance?
Yeah.
Hurry it up, then.
He's coming over to my place to play mah-jong later.
But, it doesn't seem like he's home.
That's not possible.
He must just be asleep.
See?
There's sound.
Sounds like a TV.
Really, the door's unlocked, TV's on, and he's asleep...
Hey, Shibata-san!
We're about to get started!
Hey, hey, he only ate half of his food.
Yeah...
The soup is already cold.
So is the rice.
Could this have been breakfast?
What a waste of fresh guji...
Guji?
It's west lake fish.
I'm home.
Dear?
Hey, what are you all doing?
Shibata Kyouko (38)
Wife of Shibata Shirou
You think you can just go into anyone's home?
I'm calling the police!
No...
We're just...
Hey, Shibata-san!
What's wrong!?
Hang in there!
Hey!
What happened!?
Shibata-san!
Hey, hang in there!
There's something in his right hand!
But what?
This is...
Now let's review your statements...
Mouri-san, you four came to visit Shibata Shirou-san
and after ringing the doorbell a number of times...
No one answered?
Yoshikawa-san came to meet Shirou-san
and found the door wasn't locked...
So you entered with the others?
Lastly, there's his wife, Kyouko-san, who
met with Mouri-san moments before.
And then...
Yoshikawa-san found Shirou-san's body in the living room...
Dead, with his head covered in blood.
Is that all correct?
Yeah.
The estimated time of death is some time in the morning.
And where was his wife at this time?
Y-Yes...
I arranged to meet some friends for golf,
who came around 5:00 A.M in their car.
I had prepared him breakfast and left before 5:00.
And, at that time, Shirou-san was home?
Yeah, he came home around 3:00 A.M.
Did you just say 3:00 A.M.?
Y-Yeah...
It's mah-jong.
We were playing mah-jong in my room down on the fourth floor.
As she said, we quit around 3:00 A.M.
And then, there's that newspaper next to his breakfast...
Do you know when it was delivered?
Yes.
It's always delivered to the mailbox at around 6:00 A.M.
I see.
That means Shirou-san...
Got up, collected the newspaper...
And, while he was enjoying his breakfast...
He was attacked and killed.
That's the most likely scenario, isn't it?
What tells you he was eating breakfast then?
It's because some of the food on the
table was eaten, and then it went cold.
But, who is responsible for this?
Who killed my husband?
We're still not sure.
Mouri-san, when you entered...
Did you notice anything peculiar?
Let's see...
The TV was on that whole time...
The TV was!?
Why was it off when we arrived!?
It was a little noisy...
I thought he was just watching TV and eating breakfast, so...
He was most likely watching that show, "The Hero
Sword Legend," which airs every morning at 8:00 A.M.
He records it every week and watches it in the living room.
There definitely are a lot here.
All right!
Check the TV recorder in the kitchen!
Yes, sir!
Hey...
Why isn't the LD player here?
There are LD discs over here...
But there's no player.
Look, isn't this spot particularly empty?
There's only one speaker, too.
That's true...
It must be being repaired.
Right, Miss?
No, actually, my husband...
That has nothing to do with this case, I assure you.
Hurry up with your questioning so I can get home.
Since I'll need to confirm it...
Can you get the contact information
for those you were golfing with?
Yeah...
That goes for you and your mah-jong friends as well.
They actually picked up the wife at 5:00 A.M.?
They're certain?
Yes, according to her friends, the time
was reported on the car's radio then.
By the time they brought her home,
it was already past 7:00 P.M.
7:00 P.M.?
Didn't we come after that?
We went to the newspaper publisher, and they
said the papers are delivered at 6:00 A.M.
Since the TV show was recorded, I estimate
that the time of death would probably be...
Around forty-five minutes prior to 8:00 A.M.
So, that means the wife couldn't have committed the crime?
Yeah.
Of course I didn't!
Then I must ask Yoshikawa-san...
You're behaving very strangely.
Do you have an alibi for 8:00 A.M. this morning?
I-I was asleep...
Did anyone see you?
Of course not.
I live alone.
Oh yeah.
I remember leaving a message after calling.
I said, "It's time to wake up, I'm coming up now."
If I killed him, would I have left that message?
Couldn't you have done it so we wouldn't suspect you?
Hold it!
What about all of them?
Why aren't you questioning them, Officer?
There's no way he's the murderer!
This is someone I can respect: Detective Mouri Kogorou!
Hello!
You're the famous...
Sleeping Kogorou?
Yes.
That's his daughter, Ran-san, and the
kid who lives with them, Conan-kun.
And, that beauty beside him is...
Mrs. Mouri!
Isn't that right, Mouri-san?
It looks that way?
I'm afraid not.
I asked Mouri-san to help find an old acquaintance
of mine, who happened to be Shibata Shirou-san.
My name is Ikenami.
I only came to get a thirty year-old
photograph back from Shirou-san.
Photograph?
It must be the photo in his hand, right?
Stop that.
I just saw it there.
It can't be...
T-This...
C-Could this be...
Yes.
That would be it...
The photograph I was looking for.
But, why would Shirou-san be holding this?
That's because, Mouri-san...
This photograph is Shirou-san's dying message, isn't it?
It couldn't be connected to the beautiful Shizuka-san...
Not to mention, the photograph should be in an album.
It must have fallen out or something.
There's something under that man's body!
What's that?
It's a novel.
The Thunder God's Door is the title.
Could this be...
The book you mentioned?
Yes, that would be it.
I borrowed it from Shirou-san thirty years ago and
left my photograph inside when I returned it.
Then, could the criminal be...
Hey, wait a second!
Isn't that an overwhelming coincidence?
Like how the book and photograph are both on the floor...
Oh yeah...
There was that strange phone call yesterday.
Strange phone call?
That's right, from Shibata-san.
He said, "This is interesting, you should come see."
He must have been watching a video in this living room then.
Right, Miss?
Yeah...
He was talking with someone on the
phone while looking for a book.
Then, he turned to a certain page of one of
them and said, smiling, "I got it, I got it."
And then?
Where did your husband put that book?
I think...
It was on top of that stack of books in front of the bookshelf.
It's all a mess!
Detective Yokomizo!
We found blood in the corridor!
What!?
It seems the murder started in this corridor.
Hey, Mr. CSI Guy...
Can I see that book for a minute?
No way, no way.
This is important evidence.
Not to mention, this is a ninja book with a lot of kanji.
A boy like you can't read it.
That means you've read the book?
Yeah, I've read it.
Then, is there a character named "Reiko" in the book?
There's no character by that name in it.
Another one...
That's another lie.
This woman is a liar.
But, for what reason?
Just why is she lying like this?
THE CLIENT FULL OF LIES
(PART TWO)
Detective Yokomizo!
We found a bloody bokken!
Really!?
Yes!
It was behind the stairs near the door.
Miss, did your husband keep a bokken here?
Y-Yes...
Shibata Kyouko (38)
Wife of Shibata Shirou
It's kept on that counter.
My husband used it to chase away salesmen.
It's not there now.
And how many phones do you have?
There's one in the bedroom and one in the living room.
We used to have one near the door.
I see.
I've got it now.
The criminal is Ikenami-san.
Ikenami Shizuka (42)
Client
You are the one responsible for this.
Hey, hey, Detective Yokomizo...
You first called to confirm that the
photograph was indeed still around.
Then, this morning...
You came yourself to pick it up.
You then had an argument with him
over the photograph near the door...
Which ended with you taking the
bokken in hand and attacking him.
You escaped via the rear stairs after
you thought you had killed him.
But...
Shirou-san was still holding on.
He fought his way to the living room to get to the phone.
But then, just before him, was the photo
of you inside of The Thunder God's Door.
With his last bit of life, Shirou-san reached for the book.
He then had a photograph of his killer in hand.
But, that photo...
There must be something secret in the photograph.
That's why she asked you to help her find the photograph!
Now, Ikenami-san...
Will you come with us to the station?
I won't be coming with you.
If you want a statement from me, won't you need
to get an arrest warrant from the courts first?
Well, based on so little evidence, you
won't be able to prove I'm involved at all.
As such, you will have some difficulty
arresting me without a warrant.
Of course, the wife could decide to
press charges against us for trespassing.
What's going on?
What kind of person is this woman?
Hey, look at his left hand.
There's blood here.
He could have just reached for his injury.
But, it's strange...
The bandages on his fingers have no blood on them.
That's right!
That woman's left hand!
Wait a second!
His right hand...
H-Hey!
I see!
That's how it was!
Hey...
You can't do that.
As I thought, the criminal...
That person came...
Before we did...
To this blood-stained murder scene...
Now, come on, Ikenami-san.
The victim, Shibata Shirou-san, was holding
a photograph of you, was he not?
What kind of relationship would you have with him
that had him holding a photograph of you as he died?
I've already explained this to Mouri-san.
Then, please come repeat it at the station...
I can, but...
I'll be holding you responsible for my
predicament, Mouri Kogorou-san.
After all, I am a client of yours who is
recording a statement with the police.
No...
I'm counting on you, Mouri-san!
Didn't you already get my statement?
But, there should be no need...
Mouri-san!
Well...
Are you all right?
Mouri-san?
Ikenami-san...
With things as they are, you cannot
avoid being questioned, can you?
Right?
However...
Not as a suspect.
I will now show the truth of the case...
With her as my key witness.
Then, she really didn't do it?
Yeah.
She came here with us for the photograph.
When we came here together earlier...
We rang the door bell a number of times to no answer.
She could have opened the door herself.
If she had been the one that killed Shibata-san...
She would have known the door was already unlocked.
She wouldn't have missed her chance to retrieve the
photograph before the police arrived either, right?
Then, it's the one who opened the door immediately...
Yoshikawa Takezou (47)
Friend of Shibata Shirou
Yoshikawa-san!
It's you.
Let's not forget that you were also the first to find the body.
You wanted to get here before the police...
To get rid of the evidence, isn't that right!?
That's not it...
No, Yoshikawa-san isn't the culprit.
Since Shibata-san was dead before at least noon...
We can assume the door was already open.
So, from the estimated time of death, Yoshikawa-san
had no alibi and couldn't risk returning to the scene.
Not to mention that he didn't know
there was evidence to remove.
So why would he come back to the murder half a day later?
And why would he call when he
knows only a corpse could answer it?
When we arrived, he shouted at us and told us not to leave.
If I were the culprit, I'd wait until I was alone to go inside.
Then...
Then, could the culprit be...
Yeah.
The one with the best alibi...
It's you...
Then...
Then, could the culprit be...
Yeah.
The one with the best alibi...
It's you...
Shibata Kyouko-san!
The wife is the culprit!?
Miss, did you really...
But wait, Mouri-san...
Didn't she leave after preparing breakfast at 5:00 A.M.?
How could the morning newspaper that
arrived at 6:00 A.M. be on the table?
Besides, it wasn't until after 7:00 P.M.
that her friends brought her home.
That's when you arrived, Mouri-san.
Since you came before her...
How did she get the newspaper?
In actuality, it's all due to her using her time very well.
Both 7:05 and 7:10 are "after 7:00."
Could she have not returned home before we arrived?
Wait a second...
What about the breakfast?
That's more likely a meal Shirou-san had at 3:00 A.M.
But, if you put the morning newspaper next to it...
It looks like breakfast, doesn't it?
But what about the video?
Wasn't his program recorded at 8:00?
That's simple.
Just set the timer and the video tape will record automatically.
This means she had to just make the arrangements...
First, you waited for your husband to return
home at 3:00 A.M. and have a shower.
Before you had to leave at 5:00 A.M.,
you prepared a late night meal for him.
And, while he was eating...
You called him out to the corridor and hit him with the bokken.
Next, you set the video timer...
Locked the door from outside...
And waited for your friends to arrive
at the apartment building at 5:00.
After you arrived home at 7:00...
You took the newspaper from the door
postbox and put it by the table.
That way, after you called the police...
You would have a perfect alibi.
I see.
When the coroner came and saw the newspaper and video...
He would be led to believe the victim had breakfast
around 8:00 A.M., and had been killed around that time.
But then, something that wasn't in her plan came up...
It's because her husband wasn't in
the corridor where she'd left him...
He had struggled into the living room.
Isn't that it?
Yeah.
And, still in shock from seeing this...
The phone rang.
Could the caller then have been me?
Right.
It was Yoshikawa-san's message saying, "I'm coming up now."
Hearing this message, she realized immediately...
That it would be far better for her if someone
else found the body and then called the police.
It was then that she decided to leave
and pretend to come back shortly after.
But then, where was she before?
She was likely waiting behind the main door on the stairs...
Until Yoshikawa-san came.
But, we showed up before Yoshikawa-san did, right?
But wait, Detective...
What's the deal with that photograph?
Why was he holding a photograph of that woman?
That's nothing more than camouflage used to cover up.
Camouflage?
Please take a look at the victim's left hand.
Even though there's blood on his palm...
There's none on the bandage.
I-It's true!
Now, look at his right hand.
This is...
Could it be that this is...
Right.
Before she found him in the living
room, he was clenching it tightly...
The proof of their marriage: his wedding ring.
He always wore the ring on his left
hand's fourth finger, but the wife...
She noticed he wasn't wearing it but holding
it in his right hand, so she removed it.
However, it's unnatural for a hand to
be clenched so tightly around nothing.
That's when she decided to put the picture of
Ikenami-san from the nearby book in his hand.
I see.
It's to ensure the evidence leads to anyone except her, right?
Yeah.
Then, she noticed the traces of a ring being on his ring finger...
Which is why she covered it with a bandage.
Well, it's less obvious if the other
fingers have bandages on them.
Detective Yokomizo, it's here!
There are traces of a ring being under the bandage!
Take a photograph now!
All right!
Next up is the ring!
Search everywhere in here!
No, that's not necessary...
Because his wife...
Likely still has it in her hand.
Even if you wiped the blood off of the
ring, there's still chemical evidence.
Since she was afraid the police would
find it, she couldn't hide it in the room.
Of course, she couldn't leave it on the rear stairs.
The best plan is to take it as far away
as possible once the police have left.
That's why I believe she still has it on her.
Her husband held it tightly as he slowly faded away...
His dying message that proved his wife killed him.
I guess good endings really don't exist for bad people.
What he and Yoshikawa-san did going unknown...
That's not fair.
Gambling on mah-jong!
He was gambling day and night on mah-jong!
The more he gambled, the more he got into debt!
He sold the computer, my jewelry, the car,
the LD player, the speaker system...
All until we had nothing left.
I hate that damn game!
Then, my husband said...
My golf clubs were next.
He said my father's dowry was after that...
My husband left me with no choice!
At any rate, we'll need you to come to the station.
Just let me get changed.
Dowry...
Katana!
C-Could she...
Stay away!
It was all the only choice I had!
That was the only way to stop him!
Miss, please calm down!
There's nothing left...
I killed someone...
Hey, Miss...
Allow me.
What do you want!?
Stay away!
Didn't I just tell you to stay away!?
Did you want to take another life?
After already killing your husband...
Did you want to kill again?
Another life?
I just wanted to take my own...
Fool!
Life is the most precious of all things.
How could you give in so easily?
Such behavior makes you no different
than cold-blooded murderers.
Learn to appreciate yourself.
Remember that.
Here you go...
Detective.
Yes...
One last thing, Ikenami-san.
Would you mind revealing them to me now?
The meanings behind those four lies.
You claimed you were allergic to dust, but enjoyed knitting.
You said you didn't like cooking, but you
recognized the type of fish on sight.
You're also married.
You have a bandage on your left hand's fourth finger.
And "Reiko"...
There's no such character in that ninja book.
You just said it casually at the coffee shop.
What was "Reiko" really?
"Reiko" was actually "Reikoo."
You were probably going to ask for iced coffee...
But, you stopped abruptly when you realized asking for iced
coffee by saying "reikoo" would reveal you were from Osaka.
Well, that's something only old men and women say anymore.
Isn't that right...
Old lady?
Hattori-kun and Kazuha-chan!?
No way...
Hey, old lady, isn't it time to go?
Get back to Osaka.
Hey!
How could you be so rude and call Shizuka-san an "old lady"!?
I really doubt she'd mind...
Since she's my mom.
You must be lying, since...
You have different skin tones!
It's not like that!
I inherited my dark skin from my grandfather!
What's with this?
Song by Kuraki Mai
Start in my life
ii koto bakari no mirai ja nai keredo
Even though the future won't just have good things
tashika ni ima wa ashita ni mukai dare yori mo kagayaki
For now I'm definitely going to face tomorrow shining brighter than anyone
koko ni tatteiru koware kake souna ima ni namidashi soredemo
Because I'm standing here crying for a present that seems about to fall apart, however...
We can start in my life issho ni
We can start in my life, together
akiramezu yume to
With a dream that we'll never give up
nee mou hitori no jibun ni aeru kara
You know, it's because you can meet another part of yourself
kimochi hitotsu de kawarerun da
That we can be transformed by a single feeling
hora koko kara hajime you
Come on, let's start right here
Just start in my life
It was a test?
For me?
Yeah, that's right.
Heiji got hurt the last time he was with you.
So I thought maybe your detective skills weren't quite
good enough, since you were letting people get injured.
And the last time you were in Osaka,
you didn't visit or stop to apologize.
I was beginning to worry that Heiji was
following someone with no responsibility.
So, that time you came and visited the hospital...
I wanted to see you at least one time, so I guess it's fine, but...
I guess he really has a reason to respect you.
It's because you, Mouri-san, are someone with real intelligence.
T-Thanks a lot...
You were able to find Shirou-san by phone...
Notice I was lying...
And all the while solve a murder case.
It was all solved so swiftly!
I regret what's happened to Shirou-san, but...
I did manage to recover the photograph.
Another lie...
You said you got bullied by the first year champion which
left you crying and didn't care if the photograph was lost.
I don't have to worry at all now about leaving
Heiji and Kazuha-chan with you now!
With me?
That's right, why do you have so much luggage?
What?
That kid didn't tell you?
He was serious on the phone?