A strong heart reinforces reasoning power.
The steady rhythm reveals the truth.
The client is a beautiful woman.
A strange request leads to a case!
Perceiving the one and only truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan.
THE CLIENT FULL OF LIES
(PART ONE)
You're looking for someone?
Yes, I really must see him.
Sorry, but I'm a little tied up...
Is there anything that can be done?
The truth is, I'm actually near your office already.
If it's OK, I'd like to at least talk...
Lightning!
Lightning has come flying through!
The winner is Lightning!
With that amazing come-from-behind
victory, the final race is over!
Lost again!
Hello?
Mouri-san?
Didn't I just say I was busy!?
Oh, I mean, discussing it would be just fine...
Yes, I'll see you soon.
Do your work already...
Dad!
I know...
Hey, what kind of person called just then?
It was some older woman.
She said she's coming over now.
She'll be like...
"Please help me find my long lost first love!"
She'll definitely be like that...
Come in!
I'm Ikenami, who just called a moment ago.
I apologize for intruding on you so suddenly...
Ikenami Shizuka
Client
My friend claimed that if I asked Mouri-san
for help, we could find him easily.
I very much so hope you'll help me.
Please, come sit down.
She's such a beauty...
Excuse me.
Huh?
Where did Dad go?
My apologies for having you wait...
Madamosielle.
I was busy reviewing some elementary murder case files.
Now, now, please have a seat on the sofa.
Perhaps we may rest your heart before discussing this matter.
Ran?
What about some drinks?
Yes...
It's begun again...
You're looking for a classmate from middle school?
Yes.
We were both involved in kendo as well.
Shouldn't there be an address in the yearbook?
Since he moved before graduation, the
information supplied for him was minimal.
I-It's a man?
I have a photograph from back then.
I'm looking for the one in the center holding the gold cup.
His name is Shibata Shirou.
Could this cute girl next to him be...
I'm afraid that would be me.
This photograph is already thirty years old.
T-Thirty years old!?
That means you're over forty years old?
Yes.
I turn forty-two this year.
But, since this photograph was taken
when he was in the seventh grade...
He's probably a bit taller now.
Can I get a list of hobbies?
Yes...
Let's see, he likes...
No.
I mean yours.
I've always...
Really liked knitting, so I make a lot of sweaters.
That's a perfect hobby!
My mother likes to knit as well!
And you're probably a great cook as well, right?
No, I'm not good at it at all.
I ended up doing this while trying last night.
Well, what does that matter?
Women with weaknesses are more attractive anyway.
Right! Right!
Just like Mom, right?
But, I really have a lot of weaknesses.
That's probably why I'm still single at this age.
You're single!?
It's hard to believe men haven't noticed
such a beautiful and honorable woman.
They must all be blind!
You're really great.
It's just like the person who split from
my mother, what were they thinking?
Hey now...
Excuse me.
Is something wrong?
Do you have a cold?
No, my throat just isn't well right now.
I'm allergic to dust.
I'm sorry.
I was just cleaning, so there's dust everywhere.
Then, we can go elsewhere.
I'm sorry for being troublesome.
A photograph?
You mean...
The reason you want to find this
Shibata-san is to ask for that photograph?
Yes.
The photograph was taken when we were
in eighth grade, on the summer fair day.
It was just a picture of me holding
the championship plaque.
My grandmother accidentally threw
the award away a few days ago...
So I thought about it and was reminded of that photograph.
But, why does Shibata-san have the photograph?
I was using it as a bookmark while reading a
book I borrowed from him and forgot about it.
By the time I realized it, he was already gone.
Then...
You don't want to find him because he's your first love, right?
Right...
And?
Do you have any other information?
Let's see...
Mouri-san, what would you like?
I'll take coffee.
Iced lemon tea for me.
I want...
Reiko.
"Reiko"?
Who is that?
Oh, no...
That's just what he used to call me.
He used to say there was a character named Reiko in the
book he let me borrow that had a personality like mine.
And what will you have, Conan-kun?
Iced coffee for me!
I'll take that as well.
Coming right up.
This definitely isn't enough...
With only his name, age, and a thirty
year old photograph to go on...
Um...
Perhaps I should have used that person's brilliant mind.
That person?
I've heard others mention him...
That high school detective...
They say Kudo Shinichi comes and
goes from your detective agency often.
Shinichi?
Isn't that right, boy?
No, no, that brat won't come.
He only gives us a stupid call every now and then.
I didn't know they were so stupid...
But really...
What if this was noticed...
By them already?
Could they have already deduced this?
Hey, Conan-kun.
What do you think, Conan-kun?
Weren't you about to say something?
What's the point in asking this brat?
But sometimes he notices interesting
things that no one else does.
Oh, nothing really.
I was just thinking...
Since this guy is holding the cup,
he must have got first place, right?
Yeah.
If he was already this good in seventh grade...
He must have attended some sort of recorded
competition at some point, even if he had problems.
But, I don't really get it.
Seriously?
There was a person who participated named Shibata Shirou?
Yes!
Yeah.
Did you find him?
They say he always participates and is usually in the lead.
Right now, he's a physical education
teacher at Shizouka High School.
He lives together with his wife at an apartment building.
I'll go call for a rent-a-car now.
Isn't it great that we've found him?
Yeah, it really is.
Found him...
We've already found who she was looking for, but...
What confuses me is...
This woman full of lies.
She lied about everything she said.
Just what does she want?
Could she be...
Hiding her identity?
Hey, hey, or could she be...
Could this woman be...
Thank you.
It's all thanks to you, boy.
Guess no one's in...
Since it's Sunday, they may have gone out.
Well then, let's head out and come back later.
Hey, wait.
Yoshikawa Takezou (47)
Friend of Shibata Shirou
Are you looking for Shibata-san by any chance?
Yeah.
Hurry it up, then.
He's coming over to my place to play mah-jong later.
But, it doesn't seem like he's home.
That's not possible.
He must just be asleep.
See?
There's sound.
Sounds like a TV.
Really, the door's unlocked, TV's on, and he's asleep...
Hey, Shibata-san!
We're about to get started!
Hey, hey, he only ate half of his food.
Yeah...
The soup is already cold.
So is the rice.
Could this have been breakfast?
What a waste of fresh guji...
Guji?
It's west lake fish.
I'm home.
Dear?
Hey, what are you all doing?
Shibata Kyouko (38)
Wife of Shibata Shirou
You think you can just go into anyone's home?
I'm calling the police!
No...
We're just...
Hey, Shibata-san!
What's wrong!?
Hang in there!
Hey!
What happened!?
Shibata-san!
Hey, hang in there!
There's something in his right hand!
But what?
This is...
Now let's review your statements...
Mouri-san, you four came to visit Shibata Shirou-san
and after ringing the doorbell a number of times...
No one answered?
Yoshikawa-san came to meet Shirou-san
and found the door wasn't locked...
So you entered with the others?
Lastly, there's his wife, Kyouko-san, who
met with Mouri-san moments before.
And then...
Yoshikawa-san found Shirou-san's body in the living room...
Dead, with his head covered in blood.
Is that all correct?
Yeah.
The estimated time of death is some time in the morning.
And where was his wife at this time?
Y-Yes...
I arranged to meet some friends for golf,
who came around 5:00 A.M in their car.
I had prepared him breakfast and left before 5:00.
And, at that time, Shirou-san was home?
Yeah, he came home around 3:00 A.M.
Did you just say 3:00 A.M.?
Y-Yeah...
It's mah-jong.
We were playing mah-jong in my room down on the fourth floor.
As she said, we quit around 3:00 A.M.
And then, there's that newspaper next to his breakfast...
Do you know when it was delivered?
Yes.
It's always delivered to the mailbox at around 6:00 A.M.
I see.
That means Shirou-san...
Got up, collected the newspaper...
And, while he was enjoying his breakfast...
He was attacked and killed.
That's the most likely scenario, isn't it?
What tells you he was eating breakfast then?
It's because some of the food on the
table was eaten, and then it went cold.
But, who is responsible for this?
Who killed my husband?
We're still not sure.
Mouri-san, when you entered...
Did you notice anything peculiar?
Let's see...
The TV was on that whole time...
The TV was!?
Why was it off when we arrived!?
It was a little noisy...
I thought he was just watching TV and eating breakfast, so...
He was most likely watching that show, "The Hero
Sword Legend," which airs every morning at 8:00 A.M.
He records it every week and watches it in the living room.
There definitely are a lot here.
All right!
Check the TV recorder in the kitchen!
Yes, sir!
Hey...
Why isn't the LD player here?
There are LD discs over here...
But there's no player.
Look, isn't this spot particularly empty?
There's only one speaker, too.
That's true...
It must be being repaired.
Right, Miss?
No, actually, my husband...
That has nothing to do with this case, I assure you.
Hurry up with your questioning so I can get home.
Since I'll need to confirm it...
Can you get the contact information
for those you were golfing with?
Yeah...
That goes for you and your mah-jong friends as well.
They actually picked up the wife at 5:00 A.M.?
They're certain?
Yes, according to her friends, the time
was reported on the car's radio then.
By the time they brought her home,
it was already past 7:00 P.M.
7:00 P.M.?
Didn't we come after that?
We went to the newspaper publisher, and they
said the papers are delivered at 6:00 A.M.
Since the TV show was recorded, I estimate
that the time of death would probably be...
Around forty-five minutes prior to 8:00 A.M.
So, that means the wife couldn't have committed the crime?
Yeah.
Of course I didn't!
Then I must ask Yoshikawa-san...
You're behaving very strangely.
Do you have an alibi for 8:00 A.M. this morning?
I-I was asleep...
Did anyone see you?
Of course not.
I live alone.
Oh yeah.
I remember leaving a message after calling.
I said, "It's time to wake up, I'm coming up now."
If I killed him, would I have left that message?
Couldn't you have done it so we wouldn't suspect you?
Hold it!
What about all of them?
Why aren't you questioning them, Officer?
There's no way he's the murderer!
This is someone I can respect: Detective Mouri Kogoro!
Hello!
You're the famous...
Sleeping Kogoro?
Yes.
That's his daughter, Ran-san, and the
kid who lives with them, Conan-kun.
And, that beauty beside him is...
Mrs. Mouri!
Isn't that right, Mouri-san?
It looks that way?
I'm afraid not.
I asked Mouri-san to help find an old acquaintance
of mine, who happened to be Shibata Shirou-san.
My name is Ikenami.
I only came to get a thirty year-old
photograph back from Shirou-san.
Photograph?
It must be the photo in his hand, right?
Stop that.
I just saw it there.
It can't be...
T-This...
C-Could this be...
Yes.
That would be it...
The photograph I was looking for.
But, why would Shirou-san be holding this?
That's because, Mouri-san...
This photograph is Shirou-san's dying message, isn't it?
It couldn't be connected to the beautiful Shizuka-san...
Not to mention, the photograph should be in an album.
It must have fallen out or something.
There's something under that man's body!
What's that?
It's a novel.
The Thunder God's Door is the title.
Could this be...
The book you mentioned?
Yes, that would be it.
I borrowed it from Shirou-san thirty years ago and
left my photograph inside when I returned it.
Then, could the criminal be...
Hey, wait a second!
Isn't that an overwhelming coincidence?
Like how the book and photograph are both on the floor...
Oh yeah...
There was that strange phone call yesterday.
Strange phone call?
That's right, from Shibata-san.
He said, "This is interesting, you should come see."
He must have been watching a video in this living room then.
Right, Miss?
Yeah...
He was talking with someone on the
phone while looking for a book.
Then, he turned to a certain page of one of
them and said, smiling, "I got it, I got it."
And then?
Where did your husband put that book?
I think...
It was on top of that stack of books in front of the bookshelf.
It's all a mess!
Detective Yokomizo!
We found blood in the corridor!
What!?
It seems the murder started in this corridor.
Hey, Mr. CSI Guy...
Can I see that book for a minute?
No way, no way.
This is important evidence.
Not to mention, this is a ninja book with a lot of kanji.
A boy like you can't read it.
That means you've read the book?
Yeah, I've read it.
Then, is there a character named "Reiko" in the book?
There's no character by that name in it.
Another one...
That's another lie.
This woman is a liar.
But, for what reason?
Just why is she lying like this?