A strong heart reinforces reasoning power.
The steady rhythm reveals the truth.
Today the case as well as the lies will be figured out...
the identity of the beautiful client sure is a surprise.
Perceiving the one and only truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan.
A beautiful client appears at the detective office.
Her name is Shizuka Ikenami.
She comes to ask Pops to look for
her classmate from her middle school days,
who belonged to the same Kendo club
and whose name is Shiro Shibata.
He was located immediately.
He seemed to be working as a P.E. teacher in Shizuoka.
We set off immediately to his place, but...
what awaited us there was...
the dead body of Mr. Shiro Shibata, who had been killed.
He had the picture of Shizuka Ikenami gripped firmly in his hands.
What bothers me is why the client is so full of lies...
Almost everything that she says is a lie...
What on earth is she hiding?
THE CLIENT FULL OF LIES
(PART TWO)
Detective Yokomizo!
We found a bloody bokken!
Really!?
Yes!
It was behind the stairs near the door.
Miss, did your husband keep a bokken here?
Y-Yes...
Shibata Kyouko (38)
Wife of Shibata Shirou
It's kept on that counter.
My husband used it to chase away salesmen.
It's not there now.
And how many phones do you have?
There's one in the bedroom and one in the living room.
We used to have one near the door.
I see.
I've got it now.
The criminal is Ikenami-san.
Ikenami Shizuka (42)
Client
You are the one responsible for this.
Hey, hey, Detective Yokomizo...
You first called to confirm that the
photograph was indeed still around.
Then, this morning...
You came yourself to pick it up.
You then had an argument with him
over the photograph near the door...
Which ended with you taking the
bokken in hand and attacking him.
You escaped via the rear stairs after
you thought you had killed him.
But...
Shirou-san was still holding on.
He fought his way to the living room to get to the phone.
But then, just before him, was the photo
of you inside of The Thunder God's Door.
With his last bit of life, Shirou-san reached for the book.
He then had a photograph of his killer in hand.
But, that photo...
There must be something secret in the photograph.
That's why she asked you to help her find the photograph!
Now, Ikenami-san...
Will you come with us to the station?
I won't be coming with you.
If you want a statement from me, won't you need
to get an arrest warrant from the courts first?
Well, based on so little evidence, you
won't be able to prove I'm involved at all.
As such, you will have some difficulty
arresting me without a warrant.
Of course, the wife could decide to
press charges against us for trespassing.
What's going on?
What kind of person is this woman?
Hey, look at his left hand.
There's blood here.
He could have just reached for his injury.
But, it's strange...
The bandages on his fingers have no blood on them.
That's right!
That woman's left hand!
Wait a second!
His right hand...
H-Hey!
I see!
That's how it was!
Hey...
You can't do that.
As I thought, the criminal...
That person came...
Before we did...
To this blood-stained murder scene...
Now, come on, Ikenami-san.
The victim, Shibata Shirou-san, was holding
a photograph of you, was he not?
What kind of relationship would you have with him
that had him holding a photograph of you as he died?
I've already explained this to Mouri-san.
Then, please come repeat it at the station...
I can, but...
I'll be holding you responsible for my
predicament, Mouri Kogorou-san.
After all, I am a client of yours who is
recording a statement with the police.
No...
I'm counting on you, Mouri-san!
Didn't you already get my statement?
But, there should be no need...
Mouri-san!
Well...
Are you all right?
Mouri-san?
Ikenami-san...
With things as they are, you cannot
avoid being questioned, can you?
Right?
However...
Not as a suspect.
I will now show the truth of the case...
With her as my key witness.
Then, she really didn't do it?
Yeah.
She came here with us for the photograph.
When we came here together earlier...
We rang the door bell a number of times to no answer.
She could have opened the door herself.
If she had been the one that killed Shibata-san...
She would have known the door was already unlocked.
She wouldn't have missed her chance to retrieve the
photograph before the police arrived either, right?
Then, it's the one who opened the door immediately...
Yoshikawa Takezou (47)
Friend of Shibata Shirou
Yoshikawa-san!
It's you.
Let's not forget that you were also the first to find the body.
You wanted to get here before the police...
To get rid of the evidence, isn't that right!?
That's not it...
No, Yoshikawa-san isn't the culprit.
Since Shibata-san was dead before at least noon...
We can assume the door was already open.
So, from the estimated time of death, Yoshikawa-san
had no alibi and couldn't risk returning to the scene.
Not to mention that he didn't know
there was evidence to remove.
So why would he come back to the murder half a day later?
And why would he call when he
knows only a corpse could answer it?
When we arrived, he shouted at us and told us not to leave.
If I were the culprit, I'd wait until I was alone to go inside.
Then...
Then, could the culprit be...
Yeah.
The one with the best alibi...
It's you...
Then...
Then, could the culprit be...
Yeah.
The one with the best alibi...
It's you...
Shibata Kyouko-san!
The wife is the culprit!?
Miss, did you really...
But wait, Mouri-san...
Didn't she leave after preparing breakfast at 5:00 A.M.?
How could the morning newspaper that
arrived at 6:00 A.M. be on the table?
Besides, it wasn't until after 7:00 P.M.
that her friends brought her home.
That's when you arrived, Mouri-san.
Since you came before her...
How did she get the newspaper?
In actuality, it's all due to her using her time very well.
Both 7:05 and 7:10 are "after 7:00."
Could she have not returned home before we arrived?
Wait a second...
What about the breakfast?
That's more likely a meal Shirou-san had at 3:00 A.M.
But, if you put the morning newspaper next to it...
It looks like breakfast, doesn't it?
But what about the video?
Wasn't his program recorded at 8:00?
That's simple.
Just set the timer and the video tape will record automatically.
This means she had to just make the arrangements...
First, you waited for your husband to return
home at 3:00 A.M. and have a shower.
Before you had to leave at 5:00 A.M.,
you prepared a late night meal for him.
And, while he was eating...
You called him out to the corridor and hit him with the bokken.
Next, you set the video timer...
Locked the door from outside...
And waited for your friends to arrive
at the apartment building at 5:00.
After you arrived home at 7:00...
You took the newspaper from the door
postbox and put it by the table.
That way, after you called the police...
You would have a perfect alibi.
I see.
When the coroner came and saw the newspaper and video...
He would be led to believe the victim had breakfast
around 8:00 A.M., and had been killed around that time.
But then, something that wasn't in her plan came up...
It's because her husband wasn't in
the corridor where she'd left him...
He had struggled into the living room.
Isn't that it?
Yeah.
And, still in shock from seeing this...
The phone rang.
Could the caller then have been me?
Right.
It was Yoshikawa-san's message saying, "I'm coming up now."
Hearing this message, she realized immediately...
That it would be far better for her if someone
else found the body and then called the police.
It was then that she decided to leave
and pretend to come back shortly after.
But then, where was she before?
She was likely waiting behind the main door on the stairs...
Until Yoshikawa-san came.
But, we showed up before Yoshikawa-san did, right?
But wait, Detective...
What's the deal with that photograph?
Why was he holding a photograph of that woman?
That's nothing more than camouflage used to cover up.
Camouflage?
Please take a look at the victim's left hand.
Even though there's blood on his palm...
There's none on the bandage.
I-It's true!
Now, look at his right hand.
This is...
Could it be that this is...
Right.
Before she found him in the living
room, he was clenching it tightly...
The proof of their marriage: his wedding ring.
He always wore the ring on his left
hand's fourth finger, but the wife...
She noticed he wasn't wearing it but holding
it in his right hand, so she removed it.
However, it's unnatural for a hand to
be clenched so tightly around nothing.
That's when she decided to put the picture of
Ikenami-san from the nearby book in his hand.
I see.
It's to ensure the evidence leads to anyone except her, right?
Yeah.
Then, she noticed the traces of a ring being on his ring finger...
Which is why she covered it with a bandage.
Well, it's less obvious if the other
fingers have bandages on them.
Detective Yokomizo, it's here!
There are traces of a ring being under the bandage!
Take a photograph now!
All right!
Next up is the ring!
Search everywhere in here!
No, that's not necessary...
Because his wife...
Likely still has it in her hand.
Even if you wiped the blood off of the
ring, there's still chemical evidence.
Since she was afraid the police would
find it, she couldn't hide it in the room.
Of course, she couldn't leave it on the rear stairs.
The best plan is to take it as far away
as possible once the police have left.
That's why I believe she still has it on her.
Her husband held it tightly as he slowly faded away...
His dying message that proved his wife killed him.
I guess good endings really don't exist for bad people.
What he and Yoshikawa-san did going unknown...
That's not fair.
Gambling on mah-jong!
He was gambling day and night on mah-jong!
The more he gambled, the more he got into debt!
He sold the computer, my jewelry, the car,
the LD player, the speaker system...
All until we had nothing left.
I hate that damn game!
Then, my husband said...
My golf clubs were next.
He said my father's dowry was after that...
My husband left me with no choice!
At any rate, we'll need you to come to the station.
Just let me get changed.
Dowry...
Katana!
C-Could she...
Stay away!
It was all the only choice I had!
That was the only way to stop him!
Miss, please calm down!
There's nothing left...
I killed someone...
Hey, Miss...
Allow me.
What do you want!?
Stay away!
Didn't I just tell you to stay away!?
Did you want to take another life?
After already killing your husband...
Did you want to kill again?
Another life?
I just wanted to take my own...
Fool!
Life is the most precious of all things.
How could you give in so easily?
Such behavior makes you no different
than cold-blooded murderers.
Learn to appreciate yourself.
Remember that.
Here you go...
Detective.
Yes...
One last thing, Ikenami-san.
Would you mind revealing them to me now?
The meanings behind those four lies.
You claimed you were allergic to dust, but enjoyed knitting.
You said you didn't like cooking, but you
recognized the type of fish on sight.
You're also married.
You have a bandage on your left hand's fourth finger.
And "Reiko"...
There's no such character in that ninja book.
You just said it casually at the coffee shop.
What was "Reiko" really?
"Reiko" was actually "Reikoo."
You were probably going to ask for iced coffee...
But, you stopped abruptly when you realized asking for iced coffee by saying "reikoo" would reveal you were from Osaka.
Well, that's something only old men and women say anymore.
Isn't that right...
Old lady?
Hattori-kun and Kazuha-chan!?
No way...
Hey, old lady, isn't it time to go?
Get back to Osaka.
Hey!
How could you be so rude and call Shizuka-san an "old lady"!?
I really doubt she'd mind...
Since she's my mom.
You must be lying, since...
You have different skin tones!
It's not like that!
I inherited my dark skin from my grandfather!
What's with this?
It was a test?
For me?
Yeah, that's right.
Heiji got hurt the last time he was with you.
So I thought maybe your detective skills weren't quite
good enough, since you were letting people get injured.
And the last time you were in Osaka,
you didn't visit or stop to apologize.
I was beginning to worry that Heiji was
following someone with no responsibility.
So, that time you came and visited the hospital...
I wanted to see you at least one time, so I guess it's fine, but...
I guess he really has a reason to respect you.
It's because you, Mouri-san, are someone with real intelligence.
T-Thanks a lot...
You were able to find Shirou-san by phone...
Notice I was lying...
And all the while solve a murder case.
It was all solved so swiftly!
I regret what's happened to Shirou-san, but...
I did manage to recover the photograph.
Another lie...
You said you got bullied by the first year champion which
left you crying and didn't care if the photograph was lost.
I don't have to worry at all now about leaving
Heiji and Kazuha-chan with you now!
With me?
That's right, why do you have so much luggage?
What?
That kid didn't tell you?
He was serious on the phone?