Geez.
I'd better see some gratitude, kid.
You showed up without so much as calling ahead,
telling me to join you on this stupid trip to Fukui,
and out of the kindness of my heart I agreed.
C'mon, don't be so crabby. I'm paying for it.
So? Where're we headed, anyway?
A tiny island named Bikuni Island.
But most of the locals call it...
the island where the mermaid lives.
Bikuni Island
Mermaid?
Yeah.
They say there is an old lady on that island that eats memaid meat.
I've heard about that!
About 3 years ago, there was a big fuss about her,
she is an old lady who has lived forever, isn't that right?
Yes, that's right.
I decided to come along
because I wanted to learn the secret of her beauty & longevity!
Oh! I get it.
You want to scare Heiji with those secrets, eh?
Don't talk so loud!
Hey...
That letter you got asking us to find the mermaid...
It isn't just some idiot who wants to see one, is it?
Just the opposite.
There was only three lines,
written in shaky handwriting...
The mermaid is going to kill me! Help!
The mermaid...
...is going to kill me?
Hey, this is serious!
Give me a break,
mermaids only exist in fairy tales,
don't expect me to take you seriously.
I don't believe they really exist either,
but
the name on the letter got my attention.
The envelope was addressed to me but
the letter was written to Shinichi Kudo!
You should be thanking me!
it might be somebody from your past, that is why I brought you along!
So,
did you contact the person who sent the letter to confirm it?
Yes.
The sender, Saori Kadowaki,
wrote the number for her cellular phone on the letter!
No one answered after the second time I called,
but the first time I called someone answered and hung up immediately.
On that first call though,
I can still hear
the sound coming from the other side of the receiver...
It was the sound of waves
and a woman moaning...!
It couldn't be... do you think it was her?
Maybe the memaid already killed her.
Saori Kadowaki-san is missing?
Yes. Three days ago, she stopped coming in to work.
Three days ago... That's around the time I got the letter.
Her neighbors think she took a boat to the mainland.
It's time!
Ah, right, right!
Sorry, gotta get ready for the festival!
Festival?
The annual Dugong Festival is today.
If you want to know more, try the souvenir shop on the corner. That's where Saori-chan worked.
A lucky mermaid charm...
a mermaid cell phone strap...
and special dugong buns...
This island's full of mermaids, isn't it?
What's a dugong, anyway?
Well, uh...
It's a mammal that lives in the ocean,
Some people say that that's the model for the mermaid.
They used to live in the southern part of Japan too, long ago, and it was
Believed that their meat was medical and could make you live a long life.
The Arrow of Dugong?
Yes... It's an amulet for immortality.
Only three are given away each year,
at the annual Dugong Festival.
Saori-chan won an arrow at last year's festival, but she lost it.
She was terrified that the mermaid would curse her.
Mermaids, yeah right.
But mermaids do exist.
Oh, Naoko-san!
Naoko Kuroe (28)
Saori's Childhood Friend
Souvenir Shop Clerk
After all, Lady Mikoto ate the flesh of a mermaid and received immortality.
The Arrow of Dugong has her hair tied to it, and anyone who wins one can become immortal!
Arrow of Dugong
I'm not surprised Saori ran away from the island after she lost her arrow. She could be cursed!
And she is...?
Naoko-san, a childhood friend of Saori-chan's.
And who's this Lady Mikoto?
The head of the festival and matriarch of the Shimabukuro family.
She's the icon of the island!
How old is this lady, really?
I don't know. I've heard rumors that she's 100 or 200 years old...
If you don't believe me, why don't you go to the shrine for the festival?
The shrine?
The holy person's great-granddaughter, Kimie,
Who's also Saori's childhood friend should be there too.
I think we're being given the run around.
Bikuni Shrine
200 years old? No way.
Kimie Shimabukuro (27)
Saori's Childhood Friend
Bikuni Shrine Maiden
My great-grandmother is exactly 130 years old this year!
You can check her birth certificate if you like!
Good grief,
Just because she's a little older than most, everyone exaggerates so much.
A little older...
That's old enough for the Guinness Book of World Records.
So where is yer old lady?
She's in her room, blessing the three arrows that are going to be handed out at the festival.
Then Lady Mikoto really did eat mermaid's flesh...
Huh?
Mermaids don't exist, you know!
That story's a complete lie!
B-But the Arrow of Dugong...
My late mother told me it was originally the Arrow of Jugon, an amulet to ward off evil.
Anti-Evil Arrow
jugon
When Great-Grandma started getting attention for her long life,
Arrow of Dugong
jugon
people around here renamed it the Arrow of Dugong!
Your mother passed away?
Yes...
Five years ago, with my father, at sea.
My grandparents were lost at sea too before I was born.
Great-Grandma and I are the only members of the family left.
If you lost your whole family to the sea, then maybe there's somethin' to the legends!
Of course not!
I went to the mainland with Saori just a few days ago and nothing happened!
Say what?
You were with Saori-san?
When was that?
Four days ago.
I went to the dentist and she came along.
We don't have a dentist on the island, you see.
What state was she in when you saw her?
She was terrified because she'd lost that arrow.
I'm cursed by the mermaid!
She wouldn't believe the curse wasn't real.
Silly...
You just don't believe in Lady Mikoto's powers, do you, Kimie?
Toshimi...
Toshimi Ebihara (27)
Saori's Childhood Friend
Daughter of the Head of the Fishermen's Union
She's the real deal! She really ate the flesh of a mermaid!
We even found a mermaid's corpse three years ago.
A mermaid's corpse?
Oh, wasn't it on television about 3 years ago?
The media played it up a lot.
You don't know what you are talking about.
You saw it, didn't you?
The bones were crushed in a very strange way, is was grotesque...
That's enough, Toshimi!
Rokuro...
We've got nothing more to say to outsiders.
Rokuro Fukuyama (28)
Saori's Childhood Friend
Fisherman
If you're looking for Saori,
why're you wasting time here?
Just go to her house.
That's if that drunk father of hers lets you in.
A girl's gone missing, and nobody's freakin' out.
Saori fights with her dad and runs away all the time.
Can you take us to Saori-san's house?
Sure, after the festival.
What kind of festival is it?
People buy tickets,
and if the number on the ticket matches the number Great-Grandma draws,
they win an Arrow of Dugong.
We call it a festival, but it's more like a lottery.
Ah, that's right!
Why don't you two give it a go?
An elderly couple cancelled their ticket order this morning, so I've got two extra.
If you say so...
Whether you win or lose, it's all up to the Gods!
Maybe, you'll be able to obtain eternal youth and beauty just like the rumors.
This is so cool!
Yeah!
Mikoto Shimabukuro (130)
Lady Mikoto
it's the holy person!
The holy person is making her appearance!
So that's Lady Mikoto...
She's so tiny...
It's just an old lady in lotsa make-up.
S-She... set fire to the paper screens!
The fire is taking the shape of words!
I see...
The winning numbers are under the screens!
Wow! I won!
Hooray! I'm so lucky!
R-R-Ran-chan...
I... I... I...
I won!
Attention, winners.
The time has come to bestow the Arrows of Dugong.
Please follow me...
to the Waterfall of the Mermaid!
Will the three fortunate ones please come forth?
Yes!
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
One more!
Is there one more winner here?
Benzo Kadowaki (52)
Saori's Father
Fisherman
It's me...
Huh?
Weird...
I thought that girl won.
Yeah, and I don't see her around.
But we soon found her...
at the foot of the waterfall.
May fortune light the path for these three!
Hey, what's that?
What is it?
That's right...
Long, black hair wafting...
On a slim body that sways...
it most certainly looked like...
A mermaid swimming up the waterfall,
Shiny & blue...
but it was a lifeless body...
T-Toshimi?
Was it suicide...
Or did somebody...
It might not be either.
This is the rope that strangled Toshimi.
It's part of the rope fence we strung here to keep people from falling in the river.
What did you just say?
I see.
Maybe Toshimi-san fell into the river in the dark.
She grabbed the rope, but the stake slipped out of the mud and the rope wrapped around her.
But doesn't it seem fishy?
The festival was still goin' on at the foot of the waterfall.
So why'd she go wanderin' into the woods?
Maybe she was looking for the mermaid's grave.
What?
There's a mermaid's grave somewhere in this forest.
It contains the bones of the mermaid who was found three years ago,
on the night of the festival, when the shrine's warehouse burned down.
Come to think of it, Toshimi was always curious about that grave.
Hold on just a sec!
You keep talkin' about mermaid this and mermaid that.
It wasn't really a mermaid, was it?
Who knows...
That's what the islanders believe.
But the police from the mainland thought it was the body of a woman.
How could it be an ordinary woman? The bones only went down to the waist!
They did?
A couple of large pillars in the warehouse had crushed the body from the waist down.
But then we moved the pillars.
The leg bones that should've been on the other side of the pillars...
...weren't there.
Th-That's hard to believe!
Thanks to that fact,
the media made a big fuss broadcasting that a mermaid's body was found.
And our holy person bacame famous!
But the police thought it was a woman's body, right?
Yes.
They said a disgruntled tourist must've broken into the warehouse
looking for an extra arrow,
lit a candle, and accidentally started a fire.
After a year passed without anyone claiming the body,
we decided to give it a proper burial.
Then we ran into another problem.
Problem?
Grave robbers.
Stupid tourists started trying to dig up the body and steal the bones.
It seems they heard that mermaid bones were the elixir of eternal life.
So Great-Grandmother had someone move the grave to a secret spot in the forest.
Who did she ask?
I don't know.
All she said was that it was someone she trusted very much.
Well, whether this was murder, suicide or accident,
we can't do anything but take Toshimi-san down and wait for the police.
If it was murder, Toshimi was asking for trouble, coming up here alone in the dark.
What a thing to say about your fiancée!
Fiancée?
Our parents arranged that without our consent.
It wasn't my choice.
And now my mom and dad are dead.
Toshimi!
T-Toshimi!
Who's that?
Toshimi's father, Ebihara-san.
He's head of the local fishermen's union.
Dad!
Oh, did you contact the Fukui prefectural police?
Yeah, but they won't be able to come out for a while. The sea's too rough.
Oh, for the love of...
Great! This is perfect!
It means the killer's gotta stay put on the island!
Killer, huh?
We haven't even decided if this was murder.
Take a look at this!
An inner tube?
Heiji-niichan and I found it stuck in the river, between the waterfall and the river mouth.
I'm guessin' our culprit knocked Toshimi-san out at the top of the waterfall,
wrapped the rope around her neck,
an' floated her down the river to fake a hangin'.
Toshimi-san was last seen at the shrine two hours before her body was found.
It takes less'n an hour to climb to the top of the waterfall an' back.
There was plenty of time for anyone to kill her an' make it look like an accident.
And the killer is still somewhere on this island!
Th-That's terrible.
Don't worry about it!
The murderer will be cought in no time!
When Heiji moves his hat around, he's turned his switch on!
He's ready to go!
But...
You must've fallen in love with him.
Eh?
I'm no match for you... if we become rivals...
Ka-Kazuha...
You're so sweet!
Hey, what're you doing?!
Listen...
If Toshimi was murdered,
You'd better not let that person out of your sight.
Eh?
I'm talking about Saori's drunk of a father.
Excuse me,
Would you like to go to Saori's home now,
I'll take you since I promised you earlier.
With him in that condition,
I doubt he'll be much help through.
You may be right.
Alright then...
Huh?
I'd like to meet the holy person!
Sure,
I don't mind, but...
Boy this house is old...
It doesn't look like they're making too much money from these dugong arrows.
How can you say that?
Those platelets cost 5 yen a piece.
Eh? 5 yen?
The people in this island said the price has been the same
since they can remember.
There are 108 number platelets in a huge box
And everyone lines up then pulls one out.
Then the old woman picks the 3 winning numbers.
What's taking the old lady so long?
Kimie-san said she'll come down to answer questions,
but she's tired from the festival, so she might not stay long.
What's that sound?
Are you the ones who wanted to see me?
Without her make-up, she's an ogre!
W-Well...
I was wondering how you chose the winning numbers...
Er...
At random.
For a while, I picked the winning numbers from the horse races!
Oh, geez.
Then why're ya so stingy with the arrows? You oughta give away more than three!
I can't.
I only have so much hair on my head to tie to the arrows.
Great-Grandma! Your bath's ready!
I'm sorry. If that's all, I'd like to take my bath and go to bed.
Wait! I still have a quest—
You there... Young girl...
The one with your hair tied back.
Me?
The Arrow of Dugong is a charm to ward off evil.
Let go of it, and evil will fall upon you.
Men will return to dust and become heartless devils.
Women will return to water and become speechless mermaids.
Don't ever let it go.
Even her voice sounds wrinkly and she's so pale!
She looks like she could drop dead any minute.
The Next Day
Ebihara House
Aren't ya glad we brought our school uniforms?
Are ya sure we're supposed to be here?
Don't sweat it! It's the perfect chance to snoop around!
Stop smiling like that!
This is Toshimi's wake!
Oh, sorry...
Kazuha,
did you bring the arrow with you?
Yes! I certainly did!
Huh?
It's that drunk...
he's already here.
You came too, Mouri-san?
Er... Yes...
By the way, Kadowaki-san didn't go home yesterday. Did you see him?
No, but I heard he was picking fights with tourists at the local tavern.
Drinkin' all night, huh?
Huh?
I don't see Naoko-san.
Her name was in the guestbook.
Is Naoko here?
She's probably in the restroom!
We'll go check
Okay,
good idea.
What, Ran-chan? You afraid of thunder?
That's not it!
There's someone outside!
You're right!
What's up?
Ah, Heiji...
There's someone outside!
Say what?!
That's...!