She’s been dead less than an hour.
Naoko Kuroe (28)
She was probably strangled then put in this net....
The footprints on the sand are from sandals and boots.
Naoko-san was probably wearin’ guest sandals from the house,
so the boots must belong to the killer.
But why would anyone do this to her?
Here’s your answer!
Look. Somebody stepped on an Arrow of Dugong.
Judging from the sandal prints,
Naoko-san must’ve dropped it and stepped on it
while she was struggling with the killer.
So the killer was after the arrow.
Well, if we follow the boot prints, we’ll find the killer.
Yeah.
Hey... The prints...
...go straight into the sea!
You’re right...
There’s something shiny around the prints.
What are they?
Looks like...
Scales...from a fish?
There’s a couple scales on Naoko-san’s clothes too.
What?
Hey!
What are you doing there?
Investigating the crime...
That’s the job of the Fukui Police!
Police?
So you’ve finally made it.
What?!
The killer's footprints disappeared into the sea?!
Yeah... and left some fish scales behind too!
Did you say fish scales...?!
You're not saying the killer's a mermaid...!?
How Stupid!
Mermaids don't wear rubber boots!
The killer probably approached from the shoreline and
then went up to the nets where Naoko was told to wait...
After murdering Naoko, the killer walked back to the shoreline
And left the scene walking through the water!
Now I get it...
By the way, did anyone see Naoko leave the room?
Not me ... she wasn't there when I got there...
Kimie Shimabukuro (27)
Benzo Kadowaki (52)
Rokuro Fukuyama (27)
Benzo, what about you?
You signed in right after Naoko, didn't you?
I didn't see her and nobody was in the room when I got there...
That means Naoko was the first one to get here
then she left to go where the nets were hung...
Wait a minute,
do you think the same person who killed Toshimi Killed Naoko too?
We don't know that for sure yet.
but we do know the killer took Naoko's arrow...
The dugong's arrow?
Before she disappeared, Saori also said that she'd lost her arrow,
do you think...
Yeah ... she might already be dead too...
I saw Saori near the Mermaid's waterfall on the morning of yesterday's festival.
Eh?
I saw her too.
She was far away and I only cought a glance, she was in the forest by the waterfall...
Are absolutely sure it was Saori?
No mistake, She was the only girl with brown hair and glasses...
And she always wears blue clothes...
Then she must be running away from something,
Saori Kadowaki (27)
That's why she's hiding from everyone!
Mr.Kadowaki, don't you have any idea what's happened?
Don't ask me... she never told me anything...
I just hope she hasn't turned into a mermaid like this dead girl...
Mermaid? What do you mean?
Didn't you know?
The legendary nun ate the meat of the mermaid that was cought in the net...
M-Mermaid!
If the arrow leaves your body, evil will overtake you,
women will return to the water and become silent mermaids...
Ka-Kazuha...
Never mind that, let's all go look for Saori in the morning!
Kazuha...
Stay close to me...
Heiji...
After that,
the police searched everybody at the funeral,
to see if the killer who stole Naoko-san’s arrow was still among us.
But the only people with arrows
were Benzo-san and Kazuha, who’d won them at the festival.
Hey, Kudo. Got any leads?
Not yet.
All I’ve noticed is that Toshimi-san and Naoko-san, the two confirmed victims,
and Saori-san, who’s missing,
all believed in Lady Mikoto’s powers
and were obsessed with the Arrow of Dugong.
Yeah. Too obsessed.
If we only knew who had which ticket at last night’s festival...
Oh, that’s easy!
We have everyone sign a list.
Would you like to come with me now and have a look at the list?
O-Of course!
Careful there!
Geez... Pull yourself together, Dad!
Kimie...
I know this isn’t the best time...
but have you thought about what I said?
I’m serious, you know.
I can’t.
Not after Toshimi’s death.
And I can’t leave this island and abandon Great-Grandma.
I’m sorry.
So all five of you went to school together, even college?
Yeah.
We were all big movie fans,
so in college we joined the film club,
and made our own film, “The Legend of Bikuni”!
When it won the gold medal at a film festival, we were so excited!
We were ready to go to Hollywood!
That’s cool!
But in the end, none of us could forget the island.
Who would have thought Toshimi and Naoko would end up like this?
Huh, that’s strange.
I’m sure I kept it here...
Isn’t it there?
It’s gone... Just this year’s.
Maybe the old lady took it.
That’s impossible!
Who else knew the entry books were here?
Most of the locals, I guess.
I’ll look through the other rooms.
Let me help you!
M-Me too...
Thank you.
They’re all here!
The old foreign minister...
the director of the Secretariat...
the president of the Bank of Japan!
Guess they all wanted to live forever...
Shiho Miyano?
Isn’t that... her real name?
Nah, it can’t be.
She’s not the type who’d care about eternal youth and beauty...
What’s the matter?
We just saw her! A woman with light hair and glasses!
She was starin’ at us!
You don’t mean...
Saori-san?!
Huh? What is this...
Why is this glass cracked?!
Where’s Kimie-san?
She said she was going to look through the new warehouse.
Where’s the warehouse?
She said it was behind the shrine.
Hey, check out that glow!
I-It couldn’t be...
The warehouse kept burning through the night.
It burned to the ground, just like it did three years ago.
Yes, just like three years ago,
there was a body inside.
A burned body!?
That's right... it was burned beyond recognition
but it had glasses on it.
You could just barely make out that it was wearing blue clothing...
It's probably... Saori... who was missing...
Th-Then the girl we saw last night...
Was a gh-ghost...
Kimie...
Kimie... where are you, Kimie...
Mikoto Shimabukuro (130)
Kimie...
Isn't Kimie back yet?
No, she's not...
I'll go stay with the great grandmother...
I'll go too...
Hey, Hattori...
didn't Kimie say she went to the dentist recently?
Yeah, she did...
You don't mean...
do you know what are you implying...
Don't fool me...
The same thought passed through your mind too, didn't it?
We both have the same bad feeling about this...
I-I see... Thank you very much.
Half a Day Later
Well? How’d it go?
They compared the teeth of the burnt body with Kimie-san’s dental records.
They were a perfect match.
That cannot be...
Kimie-san...
It’s not true...
It’s not true!
It can’t be true!
I see.
So Kimie has died...
I’m sorry, old  lady.
The killer swooped in the minute we took our eyes off her.
Another innocent young life snuffed out...
while an old fool like me lives on...
Hey, remember when you moved the mermaid’s grave into the forest?
Who did it for you?
It doesn’t matter.
That person has left this world as well...
Hey, old man!
Found anything?
No, nothing.
What kind of case is this?
We don’t have a suspect or a motive.
On top of that, we don't even know why Kimie was dressed like Saori...
Well, that was probably to make us think it was Saori who died...
Then the killer must be Saori...
Or it could be someone who wants us to think it is.
Huh?
Is that the ocean?
Yes, the ocean's right behind us last night...
Kimie told us that... last night...
Well, no matter who the killer is, one thing is for sure...
We've got to find the killer as soon as possible,
We can't let such a heartless killer run free!!
Dad!
What is it, Ran?
Someone just called Kimie-san’s place,
and the person on the other end said something weird!
Something weird?
“Thank you very much for selling us the arrow.”
“It was well worth the million yen. Our son’s operation was a success!”
They bought an arrow?
For a million yen?
They said a man who worked at the shrine sold it to them.
I bet it was that old couple who cancelled their tickets on the morning of the festival.
I think so too.
But who was the guy who sold them the arrow?
They didn’t know his name,
but they said he was a big guy, about 50 years old, with a stubby beard.
What did you say?!
Benzo-san?
Hey! If it was before the festival, then that arrow...
More than likely it was the arrow Saori said she lost.
And lucky for Benzo, he won an arrow at the festival and on top of that,
the register with all the names got lost...
Something's going on...
Naoko, who was killed on the day of Toshimi's wake, also
had her arrow stolen...
I'm going to the Ebihara's home where the wake was held.
Kudo, I mean... Mr.Mouri, please go and check Benzo's place!
What!?
Benzo-san left last night right after we did?
Yes. He went running out, looking pale.
It’s just like I thought. Benzo-san overheard us.
He heard us talkin’ about goin’ down to Kimie-san’s house to look at that notebook,
so he beat us there and stole it.
Then it was probably Benzo who set fire to the warehouse, right?
You're probably right...
If Kimie found him hanging around holding the registry...
What are you doing here?
Don't tell me you forgot !
You are the one who told me to stay close!
Oh... that's right...
Besides, since I have an arrow that's been blessed,
I'm your good luck charm!
You have nothing to worry about, if you're in danger, I'll protect you!!
Wow, I'm so lucky...
I'm serious... Heiji...
Now that Kimie-chan has died, I guess this year’s Dugong Festival will be the last.
I guess so...
Hey, you!
Could you show us again which footprints are yours?
Yeah, sure.
What the...
What’s wrong, Heiji?
A dent on the bottom of the sandal...
It’s still fresh...
Where are the sandals Naoko was wearing?
They were taken to the Fukui Police Department.
Kazuha, lend me that arrow of yours, okay?
A perfect match.
This is the sandal that stepped on the Arrow of Dugong on the sand.
Which means...
It’s just like I thought.
Aw rats! I knew it, no one's home!
Hey, what're you people doing here?
Well, uh, we wanted to talk to Benzo,
do you know where he is?
I haven't seen him since the wake last night...
What bad timing...
we thought at least we could take a look at the missing Saori's room...
If you want to get inside, take a look under the potted plant
That's where the key is.
Let's see now...
Aha, I found it...!
Alright, let's do it!
Are you sure it's alright to go in without permission?
He won't mind, we'll just have a fast look!
Hey, how did Saori act just before she disappeared?
Oh... well,
She was scared, even when the ocean got rough...
she said mermaid was going to punish her...
Punish her...?
Here’s Saori’s room...
What’s this bag?
What’s in it?
Conan-kun!
Aspirin, toothbrush...
Saori’s run-away kit.
She usually just stayed over at Kimie’s place.
She left clothes and an extra pair of glasses there.
So you mean... the clothes Kimie was wearing
when she was found in the warehouse,
she could have put them on herself?
How stupid, why'd she have to go and do that for...
Maybe to lure the killer out...
Just kidding!
Ha ha ha... that's ridiculous...
But if Kimie thought the killer was after Saori too
and if she saw someone suspicious hanging around the house,
she might have done what Conan said so that she could catch the killer...
You are crazy,
last night during the fire,
didn't you say you saw someone who looked like Saori in the yard?
Hey, is there a photo of Saori-san around here?
There should be a photo album somewhere.
Ran, was this the person you saw in the garden?
I don’t know. It was dark.
Are these photos from the time you guys made your own movie about the legendary nun?
Yeah.
Let me see...
This is great!
It really looks like a mermaid’s swimming in the sea!
Yeah... And this storm scene looks so real...
The movie won at the film festival
mostly because of Saori’s visual effects and Kimie’s special-effects make-up.
but 1 year after that, there really was a storm
and both of Kimie's parents, as well as mine and Saori's mother were lost at sea.
Not one of us dreamed anything like that would happen...
Wait a sec...
Her account book, bank card, name seal, driver’s license and passport are all here,
but I can’t find one thing!
It couldn’t be...
Don’t tell me...!
Hattori here...
Oh, Kudo—I mean, old man!
Perfect timing. I was just about to phone ya!
Remember the sandal prints on the beach?
I found a sandal with a dent mark
from stepping on an arrow.
It proves the killer left the funeral room,
walked out to the fishing net where Naoko-san was waiting,
killed her, then went back to the room again!
The only two people who could’ve done that were Benzo-san, and Rokuro-san.
But seeing how upset Rokuro-san was that afternoon,
I find it hard to believe he’d hurt Kimie-san.
Which means the killer’s gotta be...
Hattori, here’s my deduction. Listen to me.
Oh, go ahead.
You idiot! That’s crazy talk!
I ain’t gonna swallow that!
Hattori...
When you have eliminated the impossible,
whatever remains, however improbable,
must be the truth!
What?
Inspector!
We’ve located Benzo Kadowaki on the mountain! We’re in pursuit!
Good. Let’s go, men!
Look, I’ll hook up with ya after we arrest Benzo-san!
Just wait for me!
Heiji!
I don’t want to believe it either, Hattori...
It’s not true! It can’t be!
I’m not buyin’ it, Kudo!
Huh?
You smell incense?
Ya kiddin’ me?
Who’d burn incense up here on the...
“Danger - Cliff Ahead”
A grave...
The grave of that so-called mermaid...
If that’s the case...
The person Kudo fingered...
really is the killer.
The cliff!
Kazuha!