H...
Heiji...
H-Hold on, Kazuha...
I-I'll pull ya up in a sec...
No...
The branch...
It's gonna break...
At this rate, both of us...
I'm sorry, Heiji...
But you've gotta live...
For both of us!
K-Kazuha?!
Bye-bye...
You fool!
Naoko Kuroe (28)
a Fisherman
Hey, Detective!
I brought you the guy you were asking for.
Benzo Kadowaki (52)
Saori's father
this guy's been running all over the forest...
First, where's the kid from Osaka?
We lost track of him on the mountain.
H-Heiji, why?
Why didn't you let go?
We'll both die if we stay like this...
Let go of my hand...
Kazuha!
D-Don't ya move!
If ya move, I'll kill ya!
Heiji...
What's wrong, Hattori?
Why haven't you shown up?
What're you doing?
C'mon already! How long do we have to wait?
We're busy people, you know.
Mikoto Shimabukuro (130)
Kimie's great-grandmother
L-Lady Mikoto?
What's Lady Mikoto doing here?
Well, then. Now that everybody's here, I'd better get started.
Time for the truth behind these three murders.
The first victim, Toshimi-san, was hanged from the Waterfall of the Mermaid.
The second victim, Naoko-san, was strangled and entangled in a fishing net.
And the third victim, Kimie-san, died in the warehouse fire.
The important issue here is the second murder.
From the situation at the crime scene,
it looks like the killer walked along the shore to get to and from the crime scene,
with the footprints being washed away by the waves.
That kid from Osaka explained that already...
Yes, he told me too...
Those foorprints were put there by the killer before the murder to throw us of track...
and the killer really snuck in and out of the funeral hall.
those fish scales really had me fooled...
the killer dropped the scales around the footprints
then on Naoko's clothes after killing her, that way,
with the scales leading to the water, the killer made it look like a mermaid act & that it escaped into the ocean...
And the only people who could've snuck out of the funeral at that time...
...were Rokuro-san and Benzo-san.
It couldn't be...
Let me ask you something, Benzo-san.
On the morning of the festival,
you sold an Arrow of Dugong to an elderly couple for 1,000,000 yen, right?
Yeah. The arrow my daughter Saori won last year.
I'm her guardian, so I got every right to do what I want with it.
That 1,000,000 yen whetted your appetite for more money.
After Toshimi-san won an arrow this year,
you lured her to the top of the waterfall and killed her to steal her winning ticket!
You put her body in a swim ring so it wouldn't get stuck in the river!
But that wasn't all.
Next, Naoko-san, who'd also won an arrow at the festival—
you called her out on the night of the funeral, killed her and stole her arrow!
But if the records at the shrine were checked,
everyone would find out that Toshimi-san's ticket was stolen.
So you went to Kimie-san's house before we got there to steal the notebook,
but Kimie-san caught you, so you locked her in the warehouse and burned it down!
This notebook you had when we caught you is proof!
We found your fingerprints on that inner tube!
No. Benzo-san didn't do it.
If Benzo-san were the killer,
he could've destroyed the notebook in the warehouse fire.
All the locals knew where to find the notebook anyway.
I don't think he'd have to rush over to steal it.
Another thing, it would have been very hard for him to call Naoko out...
Naoko noticed that Toshimi won an arrow at the festival too,
and she was suspicious of Benzo who had that winning number...
What about his prints on the swim ring?
He probably found the ticket and the swim ring floating in the river.
He must've touched the swim ring while trying to pick up the ticket.
Yeah, the detective's right.
I was afraid everybody would think I was the killer, if they knew whose ticket I had
so I stole the notebook...
Then, Rokuro Fukuyama, you must be the killer!
What? That's ridiculous!
Toshimi was your fiancee, wasn't she?
She could have gone to meet you at the waterfall with no suspicions...
No, it wasn't him, either.
What?
The killer used the swim ring trick to hang Toshimi-san.
She'd float down the waterfall without getting caught on anything.
That way it would look like an accident.
But being a fisherman, Rokuro-san has very strong arms,
and Toshimi-san wasn't very heavy,
so it would have been easier for him to just toss her into the river.
He wouldn't have had to use a swim ring, which would only be left behind as evidence.
But if neither of them is the killer, then who is?
The killer made it look like Toshimi-san's death was an accident,
but made no attempt to hide the fact that Naoko-san was murdered.
Do you know what that means?
Well, uh... No, I don't...
When Toshimi-san was killed,
the police didn't arrive right away because the sea was too rough.
Normally, the police would have arrived sometime that night.
And since it was a case of murder,
the investigation would have been intense.
The killer wouldn't have been able to move about freely.
That's why it had to look like an accident.
Which means the killer planned to kill Naoko-san and Toshimi-san from the start.
But no one would have known Naoko had won an arrow until she came forward.
That's right.
The killer's motive wasn't to steal an arrow,
nor was it to kill whoever won it.
It was only made to look that way to mislead the investigation!
You mean...
The reason the killer made it obvious that Naoko-san was murdered
was so that everyone's attention was on the scene of the crime.
The killer used that time to carry out the third murder!
The killer planned and executed each crime very carefully.
It wasn't on a whim.
The only person who could have prepared everything before the festival is...
Y-You don't mean...
Someone who knew beforehand
that Toshimi-san and Naoko-san were going to win arrows.
That's right.
The killer is you!
The killer is you, Lady Mikoto!
You've gotta be kidding!
How could someone who's 130 years old do that?
What if she had an accomplice?
Accomplice?
If neither Rokuro-san nor Benzo-san could have killed Naoko-san,
then the only other person who could have done it
was Kimie-san.
T-That's impossible...
Kimie was the third victim!
What if the victim in the warehouse fire wasn't Kimie-san?
What?
But Kimie-san just told us she went to the dentist!
And those dental records matched the body...
You heard that too, didn't you, Dad?
When Kimie-san said she went to the dentist...
Yes, I heard.
She said she went to a dentist on the mainland with Saori-san.
T-Then...
That's right.
Saori-san was the one with the dental appointment.
Kimie-san went with Saori-san to see the dentist on the mainland.
Kimie-san stole Saori-san's health insurance certificate from her bag in advance,
and offered to let Saori use her own certificate.
That's how Saori-san got her teeth fixed as Kimie-san.
Then Kimie-san killed Saori-san and locked her body in the shrine's warehouse.
She set the warehouse on fire later
so we'd think Kimie-san was the victim when we checked her dental records!
Then the person with light hair and glasses we saw in the garden...
Kimie-san in disguise.
that's who the witnesses saw on the morning of the festival too...
it was to make us suspicious about the body found in the warehouse
and to make Saori look guilty...
But this is all just guesswork, isn't it?
I phoned the dentist to check.
The Kimie-san he treated had light hair and glasses.
Then Kimie Shimabukuro is still hiding somewhere on this island,
waiting for an opportunity to escape!
Alright then, I'll have this entire island searched from top to bottom!
There's no need for that.
What?
Kimie-san is right here in this room.
Say what?!
Where? Where is she?!
That can't be...
I don't see her anywhere!
You know, don't you, Rokuro-san?
Kimie's make-up skills were good enough to win her a gold medal.
Y-Yeah...
Are you saying she's disguised herself as somebody?
This isn't a movie. It wouldn't work.
Of course, it's hard to pull off a perfect disguise.
But what if it's someone who doesn't show herself to others very much?
And what if the only time everyone sees her is at the festival, when she has on very heavy make-up?
Now your choices have been narrowed down significantly.
T-That's... impossible...
B-But her height...
Think back.
Remember that strange body you found three years ago in the remains of the old warehouse?
The one missing its bones from the waist down,
and the locals said it was a mermaid's body?
It was probably the body of a woman whose legs had been bent and tied behind her.
If my deduction is correct, that woman was Kimie-san's...
My mother.
She took over the Lady Mikoto role from my grandmother,
and kept performing it for the islanders.
It's the sad end of a pitiful woman...
K-Kimie?
I'm impressed, Mr. Detective.
I was pretty confident about this make-up job.
It was that time when we found that the notebook was missing.
Maybe the old lady took it.
That's impossible!
You said that without even thinking about it.
I see.
But when we were talking to Lady Mikoto, we heard Kimie-san's voice...
Great-Grandma! Your bath's ready!
Oh, that? I recorded it on tape and played it back.
But why, Kimie?
The three of them and you have been friends since you were kids!
That wasn't enough to stop me from avenging my mother's death.
That fire at the warehouse three years ago...
Exactly.
They didn't win an arrow at the festival,
so they got drunk and set the warehouse on fire,
after seeing my mother, disguised as Lady Mikoto, go inside.
Guess they wanted to see if she really was immortal.
Saori panicked and told me the whole story recently,
the week after she lost her arrow.
But I thought your mother died five years ago while she was out fishing...
She'd been playing Lady Mikoto for a while, and my make-up job was getting better.
We decided to fake her death so she'd only have to play one role.
Then why didn't you tell us after the fire that it was your mother who died?
Mom called me on her cell phone while the flames burned around her...
Kimie... Take care of the people for me...
I love this island... so don't let Lady Mikoto die!
But...
You know what Saori said after losing her arrow?
If I can't have another arrow, tell me where the mermaid is buried!
The mermaid bones that the Holy Person had hidden in the warehouse, where are they buried?
I want to be like her too... like the Holy Person... I want to be immortal, so not even a burning building can kill me!
I couldn't forgive them.
Not Toshimi, not Naoko...
It was easy to get them alone.
I just told them I'd show them where the grave was if they won arrows at the festival.
Their eyes lit up with excitement.
The mermaid's grave is my mother's.
We worked so hard together, all alone...
You weren't alone.
Hattori!
You weren't the only ones who knew the secret of Lady Mikoto.
Ain't that right?
That old man said this would be the last festival 'cause Kimie-san had died.
I-I meant...
I'm sorry, Kimie-chan.
Most of the old folks on the island knew the truth.
No...
And we knew it was your mother who died in that fire three years ago.
After the fire, we talked it over and decided to tell you to end the festival.
But after seeing you disguised as Lady Mikoto,
we couldn't bring ourselves to say anything.
After all, this is Mermaid Island.
And if you wanted to continue Lady Mikoto...
We decided to keep quiet, and help whenever we could...
We know you did it for the island. We're sorry.
Forgive us, Kimie-chan...
No... No...
Why couldn't you have told me before?
Yeah, you guys needed to snap out of it.
Immortality ain't nothin' but a nightmare.
Life's valuable 'cause it's short.
We gotta do our best with the time we got.
Right, Kazuha?
In the morning,
everybody from the island came out to see Kimie-san off to the Fukui police station.
But a storm at sea stopped the ship from leaving,
as if refusing to part with the shrine maiden who had supported the island alone
for three long years.
When I called Saori the first time, that moan I heard,
that was probably Kimie crying...
She was probably crying while looking at Saori's body in the warehouse...
But what I don't understand is
why Saori sent a letter carry the name Kudo addressed to me
Maybe it was just coincidence?
Oh, Mr. Mouri-san and Hattori-kun!
Huh?
I know you, aren't you...
That's how we met for the first time,
on that diplomat, Mr. Tsujimura's murder case...
That's the victim's son, Takayoshi & his girlfriend, Yukiko...
Long time no see
Yukiko Katsuragi
Takayoshi Tsujimura
Did you by chance go to Bikuni Island because Saori contacted you?
Eh? How did you know that?
Yukiko's from that island
And Saori used to live next door, she asked Yukiko for some advice...
I see Kudo-kun haven't come with you...
how disappointing, after I told her he was the most reliable one...
So it was you!
You were behind that misleading letter...
Now I remember, I did change back into my body's true form that one time...
By the way, did something happen on the island?
We arrived on the island today but everyone seemed to be in such a rush,
We just decided to take the next ship back...
Well... Maybe it's better if youu didn't know...
Why'd you pick today to come?
The festival was 2 days ago, you know
We didn't come for the festival, we came for the seafood
It's cheap, delicious and the scenery's great!
People are starting to talk about it!
I see...
even without the Dugong Festival, the island will still attract tourists then...
Guess so...
I just hope their wounds heal quickly...
Hey, Hattori-kun, show me the wound!
W-What's gotten into you?
What? Come on...
That's the wound of love that Kazuha-chan marked you with!
H-Hey, Ran-chan!
Oh, that.
The scab had already come off when I woke up this mornin'.
It's all healed up now.
No way!
I should've stabbed you deeper...
Hey, what?
But I'm glad your hand's better.
Now I don't have to listen to you whine about it anymore!
Kazuha-chan, wait up!
That dope.
She got me all fired up back there.
I'm never...
I'm never gonna let anything happen to that girl.
Quit trying to look tough.