A brave heart and incredible deductions,
a rhythm that jumps to the truth.
This is a unique mystery.
A prosperous business leads to a case!
Seeing the one and only truth...
A kid with the intellect of an adult...
His name is... Detective Conan!
The Secret of the High Sales
Teitan Primary School
A suspicious man?
Yeah.
Doesn't your family own a restaurant?
I know that restaurant! It's the Manpuku!
Yeah.
But it's dark and dirty, and the food is disgusting,
so the place is always empty.
Sorry.
So, why do you think that man is suspicious?
It's because, two months ago, he appeared out of nowhere.
Hello, my name is Kamekura Yuuji. I owe a favor
to the deceased owner and I'd like to repay him.
Kamekura Yuuji (28)
To my deceased husband?
What kind of favor?
I owe him something so important
that I can't express it with words.
So, to demonstrate my enormous gratitude,
I would like to stay here and work for you.
You want to live with us?
B-But we don't have the money to hire another worker.
I'm not asking to be paid!
I just want to return the favor.
Please let me stay and work for you.
Alright, let's get to work!
And so, he invited himself to live with us.
I think there is something wrong, because my grandfather
who died was selfish and had a bad personality.
I'm sure that he never did a favor for anyone.
I'm sure that that man is after something.
That's why I want the Detective Boys to discover what it is.
Why?
I thought it would be an interesting case, but it's only
a liar that has intruded into someone's home.
I think that he is planning a crime!
I say the same thing!
Me too!
Everything about it sounds really suspicious.
Haibara...
All right! The time has come for the Detective Boys to work!
Yeah!
Good luck, Edogawa-kun.
I would really like to go, but I have other things to attend to.
Bye bye!
Hey, don't leave us Haibara!
What?!
Are you serious?
This is the Manpuku restaurant?
Surprised?
But the restaurant is clean.
And look at how many people are waiting to enter.
It's all because of that man.
We haven't had any customers today.
Well, there is nobody around, like always.
After all, there are a lot of clean restaurants
with delicious food out there.
This is not good.
I know!
Since I have a lot of experience as a chef,
I am going to teach you guys how to cook and redecorate
the shop so that it attracts more customers.
Redecorate it?
I will pay for all of it, so don't worry about it.
I just want to repay him for when he helped me.
Okay?
Ever since then, the restaurant has been doing great.
What's suspicious about him using his own money to
redecorate the restaurant to show his gratitude?
It seems like he's a very grateful man.
I know!
He wants to make the business boom and
then run off with the profit, right?
Do you think that's what he's planning?
If that's what he wanted, then why is he helping you?
Wouldn't it be faster to just find a profitable
restaurant in the first place?
Ah, I see.
Geez... A crime? What a stupid idea.
Hey, what's that?
What is it?
"I am thinking of a new menu. Please
do not disturb. Kamekura."
Well, he has been in his room day and
night creating a new menu for us.
He won't let us enter because he says
he wants to keep his menu a secret—
Rintaro!
We have a lot of work to do. Since
you are here, give us a hand.
Come on, say goodbye to your friends.
Now I understand.
If the shop has a lot of work,
the family will spend most of its time working.
During that time, he's in his room doing something secret.
This, without a doubt, reminds
me of The Red-Headed League!
It can't be.
Now I understand!
Guys, I am sure this is the same as The Red-Headed League.
Of course, The Red-Headed League!
And, what's that?
The Red-Headed League is one of the 60 famous
cases that Sherlock Holmes investigated.
A man worked for a store as an employee, and convinced
the owner to leave by finding him another job.
While the owner was working, he dug an underground
tunnel to rob the bank next door.
It was a grand and very daring crime.
Thanks for the complete explanation.
However, I would like to add that it was
written more than 100 years ago.
I doubt that there is a thief nowadays that has the
patience to dig a tunnel to steal something.
What are you guys doing?!
If he's digging a tunnel, we should be able to hear it.
Don't be so foolish!
I'll prove it!
Prove it, you say?
It's that guy.
Yeah.
What's going on, Rintaro-kun?
Well...
Mister, sorry to bother you while you're busy,
but you're like a god of good fortune!
Ever since you've arrived, the restaurant
has been doing great!
If you show me your hands, I'll check your good fortune line.
My hands?
Sure, of course!
Look at them however long you want.
T-Those are...
It can't be.
Hey, hey, hey, what did his good fortune line say?
I wasn't looking at that.
There were a lot of blisters and calluses on his hands.
They're hands that have been using a shovel.
It's hard to believe, but he is digging a hole under the house.
I told you so, I knew I was right.
Amazing, Mitsuhiko-kun!
Mitsuhiko figured it out this time!
Could something like this seriously be happening?
Anyway, we need to find where he's digging a tunnel to.
Conan-kun!
I get it now. The nearest bank to the
Manpuku restaurant is on this side.
But, it's closed.
Closed
It's been closed for more than a week.
It can't be his objective.
You were wrong, it looks like you've failed again, Conan.
Then, the place the thief is interested in has to be closer.
Ah, there's a jewelry store!
It's impossible for our jewelry store to be robbed, kids.
After a previous incident, we installed a
security system that can't be breached.
A bad experience?
Yes, that's right, little lady.
One day, a thief stole 3 million yen worth of jewels.
The truth is, the thief hasn't been captured yet.
A jewel thief, and he hasn't been captured?
Then it is possible that...
Can you tell us when those jewels were stolen?
Well this coming month would make five years.
Then I don't think...
A jewel thief, and a suspicious man
digging a tunnel underground.
I understand now!
Mitsuhiko!
Mitsuhiko-kun!
Hey Mitsuhiko, don't tell me you're thinking that!
Hey! Mitsuhiko.
I have to go, I'm very busy.
Thanks.
What did you ask her, Mitsuhiko?
I've solved the case!
The man named Kamekura is, without a doubt, the
thief that robbed the jewelry store five years ago!
He's the jewel thief?!
Seriously?!
I am convinced that my hypothesis is correct.
I also thought the same thing, but that
deduction has many dark spots.
However, this thief is not stupid at all.
If he sold all the jewels at once, he would
have been found out and captured.
It was also risky to keep the jewels during
all of those years, so he buried them.
He probably buried them under Rintaro's house,
as it was being reconstructed at that time.
How did you know that the house was being reconstructed?
Is that what you were asking the woman earlier?
Exactly.
Kamekura came into their house as a worker
so that he could dig little by little,
and in this simple way recover all his stolen jewels.
You're incredible, Mitsuhiko!
What a perfect deduction, amazing!
Come on, come on. It wasn't much.
You're amazing. Even though I thought the same thing...
Why did he wait for five years?
You still don't get it, Conan-kun?
It's pretty obvious that he was waiting until
the five year crime expiration ran out.
So, pretty soon he can dig them up and
sell them all without a problem.
You are correct in that the prosecution
for a criminal case is five years.
However, the expiration period of a civil crime is 20 years.
Even if he gets the jewels now, they won't belong to him.
We don't know the laws by heart.
If we didnt know that detail, surely
the thief doesn't know either.
H-Hey!
You just have to argue about everything,
don't you Conan-kun?
My mother always tells me that sometimes it's better
to just accept things without arguing back.
That's not the problem...
Let's go to the police right away and tell them that
he's the jewel thief that they're looking for.
Yeah!
We don't have proof. You're going to humiliate yourselves!
That's fine, all we have to do is catch him red handed.
How are you going to do that?
We will lay a trap.
A trap? Hey...
Ah, it's you guys again. Do you want
to see the palm of my hand?
We came to tell you that we know.
Eh, what did you say?
You can't easily trick the Detective Boys.
So goodbye.
Goodbye!
Now the only thing we have to do is
wait for him to fall into our trap.
And what is supposed to happen now?
He is going to panic, make a mistake, and we'll discover it.
Well yeah.
It's perfect.
How is it possible for an adult to be scared by
a threat from a bunch of primary school kids?
The Next Morning
What? The whole family is going
to a hot spring this weekend?
Yes, that man recommended to my father that we should go,
because we haven't rested a day since
the reopening of the restaurant.
And of course, that man isn't going.
Yeah, he says only family members should go.
This way he can get everybody to
leave, so he can finish digging.
Of course. That must be it!
I told you, Conan! He fell into our trap and is hurrying to dig.
It can't be.
Is this really happening?
I don't have the slightest idea of what's happening.
Seems like this case is confusing you.
Well, why would a criminal panic over
a few words said by some kids?
It's unbelievable! There are a bunch
of things that don't make any sense!
Kudo-kun...
Maybe you are confused because this criminal doesn't do
the same things as the criminals you usually handle.
What do you mean by that?
He is a very simple person.
I'm even more confused now.
It looks like Conan-kun has lost his confidence.
Yeah, this time he's really depressed.
I hope he doesn't rebel and become a juvenile delinquent.
That could happen.
I wouldn't like it if that happened to a friend.
Are you sure you don't want to come with us?
No, I have a friend that lives around here
and I already made plans with him.
Well, have a good time!
What luck! Before we couldn't even
afford to have a day of rest.
And thanks to Kamekura-kun, the restaurant is doing great!
We're lucky that such a good man came to our home.
Looks like everyone just left.
Now to wait for Kamekura to return home.
Are you going to wait all night? What if he doesn't show up?
What are we going to tell our parents?
Look, there he is!
Now all we have to do is get into the restaurant with the
key that Rintaro left us, and catch him red handed.
Really...
Are you alright, Conan-kun?
I've been digging for days and still haven't found anything.
I couldn't have buried them too deep.
There they are!
I found them!
I found them! The jewels, the jewels, my precious treasure!
Hold it right there!
We now know that you buried the jewels.
I'm sorry.
Well, we aren't the police, so we can't arrest you.
Come on, let's go, Conan-kun.
Go where? What?
Well, what else? Aren't you going to
tell the criminal your deductions?
We left the best part for you.
Because you haven't done much this time.
But, I have nothing to say to him!
Come on, go ahead.
Good luck, Conan-kun!
Kamekura-san, five years ago you entered a jewelry
store and stole three million yen's worth of jewels.
Don't contradict me, I know what I say is true.
Well yeah, that's what happened.
Hey, you just admitted your crime.
But, I'm not an idiot.
I know that, if I sold them, the police would locate me.
So, I saw that this house was being reconstructed,
buried the jewels underground, and ran.
I then worked day after day so the
police wouldn't suspect me.
I had to bear everything.
Such as being screamed at and hit by my boss.
Even my friends stopped working as apprentices
because they couldn't stand him.
Except for me.
I believed that, in five years, those jewels would be mine.
That's what inspired me to keep going,
no matter what would happen.
And finally, after five years, the time has come!
I couldn't wait for the crime expiration date to pass.
I wanted to dig right away.
That's why you invented a story to work
here and start digging up the jewels.
But it wasn't easy, since there weren't any customers.
The family members were always sitting around the house.
There was no chance for you to do anything.
So, you decided to spend your own
savings to renovate this restaurant,
and teach them some cooking skills that you've learned.
Thus, making the business prosper.
You made it so the entire family was in the
restaurant and kept busy the whole time.
This way, you could start your work
digging and looking for the jewels.
Isn't that right, Kamekura Yuuji-san?
That's exactly how it was.
We hit the bulls eye. We're awesome!
There's one thing I don't understand though.
Why did you start panicking? Just because some primary
school kids told you that they knew everything?
It's because I'm such a coward. I even got scared
after hearing the words "Detective Boys".
I see...
It's impossible for a normal adult to be afraid just because
a bunch of little kids say a bunch of nonsense.
Why didn't you just send all of them
to the hot spring from the start?
It would have been easier, cheaper, and faster,
if you gave them a free trip instead of wasting that money,
reforming the restaurant, and waiting for it to prosper.
What an absurd plan!
You're right.
That's true.
I guess that does make sense.
Why didn't you do that then?
I hadn't thought of that.
This case is closed.
Haibara-san.
Convinced?
Haibara.
Didn't I tell you before that this man was way simpler
than the other criminals you have encountered?
They're already here, I called them.
Incredible! Maybe we'll be rewarded by the police.
That would be great!
Right?
I'm sure they will. After all, you guys did a great job.
You think that?
Yes, without a doubt.
I suppose we did.
I hate this. Even after solving the case, I feel horrible.
I hate this!
We received a letter of thanks for helping in the jewel
thief's arrest before the case's expiration period.
We did it.
It was so easy this time.
Hey, I need to say something.
You know that most criminals aren't as idiotic as this one.
So don't let your guard down because of this.
It was dangerous to follow him like we did.
Eh? What's wrong with you, Conan-kun?
You have been very jittery lately.
You must've felt humiliated since we
stole your thunder, right Conan?
What's wrong with you Genta-kun? Don't you see that
Conan-kun is sulking cause of what's happened?
Cheer up, Conan-kun. It doesn't really matter.
I'm really sorry, Conan. It's really nothing.
You idiots...
My intelligence should be used in
solving complex criminal cases,
where our brains engage in a spectacular battle of wits.
I don't really care about these minor cases at all!