Song by Rina Aiuchi
Koi Wa, Thrill, Shock, Suspense
koi wa thrill, shock, suspense
mienai chikara tayori ni
kokoro no tobira tozasazu ni tsuyoku... tsuyoku...
Never ignore the power of deduction.
Its limits rely on the wielder!
Today we visit the game center.
We'll be playing a case!
Recognizing that single truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is Detective Conan!
watashi ga kanjiteita
toge o kimi ni no onaji you ni
ataeteita no kamo shirenakatta
nani ni kokoro o itamete nani ni obieteita no ka
ki ni mo tomezu motsureteku futari no shinjitsu ni
mukiau no ga kowakatta
This love is thrill, shock, suspense
mayoi o aoi kaze ni chirasou
toshite mo kakaekirezu ni ita yo
kono chisana mune ni wa
kokoro no tobira tozasazu ni
tsugi e to susumu arata na fuan to
mayoi o kakaeteshimaisou ni natte mo
The Battle Game Trap
(Part 1)
The Battle Game Trap, Part 1!
Look!
This is it!
I knew a place Sonoko likes wouldn't be too bad.
Right, right?
This place is far from school, not many know about it.
Look!
We can take a wedding photo.
No way, that wasn't there yesterday.
What's this?
This is so cute!
We should take one.
W-W-Wait a second!
We can take pictures seperately as well.
And with different looks.
Sonoko?
I get it, Sonoko...
You want to give a photo to Kyougoku-san, don't you?
It's like when Araide-sensei got a
fan letter from a girl and said...
"Is it alright to send photos of your face to others?"
The same, right?
E-Excuse me, Ran...
But I wouldn't do something like that.
Really?
But it's sad, Araide-sensei has been so busy since he quit
as the basketball coach and joined the drama club.
Now that Shinichi-kun isn't around, Sensei
is the most popular person at school.
Oh Sonoko, that's right.
The new English teacher Jodie is popular, too.
The one with the revealing clothes?
All of the guys like having a teacher that wears such clothes.
Don't you wear them as well?
But she still teaches well.
She's too serious all the time and doesn't make it fun.
She's always so reserved.
She wears such revealing clothes.
We finally got an American at our school
and she doesn't even tell jokes.
Hey, come on!
Jodie-sensei!
Why are you here, at an arcade?
Oh, Mouri-san, Suzuki-san!
Huh? Sensei?
Hey, aren't those Teitan uniforms?
She's a high-school teacher?
There's no way.
No no no no, you've got the wrong person.
You always come to this arcade after school...
Jodie-sensei?
Yes, Japanese games are beautiful and exciting!
In America, everyone loves Japanese games!
Jodie Saintemillion (28)
Teitan High School Teacher
There are always long lines to play in arcades there.
Sometimes you don't even get to play.
I've always loved playing these games.
She's a gamer?
Then, the school doesn't know...
Yes, if they find out it'll be the end.
It's so hard for an American to find a job in Japan, you see.
So let's keep this our little secret.
No one has to know, right?
But this is great!
You're like Billy the Kid.
Oh! Do you all want to play something more exciting?
It's the number one fighting game.
Great Fighter Spirit?
I've never seen this.
Now, sit, sit.
Put on your headgear...
A coin for stand by...
Now we pick the player character.
Are you ready?
Punch with the right lever to start, OK?
OK.
Ready?
Go!
That stings...
Ran!
Right, a player actually feels the hits
in this virtual fighting game.
I guess it's too much for girls?
Look, Ran! There, there!
Hey, hey...
You win!
Great! Ran is a well known karate champion!
Oh, Champ?
I'll kill you.
Huh? Someone's joining?
What? What?
Ran...
That player over there has challenged you.
Eh? No way.
Be careful...
He is terrific!
He's very skilled.
Fight!
You lose!
Ah, you lost...
Oh no!
Now that you've lost, it's time to move, girl.
That seat is reserved for skilled players like me.
Bitou Kengo (21)
Unemployed
What are you talking about?
Ran, you must take revenge, revenge!
There's no use.
It's because he doesn't just use his hands and feet, he also
uses the punchkey to apply full force in his attacks.
Dejima Hotoshi (22)
Store Employee
You won't beat him on your first try.
You, hurry this up!
This seat was made for me.
Jeez, what's with that guy's attitude?
He's the local champion that uses the character Beika Caesar.
He's joined some gang recently and developed
even more of an attitude problem.
Taxi Driver
Emori Toshitsugu (41)
By the way girl, your actions have too much force.
It's just a game, so don't use so much force.
Look at him over there.
Watch how he only moves his body slightly.
You watched our fight?
Yeah, I saw it on the big screen.
Uusually there's only a scrolling image there,
but when a match begins it shows it there.
If someone could beat him they'd become the champion.
Haido Lucas.
Game Journalist
Shimizu Takayasu (30)
I fit the part, eh?
Oh, I've been waiting, partner. Let's do this.
Wait, I'm gonna smoke.
Let's go now, Jodie-sensei.
Why?
Right right, this isn't the only arcade.
Then, let's play this racing game please, one more chance?
Jeez...
Well...
You're amazing! Keep going!
Hey, you're gonna get the high-score!
I guess she's a big gamer.
Fight!
Those two guys are fighting now.
Forget them and watch this.
But, something is...
He's good...
Who's winning? This game doesn't have a hit-point gauge!
Yeah...
After being hit in the face, it turns blue.
The one who beat me is winning right now.
Look.
Wow...
Wow, looks like that's the final blow.
Haido Lucas just didn't have it today.
The opponent can't even get up.
It'll only take one more hit until he wins.
Hey, what's going on?
He better hurry, time's running out!
Draw!
Jeez, that moron.
He would have won with just one more hit.
Hey, what's up with him?
D-Dead...
Eh? Someone died battling in a game?
Is that true?
Yes.
We were all watching the fight as
it happened on this big screen.
Right when he was about to win, he stopped moving.
That's all...
And after checking the body, you all discovered he was dead?
The victim is Bitou Kengo-san, 21 years old.
He was unemployed.
He has a reputation for bad behavior at this game center.
I see, so he has enemies here.
Ah, Mouri-san, do you know him?
Yes, he's my dad's old partner.
This is my high-school's English teacher.
English Teacher?
Yes.
My name is Jodie Saintemillion.
It's nice to meet you.
My name is Juuzou Megure.
I am Japanese "poriceman."
"Porice?"
It's not "poriceman," it's "policeman."
Oh, "poriceman?"
No no no no, policeman, ok?
"Poriceman?"
Inspector...
Anyway, the problem is how he died playing a game.
Yes.
The witnesses said that no one entered the game
center or got near the victim during the match.
Bitou-san couldn't have ate anything during
the game, so that rules out a suicide.
But, why is he wearing this stuff to play a game?
It's a virtual reality game.
When hit by the opponent, the player
feels pain in the impacted area.
The player feels pain?
Yeah, when you're hit by the opponent, you'll feel pain.
This causes the players arms and legs to move,
Making the fight seem real.
Hey hey, could it be...
He died...
Because of that pain?
Ah, no.
That's just not possible.
Even though it's pain, it's still only a mild vibration.
Hey, how can that kill someone?
It isn't strong enough, right?
Who are you exactly?
I am the one that was fighting with
him in the game before he died.
This shouldn't make me a murder suspect.
I was the one who lost.
I only got in a few good hits.
I lost even while chewing my special gum.
Is that true?
Yes.
He was losing the entire match.
We still don't know how he died, right?
Yeah, we couldn't find any apparent physical injuries.
Maybe he was poisoned?
Look, he looks like he died due to suffocation,
but there are no marks on his neck.
I guess it isn't poison then.
But Conan-kun, he died playing a game.
He didn't eat while playing the game.
And if he would have eaten something before,
His body would have been weak and his
face would have changed color, right?
Did any of you notice that?
No, I didn't.
Before this battle, the victim beat Ran.
But couldn't it have been injected through a needle?
Wouldn't he have been angry with whoever had done it?
Everyone would have noticed him yelling.
Really?
Right, right.
But Inspector, aren't you forgetting something?
This is a game center.
It's quiet right now because the games are
off, but usually it's very loud in here.
And not to mention, his hands and
feet are bound to the game chair.
Usually it's very dark in here so the
games will work correctly, right?
I see, the victim wouldn't have been able
to yell for help even if he was attacked.
And if everyone here was looking at the screen,
He could have been poisoned.
Alright!
Order an autopsy immediately and find the cause of death.
Right!
Uh huh...
First, find the suspects.
But how are we going to find suspects
with so many people here?
I know everyone that was near the victim.
Because before he died, I was with the others
watching Jodie-sensei play a racing game.
Right?
So who are the people that got near him?
That young store employee.
This tall man.
And with the four of us, that's six people.
Right, Jodie-sensei?
Oh, yes, but we weren't the only ones to see everything.
That did as well.
The security camera?
Was that camera recording at that time?
Yes...
Then, can we take you six to watch the tape?
Sure...
Come, this way.
Alright, everyone please follow us.
What is that?
What's that sound?
It sounds like metal scratching something.
And rubbing...
What is it?
Oh, here! This is it!
The victim is about to sit down in the game chair.
That was just after he took the seat.
This is you, Dejima-san, what are you doing?
I was collecting the coins from the game.
This is Shimizu-san, what are you two talking about there?
What was it?
I was preparing my battle strategy.
But it didn't help.
Huh? What'd you pick up from the floor?
I dropped my lighter, so I was picking it up.
And then the game started.
Ah, Inspector! Look at Dejima-san...
He's holding something.
A video?
I record the exciting fights.
Hey, haven't I seen you somewhere before?
Ah, no, wrong guy.
Well, it looks like a good match.
Hit after hit...
Ran-kun and the others moved away from the racing game?
Yes, we wanted to watch the exciting fight.
That means Jodie-sensei was alone and
near the victim for a moment, right?
Oh! But I was focused on playing the racing
game and didn't notice anything else.
But still, you had a chance.
Sensei really had to have been playing the entire time.
Because just when everyone went to the
victim's body, she got the high-score.
She's likely innocent, because her
driving got her the high-score.
You have to focus to do that on a racing game, right?
Then who killed him?
H-H-Hey! Someone is behind the victim's chair!
Who is that guy?
That was the guy playing the mahjongg game!
Isn't that the guy that talked bad about the victim?
What!? Bring that man here immediately!
Right.
Who is the one that committed this murder?
There's something about that match,
I know there's something wrong.
Also, what about the weapon?
We didn't find it on anyone.
Could it be that the killer still has it?
The culprit...
Where is the culprit's weapon?
Start in My Life
Song by Mai Kuraki
The future will bring misfortunes, but...
ii koto bakari no mirai janai keredo
I will keep running to tomorrow, shining brighter than anyone.
tashika ni ima wa ashita ni mukai dare yori mo kagayaki
Now standing here, even shedding tears for the weak now...
koko ni tatteiru koware kake souna ima ni namidashi
Even...
soredemo
We can start in my life together...
We can start in my life issho ni
And stick to our dream.
akiramezu yume to
You can also meet the other side of you.
nee mou hitori no jibun ni aeru kara
With one feeling, we can change.
kimochi hitotsu de kawarerun da
Let us start here.
hora koko kara hajime you
Just start in my life.