Never ignore the power of deduction.
Its limits rely on the wielder!
The game is the killer.
It's time for another case's reasoning show!
Recognizing that single truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is Detective Conan!
At the game center, we were taking pictures.
Until we noticed someone playing a shooting game...
The Teitan High School English teacher, Jodie Saintemillion.
She showed Ran a game to play.
She was quickly beat by Bitou Kengo-san.
That is until we discovered Bitou-san had been murdered!
We gathered the suspects...
A writer named Shimizu Takayasu-san.
An employee of the game center, Dejima Hitoshi-san.
A taxi driver, Emori Toshitsugu-san.
And...
Jodie-sensei.
Who is the one that committed the murder?
There's something about that match,
I know there's something wrong.
Also, what about the weapon?
We didn't find it on anyone.
Could it be that the killer still has it?
The culprit...
Where is the culprit's weapon?
The Battle Game Trap
(Part 2)
The Battle Game Trap, Part 2!
I was picking up a 100 yen coin.
Emori Toshitsugu (41)
Taxi Driver
I was buying some coffee from the
machine but dropped my change.
I admit I didn't like the guy, but I respected him as a gamer.
Don't be ridiculous, didn't he taunt
your skills at a driving game?
Is that true?
Shimizu Takayasu (30)
Game Journalist
Yeah, he told the other visitors: "If you wanna
live, stay out of this guy's taxi."
Do you not have a better motive for killing him?
Because that guy was your sister's boyfriend, right?
His sister's boyfriend?
His sister, Imoto-san, and that guy were living together.
But since he was your gaming partner, you
couldn't say anything to him, right?
And you, young man, you wanted him dead as well, I'm sure.
What do you mean?
Dejima Hitoshi (22)
Store Employee
Half-a-year ago, this young man was
known as the best gamer in Beika.
But he disappeared after losing a big match to the victim.
I guess he decided to change his hairstyle and work here.
Inspector, we have found traces
of poison in the victims blood.
What?
The poison found was tetrodotoxin.
Looks like it entered through the right arm.
T-Tetrodotoxin?
Fugu!
Tetrodotoxin, TTX for short.
Even just half of a miligram to one miligram can prove fatal.
If ingested, the fugu fish's poison works its way through the bloodstream slowly, giving the victim a chance to survive.
But if it's directly injected, it means instant death. The End.
Sensei...
Teitan High School Teacher
Jodie Saintemillion (28)
Or at least that's what a doctor friend of mine told
me, he said you have to be careful of it in Japan.
As I thought, that's why the weapon was used.
Let's go back and look for clues at the scene.
Right.
Is everyone fine with that?
Right...
That's it, that's the sound.
But from where?
Hey, your left shoelace is untied.
Ah, thanks, boy.
You should always keep it tied, right?
It's that person!
That person killed Bitou-san...
And used the game center's environment to do it.
But why did that person do it in front of the police?
Conan-kun?
What's wrong, Conan-kun? Can we go?
Inspector, we searched the entire place
and found nothing like a needle.
The security cameras tell us that no one left during that time.
That means the culprit may still have the weapon, right?
Right.
Alright, we need everyone to submit themselves to a search.
You can if you want, it makes no difference to me.
That guy died fighting me, I didn't even have the chance.
I didn't either, I was only near Bitou-san
before the match to collect the coins.
The one you should be looking for a weapon on is
Emori-san, who was near him during the game.
And what about the woman playing
the racing game beside Bitou-san?
Wait a second, didn't we tell you? Jodie-sensei
played that game the entire time, right?
I can confirm it.
You see, it can't be done from this game chair.
While sitting at this race game, you
can't reach over there, right?
I know that she wasn't involved.
I think I should remind you all that...
Bitou-san was injected from the right side, right?
I was on the left so it couldn't have been me.
Now now everyone, we're just investigating every angle.
What's wrong, Sonoko?
Really, I'm rather disappointed. Especially
with you, Inspector Megure.
The criminal is smirking right in front of you.
What!?
The victim was injected from the right side,
So that means Emori-san couldn't have been responsible.
Although Dejima-san talked with him before the battle,
He didn't kill him because Shimizu-san
spoke with the victim just afterwards.
And since we were watching Jodie-sensei play
the racing game, it couldn't have been her.
Then, the only one remaining...
Right, the only one remaining...
The one that hated the victim!
The one that hated the victim...
Shimizu Takayasu-san.
You're the one!
What are you talking about, girl?
Didn't everyone see me lose the battle?
How could I have killed him despite that?
Don't try that on me, I already knew you would say that.
What?
Ran, Officer Takagi...
Sit where they were playing the game.
This will help make everything clear.
Please sit here.
Hey, listen...
What's this? The police are taking orders from a young girl?
N-No, Sonoko-kun is pretty good.
It started?
Fight!
Isn't that guy being rough with that girl?
Isn't he an officer?
Hey, Takagi-kun, take it easy.
Hey...
K.O.!
That was merciless...
Wow...
T-Takagi-kun, I know you're competitive,
But you were playing too hard that time.
Sonoko-neechan told Officer Takagi
to use the female character.
And told him to cover his eyes with his necktie
so he could do nothing during the battle.
Then, the one using the male character...
Sonoko told me to.
Isn't that right, Conan-kun?
A mind trick.
Exactly, it's a natural impression.
Everyone expected Ran to be the female
and Officer Takagi as the male, right?
But in fact, it's just the opposite.
We thought Bitou-san chose Beika Caesar,
and that Shimizu-san chose Haido Lucas.
But this is exactly how we were fooled.
Since this game doesn't display a hit-point gauge,
it's hard to tell who is playing as which character.
So if the players' characters are
switched, no one would notice.
Then, you mean Bitou-san's was changed?
Yeah, after being attacked by Shimizu-san
and his needle, he either died or fainted.
Tetrodotoxin is known to cause instant paralysis.
Even if he didn't faint, he wouldn't
even have been able to move.
But wait, if he were poisoned before the
fight, wouldn't the crowd have noticed?
No, I don't think so.
When I was playing the game, I didn't actually use
any strength and let the machine move my body.
The game chair's chest guard kept my body in place.
Exactly, Shimizu-san made this his trick.
Before the battle, you went over to Bitou-san
and pricked him under his arm.
While Bitou-san was feeling the
effects, the game was started...
A battle where the victim would be Lucas.
After doing this, you ran over to your game and picked
Bitou-san's character Beika Caesar before pressing OK.
This way, the crowd would think that you
were the one being beat by the victim.
But why didn't he deliver the final blow on the victim?
If he would have ended the match that way,
Bitou-san's game screen would say "You Lose."
With a tie, it would say "Draw."
After that it would only say "Game Over."
What about the weapon?
Wouldn't a needle still have to be around here, girl?
I don't remember them finding such a weapon.
That's why I wanted to search you.
Go ahead and search me, you won't find anything.
He's actually right.
Because he doesn't have the weapon with him any longer.
But that's because...
The weapon is walking all around you.
What do you mean?
Dejima-san, please come over here.
Ah, sure.
What is it?
Haven't you noticed?
Um, sure...
What are you doing now?
Look, you didn't notice, Inspector?
That sound of metal scratching the floor.
What?
Could it be, your shoe has...
Right, Shimizu-san...
Placed the needle in a cigarette, kept it there with
gum, and made it stick to the gum wrapper.
This way...
He could just place it on the floor and
it wouldn't matter who stepped on it.
He did this by saying it was to pick up his lighter.
And since it was in the cigarette,
all he had to do was flatten it.
The carrier wouldn't notice it if it were flattened, and
even if they did, they would just throw it away.
Well, whether or not you removed the poison is questionable.
I'm sure you set the tobacco up beforehand.
Likely in the game center's restroom, right?
If you set it up in the cigarette box,
It wouldn't be as suspicious.
I see, if we can find Shimizu-san's fingerprints
on the cigarette, we should have our evidence.
Your reasoning has impressed me.
But this was all set up, girl.
That tobacco and gum are different than mine.
Is that true?
Yeah, someone must be setting me up.
Everyone knows I chew gum for
luck, it was even in a magazine.
You can test for my fingerprints,
but you won't find anything.
I see! It's like that, huh?
I couldn't figure out why you used the gum to discard the
weapon, even after chewing gum in front of the police.
But then, I discovered that you likely just took the gum
and cigarette from an ash tray in the game center.
The only reason you chewed gum was
in case they found the weapon.
This would be a way to prevent
the police from suspecting him.
But wouldn't he leave fingerprints?
No, he wouldn't leave any if he held
everything between his fingers.
Right, to remove the wrapped needle, all
he had to do was squeeze the packaging.
But, what about the coin?
Dejima-san, would you please open
the coin box on that machine?
S-Sure...
There should be three 100-yen coins inside now.
I recall you removing the coins from
Bitou-san's machine earlier.
Please check the amount of coins.
It's true!
She's right.
Seems that way.
There should be one coin from Bitou-san,
And another from when Officer Takagi played.
And there's another, used during the
killer's trick to have an extra game.
So, Shimizu-san, I know that that third
100-yen coin has your fingerprints on it.
But, how will we know before testing it?
It has to be, as Shimizu-san didn't
know the coins were collected.
And since he didn't have a chance to wear gloves,
his fingerprints must be on that coin.
Without gloves, he couldn't have covered his fingerprints.
My fingerprints are there...
Because I tightly gripped that 100-yen coin...
As that was my "Last Game."
"Last Game?"
Yeah, I was saying goodbye to games and that guy.
It's for my sister, who's going blind...
She's going blind?
Do you know why she's going blind?
It's due to a lack of vitamin A.
It's hard to believe...
To pay off that guy's huge amount of gambling debts,
She worked for an entire month and hardly ate.
Even after that guy joined a gang, she still didn't leave him.
So you wanted to play the victim in one last game?
That guy said if I beat him at that game,
he would leave my sister alone.
I tried my best to beat him as Haido Lucas...
But I just couldn't beat him.
So, that's why?
Yeah, but now I regret doing it...
Because now that the Beika Caesar is gone...
I'll never have a chance to beat him.
Oh! That was impressive, Sonoko. Good job.
You were really cool!
You were like Kate Martin.
Kate?
Oh, that American, female police officer?
But really, you were deducing like Shinichi back there.
Shinichi?
Ah! Wasn't he the one that appeared at the festival?
He is so cool.
He's not that good, he's just a reasoning otaku.
Bye Sensei, we have to go.
Goodbye, Jodie-sensei.
Bye bye, I'll see you at school tomorrow.
Bye bye, Cool Guy.
Yeah, right, much happened today.
I have to admit, this place isn't so boring.
I've already located one of the targets.
Yeah, he's changed his appearance.
Of course.
The target's name?
Well...
"Rotten Apple."
Let's use that codename, alright?