Song by Rina Aiuchi
Koi wa thrill, shock, suspense
Koi wa Thrill, Shock, Suspense,
Love is a thrill, shock, suspense,
Mienai chikara tayori ni
relying on an invisible strength.
Kokoro no tobira tozasazu ni tsuyoku... tsuyoku...
Leaving the door to the heart open, stronger... stronger...
A brave heart and incredible deductions,
a rhythm that jumps to the truth.
Spinning the potter's wheel in ceramics class.
Pay close attention to the words on the cup!
Seeing the one and only truth...
A kid with the intellect of an adult...
His name is... Detective Conan!
Watashi ga kanjiteita
I thought,
Toge okimi ni no onaji You ni ataeteita no kano shirenakatta
this disorder I've been feeling in my heart. Perhaps you felt the same way?
Nani ni kokoro o itamete nani ni obieteita no ka
Without knowing what hurt, what did I fear with my heart?
Ki ni ino tomezu motsureteku futari no shinjitsu ni
The confrontation of our tangling truth
Mukiau no ga kowakatta
We feared to face
This love is Thrill, Shock, Suspense,
This love is a thrill, shock, suspense,
Mayoi o aoi kaze ni chirasou toshite Mo kakaekirezu ni ita yo
Even when I tried to toss my confusion to the wind. I could not hold all of it,
Kono chisana mune ni wa
in this tiny chest.
Kokoro no tobira tozasazu ni
Leaving the door to the heart open.
Tsugi e to susumu arata na fuan to
Even if you may have to hold the new uncertainties and confusion.
Mayoi o kakaeteshimaisou ni natte mo
That will follow you to the next place.
The Murderous Pottery Class
(Part 1)
Hey, Ran. Look at this.
Kyoku Shin?
Note: Kyoku Shin is one of the most violent
and full contact forms of karate.
Is it possible that you're starting karate, Sonoko?
Look closer! It says Makoto Kyougoku!
I'm just joking.
You made this during the pottery class that you just joined, right?
Geez...
But Sonoko, isn't it too small for Kyougoku-san?
Yeah, that's because that one is mine.
This one is for Makoto-san!
It's so big...
But why did you write your name on it, Sonoko?
Isn't it obvious?
The person I love is out in distant lands exploring.
While I get stuck here waiting for his rare calls.
That is why I, Sonoko-sama, made this cup!
Now it will be hard not to remember me, right?
But Sonoko, didn't you send him the handmade
sweater that you bought from that store?
Oh, that? No I didn't.
Like you told me, I shouldn't cheat.
Plus, even if I put all my effort into knitting that sweater
myself, he would only wear it in the winter anyway.
But this! He'll be using it every day, won't he?
I-I guess so.
Although there is one thing that worries me.
I'm scared that some woman will take advantage of Makoto's
kindness and seduce him into going out with her...
Oh, the number of people like that...
They seduce others and make them fall in love with them...
Oh, how worried I am...
What an awful person...
In order to run away from the punishments for his crimes, he
killed himself without thinking about his now widowed wife.
Detective...
Ma'am, if my heart can comfort you, then I will lend it to you.
Don't worry, ma'am.
But Detective, I... I...
Ma'am.
Ran!
What's wrong, Ran?
Hey Sonoko. You said that you attend
a pottery class on Sundays, right?
Yeah, that's right.
Why? Are you interested in it too?
Yeah, a little.
Three Weeks Later
Oh, good work. Yours looks very pretty.
Mino-sensei!
Muneyuki Mino (62)
Craftsman
Too bad that great pottery is wasted with those words.
What do they mean?
Actually, uh... they have no meaning.
Is that so. Well, good luck then.
Hey, what did you write on it?
It's a secret, secret!
I know! You're going to write "I Love Shinichi" on it, aren't you?
Of course not!
Then, let me see it!
No way!
Stop it already!
Boy, what are you doing here?
No-Nothing at all!
Are you one of the student's kids?
Excuse me, everybody.
Does anyone know this child?
Conan-kun!
Why are you here?
You didn't happen to follow us, did you?
Kogoro-ojiisan asked me to come check up on you.
That's weird, Dad came here himself last week.
W-Well, you s-e-e...
I think I know.
It's Shinichi-kun, right?
It seems that Shinichi-kun asked this
boy to follow and check up on us.
To make sure that you're not cheating on him, Ran.
Cheating!?
That's not it! Shinichi-niichan would never do something like that.
Your face tells me that you're being paid!
Tell me, how much is he paying you? 100 Yen? 200 Yen?
So cheap...
Well, it's alright.
Kikuyo Kasama (29)
Muneyuki's Assistant
Well, since you are here already...
Say boy, why don't you try molding something?
Do you mind, Sensei?
Why not. Let's see what he can do.
Oh, you've met Kikuemon-sensei before?
Potter Kikuemon
Yeah, we learned a bunch of things from his assistants.
Right, Ran-neechan?
I see. That's why you're learning so fast.
How amazing! Meeting him; a human treasure!
No, he invited my dad to his house.
There was a murder, but Ran's dad
was easily able to solve that case.
S-Solve a murder? Could your father be...
My father didn't say anything when he came last week?
I'm the daughter of Mouri Kogoro, a detective.
I've heard of him. He's called Sleeping Kogoro.
Amazing!
I'm a huge fan of his!
Looks like this place is packed today.
Oh you're back, Moto-kun.
I came as soon as I finished work.
Mino Moto (31)
Businessman (Muneyuki's inheritor)
Well, father... I'll change my clothes and come help you.
Thanks, sorry for the trouble.
What? Insurance?
Were you forced to get it?
Yeah, father asked me to get it. I don't know
why, but he asked me to get it just in case.
I'm not sure if he's hoping it would help his pottery business, but...
After his daughter died, he suddenly changed.
Now he's just another pathetic drunk who
likes to fiddle around with pottery.
You're so cold towards your departed wife,
Miss "Everlasting Love", and her father.
What good is "Everlasting Love" now?
All I wanted was to get close to the old man,
take his money, and then divorce her.
She didn't last long, though.
But it is fine isn't it?
His life is almost over because of his constant drinking.
Yeah, and after his death, we'll sell this
old dump and open our own new place.
We'll make a fortune if we sell those "Sleeping Works".
By the way, who did you put down as your inheritor?
Well, who else? My one and only girl, that's you!
I'm so happy!
So, could you die for me?
F-Father!
Sensei!
Oh, Kikuyo-san, I'll take care of the furnace. Would
you please go back and check up on my students?
Right away.
So, is this neck tie new?
Yeah, Kikuyo-san gave it to me yesterday.
I told her beige wouldn't look good on me, but she kept insisting.
On the contrary.
It would look great around your neck.
Hey, Ran. Show it to me!
No means no!
Stop it, Sonoko.
Everyone will see it after you're done anyway.
S-Sorry, did it break?
No, it's safe and sound.
Then that sound...
Was it from the storage room?
I'll go take a look.
You do know what I will do to you if you look at it, don't you?
Y-Yeah, I know!
Mino-sensei.
Oh, my hand slipped and I dropped a plate here.
Sorry to trouble you, but could you clean this up for me?
Yeah, sure.
Are you alright?
Looks like there was something sharp in the clay.
Pieces of the broken plate probably got on my clothes.
Then, let me get you the first aid kit.
Do you know where it is?
Yes, the top right shelf in the closet room.
Then, please hurry and get it for me.
Geez...
Please be careful when you're doing pottery.
Fingers are the most important things potters have.
Is there something on my face?
No, it's nothing.
By the way, any idea where Moto-kun is?
I haven't seen him for quite a while.
I haven't seen him either.
Moto-kun! Where are you?
Moto-san!
He's not at the furnace either.
This is strange...
The only place left is this storage room.
He can't possibly be here! The only place someone
can hide in here is in the closet.
And I opened that closet when I got the first aid kit,
but I didn't see anyone inside it.
Look! At the bottom of the closet!
There's something sticking out.
Isn't this an apron for the pottery class?
You're right. It has the same pattern as mine.
Geez, showing part of his clothes while he is hiding...
Now then, hide and seek is over, Moto-san.
Wait, I'll open it for you.
Moto-san!
Moto-san! What's wrong?
Moto-san! Moto-san!!
Moto-san! Moto-san!
Can you hear me, Moto-kun?
Hey, go call an ambulance immediately!
Right away!
Also, you better call the police too.
Hurry!
Yeah.
Moto-san! Moto-san!!
Our victim's name was Mino Moto-san,
31 years old, and a businessman.
Was he a student in this pottery class?
No.
However, he is the inheritor to this place.
He was married to my daughter, who died 2 years ago.
I see...
I'm this class's teacher, Mino Muneyuki.
This is my assistant, Kasama Kikuyo-san.
Would you mind describing the events before
you realized that he was missing?
We lost track of him at around 5 o'clock.
He said he was going to change his clothes, put on an apron,
then come help us in class like he usually does.
Isn't that right, Kikuyo-san?
Yes. We searched for him everywhere, but we couldn't
find him. This storage room was the only place left.
And when Sensei opened the closet, he was inside it...
His Body... Moto-san's body!
I'm surprised you found him... This isn't hide and seek,
and you normally wouldn't check in a closet.
Of course we would! Part of his apron was sticking out.
Right, Ran?
Apron?
His apron was sticking out from the
closet's lower, right-hand corner.
Do you know how long it had been sticking out?
Not really.
If I recall... When we were cleaning the shards of the broken
dish next to the closet, it wasn't sticking out...
Broken dish?
A plate fell in front of the closet a while ago.
These students rushed here, after hearing
the sound of something breaking.
If my memory serves me right, Moto-kun
was there and was wearing his apron.
Huh? You were with the victim?
Right. That closet contains the student's aprons, so
Moto-kun always puts on his apron in this room.
See, his coat's there, too.
Why are there several overalls to the left?
They're for the students to use.
While making pottery, aprons are not large
enough to cover all your clothes.
But what were you doing with the victim alone?
When I was looking for Kikuyo-san, I found
her with Moto-kun in this room.
Is that true?
Yes... Moto-san asked me to come
and help him change his clothes.
Then, Sensei came in and asked me to take care of
the students while he watched over the furnace.
Then what did you do?
I went to the students, just as Sensei had asked me to do.
Then, Mino-san, that means that you were alone with the victim.
Wait a minute, Inspector.
You couldn't possibly be suspecting me, could you?
As I said, Moto-kun had left the room before I dropped the dish.
So, had I killed him and hid his body in the closet, these
students would've noticed the apron sticking out.
But still, you could've opened the closet after the students
finished cleaning, then stuck that part out.
I don't think so.
Sensei went out to the furnace while we were cleaning.
By the time we finished and returned, he was
in the classroom with the other students.
Afterwards, he helped Conan-kun make some pottery.
Isn't that right, Conan-kun?
Conan-kun!
That's right.
After that, Sensei was with us until we found Moto-san's body.
So I don't think he had a chance to do that.
I see. In other words, it happened after
Ran and the others finished cleaning.
The murderer might have asked the victim
to come here, and then killed him.
He also could have killed him somewhere else, dragged
the body here, and hid it in the closet.
Oh, that's right. Maybe Kikuyo-san saw the criminal.
Actually, I cut my finger while working on some pottery.
So Kikuyo-san went and got the first aid kit.
Moments later, we started searching for Moto-kun.
Did you see anyone suspicious?
No, I didn't see anybody.
And where was that first aid kit located?
It was in the upper, right-hand corner of that closet.
What?! You opened the closet?
Yes, but there was nobody inside.
It's the truth!
Inspector, judging by the marks on the victim's neck,
the murder weapon must've been this necktie.
But don't you find it odd?
Why would the criminal leave the necktie on the victim's neck?
That's too bad, that necktie was a present
from Kikuyo-san to Moto-kun.
What? You're mistaken. I didn't give him that.
Huh? But he said that it was from you...
What's the meaning of this?
Well, he said that, on his birthday, he found
a gift with a congratulations note.
He thought it was me being shy, but...
By the way, Moto-kun was complaining about
something as I was leaving. He said...
"Money makes people's hearts ruthless demons; even
on my birthday, one of those demons might eat me."
A demon will eat him?
Actually, Inspector.
About that...
Hurry Takagi. Verify that!
Yes, sir!
Umm... excuse me, but can anyone lend
me an ink pen? Mine is out of ink.
Oh, yes.
I'll go get it, then. It must be in the classroom.
Are those scissors?
Didn't the police officer ask for an ink pen?
That's right. I'm actually looking for it.
Oh, and look. My cup is almost finished.
Come and see!
Look at this!
Well done, looks like you like pottery.
Yep, a lot!
But I don't like to stop in the middle of things, like that
dead man did. So, I want to finish it right now.
Stop in the middle of things?
What? Didn't you notice?
There was a difference in the length of his folded sleeves.
It's as if... after he put his apron on and was getting
ready, he was killed by someone, right?
But, boy, what if one of the sleeves was
pulled on when he was attacked?
Oh yeah, then the criminal probably also pulled the necktie, right?
Necktie?
Because the pin on the necktie is so low.
If you pull its end, then the tie would get bigger.
But isn't the pin too low?
Maybe he liked it that way?
And what if the difference in the sleeve
length is something he liked as well?
But you prefer everything to be symmetrical, right?
Because I noticed that, at the time the body
fell, you were standing to the right.
You then went to the left, just to make
up for the difference in length, right?
And, the other time, when we noticed the apron sticking out.
That part of the apron was sticking out from the right side.
If it were me, I'd only open the right side.
But you opened both doors.
T-That's true.
I preferred to open both doors at the same time.
It's done!
It's my cup! Don't you think it's pretty good?
Oh... You really did a good job!
But boy, you seem to be a little confused...
Maybe you're trying to hide something
big, or you're facing a big decision...
So, am I right? Because clay never lies.
You're amazing, Sensei.
However, boy, you should think about your own problems
before you think about the problems of others.
I know, but...
You're the one who made this cup!
While you were searching the drawers earlier,
I took your cup and switched it with mine.
I thought you'd know the difference between the two cups.
But if this is your cup, doesn't that mean
that you're hiding something?
Sensei, you're hiding something, aren't you?
Right?
Start in my Life
Song by: Mai Kuraki
ii koto bakari no mirai janai keredo
The future will bring misfortune, but...
tashika ni ima wa ashita ni mukai dare yori mo kagayaki
I will continue running to tomorrow, brightly shining.
koko ni tatteiru koware kake souna ima ni namidashi soredemo
Now, standing here, shedding tears for the weak... Even...
We can start in my life issho ni
We can start in my life together...
akiramezu yume to
And follow our dream.
nee mou hitori no jibun ni aeru kara
You can also meet the other you.
kimochi hitotsu de kawarerun da
With one feeling, we can change.
hora koko kara hajime you
Let's start here.
Just start in my life
Just start in my life.