A brave heart and incredible deductions,
a rhythm that jumps to the truth.
The mystery of the pottery classroom!
What could be written on that cup?
Seeing the one and only truth...
A kid with the intellect of an adult...
His name is... Detective Conan!
Ran joined Sonoko, who was attending her pottery class.
Oh, good work. Yours looks very pretty.
Mino-sensei!
Excuse me, everybody.
Does anybody know this boy?
Conan-kun!
I followed Ran to the class.
Muneyuki Mino (62)
Craftsman
The teacher of that class is Muneyuki Mino-san,
Kikuyo Kasama (29)
Muneyuki's Assistant
and his assistant is Kazama Kikuyo-san.
Then, we met Mino Muneyuki's son-in-law, Mino Moto-san.
Mino Moto (31)
Businessman (Muneyuki's inheritor)
However, Moto-san suddenly disappeared.
The only place we haven't looked yet is this storage room.
L-Look! Look, at the bottom of the closet!
There's something sticking out.
Isn't this an apron for the pottery class?
Moto-san! Moto-san! Moto-san!
Can you hear me, Moto-kun?
Moto-san! Moto-san!
Moto-san was killed, and the murderer
has to be one of them.
It's done!
Huh?
This is my cup! Don't you think it's pretty good?
Oh... You really did a good job!
But, boy, it seems as though you are a little bit confused...
Maybe you're trying to hide something
big, or you're facing a big decision...
Am I right? Because clay never lies.
You're amazing, sensei!
However, you should think about your own problems
before you think about the problems of others.
I know, but...
You're the one who made this cup!
While you were searching the drawers earlier,
I took your cup and switched it with mine.
I thought you'd know the difference between the two cups.
But if this is your cup, doesn't that mean
that you're hiding something?
Sensei, you're hiding something, aren't you?
Right?
The Murderous Pottery Class
(Part 2)
T-This boy!
Um...
Is there an ink pen anywhere around here?
Oh, yeah.
Here.
Thank you, I'll return it as soon as I finish up here.
Ah, that's fine.
Well then, thanks again.
Also, the Inspector asked me to
escort you to the storage room.
S-Sure...
There's no doubt.
Mino-sensei is the killer.
I've figured out the trick he used for his alibi.
But when we weren't looking,
he hid the evidence somewhere.
But since he is still in possession of the scissors,
the evidence hasn't been destroyed yet.
It is still around here somewhere.
Damn! Where could it be?
Maybe there is something the murderer hasn't
accounted for... another piece of evidence?
What could it be?
Oh, boy, I'm sorry.
Necktie?
This is it!
I've found it!
I finally figured it out!
The evidence that no one noticed!
The craftsman's mark!
Inspector Megure!
It's been confirmed!
Oh, good.
The truth is, that was not the only thing we found out...
I see, insurance...
Kazama Kikuyo-san, it seems you are in a lot of debt.
Y-Yeah. I've recently bought a new house, so?
Nothing. I'm just curious...
Because the victim set up life insurance one week ago with you as the inheritor and it is equal to the amount you owe.
Don't you think it's suspicious?
In addition, you came to this room in order
to get the first-aid kit for Moto-san.
If you weren't the killer, then you
would've seen the victim's body.
I already told you! I only opened the closet,
and at that time there was nothing there!
Furthermore, it didn't take me long
to come here and go back.
How could I kill him during that short period of time?
You offered to get Mino-sensei the first-aid kit.
It is possible that you went and
hid the body during that time.
In order to slow down the actual discovery of the body,
it is possible to purposely go to the closet and get the first
aid kit, but accidentally left Moto-san's apron sticking out.
You're wrong! I didn't kill anybody!
I can't hide this any longer, Kikuyo-san.
I was searching for Kikuyo-san and found her
in this room, grabbing Moto-kun by the neck.
I-Is that true?
Yes. She said that she was helping him change
his clothes, but it sure didn't look that way.
That's wrong! It was only a joke!
In any case, let's finish this at the police station.
Please wait, Officer!
Anything wrong, Inspector?
You know how every time we try to take someone to the police station, we always hear a weird sound that stops us?
Something like "Myaaa" or "Fouhitoo".
Oh, you mean Detective Mouri, right?
But it's okay today, he's not here.
Yeah, that's right!
Hey, Sonoko!
This girl does the same thing!
You really disappoint me, Inspector Megure.
And why's that?
Haven't you noticed yet? The victim's sleeves
were folded at different lengths.
That means that he was killed during the
time he was changing his clothes, right?
Meaning, that person is the only one who
could have committed the crime.
T-That person?
You don't mean...
Yes.
That person came into the storage room a few moments
before Moto-san finished putting on his apron.
That person then sent Kikuyo-san to help the students,
leaving him alone with the victim.
Mino-sensei!
That person is you!
Sonoko-kun, we noticed the difference
in lengths of his sleeves.
But he has an alibi!
Ran said that the apron wasn't sticking
out after Mino-san left the room.
After that, he stayed with you the whole time.
In addition, just before the victim was
found, Kikuyo-san opened the closet.
We still don't know if she is the murderer or not.
She should have screamed the moment she saw
Moto-san's body, if she wasn't the culprit.
This isn't some magic trick.
How could the victim's body be placed in
that closet without anybody noticing?
No, this really is a magic trick.
Mino-sensei used Ran and Kikuyo-san
as his assistants in the trick.
He made Moto-san's body appear in a closet
when nothing was supposed to be in there.
H-He used me and Kikuyo-san?
Let's quit talking, and prove that what I'm saying is true.
Let's see... Let's have Officer Takagi be the assistant.
What? Me?
Well then, this closet is empty, and completely
void of any mechanical object or trick.
Please check that there's nothing
at the bottom of the closet.
Yeah, there's nothing there.
Now, please open the closet's right door.
It's open.
There's nothing inside, is there?
Right. There is nothing unusual inside.
T-There's a cloth sticking out from the bottom of the closet.
That's weird, I didn't notice anything before I opened it.
Oh, I see, the door's back-side!
That's right.
That's the handkerchief that I asked Conan-kun to put there.
Mino-san most likely taped the apron
to the closet's back-door.
He then closed the door, making sure it remained hidden.
So when someone opens the door, the cloth is pulled out.
And, when someone closes the door, the cloth
is stuck out, and stays outside the door.
In other words, Mino-sensei intentionally dropped
the plate in front of the closet,
and had Ran pick up the broken pieces so
she noticed nothing was sticking out.
After that, he said that he cut himself to make Kikuyo-san
open the closet to get the first-aid kit.
After opening the door, the apron fell
out, putting his trap into effect.
Oh I see. The body was in the closet, even
before Ran cleaned up the broken plate.
And what was meant by using a handkerchief, is that he
used the same method, except with a piece of apron.
However...
What if Kikuyo-san had noticed the piece of apron
sticking out after having closed the door?
When someone is injured, do you think anyone would
be interested in looking at the door's backside?
Or even be facing the door?
In that case, where was the body?
If the body fell when the closet was opened, this means
that it was placed at the door's backside, right?
It's impossible that Kikuyo-san wouldn't notice
that after getting the first-aid kit.
Maybe you'll figure it out for yourself, if we
try to open the closet one more time.
But this time, open both doors at the same time.
B-Both doors?
A-A mop?
That wasn't there when I opened the door before.
What in the world?
The trick is pretty easy.
First, tie a rope on the mop's head in such a way
that the rope is long and ends with a knot.
Then tie the rope around the left hanger-bar.
Placing the mop, so that it is tilting towards the outside.
Finally, put the knot above the left door.
The doors are then closed simultaneously,
with the knot sticking out.
Once the right door opens, the mop cannot be
seen because it is hidden behind the clothes.
However, if you open both doors together.
The knot will fall.
Which causes the mop to fall.
This mop represents Moto-san's body,
and the rope can be replaced with his necktie.
Then the knot can then be replaced with...
Y-You don't mean...
The necktie pin?!
That's right.
It will become more clear once
you look at Moto-san's necktie.
The reason the pin was on so low was to be
at the appropriate length for this trick.
And the reason why the necktie pin hole is so large,
is because of Moto-san's weight pulling down on it.
B-But wouldn't the necktie pin and the necktie, sticking out of the upper part of the door, be easy for someone to notice?
If you fold the part sticking out and slide it
back into the door, no one would notice it.
Then, where is the piece of apron hidden?
When we arrived here, we didn't find anything
similar to what you mentioned.
In addition, he found the body with his students there.
It isn't possible to recover a thing like that...
It is possible.
Since he went and sat to the right side of Moto-san's body,
he could have reached for the piece of apron, which
would be behind him, take it, and hide it.
If he pulled hard enough, the tape on it would come
off, and the piece of apron would be gone.
Look, when the door is closed, the apron can easily be seen.
Once the door opens halfway, the piece of apron
gets hidden until the door is completely open.
Mino-sensei simply took the piece
of apron and hid it in his pocket.
I see.
So, you're saying that if we searched his
pockets, we'd find the piece of apron?
Huh, this is nonsense.
Look, as you can see, there's nothing in my pockets.
Hey, Sonoko-kun.
You probably hid it in the bathroom, before the police
arrived. So, as they were checking the body...
Bathroom?
Conan-kun saw Mino-sensei searching for a pair of scissors.
He was ready to cut the apron into pieces,
and flush them down the toilet.
Alright, Takagi, check that out.
Yes, sir!
Nonsense. It doesn't matter where it's found.
It's not like anyone saw me trying to hide something.
In addition, it is possible that anyone
could have done this trick.
You're right.
Even if we found the apron, the killer would
not be the one in possession of it.
So it can't be used as proof.
But Sensei, there is a piece of concrete evidence that
proves that you were the one who did this trick.
It's on the opposite side of the necktie, worn by Moto-san.
T-These are...
Nail marks!
Yes, those are the marks left by the clay on Sensei's hands.
Finding these marks makes sense.
At that time, Sensei was making a cup next to Conan-kun.
Besides, looking at the location of the necktie pin,
the necktie was barely long enough for the trick.
In order to set the trick up, you would
have to set the necktie pin in place.
Once it is in place, you have to grab
the end of the necktie, and pull.
Sensei, you made two mistakes.
The first was that you didn't wear gloves.
The second, is that you used the necktie
to hang the victim's body.
Had you worn gloves, you wouldn't have
left any traces of clay on the necktie.
In addition, had you used a rope instead of the necktie,
you wouldn't have left any fingerprints.
Now what do you have to say?
I don't like wearing gloves. I prefer touching
things and feeling how they really are.
That necktie was a gift my daughter
sent him with all her heart.
It was a Christmas present.
So, the person who put that necktie
in the bag with the card was...
It was me. I saw him thinking it was a present from you.
All I wanted was to release my daughter's grudge,
by throwing the blame on you!
I started suspecting your affair with him when
the truck hit my daughter two years ago.
It was three days after Christmas.
When I went to my daughter's room,
I found a necktie inside the trash-can, still inside the box.
I thought it was put there by mistake, so
I went to the airport to give it to him.
I wanted to give it to the man, who I thought should
be grieving due to the recent death of his wife.
But what I saw at the airport was nothing
like sadness towards his loss.
He was a person talking and laughing
while holding Kikuyo-san's hand.
After that, I realized that my daughter
wasn't killed by accident.
She actually found out about the
affair, and so she killed herself.
But I'm surprised you knew this was for Moto-san.
How did you know it wasn't for you?
I know that because...
Because...
Beige?
Don't you think that that color is
too dark for Moto-san's taste?
No, it's good. I like beige, and I want
him to look just like you, father.
Beige is the color of clay. It's your favorite
color, isn't that right, father?
Because... Just call it a father's instinct.
Three Days Later
You got a letter from Kyoukogu-san?
You sure don't look happy about it, Sonoko...
It's because of this, look!
Why is he using it as a vase?
He's mistook it for a flower pot.
Imbecile.
What about you? Did you send yours?
Or did you go through all that trouble, just to hide it?
I sort of messed up, so I decided not to send it.
Oh, we're out of chips.
Hey, Conan-kun.
Sorry to bother you, but could you
go get some chips from my desk?
Sure.
Huh? A pen-holder?
This reminds me of something...
Super Stupid Case Fanatic
I'm stupid?
I see, that's the cup Ran made.
Makes sense that she didn't send something like this.
I'm waiting for you ♡
I'm waiting for you.
Conan-kun, what are you doing?
Hurry up and get the chips.
Yes, I'm coming.
Conan-kun seems in a very good mood today.
He's really strange.