A strong heart and the power of deduction!
A sharp rhythm gets to the root of its true nature.
Today, on a dangerous bus, Haibara's not her usual self.
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Did you see it? The happy look on the client's face as he left?
He's got no idea he drank his last shot tonight.
Eh, bro?
Bro?
Oh, so that diva's up next?
Every time I hear her sing,
it sends shivers down my spine.
And she's good-looking too.
She's your type, isn't she?
Two dry martinis.
Courtesy of the lady on the stage.
I'll take it with my compliments.
What is the meaning of all this?
I'm asking you what you're up to...
Vermouth!
I'm just kidding.
It's a joke, a joke.
Vermouth
Don't make such a scary face.
I saw you drooling over a certain someone,
and thought I'd tease you guys.
What're you thinking?
If anybody sees a famous actress like you talking to the likes of us...
Forget it.
Every eye's focused on that singer.
Never mind that.
Have you found what you were looking for?
Well, I haven't located my primary target yet.
Target?
Isn't it time you told us what you're up to?
Give it up.
Her ridiculous secret life is nothing new.
Oh, that's a nice thing to say...
"A secret makes a woman woman."
It's that touch of mystery that gives a woman her allure.
You make me sick.
Never mind me, what about you?
Did you find that kitten that got away from you?
No.
But it won't be long before I do.
My nose can sniff out traitors wherever they are.
And when I do, I'll show them what real fear is.
Her, and that man she's with.
Next stop is Beika Town, Third Street,
in front of the Kodama Products main building.
You sure you can go skiing like this, Doc?
It serves him right.
I told him to stop because he'd catch cold,
but he was up all night image-training with a how-to-ski video.
I had no choice!
I'm in charge of you children! It's my duty to set an example.
But once we get there, you'd better rest at the lodge!
You need to take care of that cold!
Don't go out and play in the snow!
Who's the child here?
Next stop is in front of Beika Park.
Hey! More passengers are getting on! Take your seats.
Okay.
You look bored to death.
Like you're sad because you won't be seeing her for a long time.
Or perhaps...
...you're sad because you won't be seeing them.
You're nuts.
These passengers have nothing to do with me.
Who'd want to run into those guys on a cramped bus like this,
especially with the kids on board?
One of the men in black?
Nope.
I can sniff them out.
Everyone in the organization gives off a stench...
I don't notice any weird scent coming from you...
Would you cut that out?
But if you've got a sixth sense like that,
then the case with Pisco...
Well, I had my suspicions.
Then why didn't you say something?
I wasn't sure about it.
And I sensed another presence too.
Somebody far worse than Pisco.
A diabolical aura that chilled me to the bone...
Kudo-kun...
Switch seats with me.
Hide me!
Please...
Haibara...
Araide-sensei!
Oh? You're all riding?
Thanks for the check-up the other day.
Sure...
Hey, what's wrong with Araide-sensei?
Ah, you weren't at school when he dropped by for our check-ups, were you?
Are you on a date today?
Oh, no. She's a teacher at Teitan High, where I work.
Hi, boys and girls!
Oh, Cool Kid! So, we meet again?
You know her?
Ah, she's an English teacher at Ran-neechan's school.
My name is Jodie Saintemillion.
I'm on a date with Dr. Araide today to Ueno Art Museum.
Nah, we just happened to run into each other at the bus stop.
Oh, shame on you embarrassing a lady like that.
But you don't want weird rumors going around school, do you?
Oh... yes.
That would be a problem.
Hey, check it out.
Those two guys already have their ski gear on!
Guess they can't wait...
But I can understand how they feel.
Same here.
Geez. They've even got their goggles on.
Why don't we change too?
What are you talking about?
We sent our bags on ahead of us, didn't we?
Oh, that's right.
Oh, Genta-kun, you're so forgetful!
Nobody move!
Make a move and you're dead meat!
What's going on?
Them!
Nobody move!
Make a move and you're dead meat!
What?!
They're hijacking...
What?
Didn't you hear me?!
I told you to shut up!
Hey!
Yes?
First, close the front door.
Right...
Now, change the front sign to "Out of Service".
R-Right.
Now, let's get this bus moving!
Just drive around the city!
R-Right.
Move it!
Alright?
At the next red light, I want you to call your company!
R-Right.
Good, you're good little children.
Now, hand over all the cell phones you got.
Don't hide 'em.
If you don't hand them over, you'll never make a phone call again.
This is W707, Kobayashi! W707, Kobayashi!
Well, you see...
We've just taken over this bus!
We have only one request!
Free Kunio Yashima from prison!
Tell the police we're going to kill one passenger every hour until that happens!
I'll get back in touch in twenty minutes.
Make sure you've got everything ready by then!
Kunio Yashima...
Kunio Yashima?
He's the leader of a gang that bombed and robbed a jewellery store last month.
He was arrested back then,
but his three partners are still on the run.
I think Yashima used to be a jewellery broker.
I see.
The other three must not know the black market.
They need their boss because he's the only one who can price the stolen jewellery.
Or maybe he's the only one who knows where the jewels are hidden...
and they're trying to get him out of jail so they can get to it.
Hey, you over there!
Hand it over!
Ah... I'm sorry.
Shuichi Akai
Passenger
I don't carry a cell phone.
Sheesh. What a dork.
Hey, old man next to him!
What's that thing you got in your ear?
It's a hearing aid!
Yasuhiko Machida
Passenger
I've been almost deaf since childhood!
S-So...
Hey, you over there! Stop that chewing sound!
What? I'm just chewing gum.
You're all gonna get arrested anyway.
Miharu Tomino
Passenger
You might as well give up and make a run for it.
F-Fine.
I'll be quiet.
Good, that's how you should've been from the start.
What's the matter? Are you all right?
Y-Yeah.
Why, you...!
Jodie...
Oh, sorry!
Oh, my God, what have I done?
Are you all right?
I didn't mean that.
I always make a blunder and get clumsy.
Are you...
Forget it! Just sit down.
It's very, very exciting.
Good grief. Is this teacher for real?
Anyway,
while those guys are at the other end of the bus,
I'll use my earring-shaped phone to tell Inspector Megure about the situation...
What the hell are you doing,
you little twerp?!
Look, twerp...
If you try anything funny again, you're really gonna get it!
Oops, almost forgot.
I'm gonna hold on to this.
Damn! He took my phone!
Conan-kun, are you all right?
But it's strange...
He made a beeline for me...
but he couldn't have seen what I was doing.
Which means...!
They've got an accomplice!
One of the three people who can see me...
But how did that person contact him,
and tell him what I was doing without letting anyone else know?
What method are they using?
Sato here.
The bus is currently heading for Takaido.
It's travelling at about 50 km/h.
This is Takagi at point E!
I've caught sight of the bus!
There are two suspects, both wearing ski gear!
I can't make out their faces under the hats and goggles,
but they seem to be armed with handguns.
What should we do, Inspector?
The bus may pass that way again.
Stay there until further notice.
Dammit.
If they're both armed, we can't take any chances.
Inspector.
I've just received orders from the head office.
Our first priority is the safety of the hostages.
We're to comply with the hijackers' demands and free Kunio Yashima.
Guess we've got no choice.
There's already been gunplay.
And if they're members of Yashima's gang,
I think at least one of them is an expert on explosives.
I can't imagine the devastation if they set off a bomb in the middle of town.
But we've got them trapped like rats.
The bus is going in circles around the city...
No, I bet they've got something up their sleeves.
Some plan that will let them escape right under our noses.
So you've decided to comply, huh?
Tell Yashima to call us an hour after you've freed him.
Once we've confirmed from his own mouth that he's in a safe place,
we'll start by freeing three hostages.
Got that? And don't try anything!
Two ski bags in a line...
It couldn't be...!
You again?!
If you don't want your life,
I'll grant your wish.
Hey, boy!
Get up!
Please stop!
He's just a little boy fooling around!
The police are complying with your demands!
Have you considered that they might not be so cooperative...
if you start shooting children?!
W-What was that, punk?!
Stop!
What if you miss and shoot that?
You two! Hurry up and get back to your seats!
Right.
If he misses and shoots that?
That must mean those ski bags...
are full of explosives!
I don't know what they're
planning to use them for.
But one thing is clear.
One of the three people behind me is in on it,
and is telling them about me.
I can't do anything until
I figure out which one it is.
Hey, Haibara...
I need your help.
Hey!
W-What is this?
I feel a piercing pressure...
just like I felt back then...
It's her... She's here, on this bus!
Did they send her? Are they after me?
Or is it a coincidence...
If my true identity is found out here...
and they figure out that I'm the one who betrayed the organization...
then Dr. Agasa and everyone with me on the bus...
everyone...
every single person will be killed...
Of course, him too...
Without question...
Please...
Please...!
Don't let her find me!
Wait, don't tell me...
Someone's here?
On this bus?
One of them?
All right, when the bus comes out of the tunnel...
it's game on!
I've always known there was no place for me.
I'm a fool, aren't I, sis?
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint! Yes, yes!—Rearview Mirror
Look forward to the next episode!
The movie opens this Saturday!
Whatever the case, you're not getting in for free.