A BAARO FANSUB
(Miki Matsuhashi)
Even fate can be used as a hint for reasoning.
Seeing through the most mysterious cases!
An odd member in a sealed-room situation?
What will happen to Conan and Haibara now?!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Haibara and I boarded a bus with Dr. Agasa and the Detective Boys
on our way to get in some spring skiing.
On the way, Araide-sensei and
Jodie-sensei also boarded the bus.
Suddenly, Haibara became scared.
She just wasn't herself...
Then two men in ski gear
boarded the bus and hijacked it!
I hid and tried to contact the police, but...
You little twerp!
Look, twerp...
If you try anything funny again,
you're really gonna get it!
Damn! He took my phone!
Conan-kun, are you all right?
But it's strange...
He made a beeline for me...
but he couldn't have seen what I was doing.
Which means...!
They've got an accomplice!
One of the three people who can see me...
But how did that person contact him,
and tell him what I was doing
without letting anyone else know?
What method are they using?
Hey, Haibara, do you have any ideas?
Hey...
Don't do anything foolish, Cool Kid!
You'll have a good chance soon.
Oh, you don't have to be so scared. It'll be all right.
What's your name, Little Red Riding Hood?
She's...
She's a stranger, we just happen to be sitting next to each other!
She's really scared, so I think we should leave her alone...
Oh!
- I'm sorry!
- You over there!
What have you been doing?!
Jodie-sensei...
Please don't do anything to irritate them!
Oh, yes!
Let's talk about it later.
Y-Yeah.
Hey.
Don't tell me...
Someone's here?
On this bus?
One of them?
But...
I still haven't figured out who the other hijacker is.
Until I come up with a plan to stop this gang,
I can't do anything about the men in black.
It's one of those three.
And the most likely suspect...
is the guy who's been coughing.
That could be his way of signalling the others.
Shuichi Akai
Passenger
But the Doc's been coughing too,
and their coughing sounds about the same.
Speaking of sounds,
there's that woman's gum-chewing.
Miharu Tomino
Passenger
It's not as loud as the coughing, though.
Those guys were standing at the front of the bus.
There's no way they could've
heard her chewing gum.
That leaves that guy with the hearing aid.
If that hearing aid were a wireless microphone,
Yasuhiko Machida
Passenger
he could be using it to talk to the others.
But neither of the hijackers
have anything in their ears.
And surely people would
notice him talking to himself.
The hijackers keep checking
the rearview mirror...
Hey, old man!
What are you trying to pull?!
I-It's only cough medicine...
Again!
Someone alerted the hijackers!
Damn! How is it being done?!
How are they communicating?!
Oh, we've been waiting for your call, Yashima-san.
So how are things on your end?
Everything's fine. I managed to lose the cops.
All right, we'll meet at the
usual place in three days.
Okay, driver,
get on the Shuto Expressway,
then head for the Chuo Expressway!
Y-Yes, sir!
When you get to the Kobotoke Tunnel, slow down.
Don't worry about it.
We'll release the passengers,
just like we promised.
Hey, you! The geek in the glasses!
And the guy in the back with the cold!
You two, get up here!
Hey, what's the matter? Hurry it up!
We're not gonna kill you.
I see. So that's what they're up to.
I've figured out who their other partner is,
and how they intend to escape from this bus!
A notebook?
"Do you have any lipstick?"
Good.
Now to use this badge and get those guys to...
Where can your lipstick bring us?
Show me your magic.
Cool Guy...
Sato here.
The bus is currently on the Chuo Expressway heading toward Otsuki.
We'll reach the Kobotoke Tunnel soon!
Keep following them. Don't lose sight of the bus!
Yes, sir!
The bus has to be running out of gas by now!
They'll probably free the first three hostages when they stop for fuel!
Contact the Yamanashi Prefectural Police for backup
and ask them to place plainclothes detectives at every parking area along the route!
Yes, sir!
Be ready to storm the bus
the instant they open the door!
Inspector! The bus is slowing down!
What?!
We're about to enter the Kobotoke Tunnel!
Okay, you two!
Put on this ski gear and sit down!
And don't forget the hats and goggles!
You're gonna buy us some time by posing as us,
while we disguise ourselves as two of the released passengers and make our getaway.
Don't worry. Once this is over, the other passengers will be able to clear your names.
And as to whether our escape is successful,
that, driver, is up to you!
When we get off the bus,
start driving away to distract the cops.
To make sure you play along,
we're going to take a hostage.
You, the woman in the back chewing gum!
Get up here.
Alright, when we get to the end of the tunnel, speed up.
Lose the cops, then pull over.
After we get off, drive until you run out of gas.
If not, I'll blow this woman's face off!
Yes, I'll do it!
No, that's wrong.
She's no hostage. She's one of them!
Just as I thought.
After the three of them get off the bus,
they'll detonate the explosives in these bags,
killing us all so we can't testify as to what happened!
That's right.
They're going to pose as hostages,
have the police take them into protective custody,
then feed them a story about fictitious hijackers.
The police think there were only two hijackers,
so they just need to say that there was a struggle between the passengers and the hijackers,
and the police will assume that the explosives went off early,
and the hijackers died in the explosion.
That means that the bodies of Araide-sensei and the guy with the cold
will be found in the wreckage, wearing ski gear,
and the police will think they were the hijackers!
They waited for the bus to get into the tunnel
so no one would see them making their decoys dress up.
But this darkness works to my advantage too!
The Detective Boys badges...
- C-Conan?
- Conan-kun?
Ears! Ears!
All right...
Do exactly what I'm about to tell you.
Don't worry. The inside of the bus is dark.
They're so sure their plan will work, their guard is down.
When the bus comes out of the tunnel...
it's game on!
Alright, step on it!
R-Right!
Don't try anything funny.
Follow orders and you'll all be okay.
You're full of it!
I know you're planning to kill us.
Isn't that why you're letting us see your faces?
Everyone, they're planning to kill us all...
with this bomb!
Y-You twerp!
I'll shut you up!
You idiot! Don't shoot!
What's that? What's that red graffiti?
Hurry!
S-Stop?
This way, mister!
Don't let go, Mitsuhiko!
I know, I know!
Ouch.
Why, you little...
Araide-sensei! Grab that lady's arms!
The watch she's wearing is the switch to detonate the bomb!
Twerp, you just made a big mistake.
Oh, I'm so sorry!
The airbrake going off knocked me off balance...
D-Don't dick me around.
Hey, what gives? The trigger...
You're so stupid.
Didn't you know you can set the safety lock on a Tokarev
by lifting the firing hammer and stopping it midway?
You should've learned how to use your piece before trying to hijack a bus with it.
W-What the? Who the hell are you?!
It's a big secret.
I'm sorry, I can't tell you.
A secret makes a woman woman.
Oh, you surrender?
We've gotta run for it! We've gotta get outta here!
When the airbrake went off, my wristwatch must've hit something.
The bomb's been activated!
There's less than a minute before the bus blows!
Say what?!
Inspector, the bus is in the area of the Kobotoke Tunnel.
They've come to a sudden stop and aren't moving.
What should we do?
Should we storm the bus?
No.
Wait for your backup to arrive.
C-Conan-kun!
What's going on?
The bomb those hijackers brought on the bus is gonna go off in less than 20 seconds!
What did you say?!
I'll stop the cars still in the tunnel.
Chiba-kun, you cover the opposite lane!
The rest of you, help lead the passengers away from the bus!
Hurry up!
R-Right!
W-Where's Haibara-san?!
I don't see her...
D-Don't tell me...
Don't tell me she...
That's right.
This is the best way.
If I make it out of this
I'll have to face her during the questioning.
But if I disappear now,
then there'd be nothing left to link those guys with the organization...
I've always known...
I knew that from the moment I ran away from the organization,
there'd never be a place for me anywhere...
I'm such a fool...
I'm a fool...
Sis...
C-Conan-kun!
Conan!
Conan-kun!
She's wounded!
Can you take her to a hospital with the Doc and the others?
I can answer all the police's questions by myself!
O-Oh, I guess so...
There...
Don't run away, Haibara...
You mustn't run away...from your own destiny.
Now hurry and get them to a hospital!
R-Right.
Oh, Cool Kid!
Breaking the window like that and rescuing the girl,
that was so James Bond!
Jodie-sensei, you're more like 007 than me.
You tripped the hijacker and pretended to apologize,
but actually, you activated the safety on the Tokarev, right?
Oh, yes!
It went exactly like in the movies!
Hey, hey.
But how did you know she was part of their gang?
It was the bubbles.
Bubbles?
She was chewing bubble gum.
That's how she was signalling the hijackers through the rearview mirror
as to which passenger was acting suspicious.
The bubble would break,
and the hand she used to pull the gum off would show the side,
and the number of fingers she used would show which seat the passenger was in.
Then how did you know her watch would set off the bomb?
She was wearing a watch that was stopped at 1:00.
That made me suspicious.
I'm so mad though!
Their boss got away!
Don't worry.
I'm sure the police wouldn't free him without a plan to recapture him.
He'll be back behind bars soon.
Attention, all passengers!
We have some questions to ask all of you,
so please get into the cars.
We've got to go too.
You're all scratched up.
Are you sure you're all right?
Oh, I'm fine.
Just as I thought! You're badly wounded!
You're a very reckless boy.
A-Araide-sensei...
Let's get you treated before you talk to the police, okay?
S-Sure.
Doesn't it hurt, Haibara-san?
Your leg's all bloody.
I'm fine. It's not my blood anyway.
That's right.
He smeared his own blood on me
so that I'd be taken away from there...
It seems you've repaid your debt to me, Kudo-kun...
Please get in quickly!
Unable to continue my assignment
due to an unexpected accident.
The target did not appear.
I'll resume my investigation later.
Over.
NEXT EPISODE
It looks like he fell from his own apartment.
Did he slip while going to and from the balcony?
Huh? I think the doorbell's broken.
Yoshimura-san's death was no accident!
He was murdered!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Sandals
The next episode will air on May 7!
Look forward to the next episode!
There's a break next week, so watch the Conan movie instead!