Destiny
Song by Matsuhashi Miki
A hint to reasoning is to dream.
There's a mystery behind every case!
Today's case takes place at an apartment complex.
There are ulterior motives behind a strange incident.
Seeking the one and only truth.
With the appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult.
His name is... Detective Conan!
Something's just not right
Something's just not right.
nani o motometeru no
What is it we're seeking?
uso ni narete yuku kyou mo fake your eyes
We're used to lying nowadays, as you fake your eyes.
The start of century
The start of century.
tashika na mono nakute
Nothing can be considered certain.
hitori ja nakenai yowasa hate myself
I can't cry over my weaknesses, I can only hate myself.
shinjiteru itami hikikae ni kono mune umetsukushite
Believing in this pain, my chest endures through the exhaustion.
ima utsutte iru futari ga eranda michi kuru
The future in which the two of us can be together is coming...
I think it's only my destiny
I think it's only my destiny.
hateshinai yami no mukou ni
On the other side of this persistent darkness,
dare mo shiru koto no nai ashita ga aru
There's a tomorrow that has no time limit.
oh yeah. You're going nowhere, It's only destiny
Oh yeah. You're going nowhere, It's only destiny
ari no mama ni susunde
Looking for that final resolution,
ima kanjite iru you're in my heart
I can feel you now, you're in my heart.
you're in my heart
You're in my heart.
The Falling From The Condo Case
Geez...
Ran goes to watch a movie and I get stuck with Conan.
That's probably because I bring you luck.
What do you mean?
Whenever I'm around, you always solve cases.
Idiot, that's just a coincidence.
Welcome!
Are you Mouri-san?
Yeah.
You must be Ueda-san, please have a seat.
Okay.
Oh sorry, does the smoke bother you?
Yes.
Hot coffee please.
Yes, right away.
I'm actually here at the request of Yoshimura,
a colleague from my medical university.
Ueda Jouji (29)
Tokyo Medical School Doctor
Is he still receiving threats?
It's been getting worse. At first, he only received threatening
letters, but recently they've started calling him.
He gets followed wherever he goes,
so he has become very neurotic.
I'm worried that he might start making mistakes at work.
That's quite troubling.
He has no idea why this is happening.
Please find out who the culprit is
and why they are targeting him.
I understand. You can leave it to me, Mouri Kogoro!
First, we'll have to get details on the situation
from the victim, Yoshimura-san himself.
Well then, I'll call Yoshimura to see if he's home.
Hello.
Yoshimura, it's me.
Yoshimura's home. I'll take you there.
We're at his apartment, Mouri-san. Yoshimura
lives in the corner unit on the fifth floor.
This way, please.
What the hell was that?
Over here!
Hey, Conan!
What happened?
That's...
Uncle, call an ambulance!
Ye-Yeah.
Yoshimura!
What did you say?!
That's... Yoshimura!
Yoshimura Mitsuo (25)
Tokyo Medical School Doctor
That's Yoshimura Mitsuo!
Yoshimura! Hey, Yoshimura! Get up! Yoshimura! Yoshimura!
What the heck is going on?
The deceased is Yoshimura Mitsuo-san, 25 years old, male.
He worked as a doctor at the Medical University.
We found the key to his apartment in one of his pockets.
So, Mouri-kun, you came to see Yoshimura-san regarding
his request and witnessed the accident?
Yes, according to his friend Ueda-san, someone
was pursuing and threatening him.
Yoshimura-san's unit is the corner room on
the fifth floor of this apartment building.
He fell from his own apartment, huh? Let's go
up to his place, we might find out why he fell.
I know it's your job, but still, thanks for your assistance.
No problem. This situation demands attention.
Hara Ryouji (56)
Apartment Manager
But is it true that Yoshimura-san is...
Huh? There's nobody there again?
The elevator stops at every floor
at night for security reasons.
I see, but it's kind of annoying since we're in a hurry.
Yeah, that's why Yoshimura-san used the emergency stairs
in the warehouse next door when he was in a rush.
The stairs in the warehouse next door?
That's right.
The space between his balcony and the
courtyard is within jumping distance.
I've warned him not to do it, but...
This is the fifth floor.
Hey officer, would you mind if I go change my shirt?
My apartment is right above if you need anything.
That's fine. As soon as you're done, please
come to Yoshimura-san's apartment.
Yes, I understand.
Yoshimura
It's already May, but it's still pretty cold.
That's true.
Diluted whiskey, huh?
It appears that he was drinking by himself.
It seems like he didn't feel safe anywhere
except at home and at work.
Now that you mention it, recently some strange men were
suspiciously loitering around Yoshimura-san late at night.
Ueda-san said he received threatening phone
calls and warnings at random hours.
That's...
Is this the balcony Yoshimura-san
used for coming and going?
That's right, Yoshimura-san always left his sandals here
when he went out. I've cautioned him many times, but...
Inspector, the apartment was locked,
the keys were in the victim's pocket,
the lights were left on, and there's
obviously no sign of a struggle.
Taking all of that into consideration, there's no
doubt that his death was merely an accident.
At this moment, your theory seems plausible.
A sandal.
How did it get there?
But...
Wait a sec.
Can't be the rooftop then. That means...
I see, sorry for disturbing you.
Must have been a prank.
Ueda
Huh? The doorbell doesn't work?
Ueda-san, Ueda-san!
Yes.
Excuse me Ueda-san, I'm very thirsty.
May I have a glass of water?
Sure.
Go ahead, come on in.
Thank you!
Wait here, I'll be right back.
Okay.
Hey Ueda-san, there was a flower delivery
person outside just a moment ago.
Yeah, that was just a prank.
What are you doing, boy?
You shouldn't climb up there, it's dangerous. Get down.
Okay!
Here. Juice.
Thanks.
We'll go and join everyone when you're done.
Okay!
Hey, Ueda-san, are you feeling warm? You're sweating.
Well, I sweat very easily.
I'm going to the bathroom for a moment.
Finish that juice, okay?
Okay!
I wonder what left that mark?
This is...
There's more over there.
And there too.
By the bed, the table, and the sofa as well.
I see. I understand it all now!
Hey, what are you doing?
Well, I forgot something in the other
room. I'm going to get it, okay?
Geez.
Hey, you shouldn't do that! We're
still analyzing the crime scene.
I'm sorry, I actually came to give you
a message from Uncle Mouri.
From Mouri-san?
He said...
Ah, all right.
I'll go there immediately, but don't
touch anything here okay?
Okay!
No new messages
I knew it, there's no mistaking it.
Yoshimura-san's death wasn't an
accident, he was murdered!
It's unfortunate. But, like Mouri-kun
deduced, the death was accidental.
For some reason, he slipped when he was jumping
from his balcony to the warehouse.
What bad luck, just when we got you to come here too.
Hey, Ueda-san. You called him to say
that we were coming over, right?
Yeah.
Then why do you think he went out?
Don't bug the adults.
Get out if you're gonna keep bothering us.
Fine.
It can't be helped.
I suppose there's no choice but to put him to sleep.
Hey, what's wrong Mouri-kun?
Inspector, I'm sorry, but I think it's too soon for us to leave.
What?
There are many suspicious details that we must cover
before we close the case as an accidental death.
Yoshimura-san's apartment was locked,
but the chain lock was not engaged.
Don't you think that's weird for a
person who's being threatened?
I see...
Also, if he was drinking diluted whiskey right before he fell,
don't you think it's strange that the ice has melted?
Hey, hey, Mouri-kun. What are you trying to say?
Simply that Yoshimura-san was not
at his apartment when he fell.
That's ridiculous. Where was he then?
Yoshimura-san's sandal gave it away.
His sandal?
The victim had a sandal on his left
foot, but not on his right foot.
The missing sandal was thrown quite far onto
the courtyard of the warehouse next door.
Even if he had lost his balance getting
down the emergency stairs,
Sandal
I doubt that the sandal would have flown all the way there.
It has to be from a place higher than the fifth floor.
Sandal
A possible place would be the rooftop.
But the door to the rooftop is locked.
What? Then that means...
There is only one other place it could
have fallen from besides the rooftop.
But that means...
Exactly Inspector. Yoshimura-san didn't fall from his
apartment, but rather this one on the sixth floor.
Ueda-san, it was your doing wasn't it?
What nonsense!
Officer Chiba, can you help me with some things?
Sure.
Please move the TV to the corner of the room.
Yes.
Is this okay?
That's fine.
Next, move the table to the center of the
room and put the chairs on both sides.
Finally, move the bed next to the wall.
Wait a minute Mouri-kun, a bed is too heavy to move easily.
Well, please wait and you'll see.
This bed has wheels so it's easy to move.
Now Inspector, doesn't this room feel
exactly like a room somewhere else?
The furniture arrangement does look similar
to that of Yoshimura-san's apartment.
Ueda-san rearranged this apartment beforehand, to trick
Yoshimura-san into thinking it was his apartment.
But Mouri-san, the furniture's not the same.
Yeah, but if he had woken up in the dark, he wouldn't
have noticed that he was in someone else's room.
That's how he got Yoshimura-san to jump
from the window, and die in the process.
Please, wait a minute! When Yoshimura fell, I
was right there with you, wasn't I, Mouri-san?
That's true. You used me to create an alibi.
But please explain, how would it be possible for
me to make Yoshimura fall if I was with you?
You used Yoshimura-san's habit of using the emergency
stairs in the warehouse next door to make this trick happen.
You were probably drinking whiskey with
Yoshimura-san in his apartment.
Then, you spiked his drink to knock him out,
carried him here, and put him in bed.
You made the disoriented Yoshimura-san believe
that he was sleeping in his own apartment.
Then, while you were with us at the coffee shop,
you called him saying, "The man threatening you
is coming to get you", and told him to run.
Moreover, you had an accomplice.
Are you saying he had help?
Inspector Megure, this man has something important to say.
I'm Umemoto, a florist.
Inspector Megure, this is the accomplice
who unknowingly helped in the plot.
Umemoto-san, if you don't mind, can you please
tell everyone exactly what you did tonight?
Sure. I received a call to deliver flowers
to Ueda-san's apartment at 7pm.
To this apartment?
Yeah.
When I got here at 7pm, I knocked repeatedly because
I had been told that the doorbell wasn't working.
But, nobody answered.
Can you please tell us what you did next?
Well, I returned here after the other deliveries, and that
man opened the door and said he didn't order anything.
Inspector Megure, do you understand now?
When the florist knocked, the phone
call filled Yoshimura-san with fear.
Mistaking it for the man that was after him, Yoshimura-san
tried jumping to the next building like usual.
But unfortunately, he was on the sixth
floor and couldn't make the jump.
He fell straight to the ground.
That's ridiculous! That's just your overactive imagination.
The reason you held Yoshimura-san's corpse was to create
an excuse to return here to change the furniture back.
By saying that you wanted to change
out of the blood stained clothes.
The reason Conan saw you sweating in your apartment was
because you had just finished moving the furniture back.
That's nonsense! Do you have any proof?!
Of course I have proof.
When we were in the coffee shop, you said you don't smoke.
But there are cigarettes and an ashtray here.
Yoshimura-san was a smoker.
If he got up early and wanted to smoke, you didn't want
him to suspect that he wasn't really in his room.
That's why you brought the ashtray
from Yoshimura-san's apartment.
Yoshimura brought it here himself when he
came over. That doesn't prove anything!
Inspector, please check the Caller ID on that phone.
Let's see...
There was a call at 7pm.
Hey Mouri-kun, this call is from a cell phone.
If I'm not mistaken, it's Ueda-san's number
from the phone call at the coffee shop.
I see.
Hey, wait! At that time, I must have
called my own number by mistake.
Oh? Then why isn't there a call record
on Yoshimura-san's phone?
How did you confirm that Yoshimura-san was home then?
You must have thought you wouldn't be
made a suspect by being with us, right?
That's probably why you didn't check your phone records.
Is that true, Ueda-san?
The truth is, I lost a lot of investments
and was desperate for money.
Yoshimura made me a deal I couldn't refuse. The plan
was to steal drugs from the university and sell them.
I did what he said and got my share. But when I told him I
didn't want to do it anymore, he threatened to tell everyone.
So, thinking I would be ruined at this rate,
I had to get rid of him at any cost.
Then I learned that he was being threatened by his
old accomplices, and used it to my advantage.
Start in my Life
Song by: Mai Kuraki
ii koto bakari no mirai janai keredo
The future will bring misfortune, but...
tashika ni ima wa ashita ni mukai dare yori mo kagayaki
I will continue running to tomorrow, brightly shining.
koko ni tatteiru koware kake souna ima ni namidashi soredemo
Now, standing here, shedding tears for the weak... Even...
We can start in my life issho ni
We can start in my life together...
akiramezu yume to
And follow our dream.
nee mou hitori no jibun ni aeru kara
You can also meet the other you.
kimochi hitotsu de kawarerun da
With one feeling, we can change.
hora koko kara hajime you
Let's start here.
Just start in my life
Just start in my life.
Another case solved!
Uncle, you sneezed earlier too. Maybe you caught a cold.
No, it's just that something is making my nose itch.
You better not catch a cold and cause trouble.
Look who's talking.
Now that I think about it, you'll come with me tomorrow too.
Are you working again tomorrow?
Horse racing! When you're with me I get lucky, so I'm
sure I'll bet on the right horse for the grand prize!
No way you'll win anything like that.