A hint to reasoning is to dream.
There's a mystery behind every case!
Four cute little pet dogs,
and the four suspicious breeders.
Seeking the one and only truth.
With the appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult.
His name is... Detective Conan!
The Evidence That Didn't Disappear
(Part 1)
So cute!
This is a male Shiba Inu, isn't it?
What's his name?
Teruya Kanou (26)
Professor Agasa's Friend's Son
It's Arthur.
You know, from the creator of the famous
Detective Holmes: Arthur Conan Doyle.
Then, if he partners up with Conan-kun,
They would be the best detective team, wouldn't they?
Hey, hey, are you comparing me to a dog?
What's wrong with that?
I think that's a cute, girlish idea.
You've said too much.
Yeah, yeah...
My, the town has sure changed over the past ten years.
Yeah, were you able to find the new parking lot?
The entrance there is quite hard to find.
Ai-kun helped me read the map, so we found it just fine.
Hey, Arthur! Will you stop that?
This is weird.
He's never been agitated enough to bark like this.
Hey, Professor.
By chance, before you got here, did you
come into contact with another dog?
Moreover, a bigger male breed than this Shiba Inu?
Yeah, Ai-kun and I pet a Doberman that a friend in the
neighborhood brought to my house this morning.
But how did you know?
There's some fur on your pants.
Dogs can figure out the size and
sex of the dog from its scent.
When he caught the scent of a larger male dog on you,
he saw you as an enemy and became aggressive.
Also, you and Haibara were at this entrance once, but
left when Kanou-san asked you to park the car, right?
Arthur got the impression that you were turned away by his
master, but came back again as his master's enemies.
So that's the reason.
You're really stupid.
I guess he and Conan may have a little bit
of the same thoughtless personality.
Hey, hey.
Don't be hard on him, that was just an instinctive mistake.
A dangerous person who is not his friend.
In my case,
he may not have been mistaken.
Hey, Haibara.
Just kidding.
Hey, I...
There's another reason why Arthur kept barking.
Your voice wasn't firm enough when you commanded him.
Yoshio Tsunashima (45)
Dog Breeder
If your voice isn't firm when commanding him,
He'll think he's doing the right thing.
Pay attention to that next time.
Okay.
Who is this man?
This is Tsunashima-san. I met him
at the Dog Breeders' Club.
He came here for the same reason you did, Agasa-san.
How nice!
Cool! I'll take this plane!
I'll take this doll!
As for me, I'll be taking this antique hourglass.
Is this really okay? These things look very expensive.
Yeah.
My late grandfather bought and gathered these
things as a hobby during his travels abroad.
The three of us in the family don't really
have any interest in those antiques.
Selling them would be disrespectful to my grandfather.
So my father and mother decided to
give them to our acquaintances.
Speaking of your parents, where are they?
My parents have been getting ready since
yesterday to move into their new house.
Since my job is forcing me to move to England,
and due to their old age, they decided to
move to the countryside, near my uncle.
That's why we're giving away everything inside this house.
The truth is, Arthur is the only thing
I'm bringing with me to England.
My parents will be taking my mother's dog, Doyle.
It's a Papillon, right?
Since you have one named Arthur and another one
named Doyle, is there one named Conan too?
The Shepherd my father used to have was named Conan.
However, he died two years ago due to an illness.
I see.
But it's all right, we'll always have you Conan-kun.
What do you mean by that, Ayumi-chan?
But isn't Papillon a weird name for a kind of dog?
Papillon means "butterfly" in French.
They were very popular in the 16th century.
Even Queen Marie Antoinette owned a Papillon.
But whenever I see this dog, I'm still amazed by his fur!
No wonder he had a crushing victory.
Crushing victory?
In those competitions that my mother
sometimes entered him in.
Yeah, he's such a fine dog that people even
offered one million yen to buy him.
One million!?
Truly,
He's a valuable, elegant dog.
And he's exactly like that selfish, spoiled
French queen who was decapitated.
Tosabayashi-san!
Aki Tosabayashi (39)
Dog Breeder
The door was open, so I took the liberty of entering.
Your mother told me that she'll give me whatever I want.
But at the moment, I have no interest
in anything except this big vase.
Besides that, everyone can take whatever they want.
Sorry, but I'll just be taking what I want.
Is she a fellow dog breeder too?
Yeah, she wasn't always like that, though.
She's still mad that her dog lost against
Doyle in the competition.
Oh no! She might take the clock that
I claimed in the Japanese room.
I should put a note on it so nobody takes it.
Hey Haibara-san, why don't you choose something too?
You don't get an opportunity like this every day.
There are many cool things here.
I guess.
In that case, I think I'll take this dog.
If I'm killed like Marie was, and when
the dew on the guillotine vanishes,
he will drown himself in the Seine river, like Marie's
dog Thisbe did, following me in death.
Right?
Hey, hey, hey!
S-She's an unusual girl, huh?
Uhhh, well...
Hey, Shinichi!
Try to lift her spirits a bit.
It's serious. She hasn't left the house since the bus incident,
and I was barely able to convince her to come here!
That's weird.
After the incident, I asked Inspector Takagi if
there were any suspicious people on the bus.
He said that there weren't any unidentifiable
people and there's no reason to be worried.
I did tell her this on the phone though.
But that fear is not normal.
She's not eating at all,
and she has trouble sleeping.
In any case, all I can say now is that even if there was
a member of the Black Organization on that bus,
they shouldn't be aware of Haibara's existence yet.
It's been ten days since that incident.
If they had figured it out, we would be dead by now.
Both of us, you, and the three of them.
If that's the case... Right?
Very well.
Hey, hey. Not again!
Um... Agasa-san, please don't be shy, help yourself.
All right, thanks a lot.
Well then...
Oh! If that's the case...
I think I'll take this stereo over here.
Oh, I'm sorry!
Someone's already reserved that.
Arthur, don't do that. You're not supposed
to come in here with muddy feet.
Hey!
What's the matter, Arthur?
I get it, I get it.
I understand, so let me go Arthur! Geez...
What do you want to show me?
I'm sorry.
I pressed the doorbell several times,
but it seems to be broken.
Shino Hasuki (27)
Dog Breeder
Arthur was thoughtful enough to bring you here.
So, please don't be mad at him.
No, it's my fault for not noticing...
Well then, go play with Arthur.
They seem to get along really well.
She's a Shetland Shepherd, right?
Yes, her name is Christie.
I see.
The king and queen of mystery novels.
Could she be the one who reserved the stereo?
Yeah.
I thought it would be a great present to celebrate
my brother's admission into Senior High School.
I don't really care, but wouldn't it be better
to separate those two dogs quickly?
If they were to mate, their offspring would
be a worthless mix that wouldn't sell.
No need to worry.
Arthur will be leaving for England soon anyway.
Isn't that right, Kanou-kun?
What's wrong with Doyle?
It's time for his snack.
My grandfather loved dogs.
So my mother,
gave Doyle his snacks in front of the Buddhist altar in the
Japanese room, so my late grandfather could see him.
But Doyle eventually formed a habit.
When he hears the clock chime at noon, he
would go directly to the Japanese room,
and sit on a flat cushion to wait.
Flat cushion?
Yes, Doyle adores the blue flat cushion.
He even brings it in front of the Buddhist altar himself.
But doesn't the clock sound the same at midnight?
What happens if Doyle mistakes that for noon?
That's not a problem.
We asked the clockmaker to set it
to chime only at 12 o'clock noon.
But is it okay for me to take such a precious clock?
Yes. My mother decided to stop spoiling him and feed
him only twice a day, in the morning and night.
That's fine then.
Come.
Take a peek through the gap.
Doyle is sitting, right? On his favorite blue cushion.
He's not there.
The blue cushion hasn't been removed either.
Is it possible that he didn't see the blue cushion
because it was placed under a brown one?
No. He usually removes it to sit on even
if there are other cushions on it.
But this is strange.
Where did he go?
In any case, let's split up and look for him.
It would be terrible if he went to
a strange place and got stuck.
Doyle!
Where are you?
Come on out, Doyle.
Doyle!
We can't find him anywhere.
So, did you find him?
No, we haven't found him yet.
We looked everywhere, even in the bathroom.
That's Arthur's bark.
Christie's as well. They're barking together.
It's coming from the backyard. Let's go there.
There's smoke coming out of the incinerator!
That incinerator...
We haven't used it in years.
It can't be...
Shoes?
It can't be! It can't be!
A dog collar!
Is that...
Doyle's?
It's a lie... It's a lie...
Doyle! Doyle! Doyle! Doyle!
Don't worry.
The only thing burnt is this collar.
There's no dog corpse inside the incinerator.
By the way, does this really belong to Doyle?
I didn't see him wearing it earlier.
Yes.
Usually we can't see it because it's hidden under his fur.
Even though it's burnt, there's no
mistaking its color and shape.
It's a very old collar that my grandfather bought
specially from France for his Papillon.
Please, come here for a moment.
The back door is unlocked.
It's true.
I see.
The culprit who kidnapped Doyle must
have escaped through this back door.
But why?
Why did he burn the collar?
Probably because without his collar, we won't
be able to identify him from other Papillons.
Since a collar with such decorations would be unusual.
I don't think that's the reason.
Because after kidnapping the dog,
the culprit had to run away quickly.
He wouldn't have bothered to burn a collar that's usually
hidden, and reveal his escape route, would he?
He probably wants us to believe that he left the house.
So Doyle is still...
Yes, that's right.
There's a large possibility that he's hidden
somewhere inside this house.
In that case...
Is it possible that the culprit is still among us?
Hey, hey. Don't tell me you're suspecting us now?
Not really. But...
But if it's as the boy says, then it's
obvious who the culprit is, right?
Now, please look.
Those feminine shoes there.
Those are mine, but how?
My, feigning ignorance are you?
Weren't you the one who brought
them here from the entrance?
That's impossible!
That's not true.
The culprit wouldn't have left their shoes behind.
Moreover, it would have been suspicious if she was
carrying the shoes under her arms in the house.
This isn't Hasuki-san's first nor second visit here, right?
That's right.
Then it would have been easy for you to train Christie
to bring your shoes from the entrance,
and also to return them back there, wouldn't it?
That's not possible.
In any case, why don't we search for Doyle again?
We children will search with Onii-san.
Professor, please search with the three of them.
Ye-Yeah...
But where do we search, Conan?
We searched almost the entire house earlier.
So this time, we won't search for places dogs might
hide, but places where humans would hide one.
That's right. Arthur can help us!
Isn't it obvious? We can use his sense of smell!
The dog's nose is its most powerful weapon.
A dog's nose is much more sensitive than a human's.
So, if we give Arthur the missing Doyle's
scent, he'll surely find him!
Here, I brought it.
It's the cushion Doyle usually sleeps on.
Here you go, smell it.
Well, that might work if it's a police dog...
Not really, this might actually work. My
father always teased him like this.
Seems like he's picked up something.
He's entering the Japanese room.
Then, maybe Doyle's in there!
A blue cushion?
Now that you mention it, Doyle likes the blue cushion, right?
Do dogs like the color blue?
That's weird. I remember that there
were only two blue cushions.
But now there are three, including the one Arthur found.
One extra?
What does this mean?
As I thought, it's impossible.
Hey, did Arthur ever hide shoes as a prank?
No, but rather the opposite.
It's a story from when Arthur was still a puppy. Whenever
I stood up, he thought we were going for a walk.
He would rush to the entrance before me, take
my shoes out from the shoe rack, and wait.
But now he understands that it's not
always for a walk, so he stopped.
He's amazing!
Arthur is definitely more than just a dog.
Here, why don't you track Doyle's scent once more?
Looks like he found something.
But he stopped in front of the living room.
He seems to be thinking about something.
Oh, he resumed his walk.
He's heading towards the entrance.
He's gone outside!
That must mean that Doyle has been taken outside!
Geez, he's just flirting with Christie.
He must have been bored of searching.
We can't do anything about that.
Hey, is there anywhere Doyle hides whenever
someone gets angry at him?
Could it be possible that he went to hide after he
was shocked by the culprit taking his collar off?
Arthur used to hide under my bed.
Under your bed?
Yes.
When we first brought Doyle home, Arthur often got scolded.
Whenever we cuddled the puppy Doyle, Arthur would
get jealous and tear the cushions to bits.
But now they've become best friends.
Poor thing. Maybe Doyle is hiding
somewhere, shivering in fear.
That's right.
Worried about being discovered, living in fear.
It's a painful thing.
Hey, cut it out. Are you sulking?
Not at all.
I'm telling them about the dangerous situation
of an optimist without a plan.
I don't know the reason but,
I'm sure that one of their men was with us on the bus.
If they noticed my true identity at that time, then...
Then you and I,
And everyone will...
Don't worry.
Your true identity will never be revealed.
Why? How can you say that?
While you can sniff out their scent,
I can also recognize them...
From their blood-thirsty presence,
through my detective instincts.
Well, it wasn't very hard once I knew
the owner of this presence.
At the very least, there wasn't anyone on that bus.
The one who thirsts for your blood wasn't there.
What's with that look?
Are you making fun of a detective?
Not at all. I'm just amazed that's all.
I see...
In any case, let's recall today's events
when Doyle went missing.
When the clock chimed at noon,
Doyle ran to the Japanese room where he gets
his snack, disappearing from our sight.
Then we followed Kanou-san to the kitchen,
where he prepared the plate of cheese.
After that, we went to the Japanese room
and realized Doyle wasn't there.
So, everyone split up to search the house.
This is a diagram of the house.
I don't know who searched where...
Where exactly did the culprit hide him?
Moreover, how is he planning to get Doyle out of here?