Destiny
Song by Matsuhashi Miki
A hint to reasoning is to dream.
There's a mystery behind every case!
When Doyle the dog went missing, the
breeders became surprisingly honest.
Seeking the one and only truth.
With the appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult.
His name is... Detective Conan!
Something's just not right
Something's just not right.
nani o motometeru no
What is it we're seeking?
uso ni narete yuku kyou mo fake your eyes
We're used to lying nowadays, as you fake your eyes.
The start of century
The start of century.
tashika na mono nakute
Nothing can be considered certain.
hitori ja nakenai yowasa hate myself
I can't cry over my weaknesses, I can only hate myself.
shinjiteru itami hikikae ni kono mune umetsukushite
Believing in this pain, my chest endures through the exhaustion.
ima utsutte iru futari ga eranda michi kuru
The future in which the two of us can be together is coming...
I think it's only my destiny
I think it's only my destiny.
hateshinai yami no mukou ni
On the other side of this persistent darkness,
dare mo shiru koto no nai ashita ga aru
There's a tomorrow that has no time limit.
oh yeah. You're going nowhere, It's only destiny
Oh yeah. You're going nowhere, It's only destiny
ari no mama ni susunde
Looking for that final resolution,
ima kanjite iru you're in my heart
I can feel you now, you're in my heart.
you're in my heart
You're in my heart.
We visited Professor Agasa's friend, Kanou Teruya-san, to
select items he was giving to friends before moving away.
Later on, we were joined by...
Tsunashima Yoshio-san,
Tsobayashi Aki-san,
and Hasuki Shino-san.
Different desires were aroused as they
gathered here to obtain things.
Then a prized Papillon dog went missing from the house.
Furthermore, we discovered Doyle's
collar, that was cut by a knife,
burning in the incinerator.
That can't be...
...Doyle's!
It's a lie... It's a lie...
Huh? That's weird.
There were only two blue cushions
when we came here earlier.
Including the one Arthur brought out,
there are now three cushions.
There's one extra.
What does this mean?
The Evidence That Didn't Disappear
(Part 2)
When the clock chimed at noon, Doyle ran to the Japanese
room where he gets his snack, disappearing from our sight.
We then went with Kanou-san to the kitchen,
where he prepared a plate of cheese.
After that, we noticed that Doyle was nowhere
to be found in the Japanese room.
Then everyone split up to search in the house.
Even with a diagram of the house, I don't
know where each person searched.
But, where could the culprit have hidden him?
Moreover, how was he planning to get Doyle out of here?
This has become a bad time to move hasn't it?
Yes, that's true.
Moving out...
You said that we can have the things that you're not
bringing with you. Can we take them home today?
Teruya Kanou (26)
Professor Agasa's Friend's Son
Yes, that's fine with me.
Are the rest of them taking their things home today as well?
No, Tsunashima-san will be taking his clock tomorrow.
Yoshio Tsunashima (45)
Dog Breeder
Shino Hasuki (27)
Hasuki-san won't be taking the stereo for
another ten days, a day before I leave.
Even though I said she could have
it now since I hardly use it.
They're both here today to see another
antique that I found in the Southeast.
Aki Tosabayashi (39)
Dog Breeder
And even though Tsobayashi-san showed up unannounced,
judging by her personality, she'll most
likely take the vase home today.
I'm pretty sure that vase is in the living room! Don't tell me...
Doyle is inside the vase?!
Not likely, huh?
Even the stereo that's being moved in
ten days can't hide a small animal.
It's impossible to hide a dog in the
clock from the Japanese room too.
Huh? That clock is five minutes behind.
That's weird. It's never been wrong since we repaired it.
Wait a minute. When I saw the clock
earlier, I'm pretty sure it was...
What's this cotton-like thing?
It looks like some sort of chemical fiber.
Hey, let me see that.
This is!
That glittering cotton was on the
cushion Arthur found as well.
Wait a minute! Where have I seen
this kind of material before?
The incinerator!
What's the matter, Conan-kun?
Could Doyle have been burnt in there after all?
When I checked earlier,
I thought this was just burnt rubbish.
There's no doubt. This is glass wool,
a sound absorbing material!
I understand now.
That's what the culprit used!
Hey, Conan-kun!
I've figured out where Doyle is hidden,
the method used to hide him,
the intention behind it,
and who the culprit is!
It's already this late?
I'll be leaving then.
Me too. I have to prepare dinner.
P-Please hold on for a moment.
Well, just accept this as bad luck and give up on that dog.
N-No way...
That sound.
The clock in the Japanese room.
But it's only supposed to ring at noon.
Then why?!
Conan-kun?
We did it, Conan.
We'll now go and make the preparations.
Yeah.
What preparation?
We're going to do an experiment,
to see if the criminal could really hide Doyle
without anyone noticing anything.
How foolish, have you forgotten that Doyle is still missing.
The leading part of this experiment, of course, goes to Doyle.
Doyle!
You found him!
Thank goodness!
Come watch the experiment then.
We'll begin in the corridor where Doyle was last seen.
Geez. Isn't it enough that the dog has been found?
I'm not going to play along with some
children's detective game.
All right, all right.
Mitsuhiko, you can begin now.
Roger that!
It's that clock again!
That's right. When Doyle heard the clock chime,
he ran towards the Japanese room
for his cheese snack as usual.
We also headed there after stopping by the kitchen.
That's what happened, right?
Y-Yes.
Now then, where do you think Doyle is?
What foolishness. He always gets his snacks in the
Japanese room, so of course he's there now.
Huh? He's not here.
Also, the chime didn't come from the Japanese room.
Really?
What in the...
Hey, Kanou-san.
The chime came from the living room.
The living room?
You don't mean that the sound came from the stereo?
That's right.
We recorded the chime from the Japanese
room earlier, and played it here,
using this tape recorder I borrowed from Nii-san's room.
So, Doyle followed the clock's sound here?
It's not possible with the chime alone,
there must be a cushion as well.
Cushion?
Well, didn't you tell us that Doyle would
sit on his cushion to wait for his snack?
But Doyle's favorite blue cushion
is in the Japanese room.
Doyle likes the blue cushion not because of its color.
A dog's sense of hearing is four times that of a human's. Its
sense of smell is also much stronger than a human's, but...
They cannot distinguish colors at all.
So, Doyle always picked out the cushion
with his scent during snack time.
The cushion just happened to be blue in color, that's all.
That means Doyle wasn't waiting
in the Japanese room at noon.
Rather, he remembers that if he sits on his usual cushion
near where the chime is, he will get a snack.
Knowing that, the culprit used it to
his advantage to get the dog here.
There are teeth marks left on Doyle's usual cushion,
so it's easy for the criminal to identify.
But Tsunashima-san and I searched this living
room and we didn't find anything at all.
Neither the dog nor the cushion, right?
Y-Yeah...
They're here, just well hidden.
Eh?
Here, behind the stereo.
Right here.
Huh? The back of the speaker is...
The culprit removed the sound absorbing material
that filled the speaker's interior in advance.
Doyle's favorite cushion was then placed in
that space, along with a piece of cheese.
Of course, the right speaker had
been adjusted to be soundless.
After that, he played the recorded sound
of the chime from the left speaker.
Then, Doyle was drawn here by the chime, the smell of his
cushion, and the cheese, and went into the speaker.
But wouldn't he come out after eating the cheese?
He fell asleep after eating the sleeping
pill that was placed in the cheese.
But would it have gone so smoothly? If it was noon
at that time, the real clock would have chimed too.
I think it couldn't chime,
because the clock was moved forward 12 hours.
The wall clock is set to chime only at noon. So, if
it's moved forward 12 hours, then it won't chime.
But who would do such a thing?
Isn't it obvious?
Eh?
I can't think of anyone else but Hasuki-san
who wanted that stereo, right?
No way...
She must have planned to hide the dog
in the speaker, then steal it, right?
That can't—! I...
Please wait a moment!
There's no way that Hasuki-san would have gone that far to—
But weren't her shoes left right
next to the incinerator earlier?
Nevertheless...
You're mistaken.
Huh?
The culprit is not Hasuki-san.
What are you talking about?
Because the stereo won't be taken
until ten days from now, right?
There's no way a dog can stay alive
locked in there that long, can it?
But if it wasn't Hasuki-san, then why
was it hidden in the speaker?
The culprit wasn't planning to steal Doyle, but rather
wanted to keep him hidden temporarily, that's all.
Hidden temporarily?
But even if that's a blind spot, the dog would be found
immediately if the back of the speaker fell open.
And the area behind the speaker will
definitely be searched first too.
True. That's why the culprit came here first to
close the stereo's back panel to hide Doyle.
Isn't that right,
Tsunashima-san?
Being the first one to search here,
you could have easily done that while pretending
to search behind the stereo, right?
That's right! I saw you searching behind the stereo
and you said that you found nothing, right?
Hey...
Uncle probably heard about Doyle's snack
time habits from Kanou-san's parents.
As well as about how rarely this speaker was used.
During a previous visit, you peeled off the
acoustic absorber from the speaker,
and left the back panel open in preparation to hide Doyle.
While the speaker would sound strange, it would
divert attention from the suspicious back panel.
You could have also recorded the chime
by being around for Doyle's snack time.
You then set up the tape and cushion in the stereo,
while we were all gathered at the entrance
when Hasuki-san arrived before noon.
You then pretended to search for the missing
Doyle and went around to the speaker,
and removed his collar while he was asleep.
You then retrieved the cushion, and closed the back panel.
You then returned it to the Japanese room,
and set the clock back to the correct time,
And all that's left is to burn the collar in the
incinerator and leave the back door open.
Making it seem like someone had sneaked in, kidnapped
Doyle, then escaped through the back door.
I see!
It seems like Tsunashima-san wanted to burn the
sound absorbent material in the incinerator, too.
However, glass wool is heat resistant.
And most of it remained unburned in the incinerator.
I see. That's why Arthur found the cushion in the Japanese
room when he was searching for Doyle.
The culprit had returned Doyle's favorite cushion there.
But Arthur, why couldn't you sniff
out Doyle inside the speaker?
He knew but couldn't step in here. This is the
room he used to get scolded a lot in after all.
But boy, I don't gain any benefits
by hiding Doyle in the speakers.
What you were after wasn't Doyle, but
what was on his collar: this diamond.
It's quite a costly item that Kanou-san's
grandfather bought in France.
W-Where'd you find it?
It was behind the pendulum of the
wall clock in the Japanese room.
That clock was accurate at noon. But when I looked
again at three o'clock it was three minutes behind,
and at 5 o'clock it was five minutes behind.
It was slowing down by a minute every hour.
That's how I knew that something
was stuck behind the pendulum.
The one who hid it there is the one who will be receiving
the clock. Tsunashima-san, that's you.
You did it!
Damn!
Tsunashima-san!
Damn it!
Stop that, Arthur!
You can't hurt them, can you?
Because you really do like dogs.
That's why you couldn't kill Doyle, right?
You removed the screws from the back of the speaker
so that Doyle could get out when he woke up, right?
Isn't that right, Conan-kun?
But Tsunashima-san...
Why?
Because of money.
The number of dogs I have has increased, and
I needed money badly to expand my house.
In that case, you could have sold some of the
dogs to decrease the number, couldn't you?
The dogs at my house are mostly
abandoned dogs that won't sell.
The only paths left to them are starvation
or poisoning. There are no other options.
Tsunashima-san.
Tsunashima-san,
here you go.
Huh?
Here, please have it.
But...
It's not for you.
It's for the dogs at your place.
Oh Kanou-kun!
Forgive me!
Don't worry.
I think that my deceased grandfather
would have preferred it this way.
Always
Song By Mai Kuraki
Always give my love
Always give my love to you
son janai ima kara de mo iin janai yareru koto
It's not a big thing! From now on there won't be any problems! We can make it.
omotta doori ni yatte miyou kimi to deau made
Let's give it a go. Like we wanted to, until I met you.
nani mo nakatta keredo me o tojite omou
I had nothing, but I closed my eyes and I could believe,
issho ni ikiru basho ga aru kara
because there is a place, where you and I always can be together.
always ai no mune ni yuuki o dashite
Always have courage and love, in your heart.
tatoe sore ga dame da to shite mo ne
Even if you think it's no use.
No sore dake ga jibun janai
No, that's just not like me.
Yes kazamuki ga kawatta ima tobitatou
Yes, now that the direction of the wind has changed, let's fly!
Always give my love
Always give my love to you
Always give my, give my love
Good grief, how shameless.
It's the dogs who suffer by being adopted
by people who can't afford to keep them!
Well, anyway, he did promise to not take in any more dogs.
But both Arthur and Christie are so amazing, aren't they?
Intercepting an escaping criminal, just like police dogs!
It's an instinctive action.
Arthur just went after the person who ran from his
master. And Christie's a shepherd dog by nature.
Shetland sheep dogs are raised to herd back straying sheep.
Instinctively, they will intercept anyone
running away from a group.
You really lack imagination.
But there's something I don't understand.
Why were Hasuki-san's shoes found near the incinerator?
He's definitely the criminal behind this.
Please hide here for a while.
What are you doing, Conan?
Look.
Arthur! When did you start doing that prank again?
Arthur, are you listening to me?
Arthur!
He must really hate me.
No. He just wants you to stay here.
Isn't that right, Arthur?
You said that Arthur had taken your shoes out
before and waited for you to walk him, right?
From that, Arthur learned that humans
can't go out without their shoes.
Eh?
So, if he hides your shoes, you won't be
able to take his beloved Christie home.
That's what it was!
But don't worry, Arthur.
Because both Christie and I will be going to London
where you and your master are headed!
Eh! Then that means...
Yes.
I actually came here today to tell you that.
Huh? So you two are actually getting married?
That's great news. Congratulations to you both!
Congratulations!
We must celebrate before you move away.
Silly.
Rest assured, nobody's angry at you.
Finally!
We were really worried about you!
You've been really depressed lately.
So we all thought of ways to lift your spirits.
I wasn't included, huh?
Because, Conan-kun, you're always
arguing with Haibara-san.
That's right!
Oh really?
Good work, Arthur!
That's a great achievement!
Yes, that's right. Keep up that expression.
With that expression, you'll be seen as just a child.
I just can't see how you're a 90 year old lady.
Isn't that right?
How rude. I'm 84 years old!