Destiny
Song by Matsuhashi Miki
Reasoning and hints are interlinked,
Allowing us to understand a case's mystery.
Today's case is in a wine cellar!
Something happens with the resting wine bottles.
Recognizing that single truth...
a child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is... Detective Conan!
Something's just not right
nani o motometeru no
What is it we're seeking?
uso ni narete yuku kyou mo fake your eyes
We're used to lying nowadays, as you fake your eyes.
The start of century
tashika na mono nakute
Nothing can be considered certain.
hitori ja nakenai yowasa hate myself
I can't cry over my weaknesses, I can only hate myself.
shinjiteru itami hikikae ni kono mune umetsukushite
Believing in this pain, my chest endures through the exhaustion.
ima utsutte iru futari ga eranda michi kuru
The future in which the two of us can be together is coming...
I think it's only my destiny
hateshinai yami no mukou ni
On the other side of this persistent darkness,
Opening Theme
「Destiny」
dare mo shiru koto no nai ashita ga aru
There's a tomorrow that has no time limit.
oh yeah. You're going nowhere, It's only destiny
ari no mama ni susunde
Looking for that final resolution,
ima kanjite iru you're in my heart
I can feel you now, you're in my heart.
you're in my heart
The Locked Wine Cellar
Wow, what an impressive collection!
It definitely has some value.
Do you know a lot about this, Mouri-san?
Uh... well...
President of
Financial Business
Shouhei Kusaka (52)
Wow, you really do know about my collection.
You truly are a great detective.
I'm not that great.
Actually, an aristocrat in Europe spent a
lot of time collecting these wine labels.
Looks like Mouri-san did it.
Now we won't be able to drink wine for a while.
What does that mean?
Your father just complimented his collection.
Takeo Nonaka (42)
Company President
Then...
Like a switch flipped inside of him, his bragging won't stop.
Jyoukichi Tonomura (40)
Sommelier
He won't let go of Mouri-san for a while.
An otaku, huh?
Yukari Takano (38)
Art Museum Owner
Well, he says the same things over and over again.
Like, "This is very hard to get."
This is very hard to get. It's a bottle of Mosel wine.
But he'll probably get sick of hearing that and won't come.
Your father received a handkerchief like this, right?
Yes.
From Kusaka-san's wife, and it had his initials on it.
Just as I thought.
If Kusaka likes you, you get one of these.
Me too, see?
But from now on, it's going to be tough.
He'll constantly be invited to parties.
Well, tell your father not to borrow money from Kusaka.
Else he won't be able to turn down invitations.
So, you're all borrowing money from Kusaka-san?
W-Well...
Hey, Conan...
You say harsh things, kid.
You're right.
We all owe Kusaka money.
Nonaka-san used all of his money in gambling.
Takano-san borrows money to run her art museum.
And I'm using his money for training to become a sommelier.
What are you talking about?
Toshiko Kusaka
Shouhei Kusaka's wife
You seem to be having fun.
Oh, we were just saying how Kusaka-san's
parties always have excellent wine,
and how we were looking forward to this.
He would love to hear that.
By the way, ma'am.
Shall we start the tasting soon?
Kusaka-san seems to have forgotten about us.
I understand.
I'll tell him immediately.
Please.
Oh yeah! Since you're here, I'll show you
the wine cellar in the basement!
Eh? Uh... well...
My best wine is there.
Honey?
The other guests are waiting for the tasting to start.
Oh, shoot! I forgot about that.
I'm saved.
Hello, everyone. I'm sorry I made you wait.
I thought the party was over.
Sorry.
Oh yeah, how's this?
Let's change today's tasting plan and have
the sommelier, Tonomura-san, guess.
It does sound interesting, but...
A sommelier would get everything right.
Really? Since Kusaka-san is saying that...
There will probably be valuable brands of wine.
A sommelier would obviously guess correctly.
If he doesn't, it'll crush his reputation.
There has to be a merit.
I understand. Why don't we do this then?
If Tonomura-san guesses all of the wines correctly...
I'll take care of that matter.
I see. Then there's no need for me to decline.
All right, everyone. Please drink as much as you want.
Ittadakimasu!
Let's see...
Good.
Tuscany region in Italy. Solaia.
Outstanding.
Whoa! Way to go, Tonomura-san!
No. This is only a warm-up.
This is rare. Isn't this Chateau Latour? Probably from 1965.
Wow, you really are something.
A real sommelier!
It's as if you knew which brands were
going to be served beforehand!
No, these are all ones a beginner
sommelier should know by heart.
I'm sorry that these are all for beginners.
I'll bring out the special bottle!
He's going to his eminent wine cellar, huh?
I feel a little sorry for him.
It's a good medicine for him.
Shall we take a break?
I'm tired.
I'm going outside to sober up.
I'm going to use the restroom.
I was kind of nervous.
I don't get it.
Umm, Mouri-san?
Isn't Kusaka-san kind of slow? He's
been gone for forty minutes.
Already?
Umm... Did something happen to my husband?
Oh, Madam. It has been forty minutes since
Kusaka-san left to go to the wine cellar.
What is he doing, leaving his guests
here? I'll call him right now.
Madam, I'll come with you. Something might have happened.
I'm sorry, thank you.
Wait, Conan-kun!
Please watch your step.
Ah, yes.
D-Dear!
What happened?
K-Kusaka-san!
Kusaka-san!
Kusaka-san! Are you okay? Kusaka-san!
Oba-san! Where's the key?
Eh? Oh, the key is right here...
Mouri-san, how is my husband?
Madam. Please call the police.
Your husband is dead.
Madam!
Please get a hold of yourself! Madam!
Why?
Why is he in such an abnormal position?
The victim is Shouhei Kusaka. Fifty-two years old.
The husband of this household and president
of a financial business in Beika City.
He was strangled to death by a
rope that was around his neck.
How was he when he was discovered?
Kusaka-san didn't come back from this wine cellar.
So I came here with the mistress to check on him...
And he was lying there.
And the door?
It was locked.
Inspector.
I asked the wife, and the keys that Kusaka-san had...
Are the keys to the wine cellar and this house.
The wine cellar's door has an automatic key lock.
Only Kusaka-san and his wife have
keys, there are no spare keys.
Auto lock, huh?
Tome-san! How are the windows?
Nothing suspicious.
There's a lot of dust on top of the wine shelves
and there's no trace that a burglar broke in.
As you can see,
there's only a handle on the inside.
So opening the window from the outside would be hard.
And look over there, too.
There's a security alarm.
So if you try to force the window open,
the alarm will go off.
The alarm system control is right here.
If you hit this button on the key,
the alarm system turns off and you
would be able to open the window.
Afterwards, when you shut the window, the
alarm system automatically turns back on.
I see, the culprit wouldn't be able to
go in and out through the windows.
That means we can limit the number of suspects.
The culprit knows Kusaka-san.
He probably had Kusaka-san open the door to let him in.
And then he committed his crime.
The reason why there were smashed wine
bottles on the floor near Kusaka-san...
Is because the culprit fought with Kusaka-san, right?
Probably.
But isn't that weird?
Look!
The wine bottles fell from the very top of this low shelf...
But nothing happened to these bottles!
If you fought in such a small space,
wouldn't it be more messy?
I see... that certainly is true.
That's a coincidence, a coincidence!
What are these marks?
It looks like something rubbed the floor really hard...
Anyways, Inspector. Let's look at the back of this house.
If there's no trace that he came from the back door,
Wait...
then the people in the house...
Maybe...
It doesn't look like anyone tried to unlock the back door.
Maybe someone made a spare key...
Oh, I don't think that's possible.
Why is that?
All of the keys in this house are special
keys called electronic keys.
You can't make copies of these keys
at your local hardware store.
You would have to speak directly to
the maker in order to make a copy.
Then there's no doubt that someone
in the house committed the crime.
What about the people in the house?
They're in the living room.
Alright, let's listen to what they have to say.
Conan! What are you doing there!?
Uh... well... p-practicing pull-ups...
Inspector!
What's wrong, Chiba-kun?
The investigators said they found two sets of fingerprints
that didn't belong to Kusaka-san nor his wife on the door.
The first set of fingerprints belonged to Yukari
Takano, who attended today's party.
The other belonged to Jyoukichi Tonomura.
What?
Alright, let's hurry to the living room!
Yes!
Take care of Conan for me, Officer Chiba!
Eh? Umm...?
Hey, Chiba-san?
What's up, Conan-kun?
Well...
No, I didn't hear that they found something like that.
Did you?
Nope. There haven't been any reports about that.
I found solid evidence!
The culprit should still have it with him!
W-What?
So you're saying the culprit is one of us?
Please explain, Inspector.
Based on the crime scene, it's very likely that the
crime was committed by someone in this house.
Especially Tonomura-san and Takano-san.
Your fingerprints were found on the wine cellar's door.
Hey, wait!
I did go to the wine cellar to ask to borrow more money.
But I didn't go inside!
What about you, Takano-san?
I wanted to ask for an extention for the
money's due date, but I didn't go inside!
Nonaka-san? You?
Eh? I was hanging out in the backyard after Kusaka-san left.
So I didn't go to the wine cellar.
I see.
Where were you, Madam?
I was in the kitchen the whole time.
I would have to go through the living room where
Mouri-san was to get to the wine cellar.
I was sitting down at the living room table the whole time...
But she didn't leave the living room.
Hey, Uncle?
I found something weird in the wine cellar.
Something weird?
Hey, Conan! Where is this weird thing?
Anyway, I am going to call a lawyer!
Yes! Until then, I'm not saying a word!
Now, now, calm down, everyone.
Excuse me.
Hello? This is Megure.
What!? You know who the culprit is!?
Well, everyone. Let me explain...
How this heinous crime was committed and who did it.
From earlier, we came to the conclusion
that the culprit was one of these three.
Yes, that's true.
What?
First, the two of you whose fingerprints
were found on the door.
Tonomura-san and Takano-san.
These two are not the culprit.
Hey... Are you saying the culprit's not here, then?
No, no... He's here.
Here? Then...
Yes. The culprit is you, Nonaka-san!
W-Wait. I was in the backyard at that time.
I didn't go near the wine cellar.
Then allow me to explain.
First, Nonaka-san went through the backyard
and knocked on the wine cellar's windows.
Oh, I had forgotten to say this, but...
I'm having Officer Chiba act as the culprit.
Kusaka-san deactivated the alarm
system and opened the windows.
Officer Takagi?
Uh, yes?
Please act as the victim.
Sure...
And then Nonaka-san lured Kusaka-san to the backyard.
He probably said something like, "I'll tell
you how Tonomura-san cheated."
In the backyard, Nonaka-san waited for a chance
to catch Kusaka-san off guard and murdered him.
With the stolen key, he locked the back door.
Then he put it back in Kusaka-san's pocket.
Wait, Mouri-kun. Then how did he carry
Kusaka-san into the wine cellar?
Even if he threw him through the window,
putting him in the middle of the room is impossible.
He used a clothesline.
Clothesline?
Nonaka-san lined up two poles next to
each other and laid the body on top.
He put the poles through Kusaka-san's belt
to secure the body onto the poles...
And then he pushed the poles through the window...
Tilted them...
I see! The smashed wine bottles were
caught by Kusaka-san's feet!
If he pulled the poles up...
It definitely looks like how Kusaka-san looked like when
he was discovered, but what about the windows?
He lassoed a thin wire on the hook of the window and pulled.
It closed!
This way, even without going into the wine cellar,
you can place Kusaka-san's body between the shelves.
What gibberish! Where's the proof? The proof!
Will you show us your handkerchief?
The one from Kusaka-san with your initials on it.
When you lowered Kusaka-san, the wine bottles broke.
Naturally, wine would get on the poles.
However, there was no wine on the poles.
Which means you wiped it off to hide your trick.
Since you didn't think the wine bottles would
break, you used the handkerchief you had.
You should still have it, because if you threw it
out, people would know who it belonged to.
Damn it! It's his fault!
He imposed a high interest rate on the money I borrowed!
Then he told me to return his money by
tomorrow because of his own issues!
I have to pay for my employees! So that's why I did it!!
Fool!
Whatever the reason may be, a murder is a murder.
The fact that you took away someone's life won't change!
Think about it carefully.
Always
Song By Mai Kuraki
Always give my love
Always give my love to you
son janai ima kara de mo iin janai yareru koto
It's not a big thing!? From now on there won't be any problems!? We can make it.
omotta doori ni yatte miyou kimi to deau made
Let's give it a go. Like we wanted to, until I met you.
nani mo nakatta keredo me o tojite omou
I had nothing, but I closed my eyes and I could believe,
issho ni ikiru basho ga aru kara
Because there is a place, where you and I always can be together.
always ai no mune ni yuuki o dashite
Always have courage and love, in your heart.
tatoe sore ga dame da to shite mo ne
Even if you think it's no use.
No sore dake ga jibun janai
No, that's just not like me.
Ending Theme
「Always」
Yes kazamuki ga kawatta ima tobitatou
Yes, now that the direction of the wind has changed, let's fly!
Always give my love
Always give my love to you
Always give my, give my love
Thanks for your hard work, Mouri-san.
Thank you...
Yeah, thanks.
I'll pay back this deed later...
Hm? Did I lend him something?
Whatever.
You can return it any time!
Oww...
Sorry, Officer Takagi.