Even fate can be used as a hint for reasoning.
Seeing through the most mysterious cases!
Today's stage is Nanki-Shirahama!
The footprints of crime on a white sandy beach!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
The Nanki-Shirahama Mystery Tour
(Part 1)
Shirahama Station
JR Kinokuni Line
Here.
There you go.
Dad! Let's go check out souvenirs at the waiting room!
We don't have to go look for souvenirs just yet, do we?
Wow! How cute!
Hey, look, look! It's Mr. Sour!
No surprise finding this in the plum-producing Kishu!
Let's buy some on the way back.
What's so cute about a sour-looking guy like this?
You can say that again.
So, where to?
Here.
Huh? Nambo Kumakusunoki...?
No, it's read Minakata Kumagusu Kinenkan—
Minakata Kumagusu Memorial Hall.
He's a world-famous botanist who was born in Wakayama Prefecture,
especially known for his research of plants and fungi.
Oh, they had a great researcher like that here, eh...
I'd advise you to study a bit before travelling.
Why don't you stop by for a meal here?
The crawfish here is good.
What do you think, dad?
It's still a bit early...
Let's go check out the memorial hall first.
Minakata Kumagusu Memorial Hall Entrance
The road's closed on this side...
Conan-kun, over here!
Right!
Minakata Kumagusu Memorial Hall
Shirarahama
Wow, the sand is really fine and white.
I wonder why it's so white.
I once heard that the secret of its whiteness
is that it's quartz sand consisting to 90% of silicate acid!
Geez. He sure knows a lot of trivia.
I want to take this sand home!
You know, put it into a little bottle and carry it around with me, like you do with star sand.
There you go again with your girlish tastes...
You were looking at a weird keychain back at the station too, weren't you?
One with umeboshi attached to it.
But it's so cute!
You moron! Only brats like things like that!
Brats?
Excuse me, but aren't you Mouri-san?
Y-Yeah.
I knew it! I'm a fan of yours!
This is awesome!
Can I take your picture?
Fuji-kun, do you know him?
Wow! What a knockout!
He's the famous detective you all know, Kogoro Mouri-san!
Ran, could you take a picture of the two of us together?
Geez.
Here goes...
By the way, did you come here to investigate a case or something?
Nah. We're just sightseeing.
We won a raffle at the shopping center.
Shut up, you!
Are you all students?
Yeah. We're seniors at Naniwa Medical University.
Oh, so you're doctors in the making!
Let me introduce everyone, then.
The girl next to you is the queen of our group, Maki Shinjo-san.
Maki Shinjo (21)
Naniwa Medical University 4th year student
Come on, cut it out, Fuji-kun.
Next to her is our gigolo, Tatsuhiko Yura.
Tatsuhiko Yura (21)
Naniwa Medical University 4th year student
This is our Madonna, Madoka Mitsui-san.
Madoka Mitsui (21)
Naniwa Medical University 4th year student
How do you do?
She's our whiz kid, Kanako Miyahara-san.
Kanako Miyahara (21)
Naniwa Medical University 4th year student
Nice to meet you.
Kota Fuji (21)
Naniwa Medical University 4th year student
And I'm the clown of the group, Kota Fuji!
The three of them are in the art club,
and since Maki-san suggested we take a nature-sketching trip,
we all decided to come.
Though it's more like we're here to help Miss Rich Lady pass the time.-san}
Talk about grateful, really...
She paid for the hotel, train tickets, and the rental car fee as well.
Yura! You've got no class, talking like that!
Where's the problem?
I broke up with her because I didn't like just what she's doing for all of us now!
I mean, she spends hundreds of thousands of yen every month just on cosmetics...
Every time a new product goes on the market, she has it sent in from Paris!
On the other hand, Madoka has no money, just like me,
and doesn't look down on me.
Her childishness is a fly in the ointment though.
Well, aren't you lucky, finding yourself a cutie-pie to go out with.
It doesn't bother me a bit.
Oh, geez.
I'm thirsty.
Kanako, can you go get me something to drink?
No!
Go get it yourself!
I'm not going to be at your beck and call anymore!
Kanako...
It's true that thanks to you teaching me math,
which wasn't my strong point, during high-school,
I made it into university.
I do appreciate what you did for me back then.
But would you stop bossing me around, harping on how grateful I should be to you?!
I didn't mean to boss you around...
Anyway, we've all come on this trip together,
so why don't we all just go on and have a good time?
I'll go get the drinks.
Right...
Maybe I'll have Fuji-kun do things for me instead of Kanako from now on.
I wonder who it was that fainted during practical dissection practice, and was saved by me?
Something like that happened to you?
Come on, Maki-san!
You promised you'd keep that a secret...
Well, I'll be right back, so wait for me.
Mouri-san, what are your plans for after this?
Um...
We're going to Shirahama Energy Land right over there.
Then we'll go to the underwater observatory
and Sandambeki,
before finally watching the sunset from Senjojiki.
How about tomorrow?
In the morning, we're thinking of going to Adventure World...
Would you like to come along with us, Maki-san?
No thanks, we've already got plans...
Anyway, where are you staying?
At the Shin'yuzaki Hotel.
I see...
Dad, we'd better get going...
Yeah, I guess so.
I guess we'll be going then.
Oh, have a nice trip.
Please enjoy yourselves.
Those people, you can't tell if they're getting along or not, can you?
Well, when you're young, anything goes.
Sandambeki
Wow, it's amazing!
It's really a bold sheer cliff!
Looks like you can go all the way to over there.
I'm not going!
No way in hell!
Okay, why don't we go tour the caves, then?
Looks like we can go down by elevator from that building over there.
And after that, we get to watch the sunset at Senjojiki, right?
I'm sure it'll be super-beautiful!
Senjojiki
What a magnificent view!
I'm sure glad we came.
Yeah.
It was worth coming, just to see this sunset.
Mouri-san?
Maki-san!
Did you come to watch the sunset too?
Yeah.
Since I've never seen the sunset from here before.
By the way, Mouri-san,
Do you like sake?
Yes! Very much!
If so, why not stop over at the Tore Tore Market before going to Adventure World tomorrow?
Tore Tore Market?
Aside from fresh seafood,
they have a whole line of top-quality locally-brewed sake.
Did you say locally-brewed sake?
You can send it home by courier service too.
I've also written the bus route to the market from Shin'yuzaki.
There is a bus stop called Bus Depot near the Tore Tore Market.
There aren't any buses that go directly from Tore Tore Market to Adventure World,
so you'll have to get off once at Shirahama Station, but it shouldn't take that long.
Thank you so much for all your kindness!
We'll visit there for sure!
Goodbye, then.
Thank you so much for all your thoughtfulness!
Thank you so very much!
Hey...
It seems like Maki-san came all the way here just to tell us about the market, doesn't it?
I guess she's just a kind person.
The next day
Ruins of Marine Palace
Shirarahama
Sandambeki
Adventure World
Tore Tore Market
The bus for Adventure World is the #3.
The next bus to Adventure World is at 10:15.
That means we've got 20 minutes left to wait.
Shall we take a stroll?
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
I felt like someone was watching me.
But it was probably just my imagination.
If you want it so badly, why don't you buy it now?
It's okay.
Hey.
Let's go take a look in the souvenir shop outside too.
Let's go, Conan-kun.
Hey, we've only got 7 or 8 minutes left, so we'd better get going.
Hey, would you mind if I stop over at the store of the station?
We don't have time, you know. Hurry it up, okay?
So you're going to buy it after all.
Again...
It's like...
Someone's watching me...
This please.
Sure.
Hey, hurry up! The bus is gonna leave!
Only one left?
Someone other than Ran bought one...
Thank you very much.
Maki-san!
Thanks again.
Take care now!
Conan-kun, that bus is headed for Sandambeki!
Adventure World
Wow, nice shot!
Come on, wave, Conan-kun.
N-No thanks...
He's only a kid, and yet he's embarrassed.
Why, it's you, Mouri-san!
I didn't think I'd run into you here.
Oh, you're—
Fuji! Kota Fuji!
So you came here...
Is everyone else here too?
No. Three of them went out to sketch in the morning,
and Maki-san said she was going to go for a drive until sundown.
I saw her around 10:00 at Shirahama Station.
Oh, I see...
Hey, over there! Let's go see!
That's a laptop, right?
Do you always carry it around with you?
Yeah...
That's why Yura calls me a computer freak.
Huh?
What was that?
Oh, excuse me.
Hello?
What?!
Calm down and tell me again, Madoka-chan!
Maki-san's dead?!
What?!
H-H-Hey!
Madoka-san, this is Mouri!
Where is she and what happened to her?!
In the bushes at Sandambeki!
There's a knife in her chest!
Sandambeki?!
That suspicious person was on the bus to Sandambeki...
Damn it!
We're all headed your way. Mouri-san's with us!
You called the police already, didn't you?
How about Yura and Kanako-san?
Not yet?
Got it, I'll get in touch with them.
Hey, didn't we just pass the entrance to Sandambeki?
Madoka-san is further inside.
This way!
Madoka-san!
Fuji-san...
Where is Maki-san?
O-Over there in the bushes!
A knife stab through the heart...
She probably died on the spot.
Maki-san's wallet is nowhere in sight...
However you look at it, this seems to be a robbery-murder case...
There are no signs of a struggle nearby.
That means...
There's a good chance the killer was an acquaintance.
That's strange...
If I recall correctly, Maki-san's keychain...
...had the rental car key on it too...
Does that mean the killer took it and fled in the car?
But this key chain...
What's this?
Work gloves?
Why does she have work gloves on her?
Haven't I told you time and time again not to mess around at crime scenes?!
I'm sorry!
Let's wait for the police to come before we investigate any further.
Ow! Geez...
This sand...
Huh?
This is...
Thank you for waiting.
I am O'ura from the Wakayama Prefectural Police Department.
How do you do?
I'm Ando, from the Shirahama East Police Station.
I am honored to be able to work with you,
the great detective Mouri-san, on this case.
Detective Ando (29)
Shirahama East
Police Station Detective
Detective O'ura (35)
Wakayama Prefectural
Police Detective
Please do give us precise advice if need be.
Well, cooperating with the police is the duty of any citizen!
I'll help in whatever way I can!
So, let me introduce you to the friends of the victim.
This is Kota Fuji-san, who rushed over here with us from Adventure World.
This is Kanako Miyahara-san, who came over here from Engetsu Island.
This is Madoka Mitsui-san, who first found the body.
And this is Tatsuhiko Yura-san, who came here from Shirarahama.
So, Madoka Mitsui-san,
please tell us the circumstances under which you found Maki Shinjo-san's body.
I heard Beethoven playing.
Beethoven?
I was sketching on the far end of Sandambeki.
When I heard a cell phone ringtone playing from behind me...
So I went toward the bushes, where the sound was coming from...
I didn't know what to do,
so I called Fuji-san right away.
It seems that the place where Maki-san was lying was fairly close to you.
Even so, you didn't notice that a crime was being committed?
I was facing the other way,
and the sound of the waves was rather loud...
But you heard the cell phone's ringtone.
W-Well...
It's only natural.
Electronic sounds like those of cell phones are made to be audible.
Yeah, I guess you're right...
Detective Ando, please give us a report on the autopsy.
Right.
The cause of death is shock by a stab wound.
There is no sign of the corpse having been moved after death,
and the estimated time of death,
in other words, the time the murder is thought to have been committed,
judging by the condition of the body, is between 9 and 11 this morning.
No...
I'm sure the time of the murder can be narrowed down a bit more.
We saw Maki-san at Shirahama Station at about ten minutes after 10.
What?
Are you sure it was about 10:10?
After bowing to us, she left immediately in her car.
We were going to get on the 10:15 bus headed for Adventure World,
so I'm sure about the time.
Detective Ando.
How long does it take to get from Shirahama Station to Sandambeki by car?
Well...
Since it's tour season now, it should take less than 15 minutes.
Let's say it takes about 14 minutes,
so she arrives at Sandambeki about 10:24.
If she parks the car in the alley closest to the scene of the crime,
it would take her 2 minutes to get there.
If we assume she was killed immediately,
the time the murder was committed would be around 10:26 at the earliest!
Yes.
We can narrow it down to the
ca. 34 minutes between 10:26 and 11:00.
By the way,
Maki-san's wallet seems to have disappeared from among her personal effects.
Just a few minutes ago,
the car that the victim was thought to have been driving
was found near Sansho Shrine, about 3 km away from here.
An empty wallet was found inside the car.
It's Maki's.
So we've already gotten to the bottom of this case. This case is—
Wait!
Was the key of the car found?
Oh, the key was in the car's ignition.
Hey, did you only receive one key from the car rental shop?
I think so...
I don't think they usually give you two keys, do they?
This is a robbery-murder case.
After attacking Maki-san, the killer stole the car and fled in it,
then abandoned it near Sansho Shrine.
No. It's probably just made to look like a robbery-murder.
It's most likely that this murder was committed by an acquaintance of hers.
If so...
the killer is among us!
The problem is you!
Unfortunately for you, Maki-san saw you,
so in order to contain the secret you decided to shut her up!
Nanki-Shirahama...
The killer must be you!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Cosmetics
Next time, the solution! Figured out who did it yet?
It has to be the person who bought Mr. Sour!
That would be you!