9:30 AM
12:00 PM
Seals (green boxes)
Dolphins (orange boxes)
Orcas (blue boxes)
Break (pink text)
note: watch the highlighting
Even fate can be used as a hint for reasoning.
Seeing through the most mysterious cases!
This is the first time Conan is handling a case like this.
Were you able to enjoy his facial expressions as well as his deductions?
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
We set off on a trip to Shirahama in Wakayama Prefecture.
Despite having a feeling that somebody was watching us,
we continued sightseeing.
Later, we found out that one of the five Naniwa University students that we met the day before,
Maki Shinjo-san, was found dead at Sandambeki.
Her wallet and her car key were missing from her belongings.
In the pocket of her jacket, she had work gloves.
Also, what is the meaning of the tiny glass bottle
and the Mr. Sour on the easel?
It's probably just made to look like a robbery-murder.
It's most likely that this murder was committed by an acquaintance of hers.
If so...
the killer is among us!
Okay, everyone,
please tell us where you were and what you were doing
from 10:26 to 11:00 this morning.
Just what do you mean by that?
Do you suspect us?
No, we're just verifying things.
Tatsuhiko Yura (21)
Naniwa Medical University 4th year student
I was sketching at Shirarahama.
Since there were a lot of tourists,
it shouldn't be hard to verify.
In your case, Mitsui-san,
since you were so near the scene of the crime,
your alibi may not help you much.
But you were there sketching the whole time?
That's right.
Any witnesses?
No.
I don't like to be watched when I'm sketching...
Madoka Mitsui (21)
Naniwa Medical University 4th year student
That's why I had them show me a place where there weren't too many people.
Who told you of this place?
Maki-san did.
She seems to have come to Shirahama often,
so she knew this place very well.
Next, Miyahara-san...
I was at a restaurant near Engetsu Island from about 10:30 to 12:00.
Oh, the parking lot where a woman was standing, calling out to the customers.
The shop where Engetsu Island is in view, right?
Yes, that's right.
At first, I was sketching in the vacant lot where Marine Palace used to be,
right inside the tunnel from the memorial hall.
Tunnel?
Back there, eh?
Maki was also the one who told you about the vacant lot where Marine Palace used to be, right?
Right.
Because I didn't want anyone bothering me.
But somehow, I didn't feel like drawing,
so I went to drink a cup of coffee to refresh myself,
and ended up eating lunch there.
Oh, so you didn't get to draw much, did you?
Yeah, it was no good.
I was sketching at the beach in the afternoon though.
You mean the one on the way to the memorial hall?
But from there, you can only get a side view of Engetsu Island, right?
Why didn't you sketch from the rocky area,
where you could get a frontal view of Engetsu Island?
I didn't want to draw anything that looked like a picture postcard.
That's what art is all about!
Don't ask such silly questions!
By the way, Miyahara-san,
we looked at Maki Shinjo-san's caller ID records
and found that you were the last person to call her.
Yes, I called her, wondering how she was.
But since she didn't answer, I hung up.
Next, Fuji-san.
I was at Adventure World.
From 10:26 to about 11:00...
I think I was watching the marine show.
Do you have any witnesses?
I didn't run into anyone,
but I took a picture using my digital camera.
Would you like me to hook it up to the TV?
You can do something like that with a digital camera?
These are pictures of Maki-san dropping us off this morning.
She first dropped off Kanako-san, then Yura, then Madoka-san, and finally me.
After that, I took several pictures inside Adventure World.
Then I watched the seal, dolphin and orca shows, that were 30 minutes each.
Oh, see, from here.
That's the same show we saw, isn't it?
We saw the one that started at 11.
Then we just missed each other.
Oops, that's it!
But might it be possible that he saw the next orca and dolphin show?
What do you mean by that?
In other words, if he took a picture of the seal show from 9:30 to 10:00,
and then takes the next dolphin show at 11:30,
it would serve as his alibi from 10:00 to 11:30.
I see!
I don't think so.
I think that's an interesting deduction,
but she's not the same woman we saw.
Oh, you're right.
The person we saw had braids.
Which means that Fuji-san has a perfect alibi.
But after taking pictures of the orca show until 11:00
why didn't you take any pictures until 1:15?
The next picture is the one you took when you saw us at 1:15, isn't it?
Isn't it strange that you didn't take any pictures for over 2 hours 15 minutes?
T-That's because I was riding the roller coasters and having something to eat.
Besides, there wasn't anything I wanted to take a picture of then.
Geez, stop it with the stupid questions!
Anyway, please let me copy the photos on your driver's licenses
so I can go verify what you just testified.
I'm pretty sure...
that my intuition is correct...
If so...
what's with the pictures he took with the digital camera?
Wait a sec...
His laptop...
Maybe...
Hey, can I go outside for a bit?
Okay, but stay out of trouble.
Right.
Adventure World
Hey, I left just a while ago, but may I go back in again?
My father is inside.
Okay.
I guess you didn't get your hand stamped when you left.
Stamp?
All right...
That's one piece of evidence.
Down with a fever?
Right. That's why we're so busy.
Just as I thought.
But why did Maki-san go to Sandambeki where Madoka-san was
after she saw us at Shirahama Station?
Moreover, the greatest mystery yet
is that I still can't figure out who killed Maki-san!
Just one more time! One more time!
Please let me ride the Adventure Coaster, OK?
What am I going to do with you?!
Will you promise to study when we get home?
I will, I will, I promise!
Okay then, just one more time!
Yay!
There's no way that boy's gonna study.
I see...
That's what happened!
If so...
All the pieces fall into place!
No doubt about it!
That person is the killer!
I'm sure that person's the killer, but I have no proof!
Oh, goodness!
It's really unusually hot today!
I see...
This was a blind spot for me!
I've found conclusive evidence!
Hey, aren't you the boy who came with Mouri-san?
Oh, Mr. Detective!
Why are you here?
Did you come to verify the time of the Marine Show too?
Yeah, just to be sure...
Uncle Mouri was saying that he wanted you to check on something else too.
What? Mouri-san said so?
First of all, Yura-san was witnessed
sketching right through from about 9:00 to after 11:00
by the lifeguard who was on duty at the beach park.
Next, as for Miyahara-san, we were able to get testimony from the people at the restaurant.
The problem is you, Fuji-san!
We questioned the Orca trainer and found out
that the same members have been on duty all day today.
Nevertheless, a person that was not even there today
was taken on your digital camera!
Well, that's because...
Fuji-san, you left Adventure World once, didn't you?
No use lying about it,
because all we have to do is use this blacklight to disclose that you did!
What is that?
Come on, Mouri-san, stop pulling our leg!
You're the one who told us to check on it.
Please go ahead.
Please show me your right hand.
Some letters have appeared?!
Fuji-san, that mark is stamped on the hand of those people who want to re-enter
when they leave Adventure World temporarily.
I-I'm sorry...
The pictures I just showed you were edited ones I took last time I came to Adventure World.
I edited them on my laptop.
Oh? Why would you do something like that?
Well...
You're going steady with Madoka-san, right, Fuji-san?
Conan-kun, what are you talking about?
Madoka-san—
Fuji-san, you left Adventure World at around 9:50
to see Madoka-san who was at Sandambeki, didn't you?
And you stopped over at Shirahama Station on the way, right?
Look, little boy...
Why would he go from Adventure World to Shirahama Station
that is in the opposite direction from Sandambeki?
He went to buy the keychain that Madoka-san wanted.
See, the one that is on that bag.
Mr. Sour is only sold at the shop at the station.
That's when you saw Maki-san, right, Fuji-san?
So...
I was really surprised back then...
I didn't think I would run into her in a place like that.
Maki-san!
Thanks again.
To top things off, I run into all of you too, Mouri-san...
I didn't want anybody to find out that I was going out with Madoka-san.
Especially when it came to Maki-san and Yura.
I knew!
That's why I went part-way to see Madoka too.
I got to Sandambeki a little before 12:00...
But you weren't there,
and that keychain was hanging from the easel...
We were having lunch then.
I sensed right away that you were with Fuji.
That's why you threw down the bottle with sand in it, right?
The sand from Shirarahama?
You got it for me?
Because I said that I wanted to take it home?
So, you found it, little boy?
Cracked just like my broken heart...
Why did you keep something so important hidden?!
Well, let's calm down a bit here, Mouri-san...
Which means you took those pictures with your digital camera
just so that you could show your friends that you had an alibi of not being with Madoka-san?
Yes, almost as if I were playing a game...
I'm really sorry.
But how did you figure it out, Conan-kun?
That I was going out with her?
Because you were the very first person
that Madoka-san called to report what had happened to Maki-san
when it would've been more natural for her to call her boyfriend Yura-san, right?
Besides, when we got to Sandambeki, you knew where Madoka-san was sketching.
That's why I thought maybe you had already seen her today.
Oh, I see...
No!
Unfortunately for you, Maki-san happened to see you together with Madoka-san,
so in order to contain the secret you decided to shut her up!
Nanki-Shirahama...
What seems to be the matter, Mouri-san?
Oh! Don't tell me!
This must be the much talked-about Sleeping Kogoro pose!
Now, Fuji-san has absolutely nothing to do with today's incident.
What? He's not involved?!
The main point of this case
is that the main character was switched partway.
The victim of the murder
which was supposed to have been Madoka-san was switched to Maki-san!
Let me explain...
First of all,
Maki-san, who hated Madoka-san for taking her lover away,
schemed to kill her.
Maki-san was scheming to kill me...?
And she chose Sandambeki as the place to carry out her plan.
However, since Maki-san had a motive to kill,
she decided to make herself an alibi.
She had someone pretend to be her
and made that person do something at Shirahama Station that would stand out.
D-Does that mean she had an accomplice?!
Right.
When Maki-san ran into us at Shirarahama,
she thought of setting us up as witnesses to her alibi.
That's why Maki-san asked us for our schedule.
She set it up so that we would arrive at Shirahama Station at 10:00 today.
But Maki-san's accomplice had other plans.
Other plans?
That plan was to switch Maki-san's alibi
and kill her!
Wait, Dad!
Then the Maki-san that we saw at Shirahama Station at about 10:10 was...
Yeah, that was an impostor!
The impostor wore a wig, hat, sunglasses and even make-up
to look just like Maki-san.
By the time we met at Shirahama Station,
the impostor had already killed Maki-san at around 9:35 at Sandambeki.
35 minutes before we met her...?
W-Who is that impostor anyway, Mouri-san?!
There is only one person whom Maki-san trusted enough
to make her an accomplice in committing the murder...
and who could disguise herself to look just like Maki-san among the four of you.
Yes, Kanako Miyahara-san...
...only you could have done it.
I...
But Mouri-san!
Kanako-san already told Maki-san yesterday that she would not listen to Maki-san anymore!
Well...
Maki-san told her to say that.
So that the police wouldn't suspect
that Kanako-san helped her construct an alibi
because she was under Maki-san's thumb.
This morning, after Maki-san dropped everyone off at their destination,
she returned to Engetsu Island, and made Kanako-san get into her car.
Kanako-san disguised herself as Maki-san as they drove along.
According to Maki-san's plan,
she was supposed to get off at the inner alley of Sandambeki,
and after that, Kanako-san would drive to Shirahama Station.
Then after her alibi was established,
Maki-san was supposed to kill Madoka-san.
I see!
That's why there were work gloves in Maki Shinjo-san's jacket!
Right!
She was going to use them when committing the crime.
However, Maki-san's plan suddenly fell apart.
After committing the murder,
Kanako-san took Maki-san's knife and wallet.
She did this to make it look like a robbery-murder.
She then drove away in the car
and arrived at Shirahama Station a little before we got there.
Then she observed us
and waited for the right time to appear before us.
Which means that when Conan-kun said that he felt as if he was being watched...
Right! It was Kanako-san!
After that, you...
...made us witness Maki-san at around 10:10.
Then you went to Sansho Shrine, while at the same time getting rid of the evidence.
You then abandoned the car and went back to Engetsu Island!
Please wait!
Do you have any grounds for saying all of this?
Of course!
Although you mentioned not wanting to be bothered by others,
you went out of your way to choose a beach with a lot of tourists and started sketching.
Fearing the estimated time of death being extended later on,
you called Maki-san on her cell phone
to make Madoka-san find her as soon as possible.
That's nothing but a far-fetched interpretation of the facts!
If you insist that I'm the killer, show me proof!
If I recall correctly,
Maki-san was using make-up that she ordered from Paris, wasn't she?
You may have been able to get a hold of the clothes that Maki-san wore,
or the bags she carried, in Japan,
but as for the characteristic color lipstick that she used,
you could find no substitute here.
Also, your saliva was found on that lipstick.
The saliva of the person who used it last—you!
Moreover...
Maki-san's lipstick, that you could not wipe off completely,
is still on your lips!
Under Mouri-san's orders,
we have already received the results of the forensic analysis of Maki Shinjo-san's lipstick.
Would you like me to explain in detail about saliva and blood type?
No, thank you.
I have that much medical knowledge myself.
When did you figure out that I was the killer?
It took me quite a while to put my fingers on you.
I only had a hunch that it was one of you,
when I found the keychain near the dead body.
Keychain?
Maki-san had the key of the rental car
attached to the same keychain as her house keys, right?
But the key of the rental car was missing from that keychain.
That's because Maki...
Yes.
A robber would have taken the keychain and all
because Maki-san's keychain was not the hook-type,
but the coil-type, that is harder to remove the key from.
So I concluded that Maki-san
likely handed over the car key voluntarily.
Very impressive, Mouri-san, as expected.
I've completely lost.
But Kanako, why did you...?
I...
...entered the university illegally.
I asked Maki's father to get me in.
After I got in,
Maki threatened to reveal what happened if I didn't listen to her.
That's why I kept following her orders all this time.
I wanted to be free...
...from Maki.
Shirahama Station
I guess we'll manage to get back to Tokyo by tonight.
It's goodbye to Shirahama...
I'm so sleepy, I can't stand it...
Then have some of this.
An umeboshi...
So sour!
I'm awake!
Now if only this could also awaken your talent as a detective.
Ray-san, you're OK. Switch it on.
Ah, Ricardo-san, that's not it.
Left, left!
Ah, wait!
This man...
Isn't he that reporter from earlier?
His left hand's latched onto something...
Next Conan:
The Osaka "3 Ks" Case
(Part 1)
Next Conan's Hint: Sushi
Next time, for the first time in a long time, Osaka is the stage!
Kanimiso, kaibashira and kaiware are the 3 Ks of sushi!