destiny
Song by Matsuhashi Miki
Reasoning and hints are interlinked,
Allowing us to understand a case's mystery.
Today we return to Osaka!
It's an exciting case at "K3"!
Recognizing that single truth,
a child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Something's just not right
nani wo motometeru no
uso ni nareteyuku kyou mo fake your eyes
The start of a century
tashika na mono nakute
hitori ja nakenai yowasa hate myself
shinjiteru itami hikikae ni
kono mune umetsukushite
ima utsutte iru futari ga eranda michi kuru
I think it's only oh my destiny
hate shinai yami no mukou ni
dare mo shiru koto no nai ashita ga aru
Oh yeah you're going nowhere it's only destiny
ari no mama ni susunde
ima kanjite iru you're in my heart
You're in my heart
A restaurant's opening party?
Yeah, that's right.
Actually, my parents were the ones invited,
but they both got colds and can't go.
So, I'm inviting you guys.
As I was saying, three of the most famous
American athletes will be here in Japan.
One thing.
What?
Where is this party?
Of course...
It's here in Osaka!
Pass.
What's with you today?
This is a unique opportunity.
Sorry, I have some stuff to deal with here.
I'm home!
Welcome home...
Oh, who're you talking to?
Just the professor.
He wanted to ask me about something.
What is it?
What's going on?
If it's bad, I can call back later.
No, we're good, we're good.
Really?
Anyway, you can't miss out on this.
Those three famous athletes will be there.
Pro-boxer Ricardo Barega,
Major Leaguer Mike Node,
And lastly...
The Osaka "3 K's" Case
(Part One)
This place has it all!
Mai Kuraki!
Miho Komatsu!
TWO-MIX!
And my favorite...
Okino Yoko-chan!
Don't be so loud, Dad.
It's embarrassing.
Aren't you the one carrying a picture around to get signed?
But is this really all right, Kazuha-chan?
We don't have an invitation and we really weren't invited...
Oh, don't worry about it!
Your Dad's famous!
Not really.
Speaking of that...
Hattori-kun? What's wrong?
He's been acting so strange lately.
Strange?
I hear him talking on the phone, saying:
"Are you alone now?"
"You haven't been exposed yet?"
"If it's bad, I'll call you back later."
Wait, you mean...
An affair.
A-f-f-a-i-r.
He must be attracted to some woman.
I thought that maybe she asked him to come here.
It's me. He's been talking to me.
All right, here we go.
Everyone, please help me welcome the
owners of the World Restaurant, "K3".
They're the special guests of tonight's party.
First, we have the former world
heavyweight boxing champion,
Ricardo Barega
Former Boxer (36)
Ricardo Barega-san.
Next is the major leaguer who pitches 160km,
Mike Node-san.
Mike Node
Major Leaguer (35)
And last up is the goalkeeper known
as the "Iron Wall of Europe",
Ray Curtis-san.
Ray Curtis
Pro Soccer Player (37)
Awesome!
It's him!
See? I told you this would be great.
Yeah.
I'll start with a few questions for them.
I'll ask why they chose Japan to open their restaurant in.
Why did you choose Japan to open your restaurant?
It's because Japan is like a second home to us.
He can speak Japanese?
My wife, and Mike's wife, are both Japanese.
And Ricardo just loves ninjas and samurais.
Does the "K" in the restaurant's name, "K3", mean "Kings"?
No, no, that isn't it.
The first is a...
Knockout.
The "K" is from K.O.
The next is a...
Strikeout, represented by a "K".
The last is a...
Goalkeeper.
"Keeper" begins with "K", doesn't it?
I see!
But, didn't you forget one, Ray?
Hey, isn't Japan the home of your many scandals?
Ed McKay
News Reporter (48)
Maybe "K" stands for "kitanai".
FILTH
Hey Ed, watch your language. Get out.
Mike, what'd he say?
Hey, hey, it's you who should watch your language.
I'm here by request, as I have my own invitation.
Well, at least we're all friends here.
I interviewed all of you fairly, didn't I?
Who's that?
He's famous in America.
He's a reporter that specializes in
exposing famous athletes' scandals.
He exposes them taking illegal drugs,
playing fixed games, and having affairs.
That somehow reminds me of Heiji.
What do you mean?
Nothing!
Oh, well then, how about you all submit some questions?
Does anyone out there have a question for these three?
Does anyone have a question?
Yes!
Oh, the young woman in the back there.
Please come up to the stage now.
Ran-chan?
Please ask your question.
Um, I actually have a request...
Would you please sign this, Mr. Ray?
Hey, hey...
You can't?
They can't, they didn't come to sign.
OK, OK.
You helped relax this party.
We'll think of this as a present.
Thank you very much!
Well, how about on this uniform?
Will this do?
Would you?
You can't, these are the prizes for the guests...
Don't worry.
I have three more.
B-But...
Oh, um...
Could you write a name, too?
OK. Young lady, your name is?
No, not mine...
"Shinichi"...
Could you please write "To Shinichi" on it?
Your boyfriend?
It's not like that...
She... remembered...
That I was a fan of Ray...
Hey!
Remember to call her soon!
Yeah, I know...
But isn't it strange?
What is?
Usually goalkeepers are #1, right? He's #8.
It's because Ray used to be a fielder.
But during the World Cup, both the first string and back-up
goalkeepers were injured, putting them in a pinch.
They decided to make Ray the goalkeeper.
His super-saves led them to victory!
After that, when he entered the Sevilla League in
Spain, he came on as a goalkeeper with the #8.
Of course, he wears it for his Major
League Soccer team as well.
Then, what does that #99 mean?
I know he's a pitcher, but are there 99 people on the team?
That stands for 99mph, which is 160km in Japan.
It's the speed of his pitch, so he requested that number.
And that "4"?
On the boxing gloves, right under his signature.
That's because Ricardo used to always win in four rounds.
So, he started putting it under his signature.
Oh, so that's why.
You should've studied up before coming here.
I get it.
I should be more interested in their phone
numbers than their uniform numbers, right?
What are you talking about now?
Who knows?
I'm back!
Jeez, did that brat have you do this for him?
He has no idea.
That's right...
Here, Conan-kun.
This is a ticket to the exhibition match in
Nagai that Mr. Ray will be playing in.
He just gave it to me.
You want it?
Of course!
Lucky!
Man, he's pretty generous.
They did ask me to do something in return though...
With this.
A transceiver?
I was a bit surprised when they asked.
Mr. Ray, you're OK. Switch it on.
Mr. Ricardo, that's not it. To the left, the left!
I see.
They're using the hotel rooms above
the restaurant to form a "K".
So, when the guests come out, they'll be surprised.
But why are they doing this themselves?
They planned for them to do it themselves.
If one of them were to come out, it'd be chaotic.
That's why they got us to look over the "K" for them.
Ran, the lights from the earlier rooms are on, right?
The light on the first floor, at the end of the "K", is off.
OK. I'm on my way.
Mr. Mike, please... um, "open", the curtains.
OK?
It's OK.
You're OK, too, Mr. Ricardo.
Yes!
Ran, is it on?
Let's see...
Yeah, it's perfect!
All right!
The "K" is complete!
That glass window...
That was a gunshot!
What?
What happened?
Is that a shot?
Wait!
Kazuha, make sure those three stay in their rooms!
Hold on, don't go alone!
Over here!
Yeah!
It's that reporter from earlier!
He was probably shot by this gun.
His hand is latched onto something.
H-His belt?
That glass window...
That was a gunshot!
Wait!
Kazuha, make sure they stay in their rooms!
Over here!
Yeah!
It's that reporter from earlier!
He was probably shot by this gun.
His hand is latched onto something.
H-His belt?
The victim is a 48-years old male from
Chicago, America, named Ed McKay.
Inspector Ohtaki
Osaka Police Inspector
The cause of death was a gunshot wound to the chest.
The weapon was this Smith & Wesson revolver.
Judging from the blood stains, death wasn't instant.
Hei-chan, do you remember when the shot was fired?
Yeah, around 8:05 P.M.
I was outside of the hotel with Kazuha.
We saw the glass break, without a doubt.
Outside of the hotel?
Were you about to go into the party?
No, it's not that.
Those three asked us...
To look at the "K" above the restaurant...
To make sure it was right.
"Those" three?
Of course I mean the owners of the "K3" restaurant...
The former pro-boxer, Ricardo Barega...
The Major Leaguer, Mike Node...
And pro-soccer player, Ray Curtis.
Then, those three were responsible for turning the lights on?
Yeah, that's right.
Ray was responsible for the 1st and 2nd floors...
Mike was responsible for the 3rd and 4th floors...
And Ricardo was responsible for the fifth floor.
Those three did it together.
That means any of those three could've committed the crime.
Judging from their pasts, all three of them have motives.
But how can that be?
The glass window that broke was
in the middle of the second floor.
At that time, they were all in their rooms.
Right, Ran?
Do you know what rooms they were in at the time?
I remember Mr. Mike was in the room above
the crime scene opening the curtains.
I know Mr. Ricardo had the wrong
light on in one of the rooms.
And after he fixed it...
Mr. Ray went to turn on the light he
had forgotten on the bottom floor.
And right when the "K" was completed,
the gunshot broke the glass window.
Did you see any of them at that exact moment?
No...
But I did see the lights go off after Mr. Mike
opened the curtains, and Mr. Ray's a bit later.
About three seconds later, the gun was fired.
Right after that, they all looked out the
windows and asked what was wrong.
Then, just who is the murderer?
Maybe a guest from the restaurant did it?
See, when it happened, Heiji-niichan and I rushed up here.
If the killer was one of those that came up with us,
He could have escaped then.
Wouldn't that mean all of the guests are suspects?
That's too many people to deal with.
Ah-le-le...
Look at this man's left hand.
What's he holding on to?
H-His belt?
And look at the fingers on his right hand.
His little finger and ring finger are curled in.
Maybe he played Janken with the criminal?
Conan-kun!
Hei-chan, does this mean...
Yeah.
Grasping onto his belt and the position
of his fingers, they're his...
Dying message.
But that doesn't necessarily mean it's about his belt.
It may be about his pants, like maybe the belt
means it's something about that pair of pants.
Are you an idiot?
If it were his pants, wouldn't his hands
be on top of his pants, not his belt?
Who uses their belt-line to take off their pants?
Then, I guess we'll have to ask all of the guests downstairs.
No...
That won't be necessary.
As I thought, the murderer is one of those three...
The belt...
Right, the evidence is that the belt is worn by the champion.
That's it! The criminal is the former
boxing champion, Ricardo Barega!
Then, what about his fingers?
Since Ricardo usually beats his opponents in
four rounds, there should be four fingers out.
Oh, then it should be the pro-soccer player, Ray!
He did great in Spain, Italy, and America
and even played for their national teams.
Ray also won a title while playing
in the English Premier League.
Oh... I see.
Hey, if he means three fingers, in baseball you...
See, when a pitcher pitches, doesn't he use three fingers?
Yeah, that's it!
The murderer is the Major Leaguer, Mike!
That's impossible.
Mike's team has never won a title.
Besides, you don't win a belt in baseball.
Wouldn't that eliminate soccer as well?
The keys to figuring this out are the three fingers on
the right hand and the white bandou in his left.
We'll need to get past these before we can go further.
Bandou?
Huh? You don't know?
"Bandou" refers to a leather belt in the west.
This guy doesn't know western sayings.
Bandou... 3...
Bandou 3...
Bandou-san!
I see!
It's Bandou-san!
All right! Check the guest registry for
anyone with the name "Bandou"!
Hey, Hei-chan...
Is this that "Sleeping Kogoro" guy?
Yeah, he's just a little drunk today.
Anyway, there's nothing else we can do
with the dying message right now.
Let's wait until after the gun powder test.
All right.
I'll head on down and get the guests ready.
Of course, don't forget those other three in their rooms.
All right, thanks for your cooperation.
Um, excuse me...
Yes?
Would your name happen to be Bandou?
No, it's not.
Excuse me, then.
Well? Anything come up, Ohtaki-han?
No, nothing at all.
What about those three?
We tested them first, but nothing came up.
Have you searched them?
Yeah, just a light body-check.
Their managers won't let us do anything more.
Earlier, didn't Mouri-han mention that
those three weren't fond of the victim?
Yeah, it's true.
That guy reported that Ricardo fought in
fixed matches and was forced to retire.
He said that Ray was kicked out of
European soccer for illegal drug abuse.
He claimed Mike had an affair that lead to his divorce.
But, I heard that his wife was Japanese
and they're doing well.
Regardless, it would seem that he
wasn't killed over the scandals.
But Hei-chan, why do you think that isn't enough to kill?
It's because he just lost the case!
They sued him for their innocence.
Those three may have disliked him,
but not enough to kill him.
I guess you're right.
Hey, Kudo...
What's wrong with you?
What's... What's stopping you?
always
Song by Mai Kuraki
Always give my love, always give my love to you!
son janai!? ima kara demo iin janai!? yareru koto
Don't you think so?! From now on, let's... Isn't it great?! Do what we can.
omotta toori ni yatte miyou kimi to deau made
With the way I feel now, I know I had nothing before you.
nani mo nakatta keredo me wo tojite omou
But when I close my eyes and think...
isshoni ikiru basho ga aru kara
I know there's a place we can live together.
always ai wo mune ni yuuki wo dashite
There will always be love in my heart; I've built up courage.
tatoe sore ga dame da to shitemo ne
To say something is impossible...
No sore dake ga jibun janai
No, that's not like me.
Yes kazamuki ga kawatta ima tobi datou
Yes, the wind has changed: Let's start now.
Always give my love, always give my love to you! Yeah!
Always give my, give my love...