Reasoning and hints are interlinked,
Allowing us to understand a case's mystery.
Today, the case gets resolved.
Will Conan catch the killer?
Recognizing that single truth,
a child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Hattori Heiji invited us to Osaka for the opening
party of the World Restaurant, "K3".
The restaurant owners were...
Ricardo Barega
Former Boxer (36)
Former pro-boxer Ricardo Barega,
Mike Node
Major Leaguer (35)
Major Leaguer, Mike Node,
Ray Curtis
Pro Soccer Player (37)
and pro-soccer star, Ray Curtis; those three.
Later, while those three were turning on lights, a gunshot...
A gunshot rang out.
An American reporter, Ed McKay,
had been murdered.
The Osaka "3 K's" Case
(Part Two)
Jeez, the case has ruined this party.
Now those three won't be able
to give out those signed goods.
Ran-chan, you're lucky you got yours beforehand.
Huh?
That's right, where are Conan-kun and Hattori-kun?
Oh, those two went off with Ohtaki-han for his investigation.
Went off for his investigation?
Jeez...
I'm sure everything'll be fine.
The police already have the pistol that was used.
I guess so.
Not to mention, now Hattori Heiji's on the case.
The hotel elevators won't be
operational until the hotel's open.
That means those three...
Could have only used the stairs.
All of the light switches seem to be installed and working.
Even the ones in these rooms.
To make it go on and off, you have
to push in the switch each time.
Wait...
She told Mike to open the curtains...
If you tied an open loop in a rope to the top of the
curtain, you could do it from outside of the room.
It's impossible.
I've already looked through Mike's room.
There's nothing to suggest anything was
tied to it or that it was tampered with.
Among those three, the most suspicious would
be the one closest to the crime scene, Ray.
It couldn't have been him, because switching on the
light and running up here takes at least ten seconds.
Ray's left knee is injured, so there's
no way he'd make it in time.
As for Mike, he injured his arm in a previous game.
Ricardo's too big and slow.
See, those three couldn't have committed the crime.
You know, Kudo...
You're acting strange.
In the past, you've always gone after suspects
until their alibi was proven beyond a doubt.
Really?
See, making it to the door and knocking
would take another five seconds.
It just can't be done.
Hey Kudo, what's that?
This?
Just a mop.
They keep these in hotel rooms now?
I guess it's a little weird.
Hey, Kudo, couldn't it be done?
The other two can't, but with what he uses so often,
he could operate the light when he isn't here.
What're you saying?
He couldn't have done it. No way.
Hiding such a small tool with so many
people around would be easy.
I already told you!
It can't be done!
I'll prove it to you!
Just watch!
Kudo...
I don't see why...
When you have eliminated the
impossible, whatever remains,
however improbable, must be the truth.
Even if it's hard to believe...
Isn't that what you always say, Kudo?
Are you OK?
Yeah, my old injury... It still bothers me.
Take care of yourself.
I'm OK. If I take some medicine, I'll be fine.
Well, take care of yourself.
Rust on an iron fortress will make it worthless.
Oh, it's tryin' to drop or somethin'.
T-This is...
But this time I can't be wrong!
I heard it in the restaurant.
Ran-chan, your dad's saying stupid stuff again.
It's true!
The employee was shocked as well.
He understood what I meant by "bandou", too!
That Ed guy that died was very familiar with Japan.
I went to a sushi stand nearby for clues and found out.
I see...
That's how it is.
How can this be!?
What's with this deflated soccer ball?
Over here's another one.
Maybe it's an extra?
Think so?
Inspector, can we head back?
These two want to head back to the hotel for a shower.
Oh, no, see...
Let them go, Ohtaki-han.
The test didn't show anything on those three anyway.
But still, Hei-chan...
But there is one thing...
Would you mind doing one thing for me?
You want me to do something?
That's right, Ray.
I'll let you do it.
Me?
Actually, someone is waiting for you...
In the hotel room you're staying in.
This request is actually...
For your biggest fan.
Oh my, gosh...
Who on earth did this?
Right...
This is the same simple method.
First, right before the door automatically locks,
You take a mop from the closet and remove the door.
You put the door near the switch and put
the end of the mop between them.
You then make sure the mop's angle allows
the door to lean against the switch.
Preparation complete.
Then, you get the soccer ball you prepared earlier and kick it.
You opened the curtain when you first came in.
You did it to make sure that...
We would see the trick the second it happened.
Isn't that it...
Ray?
After practicing a few times, even a kid like me can do it.
You were once middle fielder Ray Curtis,
known for his powerful free-kicks.
This would be nothing for you.
Right, by doing this, you can switch the light on the
first floor off while you're on the second floor.
At the same time, you could shoot the reporter.
This would give you an air-tight alibi
that no one would challenge.
Oh, little boy, don't joke around.
Allow me to go into more detail.
You were responsible for the five lights...
On the first two floors of the "K".
The room you used this trick on was #2,
the one on the far left of the 1st floor.
Not to mention, it's the one...
Facing the stairs.
After you turned on the light in the first room,
you moved to the second room to prepare the trick.
You also took the soccer ball and
gun you had prepared earlier.
You then turned on the lights in rooms #3, #4, and #5.
Of course, you left out the second room on purpose.
And then, Ran, who was outside of the hotel,
noticed that you hadn't turned on #2's light.
You said you'd go over the transceiver, giving you time
to run to the soccer ball and kick it down the stairs.
This completed the trick.
And then...
You went and shot Ed, who was waiting...
And then threw the gun inside.
After that, you ran down to room #2.
You pretended you'd been there the entire time, and that
you were as shocked by the gunshot as everyone else.
Isn't that how it happened, Ray?
Ah, very, very good.
But, little boy, you forgot something.
Ran said there were only three seconds
between the shot and my light coming on.
I couldn't have done all of this in time, it's impossible.
How did I kick the ball, run to Ed's room and knock, and
wait for him to open the door all in three seconds?
You didn't kick and then knock.
You knocked and then kicked, right?
After knocking on Ed's door, you ran to the ball
and kicked it right when he opened the door.
You were still talking to Ran on the
transceiver at the time as well.
For you, doing this in three seconds is possible.
Yes, it's possible that Ricardo could tie a string
to a mop and do this trick on the 5th floor.
But the crime scene is on the second floor, your floor.
He wouldn't be able to run from the 2nd
floor to the 5th in three seconds.
Of course, Mike looked perfectly fine
when he opened the curtains.
That means...
You did it, Ray.
You're the only one.
But, boy, what about the gun powder?
When the police were checking for it, they
only tested the outside of your clothes.
They didn't get to check inside.
You removed your jacket before the crime and
turned your shirt and pants inside out.
Before you went back to the window to
look out, you put your jacket back on.
No one would've noticed from that far away.
At that time, you used this pin to deflate the
soccerball and hide it under your shirt.
I found this in the trash can in the toilet!
During the party reception, none of the balls were deflated.
But, where's your proof?
It was Ed who told me...
That you killed him.
Ed's three fingers referred to how Japanese people eat sushi,
while his left hand gripping his belt meant to say "bandou".
In sushi restaurants, the staff tries to
avoid giving out prices until the end.
They use secret signals, like "bandou" for item #8.
That's also the number his killer, Ray Curtis, wears.
That was his dying message.
Also, the towel in your room is still wet.
You used it to clean off the powder, right?
It's true, water will help you pass the powder test.
It's ironic.
I wanted to prove you innocent, so I started to investigate.
But the further along I got, more came up pointing to you.
Little boy, how unfortunate that all
you've said isn't enough to convict me.
My shirt and pants that I wore earlier
are in the hands of the cleaners.
Maybe I changed because I sweat a lot.
I'm pretty sure they're being washed in the
laundry room of this hotel right now.
What about your shoes?
My shoes?
For semi-automatic guns, the gun
powder comes out of the barrel.
But for revolvers, the gun powder
emits from the body of the gun.
Of course it'd be on your shoes.
Ray, you were wearing shoes when you did it, right?
You wouldn't be able to kick it accurately otherwise.
Whether or not you changed and cleaned your shoes...
That'll be the deciding evidence.
Just give up.
Please just give up, Ray.
For me.
Oh, I'm sorry.
That's something I can't do.
If I were to get arrested, my fans, my
family, they'd be disappointed.
Thanks for telling me about my shoes,
boy, I'll go clean them now.
You've helped me beat the police.
Wait.
That isn't your only problem right now...
Right?
The Iron Wall of Europe...
Ray Curtis!
How good are you?
How good are you really, Ray?
That was only a high school student's kick.
You should've been able to block it with one hand.
What's wrong with you?
Answer me...
Answer me, Ray!
I'll tell you, boy.
I use drugs, that's why.
Recurring yawning and joint pains
are both symptoms of drug abuse.
I noticed when you were coming out of the toilet
earlier that your knee is still giving you trouble.
I guess you take them to stop the pains
in your muscles and in your joints.
As I should've known, that super-play...
No, it isn't like that!
I started after he wrote that false rumor.
That bastard Ed's lies caused my wife to commit suicide.
He followed me all the way over here
to Japan, to my wife's hometown...
And wrote:
"In Pursuit of Ray's Drug Abuse: On Site in Japan."
And then, my wife decided she couldn't
take it anymore and left me.
That's why...
I started...
That's why I started...
Stop.
Stop it, Ray.
Even if you are facing a bitter aspect of life...
Drugs and murder are foul, without any excuse...
Deserve a red card, for a loser.
True, I was a cheater.
A bad player, and I lost the game.
I must be ejected...
For both my late wife...
And for a fan like you.
Ray then admitted to the crime and
was taken away by the Osaka Police.
The goalkeeper who wore #8...
Disappeared from the field, forever.
Heiji's Home
Did that boy really say he wasn't
going to watch the match in Nagai?
Yeah.
He was looking forward to it so much...
Could it be because Ray won't be there?
No way, there will be many other
famous soccer players there.
What if he was going to see him?
Well...
But Conan-kun's face right now is just like Shinichi's.
Everytime Shinichi would lose something he
liked, he'd just have this sad, child-like face.
Could Conan-kun be... They both like soccer...
What're you doing over there?
You deserve to be hit.
You suck.
What'd you say?
Watch me.
It looks like he's in a better mood.
Those two look just like brothers, don't they?
You think so?