Reasoning and hints are interlinked,
Allowing us to understand a case's mystery.
Today's case is on the Shinkansen,
where a very complex case unfolds!
Recognizing that single truth,
a child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
The Bullet Train Transport Case
(Part One)
New Osaka Station
There's nothing here...
Hey, hey...
It looks like your phone's ringing.
I wonder who it is.
An unknown caller?
Oh, could this be a love call from Kudo-kun?
Hurry, hurry! This could be about a date!
No way, it's an unknown caller.
Come on.
Stop wasting time! Here!
Now the princess can speak with her knight.
Hello?
Shinichi...
Shinichi?
Shinichi!
What took you so long?
Hey, Uncle...
What're you reading?
Nothing...
Bull's-eye!
Because it's been so long since you called.
But, how'd you know I was in Osaka?
Oh, Hattori called me.
Hattori-kun called you, did he?
It was just by chance!
How was the "K3" event, anyway?
Let's see... Which do I want...
Let's see... Where are the newspapers...
You have a paper over here!
What is it, Ran?
Well, Shinichi...
Have you heard about that case?
Yeah, I saw it on the news.
The Ray Curtis case, right?
I still can't believe it, though.
Kudo?
Actually...
Actually, Shinichi...
I asked him to...
Oh, you mean...
The uniform you had Ray sign?
Yeah.
You didn't have to do that.
But...
Despite everything that's happened...
No matter what, Ray will always be my hero on the field.
Thanks, Ran.
Well, I have some things I need to look into.
Um... Shinichi?
Don't you want to know?
Just exactly how he feels about you?
What is it?
Shinichi...
Do it, Ran-chan! Do it!
I wanted to know...
Attention customers:
The train arriving at #26 is leaving
from Nozomi for Tokyo at 2:56 PM.
That was the train, right?
Yeah...
I'll call you later then.
All right...
Hey, wait!
Hey you, this conversation isn't over yet!
That jerk...
He hung up.
Don't blame him.
He's always busy.
What're you doing, Kazuha?
Oh, Heiji.
What's got you so worked up?
Kudo-kun just called...
But he hung up just when it got good.
It wasn't like that...
Really now?
That's right!
We're dealing with love!
Kudo must've hung up to avoid the attention.
That guy always does that, huh?
Don't even.
Don't hint around at it, Ran-chan!
Tell him! Tell him!
Don't dodge it!
Throw him a fastball, Ran-chan!
What is it, Ran?
Are you planning to play baseball?
Y-Yeah, kind of...
No, being too direct is bad.
I know that, but it still...
No, hold on...
Mouri-san!?
Officer Takagi?
You're transporting a suspect!?
Don't go around yelling it, Mouri-san.
Well, regardless...
What'd this guy do?
His name's Ogura Senzou, a drug dealer.
We tried to get a warrant to arrest
him in Tokyo, but he got away.
Ogura Senzou
We then staked out an old house
of his in Kansai and got him.
I remember seeing this guy in the paper.
They had something about him being
transferred from Osaka to Tokyo.
I think they found a large cache
of drugs at his Tokyo residence.
Yeah.
We're aiming big here.
We hope he'll give up their ring leader.
Right?
Coffee.
Get me some coffee.
I guess it's fine.
Would you go get him some, Takagi-kun?
Yes.
But, make sure it's cold.
He could try to do something with hot coffee.
I wonder if I have change...
Here.
These are tickets to Sana Kazumi's magic and illusion show!
Are you going?
Y-Yeah, on my next day off.
Oh, Takagi-kun? You're interested in magic?
Oh, no.
Actually...
Yumi-san from the traffic department had
an extra ticket and asked me to go.
Yumi, huh?
I told her I wasn't interested, though.
Hey, Takagi-kun.
Yes?
Go, have fun.
Let me know if you can figure out his tricks, all right?
So, so, how about this...
You tell Miwako that I asked you on a date.
If her expression changes, you can get her.
If her expression changes...
Telling a girl like Miwako how you feel directly is bad.
You have to hint around with her first.
Got it?
What're you waiting on, Takagi-kun?
Oh, right!
Well, we're going back to our seats.
Bye.
As I figured, it didn't work.
It's no use...
We're almost to Mt. Fuji.
Huh?
I think something happened.
What could it be?
Maybe it's a case?
All right, I'll go check that bathroom.
You stay here, Takagi-kun.
Sure.
Excuse me, please make way.
It's in here.
"This is a bomb. Do not touch!"
How long's it been here?
The last passenger found it, so I'd say it hasn't been too long.
I see.
Thanks.
There are a lot of people gathered back there.
I guess something really did happen.
Maybe...
I'm gonna go take a look.
Hey!
You can't, it's dangerous.
Stay still!
Hey, Officer.
Can I go to the bathroom?
I've been trying to hold it, but I'm at my limit.
Well, let's wait until Sato-san gets back.
I told you, I'm at my limit.
Or maybe...
I should just go right here.
Of course not.
Jeez...
I apologize.
Takagi-san, where are you going?
The bathroom, the bathroom.
How is it, Officer?
Do you hear anything?
Yeah, a ticking noise.
First, we'll need to evacuate the passengers.
Have the driver...
It's only a prank.
The one who found the bag...
Can you give me a statement?
Hey, are you done yet?
Don't rush me, Officer.
It's kinda hard to do this with one hand.
Jeez...
Oh yeah, Officer...
Your partner mentioned me naming
who I got the drugs from earlier.
It's too bad...
That I'll soon be a bird that can't sing, isn't it?
Hey!
What!?
Where'd you get this knife!?
Anyway, I've gotta get Sato-san!
It's no use!
We must be in a tunnel!
Damn it!
I'll be right back!
Don't move!
What'd you say?
He stabbed himself in the bathroom?
Yeah, he had a knife when I opened the door.
Why!?
How'd he even get a knife!?
I-I don't know, I just opened the door and saw blood...
Anyway, come look for yourself, Sato-san!
Got it!
Sato-san, he's in here!
In here!
He pulled it out!?
He pulled the knife out!
We're too late.
He's already dead.
N-No way...
It doesn't...
This entire scene...
Doesn't add up.
What!?
The suspect committed suicide while
you were transferring him!?
You idiots!
What the hell were you all thinking!?
Oh, well, you see...
After I took him to the bathroom,
I heard him scream.
After I opened the door, I saw he was already
covered in blood with the knife in hand.
To get to Sato-san, I handcuffed him
to the safety bar to keep him in there.
I decided it was best to make sure he stayed in the bathroom.
Even if he did have a fatal injury, having a dangerous and
armed suspect around the passengers would've been bad.
And so, by the time Sato-san and I got back,
he had already removed the knife and died from blood loss.
Regardless, I'll send some back-up
to meet you at the arrival platform.
Don't let anyone near the scene until then!
Yes, sir!
Should a suspect kill himself in the custody
of an officer, things would get messy.
A minor suspension,
a major suspension,
or a loss of benefits.
No...
Worst case scenario, they'd get discharged.
How pitiful.
Sato-san, you can't say anything!
He was your responsibility, too!
Yes? Takagi here!
Takagi-kun, it's me, Yumi.
Yumi-san?
So, how'd it go?
You know, the ticket of love scheme.
How'd it go? Did Miwako blush? Did she not react?
Come on, tell me!
You can trust me!
Now is not the time for that!
Call me at a better time!
I guess it didn't work.
Yumi?
What'd she say?
Oh, nothing for you to worry about!
But now you've gotta wonder how he got the knife.
Yeah, he isn't some magician.
While being transported and guarded by two
officers, he couldn't possibly conceal a knife.
He's not a magician...
He's a samurai!
Look at the way the knife is pointing.
For it to fall this way...
He'd have had to hold it up like this, right?
That means this guy had to pull the knife out...
Like a samurai.
Like this, right?
Hey, Takagi-kun...
Which way was he holding the knife
when he stabbed himself?
Of course it was backwards. It's easier that way.
So, he stabbed himself holding it backwards,
and switched when he pulled it out.
How weird...
Then maybe someone else pulled out the knife.
Is that really possible?
The blood is weird, too.
Look, the blood on the knife and around
most of his body is solid like jelly.
But the blood on his hand is liquid...
One's solid and one's liquid, huh?
Maybe the blood on his hand isn't really blood.
But it's definitely the same color...
Heparin.
H-Heparin?
Right.
If blood were mixed with Heparin...
You mean it would...
Yeah.
After so long, blood hardens and becomes difficult to carry.
But, if you were to mix it with heparin and put it in a bag...
You could smuggle the blood paste onto the train.
Blood paste?
You mean...
That's right.
If someone were to hide the blood paste and knife
in the bathroom beforehand, this would be...
A murder case.