Reasoning and hints are interlinked,
Allowing us to understand a case's mystery.
The Shinkansen is nearing Tokyo!
Can the two officers solve it in time?
Recognizing that single truth,
a child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
While traveling on the Shinkansen from Osaka,
We ran into Officers Sato and Takagi,
who were transporting a criminal.
Later, a bomb was found on the train...
Which Officer Sato went to investigate.
At that time, while she was in the bathroom with it,
Officer Takagi had to take the criminal to the bathroom.
And then, he apparently committed suicide.
But...
The Bullet Train Transport Case
(Part Two)
Right...
That means this must be a murder case.
A-A murder case!?
Right.
First, the criminal put the "bomb" in the
rear bathroom with the message on it...
To get me back there.
At an angle where Takagi-kun couldn't see it,
he gave the signal to go to the bathroom.
Then, he went to the toilet and faked his
suicide with the fake blood and the knife.
Next, they probably knew Takagi-kun would
handcuff him down and go get his partner.
And then, the criminal, after seeing Takagi-kun leave,
came out from his hiding spot behind the sink curtain...
And killed him.
B-But, the knife looked like it was deep inside him.
I didn't see a knife in here when I first
opened the door for him either.
It must have been a fake knife, with a removable blade.
It was probably hidden...
Back here, behind the baby changing board.
If you put the blood, knife, and a memo here,
you could hide it back here where no one would look.
A memo?
The memo was just a lie to fool the victim.
It probably said, "I planted the bomb. Use
the blood and the knife to fake a suicide.
"After the officer leaves you, I'll cut off the
handcuffs and free you during the explosion."
But why didn't you just call Officer Sato with your cell phone?
Oh, well, we were going through a long tunnel then...
Yeah, that was directed in the memo.
The memo probably said:
"When the train enters Shintanna Tunnel, do it."
But he was fooled.
But with this much blood loss, some of
it should've gotten on the criminal.
You're right.
Someone would've noticed someone covered in blood.
Was there anyone suspicious near your seat, Ran-chan?
Right, I started watching the aisle
after Officer Takagi came out...
But Officer Takagi was the only one I noticed.
All things considered, the criminal must've come
from the back and went to the 13th row.
It's gonna be tough finding this guy.
What the...
Something else is on his hand aside from the fake blood.
What is this?
I see, the murderer used that...
I thought I told you to watch him!
But I just can't figure out how the criminal told him
to go to the bathroom with Takagi-kun there...
Hey, Takagi-kun...
Yes?
When I went to the bathroom,
did anyone do anything suspicious?
Well, not really...
Only two or three people passed by us after you left.
Do you remember their faces?
No, I barely noticed them.
But I remember!
There were three that came by at that time.
There were two men with newspapers,
and one that had a newspaper and coffee.
Then, you could identify them?
In the bathroom...
There was a murder?
Why do we have to talk to you police officers then?
Oh, no...
We just think that one of you three may have sent the
victim a signal telling him to go to the bathroom...
I get it.
Do you mind telling us why you all went by our seats?
Iwakuni Taturo
Passenger (47)
I was four rows behind you.
There was so much commotion going on
that I couldn't hear my horse racing.
I had to move to the front.
I see.
And what about you?
Oh, I bought a can of coffee from the vending
machine and was on my way back to my seat.
Tokuyama Norio
Passenger (51)
And then, I heard people saying there
was a bomb in the bathroom.
I had no idea someone had been killed.
What about you?
Akashi Akira
Passenger (29)
I heard about the bomb and decided to switch seats, too.
I believe Akashi-san and Iwakuni-san were
both holding newspapers at the time?
Yeah.
I had one.
This guy was reading one at his seat, right?
Yeah, I was...
Well then, would you three go get your newspapers?
Oh, and, Tokuyama-san, don't forget your coffee.
You three got on at the New Osaka Station
and bought your newspapers there?
Iwakuni-san had "Horse Racing 7"...
Tokuyama-san had "The Daily Morning Press" and a coffee...
Akashi-san had "Nichiuri Sports"...
None of them have "bathroom" written on them.
Besides, there has to be a hole...
The same goes for this coffee.
How could you say "Go to the bathroom" with this?
Wait...
This is actually...
What!? He stabbed himself in the bathroom?
Doesn't that mean it's a suicide?
Yeah, but it's fake because when
I came back with my partner...
The knife had been pulled out and was in a weird position.
Then, isn't it likely he used two hands and
stood up since it wouldn't come out?
This guy is right!
You can't know how it would fall if he stood up!
Are you all suspecting us over so little!?
Ah, no...
Besides, once we get to Tokyo, you can't keep me.
Same here!
Me, too.
Hey, Uncle?
What?
Do you remember what you bought at New Osaka Station?
Yeah.
Let's see...
"Horse Racing 7", "Nichiuri Sports", and a can of coffee.
Oh, and two packs of cigarettes.
What about it?
Nothing.
As I thought...
The criminal is the one who made that comment.
I know...
How you got him to come to the bathroom...
How you killed him...
I know everything...
Including the weak point you overlooked.
Suicide, suicide! The guy killed himself!
Since this isn't a murder, we aren't needed.
Well...
Well then, that's that.
Thank you for riding.
We are now arriving at Tokyo.
Seeya.
I have things I must attend to.
W-Wait...
We're already in enough trouble
for letting the victim get killed.
If his murderer gets away...
It'll get much worse.
Especially Takagi, who was with him at the time.
He won't get off easy.
N-No way...
But don't worry!
There's always a job down at my agency.
I need an assistant.
Mouri-san?
As much as I'd like to, Takagi-kun...
I can't bring you on as an assistant.
I'll have to see your best work as an
officer before I can consider that.
Like, let's start with you getting
the murderer right behind you.
How about it?
You mean, you've...
Figured out who the criminal is?
We'll begin at how the criminal conveyed the message,
"Go to the bathroom" without Takagi noticing.
Here are the items the three suspects had...
Newspapers and the coffee.
Don't you see it, Takagi-kun?
Right there is a message telling him to go to the bathroom.
W-Where?
Where does it say that?
You don't see it?
Bathroom... initials...
The initials of "Water Closet", "W.C.", are used everywhere.
Something else also uses those initials...
Takagi-kun!
Could it be...
The World Cup!
Right.
When the criminal went by carrying his newspaper,
he pointed to "World Cup" on his paper in
order to silently say: "Go to the bathroom."
Isn't that right...
The one who had the sports newspaper...
Akashi Akira-san?
Don't joke around!
Having a sports newspaper doesn't make me a criminal!
That's true...
It's hard to immediately think of "W.C."
by just seeing "World Cup", isn't it?
That's another reason Akashi-san put
the bomb in that back bathroom.
With that bathroom incident just happening, the
word "bathroom" was already in his head.
And, by pointing to "World Cup" on the paper, you could
take advantage of the timing and make him go there.
It's likely that he bought tickets at the same time Takagi did, and then waited around until the three of you got on board.
This way, he had time to plan the murder...
S-Stop that.
What're you doing?
Oh, I'm sorry!
I thought you were really asleep.
Hey, hey...
I've heard about it before, but this is my
first time seeing "Sleeping Kogoro".
"Sleeping Kogoro"?
That famous detective?
I don't care you're "Sleeping"...
Are you sure? You have no proof that this was a murder.
This is a murder.
The direction of the knife is too unusual otherwise.
As I said earlier, he must've stood up and used
both hands because it wouldn't come out.
Why would you have to stand up to take
the knife out with both hands?
Are you an idiot?
He couldn't use his left hand unless he stood up.
Right, his left hand was handcuffed to the safety bar
at the time, so he couldn't do it without standing up.
But isn't that strange...
How would you know that without visiting the crime scene?
Just an assumption!
You said the guy stabbed himself and
then the officer left to get his partner.
I assumed that he handcuffed him to the safety bar.
Oh, but how'd you know he was wearing handcuffs?
When I passed by this officer,
That guy had a cloth over his hands!
Then, how'd you know the murdered man was him?
That's the word going around...
Anyway, if you plan on making me
your lead suspect, get some proof!
Were my fingerprints on the knife?
Is there any blood on me?
Of course there's no blood on you.
You had him hold the newspaper...
And stabbed him through it.
The proof is what has been left on his right hand.
The newspaper left an imprint on his hand.
I see, that means the blood would splatter on the newspaper.
What're you saying?
Look at my newspaper!
There's no blood or holes in it!
That's why you bought two, right?
What!?
That's why you bought two copies of "Nichiuri Sports".
Right, Conan?
See? It's the same as your newspaper!
Those guys seen me before, I didn't have two newspapers!
Ah-le-le...
There's something weird about this paper.
Look at this newspaper that Uncle Kogoro bought...
And then look at your newspaper.
They look the same, but the words are different.
It's true!
Dad's paper says: "World Cup Hero Arrested",
while the other says: "World Cup Hero Questioned".
The ones at the station and the stores are different.
Unlike the newspapers at stores, the ones
sold at stations have a later deadline.
That gives them time to change them if need be.
Since his arrest was such big news, they had to change it.
Then, Akashi-san bought this newspaper at...
This is what probably happened.
He got this one to lure the victim.
And then, he bought another one at the station while he
was waiting to prevent the blood from getting on him.
He bought two was just in case someone noticed he
didn't have a paper after the crime was committed.
That's not it!
I bought another because of the headline!
Then, could you show me?
The other Nichiuri Sports paper.
That's...
You probably ripped it up and
flushed it down the toilet, right?
If we check the toilet's tank, we'll find it.
Damn it!
Enough!
Now, admit it!
Amazing, Officer Takagi!
I guess we're straight...
Oh, nothing...
Soon after Inspector Megure and the
others arrived at the station in Tokyo,
The criminal was arrested...
And taken to the station.
The reason he did it was to make
sure the drug route stayed secret.
But, unfortunately for him, the Police found
one of the dealers and shut down their route.
Somehow, it saved Officers Sato and Takagi's jobs...
And Officer Takagi was saved from
becoming Uncle's assistant.
And then:
A pay cut, a pay cut!
A pay cut for three months!
That's not fair.
You know, this pay cut will be on your record forever.
I know...
Well, don't worry!
If you ever get fired, you can always get married.
I don't need marriage...
I'm here to preserve and protect the city.
But the problem is Takagi-kun.
If he doesn't get going, he'll be a
lowly first-grade investigator forever.
Oh, by the way, Yumi...
Do you like Takagi-kun?
What's with that reaction?
Since I'm older than you, I need to know this kind of stuff.
I guess so...
So? Do you...
Like him?
Don't tell me you're in love!
Not at all...
That's what I thought.
He was bumbling around about how he got a ticket from you.
Well, stop fooling around with Takagi.
You should hurry and find a real man.
She fell for it...
Miwako fell for it...
She fell for my love ticket plan!
All right! I should call the other one who got their wage cut.
This'll cheer him up!
You should hurry and find a real man.
Fine!
Why am I helping them out so much?
It's so stupid.
Thanks for coming by to give your statements.
No...
Hey, don't be so down.
You'll bounce back sometime.
Hey, Takagi, straighten up!
S-S-Straight—!?
We've got that case on 4th! Let's hurry!
Yes, ma'am!
Officer Sato seems cheerful.
Didn't she get the same pay cut as Takagi?
Maybe something good happened.