Even fate can be used
as a hint for reasoning...
Seeing through the
most mysterious cases!
Genta's the lead actor today!
He might not be all that reliable as a friend,
but we're all following him!
He sees the single truth
for what it is,
and looks like a kid
but has the mind of an adult!
His name?
Detective Conan!
Teitan Elementary School
Let's eat!
Okay, everybody, dig in!
I don't want to see any picky eaters!
Yes, ma'am!
Oh, geez.
A teenage boy eating
with grade-school kids.
It's so pathetic...
Personally,
I'm enjoying the experience.
Growing up in the States, everybody
helped themselves at the school cafeteria,
and I usually ended up
eating alone.
It's intriguing how Japanese schools
foster a sense of community.
Sure, this was fun
the first time around...
Hey, Mitsuhiko-kun,
you left your carrots again!
Uh, I'm just saving
them for last!
Yeah, yeah.
There's always somebody who picks out
the vegetables he doesn't like.
And there's always a dumb guy who brags
about being the fastest eater in class.
Of course, in this class,
it's always...
Hooray! I'm number one!
He beat Genta?
Kobayashi-sensei,
I'm not feeling too well.
Can I go down
to the nurse's office?
Genta's Misfortune
It's gotta be serious!
Genta-kun left most
of his lunch!
Maybe he's on a diet.
No way!
You know him and food!
Come to think of it, Genta-kun
hasn't played with us for a couple of days...
Yeah. He's been going
straight home after school.
Maybe an upperclassman
is bullying him...
Come on! Genta's not the kind
of guy who'd get bullied.
And even if he was,
he'd be safer sticking with us, right?
Maybe it's a problem
with his family.
Maybe someone in
his family is gravely ill,
or his parents
are fighting.
Well, we can't do anything
about death or divorce.
N-No...
That's not it, children!
S-Sensei...
His parents are fine!
They're still happily running their liquor store!
I was worried, so I dropped by
Genta-kun's house yesterday to check.
But it sounds like Genta-kun
is afraid of something.
His parents told me he was shivering
inside his futon the moment he got home...
What is he scared of?
He wouldn't tell me.
I kept getting, "It's nothing",
no matter how many times I asked.
But he might
tell his friends!
Could you tell me
if he opens up to you?
Um... Sure...
Bye-bye!
Hold it, Genta!
What are you doing
behind our backs?
Are you practicing
to become a ninja?
I see! You skipped lunch
to slim down for ninjutsu!
Y-Yeah, that's it!
I saw this cool ninja flick
the other day and...
Then why were you shivering
under the covers at home?
Maybe you had a nightmare about
being attacked by a bloody samurai,
and you're training to
fight your imaginary enemy.
It wasn't a nightmare!
I really did...
You did?
Really what?
I-I... The truth is...
M-My life is in danger!
A hitman's out to get me!
H-Hitman?
Knock it off, Genta-kun!
Why would a hitman want
to kill an elementary school kid?
Right... Unless it was me or you.
Hey...
I knew it was dumb
to tell you guys.
Hey, wait!
Genta-kun,
tell us the whole story!
I promise I won't laugh!
I was walking through that
tunnel under the train tracks,
when I heard these
footsteps behind me.
I couldn't see
anything in the dark,
but when I stopped, he'd stop,
and when I ran, he ran.
It was probably just the echo of your
footsteps against the tunnel wall.
That's not all!
After that, somebody pushed me
down the stairs on the overpass,
and yesterday a motorbike
ran a red light and almost hit me...
That was just coincidence!
It was not!
And that guy...
That guy...
A big bolt...
That was dangerous.
Where could it
have fallen from?
Look out!
I-It's from that
department store sign.
The bolt just happened
to rust out, that's all.
You're just having a bad day!
Genta-kun, maybe you should go to a shrine
and have them do a purifying ceremony...
No... This was more
than just luck.
Look.
The cord on this neon sign
was cut with a sharp object.
Someone deliberately cut it before
loosening the bolt, to drop the sign.
If that's true, maybe it was just a crazy guy
attacking anybody who passed by...
No. I think there
was a specific target.
Look at this!
Isn't this the Kamen Yaiba capsule machine
Genta's always drooling over?
T-Then he really is...
Yeah. Looks like Genta's life
really is in danger.
There's no doubt about it.
You'd better tell us
everything, Genta.
Why are you a target?
You saw the serial snatcher?!
The crook who's been snatching bags
from old people and unsuspecting women?
Did you tell the police?
Yeah... About a week later.
I didn't see the wanted
posters until then.
They asked where I'd seen
the guy on the posters,
and by that time I'd forgotten
where I saw the guy.
But then I saw a guy
who saw the snatcher with me!
Saw him with you?
Five days ago, the snatcher
attacked a woman by my house,
and I dropped by
the crime scene.
That's when I saw
him in the crowd...
The blond guy who was near me
when I saw the snatcher!
Well? What did you do?
I grabbed him by the hand
and took him to the nearest cop!
But the guy said he didn't
remember me or the snatcher...
Are you sure
he was the same guy?
Yeah. When I saw the snatcher,
I think that guy was sitting near me,
so he must've
seen the snatcher too...
You think?
Well, I was really sleepy then...
But I swear that
blond guy was nearby!
And the snatcher?
I think he was there too.
Or maybe he wasn't...
A place where you'd get
sleepy after sitting down...
A movie theater...
Or inside a train...
From the look of things, the blond guy is probably
working with the person targeting Kojima-kun.
Geez. Why didn't you tell
the police you were in danger?
I... I got a phone call...
"If you say anything about me, you're dead!
And your friends and family too!"
So that's why you didn't
tell anybody until now.
Yeah.
This is going
from bad to worse.
If he knows your phone number,
he must know where you live.
Yeah. If we went
to the police,
the snatcher might think
Genta remembered something,
and there's no telling
what he'd do.
He might even be spying
on us this very minute.
And?
Don't you remember anything
that might help us look for the snatcher?
I already told the cops,
but he was smoking a cigarette with his left hand.
Then the snatcher
is left-handed!
And he was wearing
a weird T-shirt.
It was black with
a skull and numbers.
That one! That one!
It was just like that one!
Hey, you!
Are you the snatcher
who's after Genta-kun?
What?
No. He doesn't look
like the guy I saw.
Who are you guys?
And the snatcher's T-shirt
didn't say "1999".
It said "202"!
Hey, do you remember
where you got that T-shirt?
Huh? Sure.
A shop by the train station
called Bones.
Thanks.
Let's go check it out.
That's right!
The skull shirt is an original from our shop!
We've put out a lot of versions,
but I don't remember one that said "202".
What other versions are there?
"1999", "HELP", "ESCAPE"...
Lots of dangerous-sounding words.
You remember back in 1999,
when everyone was talking about
end-of-the-millennium prophecies?
That's why we
did a 1999 shirt!
Do you remember any suspicious-looking
people buying those T-shirts?
Dunno. It's been a long time,
and I don't really remember
all our customers' faces.
Well, that didn't go anywhere.
If Genta-kun could at least remember
where he saw the snatcher...
We could try movie theaters
and trains!
No. You can't smoke
in those places.
What about a restaurant?
That's it! You must've gotten sleepy
from eating too much!
But that guy
wasn't eating anything.
I was watching him
the whole time,
and I just remember him reading
a newspaper and smoking a cigarette...
How come you can remember all that,
but not where you were?
Beats me!
But that's strange.
Didn't he get annoyed at you
for staring at him for so long?
Did he?
No, our eyes never met...
I see.
So that's where they were...
The skull T-shirt
with the number 202...
The left hand...
And a place where your eyes
would never meet,
and you wouldn't attract attention
for staring at someone.
I've got it, Genta.
The very place
you saw the snatcher!
Hey, Genta...
The optician's, right?
Huh?
That's where you
saw the snatcher!
You said he didn't get upset
even though you were staring at him.
Um, yeah...
He didn't see you staring at him...
because he'd taken his glasses off
to have them fixed!
B-But, Conan...
I've never been
to an optician's.
No, that's got to be it!
After all,
it'd also have...
No.
You've got it all wrong!
Huh? Seriously?
I thought I'd cracked it.
And you call yourself
the modern-day Holmes.
Now, now.
Even a genius makes mistakes.
Don't feel down!
Well, so long.
Call me if you remember anything else.
Sure!
But where could it be?
The place Genta-kun saw the snatcher?
A place where you can stare at somebody
without getting in trouble, and also get sleepy...
Maybe it's school!
Genta-kun always falls asleep there!
If the snatcher was at our school,
we'd have seen him too!
I see...
Hey! Hold on a sec!
Oh, for crying out loud.
You never stop eating!
You're going to put on weight again!
Who cares?
I like to snack!
You got ice cream on your face,
Genta-kun.
What's the matter?
Did you remember something?
N-No, forget it...
Be careful on your way home!
Later!
Three chicken and four liver, please.
Coming right up!
I'm getting hungry...
Didn't you just have
some ice cream?
French food!
Show some self-control!
You're almost home!
Red... White... Blue...
What's wrong?
That's the French flag.
Hey, Ayumi...
Have you seen the colors
red, white and blue anywhere else?
Hmm...
Conan-kun's always wearing a red bowtie,
white shirt and blue jacket...
I-Is he the snatcher?
Yeah, right.
Would Conan do something like that?
I don't know why, but the colors
red, white and blue keep spinning in my head...
Bye, Genta-kun!
Don't forget
to go straight home!
Yeah...
If you get any fatter,
even the piggies will laugh at you!
Shut up!
Damn it.
Stupid Ayumi,
calling me fat.
I'm not that fat, am I?
I remember!
It was back there!
The seventh floor of
the building above the station...
The elevator...
Ah, stop! Hold that elevator!
Wait for me!
Which floor, little boy?
The s-seventh floor...
Hey, kid...
Y-You're that blond... guy...
Sorry about forgetting you before.
I remembered where it was!
Where you and me saw the snatcher!
Keep it down!
He could be
listening in on us.
Then you remember too?
Yeah, I just remembered.
Let's talk it over
before we go to the cops,
and make sure we've got
our stories straight.
Somewhere safe
from other people...
Like a restroom...
I'm sure of it!
I-It's him!
What?
I-I think the name he wrote
in our schedule book was Someda...
Huh? Who the hell are you?
If you don't knock off
the accusations, I'll...
Left-handed...
A T-shirt with a skull
and the number 202...
No wonder the police couldn't
pin down the snatcher's identity.
Genta was looking at your
reflection in a mirror!
Y-You're the kids from before!
Indeed.
And you never got angry at Kojima-kun
for staring at you...
because he was watching you
in the mirror.
The "202" he saw written
on your T-shirt...
was actually "SOS"!
And the left hand
was really your right hand!
A place where Genta would go that has
a mirror in front of the customers,
and where he could get sleepy...
It was the barber shop, right?
Genta didn't realize you and
the snatcher were the same person
because you had your hair
bleached while he was napping.
A guy with a black hair and glasses
changed into a blond guy without glasses,
and Genta didn't see your clothes
because they were covered with a smock.
He misremembered you
as two different people.
What're you talking about,
you little brat?
You've got no proof.
There's an eyewitness
standing right behind you!
The barber who
dyed your hair!
You've been lucky until now.
As it happens,
the barber doesn't watch TV,
and the police haven't posted
your picture in his neighborhood yet.
You dyed your hair black with coloring
that could be washed out.
I bet you thought
no one would recognize you.
But the police got the snatcher's fingerprints
off the last bag he tried to snatch.
If those prints match yours,
you can't talk your way out.
S-So what was this kid
doing back in this neighborhood?
Luring you here,
that's what!
We had him get ice cream on his face
that looked like shaving cream...
and stare at the French flag, which is
red, white and blue like a barber pole!
Then he stared
at his reflection...
like he was looking
in a barber's mirror!
We knew all along
that you were following us,
so we convinced Kojima-kun
to play dumb—no difficult task—
and lure you into a trap.
You kids think
you can mess with me?!
W-What're you doing,
you old broad?!
You're pretty dumb, huh?
You really think I'd walk all over town
just to lure you here alone?
What?
That's right...
Look around you.
While Genta bought us some time,
we made a phone call.
This place is
swarming with cops!
That's how the
snatcher got arrested,
and the case closed.
I couldn't believe the words
coming out of your mouth!
Are you really a grade-schooler,
Conan-kun?
I-It was nothing!
Just imitating
the detectives on TV!
No way...
A huge victory for the Detective Boys!
Hooray!
But you're so lazy, Genta-kun!
I can't believe you totally fell asleep
while the snatcher was having his hair dyed!
The barber said he didn't wake me up
because I looked so peaceful.
I guess they say sleep
is good for growing kids...
I'm glad you were right
and the criminal wasn't really left-handed.
Well, I was pretty sure it wasn't him,
since he'd target me before Kojima-kun,
but it did shake me...
H-Hey, you don't mean...
You don't know?
Then here's another factoid for your files.
Gin is left-handed.
What?!
T-This is...!
I'm sure he wanted to see
what was inside this attaché case.
See, the key
is still in the hole.
It's a curse.
Next Conan:
The Fake Kogoro Mouri
(Part 1)
Next Conan's Hint: Cellular phone
Look forward to the next episode!
Next time...
How could the great Kogoro Mouri—
Who are you?