Matsuhashi Miki
Even fate serves as a hint to deductions...
Allowing us to clearly see through the most mysterious cases.
The fake Kogorou has finally taken the stage!
This tough case surprises even the real deal!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Something's just not right
nani wo motometeru no
uso ni narete yuku kyou mo fake your eyes
Original Creator
Aoyama Gosho
「Meitantei Conan」
Serialized in Shogakukan's
「Weekly Shounen Sunday」
The start of century
Planning
Suwa Michihiko
(Yomiuri TV)
tashika na mono nakute
hitori ja nakenai yowasa hate myself
shinjiteru itami hikikae ni
kono mune umetsukushite
Character Design
Sudou Masatomo
Art Director
Shibutani Yukihiro
ima utsutte iru
futari ga eranda michi kuru
Camera Director
Ogawa Takahisa
Sound Director
Kobayashi Katsuyoshi
I think it's only my destiny
Music
Ono Katsuo
hateshinai yami no mukou ni
Opening Theme
Vocals
Lyrics
Composition
Arrangement
Matsuhashi Miki
Asakoshi Satomi
Majima Kazunobu
Shimizu Toshiya
dare mo shiru koto no nai ashita ga aru
Video Editor
Okada Terumitsu
Story Editor
Iioka Junichi
Color Design
Hiraide Mayumi
Production Lead
Kobayashi Hiroaki
oh yeah, You're going nowhere, It's only destiny
Planning Support
Tsuzuki Shinichirou
Okuyama Toyohiko
Asai Mitome
Suzuki Tsubasa
ari no mama ni susunde
ima kanjite iru you're in my heart
General Director
Kodama Kenji
Director
Yamamoto Yasuichirou
Chief Producers
Suwa Michihiko
(Yomiuri TV)
Yoshioka Masahito
(Tokyo Movie)
you're in my heart
Presented By
Yomiuri TV
Tokyo Movie
So thrilled to see you here, Great Detective!
Thank you for coming such a long way to our hotel.
My, I didn't realize it was you.
Onda Yoshirou (58)
Aoiya Inn Owner
Since you did tell me over the phone that
three of you would be coming tonight.
I closed my last case quickly and
have arrived earlier than expected.
Regardless, what about that thing?
This is the attaché case we talked about.
Of course, I haven't looked inside during these five years.
In fact, it has a lock on it, so even if I wanted to...
That's fine.
I'll manage something for the key.
Wait...
Can't you open it here?
Fear not.
I shall share the truth with you as
soon as I have pierced this mystery.
Me, Mouri Kogorou.
MOURI KOGOROU'S IMPOSTER
(PART ONE)
The air is so fresh!
Humans are best suited for nature, after all!
Geez, you didn't have to purposely get off the
taxi early just to take a walk in this forest!
So what?
The inn we're headed to is at the end of this forest, and
we have plenty of time before our appointment, right?
But I wanted to get there in advance
to hang around and take a bath!
Besides that, why don't you take off those sunglasses?
It gives a bad impression.
Idiot!
A mosquito bite above the eyelid is not something
to be seen from the genius Mouri Kogorou!
Besides, it gives me a cool look if some fan
girls are waiting all excited for me at the inn.
Not cool.
Who put this stone here!?
Oh, this is...
It's a Jizo statue.
It must've fallen on the ground by accident.
Let's put it back in place.
No, don't do it!
If you raise up that Jizo, you'll be cursed!
Isn't this the famous detective Mouri
Kogorou-san I almost arrested last time?
Look, you...
It's the incompetent detective from Gunma Prefecture...
What are you doing at a place like this?
I have some business to do at the Aoiya Inn over there.
Oh, could you be referring to the
unidentified body with the red jacket?
Well, yeah...
I'm also heading to the Aoiya Inn for that case.
The body was found in this Kashiragami Forest.
Kashiragami is the jinx god
responsible for headaches.
It's said that when people worrying
their heads enter this forest...
They'll be enchanted by Kashiragami
and be unable to return.
As such, this place is famous for suicides.
Famous for suicides?
Maedaore Jizo literally means
Front Fallen Buddhist Statue
Yeah.
The statue you were about to raise is the
"Maedaore Jizo" that calms the spirits.
It's said that, when you raise it up, you also
wake the evil spirits that bring disaster.
That's why it's been in this fallen
position since a long while ago.
Now that we're heading to the same
place, why don't you ride in my car?
No, thank you, my daughter said
she wanted to walk in the forest.
But, your daughter is already inside...
Geez...
So the body was found by an Aoiya Inn employee?
Yeah.
He discovered it while going into the
forest to pick up wild vegetables, but...
There's something strange about this body.
What do you mean by "strange"?
The body was carrying a car key,
but there was no driver's license.
He also had cigarettes on him,
but no lighters or matches.
And despite him having died in
summer, he was wearing a sweater.
How do you know he died in the summer?
There were some things in the victim's bag.
There was a pack of milk and some red bean bread with
expiration dates from exactly four years ago on July 12.
We also found a receipt for those items from a nearby
convenience store in the wallet, so there's no mistake.
But, due to the shock of the body falling on the ground,
the milk and red bean bread were totally smashed.
Fall?
There was a rope around his neck with the other
edge of the rope being tied to a broken branch.
The branch probably broke after he hung himself.
Which means it looks exactly like a suicide.
Yeah, so I thought I could get information on those
strange points from the employee that found the body.
That's why I came out here again.
Mouri-san, what brings you here?
Well, the owner of the inn said he met
with the man wearing the red jacket.
When did that happen?
If I recall, he said it was around October five years ago.
The story went that a man in a red jacket suddenly
entered the inn, found the owner, and said to him:
"I will give you 100,000 yen if you keep this
attaché case and envelope safe for me."
"I'll come retrieve it in one year even if I die!"
Like that.
An attaché case and an envelope?
Yeah.
He also said, "Give me back the attaché case if I'm the
one that comes, and the envelope if it's anybody else."
Well, we can't say for sure that the man in the red
jacket is the one whose body was found in the forest.
But that man made it clear by saying, "Don't forget my
red jacket and long hair," so they're probably the same.
And it seems he didn't come
back to retrieve it after all.
Now that you mention it, the body
is one of a man with long hair...
So, maybe it's like this:
This man entrusted it to the inn owner five years ago
while saying, "I'll come retrieve it even if I die."
Then, when he returned one summer later...
And was traveling through the
forest, he committed suicide.
What a fool of a man!
He can't take it back if he's dead!
That's why the inn owner called
on me to solve the mystery!
That man paid the owner to keep it quiet from the
police, so that's why he stayed mum until now.
I see.
Say...
Did nobody come to claim that attaché case in the end?
No, a day after the red-jacketed man entrusted it to the
inn, another man claiming to be his proxy appeared.
A suspicious guy with a hat, sunglasses and a beard.
The owner hesitated a little but handed over the
envelope as instructed by the man in the red jacket.
And?
The guy opened the envelope and, upon seeing
the memo inside, tore it apart in anger...
And threw it in the garbage can in the lobby
and left the inn, never to be seen again.
What was written on this memo?
The inn's owner was also interested in it and tried
to put back together the pieces of the torn memo.
He was able to make out seven characters.
As if they were written with blood...
"I shall kill you with my curse."
That's why I told you to not come with me!
But, I...
Don't worry, if we ask the inn's owner to show us what's
inside the attaché case, Uncle can solve the mystery.
You're right.
Don't tell me that inside that attaché
case is that man's long hair!
Geez, you were too noisy!
Welcome!
Jinbo Masao (34)
Aoiya Inn Employee
Allow me to park your car.
Thank you.
Wow, this is quite a good inn!
Is it your first time coming?
You told us that you were coming
to question an employee again...
I asked him to come to the station last time.
Oh, Detective!
Ah, Urakawa-san.
He's the employee who found the body, Urakawa-san.
Well, I was really surprised at that time.
Urakawa Eiji (37)
Aoiya Inn Employee
I couldn't imagine that someone may have died there.
Even though it had turned into bones.
Were you alone when you found it?
Yes.
Say, are you the only one who
goes out for wild vegetables?
No.
Jinbo-kun, the inn's owner Onda-san,
and I all three alternate with each other.
But I'm the most prone to finding
corpses among the three of us.
I could tell by the atmosphere that it was there.
Is that so?
Well, I can't help it because it's
generally my turn after the trip.
What do you mean?
We close this inn every year before summer
vacation in order to go on a company trip.
The entrance to the forest is
just in front of this inn, right?
As such...
When no one's looking, people with suicidal thoughts
like to grab their chances and come to the forest.
Well, if it's suicide, there's nothing I can do.
Huh?
That man with the sunglasses,
isn't he a police officer too?
No, he's...
Feared by all with something to hide, the Great Detective!
His name is...
You're the companion of Mouri Kogorou-sama, right?
No, that's not it—he's actually...
If it's about Mouri-san, he's already waiting in his room.
What!?
Mouri Kogorou is already at this inn!?
Yes, he came three hours ago.
Then, the attaché case is...
He took it to his room.
He's very nice and gave his autograph to every employee.
Please don't soil it.
I will place it in a frame and put it on display later.
Where is this man now?
Room number 209.
I'm going to scold him.
Wait, Ran.
Have you forgotten these kinds of
scenes from historical dramas?
There are lots of tasty scenes when the
imposter and true person come face to face.
Enduring the unendurable and tolerating the intolerable...
I shall wait until this guy begins
his absurd deduction show...
And then appear and reveal my great deduction
to an extent that will floor absolutely everyone!
What's this crazy talk now?
Detective Yamamura, please talk some sense into him!
That's a great idea!
Isn't it, isn't it?
Please make me a part of this plan!
I don't care anymore!
By the way, may I please have your names?
Our names?
Echigo Mitsuemon.
Let us say that this one is a plain, humble man.
Touché, samurai!
I care not if my room is the cheapest one.
Understood.
Sir, it seems that the young lady
forgot her cell phone in your car.
It's your daughter's, right?
Thy kindness is appreciated!
Thou shalt be blessed.
We shall now take our leave!
O my dear assistant, let us indulge
in a hot bath and some drinks!
Nay, good sir, on duty I am.
So he calls himself Echigo Mitsuemon...
Great going!
Keep it up and deal with the imposter so that
I can enjoy your deduction show tonight!
You just leave that to me!
Geez.
That guy hasn't started his deduction show yet?
That's why I told you we should've scolded him before.
This fake may have already fled.
No, it seems nobody left the inn.
It can't be helped—how about
I give him a little piece of me.
Are you there, imposter?
He's not answering.
What's this, it's all dark!
He's sleeping in a sulk because
he couldn't solve the mystery?
Damn you, wake up!
I, Mouri Kogorou-sama...
What?
This is...
Officer!
What is it?
It's unbelievable!
Detective Mouri just hanged himself in his room...
Anyway, hurry up, officer!
Mouri-san, what an unbearable sight you've become...
I couldn't very well see your face because of all my tears!
And why did you do such a foolish thing?
To think that the Sleeping
Kogorou will sleep for eternity...
This is too much for a joke!
Hey, what are you grumbling about?
I hadn't let anyone else enter the scene, so...
You'd better hurry and call your fellow
Gunma prefecture police and forensics.
It's a ghost!
An imposter?
Is that true?
Yes, that man is just a fake who
borrowed Mouri-san's name.
And this is the one and only, the
famous detective Mouri Kogorou.
As I thought, I was sure I'd already
seen your face somewhere!
My deepest apologies, I'd never seen your face before.
But, why did this person impersonate you?
I'm sure he wanted to see what
was inside this attaché case.
See, the key is still in the hole.
That's true.
Let's have a look inside.
This is...
A sports newspaper.
Akagimaru...
Didn't this Akagimaru seriously injure himself
four yours ago and have to retire from sumo?
Look carefully: this newspaper is dated
in the September of five years ago.
That reminds me, he was rejoiced by fans for his
first championship in eighteen years at the time.
But why was it inside?
There's something coming from
the bottom of the newspaper.
See, something like black strings.
Geez, it's just black hair tucked between the pages.
But isn't this hair a little bit long?
Don't tell me that this is the curse of the long-haired
man with the red jacket who died four years ago!
If people can get killed by curses, police
officers and detectives may as well retire.
So it probably went like this:
Two men made a bet five years ago.
They were betting on a sports athlete
and had to guess his status next year.
These two men are the man we found
with the long hair and the red jacket...
And the mustached man who usurped
my name and hanged himself.
Also, their target athlete was Akagimaru, who
was in promising condition five years ago.
The man with the long hair told
the mustached man the following:
"I've put my answer inside."
"I'm giving this to the inn's owner and the key to
you, so let's check it one year later together."
Then, who's the man that claimed to
be the long-haired man's proxy?
The man with the hat and beard.
He was likely the mustached man.
About the torn memo that had
"I shall kill you with my curse" on it...
It was meant to be a threat as in, "If you
cheat by coming in advance, I'll kill you."
But inside the attaché case was only a sports
newspaper, so where is the answer?
There was something else inside—the hair!
When a sumo wrestler cuts his hair, it means...
I see, retirement!
Exactly.
But before Akagimaru seriously injured
himself, he won a championship in Nagoya...
And got promoted to the rank of Oozeki.
Well, they surely bet a large amount.
The long-haired man who thought
the wrestler would retire...
Committed suicide as he was headed
to this inn through the forest.
But why did the other one commit suicide too?
Because the long-haired man's
prediction turned out to be true.
After learning the long-haired
man had died four years ago...
He wanted to find out the contents of
the attaché case to conclude the bet.
He happened to hear that the inn's owner
asked me to take on this mystery.
He then impersonated me and was able to
confirm what was inside the attaché case, but...
The man's prediction had hit the mark.
So he felt guilty for driving the long-haired man to
suicide by demanding a pay-up four years ago...
And tied his belt around his neck,
ending his own life as a result.
As expected of Mouri-san!
A great deduction beyond all expectations!
No, no, just doing what I do best!
You're definitely right.
There's no reason for it to be a curse
in this scientific era we're living in.
It's a curse.
Look carefully.
These strings of hair have different lengths, and
there's some permed hair and brown hair too.
Beyond that, it also feels a little bit wet.
Don't you think hair that's been
wet for five years is cursed?
No, that's not the long-haired man's curse!
That's the grudge of a hippie guy
with long, brown hair and a perm!
Hey...
Say, now that I think of it, Ran-neechan's
hair was also wet a few minutes ago.
But of course, I was taking a bath!
Geez, don't say strange things.
A bath?
But you told us that you couldn't enter the bath last night.
At that time there was a "cleaning" sign on the door.
Speaking of being wet, the tatami at the entrance
to this room was also wet when we came.
Yeah...
Do you clean the bathroom every evening in this inn?
No, the bath cleaning is supposed to be during the night.
Which means someone from this inn put a "cleaning"
sign on the women's bath in order to keep people out.
They also took a load of long hair from the
drain there and brought it back to this room.
Then, they inserted the hair in the attaché case's sports
newspaper to mimic the long-haired man's curse.
It's possible they did this in order
to disturb the investigation.
Then, don't tell me this is a...
Yes, a murder case.
Most likely, the reason the tatami is wet...
Revolves around the culprit hurrying
to the bath with their socks on.
When they returned to this
room, their feet remained wet.
Moreover...
Our culprit who knew where the "cleaning" sign was
stored is likely to be among the inn employees!
Yes, this is a murder case.
The culprit is likely someone linked to the long-
haired man who committed suicide four years ago.
What's bugging me is the strangeness of this body.
He had car keys on him but no driver's license...
And he had cigarettes but without a lighter or matches.
What's more, he was wearing a sweater in the summer.
Perhaps, this long-haired man didn't commit
suicide either, but was also murdered.
Somebody did something to
this body to achieve their goal.
MOURI KOGOROU'S IMPOSTER
(PART TWO)
Then, don't tell me this is...
Probably a murder case.
Moreover, our culprit who knew where the "cleaning" sign
was stored is likely to be among the inn employees!
Jinbo Masao (34)
Aoiya Inn Employee
Onda Yoshirou (58)
Aoiya Inn Owner
Urakawa Eiji (37)
Aoiya Inn Employee
The culprit is likely someone linked to the long-
haired man who committed suicide four years ago.
Perhaps, this long-haired man didn't commit
suicide either, but was also murdered.
Somebody did something to this
body to achieve their goal.
Who did it, and what for?
Yamamura-san, I found a cell phone.
It was in this coat that belonged to the victim.
There's one number in its memory.
Should we try to call it?
Yes, of course.
Oh, Tatsuo?
What happened with that get rich
quick scheme you told me about?
Let me know if it went well.
Oh, and...
There was a call from your apartment's landlord.
Said something like, "If you don't pay your rent,
I won't renew your contract and will kick you out."
Hey, are you listening, Tatsuo?
Uhm, well...
Sorry, I have a customer.
Call me back later.
He hung up.
He mentioned a "get rich quick" scheme.
And also that if he doesn't pay his
rent, his contract won't be renewed.
Renew?
But now that we know that the victim's name
is Mori Tatsuo, we're making progress.
How do you know his surname is "Mori"?
He only mentioned "Tatsuo".
Look, there is a sticker with his name on the phone.
He's not a kid, why would he need a sticker?
Sorry to be a kid, but I also have a sticker on my phone.
You're still a kid, so that's understandable.
What's that?
Hold on, is the culprit...
Say, Mr. Officer...
Can you give me more details on the
long-haired man's belongings?
Haven't you heard?
He had milk, red bean bread, and
a receipt on him four years ago!
I mean...
How about you take a look at the pictures if you want?
Pictures?
Since I came to this inn to ask questions
about that, I brought them with me.
This is the crushed carton of milk, the front and the back.
These are the crushed red bean
bread and a pack of cigarettes.
And finally, the convenience store's
receipt that was in the wallet.
The receipt is from July 10th, which is when
you were on your company trip, right?
Yes...
I see, so that's how it was.
I finally understand the culprit's objective.
Say, Mr. Officer...
What?
Was there another body found in Kashiragami Forest
at the end of the company's trip four years ago?
Yeah, one was found.
It was near the Maedaore Jizo.
Was the person who discovered it...
How do you know that!?
As I thought, that person is the culprit.
And this sports newspaper is likely
a map pointing to a hidden place.
All I need now is the evidence.
If my deductions are correct, it may still be there.
On that shogi board and this desk,
there should be the culprit's prints...
There it is!
This is it!
You can't just come in as you like!
I was asked by Uncle Kogorou to take a
good look at this shogi board and desk.
By Detective Mouri?
He also asked me to look at the light.
Light?
He said it might be the clinching
move to corner the culprit.
Anyway, according to the estimated time of death, the
crime happened today between 4:00 and 5:00 PM.
At that time, the culprit put up the "cleaning'' sign...
Gathered long hair from the bath, and
brought it back to the crime scene.
They tried to interfere with the investigation by
making it look like the long-haired man's curse.
If we suppose that only the employees of this inn
know where the "cleaning" sign is stored...
We can narrow down our list of suspects!
Please gather all the employees as soon as possible.
I need to inquire as to their where-
abouts this evening one by one.
Hold on a second, officer.
Shouldn't the employees who never heard about or
never saw the man who died four years ago be cleared?
But you were all here when this man gave the attaché
case to Onda-san five years ago, weren't you?
No, he handed it to me in the
room he was staying in, and...
I hired this guy here four years ago in the spring.
Also, I only told my employees I called Detective Mouri
to investigate the attaché case we'd kept for five years.
I never told them it belonged to that long-haired man.
I see.
So the only one who knew about both the
attaché case and the long-haired man...
Is you, the owner, and no one else, no?
I'm not the culprit!
If I were the culprit, I would've opened
it without safekeeping it for five years!
And don't you find it strange?
That such an important case would only
contain an old sports newspaper.
I bet the culprit already stole something wrapped
in the newspaper and fled somewhere far away.
It would've changed the circumstances if the
newspaper contained a special meaning.
You're right about that.
Say...
What is this "Mae 5"?
See, next to the winner Akagimaru's name...
"Mae 5" is written on it.
It means number five in the Maegashira rank.
At the time, Akagimaru was in the East corner,
meaning he was an East Maegashira Number 5.
Maegashira?
Is it somehow related to Kashiragami Forest?
Idiot, no way they're related.
Then, what about Maedaore Jizo?
No, no, not at all!
Maegashira is the rank below Yokozuna, Oozeki,
Sekiwake and Komusubi in the top sumo divisions...
And "number five" means he placed fifth in that rank.
Then, Akagimaru wasn't that strong
but still won the tournament...
He must've been very careful.
Careful?
Because look here, Akagimaru only fell into a hole once!
Doesn't this black circle mean that a
sumo wrestler fell into a trap hole?
And there's "thrust down" written under the black circle.
That's not a hole, but a symbol for "black star".
It means Akagimaru lost the bout
on the eighth day by that move.
Oh, so it wasn't that he walked
eight steps and fell in a hole?
At any rate, gather your employees and
cooperate as I carry out the questioning.
Of course, everyone will be
questioned without exception!
So there was nobody that can confirm
your actions this evening, right?
Right.
Understood.
Next person!
Hold on a minute, is this going to take long?
I have to clean the cafeteria...
And I have to prepare tomorrow's breakfast.
Can't you let us leave earlier?
No, not possible!
Looks like I've got everyone down for now...
But there are almost none of you with
a solid alibi between 4:00 to 5:00 PM.
That much is obvious.
My employees are constantly on the move.
And I haven't hired any strange person that'd
observe everyone while looking at the time.
I guess so...
Detective Yamamura!
Have you seen Conan-kun and my dad?
I haven't.
Yes, Yamamura speaking.
Mouri-san?
Yes...
Yes.
Roger that.
Uhm, what did my father say?
Well, he...
As he was gathering information from
the people living around here...
He was mistaken for a suspicious person by
an officer and is now at the police station.
He said Conan-kun was with him.
At any rate, I'm going to that station to free them.
Please wait in your room.
Excuse me, what about us?
You and your employees can take a rest.
I'll be conducting a thorough
questioning at a later time.
Bye.
Stones?
No way!
Who...
Are you looking for this?
Jinbo-san...
Or would you prefer...
I called you what you really are: the culprit behind
the 100 million yen blackmail case?
What?
I found out everything when I checked the
serial numbers on this 100 million yen.
Five years ago, two men threatened a
confectionery company and stole 100 million yen.
You are one of those two men.
And the other one is the long-haired man who
entrusted the attaché case to the inn's owner.
The sports newspaper inside indicates the
place where the stolen money was hidden.
Akagimaru, who is shown in the newspaper
heading, was an East Maegashira-5 at that time.
Maegashira is a keyword pointing to the
Maedaore Jizo here in Kashiragami Forest.
It means that, starting from the fallen
statue, you walk five steps east.
Then, in accordance with Akagimaru's record chart,
you turn right and advance another eight steps.
And if you dig a hole on that point, you
will find the urn with all the money.
Isn't that right, Mouri-san?
The reason why the long-haired man entrusted the
attaché case with the newspaper to the inn's owner...
Was because he sensed something was wrong.
He sensed that you wanted to kill him
in order to keep all the money yourself.
Well, the long-haired man could've
easily guessed your intent.
Given that the long-haired man was
likely the one who carried the money...
And yet you decided that he should meet
you in this forest that's famous for suicides.
As proof, the long-haired man also
entrusted the memo with the attaché case.
In case you killed him and came alone to
retrieve it, he could deliver the vile message.
As expected, you killed him in this
forest and made it look like a suicide.
Then you rushed all exultant to the inn...
With your face hidden with a hat,
a pair of glasses, and a beard.
However, the only thing you found was the
memo with "I shall kill you with my curse".
But because you couldn't give up on the money, you
decided to get employed and search the inn's vicinity.
Days and months passed, and the
long-haired man's corpse was discovered.
After you heard the inn's owner decided to call me in to
investigate the attaché case he was given five years ago...
You quickly hired someone to impersonate me...
And had him retrieve the attaché case before
I came in order to obtain the contents.
But there was no money inside,
only an old sports newspaper.
The imposter who was promised a
big compensation became upset.
He probably said, "If I don't get the money, I'll tell
everything to the real Mouri Kogorou that's on his way."
With no other choice, you killed the man
and decided to let me handle the mystery.
Regardless, the fact you came here to search
for the money is the definitive proof.
Now, come to the station.
What are you saying?
I came here merely because an inspiration
hit me when I saw the newspaper.
I thought I could help with
the investigation by searching.
Why, you...
And also, the long-haired man
died four years ago on July 10.
I was on the company retreat that day.
No, the long-haired man wasn't killed
during the summer four years ago.
It was five years ago in autumn.
Just after he entrusted the attaché case to the owner.
You put the milk, bread, cigarettes, and convenience
store receipt inside his backpack afterwards.
You did it to manipulate the estimated
time of death and create your alibi.
Items like the milk and receipt belonged to another suicide
body you'd found after the company trip four years ago.
That's why the long-haired man was wearing a sweater, and
had cigarettes on him despite lacking a lighter or matches.
You took away the long-haired man's
driver's license because his was expiring.
If he had been carrying a driver's license
that hadn't been renewed for a year...
The alibi trick would have been exposed.
In addition, the reason you inserted
strains of long hair in the newspaper...
Was to lead us to believe that someone related to
the long-haired man killed the fake Mouri-san.
As such, with the alibi provided by the receipt, you would
allow yourself to be removed from the suspect list.
But no one fell for your trick!
Then, why not tell me how can you be so sure
that I planted the milk and receipt afterward?
Couldn't it be that the long-haired man
brought those in the first place?
No...
That's because of...
The straw.
There was no straw on the pack of milk.
This is proof that someone refilled a
discarded milk carton with milk...
Sealed the opening with glue and
put it inside the man's backpack.
No one in their right mind would put an
opened milk carton in their backpack.
That's it, that's it, exactly!
And did you guys see it?
Did you see me murdering this long-haired man?
Indeed, we were too late to establish that
you were the murderer for that case.
But we do possess proof that you
killed the man who impersonated me.
What?
To take someone on your shoulder
and hang them from a high place...
You have to get them near the ceiling.
To accomplish that, you climbed atop the
shogi board and the desk in the room.
Of course, you likely removed
your socks in order to not slip.
The forensics officer reported having
found someone's footprints on them.
As such, what will happen should we
compare those prints with your own feet?
You're right, I did climb on it.
But it was to change the light bulb in the room.
I'm not lying...
If you check the light, you should find my fingerprints.
Yes, I was quite surprised that there
were a lot of your fingerprints...
And all under a thick layer of dust.
You likely left those fingerprints quite some time ago.
Despite that, your footprints were still on the desk.
It could only mean you are the culprit.
After all, no inn would leave their desks unwiped long
enough to have thick dust collected on the light.
Jinbo-san, knock it off already.
There's no use trying to cheat time.
How...
How did you find out I was the culprit?
Your actions gave it away.
It was when you came to give back my
daughter's cell phone in the lobby.
Even though you'd never seen Detective
Yamamura who was next to me...
You gave it to me without hesitation.
Saying, "It's your daughter's, right?"
What about it?
When I saw the sticker saying "Ran
Mouri" on the cell phone, I knew...
Yes, you already knew the minute you saw me...
That I was the genuine Mouri Kogorou.
Kuraki Mai
Always give my love
Always give my love to you
son janai!? ima kara demo
iin janai!? yareru koto
Don't you think so!? From now on, let's... Isn't it great!? Do what we can
omotta doori ni yatte miyou
kimi to deau made
With the way I feel now, I know I had nothing before you
nani mo nakatta keredo me wo tojite omou
But when I close my eyes and think...
issho ni ikiru basho ga aru kara
I know there's a place where we can live together
always ai wo mune ni yuuki wo dashite
There will always be love in my heart, I've built up courage
tatoe sore ga dame da to shite mo ne
To say something is impossible...
No sore dake ga jibun janai
No, that's not like me
Yes kazamuki ga kawatta ima tobitatou
Yes, the wind has changed, let's start now
Always give my love
Always give my love to you
I was very impressed, Mouri-san!
The Sleeping Kogorou's great deduction!
All I remember was that brat Conan
pestering me to go in the forest...
But I was surprised!
Since you suddenly called me and said, "I'm starting
my deduction show, so hurry to the forest!"
Say, I just remembered an employee
at the inn called me "Echigo-san".
I wonder...
Don't worry about that.
Excuse us!
Is Aoiya Inn this way?
We rushed here as soon as we heard
Mouri Kogorou-san was coming.
Riiiight?
We got off the bus but lost our way...
Right?
You don't have to go to the inn because he's already...
Oh, that's perfect timing!
We were just thinking about heading back to the inn.
Hop in.
Really?
Don't worry, come in, come in.
Thank you!
Uncle, what's your name?
My name?
Tooyama Kingorou, a mere adventurer.
You'll never learn, old man.