Even fate serves as a hint to deductions...
Allowing us to clearly see through the most mysterious cases.
The fake Kogorou has finally taken the stage!
This tough case surprises even the real deal!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
So thrilled to see you here, Great Detective!
Thank you for coming such a long way to our hotel.
My, I didn't realize it was you.
Onda Yoshirou (58)
Aoiya Inn Owner
Since you did tell me over the phone that
three of you would be coming tonight.
I closed my last case quickly and
have arrived earlier than expected.
Regardless, what about that thing?
This is the attaché case we talked about.
Of course, I haven't looked inside during these five years.
In fact, it has a lock on it, so even if I wanted to...
That's fine.
I'll manage something for the key.
Wait...
Can't you open it here?
Fear not.
I shall share the truth with you as
soon as I have pierced this mystery.
Me, Mouri Kogorou.
MOURI KOGOROU'S IMPOSTER
(PART ONE)
The air is so fresh!
Humans are best suited for nature, after all!
Geez, you didn't have to purposely get off the
taxi early just to take a walk in this forest!
So what?
The inn we're headed to is at the end of this forest, and
we have plenty of time before our appointment, right?
But I wanted to get there in advance
to hang around and take a bath!
Besides that, why don't you take off those sunglasses?
It gives a bad impression.
Idiot!
A mosquito bite above the eyelid is not something
to be seen from the genius Mouri Kogorou!
Besides, it gives me a cool look if some fan
girls are waiting all excited for me at the inn.
Not cool.
Who put this stone here!?
Oh, this is...
It's a Jizo statue.
It must've fallen on the ground by accident.
Let's put it back in place.
No, don't do it!
If you raise up that Jizo, you'll be cursed!
Isn't this the famous detective Mouri
Kogorou-san I almost arrested last time?
Look, you...
It's the incompetent detective from Gunma Prefecture...
What are you doing at a place like this?
I have some business to do at the Aoiya Inn over there.
Oh, could you be referring to the
unidentified body with the red jacket?
Well, yeah...
I'm also heading to the Aoiya Inn for that case.
The body was found in this Kashiragami Forest.
Kashiragami is the jinx god
responsible for headaches.
It's said that when people worrying
their heads enter this forest...
They'll be enchanted by Kashiragami
and be unable to return.
As such, this place is famous for suicides.
Famous for suicides?
Maedaore Jizo literally means
Front Fallen Buddhist Statue
Yeah.
The statue you were about to raise is the
"Maedaore Jizo" that calms the spirits.
It's said that, when you raise it up, you also
wake the evil spirits that bring disaster.
That's why it's been in this fallen
position since a long while ago.
Now that we're heading to the same
place, why don't you ride in my car?
No, thank you, my daughter said
she wanted to walk in the forest.
But, your daughter is already inside...
Geez...
So the body was found by an Aoiya Inn employee?
Yeah.
He discovered it while going into the
forest to pick up wild vegetables, but...
There's something strange about this body.
What do you mean by "strange"?
The body was carrying a car key,
but there was no driver's license.
He also had cigarettes on him,
but no lighters or matches.
And despite him having died in
summer, he was wearing a sweater.
How do you know he died in the summer?
There were some things in the victim's bag.
There was a pack of milk and some red bean bread with
expiration dates from exactly four years ago on July 12.
We also found a receipt for those items from a nearby
convenience store in the wallet, so there's no mistake.
But, due to the shock of the body falling on the ground,
the milk and red bean bread were totally smashed.
Fall?
There was a rope around his neck with the other
edge of the rope being tied to a broken branch.
The branch probably broke after he hung himself.
Which means it looks exactly like a suicide.
Yeah, so I thought I could get information on those
strange points from the employee that found the body.
That's why I came out here again.
Mouri-san, what brings you here?
Well, the owner of the inn said he met
with the man wearing the red jacket.
When did that happen?
If I recall, he said it was around October five years ago.
The story went that a man in a red jacket suddenly
entered the inn, found the owner, and said to him:
"I will give you 100,000 yen if you keep this
attaché case and envelope safe for me."
"I'll come retrieve it in one year even if I die!"
Like that.
An attaché case and an envelope?
Yeah.
He also said, "Give me back the attaché case if I'm the
one that comes, and the envelope if it's anybody else."
Well, we can't say for sure that the man in the red
jacket is the one whose body was found in the forest.
But that man made it clear by saying, "Don't forget my
red jacket and long hair," so they're probably the same.
And it seems he didn't come
back to retrieve it after all.
Now that you mention it, the body
is one of a man with long hair...
So, maybe it's like this:
This man entrusted it to the inn owner five years ago
while saying, "I'll come retrieve it even if I die."
Then, when he returned one summer later...
And was traveling through the
forest, he committed suicide.
What a fool of a man!
He can't take it back if he's dead!
That's why the inn owner called
on me to solve the mystery!
That man paid the owner to keep it quiet from the
police, so that's why he stayed mum until now.
I see.
Say...
Did nobody come to claim that attaché case in the end?
No, a day after the red-jacketed man entrusted it to the
inn, another man claiming to be his proxy appeared.
A suspicious guy with a hat, sunglasses and a beard.
The owner hesitated a little but handed over the
envelope as instructed by the man in the red jacket.
And?
The guy opened the envelope and, upon seeing
the memo inside, tore it apart in anger...
And threw it in the garbage can in the lobby
and left the inn, never to be seen again.
What was written on this memo?
The inn's owner was also interested in it and tried
to put back together the pieces of the torn memo.
He was able to make out seven characters.
As if they were written with blood...
"I shall kill you with my curse."
That's why I told you to not come with me!
But, I...
Don't worry, if we ask the inn's owner to show us what's
inside the attaché case, Uncle can solve the mystery.
You're right.
Don't tell me that inside that attaché
case is that man's long hair!
Geez, you were too noisy!
Welcome!
Jinbo Masao (34)
Aoiya Inn Employee
Allow me to park your car.
Thank you.
Wow, this is quite a good inn!
Is it your first time coming?
You told us that you were coming
to question an employee again...
I asked him to come to the station last time.
Oh, Detective!
Ah, Urakawa-san.
He's the employee who found the body, Urakawa-san.
Well, I was really surprised at that time.
Urakawa Eiji (37)
Aoiya Inn Employee
I couldn't imagine that someone may have died there.
Even though it had turned into bones.
Were you alone when you found it?
Yes.
Say, are you the only one who
goes out for wild vegetables?
No.
Jinbo-kun, the inn's owner Onda-san,
and I all three alternate with each other.
But I'm the most prone to finding
corpses among the three of us.
I could tell by the atmosphere that it was there.
Is that so?
Well, I can't help it because it's
generally my turn after the trip.
What do you mean?
We close this inn every year before summer
vacation in order to go on a company trip.
The entrance to the forest is
just in front of this inn, right?
As such...
When no one's looking, people with suicidal thoughts
like to grab their chances and come to the forest.
Well, if it's suicide, there's nothing I can do.
Huh?
That man with the sunglasses,
isn't he a police officer too?
No, he's...
Feared by all with something to hide, the Great Detective!
His name is...
You're the companion of Mouri Kogorou-sama, right?
No, that's not it—he's actually...
If it's about Mouri-san, he's already waiting in his room.
What!?
Mouri Kogorou is already at this inn!?
Yes, he came three hours ago.
Then, the attaché case is...
He took it to his room.
He's very nice and gave his autograph to every employee.
Please don't soil it.
I will place it in a frame and put it on display later.
Where is this man now?
Room number 209.
I'm going to scold him.
Wait, Ran.
Have you forgotten these kinds of
scenes from historical dramas?
There are lots of tasty scenes when the
imposter and true person come face to face.
Enduring the unendurable and tolerating the intolerable...
I shall wait until this guy begins
his absurd deduction show...
And then appear and reveal my great deduction
to an extent that will floor absolutely everyone!
What's this crazy talk now?
Detective Yamamura, please talk some sense into him!
That's a great idea!
Isn't it, isn't it?
Please make me a part of this plan!
I don't care anymore!
By the way, may I please have your names?
Our names?
Echigo Mitsuemon.
Let us say that this one is a plain, humble man.
Touché, samurai!
I care not if my room is the cheapest one.
Understood.
Sir, it seems that the young lady
forgot her cell phone in your car.
It's your daughter's, right?
Thy kindness is appreciated!
Thou shalt be blessed.
We shall now take our leave!
O my dear assistant, let us indulge
in a hot bath and some drinks!
Nay, good sir, on duty I am.
So he calls himself Echigo Mitsuemon...
Great going!
Keep it up and deal with the imposter so that
I can enjoy your deduction show tonight!
You just leave that to me!
Geez.
That guy hasn't started his deduction show yet?
That's why I told you we should've scolded him before.
This fake may have already fled.
No, it seems nobody left the inn.
It can't be helped—how about
I give him a little piece of me.
Are you there, imposter?
He's not answering.
What's this, it's all dark!
He's sleeping in a sulk because
he couldn't solve the mystery?
Damn you, wake up!
I, Mouri Kogorou-sama...
What?
This is...
Officer!
What is it?
It's unbelievable!
Detective Mouri just hanged himself in his room...
Anyway, hurry up, officer!
Mouri-san, what an unbearable sight you've become...
I couldn't very well see your face because of all my tears!
And why did you do such a foolish thing?
To think that the Sleeping
Kogorou will sleep for eternity...
This is too much for a joke!
Hey, what are you grumbling about?
I hadn't let anyone else enter the scene, so...
You'd better hurry and call your fellow
Gunma prefecture police and forensics.
It's a ghost!
An imposter?
Is that true?
Yes, that man is just a fake who
borrowed Mouri-san's name.
And this is the one and only, the
famous detective Mouri Kogorou.
As I thought, I was sure I'd already
seen your face somewhere!
My deepest apologies, I'd never seen your face before.
But, why did this person impersonate you?
I'm sure he wanted to see what
was inside this attaché case.
See, the key is still in the hole.
That's true.
Let's have a look inside.
This is...
A sports newspaper.
Akagimaru...
Didn't this Akagimaru seriously injure himself
four yours ago and have to retire from sumo?
Look carefully: this newspaper is dated
in the September of five years ago.
That reminds me, he was rejoiced by fans for his
first championship in eighteen years at the time.
But why was it inside?
There's something coming from
the bottom of the newspaper.
See, something like black strings.
Geez, it's just black hair tucked between the pages.
But isn't this hair a little bit long?
Don't tell me that this is the curse of the long-haired
man with the red jacket who died four years ago!
If people can get killed by curses, police
officers and detectives may as well retire.
So it probably went like this:
Two men made a bet five years ago.
They were betting on a sports athlete
and had to guess his status next year.
These two men are the man we found
with the long hair and the red jacket...
And the mustached man who usurped
my name and hanged himself.
Also, their target athlete was Akagimaru, who
was in promising condition five years ago.
The man with the long hair told
the mustached man the following:
"I've put my answer inside."
"I'm giving this to the inn's owner and the key to
you, so let's check it one year later together."
Then, who's the man that claimed to
be the long-haired man's proxy?
The man with the hat and beard.
He was likely the mustached man.
About the torn memo that had
"I shall kill you with my curse" on it...
It was meant to be a threat as in, "If you
cheat by coming in advance, I'll kill you."
But inside the attaché case was only a sports
newspaper, so where is the answer?
There was something else inside—the hair!
When a sumo wrestler cuts his hair, it means...
I see, retirement!
Exactly.
But before Akagimaru seriously injured
himself, he won a championship in Nagoya...
And got promoted to the rank of Oozeki.
Well, they surely bet a large amount.
The long-haired man who thought
the wrestler would retire...
Committed suicide as he was headed
to this inn through the forest.
But why did the other one commit suicide too?
Because the long-haired man's
prediction turned out to be true.
After learning the long-haired
man had died four years ago...
He wanted to find out the contents of
the attaché case to conclude the bet.
He happened to hear that the inn's owner
asked me to take on this mystery.
He then impersonated me and was able to
confirm what was inside the attaché case, but...
The man's prediction had hit the mark.
So he felt guilty for driving the long-haired man to
suicide by demanding a pay-up four years ago...
And tied his belt around his neck,
ending his own life as a result.
As expected of Mouri-san!
A great deduction beyond all expectations!
No, no, just doing what I do best!
You're definitely right.
There's no reason for it to be a curse
in this scientific era we're living in.
It's a curse.
Look carefully.
These strings of hair have different lengths, and
there's some permed hair and brown hair too.
Beyond that, it also feels a little bit wet.
Don't you think hair that's been
wet for five years is cursed?
No, that's not the long-haired man's curse!
That's the grudge of a hippie guy
with long, brown hair and a perm!
Hey...
Say, now that I think of it, Ran-neechan's
hair was also wet a few minutes ago.
But of course, I was taking a bath!
Geez, don't say strange things.
A bath?
But you told us that you couldn't enter the bath last night.
At that time there was a "cleaning" sign on the door.
Speaking of being wet, the tatami at the entrance
to this room was also wet when we came.
Yeah...
Do you clean the bathroom every evening in this inn?
No, the bath cleaning is supposed to be during the night.
Which means someone from this inn put a "cleaning"
sign on the women's bath in order to keep people out.
They also took a load of long hair from the
drain there and brought it back to this room.
Then, they inserted the hair in the attaché case's sports
newspaper to mimic the long-haired man's curse.
It's possible they did this in order
to disturb the investigation.
Then, don't tell me this is a...
Yes, a murder case.
Most likely, the reason the tatami is wet...
Revolves around the culprit hurrying
to the bath with their socks on.
When they returned to this
room, their feet remained wet.
Moreover...
Our culprit who knew where the "cleaning" sign was
stored is likely to be among the inn employees!
Yes, this is a murder case.
The culprit is likely someone linked to the long-
haired man who committed suicide four years ago.
What's bugging me is the strangeness of this body.
He had car keys on him but no driver's license...
And he had cigarettes but without a lighter or matches.
What's more, he was wearing a sweater in the summer.
Perhaps, this long-haired man didn't commit
suicide either, but was also murdered.
Somebody did something to
this body to achieve their goal.