Even fate serves as a hint to deductions...
Allowing us to clearly see through the most mysterious cases.
Conan, Kogoro and Officer Yamamura.
The briefcase is the link over time and space.
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
To answer a client's call to solve the mystery of the briefcase,
we headed to the Aoiya Ryokan inn with Detective Yamamura.
A man wearing a red jacket was found dead in the Toshin Forest.
Strangely, the man was wearing a sweater in the middle of summer.
Car keys and cigarettes were found on him,
but without his driver's license or matches.
The briefcase in question was entrusted to the innkeeper five years ago
by a long-haired man wearing a red jacket.
And...
the man who is posing to be Kogoro finally came to get it...
The case contained five-year-old sports newspaper and a bundle of long hair!
MOURI KOGOROU'S IMPOSTER
(PART TWO)
Then, don't tell me this is...
Probably a murder case.
Moreover, our culprit who knew where the "cleaning" sign
was stored is likely to be among the inn employees!
The culprit is likely someone linked to the long-
haired man who committed suicide four years ago.
Perhaps, this long-haired man didn't commit
suicide either, but was also murdered.
Somebody did something to this
body to achieve their goal.
Who did it, and what for?
Yamamura-san, I found a cell phone.
It was in this coat that belonged to the victim.
There's one number in its memory.
Should we try to call it?
Yes, of course.
Oh, Tatsuo?
What happened with that get rich
quick scheme you told me about?
Let me know if it went well.
Oh, and...
There was a call from your apartment's landlord.
Said something like, "If you don't pay your rent,
I won't renew your contract and will kick you out."
Hey, are you listening, Tatsuo?
Uhm, well...
Sorry, I have a customer.
Call me back later.
He hung up.
He mentioned a "get rich quick" scheme.
And also that if he doesn't pay his
rent, his contract won't be renewed.
Renew?
But now that we know that the victim's name
is Mori Tatsuo, we're making progress.
How do you know his surname is "Mori"?
He only mentioned "Tatsuo".
Look, there is a sticker with his name on the phone.
He's not a kid, why would he need a sticker?
Sorry to be a kid, but I also have a sticker on my phone.
You're still a kid, so that's understandable.
What's that?
Hold on, is the culprit...
Say, Mr. Officer...
Can you give me more details on the
long-haired man's belongings?
Haven't you heard?
He had milk, red bean bread, and
a receipt on him four years ago!
I mean...
How about you take a look at the pictures if you want?
Pictures?
Since I came to this inn to ask questions
about that, I brought them with me.
This is the crushed carton of milk, the front and the back.
These are the crushed red bean
bread and a pack of cigarettes.
And finally, the convenience store's
receipt that was in the wallet.
The receipt is from July 10th, which is when
you were on your company trip, right?
Yes...
I see, so that's how it was.
I finally understand the culprit's objective.
Say, Mr. Officer...
What?
Was there another body found in Kashiragami Forest
at the end of the company's trip four years ago?
Yeah, one was found.
It was near the Maedaore Jizo.
Was the person who discovered it...
How do you know that!?
As I thought, that person is the culprit.
And this sports newspaper is likely
a map pointing to a hidden place.
All I need now is the evidence.
If my deductions are correct, it may still be there.
On that shogi board and this desk,
there should be the culprit's prints...
There it is!
This is it!
You can't just come in as you like!
I was asked by Uncle Kogorou to take a
good look at this shogi board and desk.
By Detective Mouri?
He also asked me to look at the light.
Light?
He said it might be the clinching
move to corner the culprit.
Anyway, according to the estimated time of death, the
crime happened today between 4:00 and 5:00 PM.
At that time, the culprit put up the "cleaning" sign...
Gathered long hair from the bath, and
brought it back to the crime scene.
They tried to interfere with the investigation by
making it look like the long-haired man's curse.
If we suppose that only the employees of this inn
know where the "cleaning" sign is stored...
We can narrow down our list of suspects!
Please gather all the employees as soon as possible.
I need to inquire as to their where-
abouts this evening one by one.
Hold on a second, officer.
Shouldn't the employees who never heard about or
never saw the man who died four years ago be cleared?
But you were all here when this man gave the attaché
case to Onda-san five years ago, weren't you?
No, he handed it to me in the
room he was staying in, and...
I hired this guy here four years ago in the spring.
Also, I only told my employees I called Detective Mouri
to investigate the attaché case we'd kept for five years.
I never told them it belonged to that long-haired man.
I see.
So the only one who knew about both the
attaché case and the long-haired man...
Is you, the owner, and no one else, no?
I'm not the culprit!
If I were the culprit, I would've opened
it without safekeeping it for five years!
And don't you find it strange?
That such an important case would only
contain an old sports newspaper.
I bet the culprit already stole something wrapped
in the newspaper and fled somewhere far away.
It would've changed the circumstances if the
newspaper contained a special meaning.
You're right about that.
Say...
What is this "Mae 5"?
See, next to the winner Akagimaru's name...
"Mae 5" is written on it.
It means number five in the Maegashira rank.
At the time, Akagimaru was in the East corner,
meaning he was an East Maegashira Number 5.
Maegashira?
Is it somehow related to Kashiragami Forest?
Idiot, no way they're related.
Then, what about Maedaore Jizo?
No, no, not at all!
Maegashira is the rank below Yokozuna, Oozeki,
Sekiwake and Komusubi in the top sumo divisions...
And "number five" means he placed fifth in that rank.
Then, Akagimaru wasn't that strong
but still won the tournament...
He must've been very careful.
Careful?
Because look here, Akagimaru only fell into a hole once!
Doesn't this black circle mean that a
sumo wrestler fell into a trap hole?
And there's "thrust down" written under the black circle.
That's not a hole, but a symbol for "black star".
It means Akagimaru lost the bout
on the eighth day by that move.
Oh, so it wasn't that he walked
eight steps and fell in a hole?
At any rate, gather your employees and
cooperate as I carry out the questioning.
Of course, everyone will be
questioned without exception!
So there was nobody that can confirm
your actions this evening, right?
Right.
Understood.
Next person!
Hold on a minute, is this going to take long?
I have to clean the cafeteria...
And I have to prepare tomorrow's breakfast.
Can't you let us leave earlier?
No, not possible!
Looks like I've got everyone down for now...
But there are almost none of you with
a solid alibi between 4:00 to 5:00 PM.
That much is obvious.
My employees are constantly on the move.
And I haven't hired any strange person that'd
observe everyone while looking at the time.
I guess so...
Detective Yamamura!
Have you seen Conan-kun and my dad?
I haven't.
Yes, Yamamura speaking.
Mouri-san?
Yes...
Yes.
Roger that.
Uhm, what did my father say?
Well, he...
As he was gathering information from
the people living around here...
He was mistaken for a suspicious person by
an officer and is now at the police station.
He said Conan-kun was with him.
At any rate, I'm going to that station to free them.
Please wait in your room.
Excuse me, what about us?
You and your employees can take a rest.
I'll be conducting a thorough
questioning at a later time.
Bye.
Stones?
No way!
Who...
Are you looking for this?
Jinbo-san...
Or would you prefer...
I called you what you really are: the culprit behind
the 100 million yen blackmail case?
What?
I found out everything when I checked the
serial numbers on this 100 million yen.
Five years ago, two men threatened a
confectionery company and stole 100 million yen.
You are one of those two men.
And the other one is the long-haired man who
entrusted the attaché case to the inn's owner.
The sports newspaper inside indicates the
place where the stolen money was hidden.
Akagimaru, who is shown in the newspaper
heading, was an East Maegashira-5 at that time.
Maegashira is a keyword pointing to the
Maedaore Jizo here in Kashiragami Forest.
It means that, starting from the fallen
statue, you walk five steps east.
Then, in accordance with Akagimaru's record chart,
you turn right and advance another eight steps.
And if you dig a hole on that point, you
will find the urn with all the money.
Isn't that right, Mouri-san?
The reason why the long-haired man entrusted the
attaché case with the newspaper to the inn's owner...
Was because he sensed something was wrong.
He sensed that you wanted to kill him
in order to keep all the money yourself.
Well, the long-haired man could've
easily guessed your intent.
Given that the long-haired man was
likely the one who carried the money...
And yet you decided that he should meet
you in this forest that's famous for suicides.
As proof, the long-haired man also
entrusted the memo with the attaché case.
In case you killed him and came alone to
retrieve it, he could deliver the vile message.
As expected, you killed him in this
forest and made it look like a suicide.
Then you rushed all exultant to the inn...
With your face hidden with a hat,
a pair of glasses, and a beard.
However, the only thing you found was the
memo with "I shall kill you with my curse".
But because you couldn't give up on the money, you
decided to get employed and search the inn's vicinity.
Days and months passed, and the
long-haired man's corpse was discovered.
After you heard the inn's owner decided to call me in to
investigate the attaché case he was given five years ago...
You quickly hired someone to impersonate me...
And had him retrieve the attaché case before
I came in order to obtain the contents.
But there was no money inside,
only an old sports newspaper.
The imposter who was promised a
big compensation became upset.
He probably said, "If I don't get the money, I'll tell
everything to the real Mouri Kogorou that's on his way."
With no other choice, you killed the man
and decided to let me handle the mystery.
Regardless, the fact you came here to search
for the money is the definitive proof.
Now, come to the station.
What are you saying?
I came here merely because an inspiration
hit me when I saw the newspaper.
I thought I could help with
the investigation by searching.
Why, you...
And also, the long-haired man
died four years ago on July 10.
I was on the company retreat that day.
No, the long-haired man wasn't killed
during the summer four years ago.
It was five years ago in autumn.
Just after he entrusted the attaché case to the owner.
You put the milk, bread, cigarettes, and convenience
store receipt inside his backpack afterwards.
You did it to manipulate the estimated
time of death and create your alibi.
Items like the milk and receipt belonged to another suicide
body you'd found after the company trip four years ago.
That's why the long-haired man was wearing a sweater, and
had cigarettes on him despite lacking a lighter or matches.
You took away the long-haired man's
driver's license because his was expiring.
If he had been carrying a driver's license
that hadn't been renewed for a year...
The alibi trick would have been exposed.
In addition, the reason you inserted
strains of long hair in the newspaper...
Was to lead us to believe that someone related to
the long-haired man killed the fake Mouri-san.
As such, with the alibi provided by the receipt, you would
allow yourself to be removed from the suspect list.
But no one fell for your trick!
Then, why not tell me how can you be so sure
that I planted the milk and receipt afterward?
Couldn't it be that the long-haired man
brought those in the first place?
No...
That's because of...
The straw.
There was no straw on the pack of milk.
This is proof that someone refilled a
discarded milk carton with milk...
Sealed the opening with glue and
put it inside the man's backpack.
No one in their right mind would put an
opened milk carton in their backpack.
That's it, that's it, exactly!
And did you guys see it?
Did you see me murdering this long-haired man?
Indeed, we were too late to establish that
you were the murderer for that case.
But we do possess proof that you
killed the man who impersonated me.
What?
To take someone on your shoulder
and hang them from a high place...
You have to get them near the ceiling.
To accomplish that, you climbed atop the
shogi board and the desk in the room.
Of course, you likely removed
your socks in order to not slip.
The forensics officer reported having
found someone's footprints on them.
As such, what will happen should we
compare those prints with your own feet?
You're right, I did climb on it.
But it was to change the light bulb in the room.
I'm not lying...
If you check the light, you should find my fingerprints.
Yes, I was quite surprised that there
were a lot of your fingerprints...
And all under a thick layer of dust.
You likely left those fingerprints quite some time ago.
Despite that, your footprints were still on the desk.
It could only mean you are the culprit.
After all, no inn would leave their desks unwiped long
enough to have thick dust collected on the light.
Jinbo-san, knock it off already.
There's no use trying to cheat time.
How...
How did you find out I was the culprit?
Your actions gave it away.
It was when you came to give back my
daughter's cell phone in the lobby.
Even though you'd never seen Detective
Yamamura who was next to me...
You gave it to me without hesitation.
Saying, "It's your daughter's, right?"
What about it?
When I saw the sticker saying "Ran
Mouri" on the cell phone, I knew...
Yes, you already knew the minute you saw me...
That I was the genuine Mouri Kogorou.
I was very impressed, Mouri-san!
The Sleeping Kogorou's great deduction!
All I remember was that brat Conan
pestering me to go in the forest...
But I was surprised!
Since you suddenly called me and said, "I'm starting
my deduction show, so hurry to the forest!"
Say, I just remembered an employee
at the inn called me "Echigo-san".
I wonder...
Don't worry about that.
Excuse us!
Is Aoiya Inn this way?
We rushed here as soon as we heard
Mouri Kogorou-san was coming.
Riiiight?
We got off the bus but lost our way...
Right?
You don't have to go to the inn because he's already...
Oh, that's perfect timing!
We were just thinking about heading back to the inn.
Hop in.
Really?
Don't worry, come in, come in.
Thank you!
Uncle, what's your name?
My name?
Tooyama Kingorou, a mere adventurer.
You'll never learn, old man.