destiny
Song by Matsuhashi Miki
A hint to reasoning is to dream.
There's a mystery behind every case!
Two revolutions in a day, a unique house.
A surprising trick and surprising solution!
Seeking the one and only truth...
With the appearance of a child
and the intellect of an adult...
His name is... Detective Conan!
Something's just not right
nani o motometeru no
uso ni narete yuku kyou mo fake your eyes
The start of century
tashika na mono nakute
hitori ja nakenai yowasa hate myself
shinjiteru itami hikikae ni kono mune umetsukushite
ima utsutte iru futari ga eranda michi kuru
I think it's only my destiny
hateshinai yami no mukou ni
dare mo shiru koto no nai ashita ga aru
oh yeah. You're going nowhere. It's only destiny
ari no mama ni susunde
ima kanjite iru you're in my heart
you're in my heart
West Izu
The inspector insisted we try his car, so we borrowed it.
What good luck we have, huh?
With Uncle involved, it may have actually gone like...
So, because of that, may I please
use it, Inspector Megure?
Can I beg you?
I suppose not, huh...
Inspector Megure!
Thank you, Inspector Megure-dono!
I'm fairly certain you pressured him
into letting you borrow the car.
And you call us lucky...
Even with all this rain.
We can't see Mount Fuji at all.
What bad luck.
Really?
Back on the subject, Dad, how much
longer until we get to that house?
Not sure, but I think we'll be there shortly.
Isn't that it?
THE GUNSHOT AT THE SUNFLOWER ESTATE
It took us a while to arrive since
we couldn't see the place.
Yeah, and the rain has also stopped.
Mouri-san?
Yes.
Kanazawa Ryuuichirou (32)
Architect
We were waiting for you to arrive, Mouri-san.
I always read about your famous
deductions in the newspaper.
Me too, I've read about you in the newspapers.
You're that gifted architect Kanazawa
Ryuuichirou-san...
I heard they gave you a new prize not too long ago.
Let me think, what was the name?
The Shanghai modern art museum
international competition.
Sensei, are these your guests?
I present to you, Hayashida and Amamori.
Hayashida Makoto (26)
Kanazawa Architecture Office Employee
Hi, I'm Hayashida Makoto.
Amamori Masaya (25)
Kanazawa Architecture Office Employee
And I'm Amamori Masaya.
Just listen and be surprised, this is Mouri Kogoro-san!
Mouri Kogoro?
Uhm...
I am the famous detective, Mouri Kogoro.
You've gotta stop referring to
yourself as a famous detective.
Stalker?
Yes.
I've been getting these pictures every
week since three months ago.
And it seems you appear in all of them.
First, we have to uncover this person's particulars;
do you have any idea who it might be?
No, not at all.
Come on, think hard.
The voice of experience tells me that...
There is a high probability that the stalker
is someone you know very well.
Like for example...
7:00 PM
The delivery is tomorrow?
The place is a hotel in Shanghai.
Shanghai?
Are you all going?
No, our job is to stand guard over the house.
Isn't that right, Amamori?
Well, yes.
Oh, by the way, Ran-san, what
do you think of this building?
This building has a strange aura.
That's right, that's right.
The master designed it himself.
It's quite pretty, don't you think?
Huh?
It felt like the structure itself was moving...
Yes, it's true that it has moved.
The second floor does a revolution
over the course of 12 hours.
That's why we call it the sunflower estate.
How interesting!
But why did the master build a moving house?
Well...
I'm not sure.
I'll ask the master next time.
It has no meaning.
Kanazawa Mitsuko (38)
Kanazawa's Wife
His architecture is random.
He's just lying to everyone.
7:10 PM
I am sure everything will be solved
around the time you get back.
I hope that will be the case.
Are you Mouri-san?
Yes.
Mouri-san, if possible, could you do me a favor?
This man!
Can you do an investigation
on the honesty of this man?
If the remuneration is greatly split,
I may have half the compensation.
Mitsuko, can't you stop?
Will you be able to take the plane
tomorrow being drunk like that?
Can't you go to the ceremony alone?
Or are you going there with your stalker?
I told you to stop that.
It seems it's you who has to drop this act.
You give the impression you're really
worried about that stalker, but...
In reality, you just got what you deserve, right?
From a woman you dumped before or whatever.
Hayashida-kun!
Yes, sir?
All you've been eating till now is meat, right?
Yes, but this meat...
Meat, meat... with those unbalanced eating habits...
You'll never be able to taste originality.
7:20 PM
We're in the middle of a conversation here.
Where are you going?
I'm going to get beer from the fridge.
Darling, if you keep persecuting these weaklings...
You'll finally pull out these pet dogs' fangs.
Right, Amamori-kun?
7:25 PM
I'm going to get a bit more coal.
Can you watch the food so it doesn't get burned?
Mouri-san, this dressing tastes good with salad.
But, it says "olive oil" there...
Oh, apologies!
This is a very special dressing that I made,
but I didn't have another bottle to put it in.
Don't be forced to taste it.
Her taste is strange.
Oh, isn't it your taste that's strange?
Master...
It's 7:29 PM.
One minute left.
Oh, that's right.
I'll leave the rest to you.
Excuse me, Amamori-san, where did Kanazawa-san go?
To see the Chinese lesson broadcast on TV.
He's very eager to do his speech in
Chinese at the award ceremony.
No matter how busy he is nowadays,
he always watches it live.
Isn't it a foolish hobby?
7:35 PM
Let's see, my beer was...
If you need some, here you go.
How kind of you!
Dad, haven't you had enough?
What are you saying, it's normal that I drink.
What was that?
Master.
The door's locked from the inside.
Do you have any spare keys?
We don't.
We have no choice but to break down the door.
I'll go get an axe.
7:40 PM
Master?
Master, what's wrong?
Are you all right?
Ran, turn on the light.
Got it.
Master...
Master!
The victim was known architect
Kanazawa Ryuuichirou-san.
It seems Kanazawa-san always
sat here when he watched TV.
He died instantly from a bullet to the head, and
the weapon has yet to be found in the room.
Detective Yokomizo
Shizuoka Prefectural Police
Beyond that, the windows are
all locked from the inside.
In other words, this is a sealed room murder?
No, there's a mark indicating that
the bullet penetrated here.
That means the place from where the culprit shot is...
The place is? The place is where?
The place is...
Where could it be?
Mouri-san!
Please stop it with the jokes!
Say, say, isn't it so great?
The way this room revolves over 12 hours!
Revolves?
I see!
Right now it's 8:35...
And you say you heard the shot an hour ago?
If we draw a line between the victim's
position and the hole in the window glass...
And with one hour meaning 30 degrees, we get to...
I've got it!
What's that?
On the decoration on the side of the building.
Could it be oil, maybe?
There's nothing here.
How's it going?
Yes.
Well, we haven't found any footprints
around the pine tree where the rifle was...
But we did find some around in
the yard and the party area.
From around 6:00 to 6:30 this afternoon, it
was raining pretty heavily around this area.
Which basically means no one got near the tree
where the weapon was found after 6:30.
In that case, how the hell did the sniper shoot?
For the time being, please look
for the owner of this rifle!
Yes!
Mouri-san!
This rifle is damp, so I guess the killer must
have placed it here before it rained.
The target is perfectly locked.
This is the weapon we were looking for.
But where did the killer disappear
to after he pulled the trigger?
Don't tell me you think the
killer jumped into the water!?
But, there's a beach directly below.
It's impossible to jump right into the sea.
Mouri-san!
It's a fishing line...
The end of the line is...
The wire's covered in mud.
There's also mud on the trigger.
A heavy load...
Now I understand everything!
It happened like this:
The culprit knew precisely when the victim watched
TV and calculated when the bullet should be shot.
At the time of the crime, they pulled the
string and the heavy load from here.
Doing so, they never had to enter the villa and
meant to lead us to believe they've escaped.
You're saying the culprit is from the outside?
But, we are dealing with someone
that knows the victim's routine well.
Detective Yokomizo...
The victim recently began receiving
vicious threats from a stalker.
Then, the stalker is the one responsible!?
I believe that to be the most reasonable conclusion.
That much is true.
It's amazing Uncle hasn't made a mistake yet.
It's impossible for anyone at the party to have
pulled the trigger when the shot was fired.
But, why did they disguise the crime
in such a complicated manner?
Wait...
There was mud on the wire and the rifle...
The rain in the evening should have cleaned it...
Just what does it mean?
Could it have been done to hide something?
But, what exactly?
Detective Yokomizo!
The rifle was the property of the deceased.
The robbery was reported by
the owner himself last week.
I see.
And the substance on the decoration outside
the second floor turned out to be oil after all.
Oil?
Now, please allow me to review
the events of today for everyone.
Right after his arrival at 6:45...
Mouri-san went up to the second floor with Kanazawa.
While Conan-kun, Ran-san, Hayashida-san,
and Amamori-san were in the backyard.
And you, Miss?
I was drinking a little brandy in the kitchen
and I got out of there just after 7:00.
The party started at 7:10 when
Mouri-san and Kanazawa came down.
And at 7:20, Hayashida-san: You
went to the kitchen for beers?
You were absent for approximately 5 minutes, yes?
Yes.
Amamori-san changed roles with you
when he left to retrieve some coal.
He was gone for 4 minutes.
At 7:29, Kanazawa went up alone to his
library on the second floor to watch TV.
Afterward, I came out to go to the bathroom at 7:30.
I heard the gunshot when I returned 5 minutes later.
Allow me to confirm one more time...
At the time of the gunshot...
All of the guests were actually at the party, correct?
Yeah.
That's why none of us could have pulled the trigger.
I know what the trick was, but...
Who's the culprit?
This is...
Hey, Mr. Policemen, there's
something on the ground here!
Thank you.
Actually, Uncle Mouri asked me to
have you guys check a few things.
The diameter of the building is 20 meters...
And the distance from the tree where
we found the rifle is about 10 meters.
The length of the fishing line that was secured to
the rifle is exactly 10 meters and 2 centimeters.
Thank you!
I know now...
They're the culprit!
Conan-kun?
Where the hell has he gone off to this time?
Come on, Dad!
This is no time to sleep, help me find Conan-kun!
I found it.
I'm over here.
Conan-kun!
And I also found out who the murderer is.
Ran, could you tell everyone to gather here?
Mouri-san!
I thought you told us a moment ago the
killer can't be someone from the house!
Forget all that I told you before.
But, it's true that if you pull on the wire
from over the cliff, it will pull the trigger.
That was to deceive us into believing the
crime had been committed by an outsider.
But the culprit didn't notice...
That traces of mud had stuck
onto the trigger and the wire.
If it rained, the mud should have been washed away.
In other words, the shooting
occurred in a different way.
And the person capable of the crime is
right here amongst us as we speak.
Allow me to reveal, right here and now, how the bullet
was shot without anyone pulling the trigger directly.
Detective Yokomizo...
Would you mind giving me a hand?
Please roll that hardened paper up and
form a pipe with double-sided tape.
Then turn it into a pole...
And put tape around the end of it.
What's this double-sided tape you're talking about?
Now that you mention it, I found this on the ground.
It's the same!
Then, this belongs to the culprit!?
When everything is ready,
please take a look at the ground.
This was found next to the trigger.
Please attach it to the end of the pole.
Then pick it up pointing at the building.
The fishing wire on the pine tree sticks, and
then, the heavy load on the other end...
I see!
That's why there was mud on the wire!
And now look at the top of the building.
See anything in particular?
On the top?
The decoration on the 2nd floor!
Right.
The culprit hooked the fishing wire there.
The weight was gradually lifted...
And finally it pulled the trigger.
Of course, the killer had been very careful...
By putting oil on the decoration in order to
ensure the wire would continue sliding.
Maybe he put a tissue soaked with oil on the
end newspaper pole and spread some oil...
On the wire and the trigger beforehand.
In all, it would have taken the culprit
one minute to carry it all out.
Then, Mouri-san...
The killer, who is it!?
The culprit...
Amamori-san, it's you, isn't it?
At 7:25, you left the backyard saying
you were going for a bit of coal.
You had already prepared the fishing
line and pole you'd hid beforehand...
And carried out your trick before
innocently going back to the party.
You employed the newspaper sheets
used for the stick to carry the coal.
Judging by the length of the wire, the wire
remained hooked up for 10 minutes.
In other words, we heard the gunshot at 7:35...
Which means the culprit left the party during
the 10 minute time frame from 7:25.
You are the only one that could have done it.
None of you knew the real Kanazawa
Ryuuichirou, I'm certain of that.
The one who designed the Shanghai
Museum of Modern Art was me!
Are you saying I stole your design?
Don't be so foolish.
Do you have any proof?
I have always respected you, Master!
I will say only this:
You do not realize your current position.
This design has won the eye of the
public thanks to me and my name.
If you want to stay here, be very
careful about what you say.
At that moment, I swore to myself...
That I wouldn't allow him to attend the prize ceremony.
Then, the stalker that corresponded with him was you?
Yes.
I created an imaginary stalker.
Everything was going as I planned, Mouri-san.
Everything but you appearing here today.
Always
Song By Mai Kuraki
Always give my love
Always give my love to you
son janai ima kara de mo iin janai yareru koto
It's not a big thing! From now on there won't be any problems! We can make it
omotta doori ni yatte miyou kimi to deau made
Let's give it a go. Like we wanted to, until I met you
nani mo nakatta keredo me o tojite omou
I had nothing, but I closed my eyes and I could believe...
issho ni ikiru basho ga aru kara
Because there is a place, where you and I always can be together
always ai no mune ni yuuki o dashite
Always have courage and love, in your heart
tatoe sore ga dame da to shite mo ne
Even if you think it's no use
No sore dake ga jibun janai
No, that's just not like me
Yes kazamuki ga kawatta ima tobitatou
Yes, now that the direction of the wind has changed, let's fly!
Always give my love
Always give my love to you
Always give my, give my love
What's wrong, Ran-neechan?
I don't know if I will ever be able to trust people
that are self-proclaimed geniuses.
Then, you don't trust me?
Imagine that the great Mouri Kogoro
is not the one solving all these cases.
What do you think of that idea?
What a great guess!