Matsuhashi Miki
Reasoning over hints surpasses even fate...
Allowing us to clearly see through the most mysterious cases.
Summer's hot, so let's head to the beach!
A surprising case awaits on the shore!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Something's just not right
nani wo motometeru no
What is it we're seeking?
uso ni narete yuku kyou mo fake your eyes
We're resolved to lying nowadays, as you fake your eyes
Original Creator
Aoyama Gosho
「Meitantei Conan」
Serialized in Shogakukan's
「Weekly Shounen Sunday」
The start of century
Planning
Suwa Michihiko
(Yomiuri TV)
tashika na mono nakute
Nothing can be considered certain
hitori ja nakenai yowasa hate myself
I can't cry over my weaknesses, I can only hate myself
shinjiteru itami hikikae ni
kono mune umetsukushite
Believing in this pain, my chest endures through the exhaustion
Character Design
Sudou Masatomo
Art Director
Shibutani Yukihiro
ima utsutte iru
futari ga eranda michi kuru
The future where the 2 of us can be together is coming...
Camera Director
Ogawa Takahisa
Sound Director
Kobayashi Katsuyoshi
Music
Ono Katsuo
I think it's only my destiny
Opening Theme
Vocals
Lyrics
Composition
Arrangement
Matsuhashi Miki
Asakoshi Satomi
Majima Kazunobu
Shimizu Toshiya
hateshinai yami no mukou ni
On the other side of this persistent darkness...
dare mo shiru koto no nai ashita ga aru
There's a tomorrow that has no time limit
Video Editor
Okada Terumitsu
Story Editor
Iioka Junichi
Color Design
Hiraide Mayumi
Production Lead
Kobayashi Hiroaki
oh yeah, You're going nowhere, It's only destiny
Planning Support
Tsuzuki Shinichirou
Okuyama Toyohiko
Asai Mitome
Suzuki Tsubasa
ari no mama ni susunde
In search of that final resolution...
ima kanjite iru you're in my heart
Now, I can feel you — you're in my heart
General Director
Kodama Kenji
Director
Yamamoto Yasuichirou
Chief Producers
Suwa Michihiko
(Yomiuri TV)
Yoshioka Masahito
(Tokyo Movie)
you're in my heart
Presented By
Yomiuri TV
Tokyo Movie
Ahh, how boring...
I don't come to Izu beach that often...
But swimming in this body just isn't fun.
I really hope I can return to my real one soon...
I got it!
My bad!
Are you all right, boy?
I'm fine...
I'm sorry.
Later.
Be careful.
Well, maybe I can bear with it for the time being.
Hey now, Conan-kun!
Please play seriously!
Conan-kun has to be the seeker, right?
Oh, yeah...
Then, let's start again!
You have to count to thirty first, all right?
Well?
Between those two girls, which did you like the most?
Don't hide it, you were taken in by their bodies, right?
Idiot, no way.
Well, it'd be a different story if you were talking about
that girl behind us in the blue striped swimsuit.
I see.
Superimposing that girl's figure
with a certain someone's...
You were having that kind of fantasy, right?
Now look...
Oh, isn't that Conan-kun?
What are you doing here?
Ran...
Hey, why is that little brat here?
Dunno.
Oh yeah, Ran said she was going
somewhere with Sonoko...
I see, the beach the Professor was
talking about was this one?
Geez...
The reason we didn't bring him was because
there are always cases when he's around!
It's all right—it's more fun with more people.
Right?
THE MYSTERY IN THE NET
(PART ONE)
Hey!
You can run, but you can't hide!
Take this!
That hurts...
How's that, ready to give up yet?
Damn, we'll get you next time!
Sonoko-neesan is so strong!
I'd say more childish than strong.
Huh?
Where's Ran?
She went back to the shore with Conan-kun
while you were getting the ball earlier.
Haibara said she was feeling tired, so she went with her.
But she said she'll be back soon!
Her temperature is high, her skin
is dry, and she isn't sweating.
Her pupils are contracting and her face is flushed.
However, her pulse is quick and strong.
She definitely has sunstroke.
Hey, if that's the case, shouldn't
we take her back to the hotel?
She'll be fine.
As long as she rests in the shade with wet towels
on her head and chest to cool her down...
It won't be long before she's feeling better.
Professor!
I got some water and ice from others on the beach.
Oh, thank you!
So, is Ai-chan okay?
Yeah, her temperature is going
down, so she should be fine soon.
I'm glad.
Next time, don't hesitate to tell us
if you don't feel well, all right?
Ai-chan?
Well then, I'm going to go join the others.
All right.
My, Ran-kun really surprised me.
Yeah.
She was the first one to notice
something was wrong with Haibara.
It's your fault too, Ai-kun.
Since you didn't go in the water and just
sat there on the shore the whole time.
If you were tired, you could have stayed with
the Professor under the beach parasol.
That's right.
Doing that have been the same as running away.
Running away? From sharks?
Idiot, there aren't any sharks on this beach!
Not a shark.
The opponent was a dolphin.
That's right—the favorite of the sea.
A malicious shark that's fled from the cold, dark
bottom of the sea just cannot compete, can it?
Hey, what kind of obscure thing
are you talking about now?
Sharks are the more fierce of the two.
Could you go somewhere else?
I'm very tired.
Hey, what are you guys doing?
Taking this boat out...
If you were to bump into one of the
other visitors, they could be badly hurt!
It's fine, isn't it?
It was just lying on the beach and the waves
are calm, so it'll be fine if we hold it still.
Hey, Sonoko...
I'm sorry, we'll take it back immediately.
Geez...
Hey, Noboru...
There's no need to yell.
Yuuta...
You're scaring the other tourists.
Yoshizawa Yuuta (34)
Fisherman
This guy just got dumped, so
he's in a bit of a bad mood.
Shimojou Noboru (34)
Fisherman
Idiot!
It was me who dumped that woman!
Well, we'll take care of this boat for now.
But, we were the ones who took it out...
It's quite all right.
Even cleaning up the trash on the
beach is part of our job as lifeguards.
Lifeguards, huh?
Here I was thinking you were actually
fishermen, but I guess I was mistaken.
Well, fishermen who can't get a single fish to bite...
Aramaki Giichi (51)
Fisherman
Will probably have to clean up the
beach for the rest of their lives.
Wanna say that again?
You're the reason we can't catch any fish!
Hey, calm down, Noboru.
Well, Aramaki-san...
Tonight, at 8:00, we'll be waiting at the
Queen Hotel's restaurant Tonpu.
You better not run away!
Of course I'll show up.
You're the ones who better not make a run for it.
Say, Ran...
Wasn't the restaurant we made reservations at...
That Chinese restaurant, Tonpu...
Oh, you guys came to have dinner here too?
Yeah, since we're staying at this hotel.
Wanna eat with us?
There's more than enough room for you two.
Huh?
Where's Ai-chan?
She's sleeping in her room.
She said she wasn't hungry, and would pass on dinner.
Really...
Oh, what's this?
You seem awfully attached to that brown-haired girl.
I just wanted to talk to her.
We've pretty much never talked...
And when our eyes meet, she averts her gaze.
Maybe she doesn't like me?
That's not true.
Because Haibara-san said to Conan-kun...
"She has good child-bearing hips, you should be glad."
anzan
Hey, Conan-kun!
What were you two talking about!?
You've got it wrong!
Haibara said that on her own!
Huh?
Isn't that a good compliment?
Isn't that like syrup-covered red bean paste and fruit?
anmitsu
That's not it at all!
It means being able to calculate by heart.
anzan
What?
So it wasn't about her butt?
Hey, hey, did that kid say anything about me?
Let's see...
She said that you have a small butt.
Really?
Aren't you happy?
It is small, right?
Aren't you those brats and girls from this afternoon?
Hello.
Excuse me, but what time is it?
My watch is broken.
It's 7:12 PM.
Damn...
I came too early.
Well, well, looks like a fight is going to
break out so let's order quick and eat up.
We didn't come here to fight.
But, we do plan to teach that bad guy
a little something about the rules.
Rules?
Yeah, the inviolable rules of nature.
Without regard to where he is, he uses
a dragnet and takes all the fish?
Yeah, we always went with a limited number of
fish and allowed the young ones to grow up.
Then, that guy comes out of nowhere
and takes as many fish as he wants.
That's why, tonight, we intend
to teach that old man a lesson.
A lesson about how long it'll take to fill the empty
ocean with fish again due to his transgressions.
Can't the law punish that person?
It's no use.
Even though there's a law against it,
it's just empty threats in this area.
He said he doesn't care, and that
he'll catch as many fish as he wants.
Hey, Yuuta, you're late.
It's just now 8:00, you just got here too early.
Huh?
Didn't Nobutsugu come with you?
He was excited about talking
to the old man, wasn't he?
He called me and said he was going to stop
by his dad's grave, so he'd be a bit late.
That's right.
Today's the same day, right?
The day that our fathers died.
Your fathers?
Yeah.
Our dads died on the same fishing vessel...
It was when their ship faced
a big storm, eight years ago.
Well, they say dying at sea is
every fisherman's wish, right?
That's correct, missy!
They're getting along too well...
You're being rude, Sonoko.
What?
It's fine, isn't it?
Hey, hey...
Now, now...
It's true that our dads did still go fishing
when they knew a storm was coming.
No.
The storm didn't sink the ship.
Nezu Nobutsugu (35)
Fisherman
That guy sank our fathers' ship.
Aramaki's pirate ship did it.
Hey, hey, you're telling that story again, Nobutsugu?
It's annoying, you know.
In any case, where's that pirate?
He should be here by now.
It's already 8:40...
He probably forgot, got drunk, and fell asleep.
He better not have, or I'll just wake him up.
It's useless, we already tried to call him earlier.
Hello?
He picked up?
He picked up, but isn't saying anything.
All I hear is a strange sound.
A strange sound?
This is...
Waves?
Damn, lost the connection.
That reminds me...
That Aramaki can use the beach as a
shortcut to get to this hotel, right?
Yeah, but it's high tide right now.
Don't tell me that old man blew off our
meeting and went fishing instead?
Couldn't be...
Well, when we sober up a little
more, let's go look for him.
Yeah, good idea.
I see!
The three of you were supposed to
meet Aramaki-san tonight at 8:00.
The meeting place was the Chinese
restaurant Tonpu at the Queen Hotel.
However, Aramaki-san did not show up on time.
So, at around 9:30, you guys decided
to come out to check on him.
You then found him dead on this
beach with the net all around him.
Isn't that right?
Please don't make that face at us.
We aren't lying.
Perhaps not.
However, Aramaki-san and you
three were something like rivals.
It could be that all of you drowned him, and
just said that you found the body together.
What was that?
They really are telling the truth.
Huh?
Sonoko-san and Ran-san?
We heard them confirm the meeting
time with that guy this afternoon.
Right, Ran?
Also, it's true that these people
were at the Chinese restaurant.
Hear that?
But the three of them came in at different times.
Oh, Agasa-san!
That thin guy arrived a little after 7:10!
This fat guy arrived at exactly 8:00.
And this dark-skinned guy arrived around 8:40!
Your children don't look anything like you, huh?
No, they're kids from the neighborhood.
Their parents asked me to take them
for a vacation during their school break.
Then, could it be...
Conan-kun and that strange girl are...
Yeah, Ai-kun is back at the hotel, and...
Conan-kun is over there.
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
That won't do, going around and touching things.
Hey, don't you think it's strange, Detective Yokomizo?
Look.
This guy was drowned, but his face
and body are covered in scratches.
Not only that, but why does he have a net around him?
The net was used so that he couldn't move, and he
likely got the scratches while fighting the culprit.
Look here, leave that to us police!
Hey, take the body back for an autopsy.
Uhm, can we go home now?
We have to prepare to go fishing in the morning.
Not yet, I still have some questions to ask you.
Are you suspecting us?
We told you.
We were waiting for him at the
restaurant the entire time.
However...
It's possible one of you could have killed
him before going to the restaurant.
And all three of you coming to look
for him at this beach is also...
Exceptionally strange!
It was the phone call.
It was already past 8:00, but he hadn't shown
up yet so we called him on his cell phone.
He didn't say anything, and hung
up right away, but I heard it.
The sound of waves through the phone's receiver.
The sound of waves?
Yeah.
That's why we came out here to look for him.
This beach is a shortcut from his house to that hotel.
I called him once while waiting alone over at Tonpu.
After Yuuta arrived, we tried calling two more times.
Oh, yeah, I also tried calling him once before
I got there to make sure he was coming.
Is that really true?
But, even though the call went
through, he never picked up.
If you think we're lying, check the
incoming calls log on his cell phone.
Detective Yokomizo!
A cell phone that is thought to have come out
of the victim's clothes was tangled in the net.
What should we do with it?
Right, give it to me.
Check it out.
My number should show up in the log after Yuuta's.
According to this log...
Yoshizawa-san called at 7:02 PM.
Shimojou-san called three times at
7:47 PM, 8:03 PM, and 8:18 PM.
Finally, Netsuki-san called once at 8:41 PM.
However, yours was the only call that was answered.
Which means that it was either Aramaki-san himself...
Or the one who murdered him that answered the phone.
Why then, did he not answer
Yoshizawa-san and Shimojou-san's calls?
How would I know?
Either way, you understand, right?
We can't be the culprits.
That's true.
If the person who answered Aramaki-san's
phone was Aramaki-san himself, or the culprit...
It would've been impossible for those
three to have been his murderer.
But it makes no sense for the
culprit to answer the phone.
If it was Aramaki-san who answered, why
didn't he answer the four previous calls?
If Aramaki-san was about to be killed, he
could've answered the phone for help...
But it's hard to imagine that he'd
hang up without saying a word.
Look, over there.
Could it be...
The boat we were riding this afternoon?
It sure is.
Hey, you.
Go get that boat.
It may have something to do with this case.
Yes, sir.
Damn.
You're thinking about that, right?
About the day our fathers died.
Now that you mention it, at that time, their boat
returned to this beach in a similar manner, didn't it?
Yeah.
With the crew missing and a gaping hole in
the side, it was in that horrendous state!
Well, those who have died can't be brought back.
Let it go, Nobutsugu.
Hey, what are you doing?
Hurry up!
Don't mess around!
Yes, sir!
Instead of just ordering him around...
Why don't you lend a hand?
Oh, no...
That kind of thing is the duty of subordinates...
Could it be you just don't know how to swim?
You can become a police detective
without knowing how to swim?
But your hair looks like coral!
Coral?
Inside the boat is a 1.8 liter bottle
of alcohol and a lone sandal.
And collected in the bottom of the boat is sea water.
This is...
Why's there a button here?
Hey, the victim's body...
Yeah.
The victim was only wearing one sandal,
and one button was missing from his shirt.
I see...
The culprit got Aramaki-san
drunk and put him in this boat.
Then, he entangled him in the net before
dropping him into the ocean to drown.
The wounds on his body are from
when he struggled while in the boat.
But, isn't this somehow too obvious?
If I were the culprit, I'd just throw
the evidence into the ocean.
Idiot!
You can't just throw garbage into the ocean!
That's littering!
I'm just saying, if I were the culprit...
Conan-kun is the culprit?
I didn't mean that!
I said, "If I were the culprit."
What's a "mininaru"?
Is it tasty?
Agasa-san!
I beg you to keep an eye on these children!
Hey, Detective!
Is it all right if we go home now?
No, not yet.
Well then, why don't you hurry up
and check his time of death?
We can't prove our innocence without that.
We're working on it.
Geez, even though you aren't supposed
to throw garbage into the ocean...
An empty can?
Really, now...
Are you all right?
It's just a little scratch.
You should be careful.
There are a lot of shells around here.
Shells?
Hey, Forensics Officer!
Were there any scratches on the victim's cell phone?
Yes, lots of them.
See?
I see...
That's what happened!
But it's hard to imagine that the
culprit planned such a coincidence...
There has to be something...
Some other purpose!
THE MYSTERY IN THE NET
(PART TWO)
Everyone's so late.
Right, understood.
Keep up the good work.
Right!
Detective Yokomizo!
I've figured it out.
Uhm...
What is it you figured out?
The trick the culprit used to drown that man.
What?
What's with that reaction?
How did the culprit do it?
The drifting boat was a fake.
The real trick was actually very simple.
The culprit got that guy dead drunk...
And then wrapped him in the
net and left him on the beach.
The tide will continue to rise but the
man, unable to move, will drown.
This way, the crime is possible even
without the culprit being present.
Amazing!
Sonoko's so smart!
Aren't I, aren't I?
Uhm, sorry to throw cold water
on you, but that's impossible.
Even if the tide is rising, that doesn't mean the
level of water will instantly get that high.
With the waves hitting him, and the water level
rising to the point of almost drowning him...
He'd definitely wake up.
Besides, the victim was only in the net.
He wasn't tied up with it.
He could've survived by merely sitting up.
And still, he would've been able to just crawl to a
safe place where the waves wouldn't reach him.
That may have worked if he had been given
sleeping pills or something along those lines, but...
The autopsy report didn't mention
anything about drugs in his system.
Then, then how about this?
The culprit sat on that guy until he drowned!
Right?
That could work.
Who would call that a trick?
I was so close.
Sonoko...
I see...
So that's how it happened.
That's why that person said that strange thing.
There's no doubt.
The culprit is that person!
Shimojou Noboru (34)
Fisherman
But that guy still hasn't noticed...
Nezu Nobutsugu (35)
Fisherman
That the trick he set up to escape from his crime...
Yoshizawa Yuuta (34)
Fisherman
Would be the very one that ultimately wrings his neck.
Hey, hey, can you hurry up?
It's almost midnight already!
We've already told you everything
we know, so just let us go home.
Please wait a moment!
Just a little longer.
What is it?
We need you to stay here, just a bit longer.
Say, Sonoko...
You can't think of any other
possibilities for this case, right?
Let's go back to the hotel then.
I suppose not.
Could it be...
It came?
The thing that always happens came, didn't it?
It's only a mosquito bite.
Hey, Shinichi.
It looks like the investigation won't
be ending soon, so let's go back.
Stupid, why would we head back now?
Right when the truth behind this
case is about to be revealed...
By Detective Agasa.
Then, does that mean...
Yes, I understand it now.
The one who drowned Aramaki-san,
and the trick the culprit used.
Right now, Mitsuhiko and the others are
gathering the materials we'll be needing.
When they get back, I'll just use your
voice and you follow along as usual...
What the...
Oh no!
I left my voice changing bowtie back in the hotel room!
Hey, hey...
Here you are.
Haibara...
You're here, just as I thought.
Thank you.
But how did you know that we were here?
I waited a long while for you all,
and when no one showed up...
I asked the people at the hotel...
"Is there a murder case being
investigated around here?"
Sorry Ai-kun, I completely forgot about you.
By the way, where's everyone else?
Ah, they're around.
Heeyyyy!
Conan-kun!
We found all of it.
Here, a big sea shell!
One dead starfish.
Here it is.
I asked the townspeople for a bucket and a basin.
But what are you going to do with these?
Just wait and see.
Come on, can't you leave us alone, Detective?
Why won't you just let us go home already?
Because we need to wait until we
know Aramaki-san's time of death.
Geez...
How long is this going to take?
The detectives in dramas figure it out in mere seconds!
Besides, we couldn't have killed him, remember?
When we tried calling him at 8:40...
The phone was answered but
then was hung up right away.
All calls were recorded in the phone log, and all three
of us were in the Chinese restaurant the entire time.
If you're going to suspect us, explain that first!
How we could've answered the phone while
it was with Aramaki's body in the net!
That is...
It's because of the waves.
Look over there.
It's as if that empty can is Aramaki-san, washed ashore.
Like Aramaki-san, washed ashore...
That's it!
Aramaki-san's body rolled over!
The body was rolled over by the
power of waves on the beach.
You can tell that just by looking.
What does that mean?
As Aramaki-san was rolling...
There was a chance that the buttons might be
pressed by a sea shell as the phone rang.
When the body rolled over again, the
buttons got pressed so the call was cut.
The proof in this is that the cell
phone is covered in scratches.
Not only that, but Aramaki-san
himself was also covered in scratches.
There's no doubt about it!
The phone being picked up when Nezu-san called
wasn't because it was answered by anyone...
But only because Aramaki-san's body rolled,
causing the "Call" button to be pushed.
As such, the culprit was expecting
the body to be rolled over...
Allowing him to answer and cut the
call without even being there!
But isn't that just a coincidence?
Even with the knowledge he would roll over...
It'd be impossible to time it so that the body rolled onto
something and answered the call when you needed.
That's true...
But, with this, your alibis of having been on the
phone with him when he died have disappeared.
Then, tell them to hurry the hell up!
We need to know the time of death!
Hello?
What?
The time of death has been determined?
Right, understood.
Well?
It's like this...
Hey, stop whispering and tell us already.
You found out, right?
Aramaki-san's time of death?
Yes, we know it.
According to Aramaki-san's time of death...
All of you have lost your alibis, and remain suspects!
What was that?
Then, when are you saying he died?
How are we supposed to understand if you don't tell us?
I got to the restaurant a little after 7:00.
Yuuta got there at exactly 8:00.
And Nobutsugu showed up around 8:40.
It takes at least ten minutes to
get from here to the restaurant.
Nobutsugu visited his father's grave before going to the
restaurant, so someone at the temple must've seen him.
So, tell us what time he died!
If we weren't here at the time, we couldn't have...
You wouldn't have to be here.
Being here when it happened isn't necessary...
If you use the following trick!
Trick?
Agasa-san, what have you been doing?
Getting ready to explain this trick.
You'll soon understand everything.
The sand in this basin will, naturally, represent the beach.
This starfish will represent Aramaki-san.
And the water in this bucket represents the sea water.
All right, everyone move away, please.
Yes!
First, dig a hole in the sand big enough for a man to fit in.
Then, place the drunk Aramaki-san, who's
now tangled in the fishing net, into the hole.
Uhm, Professor Agasa?
I'm sorry, but that won't work.
If the trick you're thinking of is immobilizing him
with the net and having the tide kill him...
It won't work.
Even though the tide is rising, the water
level doesn't get that high instantly.
So if he were about to drown, he'd
wake up and would be able to escape...
According to Detective Yokomizo.
Then, how about if we use this?
A sea shell?
Use it as a weight on top of the victim,
and he won't be able to move.
That's true.
If the victim was not only tangled in
the net, but had a weight on him...
He wouldn't be able to get away even if he did wake up.
If that's the case, the weight should've still been
on Aramaki-san when his body was found.
So, was it there?
No, it wasn't.
That's true.
If it were an ordinary weight, it'd still be there, but...
If the weight had a shape similar to this sea shell...
This is what you'll get.
It floated!
But, hold on a second...
What kind of weight has a
shape similar to this sea shell?
Could it be!?
That boat!?
That's right.
The culprit first got Aramaki-san
drunk and entangled him in the net...
Before digging a hole and putting him inside.
Then, he just had to place a boat on top of the victim.
This way, even if the victim did come to, he
would be trapped and would ultimately drown.
Then, once the tide came further in, the boat
would merely drift away from the victim.
All as the person waiting at the
Chinese restaurant wanted...
Shimojou Noburu-san.
Everything went exactly according to your plan!
Hey, Noboru...
Don't tell me you...
Shimojou-san, you...
How did I do?
You were perfect.
For this next part, just go along with my voice.
Oh!
What about the bottle, sandal, and
shirt button found in the boat?
Their purpose was not only to make you
think Aramaki-san was on the boat...
But also make you not consider that
the boat was used as a weight.
Also, the sea water in the boat would make it heavier.
This would make it harder for Aramaki-san to escape.
It's true that there's no need to be here
to kill the victim with this method, but...
Why do you think I'm the culprit?
You knew the order of the phone calls in
Aramaki-san's phone log, didn't you?
You said your call was after Yoshizawa-san's.
That's...
Because he said that he had called before
he came to the Chinese restaurant.
Yoshizawa-san arrived at 8:00 PM.
You first called at 7:47.
How did you know he called before you did?
No, see, that's because...
You knew when Yoshizawa-san
called Aramaki-san's phone...
Because the phone rang while you were setting
up the boat for the trick I just explained.
I see!
What are you saying?
You just made all of that up.
You can't say I'm the culprit just
because I guessed the order of calls.
And, you don't even have any evidence
that I used that trick you just went over!
Anyone could've gotten him drunk, tangled him
in the net, and dropped him into the ocean.
That's true, Agasa-san.
Do you have any evidence proving Shimojou-san did it?
There isn't any.
I have no proof that it was you.
As I said!
All you know is that, at that guy's time of
death, I was at the Chinese restaurant!
Only that truth!
Do you have a witness?
You're one of the witnesses!
Really, what time was that?
I'm so forgetful these days...
You...
Are you senile, Gramps?
I was at the restaurant at the table next to yours.
Right when he died around 8:00!
Please wait a moment, Shimojou-san.
How did you know?
That Aramaki-san died around 8:00.
No, I just heard it when you were whispering about it.
That's rather odd.
The time of death reported to me was between
6:00 and when Aramaki-san was found at 9:30.
That's not funny.
You should be able to narrow it down a bit more, right?
Using things like rigor mortis and postmortem lividity?
That's correct.
Normally the time of death is determined
from things like postmortem lividity...
Rigor mortis, and rectal temperature, but...
That's only in cases where the body remains
in a fixed place at a fixed temperature.
In this case, the waves were repeatedly
turning Aramaki-san's body over.
Because of that...
GRAVITY
the postmortem lividity is unknown since it's
determined from the condition of blood
that pools at the bottom of the body due to gravity.
Thus, it becomes difficult to hold
the stiffened muscles in place.
Also, being constantly hit by the waves caused
the body temperature to change rapidly.
This makes it hard to determine the time of death
from the temperature of the body as well.
In other words, not even the police know
Aramaki-san's exact time of death.
The only one who does is the culprit, which is only you!
Noboru...
Don't tell me... it was for our fathers?
Yeah.
You should thank me.
Eight years ago, Aramaki killed our fathers while at sea.
It took all of my courage to kill him.
Eight years ago?
You mean the accident that happened when
they sailed into an incoming storm?
The truth is, our fathers didn't
want to challenge that storm.
They went out to bring back Aramaki who
went fishing without paying attention to it...
But that bastard...
He lost control of his own boat due to the
waves and ended up hitting our fathers'!
Then, after they had fallen into the ocean,
he just left them all there to die!
A sailor who was on the boat with
Aramaki confirmed it for me.
Then, why...
Why didn't you take him to the police as a witness?
He suddenly disappeared.
What?
When I asked Aramaki about him, he just calmly said...
Do you want to know how to commit the perfect crime?
Two people go sailing, and one
pushes the other into the ocean.
The body's gone and there
aren't any witnesses around.
How's that, easy right?
Then, Aramaki killed him too?
Even so, you still shouldn't have killed him.
Now, you're no different than him.
The hell are you saying?
I took down our enemy for your sake as well!
Even after I took it upon
myself to be the sacrifice...
And summoned all my courage to carry
out divine punishment on that bastard...
How...
How could you say that!?
You can't do that.
Ran...
You can't.
Courage is a word that gives you
the strength to do what's right.
You can't use it as a reason to take a person's life.
Ran's speech had the murderer at a loss for words.
In silence, he was taken to the
Shizuoka prefecture police station.
Like a calm that no waves could break...
Quietly, with a sad smile...
Kuraki Mai
Always give my love
Always give my love to you
son janai!? ima kara demo
iin janai!? yareru koto
Don't you think so!? From now on, let's... Isn't it great!? Do what we can
omotta doori ni yatte miyou
kimi to deau made
With the way I feel now, I know I had nothing before you
nani mo nakatta keredo me wo tojite omou
But when I close my eyes and think...
issho ni ikiru basho ga aru kara
I know there's a place where we can live together
always ai wo mune ni yuuki wo dashite
There will always be love in my heart, I've built up courage
tatoe sore ga dame da to shite mo ne
To say something is impossible...
No sore dake ga jibun janai
No, that's not like me
Yes kazamuki ga kawatta ima tobitatou
Yes, the wind has changed, let's start now
Always give my love
Always give my love to you
Can't believe I said that...
It was really wise.
You surprised me.
I just figured Shinichi would've said the same thing.
What's this?
Speaking fondly of your husband?
That's not it!
Courage...
Gives you the strength...
To do what's right.
I am Haibara Ai...
Nice to meet you.
The pleasure is mine.
Nice to meet you too.