Reasoning over hints surpasses even fate...
Allowing us to clearly see through the most mysterious cases.
A tangled net murder case on the beach.
The two girls also come to terms with each other.
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
We came to visit the ocean of Izu once again.
Ran and the others got acquainted with
Yuuta Yoshizawa,
Noboru Shimojo,
and Hiichi Yoshizawa at the beach.
But there was a somewhat dark atmosphere.
That night, we coincidentally ran into
Mr. Shimojo, Mr. Yoshizawa and their friend, Nobutsugu Nezu.
The three seem to have been waiting for Mr. Aramaki.
Yet, at that time...
Mr. Aramaki was ruthlessly being washed up to the shore, a sorry sight and dead.
THE MYSTERY IN THE NET
(PART TWO)
Everyone's so late.
Right, understood.
Keep up the good work.
Right!
Detective Yokomizo!
I've figured it out.
Uhm...
What is it you figured out?
The trick the culprit used to drown that man.
What?
What's with that reaction?
How did the culprit do it?
The drifting boat was a fake.
The real trick was actually very simple.
The culprit got that guy dead drunk...
And then wrapped him in the
net and left him on the beach.
The tide will continue to rise but the
man, unable to move, will drown.
This way, the crime is possible even
without the culprit being present.
Amazing!
Sonoko's so smart!
Aren't I, aren't I?
Uhm, sorry to throw cold water
on you, but that's impossible.
Even if the tide is rising, that doesn't mean the
level of water will instantly get that high.
With the waves hitting him, and the water level
rising to the point of almost drowning him...
He'd definitely wake up.
Besides, the victim was only in the net.
He wasn't tied up with it.
He could've survived by merely sitting up.
And still, he would've been able to just crawl to a
safe place where the waves wouldn't reach him.
That may have worked if he had been given
sleeping pills or something along those lines, but...
The autopsy report didn't mention
anything about drugs in his system.
Then, then how about this?
The culprit sat on that guy until he drowned!
Right?
That could work.
Who would call that a trick?
I was so close.
Sonoko...
I see...
So that's how it happened.
That's why that person said that strange thing.
There's no doubt.
The culprit is that person!
Shimojou Noboru (34)
Fisherman
But that guy still hasn't noticed...
Nezu Nobutsugu (35)
Fisherman
That the trick he set up to escape from his crime...
Yoshizawa Yuuta (34)
Fisherman
Would be the very one that ultimately wrings his neck.
Hey, hey, can you hurry up?
It's almost midnight already!
We've already told you everything
we know, so just let us go home.
Please wait a moment!
Just a little longer.
What is it?
We need you to stay here, just a bit longer.
Say, Sonoko...
You can't think of any other
possibilities for this case, right?
Let's go back to the hotel then.
I suppose not.
Could it be...
It came?
The thing that always happens came, didn't it?
It's only a mosquito bite.
Hey, Shinichi.
It looks like the investigation won't
be ending soon, so let's go back.
Stupid, why would we head back now?
Right when the truth behind this
case is about to be revealed...
By Detective Agasa.
Then, does that mean...
Yes, I understand it now.
The one who drowned Aramaki-san,
and the trick the culprit used.
Right now, Mitsuhiko and the others are
gathering the materials we'll be needing.
When they get back, I'll just use your
voice and you follow along as usual...
What the...
Oh no!
I left my voice changing bowtie back in the hotel room!
Hey, hey...
Here you are.
Haibara...
You're here, just as I thought.
Thank you.
But how did you know that we were here?
I waited a long while for you all,
and when no one showed up...
I asked the people at the hotel...
"Is there a murder case being
investigated around here?"
Sorry Ai-kun, I completely forgot about you.
By the way, where's everyone else?
Ah, they're around.
Heeyyyy!
Conan-kun!
We found all of it.
Here, a big sea shell!
One dead starfish.
Here it is.
I asked the townspeople for a bucket and a basin.
But what are you going to do with these?
Just wait and see.
Come on, can't you leave us alone, Detective?
Why won't you just let us go home already?
Because we need to wait until we
know Aramaki-san's time of death.
Geez...
How long is this going to take?
The detectives in dramas figure it out in mere seconds!
Besides, we couldn't have killed him, remember?
When we tried calling him at 8:40...
The phone was answered but
then was hung up right away.
All calls were recorded in the phone log, and all three
of us were in the Chinese restaurant the entire time.
If you're going to suspect us, explain that first!
How we could've answered the phone while
it was with Aramaki's body in the net!
That is...
It's because of the waves.
Look over there.
It's as if that empty can is Aramaki-san, washed ashore.
Like Aramaki-san, washed ashore...
That's it!
Aramaki-san's body rolled over!
The body was rolled over by the
power of waves on the beach.
You can tell that just by looking.
What does that mean?
As Aramaki-san was rolling...
There was a chance that the buttons might be
pressed by a sea shell as the phone rang.
When the body rolled over again, the
buttons got pressed so the call was cut.
The proof in this is that the cell
phone is covered in scratches.
Not only that, but Aramaki-san
himself was also covered in scratches.
There's no doubt about it!
The phone being picked up when Nezu-san called
wasn't because it was answered by anyone...
But only because Aramaki-san's body rolled,
causing the "Call" button to be pushed.
As such, the culprit was expecting
the body to be rolled over...
Allowing him to answer and cut the
call without even being there!
But isn't that just a coincidence?
Even with the knowledge he would roll over...
It'd be impossible to time it so that the body rolled onto
something and answered the call when you needed.
That's true...
But, with this, your alibis of having been on the
phone with him when he died have disappeared.
Then, tell them to hurry the hell up!
We need to know the time of death!
Hello?
What?
The time of death has been determined?
Right, understood.
Well?
It's like this...
Hey, stop whispering and tell us already.
You found out, right?
Aramaki-san's time of death?
Yes, we know it.
According to Aramaki-san's time of death...
All of you have lost your alibis, and remain suspects!
What was that?
Then, when are you saying he died?
How are we supposed to understand if you don't tell us?
I got to the restaurant a little after 7:00.
Yuuta got there at exactly 8:00.
And Nobutsugu showed up around 8:40.
It takes at least ten minutes to
get from here to the restaurant.
Nobutsugu visited his father's grave before going to the
restaurant, so someone at the temple must've seen him.
So, tell us what time he died!
If we weren't here at the time, we couldn't have...
You wouldn't have to be here.
Being here when it happened isn't necessary...
If you use the following trick!
Trick?
Agasa-san, what have you been doing?
Getting ready to explain this trick.
You'll soon understand everything.
The sand in this basin will, naturally, represent the beach.
This starfish will represent Aramaki-san.
And the water in this bucket represents the sea water.
All right, everyone move away, please.
Yes!
First, dig a hole in the sand big enough for a man to fit in.
Then, place the drunk Aramaki-san, who's
now tangled in the fishing net, into the hole.
Uhm, Professor Agasa?
I'm sorry, but that won't work.
If the trick you're thinking of is immobilizing him
with the net and having the tide kill him...
It won't work.
Even though the tide is rising, the water
level doesn't get that high instantly.
So if he were about to drown, he'd
wake up and would be able to escape...
According to Detective Yokomizo.
Then, how about if we use this?
A sea shell?
Use it as a weight on top of the victim,
and he won't be able to move.
That's true.
If the victim was not only tangled in
the net, but had a weight on him...
He wouldn't be able to get away even if he did wake up.
If that's the case, the weight should've still been
on Aramaki-san when his body was found.
So, was it there?
No, it wasn't.
That's true.
If it were an ordinary weight, it'd still be there, but...
If the weight had a shape similar to this sea shell...
This is what you'll get.
It floated!
But, hold on a second...
What kind of weight has a
shape similar to this sea shell?
Could it be!?
That boat!?
That's right.
The culprit first got Aramaki-san
drunk and entangled him in the net...
Before digging a hole and putting him inside.
Then, he just had to place a boat on top of the victim.
This way, even if the victim did come to, he
would be trapped and would ultimately drown.
Then, once the tide came further in, the boat
would merely drift away from the victim.
All as the person waiting at the
Chinese restaurant wanted...
Shimojou Noburu-san.
Everything went exactly according to your plan!
Hey, Noboru...
Don't tell me you...
Shimojou-san, you...
How did I do?
You were perfect.
For this next part, just go along with my voice.
Oh!
What about the bottle, sandal, and
shirt button found in the boat?
Their purpose was not only to make you
think Aramaki-san was on the boat...
But also make you not consider that
the boat was used as a weight.
Also, the sea water in the boat would make it heavier.
This would make it harder for Aramaki-san to escape.
It's true that there's no need to be here
to kill the victim with this method, but...
Why do you think I'm the culprit?
You knew the order of the phone calls in
Aramaki-san's phone log, didn't you?
You said your call was after Yoshizawa-san's.
That's...
Because he said that he had called before
he came to the Chinese restaurant.
Yoshizawa-san arrived at 8:00 PM.
You first called at 7:47.
How did you know he called before you did?
No, see, that's because...
You knew when Yoshizawa-san
called Aramaki-san's phone...
Because the phone rang while you were setting
up the boat for the trick I just explained.
I see!
What are you saying?
You just made all of that up.
You can't say I'm the culprit just
because I guessed the order of calls.
And, you don't even have any evidence
that I used that trick you just went over!
Anyone could've gotten him drunk, tangled him
in the net, and dropped him into the ocean.
That's true, Agasa-san.
Do you have any evidence proving Shimojou-san did it?
There isn't any.
I have no proof that it was you.
As I said!
All you know is that, at that guy's time of
death, I was at the Chinese restaurant!
Only that truth!
Do you have a witness?
You're one of the witnesses!
Really, what time was that?
I'm so forgetful these days...
You...
Are you senile, Gramps?
I was at the restaurant at the table next to yours.
Right when he died around 8:00!
Please wait a moment, Shimojou-san.
How did you know?
That Aramaki-san died around 8:00.
No, I just heard it when you were whispering about it.
That's rather odd.
The time of death reported to me was between
6:00 and when Aramaki-san was found at 9:30.
That's not funny.
You should be able to narrow it down a bit more, right?
Using things like rigor mortis and post-mortem lividity?
That's correct.
Normally the time of death is determined
from things like post-mortem lividity...
Rigor mortis, and rectal temperature, but...
That's only in cases where the body remains
in a fixed place at a fixed temperature.
In this case, the waves were repeatedly
turning Aramaki-san's body over.
Because of that...
GRAVITY
the post-mortem lividity is unknown since it's
determined from the condition of blood
that pools at the bottom of the body due to gravity.
Thus, it becomes difficult to hold
the stiffened muscles in place.
Also, being constantly hit by the waves caused
the body temperature to change rapidly.
This makes it hard to determine the time of death
from the temperature of the body as well.
In other words, not even the police know
Aramaki-san's exact time of death.
The only one who does is the culprit, which is only you!
Noboru...
Don't tell me... it was for our fathers?
Yeah.
You should thank me.
Eight years ago, Aramaki killed our fathers while at sea.
It took all of my courage to kill him.
Eight years ago?
You mean the accident that happened when
they sailed into an incoming storm?
The truth is, our fathers didn't
want to challenge that storm.
They went out to bring back Aramaki who
went fishing without paying attention to it...
But that bastard...
He lost control of his own boat due to the
waves and ended up hitting our fathers'!
Then, after they had fallen into the ocean,
he just left them all there to die!
A sailor who was on the boat with
Aramaki confirmed it for me.
Then, why...
Why didn't you take him to the police as a witness?
He suddenly disappeared.
What?
When I asked Aramaki about him, he just calmly said...
Do you want to know how to commit the perfect crime?
Two people go sailing, and one
pushes the other into the ocean.
The body's gone and there
aren't any witnesses around.
How's that, easy right?
Then, Aramaki killed him too?
Even so, you still shouldn't have killed him.
Now, you're no different than him.
The hell are you saying?
I took down our enemy for your sake as well!
Even after I took it upon
myself to be the sacrifice...
And summoned all my courage to carry
out divine punishment on that bastard...
How...
How could you say that!?
You can't do that.
Ran...
You can't.
Courage is a word that gives you
the strength to do what's right.
You can't use it as a reason to take a person's life.
Ran's speech had the murderer at a loss for words.
In silence, he was taken to the
Shizuoka prefecture police station.
Like a calm that no waves could break...
Quietly, with a sad smile...
Can't believe I said that...
It was really wise.
You surprised me.
I just figured Shinichi would've said the same thing.
What's this?
Speaking fondly of your husband?
That's not it!
Courage...
Gives you the strength...
To do what's right.
I am Haibara Ai...
Nice to meet you.
The pleasure is mine.
Nice to meet you too.