Destiny
Song by Matsuhashi Miki
Destiny could be a hint for our deductions.
And mysterious cases can be unraveled.
It's the end of summer at a plateau boarding house.
An impossible crime on a one way street.
Seeking the one and only truth...
With the appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is... Detective Conan!
Something's just not right
nani o motometeru no
uso ni narete yuku kyou mo fake your eyes
The start of century
tashika na mono nakute
hitori ja nakenai yowasa hate myself
shinjiteru itami hikikae ni kono mune umetsukushite
ima utsutte iru futari ga eranda michi kuru
I think it's only my destiny
hateshinai yami no mukou ni
dare mo shiru koto no nai ashita ga aru
oh yeah. You're going nowhere, It's only destiny
ari no mama ni susunde
ima kanjite iru you're in my heart
you're in my heart
The Alibi of the Soothing Forest
SOOTHING FOREST BOARDING HOUSE
THIS WAY
Thanks for coming all this way to this place.
I'm sorry, but we can only get to our boarding house
using this one way road through the forest.
Murakami Shirou (32)
Soothing Forest Boarding House Owner
We should arrive in 10 minutes or so. Please
bear with us for just a little while longer.
Yes.
Do you brothers manage the boarding house together?
Err, no.
I only help out at my older brother's
boarding house during the summer.
Tateshiba Kinji (27)
Really, is that so.
Oh, this reminds me, brother, weren't you
going to bring father a watermelon?
No. We'll drop off our guests first.
A dropping in on the way?
Then, if we stop by, can I use the bathroom?
I understand. It's the place just after this bridge.
Great! I'm saved!
Geez, you drink too much beer, father.
I only drank a little!
Tsunakawa
Murakami Ryuuzou (60)
Village Head
Ah... that's a relief!
My, my what a magnificent vase this is!
Is the village headman a potter?
No, I'm not.
I just do it to kill the boredom of living alone.
But, I got injured yesterday, so I can't do it now.
Oh, yes, father. This is from my garden,
a watermelon. Please eat it.
Huh, are you trying to please me?
Father, my brother doesn't have such intentions...
You're just like him.
Despite my objections, you still married into that family.
Huh!
Listen to me, Shirou, I have no intention
of lending you money!
Take that with you and leave!
I'm sorry you had to see such an unpleasant sight.
No, it seems he was in a bad mood today.
No, it's always like this.
He's old-fashioned as well as stubborn.
Good afternoon!
Hi, Aiko-san.
Are you collecting the money?
I was planning to do that, but I forgot to bring my ledger.
Misawa Aiko (25)
Milk Delivery Woman
Since my part is a lot of money, can I pay the bill before?
Thanks, we'll do it like this, since I want
to properly manage the money.
Pleased to meet you, Aiko-san.
I'm the private detective, Mouri Kogoro.
I'll be staying over at Shiro-san's boarding
house today, and my room is... well...
Oh, Sorry! I have to continue on with my deliveries.
Please excuse me!
Soothing forest's beautiful woman...
My hat!
Ah! Be careful!
It's dangerous if you fall in the river!
I'll get it for you.
Thank goodness we got it, Ojou-san.
Thank you very much!
Good thing it didn't get wet, right?
But, your pants have gotten wet, Shiro-san.
It's fine. But it looks like my swimming
inability has been exposed now, huh?
Well then, we'll go gather wild vegetables for dinner.
The part timer at the back will handle the rest.
Okay.
Hello! Here are your additional orders!
Good work as usual.
Is today a group stopover?
Yeah, sort of.
Hey!
Any beer here? Beer!
Geez, that father of mine. He always
falls asleep when he's drunk.
Did you find any wild vegetables, Shiro-san?
Well, not really.
I remembered something I had to do and came back early.
Oh, is that so?
Yeah, but rest assured. My brother will surely
bring some wild vegetables back.
Ugh... hey, where am I?
Geez, father!
Hey, this is Detective Mouri agency what's your request?
What?! The head of the village has been murdered?!
I'm back!
Yes, I understand. We'll make our
way there immediately. Yes.
Midorikawa Youji (54)
Policeman
You are Mouri Kogoro-san, right?
I'm a police officer, Midorikawa.
Yeah, I appreciate your efforts indeed.
Anyway, let's get to the crime scene.
This way.
Father!
A paper knife. So this is the weapon, huh?
R.M? The initials, hm?
It's the village head's favorite.
Based on the state of the dead body,
the culprit came to the study room, entered through the door
and stabbed the village head while he was facing him.
Since the documents are scattered, the culprit must have
been rummaging through them, looking for something.
Yeah.
The intrusion report shows that all doors other than
the main entrance were locked from the inside.
Aiko-san, please give us a detailed account of the sound
you heard when you found the village head.
Yes.
If I'm not mistaken, I was here before five minutes to
4:00 p.m. collecting the payment for a milk delivery.
At that time, I got his stamped seal in this ledger.
And after that?
While I was going to Shiro-san's boarding house,
I heard a scream and turned back here quickly.
Then I saw the village head.
What time was it when you heard the scream?
At 4:00 p.m. That was during my patrol watch.
I was a little slower than Aiko-san was, I must
have gotten back here just after 4:05 p.m.
In that case, the murder must have occurred
in those few minutes after Aiko-san left.
In brief, the culprit was already here when
Aiko-san came for the payment.
Hey Uncle, it seems that his money and cards weren't stolen.
And only things from the desk are fallen
on the ground, it wasn't a thief...
Goodness.
Don't touch things as you please!
It seems that a conflict occurred when the culprit was
visiting the head of the village, and impulsively stabbed him.
By the way, where were you both at around 4:00 p.m.?
Ah, I was already back at the boarding house.
I was probably still on the one way street.
Can someone prove that?
About that...
When Aiko-san called around 4:10 p.m., Shiro-san
was already at the boarding house.
Moreover, Kinji-san returned during
that same call, didn't he?
Yes.
Besides,
we couldn't have done this to our father...
It takes an hour to walk from our father's
place to the boarding house.
However, it only takes 5 minutes by car, but
the both of us were on foot at that time.
The car was at the boarding house the whole time.
Are there any other means for traveling?
None whatsoever.
The boarding house is at the end of a one way
path, surrounded by a steep mountain range.
That means that it's impossible to get here, and then
return to the boarding house within 10 minutes.
That means Aiko-san is...
Can't be. The culprit would be covered with a lot of
the victims blood after inflicting such a wound.
I see.
That means, it's not possible for the people
here to have committed this crime.
The culprit came here to rob but unfortunately the murder
happened. The suspect should be an outsider, right?
Something is just not right. Something...
Can I have a look at the ledger again, Onee-san?
This?
Yes.
Of course, boy!
This is...
All documents, due to the village
head's job are dated from today.
But,
Why?
Mouri-san, are we allowed to return
once to the boarding house?
Yes, that shouldn't be a problem.
The clay diminished.
The village head was injured in the hand,
he couldn't have used any clay.
Moreover, the rope that was above is gone.
I get it.
What?
What's wrong, Uncle?
Mouri-san.
Father.
Well, it's just that I know who the culprit is.
The culprit is among you!
But, you said earlier that it was impossible for
any of us to have committed this murder...
Aiko-san's fine. She has been removed
from the list of suspects from the start.
The culprit would have needed to dispose
the clothes stained with the blood.
She hasn't changed, and she wouldn't have
had time to remove the bloodstains, either.
Shiro-san and Kinji-san have changed clothes, but...
Kinji and I changed because we got dirty
from gathering wild vegetables.
Anyway, assuming that one of
the two of them is the culprit...
How did he return to the boarding house
from here in only ten minutes?
By going down the river.
By descending this Tsunagawa river that runs next to the
village headman's house and the boarding house...
It's possible to get there in 2-3 minutes.
But, there are no scaffolds there to tie a boat to.
Right. Moreover, this was an impulsive murder, so
a boat couldn't and wouldn't have been prepared.
So, are you saying that the culprit
swam down the river, then?
Then it would have been impossible
for a non-swimmer like myself.
Then, Kinji-san is...
Please don't say such foolish things!
Well, please let me finish what I have to say.
After murdering the village head on impulse, the
culprit probably calmed down for a short while...
But then noticed that he was covered in the victim's blood.
When he thought about fleeing the village head's house as
quickly as possible and washing the blood from his body...
He hit upon a certain method.
It was the use of the clay and rope that was at this entrance.
How did he use the clay and rope?
The culprit first removed their pants that had the victim's
blood on it, and rinsed it briefly at a spout.
He then grabbed the clay and rope, and took them with him.
After that, he turned the damp pants inside
out, and spread clay all over the pant legs.
Then, he turned the pants back out,
and tied up both legs wtih the rope.
After that, grabbing the waist of the pants, let enter the
air in, and then he jumps off the bridge into the river.
The inflated pants are then used as a swimming float.
The culprit then just floated back downstream that way.
Kids often play in the bath tub by trapping air in
wet towels, right? This uses that same theory.
The clay stops the air from leaking
through the seams of the pants.
After that, just flow with the current and...
You arrive at the river right behind the boarding house!
And most of the victim's blood would have been washed off!
Then the culprit changed quickly,
and calmly appeared before us.
Who exactly is the culprit, then?
Before that, Aiko-san...
Yes.
That ledger will be taken along as evidence, so please
acknowledge Shiro-san's earlier payment first.
Yes.
Of all the times to...
OK, seal it...
So, you've noticed.
That ledger, Shiro-san, is the document
that proves you are the culprit.
Please carefully compare the seals
used by Shiro-san and Ryuzou-san.
Both of their seals have been swapped.
Ryuzou-san's seal has been cleanly
stamped up to the last month.
This month's stamp border is partly chipped, right?
That's right.
Whereas Shiro-san stamped his with the chipped
seal, until now. Now it's cleanly stamped.
I see.
Looking at it closely, I'm certain
that their seals were swapped.
That's right.
In short, Shiro-san, this is the indisputable proof that you
were at the village head's house at the time of murder.
Shiro-san had his seal with him when he visited the village
head's house. They then broke out into a quarrel.
Since the stamps were concerned, we can guess that
it must have been a quarrel concerning money, right?
Under these circumstances, when one of you two struck
and split the documents that were on the desk...
The two seals were swapped.
No, you're wrong! It must have been
swapped long before today!
That's not possible, is it? It was changed
today, right before Aiko-san arrived.
On the scattered documents, there are stamps
from the seal that was imprinted today.
Furthermore, this seal is exactly the same as the one on
the ledger the head of the village stamped last month.
That means, the seal that the village head used
today was only different in Aiko-san's ledger.
But, maybe he only changed it today...
From the standpoint of a village head, something as
important as a seal will never be changed on a whim.
Moreover, all deliberations will be clarified
once fingerprints are lifted off the seals.
Such accusations... where's your proof?
Shiro-san...
I heard from Conan that you'd used your seal for the liquor
delivery before you went to gather vegetables, right?
We just need to confirm which seal was used for that and...
It's a lie, right brother?
Why did brother have to kill father?
Say something, brother! Tell me it's a lie!
Father hated me.
I was always compared with my
more favored younger brother.
Brother...
I've kept a respectful distance for the sake of his wealth.
But I came over to beg to him when I needed money badly.
Please father, at least for the guarantor...
Stop pestering! No means no!
Good afternoon, village headman
sir! Today is a terribly hot day!
You're still sobbing there?
You cause me nothing but trouble, you
should have left home instead of Kinji!
With just those words, all of the suppressed
hatred for my father exploded all at once.
Then, I quickly wiped off my fingerprints from the knife.
Grabbed the IOU and my seal and left the room.
What followed was exactly as Mouri-san said.
Brother...
Shiro-san...
We can't say how a person like you that
can't swim came across a trick...
And only found a solution that lead them down the river.
For something such as the resentment
you harbored toward your father...
There may have been a different solution than murder.
My life would have taken a different turn had I done that.
Aoi Aoi Kono Hoshi ni
Song by Uehara Azumi
shigekiteki na sekai o matte ita kedo kitto
I'm waiting for a world that's exciting.
me no mae ni aru subete ga taisetsu na mono nanda ne
But maybe everything before me is precious, too.
ushinau koto kowagaru nante... watashitachi mada nani mo iretenai
To be afraid of losing something... we haven't got anything yet.
oh, yeah yeah yeah
aoi aoi kono hoshi ni kagirinai mirai kasane
In this blue, blue world, limitless possible futures expand out before me.
can make me free kono mama kodou kanjite itai
Can make me free, I don't want my heart to stop racing.
oh, yeah yeah yeah
kono kimochi maiagare sore to umi yaki tsukete
This feeling starts to dance within me, burning the sky and boiling the seas.
tsuyoi chikara de kimi ni dakare tobidashitai
I want you to embrace me tightly in your arms, and take off.
oh, yeah yeah yeah
kono kimochi maiagare sore to umi yaki tsukete
This feeling starts to dance within me, burning the sky and boiling the seas.
tsuyoi chikara de kimi ni dakare tobidashitai
I want you to embrace me tightly in your arms, and take off.
And it was supposed to be a soothing forest...
Uncle's awake?
He's just staying awake out of spite.
He was grumbling on about Aiko-san not seeing him off.
She couldn't help it since she has to work, right?
Mouri-san!
Conan-kun! Ran-chan!
It's Aiko-san!
Aiko-san!
My beautiful Aiko-suaan!
Do come again! Next time let's make
it a leisurely sightseeing trip!
I'll definitely be back! The only thing that
can soothe my heart is your smile!
The sleeping kid is awakened, huh?