Destiny
Song by Matsuhashi Miki
Reasons and hints are all connected.
With these, the truth unravels.
Long time, no see, Yoko-chan!
Even idols can have problems!
Seeing the one and only truth...
A kid with the intellect of an adult...
His name is... Detective Conan!
Something's just not right
Something's just not right.
nani o motometeru no
What is it we're seeking?
uso ni narete yuku kyou mo fake your eyes
We're used to lying nowadays, as you fake your eyes.
The start of century
The start of century.
tashika na mono nakute
Nothing can be considered certain.
hitori ja nakenai yowasa hate myself
I can't cry over my weaknesses, I can only hate myself.
shinjiteru itami hikikae ni kono mune umetsukushite
Believing in this pain, my chest endures through the exhaustion.
ima utsutte iru futari ga eranda michi kuru
The future that the two of us can be together is coming...
I think it's only my destiny
I think it's only my destiny.
hateshinai yami no mukou ni
On the other side of this persistent darkness,
dare mo shiru koto no nai ashita ga aru
There's a tomorrow that has no time limit.
oh yeah. You're going nowhere, It's only destiny
Oh yeah. You're going nowhere, It's only destiny
ari no mama ni susunde
Looking for that final resolution,
ima kanjite iru you're in my heart
I can feel you now, you're in my heart.
you're in my heart
You're in my heart.
L-O-V-E...
I love Yoko!
Yoko-chan!
Geez.
You keep watching the same show over and over.
Isn't it about time you stopped?
Why does it matter? I'm bored anyway.
But you've got a lot of letters piling up.
One of them might be a job request.
I'll read them later.
Just put them somewhere for now.
It's not that he's bored, he just doesn't want to work.
Let's see... There's bills, advertisements, more bills...
Huh? There's a letter from Yoko-san!
What?!
It's a party invitation.
They're having an engagement party
at her friend's apartment.
Eh?
E-Engagement?
Her friend is getting married, and she wants
to meet the famous Detective Mouri.
We're going, right Da... huh?
Engaged? Engaged? Engaged?
I don't think he can hear you...
Idol Star's Secret
(Part One)
I'm really, really, really excited
that you invited me, Yoko-san.
It's an honor to be invited to your friend's engagement party.
No, no. I'm sorry it was on such short notice.
Okino Yoko (22)
Idol
Were you surprised?
Not at all!
After leaving us for the land of depression for a while...
Anyway, who's your friend that's getting engaged?
You'll know when you see her, you
probably know her very well.
Know her?
Yoko-san!
Oh!
So you really did bring him.
That famous detective, Mouri Kogoro.
Are you...
the guy who plays Detective Samonji?
Kenzaki Osamu (26)
Actor
Kenzaki Osamu!
Then, you're Yoko-san's friend who's getting married?
No, I'm the groom.
Yoko-san's friend is the one I'm marrying.
To actually bring the famous Detective Mouri...
She'll be happy, won't she?
The truth is, I haven't told her yet...
I wanted to surprise her.
Well, let's go and see the surprised look on her face!
Doesn't look like she's home.
I thought that everyone would be here by now.
The door is open.
I'm really sorry, Mouri-san.
After you came all the way to see me.
No, no.
You don't get hit by a celebrity that
often. It's another fun memory.
Kaoru Kusano (20)
Actress
Actually, there's been someone stalking me. So when
I saw a weird face through the peep hole...
Sorry.
At least learn a person's face before inviting him.
Then, you must be Yoko-san's friend
who's marrying Kenzaki-san.
Yeah, that's right!
Our wedding will be next spring!
We aren't leaking it to the press yet, though.
Oh yeah, Kaoru-san, Kenzaki-san is in
that "Detective Samonji" show, right?
That's right.
We were thinking about watching tonight's
episode to celebrate their engagement.
Yuki Takeno (22)
Multi-talented
For the golden couple of the millennium!
It's Takeno Yuki!
Again with the bright nails, Yuki.
Aren't these fake nails just so glamorous?
What a shame...
Okino Yoko, Takeno Yuki and Kusano Kaoru...
One more, and we'd have all four!
How nice that would be!
Oh, you mean me?
Terumi!
So, you came as well, Terumi?
Hoshino Terumi (23)
Actress
Yeah, but only because Yoko forced me to.
Does it bother you?
Well, well. Since all four Earth Ladies have reunited
after such a long time, we should celebrate!
Earth Ladies?
Looks like you don't know.
"Kusa" from "Kusano" represents the fields,
"Takeno Yuki" represents the glaciers
at the top of mountains,
"Hoshi" from "Hoshino" represents the stars in the sky,
and finally, "Okino Yoko" represents the water and oceans.
That's why, together, they're known as the Earth Ladies.
I see.
Four ladies representing four elements of nature.
Yeah, but Terumi and Kaoru had a fight, so we broke up.
Out of all of us, the only person still singing is Yoko.
But what's surprising is that the youngest
among us is the first to get married!
I always thought Terumi would be the first
to get married, but I guess I was wrong.
Oh yeah, Terumi. Didn't you used to like someone?
Yes, yes.
What happened? Did you ask him out?
Forget it, nothing happened between us.
Rather than getting married, I want to keep
my distance and appreciate from afar.
Sometimes, it's better to appreciate
the person you are today.
Wait! What does that mean?!
T-Terumi...
Anyway, who's the man with the kids?
Yeah, are you Kenzaki-kun's brother?
Oh, no, actually...
Um...
"Detective Samonji" is about to begin...
Atsushi Makuma (23)
Kaoru's Manager
Don't you want to watch it?
I'll pass.
I'll take a bath while you guys watch it.
But the food that I've prepared will get cold...
And, watching it together might—
Shut up! When I say I'll pass, then I'll pass!
Don't say such things to me, you depressing low-life!
Sorry.
Hey, Kaoru!
She'll never change!
She hates watching herself on TV while around other people.
J-Just as expected!
Hold on, are we really going through with that plan?
Definitely! That's why I invited you!
Plan?
Fine, we'll wait for you in the living room.
Can you change your clothes in the bathroom first, Yoko?
Okay!
Wow! Those are the clothes the Earth
Ladies wore when they debuted!
I get it! So when Kaoru-san gets out of the bath...
That's right.
All three of us are going to sing
to celebrate their engagement.
But, the outfits are a bit... embarrassing.
No, you're fabulous! You're fabulous, Yoko-san!
You're too excited.
We're ready!
Ta-da!
So you're really gonna go through with it?
Well, I'll go change next.
Can you hurry? I have to get changed too.
Hey, let's sign this card while we wait; from us to Kaoru.
"May you have everlasting happiness."
Here.
You're next, Terumi.
Oh, forget about me.
You really should consider making up with her!
I guess I have no choice, then.
Hey.
Did Kaoru-san really want to meet Uncle Kogoro?
Yeah, she even said so herself.
Didn't you hear her talking about that
stalker that's been watching her?
She wants him to catch the culprit.
Well, once she marries me, there won't be any more trouble.
I guess you're right.
Oh, are you signing the card?
Yes, and everyone is writing something for her.
Well, I'll go change my clothes.
Wait a minute, what's this?
Geez!
"Sorry to hear about it", with a cigarette burn below it.
That's just like her.
So, if Terumi's mark is a cigarette burn, then mine is...
It's a kiss.
Here you go, Manager-san. Why
don't you write something too?
No, I...
Here, don't worry.
We won't mind, even if you write complaints about her.
I'm sorry. Did you not want to?
No, I'm just happy.
There, I'm all done changing.
Nice, nice.
Then I'll go get Kaoru-san.
What's wrong with him?
No idea.
Geez.
No one watched my show's ending!
Oh well.
I'll play the song's intro...
Now, let's wait for Kaoru.
Huh? Where's Kaoru?
About that...
I've called her several times, but she didn't answer.
Maybe she fell asleep in the bathtub.
In that case, Kenzaki-san, you should go check up on her.
She probably just fell asleep.
This is blood.
It leads directly to the doorstep.
Does that mean?!
Hey Kaoru, answer me.
Everyone's waiting for you.
Kenzaki-san! Open the door!
Hurry!
Kaoru, I'm coming in.
Kaoru?
Kaoru!
What happened?
How could this happen?
She still has a pulse.
If we hurry and get her to the hospital, she might make it.
Hurry!
What's happening? Did somebody scream?
Kaoru!
Hang in there, Kaoru!
Ran, call an ambulance!
So the victim is Kusano Kaoru-san.
Age 20, floor 28, room 1.
But for a girl in her early 20s to be
living in such a large apartment...
Probably some rich kid.
Haven't you heard of the Earth Ladies?
"Earth Ladies"? What's that?
Yes.
It's the police.
Please come in.
We're coming in...
I'm sorry, I must have the wrong apartment.
Ah, Inspector Megure!
We've been waiting for you.
So many stars!
I see.
So, I'll ask one more time:
These three here, who were invited
to Kaoru-san's engagement party,
took turns changing their clothes outside the living
room while Kaoru-san was taking a bath.
You changed in the following order:
Yoko-san, Yuki-san, and Terumi-san.
After changing your clothes, Manager Makuma-san
went to get her, but she did not respond.
After that her fiance, Kenzaki-san, went
over to the door and forced it open.
At that moment, you saw Kaoru-san with
blood on her neck. Isn't that right?
Yes.
And, as if it were planned by the devil,
this unfortunate case happened.
You don't have to say it like that.
I was invited here by Yoko-san; it was only by chance.
Translator's note: This is a Japanese pun, where Tamamata
means "By chance" and Matamata means "Yet Again".
It's not Tamamata anymore, it's Matamata.
Well then, where is Kaoru-san right now?
She was taken to Haido Hospital to be treated.
We haven't heard any news from Makuma-san,
who accompanied her.
K-Kaoru...
Is she going to die?
There's no point in waiting, I'll call the hospital
and ask them about her condition.
I'll go with you.
My father is being treated for his diabetes
there, so I know the number.
I see... Thanks.
The culprit who attacked Kaoru-san, could it be one of them?
Impossible!
But it's a possibility, right?
It's often the case that whoever discovers
the body is the culprit.
Hey, hey!
I don't have any reason to murder her!
Not to mention that the boy with
the glasses was there with me.
The boy is the one who told me to open the door.
Is that true?
Yeah, but that's because...
there was a trail of blood leading towards the front door.
When I opened the door, all of those were placed outside.
A raincoat, some old gloves, an empty
eye-drop bottle, and a handkerchief.
They were all thrown outside the door.
We moved them inside before the ambulance came.
Since these clothes are splattered with blood, they were
probably worn by the killer at the time of the murder.
There are trace marks of a woman's
lipstick on the handkerchief.
So, if this bottle had some sleeping drug in it,
he could have put our victim to sleep by placing the
drug in the handkerchief before slicing her throat.
But, who would do such a brutal thing to Kaoru-san?
It's the stalker.
It must be the same person who's been playing
Ding Dong Ditch on Kaoru for a while.
"Ding Dong"?
It's a prank where you ring a door bell and run away.
But in Kaoru-san's case, it wasn't simply a prank.
There was always a letter left in front of the door.
"I'll come again." — "I'll keep coming again."
— "I'll come even if I'm dead."
Every time he came, there was an even weirder
letter left behind, printed on white paper.
I see.
That's the reason Kaoru-san hit me when I rang the bell.
Was the door locked at the time?
It was unlocked.
Since there was a lot of people here, we weren't
worried and left the door unlocked.
Then, we can summarize the events as follows:
The stalker noticed that the door was unlocked,
and entered to face Kaoru-san, who
had just gone toward the bath.
After that, the stalker sedated her and sliced her throat.
Then, he removed his raincoat and all the
other items found outside the apartment,
and ran away.
Okay, Takagi-kun.
Question all the residents of this apartment building.
Since it wasn't raining, and the murderer was wearing
a raincoat, someone must have noticed him.
Yes, sir!
But I don't think anyone would have noticed the murderer,
because he's a very careful person.
Careful?
Normally, when someone is wearing a bloody raincoat,
they would step the blood dripping from it.
But when I looked, there was blood all over the
place, but not one drop had been stepped on.
That means that the murderer tried to run
away without stepping on the blood, right?
I-I guess so...
Huh? But that's weird...
If he's such a careful person,
why didn't he notice the large number of shoes at the
entrance and know that a lot of people were here?
Inspector...
Maybe the culprit moved the raincoat extremely
slowly while walking towards the door,
let the blood drip on the floor, and threw the coat outside...
Trying to imply that the criminal had run away.
And if that person was someone Kaoru-san knows,
he could've somehow convinced her to get out of the bath.
Once she got out, it wouldn't be hard to sedate
her and put her into a deep sleep.
Hey, wait! Does that mean...
...that the murderer is one of us.
Isn't that right, Officer-san?
T-Terumi!
It's true...
The room we used to change our clothes is situated between
the living room and the bathroom, which Kaoru was using.
It isn't too hard to believe that one
of us could have silently killed her.
Yuki...
Whatever the case, Yoko-san did not try to murder her.
We waited in front of the bathroom for her while she
was changing her clothes, then returned together.
Then I'm safe, too.
I was with the boy when we found Kaoru.
That's right.
Someone who was nice enough to walk Kaoru-san
to the bathroom could never have killed her.
You walked her to the bathroom?
Yeah.
So, you could have attacked her at that time.
For now, I'd like to question each of you individually.
Shouldn't you be searching for the most important thing?
The murder weapon...
The dagger that slashed Kaoru's throat.
If you can find it in this apartment or among our possessions,
then the murderer is definitely one of us.
I don't think an outsider would leave the
murder weapon inside the apartment.
Even if he wiped it clean, there would still be traces
of blood that forensics could find with luminol.
It's not something that one could easily hide, right?
Yes.
What...
What's this feeling I'm getting from her?
Aoi Aoi Kono Hoshi ni
Song by Uehara Azumi
shigekiteki na sekai o matte ita kedo kitto
I'm waiting for a world that's exciting.
me no mae ni aru subete ga taisetsu na mono nanda ne
But maybe everything before me is precious, too.
ushinau koto kowagaru nante... watashitachi mada nani mo iretenai
To be afraid of losing something... we haven't got anything yet.
oh, yeah yeah yeah
Oh, yeah yeah yeah.
aoi aoi kono hoshi ni kagirinai mirai kasane
On this blue, blue world, limitless possible futures expand out before me.
can make me free kono mama kodou kanjite itai
Can make me free, I don't want my heart to stop racing.
oh, yeah yeah yeah
Oh, yeah yeah yeah.
kono kimochi maiagare sore to umi yaki tsukete
This feeling starts to dance within me, burning the sky and boiling the seas.
tsuyoi chikara de kimi ni dakare tobidashitai
I want you to embrace me tightly in your arms, and take off.
oh, yeah yeah yeah
Oh, yeah yeah yeah.
kono kimochi maiagare sore to umi yaki tsukete
This feeling starts to dance within me, burning the sky and boiling the seas.
tsuyoi chikara de kimi ni dakare tobidashitai
I want you to embrace me tightly in your arms, and take off.