Destiny
Song by Matsuhashi Miki
Reasons and hints are all connected.
With these, the truth unravels.
Today's case takes place at the OK Corral.
The battle between the crime and deduction.
Seeing the one and only truth...
A kid with the intellect of an adult...
His name is... Detective Conan!
Something's just not right
Something's just not right.
nani o motometeru no
What is it we're seeking?
uso ni narete yuku kyou mo fake your eyes
We're used to lying nowadays, as you fake your eyes.
The start of century
The start of century.
tashika na mono nakute
Nothing can be considered certain.
hitori ja nakenai yowasa hate myself
I can't cry over my weaknesses, I can only hate myself.
shinjiteru itami hikikae ni kono mune umetsukushite
Believing in this pain, my chest endures through the exhaustion.
ima utsutte iru futari ga eranda michi kuru
The future that the two of us can be together is coming...
I think it's only my destiny
I think it's only my destiny.
hateshinai yami no mukou ni
On the other side of this persistent darkness,
dare mo shiru koto no nai ashita ga aru
There's a tomorrow that has no time limit.
oh yeah. You're going nowhere, It's only destiny
Oh yeah. You're going nowhere, It's only destiny
ari no mama ni susunde
Looking for that final resolution,
ima kanjite iru you're in my heart
I can feel you now, you're in my heart.
you're in my heart
You're in my heart.
This feels so good!
That's right, mother nature is great.
But Dad, why did you take us out for a drive all of a sudden?
Well... that's a good question.
Hey, didn't we pass by here awhile ago?
Ah, really?
We are here, and we need to get here...
Let me take a look at where the destination is.
W-Well...
Hey Dad, make way.
That's it!
Wait for me!
OKusu Corral?
Tragedy at the OK Corral
OKUSU Ranch
You saved me. I was able to arrive
here on time because of you.
It's nothing.
Hirohito Ninomiya (28)
Part-Time Ranch Worker
It has been awhile since we've had customers.
So this place is a horse ranch.
So, we were forced to come and share his horse obsession...
I wanted you guys to fully enjoy the outdoors.
Leave!
Get out of here!
Mochizuki Kanenari (46)
Real Estate Agent
No need to tell me. I was about to
leave anyway. I'm a busy person.
Just wait until I sell this ranch, then you
will realize that you were wrong.
Geez.
I'm sorry you guys had to see that.
Welcome to the OK Corral.
Okusu Tomoyuki (50)
Ranch Owner
I'm the owner. My name is Okusu.
OK Corral?
OK Corral is the abbreviation for OKUSU Corral.
Although this place isn't really "OK."
Ah, yeah.
Hey, kid. Do you want some chocolate?
It's really good.
Chocolate...
No, thanks anyway.
I see.
Amazing!
Ah, sorry I'm late.
I will be your tour guide. My name
is Takeuchi. Nice to meet you.
Takeuchi Sanae (21)
Part-Time Ranch Worker
We are in the middle of the racing season right
now, so not all of the horses are here.
Do you recognize any of these horses?
Is this horse Madam Leap?
Yes, she is the thoroughbred of this corral.
She made me a lot of money a while ago.
Thank you very much.
But, why doesn't she look so well?
She was trying to breed but failed,
and now she can't breed anymore.
I see, how unfortunate.
That old barn is for horse breeding.
It's where foals are brought up.
No one uses it now, but if you want, you can go take a look.
Hey, are those customers, Sanae-chan?
Y-Yeah...
Hey, thanks for coming. It's Madam Leap's turn today.
He helped me look after the corral when I was a rider.
Sugiyama Moto (37)
Farrier
His name is Sugiyama Moto.
Now he's a farrier.
Farrier?
A farrier is a person who shoes horses.
Farrier
Horses that live on farms get a lot of exercise, so horseshoes
are put on to protect the hooves from damage.
However, this prevents the hooves from being trimmed.
Therefore, the horseshoes have to be taken off periodically.
After trimming the hooves, the horseshoes
are put back on again.
You are very knowledgeable about this.
Even Takeuchi-kun looks surprised.
It's just something I've heard about.
Next, they heat up the new horseshoe,
and reshape it to the right size of the horse's hoof.
The sizes of the hooves are different.
Even for one horse, the size of each hoof
is different from the other three.
I see.
Conan-kun, you're good!
How is it? Isn't it good that we came?
Madam Leap!
Ninomiya-san, Madam Leap is...
Got it.
What happened?
Madam Leap is running away!
Steady, steady, steady.
This is her first time like this.
Good girl!
Calm down.
Blood!
Could it be...
Conan-kun!
Sugiyama-san!
Sugiyama!
It's no use, he's dead.
It is possible that he was kicked by Madam
Leap, causing his head to bleed.
How...
How could this be...
In any case, call the police immediately.
Yeah.
Please take Madam Leap to another trough.
Y-Yes.
What is this?
A piece of chocolate?
The right rear hoof looks weird.
How cruel.
The horseshoe wasn't nailed on properly.
The shapes of the horseshoe and the hoof don't match.
Why would Sugiyama-san do something like that?
But wait, maybe...
Conan-kun, that's dangerous!
Sorry!
It's okay, calm down.
Let her drink something.
Is there still some tea in the thermos?
Tea is no good.
It's fine for a human to drink, but it's a stimulant for horses.
Tea is a stimulant?
That means, this wasn't an accident.
Seems like that's what happened.
He was kicked by the horse.
Look, there's an imprint of a horseshoe on his forehead.
Still, it's best to check if the horseshoe
matches the shape of the imprint.
Excuse me but who are you?
Oh, sorry. I am a private detective, so...
My name is Mouri Kogoro.
That famous detective.
I'm sorry that I didn't recognize you.
But, this is an accident, so you don't have to do anything.
It seems like it.
Out of curiosity, what's going to happen to Madam Leap?
Umm...
It's best to just get rid of this violent horse.
What?! It is all Sugiyama-san's fault. He deserved to die.
Sanae-chan!
Onee-san, do you hate Sugiyama-san?
Why did he deserve to die?
Um, Mouri-san. Let me explain.
Yesterday, on my way back from town...
Hey, that car...
Isn't that Sugiyama-san's car?
Wait, that's...
Sugiyama was meeting with Mochizuki,
who wants to buy the OK Corral.
Okusu is trying to get the horse breeding again.
Oh, isn't that good.
If he fails again this time, he will go bankrupt for sure.
Then we will do again what we did before.
I will leave it to you, Sugiyama.
Because of money, Sugiyama betrayed Okusu-san.
Sugiyama showed up before I could
say anything to Okusu-san.
So, in order to make this ranch go bankrupt,
Mochizuki told Sugiyama-san to
interrupt the breeding process.
That's right. There's a huge amount
of money involved in breeding.
Hence, we lose money if there are no foals.
Madam Leap got involved in this human struggle.
That's evil.
But, would the horse try to get revenge because of that?
If she did, then she's no different than them.
Even though that horse looks sad, her eyes are still clear.
This is no place for kids to talk!
Sorry!
Conan-kun...
Sorry.
No, it's fine.
Huh? Onii-san, your pants are wet.
I got splashed when I was cleaning the stalls.
Sorry that you got wet too.
Nah, it's alright.
This incident will probably be treated as an accident.
Sorry for the trouble.
Hey, officer.
Aren't you going to take the horseshoe with you?
Aren't the police supposed to gather all the evidence?
But...
I will go get the horseshoe if you want it.
I did everything myself back then anyway.
No money to hire a professional.
Didn't have any before, and certainly don't have any now.
Please put it in this plastic bag.
Alright, here you go.
It's okay, good girl.
Huh?
This horseshoe has blood on the back, too.
You're right, and a huge amount of it.
That's weird.
I see. It's all clear now.
I know the culprit, and the method used.
No matter how strong the horse may be, it's hard
for the blood to get on the back of the horseshoe.
If that's the case, then there is only one answer.
The blood was there from the start!
I'm afraid so.
Wait a minute.
That's Madam Leap's blood.
Take a look.
The nails are not properly nailed on to the horseshoe.
They even penetrated through some blood vessels.
How cruel, this is all Sugiyama's fault.
So, that's why the horse was out of control.
Dad!
M-Mouri-san, what's wrong?
Nothing, except that I know how
Sugiyama-san was murdered.
But it was just an accident.
No, this is a murder case.
Conan, show everyone what you found.
Yes.
It's this. I picked it up off the ground.
It was beside the trough.
This is chocolate.
But, how is this related to the case?
To horses, tea is like a stimulant.
The same goes for chocolate.
T-That's true.
Chocolate has theobromine.
Someone gave chocolate to Madam Leap.
Who would do something like that?
Okusu-san, where is the chocolate that you
were going to give to Conan earlier?
Oh that... It's still in the office.
But, I remember that you actually put it in your pocket.
Could Okusu-san be the one who used the chocolate
and made Madam Leap go out of control...
But, maybe Madam Leap didn't eat the chocolate.
It can be checked if the horse's urine is tested.
Also, if we check for fingerprints on the chocolate.
We will be able to know whose it is.
That's not necessary.
I gave Madam Leap the chocolate.
N-No way.
Why? Why did you do it?
Even if you hated Sugiyama-san, you shouldn't
have used Madam Leap to kill him!
Wait a second, Sanae-san.
Sugiyama-san was not killed by Madam Leap.
The culprit is the person who put the unfitted horseshoe
onto Madam Leap's rear right hoof.
So, it is not Sugiyama-san who put the horseshoe on?
That's right.
If the job was not done properly, even if it was a
one-time error, he could no longer be trusted.
He would become jobless.
Furthermore, it is Sugiyama-san's blood
on the back of the horseshoe.
The culprit probably used a newly made horseshoe
to hit the back of Sugiyama-san's head.
However, he didn't know what to do with it afterwards.
So, panicking, he quickly nailed it on to Madam Leap's hoof.
Even if you were in a rush, you wouldn't put
the horseshoe on so carelessly, right?
Maybe it was Mochizuki.
There might have been some problems.
That's unlikely.
Instead of making it look like an accident,
it would be wiser to take the weapon
and run away before anyone noticed.
If this murder was planned, then it wouldn't
have been done so sloppily.
Then, who did it?
Sanae-san is right, Okusu-san shouldn't be
bad at putting horseshoes on horses.
But, since he wanted to take off the
horseshoe as soon as possible,
it seemed to me like he already knew
that the horseshoe was put on badly.
Based on that observation, I figured out
he already knew who the culprit was.
In order to protect the culprit,
he gave Madam Leap chocolate.
Then he went back to the office,
and waited for Madam Leap to start acting erratic.
He did this to cause us to focus our attention on the horse.
Okusu-san was trying so hard to protect the person.
He even gave chocolate to the horse.
Sanae-san was with us the whole
time, so she can't be the culprit.
If that's the case, there is only one
person left. Ninomiya-san...
It was you.
What happened?
N-Not me!
Your pants are wet.
If they are tested with luminol, they should show blood.
From putting the bloody horseshoe on the horse.
Also, because that horseshoe did not fit,
it was troublesome to put on.
If it has mud on it,
it wouldn't be out of the ordinary since this is a ranch.
However, if the victim's blood is on it instead,
then it will be obvious that something's not right.
I didn't...
I didn't want to kill him.
But, I couldn't forgive Sugiyama.
I was curious, so I went straight to Sugiyama
and asked about yesterday.
He said that he was going to kill me,
and make it look like a simple accident.
He then took out a knife.
While we were fighting...
Sugiyama died.
I was surprised.
So I made it look like Madam Leap's fault.
Getting a horse in trouble,
it's a dirty deed, I know that very well.
Okusu-san,
I'm sorry. I... I...
I'm the one who should be saying sorry.
I actually noticed that there was something
not right about Sugiyama before.
You are very noble. I was afraid that if I told you,
things would get even worse, so I didn't say anything.
If I had known that this would happen,
I would've told you earlier.
Sorry, Ninomiya-kun.
Ninomiya-san and Okusu-san,
You have to pay for what you have done.
No matter how you try to hide it,
it will not solve the problem.
Friendship and sympathy can never supersede the law.
Aoi Aoi Kono Hoshi ni
Song by Uehara Azumi
shigekiteki na sekai o matte ita kedo kitto
I'm waiting for a world that's exciting.
me no mae ni aru subete ga taisetsu na mono nanda ne
But maybe everything before me is precious, too.
ushinau koto kowagaru nante... watashitachi mada nani mo iretenai
To be afraid of losing something... we haven't got anything yet.
oh, yeah yeah yeah
aoi aoi kono hoshi ni kagirinai mirai kasane
In this blue, blue world, limitless possible futures expand out before me.
can make me free kono mama kodou kanjite itai
Can make me free, I don't want my heart to stop racing.
oh, yeah yeah yeah
kono kimochi maiagare sore to umi yaki tsukete
This feeling starts to dance within me, burning the sky and boiling the seas.
tsuyoi chikara de kimi ni dakare tobidashitai
I want you to embrace me tightly in your arms, and take off.
oh, yeah yeah yeah
kono kimochi maiagare sore to umi yaki tsukete
This feeling starts to dance within me, burning the sky and boiling the seas.
tsuyoi chikara de kimi ni dakare tobidashitai
I want you to embrace me tightly in your arms, and take off.
Go!
Number 2 and 6, Run!
Run!
Cheer for the riders with the black and green caps!
Run! Number 2 and 6!
Good! Run!
Not only is he bad at deductions,
he's also bad at horse betting...