Even fate can be used
as a hint for reasoning...
Seeing through
the most mysterious cases!
Today, the Detective Boys
take the scene!
The key that unlocks the mystery
is a child's drawing!
He sees the single truth
for what it is,
and looks like a kid
but has the mind of an adult!
His name?
Detective Conan!
Once again, it's
terrible, Genta-kun!
What? Speak for
yourself, Mitsuhiko.
You can say what you like.
A man's worth is not
in the quality of his art!
That's true.
But people who are good at drawing are cool
and I've got lots of respect for them.
Yeah!
Maybe tomorrow,
I'll start going to art classes.
Oh, me too, me too!
Oh, geez.
Jukichi Sakai (55)
Secretary to the President of
Tsubakuro Financial Group
I wonder what he's doing...
That guy's weird.
Somehow, it smells
like a crime.
Shh!
What? What? What?
M-Money?
That's a lot of money, too...
Could that...be?
Hold it, mister!
Why do you have
all that money?
Are you a thief?
N-No! I'm...
After him!
H-Hey! You guys!
Got 'im!
P-Please, let me go!
Young master is... Young master is...
...going to be killed!
What did you say?
I knew it.
"Kenzo Tsubakuro"
After all, my intuition
was right on the mark.
Yes...
A kidnapping case
had occurred.
The one who was kidnapped
was Akio Tsubakuro-kun,
Kenzo Tsubakuro (70)
President
Tsubakuro Financial Group
the 5-year-old grandson of Kenzo Tsubakuro-san,
the president of the Tsubakuro Financial Group.
Akio Tsubakuro (5)
He loves drawing pictures.
And all those bills were the ransom to get Akio-kun back.
All right, Tsubakuro-san, would you care
to explain to us in detail what happened?
Go away.
Tsubakuro-san?
What are these?
They're pictures Akio drew
that the kidnapper sent.
When did you receive them?
About noon yesterday.
They were tossed into the mail
along with the threatening letter.
I see.
And that is the letter?
"¥1,000,000,000 for the child.
—The Clown."
Wow! I wonder how many boxed
eel lunches I could eat for that much.
Oh, Genta-kun...
But the money from before was nowhere near a billion yen.
That money was intended to check whether there
was any intention of actually paying the ransom.
I'm sure at the time the kidnapper was...
...right?
Yeah. That's right.
Hey, you lot!
We're grateful for your tip,
but from here on in,
this is police business.
Now, hurry up
and go home!
Mr. Inspector, you lot
should go home with them!
B-But, Tsubakuro-san...
Akio is my precious and only grandson, who my late son and his wife left me
when they passed on in a car crash last year.
If something were to happen to him,
I would disgrace his parents in heaven...
I know how you feel,
but, Tsubakuro-san...
The moment we hand over the ransom money
to make contact with the culprit kidnapper
is our perfect shot
at arresting him!
A billion yen is quite a load,
so the kidnapper—
I refuse!
It doesn't matter to me
whether or not you catch the kidnapper.
I will not risk Akio's life!
Besides, I am not handing
over the money!
Just what do you
mean by that?
This was in the mailbox
this morning.
Location for bank transfer...
"locAtIoN foR bAnk TraNsfEr:
fonTaUbeRt bAnk, SwiTzeRland
account number: 259H604329
im COunTinG on You!"
Fontaubert Bank, Switzerland...
A-A bank in Switzerland?
Inspector, we should hurry up
and place a chargeback,
or at least get the bank to tell us
who the account holder is...
It's no use.
Switzerland is a bank nation.
If Swiss banks were so accomodating,
their existence would be pointless.
O-Oh, no...
I hate to say this,
but it's just as the boy says.
Whatever the case,
there are no exceptions.
But if doing so
brings Akio back...
I am asking you...
Leave!
Master...
T-Then...
This is...
A perfect crime?!
Say, Mr. Inspector.
Don't tell me that you gave up
on the investigation?
Of course.
We can't butt our way into
paying the ransom money
any further than what
Tsubakuro-san says.
But the police can't just stand by idly
and let this dastardly crime go on.
So once the ransom money is handed over,
and Akio-kun comes back safely,
you're gonna start seriously
investigating this, right?
Absolutely.
But even if the ransom is paid,
there's still no guarantee Akio-kun will come back safely.
Akio-kun sure loves to draw, doesn't he?
This is...!
What's up, Conan?
Conan-kun!
Mister, can I take another look
at Akio-kun's drawing?
As I thought,
it's here too...
Oh, that's a quirk of Akio's...
Quirk?
When he draws something, he puts down
whatever catches his eye as a signature.
Whatever catches his eye?
Come to think of it, I've seen
something just like that somewhere...
R-Really? W-Where?
Where was it again...
Oh! That's right.
When I was at Beika South Kindergarten
where Akio goes to school,
they showed me
one of his drawings...
Beika South Kindergarten, right?
Let me borrow this, mister!
I'll bring it right back!
H-Hey! Little boy!
"Beika South Elementary"
Excuse me!
What is it, little boy?
I'd like to take a look at
Akio Tsubakuro-kun's drawings.
Akio-kun's drawings?
The drawing Akio-kun's
grandfather saw
is probably this one
hanging here...
There it is!
That's the one!
Say, teacher.
Where did Akio-kun draw this?
There's no mistake.
That signature is the same
as what Akio-kun drew here.
Furthermore, what was sent was what
he drew where he was being held hostage.
In other words,
if I can figure out where that is,
I can make a good guess
as to where Akio-kun is being held.
But the problem is...
Conan-kun!
What're you up to now, Conan?!
You shouldn't go on ahead of us!
No, I didn't mean...
Don't play dumb with us!
That's right!
You're planning to rescue Akio-kun
all by yourself, aren't you?
We're gonna help you!
D-Don't be stupid!
We're dealing
with a kidnapper!
Whatever danger
might be waiting...
But!
Look at this drawing!
Akio-kun looks like he's having fun!
Yeah...
He's smiling as he's watching
TV with the kidnapper.
Yeah. That's Kamen Yaiba, isn't it?
As far as I can see from this,
he doesn't seem to be in any sort of danger.
If we're gonna save him,
it's now!
Yeah!
That's what you were thinking,
wasn't it, Conan-kun?
You guys...
Besides, aren't we the ones
who found this case?
Right, right!
Fine.
But only until we find
where he's being held.
After that, we leave it
to the police.
Yeah!
His signature?
I see.
But what's this that he drew?
Isn't it an alien?
It's a chimney,
isn't it?
Like on a building.
Nah. Definitely an alien.
Why would he be able
to see an alien from here?
But you can't see any
chimneys from here either.
Now that you say that,
you're probably right.
There's no time for arguing!
Chimney or building,
it doesn't matter!
Let's split up and look for the thing
that looks like this signature!
Got it!
There it is!
Really, Ayumi-chan?
Look! That's it, isn't it?
Looks like a water tower...
But...
It kinda looks like it
and it kinda doesn't.
No...
I'm pretty sure that's it.
Really?
How can you be so sure?
Look. What do you see
in front of that water tower?
There's a clock, isn't there?
Isn't it a park?
Yeah...
S-So what?
There isn't anything like
a park in his signature.
Look closer.
There's something in the middle of the signature
that looks like an eyeball.
He's right!
Yeah, there is...
If you put the clock on top of the water tower,
what do you think it'd look like?
Right. The thing in the signature that
looked like an eye was that clock.
Then Akio-kun's in
the water tower, right?
That's not what I meant. Akio-kun's is where it
looks like the clock's in front of the water tower.
I see!
Let's go to the
water tower, then!
Maybe we can see
where Akio-kun is!
Okay, let's go!
How is it, Conan?
Well...
What you see over there is
the park with the clock from before.
The eyeball in Akio-kun's signature lines up in
the middle of the water tower exactly as he drew it.
In other words,
it might be a little distorted,
but Akio-kun should be being held
somewhere in this area.
Ugh. There's sure a lot
of houses around here.
After all, it doesn't look like
we can really tell from here...
If we split up and search,
we should find him in no time flat!
OK, let's do it!
Yeah!
If you see any suspicious
people or houses,
contact me right away
on your badges.
Don't even try to
give chase alone,
and don't think about
going to save Akio-kun.
How'd it go?
There were a bunch of
suspicious places, but...
None of them looked like
they could be the one.
There's still too many places
to narrow it down...
Come to think of it,
where's Ayumi-chan?
Huh?
We were supposed to meet up
at the park at 5:00, weren't we?
Yes! Ayumi here!
Ayumi-chan?!
Where are you right now?
Conan-kun!
I figured Akio-kun'd be hungry, so
I went shopping at a convenience store.
Geez, what are we gonna
do with you?!
It's way past when we were
supposed to meet up!
Sorry...
I'll head back right away,
just wait a—
Huh?
A clown mask!
Huh? What was that?
I don't copy!
Ayumi-chan,
is something wrong?
What's the matter,
Ayumi-chan?!
I found a suspicious person!
A suspicious person?
The kidnapper?
I'm not sure yet,
but the clown that Akio drew
wore a triangular hat with
a star on it, had green hair,
and held a remote
in his left hand, right?
Wait a sec!
Yep, it's just like Ayumi said.
No doubt about it!
That means that the kidnapper is left-handed, right?
Ayumi-chan, don't do anything foolish!
Listen to me.
Just a sec!
A-Ayumi-chan!
I've found him, Conan-kun... He's got to be
the one who kidnapped Akio-kun!
I'm gonna follow him!
No! Stop, Ayumi-chan!
It's dangerous, Ayumi-chan!
Answer us, Ayumi!
I'll be fine!
But I don't want the kidnapper finding me out,
so wait for me to contact you!
Over!
She cut us off!
Ayumi-chan!
Ayumi!
Damn it! That Ayumi...
Hey, Conan...
How long are we going to wait here
for Ayumi to get in touch with us?
It's gonna be on us if
something happens to Ayumi-chan!
Oh, yeah!
Can't you use those glasses of yours
to find out where Ayumi is?
No, Genta...
Right now the Doc's got them
so he can fix them.
Anyway, nothing's gonna happen
just staying here like this.
Let's search one more time.
Search where?
Well...
It's Ayumi!
It's Ayumi-chan!
Conan here!
Are you there, Ayumi-chan?!
"Tohto Coating Industrial Co., Ltd."
I'm back, little boy!
Are you hungry?
I bought you
some sandwiches.
And some crayons
and drawing paper.
Wow!
Thanks, Mr. Clown!
When you were out shopping, Mr. Clown,
I did a lot of drawing!
Did you? Good for you!
W-Who's there?!
Huh? I...
Who are you, Sis?
Akio-kun! It's all right,
we're here to save you!
Who are you?
How did you get in here?!
Hold it!
This is as far as you go!
Hey, hey! Kidnapper!
You're up against us,
the Detective Boys!
Give yourself up quietly!
Right!
D-Damn...
Get over here, boy!
Mitsuhiko, there he goes!
You're not getting away!
Conan-kun!
Take this!
We did it!
Akio-kun!
Are you all right, Akio-kun?
Yeah, Big Sis.
I'm fine.
Akio-kun! What a relief!
Really, what a relief!
We did it, Conan!
Looks like our strategy
was a success.
Yeah.
Another huge victory
for the Detective Boys!
Yeah!
Afterwards, Inspector Megure and the
other police took our information,
rushed to the scene,
and arrested the kidnapper.
But as for us...
You idiots!
As we feared, we ended up getting
a piece of Inspector Megure's mind.
Bye-bye, Big Sis!
And thank you, Detective Boys!
Bye-bye!
Let's hang out again
sometime, Akio-kun!
Bye-bye!
He said "Thank you"...
It sure feels nice when
people are grateful to us.
Oh, geez...
After all, Akio-kun draws really well!
Let us see?
Conan!
Conan-kun!
W-What's that for?!
Running ahead
of us again?!
Hey, Conan!
When did you...?!
Oh, geez!
Why does this always happen to me?!
E-mail?
A robber!
Someone catch him!
He went into the alley!
You're not getting away!
This is the police!
Further escape is futile!
Three people?
Next Conan:
Yes! Next Conan's Hint: Sunglasses
Next time:
What's gonna happen to Detective
Takagi and Detective Sato?
It ain't gonna go good,
that's for sure.