A hint to reasoning is to dream.
There's a mystery behind every case!
It has all been arranged!
He had better hurry and solve the case!
Recognizing that single truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is Detective Conan!
But, Miwako...
Is it really okay for an honorable police officer
to be sitting around watching TV all day?
I'm just relaxing, it's my day off.
Then here.
Jeez, those pictures again...
Why don't you look at them?
Because I look at enough pictures as a police officer.
Why did you have to grow into an
adult that has no interest in love?
I'm all to blame! I let you have your way as a child.
How can I tell your father that died while on duty about this?
I just can't!
Fine, that one. But I'm not promising anything.
Wow, like mother, like daughter. We have the same taste in men!
The Metropolitan Police Detective Love Story 4
(Part 1)
The Metropolitan Police Detective Love Story 4, Part 1!
Huh? Officer Sato is having an arranged marriage?
That's right, I bet she's all dressed up and
meeting her future husband right now.
Hey, who's the man she's marrying?
That's just it, Miwako doesn't even know.
She said she just picked a picture from
the top of a stack without looking.
No way.
So she's going to marry a total stranger?
Don't worry, I'm sure he's just a man that's
just looking for a female officer.
I bet he's a serious and well-mannered middle-aged man.
Japanese Restaurant Minatorou
Come on, come on...
It's already ten minutes past our meeting time.
What kind of guy would make a lady wait for him?
I'm going home.
It's only ten minutes.
Sato-sama?
Please forgive me for being late.
My name is Kamishi Akia, it's a pleasure to meet you.
W-W-What!?
This old guy? How old is he!?
It's not like that, he's a butler.
This whole thing is so sudden.
The master and mistress were overseas when the news
came, and insisted I accompanied the young master.
Young Master?
No, it's alright.
Choosing the perfect flowers for Sato-san took awhile.
No, I shouldn't use Sato-san now...
I think Miwako-san is more appropriate, right?
Sh... Shiratori-kun!?
It's great to see you, Mother.
No.
What the... Why!?
What are you saying?
You chose him yourself!
Only my daughter would also be attracted to a police officer!
Huh? No one in the first division knows about this?
Then, Officer Takagi...
Right, she told me to keep it secret so no one would find out,
because she wouldn't accept his proposal anyway.
Afterall, Miwako does have a lot of
admirers I wouldn't want to upset.
But... What if the man becomes interested?
It's alright. We've arranged for a way
to save her from the meeting.
What man would marry a woman who
wouldn't attend to an important case?
But, who's going to do that?
Of course, that'll be Takagi-kun.
I'll send him a message telling him to save her from the
meeting place by making up an emergency case.
Takagi-kun will definitely go.
I'm sure he'll make it in time.
Cruel.
He may even confess his love to her.
Hey, why don't we go there?
But that's far from here...
Then, Yumi-san, please?
I can't do that, I'm on duty.
What's going on? Is something wrong?
Araide-sensei!
Lucky!
Really, I'm honored...
To be the one you chose out of everyone else.
No, it was a coincidence, a coincidence.
I didn't even look at the pictures when I picked.
Now Miwako, don't be shy.
No, I'd prefer it to be a coincidence...
For me to be the one selected by your
fated fingers must be a sign of God.
It must be our fate, huh?
That's right.
Well said, Master!
Those fated fingers were actually my toes.
But how's Yumi doing...
It'll be fine, my servant will rescue you.
What's she trying to say?
Who's her "servant?"
Are you alright, Takagi-san? You've been sneezing a lot.
A call...
Yes, this is Takagi.
Oh, Takagi-kun, did you get the mail?
Mail?
Robber!
Someone stop him!
Alright, come on Chiba!
Right!
Hello? Hello, Takagi-kun?
Hey, answer me, Takagi-kun!
Excuse me, I'm with the police!
Please let us pass!
There he is!
He's going into that alley!
Let's get him!
Are you alright, Oji-chan?
Did you see a man with a helmet?
Yeah.
That person knocked me over and ran to that restroom.
Takagi-san!
A helmet, a coat, a bag, and gloves...
There's no doubt. The robber must be in here.
This is the police! There's no use hiding.
Surrender now!
Zama Hiroshi (21)
Freelancer
Hey hey, what's this?
Koshimizu Eiko (28)
Office Lady
What do you two want?
Kamieda Yusuo (32)
School Coach
What are the police doing here?
There's three...?
We found these three inside the restroom.
Well?
Can you tell which one knocked you down, Oji-chan?
Well, my glasses fell off when I fell to the ground...
So I couldn't see much.
Tell us anything, anything you can remember!
Let's see... They were taller than me...
And it was a woman wearing a blue shirt under her coat.
A woman?
Koshimizu-san is the only woman, but she's wearing black.
I don't know everything! That's all I noticed!
Hey!
I don't know what this is about.
Can we go if we weren't involved?
I have things to do today.
Please just wait a bit.
We can't release you until we've heard your testimony.
S-Shiratori... The officer...?
Yes, he's with Sato-san now.
Then that means Officer Sato's meeting...
Inspector Shiratori!?
Um, is there something wrong?
No, we're only...
Their parents asked us to prepare a special present for them.
But we still need some time to finish it,
so can we use the room next to theirs?
I guess so, it's available...
Thank you, Onee-san.
Then, please follow me.
Please excuse us.
This kid's clever...
Wow! This course is magnificent!
We have brought along the Shiratori family chef,
As only he can make the family's true kaiseki.
The master informed me beforehand that
Miwako-san isn't fond of French cuisine.
Huh? There are foods you don't like?
Hey, Miwako...
Oh, right...
Um, excuse me!
Is there anyone that saw the convenience
store robber earlier? Anyone?
Officer, wouldn't it be quicker to just ask the store owner?
We already have. He was too frightened
because he was threatened by a knife.
He only remembers the helmet and coat.
This is ridiculous...
Damn, no one's helping...
Hey, Officer...
Yes?
I know the criminal's height.
He was wearing a helmet and coat, right?
I saw him from the window and noticed that he was taller
than everyone in the crowd, so I guess he was about 180cm.
180cm? That's about the height of the
tallest of the three, Zama-san.
And he is wearing a blue shirt...
Right right, I saw the green lining of his shirt under his coat.
Are you sure?
It was green.
Um, well, did you see if it was a man or a woman?
180cm must mean it was a man.
Not always.
Yo, Officer.
Yes?
The owner of a restaurant was bragging
about getting a good look at the robber.
Is that true?
Oh yes, yes. I saw that guy running with a helmet on.
It was about the time that I was handing
out the menus during lunchtime.
T-Then, did you notice anything...?
I couldn't determine the gender, but
I'm sure they were at least 170cm.
And with a black shirt under their coat!
Black...?
Kamieda-san is about 170cm tall, but he's wearing a green shirt.
Hey, hey! What's going on here!?
Well, we're going out for some fresh air.
You two have a fun time!
Hey, hey... Yumi, where's that person at?
I see.
Someone is supposed to come and
save this beauty from the beast?
Stupid, what are you talking about?
Then, let's do this...
If Takagi-kun comes here, I'll give up on this arrangement.
If he doesn't make it, you'll become my wife.
Why Takagi-kun?
Why not?
It's a joke, a joke.
I was only bothering you.
That's fine.
It's OK.
But Takagi-san, what did you mean by
"it doesn't add up?" How can that be?
There are three witnesses that saw the suspect, right?
Yeah, but their three descriptions of the
robber all conflict with one another.
The old man said the robber was a woman with a blue shirt.
The girl from the store said it was a male
of about 180cm with a green shirt.
And the restaurant manager said the
suspect was wearing a black shirt.
See how their testimonies don't add up?
They don't...
But I don't think those three are lying.
Well...
Why don't we question them now?
Right.
"OK?"
Did I hear you right? You're agreeing?
Yes, I am.
If Takagi-kun comes for me, we'll forget
about this whole arrangement.
But if he doesn't, I'll marry you and become your wife.
Why don't we set a time limit? How about by sunset?
Hey hey, are you sure, Officer Sato...?
This has gotten really interesting, huh?
But if Officer Takagi doesn't make it...
It's possible that Officer Sato really wants to marry him.
Inspector Shiratori's family is rich, the party would be huge.
I always thought Officer Sato and Officer
Takagi would get together...
Well, she seems confident.
She really thinks he'll come.
I understand.
Are you sure?
Yes, you have my word.
Of course, of course, it's Takagi-kun!
The servant Yumi was talking about must be Takagi-kun.
Right, I know he'll come.
But...
Why?
My name is Kamieda Yasuo. I'm a school coach.
I stopped by the restroom while on my way to a bookstore.
I'm Zama Hiroshi, a freelancer.
I had to stop at that restroom while on
my way home from band practice.
My name is Koshimizu Eiko, I work at an office.
I went to that restroom after beginning to feel sick on my walk.
Hey, I've told you everything! Let me go already,
It's already past 2:00!
Huh? You're wearing two watches?
My boyfriend is out of the country, so I try
to keep up with the time there as well.
Speaking of wearing two watches,
I was forced to in junior high.
The teacher said I was always late.
Hey man, what's funny about that?
No, it's just that I have tried the opposite for my
students, I have made them remove their watches.
Remove their watches?
Yes...
I wanted them to work without worrying about time.
I've also tried taking the clock down and other things.
What about that band you were talking about, Zama-san?
Yeah, I've been in it since high school.
It's a popular drag band.
Actually, I get calls from my fans often.
I see...
That's right, didn't Yumi-san tell you
to check your mail before this case?
It's probably about more karaoke.
She has no idea about this!
Oh, a convenience store robbery?
Ah, no, I just wanted to speak with Takagi-kun for a moment.
Well, give him my regards about the case, Inspector Megure.
What's that about a convenience store robbery?
Wasn't Takagi-kun working on that other case?
It seems he encountered this robbery after that one.
They've narrowed it down to three suspects.
But their testimonies don't add up.
It doesn't add up? There's only one criminal, right?
I don't know.
Fine, I'll call Takagi-kun myself.
It would be unfair for you to call him.
That's a disadvantage for me.
Well, there's no need to worry.
I'm sure he plans to come here after arresting the robber.
Unless you don't believe in him?
It's not that...
As a police officer, he can't abandon a case like this.
He would be suspended if he did.
He received a pay cut once before, didn't he?
If he's brave enough to leave even with this
being his second disciplinary action,
I'll respect him as a man.
It looks like she's in trouble now!
You shouldn't be acting like this.
Be quiet.
I'm going to the restroom.
Hey, Officers.
How long are you going to hold us here?
It's going to be night soon!
Ah, it'll only be a bit longer.
Hello, is this Yumi-san? I'm busy with something.
No, it's me,
Kudo Shin'ichi.
Conan-kun asked a favor of me.
What'd Conan-kun ask?
First, please try to understand the situation...
By checking your mail immediately.
The only mail I've received today
is what Yumi-san sent earlier...
"Miwako is having a marriage arrangement..."
SATO-SAN IS WHAT!?
I didn't think you had seen it yet.
But it's alright, calm yourself.
We still have some time before sunset, and the
arrangement is only taking place in Haido City.
W-What about sunset?
Officer Sato only agreed to the arrangement with one condition:
If Officer Takagi solved his case and
showed up before sunset for her,
She wouldn't accept the proposal.
First, tell me all about the case.
Officer Takagi?
Officer Takagi, can you hear me?
Heeey.
I see.
All three witnesses described the robber differently, huh?
This sounds fun.
It isn't fun, Kudo-kun!
Then let's begin with the restaurant master Mamehara-san.