Song by Miki Matsuhashi
A hint to reasoning is to dream.
There's a mystery behind every case!
What's the fate of these two officers?
Will the other half make it in time?
Recognizing that single truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is Detective Conan!
Something's just not right
nani o motometeru no
What are you aiming for?
uso ni narete yuku kyou mo fake your eyes
I'm now used to your lies, and your eyes are fake again.
The start of century
The start of century.
tashika na mono nakute
Nothing's for certain.
hitori ja nakenai yowasa hate myself
I can't cry alone and I'm weak, I hate myself.
shinjiteru itami hikikae ni kono mune umetsukushite
I've buried my heart in exchange for the pain of believing.
ima utsutte iru futari ga eranda michi kuru
The future that's reflecting our choices is coming near.
I think it's only my destiny
I think it's only my destiny.
hateshinai yami no mukou ni
Beyond the infinite darkness...
dare mo shiru koto no nai ashita ga aru
There's an unknown tomorrow awaiting us.
oh yeah, You're going nowhere, It's only destiny
Oh yeah, you're going nowhere, it's only destiny.
ari no mama ni susunde
Keep moving as you are...
ima kanjite iru you're in my heart
I can feel you now, you're in my heart.
You're in my heart
You're in my heart.
After hearing about Officer Sato from Yumi-san,
We found out Officer Sato had agreed
to a marriage arrangement.
It's alright. We've arranged for a way
to save her from the meeting.
But, who's going to do that?
Of course, that'll be Takagi-kun.
I'll send him a message telling him to save her from the
meeting place by making up an emergency case.
Takagi-kun will definitely go.
I'm sure he'll make it in time.
Cruel.
So we all decided to go check on her.
S-Shiratori... The officer...?
Yes, he's with Sato-san now.
Then that means Officer Sato's meeting...
Inspector Shiratori!?
Robber!
Someone stop him!
And so, Officer Takagi took up the robbery case.
After watching the criminal enter the restroom...
They found three.
But they had a problem.
Everyone's stories were different.
Ah, it'll only be a bit longer.
Hello, is this Yumi-san? I'm busy with something.
No, it's me,
Kudo Shinichi.
Conan-kun asked a favor of me.
What'd Conan-kun ask?
First, please try to understand the situation...
By checking your mail immediately.
The only mail I've received today
is what Yumi-san sent earlier...
"Miwako is having a marriage arrangement..."
SATO-SAN IS WHAT!?
I didn't think you had seen it yet.
But it's alright, calm yourself.
We still have some time before sunset, and the
arrangement is only taking place in Haido City.
W-What about sunset?
Officer Sato only agreed to the arrangement with one condition:
If Officer Takagi solved his case and
showed up before sunset for her,
She wouldn't accept the proposal.
First, tell me all about the case.
Officer Takagi?
Officer Takagi, can you hear me?
Heeey.
The Metropolitan Police Detective Love Story 4
(Part 2)
The Metropolitan Police Detective Love Story 4, Part 2!
We've determined that the criminal responsible for
this case is one of these three from the restroom.
Those three are...
First is Zama Hiroshi-san, age 21. Freelancer.
Zama Hiroshi (21)
Freelancer
He is wearing a blue sweatshirt at the moment.
Kamieda Yusuo (32)
School Coach
The next one is Kamieda Yusuo-san, age 32.
He said he is a school coach at a local school.
He's wearing a green sweater.
Koshimizu Eiko (28)
Office Lady
The last one is Koshimizu Eiko-san, age 28, an O.L.
She's wearing a black shirt with a purple top.
When the criminal did this,
He was wearing a helmet and coat.
He was holding a sign that demanded
the owner surrender the money.
So, we followed him to the toilet and found his clothes.
But there was an old man that saw him up close.
The old man said the robber was a woman with a blue shirt.
There was a girl in a shop that saw the criminal from a shop
window, and said he was wearing a green shirt under his coat.
And the restaurant manager said the
suspect was wearing a black shirt.
The girl said it was a male of about 180cm,
but we're not sure about the shirt's color.
I see.
Everyone's description of the criminal is different, huh?
This sounds like fun.
It isn't fun, Kudo-kun.
Then let's begin with the restaurant master Mamehara-san.
How did you know the master's name?
I know him well.
Oh, Officer! What is it?
Did you catch the criminal?
No, it's not that...
Take the master outside.
Hurry!
Hey, hey... Where are we going?
We can talk inside.
Excuse me, just wait...
What is it?
Your glasses turned into sunglasses!
Yeah.
The master's glasses are likely the type that take 15 seconds
to tint themselves after being exposed to UV light.
I just remembered that the master
I know doesn't even wear glasses.
Well, I forgot about the glasses.
I only started wearing them because it's today's fashion.
Then is it possible that when you saw the robber your tinted
glasses changed whatever the color was to black?
But, I'm sure the robber was about 170cm tall.
But a girl that saw the robber claimed he was at least 180cm tall.
From which store did she see the robber?
It was from a clothing store about
one-hundred meters from here.
Ah, that store...
Could you go there now?
That girl said the robber's head was
sticking out from the crowd, right?
Yeah.
The sidewalk leads from the subway exit to the bus stop.
It often gets rather crowded.
If other people were walking toward you,
how would you walk, Officer Takagi?
Well, I would avoid running into them.
But what if that slows your pace?
I would get off of the sidewalk...
And walk on the curb.
I-I see!
If the criminal was running on the curb,
she would think he was 180cm tall!
Puzzle.
This is a jigsaw puzzle, Officer Takagi.
Sometimes if a piece doesn't fit at first,
You can change the angle and make it fit perfectly.
Be sure to remember that their testimonies
are crucial to completing the puzzle...
And showing us the true face of our criminal.
Conan-kun is taking awhile.
I'll go check on him.
Did Conan-kun eat something bad?
For breakfast we had eggs and toast...
For lunch...
That man...
I've seen him before.
Huh? It wasn't the person you knew?
But where was it?
Next is the old man that ran into the criminal.
If my reasoning is correct, he has the key to this case.
Hey, Kudo-kun.
Yes?
Why... Why are you helping me so much?
Well, that's because...
Conan-kun?
Oh no, it's Ran!
Conan-kun, are you alright?
Make sure you talk to the old man again!
And then you'll know who the criminal is!
Hey, w-wait...
Let's see, the old man said...
That the robber was a woman with a blue shirt under her coat.
But the only one in blue is Zama-san.
I see, it's the piercing. He thought Zama-san
was a woman because of his piercing.
No, the robber was wearing a helmet at the time...
He couldn't have seen them.
Then why a woman...
Damn, there's only forty minutes until
sunset. If I don't hurry, Sato-san will...
The clock...
That's right, then...
I see! I see it now!
I understand! I understand who the criminal is!
It's getting darker out, huh?
Oh, I guess so.
Sato-san, it isn't that I don't trust you...
But if Takagi-kun doesn't show, I'll need a confirming kiss.
A kiss?
A kiss of engagement.
You mean the two of us...
You mean us, Shiratori-kun?
Yeah, that's right.
If Takagi-kun doesn't show, we'll be getting married anyway.
Well, you did give your word, right?
Yes, of course.
What's taking so long, Takagi-kun?
Hurry and capture that criminal!
Ah, Takagi-san,
Did you discover anything?
No, nothing. The three testimonies still don't add up.
A woman with a blue shirt...
A man with a green shirt that's 180cm tall...
A person in black that's about 170cm tall...
Based on this...
We can't pick out just one of these three as the culprit.
Well, we can relax. It's still just before 15:00.
Hey, hey, what are you talking about?
Your watch must be broken.
It's past 16:30...
I knew it was you.
Takagi-san...
The restaurant master said he saw a black
undershirt through his tinted glasses.
And the girl said 180cm because she saw
the robber running on the curb.
If you take black clothing and 180cm away,
what we know about the robber is that...
It's a man of 170cm wearing green.
So Kamieda-san, it's you.
But, the old man that was knocked down
said it was a woman in blue.
Right, but we forgot to take into account that he is elderly.
Look outside, Miwako-san.
The sunset is beautiful.
We have about thirty minutes to sunset.
Takagi-kun...
Takagi-kun?
Takagi-kun!
Takaaggiiiiii!
I see! He's elderly.
It makes sense for him to call green "blue."
Right, indigo, aqua, green...
They all used to be called green, right?
It hit me when I remembered you were a school teacher.
It's because you don't want your students to determine the time.
You wear your watch on the inside of your wrist,
So only you can tell time in class, right?
I see.
The old man thought the robber was a woman
because he saw the watch like this, right?
Right, after becoming tired of changing it before and after class,
He decided to always wear it this way.
That means, after considering all three testimonies...
You're the only one that could be the robber, Kamieda-san.
There's only ten minutes left.
I guess I win then.
Please don't look so depressed.
I don't want to get married right now.
I'm willing to give you all the time you need to prepare.
I'll always be at your side.
Shiratori-kun...
A call?
Oh, Sato-san? It's Takagi.
I've just captured the robber.
The restaurant you're at is five minutes
from here so I think I can make it.
What has taken you so long!?
Jeez.
Um, can I ask you something before I come?
What is it?
Why me?
Why did you pick me to come and rescue you from this?
I just thought you'd come, is that a problem?
Umm... Does that mean...
T-That Sato-san...
Does that mean...
That you...
What the? The criminal is getting away!?
What are you doing, Takagi-san!?
Ah, but... The time...
Takagi-kun:
It's either me, or the robber...
Go after him.
Go, Takagi!
Y-Yes!
Are you alright with that? He won't make it if he goes after him.
Maybe this is our fate.
It'll be my fault for making this deal simply
because of my trust in Takagi-kun.
But a deal's a deal.
Let's get ready...
For the confirmation.
Suspect arrested at 16:46.
The money, it was for the money.
For my divorce...
I needed money for it...
Jeez...
I'm too far away now...
From the Minatorou restaurant...
It's of no use...
Takagi-san!
You did it, Takagi-san!
No, I've lost it.
That thing I wanted the most...
What is it? Let's do this.
Just do it already.
O.K.
I can see it...
Are you alright, Miwako-san?
Take time to clear your mind.
There's no longer a wall between us.
Here we go, here we go...
I'm gonna stop them!
What are you doing?
Hey, Araide-sensei.
Come here.
I'll take care of the rest!
Takagi-san, go!
Aren't you an officer? Then act like an officer
and don't give up until the time is up, Takagi!
Well, the sun has almost set.
Are you ready?
Yeah.
What is it, Conan-kun?
Did you know...
Not until now...
Did I realize...
How important he has become to me...
H-H-Hey, stop!
To realize this so late...
I'm no officer.
It's time to stop being one.
Bye bye, Takagi-kun.
Secondary Inspector Sato Miwako!
I apologize for disturbing you on
your day off, but there's a case.
Your help is needed!
T-Takagi-kun?
He came, Officer Takagi!
Guess it isn't happening.
Takagi-kun! Huh? Takagi-kun?
Conan-kun?
Officer Takagi um...
Officer Takagi ran toward the exit just then.
Jeez, what's this about?
Hey, Miwako.
Miss?
Aoi Aoi Kono Chikyuu ni
Song by Azumi Uehara
shigekiteki na sekai wo matte ita kedo kitto
Me no mae ni aru subete ga Taisetsu na mono nanda ne
Ushinau koto kowagaru nante... Watashitachi mada nani mo iretenai
Oh. yeah yeah yeah
Aoi aoi kono hoshi ni Kagirinai mirai kasane
can make me free Kono mama kodou Kanjite itai
Oh. Yeah yeah yeah
Kono kimochi maiagare Sora to umi Yaki tsukete
Tsuyoi chikara de Kimi ni dakare Tobidashitai
Oh. Yeah yeah yeah
Kono kimochi maiagare Sora to umi Yaki tsukete
Tsuyoi chikara de Kimi ni dakare Tobidashitai
I'm late, the sun has completely set...
I didn't make it...
Sergeant Takagi!
What are you doing? Hurry and get in!
S-Sato-san...
There's a case, right?
Y-Yes!
I have to help them.
Looking at their developing romance...
Reminds me of someone and someone else...
Young Master...
I do feel sorry for Inspector Shiratori, though.