Destiny
Song by Matsuhashi Miki
Destiny could be a hint for our deductions.
And mysterious cases can be unraveled.
A high-profile summertime mystery
In the beautiful scenery, a puzzle is revealed.
Seeking the one and only truth...
With the appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is... Detective Conan!
Geez, you're still drinking.
Just leave me alone. After all, I did win the shopping mall's lottery...
You won't say " We can go on a trip because I won the lottery" again, right?
You have said that countless times already, right Conan-kun?
Yeah. Uncle is a real genius at lotteries, right?
It's no talent, it's a gift!
Even so, was it all right to leave the trip's planning to this kid?
It's okay. Conan-kun always gets things done.
That aside, you're drinking too much, dad.
I know that.
At the Matsue we'll see...
Matsue Castle
Firstly, the famous Matsue castle.
Lake Shinji
And next is Lake Shinji
Apparently, the seven treasures of Lake Shinji are quite delicious.
Jouzan Inari Shrine
What are the seven treasures?
From Lake Shinji, local sea bass, Icefish, lake smelt, Shjimi clams, Moroge shrimps, carp, and eels.
Koizumi Yakumo Residence
Finally, Lafcadio Hearn, or rather, Koizumi Yakumo, right?
Kaizumi Yakumo was the author of kwaidan-ghost stories, right?
Yeah, famous stories like mimi-nashi hoichi or snow woman. (Both are stories from his book Kwaidan.)
Moreover, there are terrifying stories about Matsue as well.
Do you want to hear them, Ran-neechan?
Maybe another time.
Oh, you're scared.
Matsue Lake Hotel
Someone will be with you in a moment, Mouri Kogoro-sama.
Please wait there briefly.
You'll be served some tea and japanese confectionery there.
Thanks
Wow, it's Lake Shinji.
The lake looks beautiful from here.
We will be able to watch them catch shijimi clams tomorrow morning.
Even the place for catching shijimi has a poetic verse.
Both watch Shijimi catching and parting ways as the autumn passes by.
Watch yourself, Shina-san.
But, sensei...
Pardon me for being rude, but that should be hamaguri rather than shijimi.
Hamaguri?
Yes. The accurate verse should be,
Both watch Hamaguri catching and parting ways as the autumn passes by.
In this connection, many shops at Hasamichi are called ogaki.
You do know better.
Matsue is a city with Japanese confectionery that rivals Kanazawa and Kyoto.
We better buck up at Osaka or else.
Yeah...
Yagisawa Takumi-san runs a Japanese confectionery shop in Osaka.
Yagisawa Takumi (32)
Japanese Confectionery Shop Owner
Well, I only took over my father's shop that's all.
Oh, a young master.
It looks really delicious. Itadakimasu!
I'll have mine too.
The proper...
thing after eating is to brush your teeth properly.
He is Shiina Ryousuke-san, an elite dentist.
Shiina Ryousuke (38)
Dentist
Pleased to meet you.
And the lady there is Kawaguchi Mizuki-san. She's the student in charge of the library.
Kawaguchi Mizuki (27)
Librarian
Y-You are welcome.
You said student?
Oh, pardon me for the late introduction.
Andou Reiko (43)
Junior College Assistant Professor
Department of Japanese Literature
I'm Andou Reiko, I'm doing researsh on Japanese literature at a junior college in Osaka.
I see, you're all specialists.
We are all in a reciting linked verse association at Osaka and are here at Matsue on a linked verse related trip.
Linked verse, huh?
And finally, having a conversation over there is Ushikubo Kouzou-san, an investor.
Ushikubo Kouzou (51)
Investor
In other words, its value can still increase, right?
I'm Mouri Kogoro, a detective from Tokyo.
Mouri Kogoro!
Mouri Kogoro-san... that famous detective?
You're famous detective, are you making some money?
No, not really.
Don't be so modset.
Say... I work for Naniwa business at the Okayama office, Tomonaga.
I once worked with Ushikubo-san...
Hey, you. Isn't it about time you left?
Yeah, that's right. Well, I like haiku and write a lot of poems.
So I couldn't help joining in. Well then Mouri-san, have a good trip.
Reiko sensei, what's that big book about?
Ah, this?
It's a dictionary of naming objects. I use it when composing linked verses.
Would you like to have a look?
Yea.
It sure looks interesting. Oh... look at these shoes.
They're similar to Shiina-san shoes, aren't they?
Oh, these are hiking shoes.
Well, mine are a bit different from the genuine ones though.
Your shoes have hooks and marks, they look really expensive!
Even though you're broke.
Yeah, would you like to join us for dinner, Mouri-san?
Yeah, it's rare to listen to the adventures of Japan's most famous detective.
Japan's most famous?!...
I'll accept your offer to join you for dinner then.
Hot springs are great, aren't they?
That's right. Feels like all the strain on your body melts away in the water.
Indeed.
Say, Yagisawa-san.
What was the linked verse you were talking about earlier?
Well, to put it in simple terms, it's a game where a few people connect each other's verses.
For example, if Conan-kun leads with a 5, 7 and 5 syllable verse,
following that verses, the next person will create a verse of 7 and 7 syllables.
And after that, someone else would create a verse of 5, 7 and 5 syllables.
And like that, the verses keeps connecting,
Is it different from haiku poetry?
The first verse of 5, 7, and 5 syllables is called hokku.
Thinking about it like this, it differentiates from haiku, doesn't it?
And it helps get into the mood to.
I see.
Say Yagisawa-san, what kind of verses do you like?
I like humorous verses.
What about you Shiina-san?
Me? Let me think...
I like emotional verses.
Things like a father's love for his daughter.
Shiina-san, pardon me but do you have kids?
A daughter, who was taken by my wife when she left the house.
Oh... I'm sorry.
Don't mind. It was my fault for being in debt, that was unavoidable.
You have my gratitude.
That's amazing, Yagisawa-san.
Now Mouri-san. Don't hold back.
Thanks
By the way, have you decided on your plans for tomorrow?
Oh yeah, about that, Conan-kun, have you heard of the Yaegaki shrine?
I heard about it from Reiko-sensei in the bath earlier. Shall we go tomorrow?
Tomorrow morning we're going to Tiffany Teien at the Art Museum. And in the afternoon...
Oh, Yaegaki Shrine.
If I'm not mistaken, it's dedicated to the gods of marriage and its "Mirror Pond" is popular for love fortune telling.
Yes.
Then how about all going together? Besides Ushikudo-san, we're all single.
That's true. But Ran-san already has someone she likes, right?
We're going to the Matsue hot springs in the morning, there should be a bus to Yaegaki Shrine from there.
You can go to Teien Art Museum in the afternoon.
L-Let's do that then.
Geez, you're both acting like you're in love.
Now, now...
Hey, Reiko sensei.
Yes.
Can we decide on the place we're doing our first verse?
That's right.
On that note, Shiina-san please.
Yes.
What is about the first verse place?
We decide on the places to compose our linked verse through a drawn lot.
Oh, hokku is the first line of a linked verse's 5, 7, and 5 verse, right?
Right. It's a general rule to compose from the scenery before us.
Oh, that's right.
I'd like to give you this book, Mouri-san.
It's a book I wrote about linked verse.
Out picture is there, too.
Oh... I see. Everyone's gathered.
Alright, done.
Mizuki-san. Could you pass me my hat from there?
Okay.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Than let's start with Ushikudo-san.
Going by our age, I'm next.
Let me see...
The nearest one is ... which one... which
Now, please open it.
Matsue castle.
Mine's Gassho-ji.
Shiomi Nawate.
That means mine is Teien Art Museum, huh.
Well then, let's leave the hotel at 9 am and return by 11:30 am.
After that we'll shoot off to Tamatsukuri Onsen and the linked verse can...
What is the matter?
I wear contact lenses, and my eyes dry easily.
The eye drops that I always get from the doctor... found it.
I'm a little careless and always lose it somewhere.
Humph, you shouldn't be careless with something so important.
I always have this prepared in my bag.
Oh Sensei, I have a phone call.
He sure is a busy guy.
He probably found another sucker.
Huh?
That man only joined out group to rip us off anyway.
Good grief, what a horrible man.
Get a grip on yourself, Yagisawa-san. The shop is in trouble because of you.
That's...
Now, listen up carefully. Return the loan by the middle of next week.
Otherwise, I'll have to foreclose your shop.
Yes.
Yaegaki Shrine
Mirror pond
Oh, if the paper sinks within 15 minutes, your love wish will come true.
And if it sinks near you, it will be with someone close by.
Yeah.
Well then...
That's why I didn't want to bring her here.
Ran, I don't know how the gods will answer you, but I...
Thanks for waiting, Conan-kun.
That's a cute puppy!
Ran neechan...
Shall we go?
Hello.
Father? what is it?
What, Ushikudo-san is dead?
What!
Karamete Park Section
There's no doubt, it's Ushikubo-san.
So, it's really him.
He appears to have been beaten to death.
He was hit in the back of the head several times with a blunt weapon.
Police Detective Hirose
Matsue Police Station
Shimane Perfecture
Oh! could you be...
I'm Mouri, a detective.
Ushikubo-san Probably protected himself with his left hand when he was attacked.
That's why his watch broke.
10:05 am. That can be assumed to be the time of crime, right?
Yes. And on the corpse's right hand, the index finger is stretched like it is pointing at something.
Bamboo, huh?
It might be his dying message.
A bloodstain on the tip of his finger?
Moreover, it looks like it touched something.
There's no bloodstain here.
One page has been torn off.
"Surge in Autumn, there's no sorrow in my life".
Damn it!
That hurt!
Don't touch the evidence!
Matsue Police Station, Shimane Perfecture
Hello. Thank you for waiting.
I'm Yasugi from the Shimane Perfecture Police Department.
Police Detective Yasugi
Shimane Perfecture Police
Officer Tsubaki
And my subordinate beside me is officer Tsubaki.
Hey, where's that kid?
He was talking to the others before he disappeared somewhere.
Good grief! Geez...
The reason I've gathered everyone here is to ask where you were at 10:05 when Ushikubo-san was murdered.
What do you mean?
Speaking with Mouri-san, we've come to the conclusion that all of you have a motive to murder Ushikubo-san.
It's better to clarify things now since we'll find out eventually anyway.
If that's the case, I was at the Tiffany Exhibition in Teien Art Museum.
To write the first line of my linked verse.
Lewis C. Tiffany - Teien Art Museun
There was a painting named the "Deer's Window" on display in the Museum.
Looking at that, I wrote a verse.
"Even the gods, as soon as they gather and look, the deer's window".
Oh, I remember that guest.
He dropped some coins and leaned over the pond near the fountains in the English garden over there.
What time was that?
I think that was around 11:00 am or so.
Thank you very much.
What are those marks?
I was at Gessho-Ji at that time.
There is a statue of a large tutle there, right?
Yeah.
Gessho-Ji
I found a praying mantis next to that statue.
"The praying mantis is raising a hatchet over the big turtle",
Is what I wrote.
That was right about 10:05 am.
Now that you mention it, he was standing by the statue in deep thought.
Do you know what time that was?
That was around 11:00 am.
11:00 ?...
I was at the samurai estates in Shiomi Nawate.
It was from 10:00 am to 11:00 am. There were no witnesses but I was sitting in the rest area, thinking about my verse.
Samurai's estate
And did you finish it?
Yes.
"The tender trees bend to the sun's light as the autumn colors whirl".
These are autumn leaves.
uh?
Blocked by thick shrubs the autumn leaves cannot be seen from the rest area.
I walked around aimlessly along the lake shore, then I went to the prefecture's art museum.
I didn't write a verse.
Why is that?
This time I was supposed to gather a verse from everyone, and choose which one we would start with.
Shimane Prefecture Art Museum
Nobody remembers seeing sensei here.
That reminds me, that notebook...
had information about various loans in it.
The page that was torn out,
might be something he wrote down when he spoke to that person.
Yes, Ushikubo-san liked it a lot, and had written it down in the notebook.
I understand. Thanks.
Alright. with this, I've got all of the facts.
I can't say that any of you have solid alibis.
By the way, was the weapon found?
We are currently searching the vicinity.
Tentatively, the places that you have all been to will be searched.
In the meantime, please remain in Matsue.
Understood.
Everyone, whether it's to remember Ushikubo-san or not,
I think we should proceed with the linked verse contest as planned.
That's fine. Please, let's do it.
Linked verse contest, huh?
What? I join the linked verse contest?
Yes. Since it's you uncle, you'd know who the culprit is by their behavior, right?
Yeah, well that's...
That's a great idea.
Please do that.
O-Okay.
In all probability, the culprit
is one if these four people.
The linked verse contest, it's a showdown.