Destiny
Song by Matsuhashi Miki
Destiny could be a hint for our deductions.
And mysterious cases can be unraveled.
The Matsue mystery is resolved today.
Many secrets lie in the linked verses.
Seeking the one and only truth...
With the appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is... Detective Conan!
Something's just not right
nani o motometeru no
uso ni narete yuku kyou mo fake your eyes
The start of century
tashika na mono nakute
hitori ja nakenai yowasa hate myself
shinjiteru itami hikikae ni kono mune umetsukushite
ima utsutte iru futari ga eranda michi kuru
I think it's only my destiny
hateshinai yami no mukou ni
dare mo shiru koto no nai ashita ga aru
oh yeah. You're going nowhere, It's only destiny
ari no mama ni susunde
ima kanjite iru you're in my heart
you're in my heart
Matsue Castle
It was a day in autumn, we were at Matsue in Shimane Prefecture on a trip.
At the Matsue hot springs, we met 5 members in a group doing a linked verse trip.
On the following day, one of the members,
Ushikubo Gozou-san, was murdered in front of Matsue Castle.
With the index finger on his right hand extended,
a mysterious message was left behind.
The culprit is probably among the remaining four members.
Linked verse contest, it's a showdown!
The 14th Round of Matsue Tamatsukuri Linked Verse Contest
(Part Two)
Tamatsukuri Hot Springs
And we shall now commence with our gathering.
Tamatsukuri Shirasuna Inn
This time we will be reciting a total of 14 linked verses.
And to make it easy for our guest, Mouri-san.
We shall recite in a Shiritori manner.
Shiritori is it?
Yes, you only have to follow a few rules,
but besides that, you can do anything you want.
Andou Reiko (43)
Junior College Assistant Professor
Deprtment of Japanese Literature
First, we shall begin with an opening verse with 5, 7 and 5 syllables,
And then with two lines of 7 and 7 syllables, then one of 5, 7 and 5, and keep repeating the pattern.
But please, be careful to not link your verse to the second one before, called Uchikoshi.
Shiina Ryousuke (38)
Dentist
Also please try to include the four seasons in the 14 verses.
Yagisawa Takumi (32)
Japanese Confectionery Shop Owner
Besides that, the first verse will be about the moon, the second and third one, about love,
Kawaguchi Mizuki (27)
Librarian
then the 13th verse should be one with flowers as a theme...
And the final verse, should be a Spring theme to end on a happy note.
That's about it.
Y-Yeah...
Hey, hey, are you alright old man?
Well, we'll give the actual recitation a try.
First, the hokku (first verse). The verses you all wrote are,
for Shiina-san,
"Even the gods, gather to look through the window at a deer".
Yagisawa-san's verse reads,
"The praying mantis is raising a hatchet over the big turtle"
Miauki-san's is,
"The flame that singed the tender trees dances in autumn colors"
And Ushikubo-san's verse,
"Autumn surges, there's no sorrow in my life".
These are all fine verses, but since the reason for this gathering was to ease Ushikubo-san's regret.
I think we should begin with his verse.
Yes.
Then would somebody start off with the "waki"?
What is "Waki"?
That is the second verse.
It is composed with a seasonal word related to the season in the opening verse.
"In the midst oof silence, a fruit now falls".
Ah, it's a good verse proceeding with an honest acceptance of the opening one.
Next is Yagisawa-san.
Yes.
Hey, will father be able to add a good one?
Expecting him to have any aesthetics is a long shot.
I've finished.
"In the moonlight, your next verse would be about Dracula".
How interesting. To use such an extreme character as Dracula is refreshing.
Excuse me. Is that acceptable?
Yes the third verse can be recited wholeheartedly.
From here on, just let your imagination soar.
Imagination soar!?
So, it's Mizuki-san's turn right?
Yes.
"Texts are made in Japan".
For that, instead of "texts", it would be better to use "textbooks", wouldn't it?
"Textbooks are made in Japan".
It would have more words, but that doesn't matter.
Yes.
Mouri-san.
Would you try composing one too? It's a shiritori, so please start with "pan" or "han".
I understand.
This should do it.
"The culprit, will be revealed by the famous detective".
Something like that, right?
Well about that, the use of "famous detective" registers in the same category as "Dracula".
It leaves an impression of reverting back, but that should be fine.
Well then, I'm next.
"The destination that we will arrive at, is the eye of a needle of God's knowledge.
As expected of Reiko-sensei.
Gently discarded the famed detective's enthusiasm.
You're not letting this end so quickly.
I shall recite the next one then.
The anthropoid ape, its face looks just like the child by its side.
That's amusing, isn't it?
We, the seven people here, need some pleasant moments in our life.
What does that mean?
Yagisawa-san. Here you go. It was at the lobby earlier.
I'm such an idiot. I dropped it again? Thanks.
You're welcome.
I see.
Everyone's doing very well.
How is it, Mouri-san?
Well, I'm completely clueless.
Only 3 verses remaining.
If I don't get a breakthrough in the case around now then...
Hey, Mizuki-san.
You said that you composed the verse earlier about autumn colors at the rest area in the samurai mansions, right?
Yes.
That's strange.
I went to the samurai mansions earlier but I couldn't see the autumn colors from the rest area though.
Is that true, Conan?
Yes.
It's possible that I saw the autumn colors from a different place.
A different place?
Where would that be?
Is Mizuki-san the culprit?
But if she isn't, why did she lie?
Could this verse possibly be...
Then, Mizuki-san must have done this for his sake.
Moreover, what does that dying message mean?
So that's what it means.
But, why did that person do such a thing?
I see.
That's what it was!
What? Mouri-san wants me to?
Yes. He said to keep it secret from Inspector Yasugi-san and have Tsubaki-san investigate instead.
Yes. I got it.
If my instincts are right...
the culprit is most likely, that person.
I've figure it out!
W-What exactly did you figure out?
The deceased Mr.Ushikubo's dying message.
His finger wasn't pointing the bamboos. But rather, something else that was before it.
Something else before it?
Something through the thicket that surrounds the promenade, further ahead across the canal.
Right. That's where Mizuki-san composed her peom, it's the samurai mansions.
In other words, the culprit is you, Mizuki-san!
No way!
Hey, Mizuki-san.
The tenth verse is about love isn't it?
In addition, it's on unrequited love.
That reminds me, didn't you play the reed pipe during dinner last night?
Yeah.
I get it. Mizuki-san unrequited love is Yagisawa-kun.
I see. That's why last night Mizuki-san was...
What happend last night?
Ushikubo-san said horrible things to Yagisawa-san.
And Mizuki-san was looking at them worriedly.
W-Wait a minute... That means...
I see. I got it.
Mizuki-san! You were sticking up for Yagisawa-san.
What do you mean, Mouri-san?
In other words, Mizuki-san was worried about the matter between Mr.Ushikubo and Yagisawa-san.
She changed her plans and met with Ushikubo-san at Matsue castle.
And that moment, what she saw was...
T-That's not it. I didn't see anything like that. I just...
Just what?
Mizuki-san.
Mizuki-san. It's better to answer them truthfully.
But sensei...
I think you shoud too.
Sorry for sounding so impertinent.
But, if you really like that person... and really care about him then you should.
I...
I wasn't going to Matsue castle, but instead, I was heading to Gesshoji.
I was worried about Yagisawa-san.
But on my way there, the bus to Matsue castle passed mine and,
I saw Yagisawa-san in that bus.
I set off for Matsue castle immediately.
But when I got to the promenade,
Ushikubo-san had already passed away.
And a little way from his extended finger there was...
After that I hurried back to the Samurai mansions, and I tried to calm down at the rest area.
Then it was time to meet back and I returned to the hotel.
Please hold on. It's true that I went to Matsue castle.
But I didn't do it.
I didn't even go to the promenade.
Then where in Matsue castle did you go to?
At Jozan Inari Shrine.
That's where a lot of fox statues are, right?
I was asked by Ushikubo-san to meet there.
I was at Gensshoji for about 30 minutes.
When Ushikubo-san sent me a text message on my cellphone.
It says, " Come immediately to the Inari temple at Matsue castle".
It was about 5 minutes past 10 when I got to the temple.
After that I waited for 15 minutes, Ushikubo-san didn't show up.
And I couldn't get through to his phone.
With no other choice, I returned to Gesshoji,
and composed my verse on the big turtle.
If that's the case, why was your eye medication at the crime scene?
I don't know.
But that's the truth, Police officer.
If you think I'm lying, pleses check Ushikubo-san's cellphone.
We have checked all the records on his cellphone.
A record of the text message you mentioned wasn't there.
No way!
What about his reserve phone?
Ushikubo-san said he has a spare phone in his bag.
We've checked through all his luggage, and there was only one cellphone.
Yagisawa-san, sure you didn't steal Ushikubo-san's reserve phone and sent yourself a text message?
I didn't.
Detective Yasugi.
We found the murder weapon.
What!
It was thrown in the Gesshoji pond.
The special police department examined this raincoat
and found some blood identical to the victim's blood.
And on this raincoat...
Yagisawa!
This settles it, right?
This can't be!
Shall we continue this at the station?
I didn't do it, detective.
This must be a mistake.
Yagisawa-san.
What an unbelievable linked verse contest this has turned ot to be.
Let's end here for today.
That's right.
Hey, let me recite the next verse.
I begin with the "chi" sound, right?
Done.
"Chocolate cakes, quickly give them to me".
That won't do. That doesn't cut it as a linked verse.
Not true.
From this point, you can associate ideas about chocolate cakes, right?
It's a child-like fun verse.
Next is a verse with flowers theme, right?
Shiina-san, please form one.
Hurry up.
It's a verse that starts with "i" sound.
Compose a beautiful verse.
Okay.
I'm done.
"Someday, my daughter and I will go to temple with flowers".
How is that?
Hey, hey...
That's strange.
That verse was the same as the one Uncle Mouri recited to me earlier.
Here.
Father, when did you compose that verse?
Well, I...
oh-no-this-is bad...
Father?
Ran, actually that verse wasn't composed by me,
The man we met at the lobby yesterday, Tomonaga-san from the business district composed it.
That was what Mr. Ushikubo had written in his notebook.
Shiina-san, you were certain that it was a verse that Ushikubo-san composed weren't you?
You could not forgive the fact that such a crude man could compose such a beautiful verse.
That's why you tore it out from his notebook, right?
Aftre murdering Mr. Ushikubo.
You added codes in the verses that you recited.
The 7th word from the 7th verse, 9th word of the 9th verse,
and the 11th word from the 11th verse. It says
I am the culprit.
And then, you recited provoking verses while subconsciously confessing that it was you.
Adding your message in your verses,
ridiculing both me and the police, chuckling away.
Judging from that part of your personality, I thought that with the appropriate conditions,
you would definitely recite the verse stolen from Mr. Ushikubo, as your own.
With the simple reason that you really like this verse.
I like verses with emotions.
Like the love of a father for his daughter.
And the required conditions were, having Yagisawa-san taken into custody as the suspect,
and connecting the 13th verse on flowers from the verse prior to it in shiritori manner.
And was that the verse you told Conan about earlier?
Just as I had predicted, you read the verse you stole from Ushikubo-san.
As if to personally display your victory.
The codes in the verses were just a prank, that's all.
Moreover, last night Ushikubo-san had shown me the verse I just recited.
Hold on a minute, I have an alibi.
Alibi?
Yes.
Around 10:05 when I was at the English Park in Teien Art Museum,
a lady on duty found the parents of a lost boy. I just remembered this.
You can know something like that easily by setting up some video cameras,
That was under the hedge.
Conan found some tripod marks.
You had gone to Teien Art Museum in the morning,
and set up a video camera by the pond.
With Mr. Ushikubo's spare cellphone that you had stolen, you sent a text message to Yagisawa-san.
Then you went to Matsue castle and murdered Ushikubo-san.
After that, you placed Yagisawa-san's eye medication near Ushikubo-san's finger.
Then throw the raincoat and the murder weapon at Gesshoji.
Retrived the video from Teien Art Museum.
And nonchalantly you returned to the hotel.
That's quite an interesting deduction, Mouri-san.
But unfortunately...
If you are talking about proof, I have some.
Ushikubo-san's dying message.
That wasn't pointing to the bamboo, nor to the samurai's mansion.
The message was the number, '1'.
What does that mean?
Ran, what was the first verse of linked verse called again?
Hokku?
Then, Detective Tsubaki, what is the result of your observation?
Yes.
From these shoes of Mr.Shiina. On the left foot, topmost left hook, we confirmed
Mr.Ushikubo's streched bloody index finger fingerprints.
In other words, his dying message was the hook on your shoe.
Your heart was probably taken in by the verse in Mr.Ushikubo notebook,
and didn't notice him touching the hook on your shoe.
I lose, Mouri-san.
I killed Ushikubo.
But, why did you suspect me?
My first suspiction were when you were drawing a lots last night.
Normally, the one who created the lots would draw last.
But, you went on the second draw.
Next, according to age line up, will be my turn.
You manipulated the lots at that time for Mr.Ushikubo to pick an easy place to be murdered,
and gave yourself the furthest location where you could create your alibi easily.
As expected of Japan's best detective.
The motive for killing Mr.Ushikubo must be...
Yeah, for tricking us out of our money, I just couldn't forgive him.
Even then, you do not have the right to pass judgment on him.
Yeah, I know.
I know that...
The only one who can pass judgment on him is God.
And for the sake of telling me that, the God in Izumo must have called you here.
I'm glad.
Nagatama Bridge
Mizuki-san's feelings seem to have reached Yagisawa-san.
That's right.
That's right, Reiko sensei.
There's one verse left for the linked verses.
Then, from my feelings of gratitude for Mouri-san and a greeting to Matsue,
"Lafcadio Hearn, the spring of his smile".
That's wouderful verse!
Right father?
Yeah.
L-af-ca-?
Lafcadio Hearn.
That's Koizumi Yakumo, wasn't it?
Koizumi...
With that, it's more like,"Lafcadio Hearn, the spring of his amazement".