Even fate can be used as a hint for reasoning.
Seeing through the most mysterious cases!
Even if the money is thrown into the offering box...
Sinful desires will never be fulfilled!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Created by
Gosho Aoyama
"Detective Conan"
Serialized in Shogakukan's
"Weekly Shonen Sunday"
Planning
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Character Design
Masatomo Sudo
Art Director
Yukihiro Shibutani
Director of Photography
Takehisa Ogawa
Sound Director
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
Music
Katsuo Ono
Opening Theme
Performed by
Miki Matsuhashi
Lyrics
Satomi Asakoshi
Music
Kazunobu Majima
Arrangement
Toshiya Shimizu
Editor
Terumitsu Okada
Story Editor
Jun'ichi Iioka
Color Key
Mayumi Hirade
Executive Producer
Hiroaki Kobayashi
Planning Support
Shin'ichiro Tsuzuki
Toyohiko Okuyama
Mitome Asai
Tsubasa Suzuki
Director
Yasuichiro Yamamoto
Producers
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Masahito Yoshioka
(Tokyo Movie)
In the dead of the night...
After everyone had already fallen asleep...
At 2:15 AM...
The earthquake happened.
Earthquake in the Dead of Night, West of Tokyo
My my, the earthquake last night surprised me.
This is...
Hey, you, are you alright?
Bells?
Could the bells that fell down due to the earthquake last night have hit his head?
Offering
Someone broke into the offering box.
That means this man is...
The Mysterious Punishment From Heaven
An offering box robber?
Yes.
This morning at Teitan Temple.
Won't those robbers be really cursed?
All right!
As the detective boys, let's catch the culprit!
Hey, that's not it!
The culprit has already...
Already?
What!
So the culprit was arrested by the police just like that?
That's why you should listen to what others have to say till the end, Genta-kun.
But is such a coincidence possible?
While robbing the offering box, there was an earthquake, and the "clang-clangs" accidentally fell...
And knocked him unconscious.
What's "clang-clang"?
Come on, Conan-kun.
The bells at the temples are called that, aren't they?
Don't you know that?
Yeah, I see.
This was certainly a divine punishment, humans aren't allowed to do evil deeds, that's all this was.
But, what a dump robber that was, right?
Really, what a clumsy fool!
Right, Conan-kun?
Conan-kun?
Why did the culprit target such a run down temple?
What do you mean by that?
Look around.
How troublesome, we don't have any money for the repairs!
Even if he managed to rob the offering box, there wouldn't be much money in there, right?
That's true.
I could understand if he had targeted Beika Temple instead.
Many worshipers pay homage there.
Maybe he didn't know about Beika Temple.
That's right.
The culprit must have come from far away.
Besides, there may be other incidents that have occurred due to the earthquake.
That's right.
There may be other people who are troubled by it.
In that case, we're not finished yet, right?
All right!
Start of the Detective Boys investigation!
Yeah!
What was that?
A scream!
Takeo-san, what's wrong?
Hang in there, Takeo-san!
Takeo-san, wake up!
Takeo-san?
Genta!
Call an ambulance.
Takeo-san, are you all right?
Stay strong, Takeo-san!
I see.
So the two of you are getting married next month, right?
Togawa Yuki (25)
Takenaka Takeo (33)
Yes, we were supposed to meet up at the matchmaker's place today.
But he didn't make it to the appointment, and he wasn't answering his phone.
So you got worried and came here to see if he was all right?
Yes.
When I got here, he had already collapsed on the floor.
I was really surprised.
How are your injuries?
Thankfully. this is just a mild cerebral concussion.
Nothing seemed off during the exam.
That's good to know.
I know it's sudden, but please let me hear the details from the time Takenaka-san was attacked.
Yes.
Last night I got home late after a meeting.
I got in after the earthquake at around...
2:30 AM.
What a mess!
Must be from the earthquake.
Good grief.
Who are you?
Hold on!
You're not getting away!
No way!
He died?
You must be kidding me!
Wait...
So the culprit ran off when he thought he had killed you?
Probably, but actually I was only unconscious.
The culprit's quite scatterbrain, isn't he?
We keep coming across idiotic culprits today, don't we?
That's true.
Are there any other damages?
The 200,000 yen I had in my pants was stolen.
Was it only cash?
Yes.
I'm at a loss.
It's hard to track cash!
Say, is it impossible to catch him?
Rest assured, it'll be all right.
It'll be fine once we get his fingerprints.
But, the culprit wore gloves.
First, I'll get information from the neighborhood.
Good work, Takagi-san.
Otani-kun, what's up?
There was an on-site investigation at Teitan Temple.
I heard about that.
The offering box robber, right?
Urasawa Rokusuke (35)
He's that clumsy robber.
He even looks the part.
That's mean of you two to say such things!
The criminal, Urasawa said that he lives near here at Block 4.
Block 4!
He's a wimp, and doesn't learn from experience.
We've already caught him two times for robbery.
So, he's just a rotten criminal, huh?
I have an assault robbery case on my hands.
What's the matter?
No, nothing...
But, with you on the case, it'll be solved in the blink of an eye, right?
We,ll take our leave then.
Thanks for your hard work!
If only that were true, right?
First, I'll try to find some witnesses.
I'd love to see Detective Takagi solve this case.
He blundered in a case recently and was punished for it, too.
He'll be fine.
This time it's a simple case with no hidden tricks in it, right Conan?
Conan?
What are you doing, Conan?
As I suspected, it's strange.
What's strange?
That offering box robber, Urasawa.
Look closely at this map.
Block 4 is right next to Beika Temple.
With him living nearby, for him to specifically target the distant...
Not to mention unpopular, Teitan Temple...
Beika Temple
Teitan Temple
Isn't it unnatuaral?
That's not important, is it?
He received divine punishment because he tergeted that run down temple.
Divine punishment?
The "clang-clangs".
At other temples, they don't fall off just from an earthquake, right?
Don't tell me...
No, if we think along these lines, then it's clear why it has to be Teitan Temple.
And if that's the case, then...
Hey, Conan!
It should be here.
If my deductions are right...
Then on the way Teitan Temple, there must be...
I'm sure!
What's the matter, Conan?
Why did you take off so suddenly?
Found it!
Conan-kun, could this possibly be...
Yeah, very likely.
This probably belongs to Takenaka-san's attacker.
You did it, Conan! Great job!
Let's tell Detective Takagi-quickly.
Let's do that.
But, the essential piece isn't here.
He couldn't have had it on him, either.
I see.
It's in there.
Hey, hey, Mr.Priest. Hurry up! Hurry.
If it was mistaken as an offering, there's no doubt I'll be punished!
I know, all right.
I'm opening it up now.
This is...
There it is.
Thank you, Mr.Priest.
But this is amazing, isn't it Mr.Priest?
I-It's the first time som many offerings have been made.
Beika Station
How did it go, Detective Takagi?
Yeah, there's no doubt.
This is definitely the 200,000 yen stolen from Takenaka-san.
The victim, Takenaka-san's fingerprints are found on them, too.
As we thought...
But, along with it, unexpected fingerprints were found as well.
An unexpected person?
It's Urasawa, that offering box robber.
That means he was the culprit, right?
What a terrible guy.
Hold on, Genta-kun.
Wasn't Takenaka-san attacked at around 2:30 AM?
Yeah.
But the earthquake happened at 2:15 AM, right?
Yes.
Then wouldn't he have actually been unconscious at the temple at 2:30 AM?
That's right.
He was hit by the "clang-clangs" that were loosened by the earthquake, and lost consciouness.
Yes.
It's impossible for an unconscious man to commit a crime elsewhere.
What exactly is going on here?
What should I do next?
And here I thought it was just a simple case of robbery.
Detective Takagi.
Hey, Detective Takagi!
How about asking Inspector Megure for help?
I think that would be a wise decision.
You must be kidding!
I'll solve an easy case like this myself.
But...
Right, Conan?
Conan?
Conan-kun?
Yes, Takagi speaking.
Inspector Megure!
Uhm...Inspector Megure, actually...
Don't sound so pitiful!
Otani-kun told me the situation on the phone.
However Takagi, this is a chance to prove yourself, isn't it?
So don't complain!
But, Inspector Megure...
You are an excellent officer.
I know that more than anyone else.
What you need is more confidence.
Confidence?
Yes, confidence.
You can definitely slove this.
Stand proud, Detective Takagi!
Okay.
All right!
I'll be waiting for good news, then.
Thank you, Inspector Megure!
Hey, what's with Detective Takagi?
He seems suddenly rejuvenated.
He just got a call from Inspector Meguri.
He encouraged Detective Takagi to do his best.
Really!
Hey, Detective Takagi...
What is it?
Did that Urasawa guy really get hurt at 2:15 AM?
What are you saying?
The earthquake happened at that time, though.
It was then that the "clang-clang" fell on his head and knocked him unconscious.
But, nobody saw that, right?
That's right.
It's all just based on what Urasawa said.
Now that you mention it...
All right! let's retrace the steps of Urasawa's actions around the crime time.
We'll go with the assumption that Urasawa attacked Takenaka-san.
Yes.
Urasawa hates working and was going thourgh some difficulties in his life.
Urasawa's Apartment
With that in mind, he started planning to steal some money.
Urasawa walked around looking for possible homes to brake into.
And then...
He settled on targeting Takenaka-san's house.
But why did he pick this house?
There are so many houses just like this.
It's probably because this house was unattended, right?
But a night, you can't tell if it's unattended, or if the residents are just asleep, can you?
That's...
He most likely picked it by chance...
That's right. His choice doesn't matter, does it?
No, that's not true.
There has to be a reason... There's certainly somthing.
Yes.
There is definitely a significant reason.
Why?
How did Urasawa know that Takenaka-san's house was unattended?
Do your best, Detective Takagi.
Did something happen in the house at that time?
Can't be.
It was unattended, so nothing should have happened.
That's right.
The earthquake!
What?
While Urasawa heppened to pass by this street, the earthquake happened.
A great earthquake in the middle of the night.
All of the residents must have panicked and woken up in their houses, then turned their light on.
But, only Takenaka-san's house remaind dark.
That's how Urasawa knew that there wasn't anyone in there, and broke in.
But while he was looking for precious things, Takenaka-san returned home.
Man, what a mess!
Must be from the earthquake.
Good grief.
Who are you?
Hold on!
You are not getting away!
No way!
He died?
You must be kidding me!
Urasawa thought he had killed Takenaka-san, and ran away in a panic.
At any rate, he had to dispose of his disguse and gloves somewhere.
At that time, having found the garbage collection point, Urasawa threw them here.
This was done so that the evidence wouldn't be found.
The culprit must have been terribly anxious at that time, right?
Very likely.
He's a wimpy guy.
Even though it was a misunderstanding he did think he killed a man.
He was definitely in a bind, right?
The police would be searching thoroughly if it were a murder.
And he didn't have an alibi.
Yeah.
Alibi?
Alibi!
Urasawa must have thought of it!
"If only I could build an alibi, then..."
I see.
Urasawa must have discovered it here.
The bells that had fallen off.
He then disquised himself as a box offering robber.
In other words, his aim wasn't to rob the box offerings, but to be cought as a robber here.
This was done to have an alibi when Takenaka-san was attacked.
I see.
Amazing, Detective Takagi.
You can do it when you try!
But why give the money he worked so hard to steal as an offering?
He had no choice.
A box offering robber couldn't possibly have 200,000 yen in cash on him.
I see.
Besides, could it possibly be...
I have committed a murder.
But no matter what, I don't want to be in prison for decades.
Somehow...
Please, somehow dear God, save me!
He maybe made a wish.
Made a wish?
What!
Yeah, that might be possible.
Urasawa was totally desperate after all.
And then Urasawa...
It's exactly as you've said, officer.
Takagi-san!
In other words, you tried to cover up a crime with another crime, right Urasawa?
But, anybody would think that way too, right?
Robbing an offering box is a petty crime to be cought for.
That's a cheap to pay for escaping a major crime like murder.
Right?
Idiot!
Listen up, Urasawa.
It doesn't matter whether it's a petty or a major crime, all crimes  are unforgivable!
That's right.
I'm sorry.
Oh, Takagi-kun.
Inspector Megure!
You did a splendid job solving that case, didn't you?
Inspector Megure, I'll continue building my confidence as an officer.
Is that so?
It's all thanks to your encouragement, Inspector.
Thank you very much!
Well then, Inspector Megure.
I'll take my leave.
Yeah...
I have no idea what he was talking about, that Takagi.
Don't be shy, you caring boss.
Caring boss!
You shy person!
Well, at least it all worked out, right?