Even fate can be used as a hint for reasoning.
Seeing through the most mysterious cases!
Today is a mysterious kidnapping case.
The meaning of English is difficult!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Created by
Gosho Aoyama
"Detective Conan"
Serialized in Shogakukan's
"Weekly Shonen Sunday"
Planning
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Character Design
Masatomo Sudo
Art Director
Yukihiro Shibutani
Director of Photography
Takehisa Ogawa
Sound Director
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
Music
Katsuo Ono
Opening Theme
Performed by
Miki Matsuhashi
Lyrics
Satomi Asakoshi
Music
Kazunobu Majima
Arrangement
Toshiya Shimizu
Editor
Terumitsu Okada
Story Editor
Jun'ichi Iioka
Color Key
Mayumi Hirade
Executive Producer
Hiroaki Kobayashi
Planning Support
Shin'ichiro Tsuzuki
Toyohiko Okuyama
Mitome Asai
Tsubasa Suzuki
Director
Yasuichiro Yamamoto
Producers
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Masahito Yoshioka
(Tokyo Movie)
Wow, that was so super-cool!
And the animals were so cute!
I liked the part with Leon the white lion the best.
Leon is the star of the show.
Right! I got him on a keychain! See?
Wow, that's great!
Cute, isn't it?
Haibara-san and I bought them at the gift shop before the show! Right?
Yeah...
Guess now I know your taste in jewelry.
Oh, I think I've got much better taste...
than the guy who never tires of reading the same pulp mystery novels over and over.
Leave me alone.
Who's the geezer in the middle of the crowd?
Ah...
That's Randy Hawk-san. He's the sponsor of the Animal Show.
He's from Oklahoma, in the south of the United States.
He started raising exotic animals as a hobby after he made a fortune from oil.
He passed his love of animals on to his children, Paul and Annie,
which was how they started travelling the world with their circus.
See, he's on the last page of the souvenir book.
Since he retired, he's been touring the world with the animal show and visiting zoos.
When asked why he never travels with bodyguards,
he said, "The Hawks have always been cowboys! We can look after ourselves!"
That was when he was on a TV special.
He's pretty fluent in Japanese too.
Hawk-san, may we have a word?
Y-You're wrong!
I'm not Hawk-san!
You're joking again...
Is it true you donate half the money from the show to zoos around the world?
No, I'm...!
How does it feel to be back in Japan after three years?
Please say something, Hawk-san!
Hawk-san!
Please, Hawk-san!
I can't give answers to all of your questions at the same time!
The Man From Chicago
(Part 1)
I guess even a tough cowboy has trouble with the press.
Talk about conceited.
We couldn't even have bodyguards if we wanted them.
Serves him right if he gets mobbed.
Come on, why don't we help him?
Her Majesty's cowboy, brought to a standstill by a herd of cattle.
Like I've just been saying, I'm...!
Oh, there you are, Uncle Thomas!
T-Thomas?
This person isn't Hawk-san?
Right.
He's my grandpa's friend, an English teacher.
That's right!
Hey, let's go, Uncle Thomas!
O-Oh...
You promised to have lunch with us, remember?
Hey, hurry!
Thank you very much!
You saved me.
People often tell me I look like Hawk-san,
but this is the first time a crowd of reporters mistook me for him.
So you should've put on a disguise.
That'd make him look even more suspicious.
But you like Paul and Annie's Animal Show that much?
Oh yes! Their show is the best.
So...
I just had to buy one of these. That's why I came to Japan!
We bought that too.
But they sell those keychains all over the world.
You didn't have to come to Japan to buy one.
Oh no, look at the back of the keychain.
"In Japan" is written there. This version is only sold here!
I see. So it's a collector's item.
But it's a bloody shame I got involved in that bother.
I missed meeting up with the friend I was planning to see after the show.
You didn't happen to see a man with long hair, did you?
No... The place was packed.
By the way, how did you know...
that this person wasn't Hawk-san?
By how he spoke.
H-How he spoke?
What?
When he was saying "I can't" earlier, he didn't say it "kyanto", but "kanto", right?
That's Queen's English.
I thought it was strange for a Southerner,
descended from generations of cowboys,
to have a British accent.
Come to think of it, the Hawk-san I saw on TV was a boisterous man with a strong southern drawl.
And if you look real well at the photo in the booklet,
their faces are different.
But I can't blame the Japanese media for mistaking you for him.
Foreigners often have trouble telling Japanese people apart,
but the Japanese can easily make the same mistake
with foreigners who have similar skin tone and hairstyles.
Oh, how perceptive of you!
My name is James Black.
James Black
And you are?
Conan Edogawa.
A detective.
Edogawa? Conan? Detective?
Conan ain't the only detective!
We're all members of a detective group.
That's right! Look.
Oh! Sherlock Holmes!
Then you must be the Baker Street Irregulars!
Beika Town...
That's the group of kids who gathered information for Holmes.
I was born on Baker Street.
Oh, yes! I ought to give my regards to the irregulars I met today.
Let me treat you all to lunch at a lovely restaurant I know.
Did you come by car?
Yeah, but we don't have room for you with all of us...
OK, OK.
We'll take my rental van.
Wait right here and I'll bring it around.
Yeah.
I warn you, my driving isn't as good as the lunch we'll be having.
It's hard to drive with the steering wheel on the right.
Mister, if you're not used to driving with the wheel on the right,
you don't live in England now, do you?
Oh, yes...
I was born in Holmes' London, but I live in Chicago...
the Windy City, where Capone stormed.
Hey.
You don't feel anything from him?
N-Not really...
I see.
Then that's fine.
Oh, excuse me.
We're from the police.
Is this your car?
Y-Yes...
I rented the car.
Is that so? Actually, this is a stolen car.
Oh no...
We received a report on it a week ago.
We'd like to ask you when and where you rented this car,
along with your name and current residence.
Why don't we talk in our patrol car over there?
That okay with you?
It won't take that long.
What's the matter?
Please get in.
Oh, I have friends waiting for me.
Can I go back and let them know?
Get in.
What?!
I said get in!
He dropped something.
Just a keychain...
Okay, step on it!
Roger.
Ouch!
I've cut my finger.
Sheesh.
I don't want any more trouble out of you.
Y-You...
aren't policemen, are you?
Shut up!
You dumb cowboy.
Y-You've made a mistake! I-I'm—
We just want you to share some of the millions you've made tormenting helpless animals.
Strange...
It's been 40 minutes already.
What's taking him so long?
What could he be doing?
I'm starving!
Let's leave the Doc and go look for him.
Sounds good.
There aren't a lot of parking lots within walking distance.
Let's go, Haibara-san.
Sure.
This is the parking lot, isn't it?
James-san!
Hey! Where are you?
Huh? I ain't looking for a cat...
James-san!
Found it!
This must be his van!
Look! There's a stuffed Leon on the dashboard!
But nobody's inside.
The door's open, and the keys are here...
Are you guys looking for someone?
If it's the foreigner with the mustache,
when he was going into his car, two men in coats took him that way.
Hey, Conan!
Conan-kun!
What's wrong?
Hey, did you find him?
C-Conan?
That's a Leon keychain, isn't it?
Is it James-san's?
If it is, perhaps he got into another car from here.
Come to think of it, he said he was waiting for a friend, didn't he?
Hey, maybe that foreign guy
forgot about us and ran off with that friend of his.
No way!
No, he hasn't forgotten about us.
He's probably in some kind of trouble right now.
Look at this keychain!
There are spots of blood on the "P", the "&" and the "A".
Maybe he figured we'd come looking for him,
and left us a message.
T-That's bad!
W-We've gotta hurry...
And tell the police!
But...
What is it?
What is "P & A"?
That was too easy.
The only question now...
is how much his children are willing to pay.
Five hundred million, minimum.
This guy's so loaded he's able to give money away to zoos.
Hey, thank your buddy for fixing up this old sedan to look like a real cop car.
And let's not forget to thank our brave cowboy friend
for strolling around without a bodyguard.
I...
I'm not Hawk!
I'm James Black! You have the wrong person!
James?
After being a cowboy, now you want to be a secret agent?
No, no!
That's James Bond!
Well, it doesn't matter either way.
Just stay quiet until we get back to our hideout...
Mr. 007.
Well—
Wait'll you see how we whisk away your money.
That'll be a real circus.
No. You are not the featured cast...
to thrill me most.
Look, how many times do we have to tell you?!
This foreign guy with a mustache and glasses is in trouble!
He may have been kidnapped!
But you didn't actually see him get kidnapped, did you?
And there are a lot of foreign guys here with mustaches and glasses.
If only you had a photograph or something...
We do have a photo!
This is what he looks like!
Ah, Randy Hawk-san?
He's just fine.
He was on the radio a minute ago...
N-No!
He's James-san! He looks a lot like this Randy Hawk-san.
Hey, was that a live radio broadcast?
Y-Yeah.
I think it's still on, isn't it?
Yeah, pretty sure it is.
Shoot.
If these guys mistook James-san for Hawk-san and kidnapped him,
there's a good chance they'll check out the radio show he was supposed to be on!
Hey, now! If they do that, they'll soon figure out...
Right.
Once they realize they have the wrong man,
they may decide it's not worth keeping him alive.
H-Hey!
W-What's the meaning of this?!
Please keep on cheerin' for Paul, Annie, and me, Randy!
How the hell is Randy Hawk on the radio live?!
T-Then who are you?!
I-I already told you!
You have the wrong man!
Damn! I can't believe this!
Hey! What are we gonna do now?
He's seen our faces!
We'll just have to kill him!
Stop it.
You want to drive around the city with a bloody corpse?
We'll blow his brains out once we get to the mountains of Gunma,
like we planned from the start.
After we bury him, we'll plan our next move.
What? If all goes according to plan, no one will ever know.
The cops have no clue who we are,
and they don't know this foreigner was kidnapped in the first place.
Hey, doesn't this seem fishy?
What are you getting at?
I just have this feeling...
that we're being played for fools.
You mind if we go on ahead?
We need this guy to verify a crime scene before dawn.
Well done, Ayumi-chan!
I know where James-san is!
Next Conan:
The Man from Chicago
(Part 2)
Next Conan's Hint: "P and A"
Look forward to the next episode!
Next Conan, it's Part 2 of The Man From Chicago.
You said "Part 2" in Japanese.