The inside of one's heart is a mystery.
Stars and snow shine around the two of us.
With Ayumi's idea, the secret code is broken!
Who is this person full of mysteries?
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
We went to watch Paul & Annie's animal show.
There, we helped James Black-san, a foreigner who'd been confused for somebody else.
But afterwards,
James-san went to get his car to take us to a restaurant,
and suddenly disappeared,
leaving behind his keychain, stained with blood.
P & A?
What's that?
It fell here.
It's probably a clue to the kidnapper that James-san left behind for us.
Look!
He left blood on the "P", "&" and "A" on the keychain!
Well, first things first.
First, we'll take it to the station and check if it really is blood.
Stop by our police box tomorrow.
Um—
H-Hey!
Damn.
If we just knew what "P & A"
was supposed to mean...
P and A make "pa"...
Maybe it's a shop starting with "pa"?
Hey, like a bakery!
pan-ya
Nah.
If he was in a hurry and trying to spell "pa",
he could've left blood on the first two letters of "Paul".
I think we have to separate the P and A to decipher this clue.
"P and A"...
Pink and red...
aka-iro
Pro wrestling and anman...
PC and access...
Pistol and assassin...
Hey.
Maybe it could be "Parking Area"!
Ah, the parking lot!
But how are we supposed to know which parking lot?
Maybe he left us another clue inside the van at the parking lot...
Well, I thought so too, and searched inside already. I didn't find anything.
I guess you're right.
Damn!
We're not getting anywhere.
Our best hope now is to assume they're still nearby,
and look for witnesses!
Okay!
Let's split up and ask around.
See if anybody spotted two men with a foreigner!
If you find something, contact me with your Detective Badge!
Right!
Oh?
What's wrong, Ayumi-kun?
I'm missing my Detective Badge!
S-Seriously?
Maybe you dropped it somewhere?
Strange...
I showed it to James-san just a little while ago...
Oh! Sherlock Holmes!
Maybe James-san still has my badge!
Really?
Yeah, I think so!
In that case, I can track him with the badge's transmitter.
He's currently at...
Found him!
He's 16 km north-northwest of here.
He's traveling north on Ikumo Road along the Teimuzu River.
At that speed, he must be in a car.
In a car?
Ikumo Road?
Traveling north?
Okay.
If that's what they're doing...
Do you know what you're asking of me?
You want us to set up a checkpoint on Ikumo Road at the Saitama border?
That's impossible, Conan-kun.
We can't tie up the roads on such flimsy information...
But that foreigner's life is in danger!
Uh, well, you see...
Conan-kun? This is Sato.
There was an accident in that area a moment ago,
and Yumi's down there controlling traffic.
I can ask her to keep an eye out for the car.
A car carrying...
an American of English descent, in his 50s or 60s, with glasses and a mustache,
about 180 cm tall, right?
Gotcha.
I'll have Yumi stop any suspicious cars.
What? The kidnappers might be armed?
No problem. Takagi-kun and I will head out there too.
Me too?
Why not?
It's a slow day at the station anyhow,
and things always get interesting when that boy's involved.
Right?
Right...
Alright, let's go. Get your car, Doc.
We're the only ones who can identify James-san.
Alright, gotcha.
Hey.
Doesn't this seem fishy?
James-san left the parking lot, passed through this alley with two other men,
and got into a different car at the curb.
He must've pricked his finger and created the code while he was walking, right?
Yeah.
Those men must've threatened him with a gun while he entered the parking lot,
and he must've put the blood on the keychain while they weren't looking.
Or maybe,
he knew from the start that those two couldn't be trusted,
so he left the message just in case.
Hey, what are you trying to say?
I just have this feeling...
...that we're being played for fools.
Aren't you overthinking this?
I suppose you're right.
H-Hey, did you see that?!
The face of the guy in that car...
No... it just sped by...
I see...
A foreigner...
A foreigner?
Uh...
No.
A foreigner...
Let's see...
Oh, excuse me.
Yes?
You mind if we go on ahead?
We need this guy to verify a crime scene before dawn.
Oh... Nice work, boys.
Nah, he's just a lowlife who got high and trashed his girlfriend's place...
Okay. Go ahead.
Thanks a bunch.
Now then...
Uh...
A foreigner... a foreigner...
You didn't see him?
Aw, nuts!
He's a foreigner!
No, I didn't see even one foreigner...
What's going on, Conan-kun?
Where's the car now?
About 8 km away from here and still moving.
But the transmitter's battery is dying.
How'd they do it?
How did they get past us?
If that foreigner's got the badge, why can't we just call him and ask where he is?!
Don't even think about it!
The kidnappers could hear it and they'd realize we can contact him.
I guess our only hope is to solve the "P & A" riddle...
Maybe it's a clue to where the car is headed.
Maybe it stands for "parfait and anmitsu", and they're going to a restaurant?
Or maybe "perm and afro", and they're headed for a beauty parlor!
Can you get serious, guys?!
Ooh, I know!
"Pelican and Sea Lion"! A zoo!
ashika
James-san likes animals, right?
Nah.
If he wanted to tell us to try the zoo, he could've marked the "Animal" of "Animal Show"...
I've got it! That's what he meant!
Well done, Ayumi-chan!
I know where James-san is!
The kidnappers...
are in a police car?!
B-But that can't be...
I'm serious!
If we don't find them before dark, they'll get away!
Yumi! How'd it go?
Did you find the kidnappers Conan-kun was talking about?
So, where's the kidnappers?
W-Well...
He's telling me they're in a police car...
A police car?
That's right.
It's the code James-san left us, "P & A".
He was saying "police car".
Huh? How does "P & A" mean "police car"?
Spell out the "&" in "P & A", and it'll become clear.
Hm...
"P & A"...
"P" and "AND" and "A"...
PA-N-DA...
That's it! Panda!
So it is!
The coloring of a police car is black and white.
I see, just like a panda!
Wow, Conan-kun!
It's true, police in Japan do call a squad car a "panda"...
but the guy who was kidnapped was American and came from England, wasn't he?
How could a foreigner know slang used by Japanese police?
Well...
Maybe it's not a police car.
A little white car with black trim would look even more like a panda.
Yeah...
Yeah, in fact, for a foreigner, it'd make more sense for him to call one of those a panda.
No, it's because James-san, the kidnapped man, grew up in London...
that it's got to be a police car.
English police cars used to be painted the same way Japanese cars are today.
The coloring was first used in 1965 by the police in Lancashire, England.
Police cars there were called "pandas", and the name gradually spread across England.
You can still find the term in English dictionaries.
Well...
It probably isn't common slang among young people in Britain,
but someone James-san's age would think of a police car as a "panda".
Just what era person are you?
Come to think of it, I did let a police car pass without checking it.
But I didn't see a foreigner inside.
Did the officers in the car strike you as odd?
No... There were two detectives in the back seat escorting a suspect with a coat over his head...
T-That's it!
Piece of cake!
Looks like we'll make it to the mountains of Gunma before dawn, just like we planned.
You're a genius. Your plan is absolutely perfect!
Don't let your guard down.
Don't you find it strange...
that that traffic cop was checking inside everybody's cars?
Hey, you don't mean...
the cops are already onto us?
Don't panic.
We've got a hostage.
Keep the gun at his throat in case anything goes down.
If we hit another suspicious checkpoint,
we just force our way through.
Uh, w-w-what's the matter, Sato-san?
We're already in Saitama.
We've had the Saitama police set up a checkpoint,
so we don't need to chase the crooks...
Don't you get it, Takagi-kun?
Yumi already checked the kidnappers' car once.
If they figure out we're after them,
they could try to muscle their way through the next checkpoint, with him as a human shield.
Besides,
when Yumi was checking the car,
that foreigner sat there silently without trying to alert her or escape.
There's a good possibility the kidnappers are armed.
W-Wait just a minute!
If they have a gun,
and they start shooting into traffic at the next checkpoint...
T-They'll create a panic!
That's why I've been trying to think of a way
to surround the kidnappers without attracting their notice...
before they can pull a weapon...
But something like that would take magic.
It's not impossible.
Conan-kun?!
D-Detective Boys badge?
Sorry! I left my badge with you!
Well, where are you right now?
I'm about 500 meters away from your car.
I've got a plan, but I have to ask if you're up for it.
Whether or not this crazy plan works...
depends on how many cops you can get to join in.
Sheesh. What am I doing...
all the way out here?
Yumi? Are you following us?
Y-Yeah, I guess so...
I just want to make up for letting them get away.
Didn't you throw a party the other day with officers from the Saitama police?
Y-Yeah, I did...
Damn!
Another red light!
Calm down.
We don't want to attract attention with reckless driving.
Once night falls, we'll be safe.
Oh no, it's the cops!
Looks like they caught on!
Hey, get the lead out!
We'll use the hostage and escape!
H-H-Help!
W-What?
Police!
Please help!
C'mon!
Excuse me!
I'm Takagi from the Metro Police!
Could you assist us in apprehending that kidnapper?
Drat. Talk about bad luck.
Okay.
Go along with him for now, and turn off when you get the chance.
Got it!
Good, they fell for it!
Well? How's it going?
I-It's fine.
Just as we planned. Don't sweat it.
Okay, find a street and turn off...
Hey, what's with the Sunday driving?!
You'll let them get away!
If you can't turn left, turn right!
B-But...
There's another cop car on our right!
Then drop back! Slow down and get behind them!
N-No good.
There's a cop car behind us too...
W-What?!
Hey!
We're completely...
surrounded by cops!
Goddamn!
How smart of you, irregulars...
Well, I had better call you Holmes.
The cops set us up!
Don't worry about it.
We've still got a hostage!
You are hopeless.
When a commander makes a sign,
all cars hit the brakes at the same time.
When the offenders are about to pick themselves up...
they will be under arrest.
It's a little rough, eh?
But I've got to hand it to him...
Cool Guy.
Thanks a lot, everybody! You saved the day.
Nah, no problem!
Easy job!
But don't forget your end...
I know!
I promse to get all the cute girls from Metro Police to the next mixer!
Uh, no, I...
I'll be happy as long as Sato-san's there.
Yeah, yeah.
Hey, Yumi...
What happened to James Black-san, the hostage?
He was here a minute ago...
Huh?
I knew there was something strange about that foreigner.
He disappeared before the police could question him.
He's definitely hiding something.
You think so?
He seemed okay to me.
The only thing that bugged me was his name.
Name? You mean "Black"?
No, "James".
Huh? James Bond and James Dean...
I can only think of positive associations for that name.
Professor James Moriarty.
The Napoleon of crime.
It's the first name of Professor Moriarty,
Holmes' arch-nemesis.
But I guess only a Sherlockian would think of that.
It's not like James is an uncommon name in Britain.
Right...
But there's still the question...
of that guy watching us from the other car.
He was one of the passengers in the busjacking incident.
If I remember correctly,
he gave his name as Shuuichi Akai at the police station...
You always amaze me.
To leave a clue like that on the spur of the moment...
So when did you notice they weren't real cops?
The moment they spoke. They used Japanese without hesitation.
If they were cops,
and knew that I was a foreigner who spoke Japanese,
they would have started by confirming my name.
I assumed...
they were agents who already knew my identity.
But it turned out they were just common criminals,
who mistook me for someone else.
You know, you gave me a start.
I never thought you'd cut your long hair.
I wanted a fresh start.
My sweetheart keeps rejecting me.
Well?
You called me all the way out here.
Does that mean you're back on good terms with your so-called sweetheart?
Here's hoping.
After rejecting me like that...
I'll make my sweetie pay...
with tears of blood.
What's with this bloodstain?
Wow.
Today he's reasoning without falling asleep.
What?!
So that's it...
How could this happen?
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Fish scale
Look forward to the next episode!
Next Conan, a mysterious restaurant!
It's one who gives you eel on rice whatever you ask for, right?
Ahh! What a great restaurant!