Heart contains mysteries stars and snow sparkle for the two.
Snow falls silently at night.
A frightening suit of armor
Iooms up from the darkness.
He sees through the one and only truth,
a child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved with Detective Conan.
No case is leftunsolved with Detective Conan.
Gosho Aoyama / Shogakukan * YTV » TMS
All Rights Reserved
In the warring era,
military commander
Hidetomo Okikatsu advised
his lord Genbu Ohara, who was a tyrant,
to stop oppressing the people.
But this angered Genbu
and he ordered the Okikatsu clan to be disbanded.
Filled with despair.
Hidetomo put on his,suit of armor
and killed Genbu,
then he committed suicide by stabbing himself in the throat...
Hidetomo's ghost still wanders about
and it is said that whoever sees it will die an untimely death
This Okikatsu Festival is held
to appease the spirit of
Hidetomo Okikatsu
For your information, the rainwear of straw worn in the dance
symbolizes the suit of armor worn by Hidetomo when he killed himself
Good:grief, the hot.springs just ever that mountain,
why do we have to sit through this boring festival...
Oh but this is so surreal...
Good grief...
This is the 500th anniversary of Hidetomo's death...
Please relax and enjoy the evening...
Gee, thanks...
Are you satisfied now-Ran?
We'd better start heading for the hot spring already...
YN XCcuse me...
hjust heard that
the road 10 the-hot springs have been closed
due to heavy snow
Are you sure?
What're we going to do. dad?
Don't ask me
I guess we'll just have to find some place
around here to spend the night
But I didn't see any inns around here
xXcuse me.
Maybe I can help,
there:s a house up ahead owned by the Daimon family.
I'm heading there now, you can come with me if you want
Uh, thanks...
FRIGHTENING LEGEND
ON A SNOWY NIGHT-PART I
Are you sure it'll be all right for us to go along?
Yes, in fact,
I'd prefer you come with me...
uh...
The head of the Damon family is the president of Daimon Industries
Wow, that company's well known...
The president is a man who'd do anything for money.
He's even a tyrant in his own home, he and his oldest son,
who is next in line to be president, are always arguing.
And that son's wife prefers partying to helping in the home.
I've heard rumors that a divorce is imminent...
You sure know a lot
econd son.
My name's Yoshiro Daimon.
Econd son.
Yoshiro Damon
-- - oo
11 KX JI \C
I haven't been home for quite awhile now.
This is quite a mansion...
They must get a lot taken...
Huh?
In taxes...
Kazuki, I'm home...
Yousre looking goodn...
Yoshiro. .why'd you come back er all this time
Yoshiro... why'd you come back er all this time...
Kazuki Daimon
Is that any way to greet your younger brother,"
we haven't seen each other for five years...
h. young master, please come inside...
Hatsuho, you keep out of this!
Kayoko Damon
Yoshiro. who are these people?
I met them at the Hidetomo Festival.
It was snowing heavily and they didn't have a place to stay...
You comeback out of the blue
and you bring strangers with you on top of that!
Forgive me
I forgot to introduce myself.
Ni'm from Tokyo and ll...
what's all the commotion!
OS IFO. YOU V6 ma YCOITIS 0M8.
I'mrso happy
Good evening. father...
You over there,
Genichiro Damon
WPA LYS BS
Xr -es (70)
aren't you the famous private tective Kogoro Mourn...
Genichiro Damon
1.151085 LIB 5'5
KrPIim-es (70)
ufihfilu MB B5
XrlR-BB (70)
That's right. but...
Private detective...
Kogoro Maura...
I'm one of your greatest fans...
This must be destiny, please do spend the night.
Hatsuho...
prepare the guest rooms for Mr. Mouri's party and Yoshiro
Yes, sir
* 0 OS
?!...
Please, follow me
Mr. Mouri. you and your party can stay in this room.
Master Yoshiro, your room wi »2e (own 1e 1a
You can enter the garden through this-back door.
It is very pretty, everything is white with snow.
Please walk through it
Thank you--we will
Please forgive my brother and his wife,
they behaved terribly back there...
You don't have to apologize,
we're the ones who barged in unexpectedly
Excuse me ma'am,
where's the toilet?
Jad,
Oh. it's right down the hall. there...
at the far end
the light switch is hard to find ¢ so I'll go with you
Thank you, I'd appreciate that
I'll prepare some tea so please relax
You needn't bother...
but I'd sure appreciate some...
I'll join you later
Eh?!
Here .
Aha. haha...gee. thanks...
For goodness sakes, dad
Here it is. the toilet
Thank you.
This sure is a huge house
It certainly is...
What's down that way?
Everyone else's rooms.
Master Kazuki's audio room is down the hall and the kitchen is in front of it.
Next to the kitchen,
we have a door that
Ieads into the garden...
You can go in now.
we wouldn't want you to have an accident
Right!
This is a very impressive home you have.
I am honored to be staying in a place like this
o. this is just an old place...
We're always having to repair things
madam says she isnst feeling well
she s resting
What, again!
And just-when Mr. Mouri is visiting
Please don't get upset on my account
I don't think mother can be bothered with dinner either tonight
Kayoko!
Don't be like that.
I think it'd be better if they knew...
of Hidetomosrstdeathmat 12mdnight.
My mothernzin=law sits
=in front of the altar ingher room praying +
SupposediyBthat's the time hewkilled himself
Supposedly that's the time he killed. himself.
I heard her once and it sounded so eerie...
Ever since then, whenever (his day comes,
I climb 'into bed and cov "my head with the blanket
Mother really is quite frail,
I wish you'd be more considerate...
Kazuki!
You needn't worry about your mother!
Rather than spending your time worrying about her,
you should worry about your job!
Eo 60
117?
Uh. Is the feed to your liking?
It's delicious.
The rice is good too
"UT stomary in this household to cook the rice over a "'kamado
Really,
I've never had kamado cooked rice before...
The burnt part was delicious!
By the way father,
about the appointment of the next president...
We're in the middle of dinner!
We'll discuss that later!!
Yoshiro, what are you doing now?
I'm a guitarist.
What's!?
Such foolishness. quit that immediately and come back home.
I think it's about time you started considering helping my business.
Yoshiro.
What kind of music do you play?
Flamenco.
Really, I'd like to hear you play.
Mr Mouril! Excuse me,
May I have your autograph?
The truth is; lm a big fan of-yours too.
You are, arejyou, it'd be my pleasure then!
Eeek. I'm so thrilled!
Yippee!
What a happy go lucky pair.
It seems the atmosphere in this house has
also brightened up thanks to Hatsuho
Oh it's just-that I don't let things upset me
Hatsuho, how long have you been wanking here?
Just over a year.
Your family sta> very old family and there+s so much to remember,
I'm having a hard time...
Oh, I see you have another one...
es...this is for Master Yoshi
You want my autograph too?
Of course after all, you're-going to be a very famous guitarist someday
I hope so...
If you become famous.
Signing autographs will be the least of your worries,
Iook at me...hahaha
Haha I'll remember that
Hey? You're left handed
Uh huh
What are these figures!
I gave you the benefit of the doubt and waited until the very last minute
but I guess it was a waste of time
I can't relinquish my position to you at this rate!
Well dad, your methods are rather high handed themselves
I didn't ask you for your opinion!
All right then
who are you going to name as president instead of me!
You're both two of a kind!
I came back (here'today
because I wanted to settle things with my dad once and for all
Settle things...?
Dad wants me to become one of the company's executives.
But everything is money, money, money.
He doesn't even try to understand how other people feel.
I left five years ago because I hated how pushy he was...
Well, he does look very overbearing
The truth is,
I'm going to Spain next month...
I don't intend on coming back to Japan until I've become a first rate guitarist
I may never see my father again...
That's Why thought Ixd better come back
andrtry-to-make-him-accept the way I choose to live my life...
That's what you'd like us to believe.
IsnAtéit: Yoshiro
but the truth is you came back to seize control of the company, didn't you
You're out of your mind!
I'd never have left in the first place if I intended to do that!
Oh really!
Ma-am...
oe a &o8sd
What's all the fuss!
Oh for goodness sakes, everybody makes me so mad!
I'm going back to my place!
I almost forgot, Mr. Mouri
I'd like to show you something interesting. it'll lift your spirits
That's where I live
LE A) 3
Dee...
this is very nice...
It's always so noisy at the main house
so I spend most of my time here relaxing
Wow! Look at that...
That suit of armor looks so imposing...
You re right...
What do you think.
Impressive, isn't it.
That's my pride and joy.
It's Hidetomo Okikatsu's suit of armor
So this belongs to the festival's hero...
So it's'in your possession...
That suit of armor is cursed!
Tatsuko!
What are you doing here!
Hidetomo's spirit still roams-this ear
Tatsuko Damon
Hidetomo's spirit still roams-this ear ms n? (so)
Those who see it are said to die untimely deaths!
1€8Se are so I] € OMoO SS ee don't get cold...
Please use these socks...
Stop that!!
I don't approve!
How dare you say that to me!!
I pray to Hidetomo on the anniversary of his death every year
and give offerings in penance of the horrible way you do business!
So don't you ever say anything
Iike that to me again!!
Tonight is the 500th anniversary f Hidetomo's death...
something might happen tonight...
Mr. Mouri.
I've decided to postpone talking to my father until tomorrow
Why don't we drink more of that locallsake. since we have thé time
Sounds good to me!
Yoshiro!
Mother. I thought you were asleep...
Yoshiro, Hidetomo must have brought you here tonight
you're the only one who can protect this family...
take this...
Mother, she was keeping articles like these
Allow me
December 10th 1996, Kenichi Saegusa
president of Saequsa Industries commits suicide
Damon Industries used dirty methods
to deliberately drive ee company in O° »an «rup Cy...
this was behind the suicide....!
That's the way father always does business...
But you don't know for sure that this article was completely right...
I understand you saw the suit of armor in father's room...
The man who committed suicide...
he was the original owner...
What?!
The day that man committed suicide,
December 10th, that's today
\ Nw, 5800
His factory was left untouched, it's falling apart
Some people have seen his ghost there...
Spooky »isn't it!
Uh uh
Hidetomo Okikatsu and the: owner of his suit of armor,
ge] } . v!
1e: anniversary o 201» weir cea 181S
December 10th, unbelievable...
Could it be... the curse of the suit of armor...
It's mere coincidence. that's all!
Besides, time's a wasting.
Vil. Let's enjoy our drinks and take:inithe:beautiful snowy:scenery!!
Oh...it'g stopped snowing...
It's so beautiful...
If only the snow could fall in our hearts
and cover everything up like this,
It would be so nice...
Oh. I nearly forgot.
Your beddings been laid out
SO you can turn in
Thank:you Hatsiho.
Come on dad,
you must be tired after all that driving.
You'd better get some rest
Yeah, hey
I'm goingto: go get a drink
I meant water!
You'll get the inheritance money
If your father dies. won't you!
But I don't think he's going to die very soon
You're right...
What I don't understand is
why did that Yoshiro come back so suddenly!
He's not leaving Japan, that's a lie!
I'll bet he's going to tr and make good with your ather!
There wouldn't be any trouble
if only you could automatically become president...
And what about you, you married me for the money. didn't you
How dare you!
Because if you get a hangover and we have to spend another night here,
I'll be very angry
Hey Conan.
Ran here's in a real bad mood, we'd better get to bed and fast
Dad. you're talking too loud!
Come on sir, let's go to bed come on...
Are you sleeping in the audio room again tonight?!
You love music more than me
Hatsuho.
I'd like a cup of my usual coffee
Could you bring it to the audio room
Yes sir
Nanmandabu. nanmandabu
Eeeek!
As er amon iis. as er amon is.
What on earth's the matter?
Master Daimon is dead in his room
Are you sure?!
1! You Kids stay here
Conan!
Is something wrong?
Aster Yoshiro...
Your father, in his room...
Father?!
Father!
Don't go inside!!
It looks like he was stabbed once in the chest with a sharp object...
e-died instantaneously...
Sir. look
Huh
he suit of armor is gone...
Nd so is the sword...
It appears Mr. Daimon was killed while he was having a glass of brandy...
Oh...
ho did this...
Even the socks...
This is the only entrance to this place
and on top of that, there were no footprints leYding here
What's that?!
I get it...
that door hid the footprints
and on the way here,
the man-made hill and hedges cast a shadow over the footprints,
that's why we didn't see them...
sheet?
For goodness sakes,
why are you always; wandering around like this...
There's a huge footprint over there!
It doesn't look like Va human one
What in the world is this?
I told you
What huge footprints...
Hidetomo...
It's Hidetomo!! I saw him!
I saw him walking around in his suit of armor last night...
But the curse didn't fall on me although I saw him,
I € on cenicuro Ins eac...
At any rate,
these footprints seem to lead to the back door of the main house
We'll go back to the main house the way we came
'but make sure you don't erase any of those footprints,
Iet's see where those footprints lead
The killer came this way...?
Kazuki?!
He said he was coming here to listen to music but he never returned
What!
Kazuki!
There another way in?!
No. there isn't!
Damn!
I guess we'll have to:break it down...!
Mr. Mouri!
Kazuki... Kazuki!
Don't go in there...
Hidetomo was angry after all!
I don't believe it!
Azuki...
It's HidetomoO's curse: the curse!!!
0. this is NO curse...
But who in the world did this and how?!
ORIGIN 1 COMIC BOOKS BY.
Goshp Aoyama
PRODUCERS.
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER D SIGNS BY
Masatomo Sudd
STORY EDITOR.
Junichr -hoka
Junichi lioka
SCRIPTS BY.
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouct?
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi1 Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura fakashi1 Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR.
Yukihiro Shibiatan
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY.
Takishi Nomuri
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Ogawa
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
JIT?
Erumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
Kenn Kodamay
PRODUC D BY
TMS EMe tiinment, Lid.
In associfion bath
Yomiuri Télecastino. Corporation
J=I2C11/2 Ce) by]
GoSho Aoyama +Shogakukan * YAN * TMS
All Rights Reserved
This room was completely locked,
so how was this possible?!
It's true. it's Hidetomo's curse after alll
That suit of aromor summoned
Hidetomo's spirit...
to punish my husband, for all his dishonest dealings...
and Kazuki in the main house too...
So that's what it is, I've got it now!