The heart contains mysteries, stars and snow sparkle for the two.
The mystery of the samurai in the suit of armor is solved,
Sadness is behind the legend.
He sees through the one and only truth,
a child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult,
No case is left unsolved with Detective Conan.
No case issleft unsolved with Detective Conan.
Gosho Aoyama / Shogakukan ° YTV « TMS
All Rights Reserved
We were headed for the hot springs but a heavy snowfall closes the road
we end up staying at the Daimon residence.
When we get up the next morning.
We learn that the head of the household.
Genichiro Daimon has been found dead in the annex
And then the eldest son,
Kazuki is found in the audio room wearing a suit of armor
dead under strange circumstances...
FRIGHTENING LEGEND OF THE
ARMOR CLAD WARRIOR-PART II
The wound is the same as Genichiro's, a single thrust with a sharp object
I believe it was with this sword...
It's true, it's Hidetomo's curse after all!
That suit of armor summoned Hidetomo
to punish my husband for all his dishonest dealings...
to punis ¥my husband for all his dishonest dealings...
and Kazuki in the main house too...
And to show us it was the curse, he put the suit of armor on Kazuki...
Hmm...
I can:t prove if it was a curse or not but those footprints are for real
The only footprints leading from th ) annex to the main house
are those from the warrior in the suit of armor...
Which means...
Do you really think it was the warrior the suit of armor...
At any rate, we've got to call the police...
I want everyone to wait in the living room until the police arrive,
I'll go prepare some coffee
AY LO
LTL OO ST
now's my chance...
Oh no yourdon't!
Pad is going to be angry
Oh. but...
Hatsuho! We'll help you
We'll be waiting, please hurry
The police won't be able to get here right away because of the heavy snow
I see
Yoshiro
you're the only one who can lprotectithis family now...
Mother...
I wonder who could have killed father and Kazuki
Hmm
What is that stain.
Blo 87
From the murder scene... No.
Therers only one possibility...
Kazuki killed Genichiro in the annex then returned to the audio room
and committed suicide...
Why would Kazuki do such a thinge=
He had a good reason didn't he
Kazuki criticized father's methods and they were always fighting!
MaYbe he got carried away and...
That sounds just like the legend of the suit off armor...
What about you, Yoshiro, you came back to settle things with father, didn't you.
It applies to you too
Maybe all that talk about becoming a guitarist was a lie
and what you really wanted was to become president of Daimon Industries.
If father and Kazuki were out of the way.
You'd be guaranteed the position, wouldn't you
What utter nonsense!
How did I get to the annex in the first place!
There were no footprints
Ieading from the main house!
Well the same goes for Kazuki too
Hmm. it's true.
There were only footprints leading tom TO ina UO Wr meting house)
It's the curse
The armor clad warrior walked from the annex
to the main:house in the middle of the night,
I saw it with my own eyes
Perhaps you were dreaming. mother
I was not dreaming!
I saw it with my own eyes'. I know I did
The huge form of the warrior in the suit of armor
walked under the moonlight...
Excuse ma'am.
Was the warrior carrying as ofd?
Eh? Let me see...
I'don't think he had a sword.
Maybe it was in his right hand though...
Oh for goodness sakes.
What a stupid question
Haha...
Thefe's two problems.
How did Genichiro's Killer get to the annex without leaving anyfootprints?
And why did th ) Killer head for the audio room...
Aha, I've figured-it out!
Yawn
I don<t understand what everybody's talking about,
I'm going outside to play in the snow
Oh no!
You stay right here!
What the heck are you thinking about at a time like this!
Yahoo!
That's enough!
How many times do I have tell you not te wander around!
Good.
Look sir,
my footprints are gone.
I wonder why?
Wit You're talking nonsense!
Hey!
Maybe that's what happened...
Now's my chance...
The door was locked from the inside.
The walls are thick,
Iike all audio rooms...
there are no spaces around the door
you can opera es rom e ou sSI ee...
The power on the audio set was off.
and the wound on the body was the same as Genichiro's...
both of them were probably killed with that sword.
But why was that sword
Iying near the door...
the sheath was by the body...
Did Kazuki throw it there after stabbing himself?
0. that's impossible...
Huh?
Why's there a scratch here with blood on it...
There's no blood on the tip...
That's it!
I've figured how this room was locked...
I knew it!
There's no blood splatter on him
but who...
Huh?
What's this?
? He's barefoot...
Wait a minute,
the killer took the socks too...
If the killer didn't mean to put them on Kazuki,
then why take them in the first place?
Did the killer use them for something else?
Nd if so, what was it...
Aha!
Go ty.
And if I'm right
then it must be hidden somewher »...
Listen up everyone,
I've solved the mystery
You mean about the footprints going in onlyfone direction?
That's right!
he way I figure it. late last night
Kazuki went to the annex wearing flat sandals or something
and for some reason ha killed his father.
After that, he put the suit of armor on
and headed for the main house...
very carefully retracing his footsteps...
since he had the suit of armor on which added to his weight,
his previous footprints were completely erased
and the only footprints that remained
were those going from the annex to the main house
I see
He then returned to the audio room but felt guilt.
He locked himself in
and committed suicide by stabbing himself in the throat...
I. I don't believe It...
He would never do such a thing...
I knew it
Now to find 'the thing",
I know it's hidden some place...
What is this
So that's what this was about...
Here it is!
I've found it!
Jusi1as I figured.
these murders were committed using the legend of Hidetomo's curse...
and the real killer is. that person!
MM. Mr. Mour,
I don't believe he'd commit suicide.
I'm sorry ma'am but it's the truth...
Aheeeen!!
M. Mr. Mouril?
But actually l said:.that just to throw the killer off guard
Eh!?
What dd you mean?
That's only:half of my theory
Like I just explained.
Genichirds killer returned to the main house erasing the earlier footprints.
Anyone could Have done this
except for Ka-suki and the elder
Mrs. Damon who Saw the warrior outside
What do you Mean, anyone...
What you're saying is,
JKazukiiwho egmmittedisuicide didn't kill father...
That's right
your brother did not kill your fa her.
And,
he didn't commit suicide either
Judging from the wound on Genichiro,
I'd-assume the killer was splattered with blood
KazukKi's clothes
under the suit of armor was spotless,
After the killing Genichiro
the killer snuck into the audio room
and killed Kazuki
But how!?
Remember the sword on the floor of the audio room.
We looked upon it as the murder weapon, nothing else
but that sword was not just the murder weapon,
It served another purpose too
it was used to lock the audio room!
After killing Kazuki,
the killer put the suit of armor on him and stuck the sword
NO ewa Yy e oor.
Then took the hilt on the opposite end and
placed it on top of the door handle so that it would touch the bolt
the killer then exited the room cautiously
so the sword wouldn't fall then very, very slowly closed the door
the hilt of the sword pushed against the bolt
and there you have it, a locked room
To open a door as sturdy as that, you'd have to break it down.
The vibrations created when the door was being broken
would cause the sword to fall and the set up would never be discovered.
I'm sure that's what the killer planned
But Why Would anyone do such a thing?
Before I answer that,
you all must think
as to why this happened on the anniversary of Hidetomo's death,
it has a special meaning
The killer used the legend
of Hidetomo's suit of armor to it's full extent
The killer created the illusion of one set of footprints going in one direction,
so that we'd all believe
only the armor clad warrior was capable of committing the. murder...
and succeeded in making us think
Kazuki killed his father then committed suicide.
And to support the illusion,
the killer made Tatsuko, who believed strongly in the legend,
see the warrior walk.
At 12 midnight on the anniversary of Hidetomo's death,
she prays at the altar, everyone in this family knows that.
Unfortunately though
that's where the killer left us a clue
Ma'am
Iast night,
when you saw the armor clad warrior, it wasn't carrying. a sword. was it?
No. it wasn't
Actually though, he did indeed have it with him
it's just that from Tatsuko's position, she couldn't see it in his right hand.
Whieh means, the killer was probably left handed...
It wasn't me!!
Besides.
How do ou know the killer was
Ieft handed I the sword was in the right!?
In-order to draw the sword with the left hand.
You need to hold the-sheath in: your right. don't you
That's so. so .
But Yoshiro is not the killer
There is another leftthanded person here 8
Hatsuho Hojo!
It's you!
Hatsuho...
You're left handed too. aren't you
you used your left hand when you served us coffee just now
Yes, that's right...
But you need special skills
0 handle a sword 'don't you!
And another thing, I had no motive for killing Mr. Daimon, or his son!
Ran.
Can you go to Hatsuho's room
and get an old photo frame from the drawer in the chest
Okay...
While we wait for Ran to get back, there's another thing...
Hatsuho. you said you looked out your window at the annex
and saw that Genichiro was dead..isn't that right
Master Genichiro is dead.
Master Genichiro is dead...
Master Genichiro is dead in the annex!
But think carefully.
How could you tell. by looking from the or Bin house to the annex
whether Oenichiro was dead or just lying on the floor?
Well, uh when I saw him on the floor
I got so excited, I
Ran,
you're back... put the photo there where everyone can see
Okay...
So tellime Yoshiro,
do you-recognize the person inthat photo?
It looks like Hatsuho and that's probably her father. .!!
He's...
It-s'the man in the newspaper article, the one who committed suicide!!
That's right...
she did have a motive for killing the two...
Hatsuho...{
you watched Kazuki in the audio room
to make sure the tranquilizer in his coffee took effect,
then you headed for the annex through the back door
Genichiro would surely open the door for her
without a second thought if she were to call out to him...
after killing him, you put the suit of armor on
and walked back to the main house over your own footprints
You used a route where you wouldn't be seen
from Yoshiro, Kayoko or our rooms.
It could only be seen from Tatsuko and your room.
When you went to the annex.
You probably covered yourself with a white sheet or something
so that if someone saw you, you'd blend in with the snow.
After committing the murder, you hurriedly stuffed the sheet
into the bedroom closet in the annex...
Hound? it sticking out...
it's all...
It's all 'ust theoretical!!
Yes, sure it was my father who committed suicide.
And yes, so I changed my name to hide my past so no one would know.
But that doesn't prove
I killed the two men!
I have proof
it's inside the stove in the kitchen!
Conan found it.
Inside the stove,
He found a bloody-jacket
and the white socks
Tatsuko left on the altar...
So you found them in the kitchen, that doesn't prove I put them there!
Somebody might have put them there to frame me!
After the murders, it would have been possible for anyone
to hide them there!
Unfortunately, you were the only one with the opportunity
The white socks Tatsuko left by the suit of armor disappeared
from the annex but they weren't on the victim's body.
If the killer didn't mean to put them on Kazuki,
they why did the killer take them then hide them in the stove...
Hat$uho
you've hurt your left foot. haven't you
It appears you didn't bandage it well enough.
It seems to have started bleeding again a little while ago
When ou were serving the coffee just now.
NO IC some O00 ON your soc
When you killed Genichiro in the annex,
you dropped and broke the cup!!
You mistakenly stepped on the glass cutting your foot
You knew that if you put the warrior's shoes on you'd get blood on them,
So you put the socks Tatsuko had left and then put the shoes on over them.
Then you hid the socks in the kitchen stove along with the jacket
You realized that using the stove in the middlesof the night
would cause:suspicion
SO you decided to wait until merning then burn:ithe-evidence.
But when you went to prepare the coffee,
Ran went with you
SO YoU los Go Of ert
you-re right
I killed both of them
Why did you do it! ?
You were always so kind to me...
My father, who ran the factory, was an old fashioned man
he felt that helping others was more important than making money...
he took Daimon Industries orders although it was too much to handle
just because they'd done business with them for so long...
But dhe day.
Just because of one little error,
Damon Industries stopped using olir factory...
my father's company went bankrupt.
Damon Industries
WES Re RAR) ATE = gel) EONS
but saved themselves
By sacrificing my father's company.
And as if to rub salt in my father s wounds,
Oenichiro took the suit of armor from my father as payment for debts due,
that suit of armer was a family heirloom
It happened just when father decided to sell the suit of armor
in order to pay the employees their salaries...
he wasn't able to do anything for the employees
and on top of that, he couldn't use the family heirloom to help anyone
father killed himself because he blamed himself for everything
I had been working in Tokyo,
but in order to avenge my father,
I changed my name and last year,
I came here to work as their live in help
I was determi ed 6 ¢arny out my revenge
on the anniversary of father's death
Hatsuho...
Do you think your father is happy that you avenged his death?
Do you think he'd praise. you...
Matsuhe...
it wasn't Hidetomo's spirit that put that suit of armor on...
your heart wore the suit of armor...
the cold armor called revenge...
ORIGIN 1 COMIC BOOKS BY.
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS.
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
Katsuo Ono
» » gt od AN ed pp Dd
Masatomo Sido
Junichi hook
\isRIPTS BY.
Ha 7ji Kashiwabara
Kizunari Kouchi un chi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Joshiki In 'ue
oy Jd ed
Kan]: Kashrwabzarfi
Kazunari K Gthi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
TION DIREC
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Harup Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR.
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF~PHOTQGRAPHY. a 11S 11}. omMmur
Hironobu Horikoshi
Ta ahisa Ogawa
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
JIT?
R mitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
Ken]: Kbdamfl
PRODUCED BY.
TMS FEritert§inment, Ltd.
I!) JSSTIOIJ ION HI 7
Yomiuri Telecastine Corporation
JD IFCrl/z ce bhi
OGosho Aoyama mshogaikukan - YTV - TN'!
Al Rights Reserved
Ouch!
Conan, are you all right?
Ran. you okay?
Look...
The imprint I left got erased by yours!
It's just like that case with the suit of armor. don't you think?
Oh oh.
Conan, you [little rat... what are you trying to say
I... uh, I didn't-mean anything by that...
Why you! Ceme back here Conan!!
I'm sorry!
Did she think I meante she was bigger and heavier...?
Hahaha.
The problem is where and what you were doing
at the time the crime was committed
I don't remember anything
Have you ever seen this person before?
I'm sure I saw him
Isn't Kogoro Mour, the lawyer, Ms. Kisaki's husband?
This is going to be interesting
Wait a minute
if that's the case, then...
sO UD 080 :
44 VS
(ATE)