What's inside of the heart is a mystery.
Stars and snow shine down on us.
Naniwa is the stage for this two-hour Conan special.
A tag-team match with Conan and Heiji!
Recognizing that single truth,
a child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Osaka Double Mystery
The Naniwa Swordsman and Toyotomi's Castle.
Osaka Double Mystery:
The Naniwa Swordsman and Toyotomi's Castle!
Naniwa Central Gym
NOTE: "Men" refers to a head strike in kendo.
Men!
Men strike, one point! Match goes to red!
All right! Now they're past the first round in the brackets!
Yes. Kaihou Academy is fielding a very able team this year.
They're doing very well in the competition.
If you think they're something now, wait until you see our team captain!
Heiji's so good, it's scary!
Oh? Heiji is Kaihou's team captain?
That boy never mentions things like that at home.
Taihou Academy Captain, step forward.
That's not Heiji.
Maybe he's over there?
The one that's surrounded by all those young girls.
Hey, Heiji!
You skipping or something?
The match is starting! Hurry up and-
Huh? Pale skin?
Uh... Hi.
You're that freshman...
Hattori-senpai asked me to do this.
He said, "You won't need me till the semi-finals. Put on my name-tag and stand in for me."
But he's really popular...
So when these girls saw my name-tag, they came over.
And? Where's Heiji now?
In the restroom, I think. He went towards the side building.
Side Building.
Listen, I'll tell you again:
Naniwa Central Gym is the seventh stop on the bus that you'll take from Osaka Station.
If you get lost, just ask the bus driver:
"Where can see Hattori Heiji-sama play in the Western Kendou Championships?" All right?
Fine, get it already.
I'm not a kid, you don't have to keep repeating yourself.
Sorry! You just look like a kid, so I couldn't help but worry.
Whatever, just quit calling.
I have a hard time giving Ran and her dad the slip.
At any rate, we were invited to your place to eat blowfish.
Your tournament just happened to be on the same day.
That's you all right, cold as usual!
Besides, the train just left, so we won't get there till 2:00.
Won't your match already be over?
Don't worry! The semi-finals start at 2:00, so you'll make it.
Oh... Great.
See you soon, Kudo!
K-Kazuha...
What are you doing?
That's my line! This the guys' bathroom!
Oh? l hadn't realized.
I thought this was some kind of hideout for boys who decided to skip the tournament.
All according to plan. I'm gonna beat him.
"Him?" You mean that guy who looks like Kudo-kun?
Okita
Yeah. Okita from Kyouto High.
NOTE "Tsuki" is the Japanese word for 'thrust'.
He gave me this scar with a tsuki last year, so I owe him some payback.
Isn't that being too hopeful? He beat you last time.
Fool, I didn't lose.
When my neck started bleeding from that hit, the doctor stopped the match.
Afterwards, he skipped some rounds, sulked around, and even took a nap outside.
I'd call it a draw.
Don't worry, you'll win! You've got your lucky charm, right?
That's not the only reason I skipped the preliminaries...
To tell the truth, it was because of this scar you gave me on Bikuni Island...
It's itching so much that it's distracting me!
Does it? I get it.
I'd better go tell your mom that she needs to smack some sense into her boy.
Mom's here?
Hold on, Kazuha!
What the hell is wrong with you, dumbass!?
"Dumbass"?
Don't look at me.
You can't fight because you have a hangover?
I had to. That company that offered me a job after graduation went bankrupt.
Tarumi Atsushi (22)
Shinrai University - Senpou (1st Fighter)
Idiot! There's a time and a place for that.
Omotani Mineo (22)
Now, now, we've got an hour before the match.
Douguchi Noriyuki (21)
He's right Until then, cool off and think about what you've done.
Kotegawa Takashi (22)
You know... I could tell everyone about., that.
What the hell did you just say?
Unlike you guys, I don't have a job waiting for me.
I have nothing to lose.
I don't know what you're talking about, but if you don't wanna be a team player,
I can have someone take your place.
I won't let you embarrass our team and the school.
Hakamada Mashimichi (22)
Big talk from the guy who stole my girlfriend.
Idiot. She left you on her own. I didn't steal her.
Man, you really need to cool off and think for a minute.
If you don't get some sense pretty soon, you might end up a loser all your life.
I'll kill you.
I'll fucking kill you!
Heiji, what are you doing? C'mon, let's go.
"Dou" refers to a midsection strike.
Dou!
Dou strike! One point!
"Dou" refers to a midsection strike.
All right! That's it!
Hey, I can't find Tarumi anywhere.
Maybe he went home?
We have no choice. Let's split up and look for him.
Got it.
Get your head in the game!
Get those two points and make the top four!
Find him?
Annex
No. I checked the bathroom and the dojo.
Did you look in that storage room?
Not yet...
But why would he be out here?
T-Tarumi...
Oh, my God!
Someone call an ambulance!
I'll do it, hold on!
Omotani, get the police!
I'll go tell the judges.
Right, get someone in charge!
Got it!
All right! We made the top four.
Now we've got a shot at the championship.
Tarumi is? You sure?
I don't know if he was breathing or not, but he was covered in blood!
Where was this?
Who the hell are you?
I asked you where this was!
What? There's no one here.
That's weird... He was leaning against this vault just a minute ago.
What's this dummy doing here?
Isn't it one of those dummies they use for practicing CPR?
Yeah, for mouth-to-mouth respiration and stuff.
Don't tell me you confused him with this dummy?
Don't be ridiculous!
Hey! I brought the police.
They said the ambulance would be here in about ten minutes, so...
But we can't find Tarumi.
What?
Could he have done this as a prank?
All right, let's split up and look again!
If he's sitting somewhere laughing, I'm gonna beat the shit out of him!
Excuse me, are you all from Shinnai University?
Yes. What's the matter?
We received a strange call at the front desk.
A man said to ask the people from Shinnai in the storage room to come to the pool.
It's Tarumi!
That bastard's screwing with us!
Let's just go and check it out.
Locker Room.
Tarumi!
Hey... There's no way.
He's really dead.
It can't be!
A body that was first found in the side building's storage room ended up in the locker room by the pool.
That means someone must've moved it.
But, carrying around a bloody body would definitely attract attention.
A few kendo clubs were eating lunch near the side building's exit, too.
Hey, Heiji!
What are you doing? Come eat some lunch.
We've got less than an hour before the semi-finals!
Enough, already! I've got a case to solve.
A guy was killed in that building over there.
Really?
It looks like a tough one, so I'll probably not make it in time for the match.
Then, why don't you ask Kudo-kun to handle it? You invited him, right?
Kudo! That's it! I'll just call him and-
That way you won't have to worry at all. He can solve it for you in no time!
Just leave the case to him so you can get back to the tournament.
Listen, Kazuha. Don't say a word about the murder to Kudo.
I mean it!
I have an hour and a half before Kudo gets here. I've gotta crack the case before then!
Look at you. You've got rice on your face again.
What!? A murder case!?
Don't tell me that Hattori's-
Yep. He said he "didn't have time to worry about the match."
What the hell!?
The semi-finals are starting soon!
There's nothing else to we can do...
We've gotta win without Heiji...
And then, totally rub it in his face!
Um... we're the ones competing.
You sure this is your friend?
Yeah. He's our classmate, Tarumi.
They put him in the shower to try to hide the time of death.
At any rate, the murder weapon was this katana.
If we find out who this belongs to, we'll-
I'm afraid not, Ohtaki-han.
It's a live blade one of the teachers brought here for an iaidou demonstration.
Someone probably left it unattended long enough for it to get stolen and used as the murder weapon.
Hei-chan, what are you doing here?
Can't you tell? I'm competing in the tournament.
Oh, yeah. Today's the Kansai tournament for the high school and college kendo clubs, right?
So? You think that someone snuck in and stole the katana?
Yeah. Whoever did it has been here before...
Someone who knew about the iaidou demonstration.
They knew the layout of the gym, the side building, and the locker room.
In other words, someone like one of you.
I can see why it has to be someone who knew about the live sword demonstration,
but why does he have to know about the buildings?
Because if he didn't know, how could he carry Tarumi's body without anyone noticing?
What puzzles me more than why he moved the body is how.
At the time, a few kendo clubs were eating lunch right in front of the entrance.
I can't believe that they wouldn't notice a man carrying a bloody corpse.
Well, after you guys found the body in the storeroom,
the last person to leave would've had the best opportunity.
Does anyone remember what happened then?
The first person to leave was Kotegawa.
He said he was gonna call an ambulance.
After that was me.
Kotegawa told me to go get the police.
So the last one left was you, right, Douguchi-san?
But just after that, I went to the gym to tell Hakamada and the tournament judges!
You wouldn't be lying, would you?
Isn't that what I said, guys?
Besides, the last one to leave wasn't Douguchi. It was me.
I wanted to call the ambulance as fast as possible,
so I went and borrowed a cell phone from one of the guys eating outside.
Then the paramedics asked me about Tarumi's condition,
so I went back to the storeroom and checked.
Of course, I was alone.
And after that, I gave the guy back the cell phone, and headed for the police box.
You're sure that's what happened?
It's true that Kotegawa came to the police box.
I'm not good at explaining things, so he helped me out.
And about how long did it take to go from the side building to the police box?
The police box is near a big intersection, so you get stuck waiting at the pedestrian crossing.
I'd say about 14-15 minutes.
14-15 minutes?
Don't you think it's a bit odd, Douguchi-san?
Omotani-san and Kotegawa-san brought the police just after we went to the storeroom.
It sure took you a long time to find Hakamada-san, even though he was in the gym next door.
It probably did take a while to find me.
There are a lot of others wearing this same uniform around.
Which means that you also had time to move the body, doesn't it?
You can believe me or not, but let me ask you something.
How did I supposedly carry Tarumi's body here without anyone noticing?
Yeah! If you can't prove that, we're all innocent.
No use staying around for more of this.
Detective, we'll go notify Tarumi's family.
Hakamada-kun, why aren't you wearing a name plate?
I thought I'd brought it I guess I must've misplaced it.
It doesn't matter anymore since we can't continue regardless.
Speaking of which, how'd the tournament go, Hei-chan?
Did you win? Lose?
Kote!
Kote strike! One point to white!
"Kote" refers to a wrist strike.
All right, we scored!
Just a little bit longer until the finals!
Yeah! We'll win even without Heiji!
"Tsuki" refers to a throat strike.
Tsuki!
Tsuki strike! One point to white!
Kyouto High wins four to one.
Kyouto High?
It's that Okita guy Heiji was talking about!
Oh, no!
If I don't get Heiji...
we're gonna lose!
There aren't any windows that open to the back of the side building,
and the front entrance is too conspicuous.
If he was going to carry Tarumi-san out, he'd use this entrance.
But he wouldn't be able to do it without passing in front of the busy gym.
It's impossible.
Someone would notice a bloody corpse and catch him.
Damn! Kudo's going to be here in 10 minutes...
Hey, you! Wait a sec!
You just came out of the side building, right? What were you doing?
I was just going to the bathroom!
I have something I wanna ask you anyway.
About what?
Before he was killed, Tarumi-san said something.
"I could tell everyone about that."
What was "that"?
I don't know! I'm telling you, I don't know!
Then what about that woman that Hakamada-san and Tarumi-san were fighting over. Is she here?
Are you kidding!?
Haori quit being the kendo team's manager ever since the...
Ever since the what? What are you hiding?
Man, did you see Okita's tsuki?
Yeah, seriously! If he hit me with that, I'd just fall over and die!
Hey, it's that college student.
He was running around during lunch, too.
Lunch? Were you the guys eating outside the entrance?
Yeah, that's us.
Those college guys were running around. One of them even borrowed my phone and brought the cops here.
After those three left, did you see anyone strange leave the building?
Yeah, actually!
You!
Before me, stupid!
There was another guy.
Someone else was carrying a bougu bag.
"Bougu" refers to kendo armor.
How do you know it was someone else?
Because even though he was wearing his armor, he was still carrying a bougu bag.
That's it! A bougu bag!
If you put the body in there, no one would notice.
The only one who could do that is Hakamada-san.
He killed Tarumi-san beforehand, and hid the body in the storeroom.
While he had the others out looking for Tarumi-san, he got to the storeroom first.
After the other three discovered Tarumi-san,
he stuffed the body in a bougu bag, and carried him to the locker room.
No... that's not right.
He couldn't hide in the storeroom before, as he couldn't be sure they'd even search there.
Not to mention, it was only by chance they all left.
He'd be trapped if anyone had stayed behind...
Hey!
Knock it off, if you know what's good for you.
Don't go around asking about Haori.
He went off and told you?
' Of course he did. Douguchi and I go way back.
He's been coming to me for help since we were kids.
No use suspecting this guy, anyway.
He can't stand the sight of blood.
Stay out of this. Got it?
Hattori, it's me.
Oh, Kudo?
Where are you, on a bus?
Nope. Uncle said waiting for the bus would take too long, so we got a taxi.
Oh, take your time! Get out and maybe stop for some udon.
And walk the rest of the way, take in the lovely Osaka scenery.
Stupid, we already told the driver where to go. We'll be there in a few minutes.
Anyway, are you guys even still in the tournament?
Hattori? Hattori?
Hey, you guys. Do you know anything about the CPR dummies in the storeroom?
Yeah, I come here a lot for practice.
How many dummies are there?
Two. A thin one and a big one.
That's it!
Say, that guy's Hattori from Kaihou, right?
Should he be out here? The finals start soon.
If my deduction is correct...
it should be here!
It should still be inside this storeroom.
I knew it.
That's how the killer moved the body.
Heiji! Heiji, where are you?
Just where in the world is that idiot?
Kazuha-chan!
We came to cheer you guys on.
Ran-chan!
Is Hattori-kun's team still in the tournament?
Actually, the finals are next, but I can't find Heiji anywhere.
I think he might have-gotten caught up in solving the murder that happened a little while ago.
M-Murder?
The question is who moved Tarumi-kun, and how he did it.
We found out how he did it.
One of my officers questioned a student at the entrance.
He said he saw a man in a face mask carrying a bougu bag leave the side building.
Wearing armor and carrying a bag for it?
I see! He put Tarumi-san's body in the bag, and hid his identity using the face guard!
Say, when did this guy leave the building?
They said it was after the three-students found Tarumi-kun's body.
In other words, the person who carried the body was someone other than those three.
Yeah. He was most likely already hiding in the storeroom when they found the body.
Tarumi's body was found earlier than he had planned, and so he moved it here.
By the way, Ohtaki-san... Have you seen Heiji?.
He was here, but he ran off somewhere.
Don't bother.
A trick like that won't make it look like Tarumi was killed here...
Kotegawa-san.
That's right, this isn't the place where Tarumi was murdered.
That happened in the pool locker room.
After Omotani-san and Douguchi-san saw the bloody body and left,
you came back and told him to go to the locker room, where he died.
Fool, it was only by chance that everyone left.
If anyone came back, that wouldn't work, would it?
No, it wasn't by chance.
If you told Omotani-san to go get the police, that'd make sure no one else stayed behind.
With Douguchi-san panicking, you knew he'd run straight to Hakamada-san. Besides, he can't stand the sight of blood.
He wouldn't touch the body and would just leave the scene.
You put a sedative in Tarumi's liquor and put him to sleep.
You used red paint to make it look like he was dead.
No one would've guessed he was alive.
In this dark storeroom, the paint looked like blood.
If a paint-covered man left, everyone outside would've noticed.
Oh, but they did!
They saw a man wearing a mask and carrying armor.
Hey, hey, you're not seriously suggesting that was Tarumi?
Why would he go out dressed like that just because I told him to?
You wouldn't be able to convince him with just words...
But if you showed him this in his drunken stupor, he might.
He said what!?
Tarumi-san really said, "I'll fucking kill you"?
Yes. The other members said that he may have had a grudge against Hakamada-san.
In other words, this could be some sort of retribution for Hakamada-san.
He's wrong.
The killer must have used this grudge to is advantage...
Right.
That's exactly what you did.
You came back here, put the sword in Tarumi-san's hands, and woke him up.
Then you showed him the dummy you'd dressed up in here earlier, and said:
"My God! What have you done!?"
Tarumi-san hated Hakamada-san, and he was still drugged and groggy.
He didn't realize it was just a CPR dummy with armor and Hakamada's name plate.
When he saw the sword in his hands, he naturally thought he'd done it...
Even though he didn't remember a thing.
You probably told him something like:
"Put on the mask and hide in the pool room before the police come."
You took off the bloodstained armor and put it in the bag, along with the sword, and told him to take them.
Of course, you had the bag ready nearby.
You made it look like the real killer was leaving with the body inside the bag.
Then you got to the locker room first,
waited for Tarumi-san,
and killed him for real...
You turned on the shower to wash off the fake blood on Tarumi-san,
then put the armor back in the bag.
You hid it somewhere and went to meet Omotani at the police box.
Isn't that when blood got on that towel?
You came to retrieve the CPR dummy and smear blood on this box to make it look like the murder happened here.
The fact that you have that towel is the real proof you're the killer!
If you're figured out all that, you probably know the motive too.
Of course.
I called your school and had it confirmed.
Last year, one of the new members in the kendo club lost consciousness and died in the middle of practice.
The school said it was an accident, but the truth was-
Yeah.
While we were breaking in the freshmen with a little hazing, Tarumi went too far, and he died.
Hakamada, the coolheaded one, happened to be absent that day and wasn't there to stop him.
And Tarumi said,
"I may have been the one who did it, but you all are just as guilty as I am. Even the manager."
"We're all in this together!"
And you were afraid that if this got out, it'd ruin your bright new career, so you shut him up.
Looks like you got it figured all out.
But since you didn't bring a weapon, there's one thing you forgot.
At the iaidou demonstration, there were two combatants.
So when I went and took the iaidou teacher's room to steal the katana,
instead of one sword, I took two!
What? A strange man told you to come to the locker room? Really?
Yeah... And when we got here, Tarumi-kun was like this.
The reason the culprit deliberately told them about Tarumi's location...
It was because he didn't want hem to look closely at the storeroom.
Which means that there's still something there that he doesn't want to be found.
Hey, which way's the gym storeroom?
Inside the side building, but...
Take me there!
Hey!
Conan-kun, where are you going?
Dumbass! If you kill me here, you're not gonna get away with it!
Don't worry. The police will just think it was the same killer.
Since I have an alibi,
I'll never even...
be a suspect!
Looks like this just isn't your day.
What!?
Hattori?
Don't tell me...
You're that high-schooler who single-handedly beat the best kendo players in Osaka!? That Hattori!?
You realize thy folly too late,
Yuranosuke!
Oh, there you are!
Heiji?
You can take it from here, Ohtaki-han?
Yeah, just leave it to me! You do your best, too.
Oh yeah! The tournament!
We don't have time for this!
You okay, man?
Oh, no...
Looks like it's over.
Oh, well. I lost the tournament, but I won the duel, right?
Heiji's match is really starting late...
It's very delicious.
This is the best!
Of course! Mom's blowfish is the real thing.
What's with her? She fell asleep before she could even pick up her chopsticks.
It's all your fault, Heiji!
Kazuha-chan was running around all day looking for you.
I couldn't help it I had to solve that murder case.
Like father, like son! He solved that case in record time.
No, this dull-witted son of mine just likes to play detective sometimes.
He's got a long way to go to catch up to you, Mouri.
So in reality, that means he thinks I'm not as good as Kudo?
He's the spitting image of you when you were younger, Heizou.
Who knows what he'll grow into?
You shouldn't be drinking, Toyama. Aren't you driving?
Relax, I was planning on having you drive me home anyway.
Something on your mind? That's why you had me drive, isn't it?
Yeah. It's about Heiji-kun and my daughter.
Don't you think they get along pretty well?
Kazuha's already seventeen; college and turning twenty are coming up fast.
If I don't want her to run off with some irresponsible punk she meets, I might as well have that kid of yours-
Toyama... Hurry up and spit it out.
Still haven't found a sense of humor, I see.
Real funny, Dad.
Do you remember that case at Osaka Castle thirteen years ago?
You mean the one with the body burned beyond recognition?
We took this pottery piece from the victim's belongings.
Yeah. We used to talk about what those .day pieces were for, remember?
We sure were ambitious.
Maybe it wasn't just big talk, though.
They found another one.
Another piece that looks quite similar to the one found on the victim's body.
I'm having people look into it, but it seems that it was made around the same time as the other shard.
And on this one, you can faintly make out the characters for "848".
Maybe, just as we suspected thirteen years ago...
It's still out there.
Yeah, an unimaginable treasure from the feudal era.
And that round one is Osaka Castle Hall.
The skyline behind that is Osaka Business Park.
You can't see it from here, but behind that is the coolest TV studio in Osaka!
And there's the symbol of Osaka, Osaka Castle!
Well? Isn't Osaka great?
Those're the exact words I used when I showed them around before.
And another thing: I already showed them the Osaka skyline from the Tsuutenkaku earlier.
I never should have let you guide the tour.
Come on! The Tenjin, Gion, and Danjiri festivals are already over! Osaka Castle was all that was left.
Well, if it were you, where would you take us next?
Let's see. If it were me...
I'd take you to the new Osaka Police HQ they recently began building.
Of course, I'd show you around as well.
Dummy. You're the only one interested in that stuff.
Sounds cool.
Wow, Osaka Castle looks a lot prettier than it does in pictures or on TV.
Doesn't it? It looks brand new thanks to all the renovations they've been doing.
It's been about sixty years since they last worked on it, so it's almost like it's being reborn.
It was seventy years ago.
Taikou-san originally built the castle in 1599.
Tokugawa took control of it in 1629.
And the last time was when the people of Osaka renovated it seventy years ago in 1931.
Kasuya Arihiro (64)
Wow, you sure know a lot about it.
Of course! Taikou Hideyoshi is my role model, after all.
And yet the crest pin you're wearing on your chest...
looks like the Tokugawa family's three leaf clover coat-of-arms.
Yes, well, this is-
Ieyasu-san, what are you doing here? His Lordship is waiting for you.
Oh. My apologies, Mitsuhide-san.
Ieyasu?
Mitsuhide?
"His Lordship"?
The "Four-day Toyotomi Hideyoshi Experience"
Yes, that's the name of our tour group.
All of the tour group members are fans of Hideyoshi that met on the internet.
Fukushima Toshiaki (32)
We've toured Nagoya and Kyoto, and now we're here in Osaka.
So, those nicknames and badges...
It's like a little role-playing game.
We draw straws every day after breakfast to determine our roles, and put on these badges.
Nobunaga, Hideyoshi, Ieyasu, and also Mitsuhide.
We call each other by the names we've drawn, and act according to those rotes.
The person who acts as Nobunaga gets to order everyone around.
Like having us buy juice or take pictures for him.
But in exchange, the person who plays Nobunaga has to pay for Hideyoshi and Ieyasu's dinner.
Isn't that right?
Yes, Nene-san.
You have a Nene, too?
That's right.
The person who picks the blank ticket plays Nene, who watches and laughs at the others' activities.
Katakiri Maho (39)
But I feel sorry for the person playing Mitsuhide then.
He doesn't get a free meal from Nobunaga and still gets ordered around.
But for three minutes in that day, he can choose to be Nobunaga.
I see, so his "Three-Day Rule" turns into three minutes?
Sounds retarded.
Sounds pretty fun!
Doesn't it?
There you are, everyone!
I couldn't find you. I looked all over.
Wakisaka Shigehiko (35)
Oh, please forgive me, my lord Nobunaga. Here is my tribute of oolong tea.
And I give thee these postcards of Osaka!
Oh, you didn't have to do that!
He doesn't seem like a very imposing Nobunaga.
But that's weird.
Where's the main character, Hideyoshi?
That's right. Weren't you guys together?
We were until just a while ago, but he ran off when his phone rang.
Any idea where he went?
No idea... He said to go eat lunch without him, though.
Then maybe he went to grab a bite by himself-
Hey, forget about these weirdos.
Yeah, we should be going to lunch ourselves...
Ladies and Lords Restrooms.
Finally! It's finally within reach...
I had to give up on it thirteen years ago...
Katou Yuuji (36)
Tour Group Member
But now, it'll finally be mine!
You idiot! Now we're back at Osaka Castle again!
How did you lose your wallet when it was in your purse?
You kept rushing us! I must have left it behind somewhere!
So? How much was in it?
...which is about $43.
5000 yen.
Forget about it then, it's probably gone already-
No way! My good luck charm was in it!
Don't cry start crying about it!
I'm not crying.
It's raining.
Doesn't look like it's going to let up anytime soon.
I brought an umbrella, actually.
This sucks.
What am I going to do?
Hey, maybe you forgot your wallet in that store.
Didn't you buy a disposable camera there, Kazuha-neechan?
That's right, I did.
We'll go ask.
I'll go check over there,
I already looked!
Is something wrong?
Yes. Remember the person playing Hideyoshi we mentioned earlier? We can't find him anywhere.
We looked in the castle, the stores around here, and the restrooms.
He doesn't seem to be anywhere.
Where could he have gone off to?
What's that up there?
Someone's on fire!
Uncle, get an ambulance!
Right!
Hey! What is it? What happened to you?
Hey! Hang on!
Yeah, this is it! This is my wallet!
You should thankful. I thought you might be back for it, so I didn't turn it in to the police.
It's your precious wallet, right? It had quite a few good luck charms in it, too.
Yup! Thanks, auntie!
There wasn't only one charm?
I picked up a few hoping that there wouldn't be a case like before that would ruin our sightseeing trip.
Really!? A man on fire fell from the roof? Are you sure?
Yeah. The police just came. Everyone's making a big commotion about it.
These things don't work.
I feel sorry for you, Inspector Ohtaki. This is the second case for you in as many days.
Well, that's the way it goes.
But I'm surprised you were able to figure out this man's name is Katou Yuuji...
It was from that badge.
Badge? You mean the family crest on his shirt?
The golden marrows are Hideyoshi's family crest. That's how we knew he was playing Hideyoshi in their tour group.
We had them identify him for us.
What? He was "playing" Hideyoshi?
We draw for parts from feudal Japan as a type of role-playing game.
I'm playing Mitsuhide, and Ieyasu is played by Kasuya-san here.
Kasuya Arihiro (64)
Fukushima Toshiaki (32)
Wakisaka Shigehiko (35)
Katakiri Maho (39)
Wakisaka-san is Nobunaga, and Katagiri-san is Nene.
And Katou-san was Hideyoshi.
Oh, that sounds like fun.
But if you knew he was missing, why didn't you report it?
Uh, well-
He disappeared so suddenly. We've been looking for him ever since.
He was wearing a red fleece sweater, so we thought he'd be easy to spot...
We never thought he'd fall from a place like that.
By the way, would you happen to know if Katou-san planned on committing suicide?
Not at all...
What makes you say it was a suicide?
No one would go out onto the roof in a downpour like this.
Besides, he was wearing an extremely flammable fleece sweater.
That's the proof he went out by himself and set himself on fire.
Wow, you've done a really thorough job of investigating. You sure you want to get involved?
Instead of telling me, you should be telling that the Chief's son...
What!? Hei-chan's here?
Yeah. He and Conan went inside Osaka Castle a second ago.
Hey Kudo, be sure to not slip and fall off.
Geez. He must think I'm an organ grinder's monkey.
What? Did you find something?
Just some fragments of something.
A lighter.
Could he have used this to
That's strange. Why is that...
T-That mark!
I still can't believe that Katou-san would commit suicide...
I know. He was really looking forward to coming here.
It's impossible to know what's going on inside a person's mind.
He may have come with us intending to commit suicide all along.
All that's left is to find what he set the fire with.
Yeah. If we could find that...
It was on top of the tower on the roof, this lighter.
Isn't that Katou-san's lighter?
Y-Yeah.
No doubt it was a suicide now.
No, not necessarily.
The top of this lighter was closed.
Would a person setting himself on fire really close the lighter afterwards?
But Hei-chan, couldn't the lighter have accidentally dropped and shut?
If that were the case, then the lighter would have slid further down the rooftop.
Besides, this lighter was placed where something else had been.
Something else?
Underneath this lighter, there was a strange pattern where the roof hadn't gotten wet.
There was a clean mark from the rectangular edge.
Something cylindrical was probably put there before the rain started.
Afterwards, it was taken and the lighter was put in its place.
Right, kid?
But Hei-chan, what could that "cylindrical" thing be?
Right now, I have no idea.
I think it's related to some shards we found nearby, though.
Inspector Ohtaki, these are the effects we found on Katou.
Wallet, wristwatch, cell phone.
Keys, cigarettes, and a fragment of something.
Hmm? A scroll?
What is this?
It just says, "Dragon".
And what's this fragment here?
Looks like a piece of pottery.
What? That fragment...
Maybe it's like the one in that case before where another person burned to death.
Our dads were talking about it in the car last night.
The body they found thirteen years ago and another body found recently were carrying similar fragments.
They said the one they found recently said, "848".
"848"? What's that supposed to mean?
I dunno. I didn't really understand what they were talking about, but I think that shard was part of a treasure.
I'm not lying!
They were whispering about some big treasure that a feudal lord left behind.
A big treasure, huh?
You're not making all this up, right?
Heiji-niichan!
Take a look at this burnt fragment.
The back of it is dotted with something shiny.
Hey, isn't that gold?
Yeah, but this alone isn't much of a treasure.
Man, this case makes no sense.
Why Katou-san left the group, went out onto the roof,
and suddenly burst into flames are all unsolved mysteries.
And the last puzzle is...
Why did he, as he was dying, grab...
The umbrella.
The obvious word we can associate with umbrella would be "rain".
One connection between rain and Osaka Castle is the Ryuukoseki.
"Ryuukoseki" means "Dragon Tiger Stone."
What's that?
Haven't heard of it?
Here at Osaka Castle, at the Sakura Gate, there are two stones called the "Ryuukoseki" that protect the castle grounds.
Sakura Gate (Ryuukoseki)
Legend has it that when it rains, the images of the dragon and tiger materialize.
Rains!?
Let me see this!
Hey!
That's evidence!
So it may be true after all.
Yeah, it may be waiting around here somewhere...
A secret cache of Hideyoshi's gold!
Somewhere right here in Osaka Castle.
T-Treasure? The unimaginable treasure that Hideyoshi left behind?
It's me. Don't make your move yet.
The police will be in the area for awhile.
Don't worry. The goods are almost within our reach.
Just stick to the plan.
What? A huge treasure left behind by a warlord?
Is this for real, Hei-chan?
I'm nearly certain.
It's this fragment that Katou had on him before he died.
It's faint, but you can see that the back has traces of gold.
He's right.
And how does this prove there's a vast treasure, exactly?
Put it together with this scroll he was carrying.
Still, that scroll only had "Dragon" written at the top...
This is-!
The characters were likely written with several sheets of paper on top.
So that if it were rained on, like the Ryuukoseki of Osaka Castle, the letters would appear.
But the important parts have burned away, rendering it useless.
The hell is this picture on the left?
Isn't it shaped like a gourd?
Taikou is the nickname of Toyotomi Hideyoshi.
The gourd was the symbol of the Taikou.
Maybe the fragment was originally from gourd-shaped pottery.
And maybe the pottery was packed full of gold!
But the size would be around 30 centimeters at most, judging from this.
In a gourd that small, no matter how much gold you put in, it wouldn't-
Have you forgotten?
The golden symbol of Hideyoshi, with one small piece for each valorous deed in battle...
A thousand!
But that means-
Right with a thousand of them, it'd add up to quite a treasure.
If you include the historical value, it would be priceless.
If these fragments were on the corpses from 13 years ago, the recent incident,
and Katou's corpse, the three of them could have been killed by someone plotting to keep it all to themselves.
But isn't it strange that the chief and the old man saw only the two fragments and knew about the treasure?
They couldn't have seen the scroll that we just did.
Maybe they figured it out from the shape of the pieces?
The fragment that my dad was looking at in the car looked like it had the mouth of a bottle,
and 848 was written on it.
I see. 848 is a number between 1 and 1000.
And if those fragments had gold on the back, one would be able to formulate such a theory.
But even so, it seems a bit far-fetched...
B-But it's not out of the realm of possibility.
Even after Hideyoshi's death, he'd amassed so much wealth at Osaka Castle that even Ieyasu considered it a threat.
There's still a legend that he dropped large amounts of gold into the wells to purify the water,
like with the "Clear Gold Water Well that sits in front of the tower.
Be that as it may, why is this a treasure map?
Couldn't this just be a regular castle blueprint?
Dummy. The gold hidden in pottery and disappearing ink is proof that someone's hiding something.
That scroll is the "Dragon," which means that naturally, there must be-
A Tiger.
If the scroll of the Dragon appeared like the Ryuukoseki and showed a clue,
then there should be a Tiger as well, correct?
And on that scroll, it's likely the clue will give the location of the jars.
Isn't that what you were about to say, Heiji-kun?
Toyama-san! Why are you-
Because I called him, and headquarters isn't far from here.
It looked like it had to do with the case Dad was talking about If I hadn't called, you'd be tied up here the whole time, Heiji.
She's done it to me again...
Kazuha's right Just leave this to us.
Yup, exactly!
I know a great little place across the Osaka Castle Shinbashi Bridge. Let's get dinner there!
There's a case going on right before my eyes, and you think-
Ah... I mean, I must respectfully decline your invitation...
Don't mind me. You just go enjoy yourself with Ran-chan, all right?
Forget you,then!
Come on, Ran-chan! It'll be just us!
Hold on, Kazuha!
Anyway, c'mon! You'll love this place!
Would it be all right if we went to go eat dinner?
We haven't had a thing to eat since lunch.
My clothes are soaked, so I'll change at the hotel.
Hold on!
We'll come right back, our hotel is close by.
Well, please hurry back.
That voice... could it be?
Hey, Ohtaki.
Understood. I'll tell my men.
Heizou? It's me.
You called your dad for Hattori-kun, didn't you?
You figured your dad was working on the case, and might be able to give some information, right?
And on top of that, you tried to cover it up by saying those mean things.
Yeah, but...
I just wanted to see his face when he solved the case.
I must be an idiot.
Yup, completely!
I am?
The same as me.
I hate to admit it, but there's something about seeing Shinichi at times like that.
Well, I mean, just at that one moment.
Don't you think, Conan-kun...
Ah, I forgot to bring Conan-kun!
Hey, you're right!
Hey, Hattori.
Have a look. Something unusual fell in an unusual place.
A battery?
Hold on... If this is from when Katou-san caught fire, then...
Yeah. It wasn't a suicide.
He was murdered.
I'm telling you, he's fine! Heiji and your dad are with him.
Besides, there's cops everywhere. There won't be any more incidents.
The deceased is Katagiri Maho-san. She belongs to the same tour group from earlier.
According to Kazuha, she suddenly lit her coat on fire and then fell in the river.
But the direct cause of death appears to be blunt trauma to the back of the head.
I believe that when she fell, she hit her head on one of the protruding stone pillars there.
A suicide?
I can't see any other possibility.
Kazuha, are you sure she wasn't holding anything other than a lighter?
Yeah. It looked that way to me...
Then was there anyone standing near her?
Not nearby, but.
There was someone at the entrance to the bridge.
That's it, then! That's who set the fire.
But I don't think that's possible.
That person was on the opposite side of us.
I'm sure it must be a suicide.
Like hell it is!
There must be something... Something to prove it was murder!
Stop, Hei-chan!
Dad...
Heiji, your ridiculous theory is way out of line!
You're making problems for the officers at the crime scene.
Don't be too hard on him, Chief. Heiji was just trying to solve the case in his own way...
Mouri-san, that may be what you're doing, but he's not investigating.
He's just getting in the way!
The spoiled brat let all this nonsense about "high school detectives" go to his head.
He's disturbing the body and the crime scene to feed his own ego.
He's just a liability to preserving the evidence.
Just now, two people died right under his nose while he couldn't do a thing to stop it.
He figured the police had established a perimeter so nothing would happen.
You should say that to the rest of us police, too.
What? At any rate, I don't want to put up with these amateurs any more.
Get out of my sight!
Chief! You're going too far!
Ohtaki, have you forgotten about the man I told you to shadow?
Oh! So that's why the Chief is...
Yeah. This is his own brand of tough love.
Ohtaki, were these homicides?
No... Katou-san lit himself on fire and fell from a castle tower.
His own fingerprints were on the lighter.
And with Katagiri-san, Kazuha can attest to the fact that she lit herself on fire and then fell in the river.
We have a few unanswered questions? but I've tentatively ruled them both as suicides.
In that case, shouldn't 2 or 3 officers suffice?
Toyama, we're leaving.
The police don't have time to spare this much manpower for such a small case.
Chief!
Heizou...
what are you planning?
Don't feel down, Hei-chan.
The Chief was just frustrated at not being able to do anything about the two cases, and took it out on you.
Well, I didn't think he had to hit him...
Could it be because of the killer?
Remember, I said I overheard my father talking about an old arson case?
He also said,
"Maybe there's a relation to the string of burglaries from around the same time."
Burglaries?
Yes. It was an unsolved case, a string of five murder-robberies.
Then maybe Heiji's father thought that the culprit from this time is the same criminal...
I see now.
Though it secretly pained him to do it, he played the stern father to get his son off the case.
Kanjinchou is a kabuki play about General Yoshitsune and his warrior monk servant, Benkei.
It's like something out of Kanjinchou, it could move one to tears.
Yeah, tell me about it...
...to think my old man had gone that senile.
Heiji...
I'm not understanding like Yoshitsune. If you push me, I'm going to push back.
I'll find the real killer and shove it in his face!
So basically, you're stupider than Yoshitsune.
But it's strange...
Hattori's father should have known that his son would react like this.
But Hei-chan... Even if you say there's a killer, this still looks like a suicide to me.
Then have a look at her right side. It's faded a little because of the water, but it should still be there.
A strange pattern with two or three dots.
You're right!
There're three markings, all the same shape.
Is that blood?
Yes. Probably spurted from the fatal wound.
Fatal wound?
Yes. Katagiri-san didn't die from hitting her head on the pillar as she fell.
If we suppose she was killed by being struck with a blunt object...
The splash of blood got o the killer, and got back on her when he moved the body.
In other words, the Katagiri that Kazuha saw on the bridge had already been bludgeoned to death,
And the body was set on fire then thrown down into the river to make it seem like a suicide.
But., after the fire was set, she looked like she was writhing around so painfully.
Yeah, there's no way that was a dead person.
That's just how it looked. Wasn't it dark out there anyway?
Well, yeah, but...
Anyway, those guys are the most likely suspects.
Let's find the tour group and ask for their stories.
You mean us?
We came back just like we said, to find all this commotion.
There seems to be a bigger crowd than before...
Did something happen?
What?
Katagiri-san caught on fire and fell off the bridge and died?
Off the bridge here?
Yes.
But why would she commit suicide by setting herself on fire?
Well, we're not sure it was a suicide.
Well then, would you mind telling us what you all were doing when you left with Katagiri-san?
I was eating in a local restaurant.
I was as well, but in a different one from Kasuya-san.
I went to go change at the hotel where the group is staying, the Seven Spears Hotel.
So you were with Katagiri-san?
Yes, until we got to the hotel.
If I'd known something like this was going to happen, I would have just stayed with her the whole time.
But why did Katou-san and Katagiri-san set themselves on fire?
It's almost as if someone ordered them to do it.
Ordered them?
That reminds me, Wakisaka-san... According to the rules of your tour, you were acting as Nobunaga, weren't you?
So everyone would have to follow your orders...
hen that goes for Fukushima too, since he can be Nobunaga for 3 minutes.
Since I play Ieyasu, I have nothing to do with it.
So it's down to the two of you, then...
That was all just for fun, we weren't ordering each other around!
It's not like anyone would obey an order to set fire to themselves.
Besides, Katagiri was playing Nene, who was just a spectator.
And in the first place, do you think we'd keep playing the game after a tour member just died!?
Ah, well. I guess there's some truth to that...
Inspector Ohtaki, Katagiri-san's personal effects included this shard.
What?
Why do they all have one of these?
She also had this photograph.
The two young people on the right side... aren't they Katagiri-san and Katou-san?
You're right So they were old acquaintances.
But who are the other three?
Isn't that Hirano?
This guy.
You're right He looks much younger in the picture, but that's him.
Who's this Hirano?
The whole idea of this tour was his idea.
All of us met each other through his website, and this is something he arranged.
He's also the one who thought up this roleplaying idea.
Unfortunately, he said some urgent business came up during the trip.
I see. So the guy who set up this mysterious murder tour didn't even come.
But was Katagiri-san really killed?
Yes.
As far as we can tell...
Well, if the killer is using the trip to commit his murders, then you should talk to Hirano-san.
You can find the homepage if you do a search for "The Legendary Lord's Treasure."
It was him, wasn't it?
The one that Ran and Kazuha saw when Katagiri fell burning into the river.
Yeah, but what I don't get...
He called Katagiri-san to the bridge, killed her, leaned her up against the railing...
...tied a rope to her and waited for someone to pass by.
Timing it so that she would burst into flames and then seem to fall wouldn't be simple.
Could someone really have done all that?
On top of that, what about the strange pattern of blood on Katagiri-san's right side?
That was definitely a zipper mark.
But still... None of those three were wearing clothes that zipped.
Could there be a reason for the murderer to deliberately change clothes and then lure her to the bridge...?
There is one.
One that would require a special change of clothes with a zipper.
The only thing left is to figure out who used that trick.
Yeah. It could have been any of the them.
Come on, Heiji. Let's head back.
The wind's picked up, too.
My umbrella!
Hey, Hattori! I think we both...
Overlooked a big possibility.
What a mess...
You can always just buy a cheap one from that store nearby.
Hey, where's Hei-chan?
He took Conan-kun and left He must have figured out who the culprit was.
His face was practically sparkling!
Damn it He couldn't have gone far, but where is he!?
It's no good. One's already at the hotel, but the other two haven't gone back yet.
Wait, what if he's planning to strike again?
He knows that if he waits too long, the suicides will be discovered to be murders.
So if he wants to finish the job, he'll have to do it tonight!
Damn it! Where is he?
There he is! It's Kasuya-san!
There's no way he's on his way back to the Seven Spears Hotel.
He's on his way to take care of some business.
All right, I'll call the police.
Don't If he sees any cops, he might panic and run before we have him.
Why don't the two of us...
see if we can shed some light on this case?
Hey, Hattori!
The old guy went into that shady-looking warehouse.
Hattori. Do you get the feeling we're being watched?
What are you doing? I'm going in!
Right.
It's pitch black. I can't see a thing.
Shh! There he is.
Looks like he's headed up.
Kudo, get that dart shooting watch of yours ready.
Right.
Kudo, what's going on? You gotta take a leak?
Damn, if he gets any further away, I'll lose sight of him!
Catch up as soon as you can, Kudo!
While visiting Osaka Castle with Heiji as our guide,
we met a strange tour of people who were roleplaying as feudal lords.
A member of that group, Katou-san, suddenly caught on fire and fell from the castle tower.
On a scroll he was carrying, we found the word "Dragon," and a message about a gourd.
It referred to the lost treasure of Hideyoshi.
Before a verdict was reached as to whether Katou-san had killed himself or been murdered, the second incident occurred.
Right in front of Ran and Kazuha's eyes, Katagiri-san set fire to herself, and fell off the bridge.
Hattori and I noticed a strange pattern of blood left on her coat, and determined that she'd been murdered.
We then tailed Kasuya-san to an abandoned warehouse.
Shh! There he is.
Looks like he's headed upstairs.
Kudo, get that dart shooting watch of yours ready.
Right.
Kudo, what's going on? You gotta take a leak?
Damn, if he gets any further away, I'll lose sight of him!
Catch up as soon as you can, Kudo!
Sorry to keep you waiting, Wakisaka-san.
It's all right.
So, where's the package?
There. It's in that box.
Oh, really?
There's so much in here, and I can't really see it in the dark...
There's a flashlight next to the box you can use.
This?
If you use it, I'm sure you'll find what you're looking for...
The Scroll of the Tiger.
Don't turn it on.
If you do, you'll be burnt to a crisp.
Just like what happened to Katou-san on the roof of Osaka Castle.
Isn't that right, Wakisaka-san?
Then... he killed Katagiri-san, too?
Yep. The one who killed the two of them was Wakisaka-san.
Giving them the same line he gave you: that he'd tell you where to find the Scroll of the Tiger.
In Katou-san's case, it was simple. He told him the scroll was hidden under one of the roof tiles.
He'd have to wait until night when there weren't many people around.
Getting onto the roof isn't hard, but finding the correct tile would be impossible without light.
Having no other choice, Katou took out his lighter...
Until he found a flashlight.
A specially rigged flashlight that would explode when turned on. A flashlight that Wakisaka-san left there.
So Katou-san thought the flashlight would work better than his lighter.
Yeah. That way the flashlight would disappear and the lighter with fingerprints would establish evidence to suggest suicide.
The shape of the dry patch on the roof is the proof of that.
Leaving the lighter in place of the flashlight would create the dry mark we found, and the explosion left a battery at the base of the castle.
But then what about Katagiri-san?
According to what those girls said, Katagiri set fire to herself, and there was no one nearby.
They saw her body burning in the river,
and all she had in her hand was a lighter.
That had to be a suicide.
Of course it would appear that way.
Because the one who was standing on the bridge on fire wasn't Katagiri-san... but Wakisaka-san.
What?
Since everyone had gone to gawk at the Osaka Castle crime scene, the bridge was empty.
Wakisaka-san called her there.
He hit her with a blunt object, killing her.
He threw her body into the canal, and poured kerosene onto it.
All that remained was to wait for someone to come by, and then set fire to his own coat.
He'd pretended to be on fire, dropped the lighter and set fire to Katagiri's body.
Then, he jumped into the canal himself.
If someone looked over the railing, all they'd see would be Katagiri's burning body.
That way, even if one determined the cause of death was a blow to the head,
the witnesses would say it was due to hitting her head on the bridge pillars on the way down.
It worked out well since those girls saw him by chance.
If no one else had been there, the estimated time of death would have been way off.
No, he called his own witness just in case.
Kazuha and Ran nearly saw him by accident on the bridge, though he panicked and ran.
T-That person was-!
Fukushima-san.
Even though he didn't know a thing about the case, just from hearing she fell burning into the water, he concluded it was a suicide.
But think about it:
Normally, a person who would want to kill themselves with fire wouldn't jump into water.
In that case, one would assume the fire was set by someone else, and the victim jumped into the water to put out the flames.
That's the proof that he saw her light her coat on fire.
With the way things were going, if you changed your voice and called Fukushima pretending to be the police, he'd come running.
But that's strange...
Afterwards, Wakisaka's hair and clothes weren't wet at all and if he'd made a small error, he'd have serious burns.
That's because on top of his clothes...
...he was wearing a drysuit.
With a hood, he wouldn't have to worry about burns, and neither his hair nor his clothes would get wet.
He could dive into the water, resurface some distance from the bridge, take off the dry suit and hide it somewhere,
and rejoin the onlookers without attracting suspicion.
And the very flammable fleece and coat are both items you gave to the victims ahead of time, right?
You said it would be a signal to help identify each other for these secret meetings.
You left a trace of blood on that very coat in the case of Katagiri.
A mark left when you carried her body.
It was the zipper from your dry suit, and the edge of the crest button you were wearing.
In other words, if we look closely at that badge, we should find the evidence that we're looking for.
But why target me and other two?
It wasn't just you three. He also killed the tour's founder, Hirano-san.
had a professor friend of mine check out his homepage,
and the daily updates he made haven't been kept up for three weeks.
So the burnt body found in the castle moat the other day was most likely...
Yeah, that's right.
I killed Hirano-san, and Katou-san, and Katagiri-san.
To avenge my murdered grandfather Masakiyo, who loved studying Hideyoshi more than anyone.
Grandfather?
You saw the photo.
The old man unrolling the scroll in the middle was my grandfather.
He always used to tell me about the scroll he found...
and of Hideyoshi's hidden treasure.
He stopped his quest to find the treasure, and tried to donate the scroll as a national treasure.
His colleagues, who had begun searching for the treasure themselves, opposed him.
He left thirteen years ago for Osaka, to finally convince them...
He left thirteen years ago for Osaka, to finally convince them... but he never came back.
The burnt corpse they found in the moat thirteen years ago...
It was my grandfather, murdered by his colleagues.
The pottery shard, along with the Tiger Scroll are two clues my grandfather found and kept secret from the rest of them.
The only clue I had to go on to find his colleagues was that one photograph they took with my grandfather.
I looked long and hard for each of them.
I never thought that one of them would have had plastic surgery.
Then the man in the picture next to your grandfather-
Is me. After that incident, I needed to change my appearance.
It seemed that Katagiri-san recognized my identity as her former colleague.
I can see why you'd want to kill me, but why Wakisaka-san, too?
If you do, you won't be able to find the treasure!
As for that, he most likely doesn't have the Scroll of the Tiger on him.
I've found his address, I suppose I'll just have to ransack the place.
Step back, the both of you!
Push the button on that flashlight, and fall to your death.
The fallen killer and the boy detective.
Before that, will you tell me how you knew Wakisaka-san was the culprit?
Someone besides him could have pulled that trick off.
You must have had some other sign.
And why would I tell a loser like you?
It was the umbrella!
The umbrella that Katou-san grabbed with his dying breath represented the symbol of Nobunaga: the golden paper umbrella.
That's how we knew that it was the one who played Nobunaga, Wakisaka-san!
Brat! When did you-
Get down here before I pump your friend here full of lead!
Don't! Stay back!
Oh, well...
Idiot!
What an obedient little...
You're... Hattori Heizou!
Dad...
Even though you changed your appearance after disappearing 13 years ago, it seems your rotten voice and nasty personality are just the same.
You're under arrest for illegal possession of firearms and attempted murder!
And let's not forget about the five robbery murders you committed thirteen years ago...
It's long past time for you to pay up!
Murders? What are you talking about?
Don't bother playing dumb.
We have your voice on the victim's answering machine,
and a palm print from when you hung up the phone.
Things will just be harder on you if you resist arrest.
So unless you want to get hurt...
Come along quietly, and let us take you in!
And so, as we watched in amazement, the Osaka Chief of Police led a massive group of arrests,
closing a case that had been open for thirteen years in the blink of an eye.
You're probably feeling pretty good right now.
You lured us here with that shard and the promise of the Scroll of the Tiger.
And you were finally able to avenge your grandfather.
On top of that, you'll get to keep the treasure all to yourself.
It's not a map to the treasure.
What?
The Scroll of the Tiger says:
"I go now to obtain that which is described in the Dragon Scroll. -Kajisuke"
Kajisuke? The thief who dove into the Clear Gold Well to steal Hideyoshi's gold?
Yes... That was a letter he left behind as a joke.
Then why didn't your grandfather just tell us all that?
He couldn't bring himself to.
Not when he saw how hopeful and excited you all looked.
Especially you, who'd invested so much in finding the treasure.
It... can't be.
What!? He used us as bait?
Yeah, that's what your dad said.
"Sorry, Conan-kun. These guys are pros who can smell cops coming from a mile away."
"To round up the whole gang, Heiji's hot-headedness and clumsy tailing will make the perfect diversion."
So he hit me and got me all riled up just to dangle me in front of the bad guys?
Yeah. He predicted that Kasuya-san would bring some henchmen, since carrying 1000 gourds would require a lot of manpower.
Before I got in danger, Inspector Ohtaki, who was sitting there waiting, grabbed me.
Hold on, if he was "sitting there waiting," then my father knew Wakisaka-san was the murderer all along?
Yeah. He heard about Katou grabbing the umbrella, and had a tail put on Wakisaka.
That goddamned sly-ass dad of mine...
If he ever does that to me again, I'll stick my fingers so far in his ears, his teeth'll wince!
Ow. Shizu, can't you be a little more gentle?
You can put up with that much.
You put Heiji through a lot more.