The inside of the heart is like a mystery,
shining on the two is star and snow
Finally a showdown between this duo, the courtroom
as the stage, what's going to happen?
The one who sees the single truth, his body is a child, his
mind that of an adult, his name is Detective Conan!
Tokyo District Court
Thank you very much for all that you've done.
It's all thanks to you.
No, it was nothing.
Anyway, Okada-kun, although there's going
to be a lot ahead of you, try to work hard.
Yes.
Terumitsu, let's get going.
You're right.
We'll be taking leave now.
Okay, take care.
Mom!
Mom, did you win again?
It wasn't me who won, but my client over there, I just helped out.
Anyway, Ran, I'm sorry, did I make you wait?
Just a little.
But in return Conan said that you're
going to take us out for a feast.
Hey...
Well, the thing is, some business that
I have to attend to just showed up.
Eh?
Sorry, but I'll be sure to make it up to you later.
Ma'am, I have a car ready for you in the back.
Thank you.
Ah, Kuriyama-san, after this could you take
Ran and Conan out for something yummy?
Ah, Kisaki-san.
Huh? Kujoo-san.
I heard that you took up to be Usami Shinji's attorney.
Yes, I was actually thinking of greeting you.
Kuriyama-san, who is that person?
She's an ace at the Tokyo District Court who has been
called the "Madonna of the Courtroom", Kujoo Reiko.
Kujoo Reiko (33), Prosecutor
She's in charge of the case that the boss is going up against.
Oh.
So that's the famous "Madonna of the Courtroom".
It's going to be fun, going up against someone like you.
I hope you'll go easy on me.
Same here, please go easy on me.
Let's both work hard.
Very well then, I will have to excuse myself now.
It seems like Kisaki has kept her winning streak.
Yeah?
Well, that's going to end soon.
I'll show her what it means to be truly defeated.
The Courtroom Showdown! Kisaki vs. Kogorou
(Part One)
Sheesh, all my mom ever seems to think about is her job.
Hey, Kuriyama-san, what is the case
that Miss Kisaki took up about?
Eh?
About one month ago, there was a case in a Haido district
construction site where a man's body was found.
Do you remember?
The victim was a man named Hirasawa Tsuyoshi.
Hirasawa Tsuyoshi (28), Victim
Looking at a steel pipe at the crime scene, they were
able to tell that he was killed with a blow to the head.
And then, with a set of car keys found at the scene,
they were able to come up with a suspect.
So, that suspect is the person that the boss
is going to be defending, Usami Shinji-san.
So what is the prosecution suggesting that the motive is?
Well,
three years ago the victim was drunk at a train station
and pushed Usami-san's son down the stairs.
That boy, Masaki-kun, hit his head and died.
That's horrible...
Hirasawa-san was tried for capital punishment,
but the fact that he was under the influence of alcohol
helped so that he was only given probation.
That's impossible!
You go out and kill a person and don't even go to prison for it?
Give me back my Masaki! Bring my Masaki back!
The prosecution believes that Usami-san murdered
Hirasawa-san for revenge of the death of his child.
Oh... I feel so sorry for him.
So, what is Usami-san saying?
The thing is, he says that he was drunk and can't remember.
Tokyo Detention Center
You look well.
Please, sit down.
So? Do you remember anything yet?
Usami Shinji (40), Suspect
No, nothing.
Oh. Then I'll ask again, from the beginning.
On the night of the crime at 8:30, at the
Yamazen bar, you ran into the victim.
I just met him by chance.
Because of what happened in the past, we got into an argument.
The problem is after that.
The victim was murdered at the construction
site between 9:30 and 10:00.
During that time, where and what you were doing is the question.
Anything at all would help us.
If you remember something, please come talk to me.
By the way, about your wife... No matter how
many times I call, I can't get a hold of her.
She's not involved in this!
Why?
You may be divorced now, but she was still your wife.
She's probably worried about you.
She hates me.
She doesn't care what happens to me.
Sign: Haido Yokochou Business District
Boss!
Kuriyama-san.
So, did you find it?
According to the address I got from
the police, it should be around here.
Mom, over here!
Ran!
Why are you here?
I'm sorry, they said they could help, so Conan-kun and...
Eh?
Conan-kun, it's not good to come
to this kind of place at this hour.
Anyway, this is it right?
The shop we were searching for.
Huh?
Note: A "masu" is a small, wooden, cube-shaped cup for drinking sake.
The "mi" at the beginning of "mimasu" is short for beautiful.
This is the victim's wife's bar?
Beautiful Masu written as "Mimasu"?
This must be it!
What an unusual name.
Kameda Masako (38), Usame Ex-wife,
I've already forgotten about him.
I've heard how you two got divorced, however Kameda-san...
'It's all your fault that Masaki died,
why didn't you die in his stead?'
When he got drunk, he repeatedly said that.
I understand how you feel, but your
ex-husband is in trouble right now.
At this point, if there's anything that can help him, please tell us.
I don't even want to remember him right now.
The construction site where the accident
occurred is near here, isn't it?
Regarding the night of the crime, if you now anything...
I don't know anything.
If that's all you wanted to talk about, please leave.
Welcome!
H-huh?
Dad!
W-what are you guys doing here?
The same goes for you!
Me?
Well, I just thought I'd have a drink like always.
Are you acquainted with this lady?
Uh, well, I think I'll come another time.
Does that man come here often?
Yes, Mr.Mouri is a frequent patron here.
Speaking of which, on that night...
Huh?
Ah!
"That night"... do you mean the night of the crime?
Do you know something about what happened?
That night... my husband, Usami, came here.
Usami-san came to this bar?
Yes.
And you're sure that it was on the night of the crime?
That was the only time he'd ever come to this bar.
Boss!
The night that Usami-san came here,
do you remember what time it was?
Well, I don't remember it to that extent...
However, Mr.Mouri might remember.
That man?
Thank you, good job on remembering.
Well, it's not like I remembered it for Usami's sake.
It seems that we're finally starting to shed some light on this.
Sign: Mouri's Detective Agency
I'm home.
Dad!
W-what is it, Ran?
You were still awake?
At this hour, where were you out drinking?
Who cares where I drank?
You're starting to sound like your mother...
If you have a problem with her, why don't you say it in her face?
Same as usual.
Huh, it's none of your business.
You reek of alcohol!
Hahaha! 'Drunken Beam', fire!
Stop it!
Childish...
Other than that, I came here to ask you about something.
Hmm, my measurements are a se-cr-et!
The murder at the Haido district construction
site, do you remember?
Yeah, I guess there was a case like that.
That night, you were at the Mimasu bar, weren't you?
Huh?
Well, I can't remember every little detail...
Drink some coffee and straighten yourself up.
Just looking at her face has made me sober.
Perfect timing, then.
Do you remember seeing this person?
Huh?
This man, if I remember correctly, was at Mimasu.
Please, tell us in detail.
Well, if I'm not mistaken...
I was drunk at Mimasu and sleeping.
Sir, your phone. Sir!
Sir!
Huh?
Uh, hello, this is Mouri.
Hello?
It sure is hard to hear in the bar...
Yeah, that had to be him.
Are you sure?
What, are you saying you don't trust me?
That's not what I was saying.
Hey, you only saw his face for a moment,
yet you say you remember him?
Detectives only need to see a face once to remember it!
At least, that's what I'd like to say.
After I finished up my phone call, he
was sitting down at the counter.
That's weird...
Ah!
Did you finish your phone call?
Ah, no.
It was a wrong number.
He's an unfamiliar face.
Oh... he's just an old acquaintance of mine.
Hmm.
Well, I guess I'd better head home.
It's all right, just take your time Mr. Mouri.
Here, I'll serve you one on the house.
On the house?
Oh, then I guess I'll have another drink!
He was there for about 30 minutes before he left,
but when I left the police cars were really noisy.
I heard that someone died at a nearby construction site.
That person at the bar, do you remember what time he came in?
9:25
Huh? How can you say that so confidently?
It's like I said, I'm a detective.
You looked at your cell phone's clock, didn't you?
Shut up!
What time did Hirasawa-san die?
The estimated time of death was between 9:30 and 10:00.
So if Usami-san came into the bar at
9:25, then we've developed an alibi.
That's true.
That is if we can rely on what this person has said.
What, you're still doubting my story?
Of course!
At the time, you were drinking weren't you?
Why you!
You were out drinking as usual!
I'm home. Oh!
Welcome home, Mom.
You guys came?
Hello.
Hello, Conan-kun.
We were planning on bringing Dad too, but he ran away.
Is that so?
Boss, did the defendant remember about going to his wife's bar?
After leaving the bar, he insists that he can't remember anything.
In that case, the time gap doesn't get filled.
Hm?
Time gap?
Looking at this case's timetable, Conan-kun
started saying something unusual.
The time that Usami-san left the bar with
the victim, Hirasawa-san, was 8:30 right?
The time that Mouri Ossan saw Usami-san at Mimasu was 9:25.
But the time it takes to get to Mimasu from the bar is fifteen
minutes, so he should have been there at 8:45.
I see, so there's a 40-minute gap in time.
With a person that he hates so much, I was wondering
what he was doing for 40 minutes.
Um, about Mouri-san...
With that man, it's all right.
He's not the kind of person who would
refuse to testify just to get back at me.
The defendant was at his ex-wife's bar?
Yes. lt seems that he has an alibi, so the
defense is moving to gather witnesses.
Even if they insist on an alibi, if it's just
his ex-wife, there's little credibility.
The thing is, Mouri Kogoro is on the witness list.
When the defendant showed up at the ex-wife's
bar, Mouri happened to be there.
Oh, is that so?
Hey, Mouri Kogoro used to be Miss Kisaki's husband, didn't he?
Yes. They're currently separated.
This might turn interesting.
Be sure you testify for Mom!
It's like I said, if she begs me on her
hands and knees, I'd think about it.
Good grief...
Here's your oden.
Note: A Japanese stew.
Thank you, Ma'am.
Huh?
There's some cute octopus in here!
It's a baby octopus.
We don't usually use it in the Kanto region, but it tastes good.
Ooh...
You're right, it's delicious!
After you eat that, kids should go home.
Hm?
That sound, isn't that your cell phone?
Mama, could you get that?
Note: A general term for female bar owners.
All right.
Here you go.
Thanks.
Hello, who is this?
Wah, you're...!
Wha-
Hey Ma'am, does the Ossan always hang his coat there?
Yes, so it doesn't get dirty.
Then that means on that night, too...
Wait a minute, if that's true...
Hey, you guys.
Hurry up and go home.
But we haven't even finished talking!
Like I care!
Kiddy time is over, and now it's grown up time.
Go on, sheesh!
Dad!
Sheesh, so annoying.
Huh?
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
That phone call, was it from that person?
That person must be... the prosecutor?
Welcome!
Yo! I was waiting!
I wonder what the prosecutor has to do with Dad?
Who knows...
We will now begin with session one of
the defendant, Usami Shinji's, trial.
We'll start with the prosecution and their opening statement.
Defendant, Usami Shinji. Registered address, Yamanashi
prefecture, Shimokasuya county, Tsubonouchi village.
Grounds for our appeal...
Is this all that the prosecution has requested as witnesses for?
Yes, it's just as we thought.
In accordance to section 199, we request
that he be tried for homicide.
Real trials sure are tense.
Yea.
Okay, we will now commence with witness testimony.
Your Honor.
Hm? What is it, prosecution?
Before that, we would like to call a new witness to the stand.
A man who runs his own detective agency, well known
as the Sleeping Kogoro, Mouri Kogoro-san.
Boss, what could this mean?
I'm not quite sure myself.
Why is Dad going to be a witness for the prosecution?
It's as I expected.
What does the Defense think?
No objections.
Very well then, we call Mouri Kogoro to the stand.
Bringing him forward like that, what is she planning?
Soon, I'll present to your first true taste of defeat.
As I thought, Madonna has realized that, too.
If that's the case, this battle isn't looking good, Oba-san
Boss, what could this mean?
Why would the prosecution bring up the defendant's alibi?
I don't know... They must have something planned, though.
It sure was a surprise that Dad would testify for the
prosecution, but I guess he's still on Mom's side.
Yeah, you're right, For now.
Next Conan: The Courtroom Showdown!
Kisaki vs. Kogorou (Part Two)
Matches
Next time, everything will be resolved!
You mean between Mom and Dad?
Uh, well...