The inside of the heart is like a mystery, but the shining stars and sparkling snow illuminate them.
The tension is rising in this courtroom scene,
what will happen to the couple's case?
The one who sees the single truth, with the body of a child, his mind that of an adult, his name is Detective Conan!
Ran's mother, Attorney Kisaki, has gone up against the prosecutor, the "Madonna of the courtroom," Kujo Reiko, in the Usami Shinji case.
The one holding the key to Usami's alibi
is none other than uncle himself.
However, he was suddenly called as a witness for the prosecution.
The Courtroom Showdown! Kisaki vs. Kogorou
(Part Two)
Tokyo District Court
Mouri-san, where were you and what were you doing the night of the crime?
I was in the Haido district, drinking sake at the Mimasu Bar.
There, you got so drunk that you fell asleep, right?
Yes, that's correct.
Kujoo Reiko (33), Prosecutor
Do you remember what time you woke up?
It was at 9:25 P.M.
How did you know the time?
While I was sleeping, I got a call on my cellphone, and the bar owner woke me up.
And my cellphone's clock read 9:25.
At that time, were there any other customers?
I was the only one, but my signal wasn't very good
so I tried to exit the bar as a man came in.
Do you remember that man's face?
Of course, it was the defendant, Usami Shinji.
Usami Shinji (40), Suspect
Sensei, what could this mean?
Why would the prosecution bring up the defendant's alibi?
I don't know... They must have something planned, though.
It sure was a surprise that Dad would testify for the
prosecution, but I guess he's still on Mom's side.
Yeah, you're right.
For now.
I am through with questioning.
Very well then, the defense may begin cross-examination.
Thank you.
So, Mori-san, how long was the defendant, Usami, at Mimasu?
He was there for about half an hour, that is, until about 10 P.M.
So you're saying that at the time of the murder, between 9:30 and 10:00 P.M., he was at Mimasu?
Well, I guess that's how it'd be.
That is all.
Then we will escort the...
Your Honor.
May I ask just a few more questions?
Very well then.
Thank you very much.
Mouri-san, you stated earlier that you fell asleep in the bar and the hostess woke you up.
Yes.
Where was your phone at that time?
Here it is!
Of course, it was in the pocket of my jacket, which was hanging on the coat hanger on the side of the counter.
In that case, someone could very well have changed the time on your phone while you were asleep, right?
For example, the bar's hostess.
That's absurd!
Objection!
What the prosecution is stating is pure conjecture.
I ask that the prosecution back up their accusation with facts.
I understand.
Then, Your Honor, I'd like to call the owner of Mimasu to the stand, Kameda Masako-san, as a witness.
She got us...
S-Sensei!
To be so caught up with the alibi and to overlook
this possibility, it was my miss.
What's happening, Conan-kun?
So long as the cell phone wasn't in Uncle's hands, the alibi doesn't hold up.
In other words while Uncle was asleep, someone could have changed the time on his cell phone and called him to get him to check the time.
After that, once Uncle took his eyes off of the phone again, you would just have to change it back.
There's a possibility that the bar hostess could have done it.
B-But...
Yes, just like you, Kisaki-sensei believed that the couple didn't get along, and overlooked the possibility that the alibi was fake.
However...
Kameda Masako-san, on the night of the crime, did you
tamper with the clock on Mouri Kogorou's cell phone?
Kameda Masako (38), Usami's ex-wife
Well, what is it?
Let me remind you that if you give false testimony, you can be charged with perjury.
Masako-san.
It's as... it's as the prosecutor said.
So you admit to tampering with the cell phone?
Yes.
In that case, what time did Usami actually cross paths with Mouri and showed up at your bar?
I added 30 minutes, so I expect it to have been 9:55.
Your Honor, the crime scene and the bar are about a 10-minute walk away...
which means the defendant had more than enough time to commit the crime.
Any questions from the defense?
Just one.
Masako-san, when we talked before the trial,
you stated that you hated the defendant.
Then why did you agree to tamper with his alibi?
I don't know.
I'm done.
Tokyo Detention Center
Hey, Usami-san.
Is what your wife testified in court true?
But it's strange, if you got your wife
to craft your alibi, why didn't you use it?
I've told you before that no matter what, to tell me the truth.
Otherwise, I can't continue to be your lawyer.
I don't need a lawyer anymore.
What are you saying?
I'm the one who committed the crime!
Just hurry up and throw me into prison or whatever!
Hello, Mori's Detective Agency.
Oh, Detective Takagi.
So, how did it go?
And Usami's home address is?
Uncle.
Ah, is that so? I understand.
Thanks for the trouble. I'll buy you a drink later.
See you.
Hey Conan, I'm going out for a while.
Take care!
"Hirasawa's Murder Investigation Report."
I knew it.
I'm home!
Huh?
Conan-kun, where's Dad?
Hey, Conan-kun.
Baby octopus was found in the victim's stomach?
Isn't that...
Hey Conan-kun, sheesh.
Usami's Apartment
Well then, where should I begin?
O-ji-san!
C-Conan, why are you here?
Ran-neechan asked me to watch over you to make
sure you didn't get used by the prosecutor again.
Jeez, she needs to trust her own father more.
Just don't mess anything up.
Okay!
This must be Masaki-kun.
What's that?
These are... Mimasu's matches!
But why are they here?
Hey Uncle, was there an ashtray in this room?
Huh?
Now that you mention it, I don't see one.
Usami probably doesn't smoke.
But look, there were matches sitting there.
These are Mimasu's matches.
It's not that strange for him to have these then.
But he was on bad terms with his ex-wife, right?
Then why?
There are different types of couples.
Kids wouldn't understand.
Jeez...
This is...!
Haido Yokochou Business District
Hey, auntie.
Are you putting baby octopus in the stew today?
Oh, little boy.
That's right, it's sort of like our signature dish here.
Do you like it?
Yeah! After all, it's really delicious.
I see. I'll treat you some, then.
Woo-hoo! Thank you!
You're welcome.
Auntie, you have it too, that photo.
There was one in Usami-san's room, too.
Is that so?
What? Call him as a witness again?
Yeah, he said that he screwed up last time,
so he wants a chance to make up for it.
But we don't have a solid alibi anymore, even if Mouri testified now...
Whatever it is, it must have something to do with the time gap we were talking about the other day.
That, and he said that if you looked at this you would know.
These are Mimasu's matches.
That and one other thing.
He said to look at what was inside the victim's stomach.
In his stomach?
Sensei.
All right then, Mouri-san, could you please tell us about that night again?
At what time did you go to Mimasu?
The usual time, at 7:30.
And when did you fall asleep?
8:30.
In other words, you were asleep from 8:30 until 9:55, the real time when you were woken up by the phone?
Well, I guess you could put it that way.
What is Kisaki trying to prove?
Who knows, probably just going around in circles.
So if anything happened in the bar during that time, you wouldn't have noticed?
What are you trying to say?
For example, if the defendant Usami took the victim to the store while you were asleep.
Objection! This is all baseless conjecture.
No, I have proof.
Please take a look at the victim's autopsy report.
In the victim's stomach, something
called baby octopus was found.
It is considered a signature dish at
Mimasu and is prepared regularly.
When I checked with restaurants around the area, none of them had baby octopus on their menu except for Mimasu.
Even if what the defense says is true and the victim
visited the bar, what difference does it make?
Quite a difference.
The victim would have met another person with a motive to kill him besides the defendant.
Hey, hey, I was the only customer in the bar at that time.
Not necessarily a customer.
What?
Y-You don't mean...!
Don't say something stupid!
Mimasu's owner doing such a thing! I, Mori Kogoro, must...
Your line of thinking is completely wrong.
D-Dear!
The key to solving this case lies in what the defendant Usami and his ex-wife Masako-san truly feel for each other.
Since the accidental death of their beloved son, the two had grown so bitter that they divorced.
It is the fault of that man, Hirasawa, and that night Usami met up with him and got into an argument.
After the argument, they were kicked out of the bar at 8:30.
From there the defendant brought Hirasawa-san to his ex-wife's bar, Mimasu.
Apparently, the defendant, upon encountering the man he hated for so long, didn't know what to do and took him to his wife.
That's what happened at 8:45.
With Hirasawa-san in front of the wife, her forgotten rage against him was rekindled.
From there, she first sent the defendant home, lead Hirasawa-san to a nearby construction site and murdered him.
The wife hurried back to Mimasu, saw me sleeping and planned a way to create an alibi.
In other words, the alibi that the prosecution saw past
wasn't for the defendant, but was for his wife solely.
As expected of you, Mr. Detective!
A wonderful and elaborate story.
However, this is a courtroom, not a place for you to share your clever guesses.
It's a place where we unveil the truth.
Do you have any objections to my theories?
First off, how do you know that the defendant
left first, leaving the victim behind?
How can you be sure he didn't take the victim out after asking his wife for a made-up alibi?
If that were the case, wouldn't the defendant have asserted his alibi from the beginning?
One more: how do you explain the defendant's car keys left at the crime scene?
That's easy. The defendant deliberately left them near the body.
After leaving the bar alone, the defendant
probably got worried and returned.
This is when he witnessed Masako-san murdering Hirasawa-san.
Perhaps the defendant thought of it this way:
Rather than his wife take the blame for it, wouldn't it be better if a drunken him take it?
And maybe he, like Hirasawa who killed their son, would have gotten off easier.
How absurd. The fact that he was drinking doesn't necessarily mean he would have gotten off lightly.
He could have been charged with a felony.
That's because he still loves his wife even now.
He thought he still had a place in her heart.
As evidence, I have Mimasu's matches.
It is written Mimasu in Romaji, too.
So what exactly does that prove...
Yes, if you read this Romaji backwards, it is "Usami M".
In other words, their late son's name, Masaki-kun.
The name that brought them happiness before the divorce.
The defendant saw these matches and realized how his wife truly felt, and so he took the blame to save her.
That's a lie! I'm the one who killed him!
That detective is full of crap!
I killed him with my own hands!
Please stop, dear.
It's all right, now I understand how you feel.
I'm sorry, having to testify against you like that.
I didn't know about the keys at all.
It's just as Mouri-sensei said, I killed Hirasawa.
Masako...
That man... didn't remember me at all.
Sir, haven't we met somewhere before?
Huh? With you, babe?
Well, I don't remember. If I'd met a beautiful woman like you, I'd never forget.
Is that so?
I couldn't forgive him for ruining our family's happiness, and then not even remembering my face.
Masako...
No matter how beautiful this couple's love is, a crime is a crime.
If you truly love your wife, after she's paid for her sins,
you'll find the strength to start over. Isn't that true love?
I admit defeat today. Congratulations.
And I can't believe that the case took a turn, not because of a lawyer, but because of a witness.
That's a first for me.
You're right. A first for me too.
All right then, until the next trial.
When that comes, please go easy on me.
Same here.
Attorney Kisaki from now on should extend her winning streak.
Pardon?
Flinging dirt on people like her, that's my job after all.
Dear, thanks for everything today. I suppose I should thank you.
Huh?
The thing is, um, after this, if you have the time
we could go to a restaurant and just relax...
Young lady.
Hmm?
If it's all right with you, would you like to get a bite to eat?
Dad!
Well, it seems like he's pretty busy, so let's do
it another time. We're going, Kuriyama-san.
O-Okay!
Ah, Mom, wait a minute! Mom!
Dad, you're impossible!
Geez... It doesn't look like things are going to go the way Ran wants anytime soon.