The inside of the heart is a mystery.
Stars and snow are all around us.
Valentine's Day is almost here!
Would you like a case with those chocolates?
Seeing through to the one and only truth,
I look like a child, but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
Right around the time people start getting over the New Year's fever...
Girls begin to pour their hearts into a bittersweet gift of giri or honmei chocolates.
Giri chocolates are obligatory gifts to friends and colleagues, while honmei chocolates are gifts for boyfriends, husbands, or potential lovers.
And, that's because...
The Truth Behind Valentine's
(Case Part)
What's so great about Valentine's Day? It's just nonsense...
Everyone just falls for the candy companies' marketing hype...
But, people are always happy to receive candy!
Chocolate tastes so good!
You're complaining because you know you won't get any, right?
That's right...
Being in this body means I'll only get the kind of chocolates meant for babies.
Well, in a way, Edogawa-kun's right.
The Japanese are the only people who get all lovey-dovey saying "chocolate this, chocolate that..."
No one seems to realize that Valentine's Day was named in memory of Saint Valentine, who died a gruesome death.
Is that so?
But, my mom told me...
Valentine's Day is when girls create precious memories by professing their love through chocolates.
That's why chocolate can be both sweet and bitter.
Then, did you buy any chocolates for your "special someone," Ayumi-chan?
No, my dad said I'm still too young for that...
Well, it is too early for kids like you to be worrying about love...
So, then?
What about that girl back at the Detective Agency?
Oh, Ran?
She's excited that we're lodging at the Suito House tomorrow...
But, she never mentioned anything about chocolate.
I see...
Well, let's just pray that there won't be another case of "Bloody Valentine's"...
Hey, hey...
Bloody Valentine's was the day when...
Al Capone shot down seven people with machine guns as they stood in front of a garage on February 14, 1929.
Capone?
Now that I think about it,
that guy said he was from the same town as Capone...
Conan-kun, you're gonna get left behind
Sorry...
What are you doing, Conan?
So, Haibara-san, chocolate is...
Geez!
Why do we have to go all the way to a lodge deep in the mountains just to make sweets?
It's so we can become good brides. Good brides.
Maybe so, but couldn't you do that just as well at home?
Now... Don't worry, don't worry!
But, you never told me we were making sweets.
You said we would get to see lots of cute mountain animals.
Oh? You didn't know?
Suito House is famous for making chocolates that will make you lucky in love.
What?
Then, you're going to make homemade chocolates for Kyogoku-san and finally confess your feelings to him?
Y-Yeah... At least that was my plan...
What's wrong, Sonoko?
He hasn't called lately, Makoto-san that is.
And, I always get his answering machine when I call him.
You're kidding.
I called and told him I'd make Valentine chocolates and give them "to the person I like most."
It was my "love-love strategy" after I failed in knitting a sweater for him.
She's in for it now!
I should've came right out and said, "This chocolate is for you."
It'll be okay!
When you give him those chocolates, I'm sure Kyogoku-san will...
You're strong, Ran.
Huh?
I'm falling apart after not being able to talk to him for only a week...
But, it seems like forever with Shinichi-kun, doesn't it?
A little...
But, I've gotten used to it.
It doesn't matter that he's not around...
It's not a big deal.
Good afternoon!
We're here to make chocolate.
Please take care of us.
Ah, granny, so you're the one...
You're the owner of this lodge, who tricked my girls into coming out to the mountains just to make sweets.
D-Dad!
I'm terribly sorry.
Yuasa Chiyoko (61)
Lodge Owner
Whether it's a trick or not...
Couples have come here to make chocolates for the past ten years, and end up getting married later on.
The stories in magazines and on TV just exaggerated things.
After my husband, the previous owner, died four years ago...
Mononoke-san started appearing and has caused the number of guests to steadily decline.
Mononoke-san?
Well, if a snow storm comes, don't go outside by yourself...
Unless you want to get strange gifts from the Mononoke that lives in these mountains.
S-Strange gifts?
She means the chocolates!
These mountains are quite difficult to navigate, and accidents happen often.
Especially during this time of year, chocolates are always found lying atop the snow.
Next to the bodies of those who died there, that is...
Nigaki Yoshitaka (28)
Lodge Guest
Some say it's the ghost of a woman who came to this lodge to make chocolates, but got lost in the woods and died.
Other rumors say it's the doing of the Yuki-onna.
Yu-Yuki-onna?
Now, there's nothing to worry about.
The police said wild animals scavenge through the victim's belongings looking for food.
So, they said it's a coincidence that there are always chocolates around the bodies.
Well, I'm heading off to work now.
Take care.
Nigaki-kun!
It's good to be a hard worker...
But, please don't get lost in the woods.
Konakawa Mika (26)
Lodge Guest
If the Yuki-onna finds you, it could be very bad.
It'll be alright.
If the Yuki-onna wants to give me some chocolates, I'll just tell her this...
"I already have a girlfriend, and her name is Ako!"
Amari Ako (25)
Lodge Guest
Don't, Yoshitaka. It's embarrassing...
Later.
Hey...
What is it, little boy?
That guy said he's going to work, but what's he going to do?
He's a reporter who's going to film and take some pictures...
...so he can use them as evidence in the case he's been working on for five years.
At first, I was the one who followed him with the camera, but he said I would've definitely seen something.
"Seen something?" You don't mean the Yuki-onna, do you?
That's not it! He wants to take pictures of a certain animal.
But, right now, it seems it's as much a myth as the Yuki-onna.
Myth?
That's right.
After one was found dead in 1905, there hasn't been a verifiable sighting of one in over 100 years.
Sagami Yuusou (42)
Lodge Guest
It's an animal that's on the red list of endangered species.
The legendary Japanese Wolf!
A wolf?
But, is that okay to do?
Hunting such an endangered species...
Oh, this gun?
I'm only going to use this rifle to lure the wolf into a trap.
Well then, ma'am, I leave my friend in your care.
Time and time again, we get visitors who think about nothing but hunting wolves...
I guess I'll go out for a while, too.
If anyone else shows up, please take them to an empty guest room.
Granny, where are you going?
I'm going to visit my husband's grave in the woods.
Is it okay to go by yourself?
This forest is like my garden.
Also, Saburo is coming with me.
Saburo?
There, there... What a good boy!
What the...? It's a dog.
I hope that reporter doesn't mistake your dog as the wolf if he sees it in the woods.
That's not possible. He saw-the wolf around 10:00 PM.
So, what does that have to do with it?
Saburo isn't allowed outside after dark.
Ah, is that so?
Well, while she's out, how about we get started on making some chocolates?
Yes!
Huh? Isn't that old lady supposed to teach them?
That was how it was done in the past.
We're the ones who teach the guests now.
It's to thank her for taking care of us each year.
But, she continues to prepare the ingredients to this day.
I see.
Looks like your "love strategy" or whatever might fail again.
Shut up, old man!
Valentine's is in three days!
Let's get a move on!
I see,
So, Granny's husband died in an avalanche?
Thats right.
It was four years ago, on February 14th.
They said it had been a week before Saburo found him buried in the snow.
However, the other body hasn't been found yet.
"The other body?"
My brother's.
He went missing on the same day.
The police said his body is still buried somewhere in the snow.
But, I get the feeling he's still alive.
Other than visiting the previous owner's grave, that's why I've been coming here every year.
I'm sorry for telling you such a sad story.
No, that's fine.
Excuse me, is there anything we can do to help?
No, no! Men aren't allowed in the kitchen!
You'll end up get hurt just like Nigaki-kun did!
I'm sorry.
I did it! It's complete!
Lovely!
It looks so good, it looks so good!
It really does.
Well then, should we take a group picture with your chocolates?
Sure!
Looks like a snow storm's coming.
I wonder if Nigaki-kun is all right...
Hey, we're going out for a little while to check up on Nigaki-kun.
Wait here.
Okay!
Oya, where are you going?
We'll be right back.
Nigaki-kun!
Where are you!?
You can't find Nigaki-san anywhere?
Yeah, we split up to look for him, but...
The storm's getting worse.
Anyway, let's go search for him before the probability of finding him is zero!
Conan-kun, wait here in the lodge.
Like I'd do that...
Let's go, Saburo!
Yoshitaka!
Nigaki-san!
Nigaki-kun!
Where are you?
Nigaki-san!
Where are you, Nigaki-san!?
Hey! Answer us!
Where are you?
Nigaki-kun!
A gun shot?
Now, this is bad...
Did he kill it before me?
Who are you?
Me? I'm a guest who's lodging at the Suito House.
Itakura Hajime (37)
Lodge Guest
Damn it...
Where are you, Nigaki-san?!
Hey, Saburo!
Nigaki-san?
It's no use, he's no longer breathing.
He was beaten to death?
What is this?
This is...
...a chocolate?
Yoshitaka, please answer me!
Not good, the snow storm has gotten stronger.
What should we do?
If we continue searching in this, we'll be putting ourselves in danger.
B-But, we can't just leave Nigaki-san out here...
A dog?
So deep in the mountains...
Could it be Saburo?
That can't be! Saburo is supposed to be at the lodge.
Could it be that Conan-kun...
Conan-kun!? What are doing out here?
Didn't I tell you to stay at the lodge?
I'm sorry!
But, look...
Didn't Mika-san tell us that Saburo found the previous owner, even though he was buried in the snow?
Huh? Yeah.
That's why I thought he could help us find Nigaki-san.
Nigaki-san has come to this lodge several times before, so Saburo should know his scent.
Then, did you find Nigaki-san?
Yeah, I found him,
but it's already too late.
What!?
It can't be!
It's a lie... Right, Yoshitaka?
Yoshitaka!
Stay where you are!
Look! There's blood on his face.
And there's a blood-covered stick laying next to him.
There's no doubt about it.
This is a murder case.
Until we find the murderer, we shouldn't disturb the crime scene.
Murder...?
No way...
You're awfully cocky for someone who's not with the police.
Yeah, it's true I'm not with the police anymore, but I'm a former officer, detective Mouri Kogoro.
What!?
Mouri, as in...
That famous detective?
Then, do you know who the murderer is?
No...
With the weather like this, it's difficult to get an accurate time of death.
Also, the murderer's footprints have been covered up by the snow.
All I can gather is that the murderer's clothes should have Nigaki-san's blood on them,
and that Nigaki-san was most likely killed in the afternoon.
The blood on Nigaki-san's face has been wiped off in one area,
and the sunglasses he's wearing indicate that he was killed before sunset.
After that time, it would be too dangerous to wear sunglasses and walk around in this dark snow storm.
I see. As expected of a famous detective.
Oh, this is nothing.
It's not too tough for a good investigator like me.
Are you really sure about that?
Geez... Not this kid again!
That's why you need to look carefully into his sunglasses.
Now, you can see that his left contact lens is out of place.
You idiot!
That must have happened when the murderer hit him.
But, there's no contact lens in his right eye, and it's not in his sunglasses either.
You're right.
I see!
When he was hit, his right contact lens and glasses fell off,
but the criminal only noticed the sunglasses, and put them back on the body.
I see. This sure is one elaborate criminal...
Hey, don't misunderstand.
Hey, isn't it possible that the criminal did that intentionally?
Right, right!
But, what reasons would they have for doing that?
Oh, yeah... I also found something strange.
See? It's a chocolate!
It was on this guy's lap.
It has "Yoshi" is written on it.
What?
Wait, that's the chocolate Ako made today.
Why!? Why is my chocolate here?
Didn't you put it there next to the body?
That's impossible for Ako-san, because the chocolate was in the kitchen before we all left the lodge.
Both before and after that, Ako-san had always been with us.
Then, who brought the chocolate all the way out here?
It was probably the criminal.
Since we already know they've tampered with the body...
...there's a high probability that they put the chocolate here to frame Ako-san.
Anyway, the first thing we should do is to head back to the lodge and call the police.
The police won't be able to come for a while.
Oh, Sagami-san! How did you know we were here?
I just followed the sound of the dog barking.
You said that the police can't come, what do you mean?
The tunnel that links the lodge to the road was blocked off by an avalanche about 30 minutes ago.
It'll probably be a day or so before it can be reopened.
I can't believe it.
Are you serious?
Then, does that mean we have to spend the night at the lodge, even while the culprit roams around freely?
The criminal who killed Nigaki-kun could even be among us.
I don't have a problem with it.
There's more of a thrill that way.
If you don't want to stay with us, you can sit next to the corpse all night.
But, by the time morning comes, you'll have frozen and turned into the Yuki-onna.
The remaining blood that wasn't wiped off,
the repositioned sunglasses,
and then Ako-san's chocolate...
Why did the culprit go through all the trouble of bringing Ako-san's chocolate from the lodge?
This picture was taken right after Nigaki-kun was beaten.
How do you know that?
That reminds me...
Before I ran into you guys, I saw a very suspicious person in the woods.
Eh!?
It was a tall, well-built man wearing a black wool hat.
A black wool hat?
Could it be...
Could it be?
The Truth Behind Valentine's
(Deduction Part)
Next Conan: The Truth Behind Valentine's (Deduction Part).
Next Conan's Hint!
Playing ball.
Next time, the case rises to its climax!
A brilliant dog plays a major role!
It's Saburo!