The inside of the heart is a mystery.
Stars and snow are all around us.
The big event is Valentine's!
Both love and the case draw closer.
Seeing through to the one and only truth,
By Sonoko's invitation, we went to a lodge in the mountains called the "Suito House" to make Valentine chocolates.
However, a reporter by the name of Nigaki Yoshitaka-san...
went into the forest to find a certain species of wolf, but still hadn't returned when a fierce snow storm began.
Worried, we searched the forest for him...
But, by the time we found him, Nigaki-san had been killed!
The remaining blood that wasn't wiped off,
the repositioned sunglasses,
and then Ako-san's chocolate...
Why did the culprit go through all the trouble of bringing Ako-san's chocolate from the lodge?
The Truth Behind Valentine's
(Deduction Part)
The Truth Behind Valentine's,
Deduction Part!
I see... I understand.
So, what did they say?
Did the police say they're coming right away?
Yuasa Chiyoko (61)
Lodge Owner
There wasn't an avalanche, right?
No, an avalanche came down around 8:00 PM, and the tunnel's full of snow right now.
They're not sure when they can get here... It might be as late as tomorrow morning.
See? It's just like I told you!
What about the chocolates?
It's just like we thought, only Ako-san's chocolate is missing.
I thought we'd find something on Nigaki-san's camera and video camera, so I brought them back...
But, the tape in the video camera is blank.
The only lead we have is this single roll of film in the camera.
However, we can't get it developed unless the officers are here.
Oh? If we just need to develop and print the film, I can do it for you.
Nigaki-kun said he wanted to see the picture of the wolf as soon as possible, so I brought the equipment with me.
Just wait a little while... I'm going to use the bathroom as a make-shift dark room.
Yeah, go ahead.
Let me help you.
Hey, is that really all you found?
Isn't there anything else in the in the victim's bag, like more rolls of film or extra tapes?
There are, but they're all unused as well.
Then, is it possible he was killed before he started filming?
It might be that Nigaki-san likes to take pictures more than video.
That's not true!
Between the two, he actually liked filming video more.
He even filmed a lot last night.
Then, can we see those video tapes?
S-Sure...
But, there are a lot of them in his bag, so I don't know which ones were from last night.
Kid, you really shouldn't watch them
They're a dead person's videos, after all.
Why? Is there anything we shouldn't see?
N-No, nothing like that...
It's just kind of weird...
In that case, do you want to watch them together on the TV in the living room?
Good idea, having more eyes might help us find some kind of lead.
Then, I'll go bring the tapes from his room.
Is this it? The "chocolate of love" you're making for me?
Too bad, this one's mine!
Hey, hey... Don't tell me it's for another guy?
Maybe...
I knew it... Watching someone else's home videos is really boring.
I'll make one for you when the girls get here tomorrow.
What the heck? Unlike you, I prepared my present ahead of time.
Huh? Hey, you piece of junk TV, work right!
I apologize for having a really old TV...
My husband treasured it because it was the first gift he gave to Reiko-san.
Reiko-san?
She was my husband's ex-wife, but she died of an illness about 12 years ago.
Hey, Saburo! Isn't it time for you to go back into your cage?
So, she's his second wife...
Yeah, I heard about it from the previous owner.
While he was mourning the loss of his wife, that old lady stayed here as a guest.
They comforted each other, and later decided to get married.
The old lady's also very good at making sweets, which has brought a lot more customers here.
But, I guess I still feel sorry for her husband.
You've heard about this? Have you stayed at this lodge before?
Y-Yes, we were here once before.
Aside from that, is this fourth video tape the last one, young lady?
Yes, that's the last tape that was recorded yesterday.
Now then, the tape's almost full.
Finally, it's over.
Neither of you were on these videos.
Of course! I just got here this morning!
And I got here just a little while ago.
Still, we didn't get anything useful from that.
But, I know Nigaki-kun's time of death.
Huh?
Look at this picture.
This picture was taken right after Nigaki-kun was beaten.
How do you know that?
You see the shadow spots in the picture, right?
None of the pictures have them except for this last one.
See? It's the shadow of blood on the camera lens.
He probably pressed the shutter button accidentally from the shock of being hit.
But, we don't know if those shadows are blood or not.
It has to be.
Because we just tried to take more pictures with that camera, and the same shadow spots were shown.
Then, this confirms that he was killed in the afternoon.
That's strange...
There's something about Mika-san's explanation that doesn't match up...
So, in other words...
The criminal must be one of you three who weren't in the lodge with us during that time.
Hey, hey!
Then, what about the chocolate?
It was left in this lodge until 8:00 PM, right?
Then, tell me who brought it there!
More importantly, what kind of idiot would do that?
Walking all the through a snow storm, giving chocolate to a person they just killed, and then returning here?
T-That's true, but...
Didn't I tell you?
There really is someone or something living in these mountains.
S-Something?
That reminds me...
Before I ran into you guys, I saw a very suspicious person in the woods.
Eh?!
It was a tall, well-built man wearing a black wool hat.
I shot him by mistake, thinking he was a bear.
A black wool hat?
Could it be...
Could it be?
A man wearing a black wool hat?
Is it possible that it's that guy?
Um, excuse me...
Do you remember what the man you met in the woods looked like?
He might be someone we know.
Not really...
I could tell he was a man from his muscular build,
but he had sun glasses and a scarf covering his face, so I couldn't see his face.
Is that so?
Ran?
It could be Nattsuya-kun...
It has to be.
I know Nattsuya-kun's still alive!
I have to go welcome him back!
Mika...
You can't! There's still a snow storm outside.
But, Nattsuya-kun's waiting for me in the woods. Nattsuya-kun is...
Nattsuya's already dead!
He died in an avalanche four years ago!
I'm sorry. I'm really sorry, Mika.
Um... Who's Nattsuya?
He's my brother, the one who disappeared four years ago.
Mika was his girlfriend.
Then, the chocolate with the checkered pattern that Mika-san made this afternoon is...
Yes, she was going to offer them to my brother at his grave.
My brother really liked chess.
My brother's grave is also in these woods, next to the graves of the previous owner and his ex-wife.
It wasn't that way three years ago, though...
There used to be a grave for each person who died here.
However, wild animals destroyed most of them, and now only those three graves remain.
How come those three graves were the only ones that didn't get destroyed?
It's probably because I take Saburo to visit them everyday.
My husband used to always take him there too.
Well, anyway... Unless there's someone else besides us hiding somewhere...
The criminal must be that suspicious man in the woods who was wearing a wool hat.
So, what does that mean?
I don't know when that Nigaki guy was killed...
But, we know the criminal's the one who put the chocolate on his lap, right?
You left the chocolate here around 8:00 PM while looking for Nigaki, and stayed together until you found him...
So, it's impossible for you guys.
I ran into you not far from the lodge, so you probably just started searching for Nigaki, right?
Since it takes at least 20 minutes to go from the lodge to the crime scene...
I wouldn't have enough time to get the chocolate and put it on the body.
Of course, it's also impossible for me.
Because at 8:00 PM, I was far away from the lodge, watching the avalanche cover up the tunnel.
But, you could have just heard about the avalanche from the news on the radio.
That's not true.
When I called the police after we returned to the lodge, they had just received the report about the avalanche.
Well, since that girl made the chocolate, wouldn't she have had the best opportunity to put it there?
What?
You took your friend and left before everyone else had gone to start searching, right?
Isn't it also true that you weren't together the whole time?
Y-Yeah. We split up in the middle of searching, but...
You could have prepared a similar chocolate in advance,
and placed that one on Nigaki when you "searched for him" the first time.
Then, you snuck back here while everyone else was looking for him and hid the chocolate you made today,
in order to make everyone believe that the criminal stole your chocolate, right?
Of-Of course not...
That's impossible.
It was already snowing when we first went searching for him.
If he was killed when you said, it would be snowing in this picture, wouldn't it?
But, the chocolate...
Then, do you want to compare them yourself?
I took pictures of all the chocolates we made today.
If you look at them closely, the one found at the crime scene has melted a little bit, and has a small mark on it.
But, the handwriting and shape is exactly the same.
If there's someone who can make an exact copy like this, I'd love to meet them.
In other words, your deduction is wrong.
Y-Yeah...
Well, what a relief!
At least we can rest easy now, knowing that the culprit isn't one of us.
Then, good night, everyone.
It looks like the criminal really is the man wearing the black wool hat.
Hey, were the pictures on the film in Nigaki-san' camera really taken in the past two days?
Huh?
Because the film was full, right?
Wouldn't he have put a new roll of film inside?
Then, why don't we compare those photos to the still frames of the video he recorded yesterday?
The outfits in the photos and video are exactly the same.
However, Nigaki-san was taking the pictures and video, so he wasn't able to be compared.
If you look through the window in the first photo, you can also see that they were both taken last night.
Therefore, the last picture with the blood spots on it must have been taken this afternoon, right?
No one left the lodge since our arrival yesterday, until he went to take photos in the afternoon.
So, that means no one could have taken the picture except him.
It's a possibility that the photo was tampered with while it was being developed...
How could I have done that?
Ran-chan was standing right next to me while I was developing them!
Right?
Y-Yeah... She didn't do anything suspicious.
She even wore gloves when she removed the film from the camera, so she wouldn't get her fingerprints on the pictures.
More importantly, wouldn't it be easy to know if the photo was edited just by checking the negatives?
Oh, yeah! There was those strange, completely black photos, though.
Completely black photos?
There were some pictures before the last picture with the blood spots.
But, the pictures were so dark, we couldn't see anything on them.
Really?
But, we thought that something might have been covering the lens when the shutter was pressed.
It's just as I thought...
The trick was the blood spots on the photo!
But, I still don't know how the criminal shot that picture.
And the point I don't understand the most is the chocolate placed on the body...
Having it there ruins all of my possible explanations behind the trick!
Here you go, Saburo! It's your favorite ball.
Could it be that the man wearing the black wool hat really is the criminal?
Oh? That's strange.
When I came here last year, you loved playing with it.
Hey, why did you name your dog Saburo?
Taro used to have a another dog named Jiro, but he's already gone.
Eh? He died?
Yes. My husband, Taro, used to have a dog named Jiro, another hunting dog like Saburo.
Note: Taro means "First Son", Jiro means "Second Son," and Saburo means "Third Son."
He told me when that Jiro died only a little while after Reiko-san did.
I'd really like to see a picture of Jiro.
I think there are some in my husband's photo album.
I'm pretty sure it's kept in the room that Nigaki-san was using.
Then, I'll go and get it for you.
I'll go with you too.
Hey, does Saburo have any strange habits?
Like going out for walks on his own, for example?
No, he just stays in the lodge most of the time.
The only time he usually leaves the house is when we go visit the graves.
He's a very smart dog!
When we get close to the graves, he runs ahead, sits there, and waits for me happily.
Actually, he does have one unusual habit...
He won't eat anything on a stormy day.
It must be because he's sad that he can't go outside!
But, the day after the snow storm's over, he eats a ton!
Wasn't that Ako-san just now?
What happened?
Come and see for yourself.
Those guys were rooting around looking through everyone's stuff without permission!
What?
N-No...
We thought we might find something that would give us some kind of lead for the case.
W-We didn't take anything.
I suppose you won't mind if I search you, then?
S-Sure...
Then, let's go to the other room.
There's a streak of blood on this sweatshirt, but it looks like the middle part is missing.
That's the sweatshirt Nigaki-kun was wearing when he cut himself.
He cut himself?
While he was chopping the chocolate into pieces, he accidentally cut his left thumb with the knife.
The cut wasn't very big, but since he was afraid of blood, he swung his hand around and got it on his sweatshirt.
After that, Granny was shocked and hurried to get the first aid kit.
Ako was so worried about him, she started crying in his room...
So, I had to try to calm him down instead, to keep things from getting worse.
However, Ako was probably the most tired person there, since she had to take care of him afterwards.
Right?
I'm sorry.
I found it!
Here it is!
See? The dog on the left is Jiro, and the one on the right is Saburo.
The medals on their necks are awards the local government gave them because they had helped save several people.
Wait. It might have Saburo on the left and Jiro on the right...
Just as I thought.
I understand everything about this case now.
I know why there are two completely black photos before the blood-spotted one.
I know who brought the chocolate, and why it was placed on the body.
Most importantly, I know who killed Nigaki-san.
It was...
that person!
You know who the culprit is?
Is that true, little boy?
So, who is it?
Is it that man wearing the black wool hat?
About that, Uncle Kogoro's going to explain it to everyone in the kitchen right now.
In other words, the culprit can only be you.
Don't move.
The Truth Behind Valentine's
(Solution Part)
Next Conan: The Truth Behind Valentine's (Solution Part).
Next Conan's Hint!
Completely black photo.
Next time, we'll finally find the solution!
Whenever something's solved, that person is never around, right?