The inside of the heart is a mystery.
Stars and snow are all around us.
All the pieces have come together!
What's going to happen to Ran and Sonoko?
Seeing through to the one and only truth,
I look like a child, but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
By Sonoko's invitation, we went to a lodge in the mountains called the "Suito House" to make Valentine chocolates.
However, a reporter by the name of Nigaki Yoshitaka-san,
went into the forest to find a certain species of wolf, but still hadn't returned when a fierce snow storm began.
Worried, we searched the forest for him.
But, by the time we found him, Nigaki-san had been killed!
Just as I thought.
I understand everything about this case now.
I know why there are two completely black photos before the blood-spotted one.
I know who brought the chocolate, and why it was placed on the body.
Most importantly, I know who killed Nigaki-san.
It was...
that person!
The Truth Behind Valentine's
(Solution Part)
The Truth Behind Valentine's,
Solution Part!
All I need now is proof.
If I could find some proof that shows how the culprit moved the chocolate to the crime scene,
I could expose the culprit who killed Nigaki-san.
This is Sonoko's chocolate and the checkered one next to it is Mika-san's.
Then, where's Ran's?
Hey, what are you doing here?
Huh?
Why are these here?
W-What?
Itakura Hajime (37)
Lodge Guest
Sagami Yuusou (42)
You know who the culprit is?
Is-is that true, little boy?
So, who is it?
Is it that man wearing the black wool hat?
Yuasa Chiyoko (61)
Lodge Owner
Uncle Kogoro's going to explain it to everyone in the kitchen right now.
Here we are, just like you asked, Detective-san.
When you said you know who the criminal is...
Does that mean you know who the man with the black wool hat is?
No. There really isn't a need to investigate that mystery man,
because the criminal who killed Nigaki-san is here in this room!
W-What did you say?
Didn't I already tell you?
In this situation, it's impossible for one of us to have brought the chocolate all the way over to the body!
That's right, the chocolate.
The one who holds the key to unlocking the mystery behind it...
Sa-Saburo!?
Then, you're saying the key to solving the mystery is Saburo?
Yes, thanks to him, I solved the mystery of how the chocolate was placed on Nigaki-san's body.
Surely you're not suggesting that the dog put the chocolate there.
After you guys left the chocolates here to go looking for Nigaki, the four-eyed brat left with that dog, right?
If the kid and the dog found the body before anyone else.
How could the dog have put the chocolate there?
Yes, it's true that a dog was with Conan.
But, was it this Saburo?
This Saburo?
Everything became clear to me when I saw that this Saburo likes to play with round, ball-like things.
However, the dog on the video from last night wasn't interested in those things at all.
Moreover, I heard that the previous owner took Saburo to visit the graves everyday.
When I heard the story about the wild animals that destroyed every grave but those three,
I figured out everything.
The reason the dog does that, is because the previous owner...
had trained Saburo to guard his ex-wife's grave all day.
What are you talking about?
The dog goes to sleep in his cage every night. How could he go visit the graves?
Yes, that would be impossible, if there was only one dog.
Granny's husband told her that Saburo had a twin named Jiro, who "died" 12 years ago.
Actually, after I saw the mark on the chocolate, I should have known.
There are actually two Saburo's, and the mark on the chocolate was a dog bite!
Simply put, the other dog is Jiro.
Both dogs took turns to visit the grave each day.
For some reason, Granny's husband decided to keep Jiro a secret by faking his death.
Now I get it.
They were trained to eat every other day.
That's why one wouldn't eat whenever there was a storm, because they rotated eating schedules each day, right?
Then, the legendary Japanese wolf that Nigaki-kun saw five years ago was.
That was probably either Jiro or Saburo.
They also brought chocolates to other victims.
Are you crazy?
They're just regular dogs, so how could they bring chocolate to victims?
No, they aren't regular dogs.
They're famous search-and-rescue dogs that even received medals for their work.
They were trained to give a chocolate to each victim that they found.
But, they can only do this during this time of year, since there are a lot more chocolates in the lodge.
Also, the reason why some of the blood on Nigaki-san's face was wiped off,
was because the dog thought he was a victim, and licked his face in order to wake him up.
Hold on.
If the dog put the chocolate there, the criminal could be anyone, right?
What are you talking about?
Didn't you see it?
The blood-spotted photo was taken in the afternoon, right after Nigaki-kun was attacked.
In other words, the criminal must be one of you two who don't have an alibi during that time.
Did you see anything strange in that photo?
Since that photo was the last one taken, the film rewound.
You know how it makes that "jii" sound when it's rewinding?
The criminal must've heard it.
But, for some reason, the culprit didn't take the film,
even though there was a chance that their picture might have been on it.
That's true.
But, why?
Because that picture was not taken when the attack occurred.
It was just a normal picture Nigaki-san took in the afternoon.
However, he didn't know that his blood had been on the camera since the night before.
Last night? You don't mean when he cut his finger with the knife?
That's right.
The proof is that there wasn't any blood in the middle of the sweatshirt he was wearing.
Most likely, the camera was hanging from his neck, and the blood got splashed onto the lens.
So, the culprit told Nigaki-san to take a picture with the now blood-covered camera in the afternoon.
They met up with him again in the evening, attacked him,
and put sunglasses on him to make us think he was killed in the afternoon.
In other words, the only one who could be the culprit is you!
Original Broadcast Date:
February 11th, 2002
Based on manga:
Vol 33 Files 3-6
In other words, the only one who could be the culprit is you,
Amari Ako-san!
It can't be.
Ako is...
Ako's the culprit?
It's a lie!
Because, when we went looking for him, the snow storm was coming and it was getting dark.
That's why she had to leave in a hurry.
If the snow storm kept getting stronger, and he decided to return to the lodge early, her plan would be ruined.
She also took two blank pictures so that the blood-spotted photo would be the last one on the film.
She knew that it would look suspicious if there had been three blood-spotted photos.
All the other films and videotapes taken before the crime were replaced for the same reason.
But, I could have done that trick as well.
No, only Ako-san could have done this.
This trick required the correct film to be in the camera for the crime.
She took all the other rolls of film out beforehand,
so she could easily switch the camera's film with the one that had the blood-spotted photo on it.
She's also the only one who could have taken the film from his bag without being suspected.
That's right.
Being the one he could always count on to develop his photos,
I honestly can't understand how you can be fine with tampering with the film he liked so much.
How about we watch one of the videotapes that you threw away and replaced with a blank one?
On it.
There's a clear view of you walking towards Nigaki-san in the snowstorm.
Here, you can see it for yourself.
&
The dog brought back the bag you had put a lot of videotapes in, thinking you accidentally dropped it.
I've not seen all the tapes inside that bag yet, but I saw some of the tapes were from four years ago.
Most likely, those are...
That's right, those tapes recorded the last time my brother was seen.
My brother was unable to walk on his own, so the former owner had to carry him.
Recorded from the other side of the woods, the tape showed them getting swept up into the avalanche.
Do you mean Nigaki-san stood there and filmed it all on his camera, but didn't help them?
Yes, because my brother didn't approve of my relationship with Yoshitaka.
I found the tape when I went into his room to bring him a change of clothes.
When I saw a tape dated four years ago, I thought it was a present he intended to give me.
So, I watched it secretly.
Then, that was the real reason you were crying that time.
But, I didn't think Saburo would help me take my chocolate to him.
Perhaps you knew it all along?
That, although I'm a murderer,
I still deeply love him.
Why did you do something so stupid without checking to see if Nigaki-san was the one who recorded the video?!
I'm sure it was him.
On the tape, the avalanche came, there were two gunshots, and then he said,
"Sorry, Nattsuya. Let me take your sister."
Two gunshots?
Wait a minute, is that...
Is this the noise you heard on the tape?
That's right.
We're the ones who set off that avalanche!
We also accidentally shot your brother, mistaking him for a wolf.
Nigaki called us back here because he was trying to blackmail us to get our money.
He threatened that he'd expose the videotape, and then they'd use it to find his body and arrest us.
Thanks for killing him for us, since we had already planned to kill him ourselves.
It saves us the trouble of causing another avalanche just to take the tape back.
Alright, everyone move next to that detective. Quickly!
What should I do?
I just used the last tranquilizer needle in my watch, and I didn't bring my super-powered kick shoes.
Let's see, who should we start with?
Someone. Someone, help me.
If not, I'll never have a chance to give this chocolate to him!
Alright, Brown-Haired-Girl, pick up the knife behind you and kill your friend!
Don't just stand there, get to it!
Who's there?
Go check it out.
Hey! Is someone out there?
Who are you?
Don't come any closer.
Don't move.
You bastard, I told you not to move
You really shouldn't move.
It's okay.
The force produced from large guns like this one causes the shot to swerve a little.
Don't you dare make fun of me!
I'm not making fun of you, I'm just stating the facts.
Damn it, if you want to try to dodge it, then go ahead!
Makoto-san.
Why you...
Over here.
Right here!
That's got to hurt.
Makoto-san, why are you here?
I came to see the person you have a crush on.
So I can see if he's really suitable for you or not.
Huh?
Don't play innocent!
I mean the guy for whom you knit a sweater, attended a pottery class, and made homemade chocolate.
Now, where is he?
That guy you "like the most!"
I was referring to you.
Huh?
Look!
By the way, Sonoko gave up halfway on the sweater, but she did send the clay cup to you, Kyougoku-san.
Oh? That wasn't a vase?
Did that clear up the misunderstanding?
Y-Yes.
T-Then, if you'll excuse me.
H-Hold on a second!
Since you're already here, please take this, okay?
Here!
That's very kind of you.
Incredible!
Her "love-love strategy" was actually successful.
By the way, Sonoko-san.
I'm not sure about that animal print outfit.
Really?
Good for you, Sonoko.
The next morning, the police arrived.
And so, those tragic events ended along with the snow storm.
But, on February 14th.
Hey, why haven't you written anything on your chocolate?
I thought I'd write it later.
Well, I'm gonna go to the airport to see Makoto-san off.
Good luck, then!
Bye!
Sonoko.
I can't write it yet...
because giving a Valentine's Day present on any other day wouldn't relay my feelings for him.
The name of someone I can't even find.
I just can't write it yet.
I'm home!
I wonder if I should give Dad...
this chocolate?
You're strong, Ran.
It would be really great if I was actually that strong.
Stupid! Don't cry, don't cry.
Who put this coat on me?
It's snowing.
Oh, no! It's this late already?
I have to hurry and make something for dinner.
I have a mail?
It's a picture-mail?
Wait? What is this?!
This is me, isn't it?
"I've stolen your sleeping face. Detective Kid?"
Uh, yes?
Good evening. This is Detective Kid.
Shinichi?
Shinichi, were you here?
Yeah, I just left there.
If you have time to do such stupid things, you should have woke me up.
Sorry, sorry!
You looked so comfortable there, sleeping like the dead!
The dead?
Oh yeah, I got hungry waiting for you to wake up, so I ate the big chocolate that was on the table.
What?
But, a peach-shaped chocolate is quite unusual.
Really?
Yeah. It's the best one I've ever eaten.
No way!
I can't tell you because it's my own special place.
Eh?
I knew that was coming.