The inside of the heart is a mystery.
Stars and snow are all around us.
The Detective Boys are searching for a watch...
But we wind up in the middle of a big case!
Seeing through to the one and only truth...
I look like a child, but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
How cute!
Ah, this is me!
They look just like us!
Can we really eat these chocolates?
Of course!
I put all my energy into making these at the lodge for you guys.
But when did you make these chocolates?
I didn't see them on the table at the lodge.
I made them for practice and put them in the refrigerator.
Well..
I'm gonna go make some tea, so give me a second, okay?
Okay!
Judging from her appearance...
It looks like you were able to accept her chocolate and fool her into thinking her sulking had gone unnoticed.
What makes you think she was sulking?
Creations reflect the heart of the creator.
Everyone's chocolates are smiling...
But it's bittersweet—they still have heartbroken faces.
Now that you mention it...
Really...
A sorrowful face that's holding back tears...
Tears that could burst at any moment.
She's overdoing it.
I guess you can say some girly things after all, can't you?
Oh...
Do I look like a boy to you?
The Forgotten Memento from the Crime
(Part 1)
The Forgotten Memento from the Crime:
Part 1!
This is so good!
It really is!
It's like a chef made it!
Could you keep it down a little?
I'm trying to focus on my work.
Sorry, sorry...
After the tea comes, we'll take our leave.
Uncle, are you actually doing work?
I heard you're always sleeping.
Idiot!
I'm listening to my client's tape...
What's that?
Isn't that horse racing?
Ah, no, that's...
Ah, yes, please wait a moment.
See, I've got a client.
So many people across Japan come to see me everyday!
There's no way I would have free time.
Now then, what kind of difficult case will it be today?
Welcome.
Ah, yes, um...
I was wondering if you could search for a lost watch.
Morita Hideo (49)
Client
I see...
The watch belonged to your wife who passed away?
Yes.
It's an old wind-up watch that I gave to my wife.
Why would you even want something like that?
Didn't your wife die?
I see! You want to pawn it off, right?
N-No.
My wife comes to see me in my dreams at night, saying...
"Right now, dear..."
"What time is it right now?"
Y-You're probably just tired.
I thought so too, but...
Maybe you lost it when you went out somewhere?
Or maybe a thief broke into your house?
No, it's probably somewhere in my house.
Huh?
My wife was very careless.
There was a time when she searched all day for her lipstick that was just under a magazine.
So I thought that if we found it, my wife would stop haunting me.
Give me a break!
If it's something inside your house, search for it yourself!
But I'm as careless as my wife...
I am the famous detective Mouri Kogoro!
Why would I want to deal with such an insignificant case?
M-Mouri?
You're that famous Sleeping Kogoro?
He's just trying to slack off from work.
He's like a store that picks and chooses its customers.
He should find time for even the smallest case, right?
Well, if my services are really necessary, then...
I-It's okay, I'll try to find it.
I just saw the sign outside and thought I'd come in.
Huh?
Where's the client and everyone else?
They all went out somewhere.
Hey...
Do you think we could help you find that watch?
Huh?
Of course, we won't charge you a fee.
O-Okay...
Excuse us!
ow, such pretty flowers!
But they're starting to dry up.
Yeah..
My wife had always watered and taken care of them before she passed away...
But now, as time passes...
Then it hasn't been very long since your wife passed away?
Yeah..
She died in a car accident only three weeks ago.
What's in this room?
Ah, that's...
Wow..
Wow...
Awesome!
There are so many audio devices!
What a big TV! It's almost like a mini movie theater!
Look! He has Gomera in English!
Yeah, I had to go all the way to America to buy it.
Video, LD, DVD, AV Amp, Frequency Selector, and TV remotes...
The table is filled with nothing but remotes.
On top of that, the floor has mountains of movie pamphlets.
It's not surprising that things get lost in this house.
Ah, well, this is really the only messy room.
It seems you have a guest.
Y-Yeah, it seems so.
Is it ready?
Ah, yes...
I managed to prepare 50 thousand.
Idetsuki Eiko (46)
Apartment Manager
50 thousand?
Where's the other 150 thousand?
I intended to sell this place to muster the rest of the money.
I see.
Sorry if it seems like I'm chasing you out of here.
Then..
As a thank you for waiting for the payment...
I found the "Sakura Sanjiro" video that you've been looking for.
Really?
Then I hope you don't mind me watching it here in your great audio room...
Sure, go ahead. I don't mind.
Who are these kids?
Uh, they're nobody.
Okay, we can search this room later...
Let's move onto another room.
When you're finished, could you please return it to the video rental shop manager by the station?
He said it was a valuable tape that isn't usually available.
Sure, I don't mind.
I was going out anyway.
Well then, enjoy the movie.
Well, I'll accept it as interest on the money I lent you.
Which room should we search next?
How about the living room?
Why does she have to watch it at such a loud volume?
But it sounds really interesting, doesn't it?
Come on, focus. It'll get too dark if we don't find it soon.
Ah, okay!
But Haibara-san..
We've already searched all the rooms without any luck.
I'm too tired to move.
Then how about I make some sandwiches?
I actually work at a coffee shop in the next town, so I have all the ingredients.
Please let me treat you as thanks for all your hard work.
All right!
Um, is there anything I can help you with?
Thanks for asking, but I can manage by myself.
Then while the sandwiches are being made...
How about we search a little more?
Okay!
Here you go! Help yourselves.
Wow, it looks so good
This is a club house sandwich, isn't it?
As expected of a professional!
Could I ask someone to take these to Idekitsu-san so she has a snack while she's watching her video?
Sure, I'll give them to her.
Me too!
We brought tea and sandwiches.
Shh, I'm at a good part right now!
Just leave it on the table.
O-Okay.
Did she think they were good?
No, she was too busy watching her movie, so we put them on the table.
Well..
She's a movie lover, so it can't be helped.
What's that package over there?
It's my laundry.
I wash it in coin-operated machines.
But your bathroom had a washing machine.
Using that machine is really complicated.
Without my wife here, I don't really know how it works.
Hey...
Is the watch we're looking for something your wife always wore?
Yeah, she really liked it.
Since the day before the accident, she always wore it.
She rarely took it off.
But she must've taken it off before she took a bath, right?
Conan-kun!
I found the watch!
It still works, too!
What?
Look!
Thank you!
This is the watch my wife always wore!
I see...
She must have taken it off before her bath...
And thrown it into the washing machine along with her clothes.
No, that's not right.
He didn't lose that watch.
Then what is it?
Why would he lie about that?
The sound of something breaking...
And the sound of running footsteps...
It can't be!
Hey, what was that sound?
Now it's the sound of the front door closing!
The vase is gone!
What's going on?
Hey, Conan...
I-Idetsuki-san!
Original Broadcast Date:
February 18th, 2002
Based on manga:
Vol. 33 Files 7-9
The weapon is this vase filled with water and flowers.
Most likely, the culprit followed her here, broke into the house...
Took that vase from the entrance...
And beat her to death with it.
The victim's name is Idetsuki Eiko-san, age 46.
She's the manager of this apartment complex.
Then, to the owner of this apartment, Hideo-san...
What's your relationship with Idetsuki-san?
I was borrowing money from her.
She came here to collect.
After I paid her and showed her a video she had been looking for...
She said she wanted to see it right away, and watched it in my audio room.
So when you heard the sound of the vase break and ran to this room...
Idetsuki-san was lying down with blood dripping from her head. Is that correct?
Y-Yeah.
Idestsuki-san held the video tape in her left hand...
And put it in while she held the remote in her right hand, like this.
Sakura Sanjirou
Oh, Sakura Sanjirou?
That really takes me back.
Inspector Megure, do you know this movie?
If I'm not mistaken, it starts like this...
"The path you must take is as beautiful as flowers. You must live a life that is..."
"As strong as a trunk."
Right?
We heard the whole thing.
That lady had the volume up really high.
W-What are you guys doing here?
We came to help look for an item that was missing.
It was a wind-up watch that belonged to Morita-san's wife before she passed away.
Well, it would seem that Edogawa-kun found it in the washing machine.
But why did you have the children help you?
I originally asked Detective Mouri, but he turned me away.
On my way out, Agasa-san and the children offered to help me.
I see...
Then Mouri-kun isn't here.
Huh?
What about him?
It's nothing, there's just something I want to confirm with him.
The tape has been completely rewound, which means...
She had finished the movie, and while ejecting the tape from the VCR...
She was hit from behind.
Excuse me for asking, but...
Where were you at that time?
I believe I was in the bathroom.
He really is telling the truth!
We heard the sound of the vase breaking right when Conan-kun and I found the watch...
He was in the bathroom too!
After that, there was the sound of running footsteps and the sound of the front door closing.
There's no mistake—the culprit must be an outsider!
Then Morita-san was always with you, Agasa-san?
No... At one point, he went into the kitchen to make sandwiches.
The kitchen?
Where is it?
It's through the living room.
Here it is.
At that time...
Where were you, Agasa-san?
I was in the living room with the children.
If you open this door, from the kitchen to the hallway...
It's a straight line to the audio room, isn't it?
R-Right.
Moreover..
The door to the living room is shut.
You could've slipped into the other room without anyone hearing.
What are you saying, Inspector?
In other words...
The sound of the vase breaking, the sound of someone running away...
And the sound of the front door closing...
If we assume that you recorded them all beforehand...
It's possible for you to sneak out of the kitchen while pretending to make sandwiches...
And play the recording after murdering Idetsuki-san.
If the video was loud enough...
It's possible to cover up the real sound of the vase breaking.
Y-You can't be serious...
But that's impossible.
There were tea and sandwiches in the audio room, right?
Ayumi-chan and I brought those to her during the movie.
At that time, Idetsuki-san was still alive.
After that, we heard the sound of the vase breaking, so we ran and found the body.
Until then, Morita-san was with us the entire time.
I-Is that so?
Inspector Megure!
We're finished with the questioning.
The victim, Idetsuki-san, lent money to other people in this building as well.
When they couldn't repay her by the due date...
She seized their valuables as compensation.
In other words, she didn't have a very good reputation.
Apparently the other residents of this apartment already knew that she was here today.
What?
It's the volume of the video.
She often came to this audio room to watch videos at a loud volume.
If they knew her whereabouts, then perhaps this really was an outside job.
Okay!
Find everyone who was borrowing money from her!
Yes, sir!
If it's an outsider, then there's no need for your help.
No...
The culprit is probably Morita-san.
Didn't you just say it was impossible for him to have done it?
Don't you find it strange?
The wind-up watch that was supposedly lost three weeks ago is working perfectly.
The maximum time that a wind-up watch can function is about 50 hours.
There's no way it could run for three weeks.
Then that watch is..
A setup to lure us here...
Probably to confirm his alibi.
However, Morita-san was definitely not in the audio room during the time of the murder...
And I saw him in the kitchen every two to three minutes.
And when we found the body, he didn't do anything suspicious.
How did he do it?
By the way, Morita-san...
When you went to visit Mouri-san's office...
Did you notice anyone strange?
No, no one in particular.
I see. Thank you.
Hey, Takagi-san...
What did you mean by that?
Ah, well...
Right now, the Inspector and I haven't decided if we should tell him or not...
But it seems that someone is checking up on Mouri-san.
It all disappeared from police headquarters.
The case reports that Mouri-san had been in charge of until now have been stolen.
Superintendent Matsumoto had kept copies, so it didn't cause any problems in court...
But, surprisingly, the stolen reports were sent back to headquarters last night...
In an envelope with no address or name.
Do you know when they went missing?
Let me see, I think it was...
On the day you guys were involved in that busjacking incident.
There's a possibility that the criminals' families have a grudge against Mouri-san, so we're investigating them.
So far, we haven't been able to find a suspect.
We're not sure if we should provide Mouri-kun with a bodyguard...
But it could also just be someone's prank.
Anyway, if you see anyone suspicious around Mouri-san...
Call the police right away.
Okay, I understand.
No, their target isn't Uncle...
Could it be...
The one they're aiming for...
Hey...
Don't you smell something weird?
Now that you mention it, it smells like something's burning.
Could it be coming from the microwave right there?
You're right, it's coming from inside here.
There are still some sandwiches left!
Jeez, Genta-kun, you sure eat a lot.
I see...
So that's what it was!
The Forgotten Memento from the Crime
(Part 2)
Next Conan: The Forgotten Memento from the Crime (Part 2).
Next Conan's Hint!
Sandwich.
Next time!
I GOT IT!
Did the old man get the right guy, or...
He got it.