The inside of the heart is a mystery.
Stars and snow are all around us.
The vase is the cornerstone of the case!
Within the boundary of the crime scene, what will the culprit do?
Seeing through to the one and only truth...
I look like a child, but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
After Uncle refused a case to find Morita Hideo-san's watch...
The Detective Boys stepped in to help.
While we were searching for the watch in his apartment...
Idetsuki Eiko-san, manager of the apartment complex, barged in...
And began watching a movie in the audio room.
After some searching, we found the lost watch in the washing machine.
Then, at that time...
We heard the sound of something breaking coming from the audio room.
When we ran to find the source of the noise...
We discovered Idetsuki-san lying dead on the floor...
Killed by blunt trauma to the head.
Most likely, Morita-san is the culprit.
However...
Since he has an alibi that we can confirm...
Just how could he have done it?
And that's not the only thing that's troublesome.
It seems that someone is checking up on Mouri-san.
They all disappeared from police headquarters.
The reports from cases that Mouri-san has solved up until now have been stolen.
Do you know when they went missing?
Let me see, I think it was...
On the day you guys were involved in that busjacking incident.
No, their target isn't Uncle...
Could it be...
The one they're aiming for...
The Forgotten Memento from the Crime
(Part 2)
The Forgotten Memento from the Crime:
Part 2!
Shinichi, what did Detective Takagi say?
Oh, it was nothing important.
Just as I thought...
You won't tell us anything.
Stupid, how are you any different?
Who knows?
What's wrong, Shinichi? Are you really hiding something?
No, that's not it...
Without considering the consequences, you pursue truth and justice.
The burdens you bear are yours alone because you feel obligated to protect those around you.
You dangerous, boy-like personality is so painfully and achingly intriguing.
I wonder if you realize...
That that pure scent of yours...
Is strangling me, her, and yourself with loneliness, uncertainty, and vulnerability.
Kudo-kun.
Don't you smell something weird?
Now that you mention it, it smells like something's burning.
Could it be coming from the microwave right there?
You're right, it's coming from in here.
But there"s nothing inside.
Conan-kun?
These... Aren't these dry flowers?
Or rather, they may have been thrown out because they all dried up.
In that case, it must be somewhere around here.
Damn, where is it?
Something that big shouldn't be this hard to find.
Could it be in another room?
There are still sandwiches left!
I can eat them, right?
Jeez, Genta-kun, you sure eat a lot.
Sandwiches?
Wait a minute...
Could it be?
I found it!
Just as I suspected, it was a trick after all.
In that case, in the audio room..
What's up, Conan-kun?
Um, I forgot my paper airplane in this room when I was playing with it.
Where is it?
Behind that curtain above the TV.
Please get it, please!
Okay, okay, I'll get it for you.
Jeez, I thought he was smart, but I guess he's just a normal kid after all...
Conan-kun, it's not here.
I don't see a paper plane anywhere.
Oh wow, there are so many appliances!
Awesome!
Hey, what are you doing? Hurry and get him down.
Yes, sir!
But you sure have a lot of VCRs.
Y-Yeah.
When I don't use them anymore, I put them all up on the shelf.
Conan-kun!
A timer?
Please come down, Conan-kun!
I see...
So that's what it was!
What Idetsuki-san was watching...
She had no idea it would be her last movie...
Or that it would be a cruel story...
That's strange...
They didn't say anything about going out.
Hey, I told them!
And? What did the inspector say?
He thinks it's an interesting theory, so he's going to help us out.
All right...
It's your turn now.
Do exactly what I told you, okay?
Yeah!
You just keep worrying and worrying...
It's about your precious girlfriend, isn't it?
But understand this.
I don't know what Detective Takagi told you...
But don't lose your grip.
You mustn't tell her about your true identity or the Organization.
Well, since you're a boy, I can tell that you're happy to have received her chocolate.
Stupid, I'm not happy at all...
Since, after so long, I haven't told her anything.
But Shinichi, you did accept Ran-kun's chocolate, right?
Yeah...
Then you must've, in return...
She would want to see me.
If I told her how I feel, she'd just miss me even more.
After all, I'm the guy who's been breaking her heart by making her wait an eternity...
Even though I'm always by her side.
I don't want to see her cry anymore...
Even if it means that I no longer have a place in her heart.
Seems pretty immature of me, doesn't it?
Pitiful...
Both of us.
What? There's something that's been stolen?
Are you sure?
I'm really, really sure!
Something weird is missing.
The culprit's real motive must've been a burglary!
Anyway, please come to the kitchen.
Then, Morita-san, you too...
Oh, okay.
So what is it that's been stolen?
This!
A bowl?
That's not it.
Not a whole bowl—just the bottom of one.
Look.
The other ones in that stack have a bottom, but this one doesn't.
You're right.
I think it was like that when I bought it.
It was a defective item.
Inspector!
Everything is ready.
W-What's ready?
If you'd be so kind, Morita-san, please join us.
It's a simple, on-site investigation.
Now then, let's go to the audio room where Idetsuki-san was murdered.
Original Broadcast Date:
March 4th, 2002
Based on manga:
Vol. 33 Files 7-9
Please come in.
O-Okay.
It's turned on!
The VCR is turned on!
Oh, is there anything wrong with the VCRs on the shelf?
N-No, it's not the VCRs, it's the video tapes.
Oh, sorry.
We had to move them there for a while—there are just so many...
Um, let's see...
If I remember correctly, Idetsuki-san rewound the tape after watching it.
Then, when she was about to take it out of the VCR, she was attacked from behind, right?
Then...
Let's re-enact the whole incident using the VCR.
All right, Takagi-kun, you can be the culprit.
As for the victim... Agasa-san, could I ask you to do it?
N-No...
Something wrong?
N-No, I'll be the victim.
Idetsuki-san often watched videos here.
I think it's better if I do it, since I know the room better.
Oh! That's a good point!
In that case, please do so.
First, she inserted the tape into this very bottom VCR...
Second, she sat down to watch the video.
Am I right?
Yes.
Afterwards, when the movie ended, she rewound the tape.
What's the matter?
Please rewind the tape.
O-Okay.
While the tape was rewinding, the culprit lurked behind her from the entrance, holding the vase.
When the tape finished rewinding and the victim was about to take the tape from the VCR...
The culprit raised the vase, and...
Morita-san, please hurry and take out the tape!
Y-Yes, I understand.
Let's see...
Hey, why aren't you using the remote?
See, the remote you're holding has an eject button on it.
Um, that's...
Here, I'll eject it for you.
The video tapes aren't going to fall.
We changed the code number of the VCR on the shelf.
Basically, Morita-san...
This is how you committed the crime.
You programmed your VCRs so that the one on the bottom...
As well as the one on the shelf...
Would be controlled by a single remote.
You placed a tape into the top VCR.
Next, you set the vase filled with water and flowers in front of it.
Also, to make sure the vase would tip over, you had it balanced halfway on top of another video tape.
After that, you closed the curtain and the trick was complete.
Later, using the movie that Idetsuki-san had been looking for as bait...
You lured her into this room.
All you had to do then was to ask her to eject the tape and give it back when she was finished.
When she went to eject the tape with the remote...
The tape in the top VCR came out as well, tipped over the vase...
And caused it to fall on her while she was reaching for the tape in the bottom VCR.
In other words, it's possible for you to have set up this trap because she comes here frequently.
You could easily predict the timing of her actions after she ejected the tape.
Just like this.
Moreover, the top VCR has a function which automatically reinserts the tape if its opening is obstructed.
And if the tape had sounds prerecorded onto it...
They would automatically start playing after the tape was reinserted.
Immediately after the vase fell...
We heard sounds of a person running and the front door slamming...
Making it seem as though the crime was committed by an outsider.
We could hear it very clearly because she had turned the volume up very high.
The reason for using the very bottom VCR...
Was to lengthen the falling distance of the vase.
Finally, you had a timer set up to turn off the power of the top VCR...
So that the police wouldn't get suspicious when they opened the curtain. Am I right?
We've just re-enacted the clever trick that you used.
The vase in the entryway was..
These bowls!
You glued them together like a sandwich and placed them at the entrance, right?
While you were making sandwiches...
You secretly took these bowls to the kitchen...
And hid them together with the other bowls.
This is one of the flowers that was in the vase.
You threw it out after drying it up in the microwave.
Your wife even arranged these flowers for you.
Poor flowers...
My wife didn't arrange those flowers.
That woman sent them to me on the day of my wife's funeral.
I was already so broke that I couldn't afford the same flowers.
It's because of stocks.
That woman urged my wife to trade stocks behind my back.
As a result of her massive debt, my wife was driven to her death.
Then her accident was...
Yes.
She jumped in front of a car the day after she told me about the stocks.
She left me only a letter, with that watch wrapped inside.
She wrote, "This is the one thing I don't want to get broken, so I'll leave it with you."
I could care less about those flowers from that despicable woman!
We'll discuss the rest down at the station.
But still, I pity those flowers.
They would have been so beautiful...
But they didn't even have a chance to bloom.
Making them die so early is...
I know.
Well, I have to go now.
That's right...
Flowers are fragile and ephemeral.
No matter how well you protect them from the wind or the rain...
Even if there is a fence all around them...
The flowers will die without sunlight.
A fence has no chance against a storm.
Are you sure you're aware of that, Kudo-kun?
Damn!
Why isn't anyone answering?
Ran! Uncle!
Please stop trying to catch me...
There you are, my dinner!
That's right...
It's dinnertime.
They must be upstairs.
Ran!
The ingredients have been abandoned...
And the TV in the office wasn't turned off.
It can't be...
t seems that someone is checking up on Mouri-san.
Could that guy have...
Guess who?
Ran-neechan?
Exactly right!
H-Hey, where have you been?
At the supermarket.
Dad hit the jackpot in a horse race.
J-Jackpot?
He was so excited that he said...
"We're having steak tonight! Go get beef and sake!"
So I dropped everything in the middle of cooking and ran out to buy it...
Because the best and freshest meat always runs out quickly.
Where did Uncle go?
He's probably bragging about it to the neighbors.
Just you wait, Conan-kun.
I'll make a steak that's as delicious as a five-star restaurant's.
Um, Ran-neechan...
You see...
That man with the black wool hat...
He might be someone I know.
What is it?
Black...
Blacken the meat, but please don't burn it.
Of course not! Leave it all to me.
Well, there's no way Ran would know him.