Love is hard to define.
And the reason is suspense.
What docs the cross mean?
It's a coded case!
Recognizing that single truth.
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is Detective Conan!
I know it...
I've seen him before.
But where did I see him
That man with the black hat...
Right, why do I feel...
Like something will break...
When I remember?
Right it's just like that time, that time...
It's just like that time.
An unsettling feeling...
Ran.
Hey!
Ran!
What, Sonoko?
Not like this...
Hey, Mouri-san
Were you paying attention to the lesson. Mouri-san?
Yes...
Then, Mouri-san, what is that mark?
Do you know what it means?
A cross? No, an X?
Ran, it means...
Time's up.
Mouri-san will have to tell us at the beginning of the next class.
This is a very important symbol.
Especially for ladies.
It's such a cute mark.
O.K.?
Yes...
The Secret Rushed Omission. Part 1!
X?
And it's supposed to have a special meaning?
Jodie-sensei mentioned it at the end of class.
It's a cute mark, right?
Ran, now now, it isn't something a kid would know.
But Conan-kun often knows unusual things like this.
Really?
X... X... X...
X is a variable in algebra.
Or it can also mean a question, the unknown, or the unexplained...
X could mean as in X-rated, only 18 and above...
The X-Ray would be Roentgen...
Wait a second.
If it's actually a cross...
The cross would mean error or reversed.
"X1" would mean once divorced...
Right, right, she said it was an important mark for women.
Woman?
That's right, my mom often writes them at the end of her letters.
But she has never told me what they mean...
Hey Sonoko, don't you think that Jodie-sense's teaching has changed?
Right, right, she was so serious before.
But now it's fun because of the English expressions, right?
Hi, even with those compliments I won't make the exam easy.
Sensei?
Mouri-san, have you figured out X?
Nope, not yet.
Right, why don't you send a message and ask Shinichi?
You can say "I'll give you my special X if you tell me the answer."
"l give you my X!"
Oh! Good idea.
Right right?
What the... What is X?
X... X... X...
So what are you doing out here?
That's right...
There was something I wanted to ask you.
Can we hang out?
X... X...
Cross?
Eh?
A groper?
Is there one we should know of?
Oh yes.
Teitan schoolgirls have become victims on buses and subways.
It hasn't happened to us...
Even if one of them tried to get us.
Ran would use her karate!
Oh! Bodyguard?
No, no.
But you need to be careful.
It could be anybody.
They could follow you all the way home, waiting for their only chance to strike.
Cute, cute...
Such a stalker could be anywhere.
If a stalker came to my house, my security would chase him off.
I haven't noticed anyone around my house.
Right, Conan-kun?
Well, if you sec anyone like that, tell me immediately.
Tell you
Yes! Japanese people still don't know how dangerous stalkers can be.
If you tell me. I'll teach that stalker a lesson the American way!
What? A suspicious man is following you?
Where are you right now?
I'm in front of the building you're in.
I said a suspicious man.
But it's likely just the guy I've been investigating.
He's probably wanting to negotiate a better deal.
He may offer me twice as much as you, if I forget the things I found on him.
The money will determine.
I understand.
I'll pay three, no four times as much, just hurry!
Bring me the evidence and his name now
That's all I needed.
I'll be there in a moment.
Well, that's how it's gonna be, unless you can match his offer?
Hey, hey, following me won't make things any easier.
This is it.
All of your criminal activities are in here.
No way...
What's going on?
Is this a blackout?
It's over.
Scary...
Of course, but you've experienced a blackout in a building before.
Hey, look outside!
Really, I wonder what happened.
Mouri-san, Suzuki-sad call the police and an ambulance.
Y-Yes!
What?
What is that written on the envelope?
"Circle, cross, triangle"
What the...?
Stabbed in the stomach with a blade?
Yeah, the victim was Chuujou Katsunori-san, age forty-three.
According to his card, he owns a detective agency.
A detective?
But what I don't get is this "dying message"...
No, no, no!
Dying message!
Wait, aren't you...
Yes, Jodie Saintemillion.
It's nice to see you again. Keiba-san.
She should improve her Japanese before correcting anyone's English.
You seem to get involved in cases often.
Yes, but not as many as those girls.
Oh, is that Ran-kun?
We were talking in that cafe until the blackout happened...
When the lights came back on.
We came out here and found him.
A blackout?
Oh, that's right, the blackout occurred because of an error made by an electrician during maintenance.
It lasted for less than fifteen seconds.
Then the criminal took advantage of this coincidence...
And then Chuujou-san wrote this strange dying...
"Message Just after he was attacked.
But what's the meaning of these symbols?
Sometimes they can replace characters.
It's possible that this could be someone's name...
That's right. I've seen these marks before.
What did
Where did you see them?
Please think. Jodie
Oh!
Controller! On a Japanese game's controller!
That's where I've seen those marks.
Docs that help you?
That's right, Sensei's a gamer...
Inspector Meguro.
The call history says a call came thirty minutes ago.
Thirty minutes ago? That's the time of the case.
Then, let's return the call.
Then it was you that called Chuujou-san thirty minutes ago?
No, sec...
Could it have been that phone call!?
That guy was talking weird.
Let's see. I think it was: "I'll pay four times as much, just hurry."
Isn't that right?
Hey, what's going on?
I got it, hold on.
I'll explain everything.
You hired a detective to investigate your company?
Yes
We discovered that someone was embezzling money from the company last month.
An executive ordered me to find out who it was before the president found out.
Where is your company?
We're located in this building on floors eight to eleven.
I see, after the detective discovered the culprit...
You arranged to meet him at that cafe to avoid a scandal.
But, he didn't show at the arranged time, so you decided to call him, right?
Yes
The envelope Chuujou-san was holding turned up empty.
Is it possible that the embezzler and the killer are the same person?
Yeah, he may have killed the detective and retreated to an office upstairs.
Right, do you have any idea who the embezzler is?
Yes, just last week the detective mailed me a partial report with a list of all the suspicious employees.
Here is the list.
Inspector Megure.
Hey, hey, checking all of them won't be easy.
A list of fifty-eight suspects...
And the only clue is "circle, cross, triangle."
Sounds interesting.
Inspector Megure!
The lab has determined that the "circle, cross, triangle" symbols have the victim's fingerprints on them.
Ah. I see.
As we thought, it seems Chuujou-san drew them himself.
So after being attacked by the culprit, Chuujou-san must have drawn the symbols as a dying...
M-Message...
To help identify the culprit.
Good!
Also, it seems Chuujou-san was stabbed before the blackout.
Before the blackout?
Right.
According to a witness...
The lights went out just as Chuujou-san was stabbed by a man in a coat.
The stabbing happened at the foot of this escalator
Chuujou-san was most likely stabbed in a struggle over the envelope.
When the lights came back on. Chuujou-san was crouching near the escalator.
The man in the coat then approached the victim, stole the documents inside the envelope, and ran up the escalator.
Then. Chuujou-san must have started drawing the symbols while he was here, at the foot of the escalator?
Yes
Likely during the blackout.
That means that even though he was able to keep the envelope, the criminal was still able to get the documents.
That's how he died and ended up at the top of the escalator, right?
But why didn't that witness scream after seeing this?
She thought they were filming a suspense drama.
Alright, we can assume that the embezzler is the murder.
All we have to do now is figure out what "circle, cross, triangle" means, and from this list of fifty-eight employees...
Find out which one it refers to.
I think it may be...
I think the "cross" from "circle, cross, triangle" may refer to the X from mathematics.
But why "circle, cross, triangle?"
The "circle" and "triangle" could have been to throw off the criminal from suspecting anything.
Oh! So the criminal's good at math.
Is anyone in your company good at math?
No, we primarily focus on recruiting those who are adept at different languages.
If it were "triangle, circle, square" it would be Oden...
Hey, maybe the "cross" refers to that X.
Yeah, the cute mark Jodie-sensei was talking about.
No, no!
No way, it can't be that X.
Oh, you mean the X girls put at the end of letters, right?
Oh, yes.
Officer Takagi, do you know what that X means?
I see, you must get those types of letters often.
No, just an occasional tease...
What does that "X mean anyway
No, it has nothing to do with the "circle, cross, triangle" from this case.
Hey, maybe there's more to this than "circle, cross, triangle."
Hey, look at this.
There 's something to the left of the "circle.
It looks like blood.
Wouldn't that mean there was something else besides "circle, cross, triangle" written here?
Oh, we noticed that as well.
We didn't find anything to the left of the envelope.
Then, have you checked...
The steps of the escalator?
At the moment the escalator isn't moving.
Isn't it possible the blood is here?
I see...
But the escalator was moving for a while, wouldn't it have wiped away the blood?
That's alright
Because there's a chemical that can make the blood reappear.
Right. Officer Takagi?
Yeah...
Luminol should highlight the blood.
Since the victim wrote that while crouching.
It should be easy to tell which step it was, because it should still be covered in blood, right?
Is that right?
Hey, there is one tiling.
What is it?
What is X?
The one that Sonoko-neechan mentioned.
You're a bit too young to know about that.
Kanski-san, I need you to see...
Inspector Megure. I believe this coat, this hat, and these gloves belonged to the criminal.
Ah, I see.
We found them in the restroom on the 5th floor.
But unfortunately, there was no sign of the documents.
Then, what about the checking of the suspects' alibis?
Yes, were checking.
Many of the employees were either eating or sleeping alone during the case.
From the list, we could only confirm alibis from twenty-seven of the fifty-eight.
That leaves thirty-one without alibis.
Were still searching for the "document, primarily focusing on floors eight through eleven".
Good, everyone continue searching.
Now there are thirty-one suspects...
The only clue we have are those symbols.
So if they don't find anything on the escalator...
Inspector, we found another symbol!
What? What is it?
Inspector, it's actually...
Huh? What is it?
A "square"?
It could be the kanji for month, or the katakana for "ro".
But if you consider the other symbols, it's probably a square.
This doesn't help any...
Since it matches the shape on the envelope. Chuujou-san must have made it.
That "square..."
Is larger than the others...
What docs that mean?