The deduction and suspense that closes
the distance between
two people's love and hate.
I'm gonna solve the dying message.
The common point
between the letter and symbols.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the l.Q of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
While we were with teacher,
Jodie, in a coffee shop,
all the lights in the building went out.
And after the blackout
the dead body holding an envelope was
found by an escalator.
The victim was Mr. Katsunori Chujo,
the manager of a detective agency.
His dying message. circle, cross
and triangle was written
with his own blood on the envelope.
And.
Inspector, we've found another character
written with blood.
What?
A square?
It also looks like a Kanji character,
mouth or a Katakana "Ro",
But judging from the previous symbols,
this is most likely a square.
Well I'm more confused than ever now.
Isn't that square a little bigger than
other circle, cross and triangle?
HIDE, HURRY UP AND ABBREVIATE IT
Part ll
Hey. Ran.
Eh? What?
We can make a character by combining
two of the marks-the circle, cross
and triangle, can we?
Huh?
For a example,
combining square with cross create
the character meaning the rice fields.
Yeah...
If so, this Mr Hari is very suspicious
If so, this Mr. Hari is very suspicious.
And this last name is very unique.
But how about this Mr. Nawata?
His name has three parts of that caracter.
BED 2
But how about thissMr. Nawata?
His name has three p TS of that caracter.
LO we
Oh! Mr. Asai also hasvan unique shape
of two overlapping crosses.
Oh! Mr. Asai also has an unique shape
of two overlapping crosses.!
of two overlapping crosses.
Shape?
Yeah, that's it. It's a shape.
For example,
think about Mr. Suzuki's Suzu.
Suzu has a round shape.
The circle could indicate" Mr. Suzuki.
How rude!
I'm Suzuki too.
There are no bad people
by the name of Suzuki.
Oh, but
Oh. but
Ahem!
Anyway leave it to us the police.
And stay away from the crime scene.
Oh come on.
Takagi,
You go ahead and help Chiba
search the upper floors.
Oh. yes sir.
Oh! I got te go tell dad that
I'm going to be late.
Um. hello Chiba?
Where are you now?
The eighth floor?
Yeah, Inspector told me
to go help you
All right.
Just hold on and I'll be right up.
Hey. oh...!
Shhh.
R.Ran, what's wrong?
What is it?
What is that XJ A
Huh?
You remember .
You said a little while. ago it's a tease.
Yumi often puts XXX at the end of
the mail to tease me.
Well, Ran, just you wait, someday,
sooner or later you'll see what X means.
Tell me right now
Please, detective Takagi!
Ra, Ran.
Um...oh...
It's... OK.
Ms. Mori, is sure taking
a long time to come back
That brat's gone somewhere, too.
Oh. You mean that cool kid.
He's over there.
All right. That's enough.
Hey. cool kid.
You look like an Ostrich.
An Ostrich?
And did you figure out the meaning of
the circle cross and triangle?
Not. yet. Ahaha. Not at all
Well, as Ran said,
don't you think that those shapes may be
representing something else?
'Let me see. For example.
Most people know that the U.S.
Department of Defense building is
commonly called the Pentagon
ecause 0 lS Ss ape.
Inthe US.
there are many words that represent
something other than its original meaning
The White House means the
Presidential residence
The Oval Office I$ the official office of
the President of the United States.
The Oval Office is the-gfficial office of
And there is another word: "Bureau"
that originally means an office.
But the word as it stands alone
often means FF. B I
The FBI is an abbreviation for the U.S.
Federal Bureau of Investigation.
Was my advice any good to you,
cool kid?
Ye yeah.
By the way, what did you mean when
you said the word, Ostrich?
Oh! I was talking about you. cool kid!
The officer caught you even though you
were hiding yourself in the suit case
We, Americans,
call such dorks Ostrich.
Once he sticks
his small head into the sand.
The ostrich usually
fails to realize what remains exposed
and thinks he can't be seen
because he can't see.
There is a similar expression
in Japan here.
That is, "Hiding your head but
Ieaving your rear end exposed!
Hiding the head
Ieaving the rear end exposed.
Let me see the envelope for a second.
Il]/
Hey you!
Ah, now I see.
So that explains it
here's no doubt.
« That person.among
those thirty one suspects is...
the murderer!
Well, I understand.
We willrsend investigators
there right away
Yes'
Now. please don't touch the manager's
computer any more
Well then
What's going on?
Oh... Umm
The victim killed was
the chief of a detective agency
and the culprit is most likely to be
the embezzler of the company.
So that's why I inquired at the agency.
Just hoping to find someone
who worked with him
and can tell us
the name of the embezzler
And then?
Hmm? Ah...
Unfortunately, Mr. Nakajo was working
on this case all by himself.
So none of his employees know
anything about the case
And our last hope is
the data stored on his computer,
But no one can access it
without the password.
Password...
Huh?
That's it. That's the password.
The circle, cross. triangle and square,
Isn't that his password?
Yeah, I thought so too and
asked the agency staff to enter them
in the password box, but it failed.
Hmm. Oh, but.
@ff course, they tried all twenty-four
possible combinations.
Umm. They couldn't make it.
Then, could the circle, cross, triangle,
square be the name of the culprit?
Oh! Isn't that about Quiz?
What?
Japanese Quiz Show often uses those
marks instead of answering Yes or No.
Oh. You mean, the circle or cross Quiz.
So. is the culprit the King of Quiz?
Yeah Could be.
Anyway, you just stay still here.
You don't need to stick your nose into this
affair any further than you've done.
But, if the the circle, cross, triangle and
square is the name of the culprit.
Then\Detective Chiba
could also be a suspect?
Huh
Because just look at the character
Chi of Detective Chiba
It: looks like cross when I hide it like this
And it looks like triangle
when I hide it like this }
Don't you think he is
also Very suspicious?
Hide? Umm
Detective Takagi, viewed in that way
is alb a suspect.
Huh?
Look! The character of Taka of
Detective Takagi!
It looks likebOth square or circle
if I hide it like this
I understand it looks like square but
why does it look like a circle.
Because there are some people who
write the carracter of "mouth" as circle.
Dr Agasa also often writes mouth in A
in that way when he writes his name.
Dr. Agasa said it's OK to abbreviate
them when you're in a hurry.
Hide it. Hurry it up, and abbreviate it.
Hmm.
Hey, come on!
Detective Chiba and Detective Takag:.
Both came here because I called them.
Both of them can't be the culprit.
Are you listening to me
Oh. wait asminute.
There is someone on the suspect list.
Oh. wait a=sminute
Theréxis someones«son the suspect list
Oh, waitda minute.
There is someoneson the suspect list.
Oh. waitéa minute.
There is someone on the suspect list
11 Fm
Oh', wait a minute
There is someone on the suspect list.
Oh, wait a minute.
There 1s someone on the suspect list.
Ah, wait a minute.
There us someone on the suspect list.
I think...
T. hiss it.
Oh, wait asminute.
There is someone»on the suspect list.
BY 3%
Oh, waitO¥a minute.
There is someoneaon the suspect list
Oh, wait a minute.
There is someone on the suspect list.
Ad Jy F
Oh swaitea minute.
There is someone on the suspect list.
Ah, wait a minute.
I think...
This us it.
Kuniyoshi Bunta.
Ku-Kuniyoshi BuntaO
Ah, that's right.
Well, then how does he become the
circle, cross. triangle and square?
There appears to be no connection
between those two.
But, if you hide the top halves of the
three characters, yoshi, bun, and ta.
See? These characters become
cir€IOO cross, and triangle'.
Oh, yes.
They sure are
circle, cross, and triangle.
But don't you think that it is difficult to
Iook upon the character ta as "tFianglée;
Sonoko. You're...
Tihescharacter doesn't look like a triangle
when it is printed
butsif it weregshand written and
the dot-of ta was elongated,
but if it were hand written and
the dot of "ta" was-elongated,
but if it were hand writtensand
the dot of "taswas elongated.
Then'wouldn't it look like a triangle?
But why were the top halves hidden?
They weren't hidden but removed.
Don't you remember
that the circle " were written down\
at the edge of the envelope.
And that the square,
which was discovered later,
was one size larger
than any other marks.
It means the three characters other than
square were written across the envelope
a sheet of paper
sticking out of the envelope.
And the murderer took the documents
including the sheet of paper
with the top halves of
the three characters written on it.
So. what does square mean?
Well, of course,
it means the character "koku".
If the victim had written it insa hurry
before the culprit noticed him doing so,
abbreviate to the square.
Now I've got it!
Yeah, I've seen people
who abbreviate "kuni to square
when taking shorthand dictation.
Oh, you're great. Inspector Megure!
You're just like Jules Maigret straight
coming out of the novel
Oh, Geme on! Hahahaha
Now we know who the culprit is
Let's go get him at the upper floor.
Yes sir.
Oh, it's this late already.
Ms. Mouri sure is late.
Maybe she's asking Shinichi about
the meaning of the "X" on the phone.
Yeah. A) I suggested,
if he get )the answer right,
sh) may give
Well. well,
I will give "myjcherished X" to him.
Sonoko
I have asked Detective Takagi
about the meaning of "X"!
Oh, you've already asked him...
Hahaha.
If I say that I'd give him my X'.
Shinichi wouldn't answer even if
he knew the answer, huh?
Well. I bet"he doesn't know the answer
ecause e nnows very I e
about this sort of thing.
Oh, .by the way,
where is"Conan«If'wonder.
What?
Oh. don't tell me he's missing again.
That little brat is always going
straying off somewhere.
Huh? Kuniyoshi?
Yes, he is here.
Hey. Kuniyoshi.
Huh? What is it?
Sorry to bother you but,
We have questions to ask you.
Could you come with us
to another room, please?
Huh? That's...
No problem.
A shredde yr.
OK, square and
circle, cross and triangle: huh?
And you're saying that those marks
signifies my name
If you add those missing parts to the
if you add those missing parts to the
Bunta Kuniyoshi
Chi &L JA
ES XX
Yes, exactly
But, Ihspector,
It seems too hasty to conclude, based on
the deduction, that I am the culprit.
Yet, that is his dying message.
Well, look at it this way=-
The murderer might have written
those bloody marks with his finger
trying to put the guilt on me.
So, if you want to grill me
you go find the missing document
and'"show it to me first.
Let's say, if I were the culprit
I wouldn't stay in this building
where the murder was committed,
but.run away outside
and try to burn the papers.
That's why you destroyed them
with thershredder, right?
Huh
But it was much easier than
a jigsaw puz Te to put together
because of the red marks.
Right, Detective Takagi?
Yeah.
Herd" is.
Oh. you've found it
Yes.
It wasn't too difficult because we looked
for only shreds of paper with blood on it,
andfthen the pieces them together.
They correctly matched
the characters on the envelope.
There is no doubt that these bloody
characters signify "Kuniyoshi Bunta.
As you've already
identified the shredder.
You can put together the remaining
pieces of the original document, right?
Yes.
And since we've also found the
murderer's cast-off gloves at a rest room,
If Mr. Kuniyoshi put the papers
into the shredder himself,
we can detect his fingerprints
attached to them.
Circle, cross and triangle.
Now I see.
Huh
I had the nicknames of "Big Mouth
and Circle, Cross and Triangle
when I was in college
But back then I didn't know why
they called me by these names.
Aha; that explains it.
I started embezzling from the company
because I really wanted to give my family
a better life, not one that was all mouth.
But once I made it
'just couldn't stop myself...
After all I have a big mouth, I know it.
All 'evil comes from:.the mouth.
Oh, the police arrested the guy,
Mr. circle, cross, and triangle.
Yeah. gy [UR
he was taken 'to the police just now
through the back door
(I ot
Hey hey.
Now, you(gotta tell me.
What's the X" anyway?
Oh. do you still wanna know?
Yeah.
If you really want to know about it,
ask Ran
Look. She's tapping out
awe-mail over there.
Hurry and come back.
Hey! WHat do s the O < me HA?
Huh
Sonoko told me to ask you.
It? It's not good for you.
No. no!
Not good?
Yeah, yeah!
The yX" means No-good.
See you then,
Ms. Mouri and Ms. Suzuki.
Watch out for the stSlker.
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers
MICHIHIRO SUWA
Background Music
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs. By
MA TOMO SU
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
HI HI(
rosmx! may
Animdtion Directors
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
4 'yY.
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KEN]! KODAMA
Produced By
TMS EN ERTAINMENT. I 1»
in association with
CORPORATION
DETAINEE CIN AN
COSHU AQYIM Ts SHOGARUKANY IV TMA :
All Rights Reserved
They are so annoying.
Oh, I got a mail.
From Ran.
Today, I got involved in
an incident again.
aybe, I'm...
I must be cursed...Nah!
I know you wanna know about the case.
I'll let you know the details later.
So hurry on back!
KooALK
What's this?
Does this means,
I'm "no good. no good. no good. huh?
ED COMHEIIBT TUES
FTXICLTIETmNAr-&
core
Bo rc J)-IIBET B25 xFxH sages Tl
HUNT
LFIFICLTUYS ID
XJiEFAY
FD -TAKIFHFAR-D
XulE=HF AT
KIA FAR
BL\Oad LadilA
I= BIN
5. TOME
BIC IMUPFDIBENE &£D
I; IOU
_- -O =
TEEN
BEDI
Ayumi?
She said she is meeting with guys called
Bruce and Chucky at the park.
Key.
You spilled something on your clothes.
Huh'?
What is this?
It's a bloodstain
Next conan,
Missing Quiz Granny