The deduction and suspense that closes
the distance between two people's love and hate
A granny. friend of Ayumi
Deciphering a code and solve the case.
He sees through the one and only truth,
A child in appearance with the IQ. of an adult
no case is left unsolved with Detective Conan.
Well, that figures.
Yeah.
She's not hanging around with us anymore.
Ayumi?
Looks like she's meeting guyssnamed
Bruce or Jackielin'that park every-day.
Seems she has a foreigner boyfriend.
And you want to go to see them?
Thatis been too nosy... isn't it?
It's
ot being noisy!
We must investigate whether the person deserves seeing Ayumi
I resign.
Conan! This is a serious matter that can affect her entire life}
Hey. isn't that a bit too far-fetched?
QUIZ GRANNY IS MISSING
Who's that old woman?
The character ta in rice paddy?
Yes. with three matchsticks.
The character "ta"...
Can I bend one?
Oh, no. no, no, Ayumi.
I give up. How do you do it?
Here, let me do it.
Sea?
Huh
Wow It's the character "ta"!
You see. this quiz was in th'$" book, too.
Wow sounds interesting!
I'll lend it to you some time.
Now...
Hooo hooo.
HoooO... hooo .
WwWhatin the world are: they doing?
Ho000...hooo...
Ho0o0...hooo...
Oooh. here you are.
Looks like your leg is
SO Much better. Jackie
Ja-Jackie?
Shizgka Oman
Here you are, Steve.
A little more time for your skin to cu
Shizuka. Omon
Shizukanflmoru
AL um dear.
Will you put the ointment on Steve?
Steve. .?
Aah, Steve don't move! Stay still. »
Jackie and Steve were cats!
So much worry for nothing.
I knew it was something like that.
Brice! What's the matter?
Hey. Granny!
I need to have that cat now!!
Jozi Yabuki
Jie Cad UL
SR 3 (25)
JoziYabukl
CD UO
I hear you! You don't have to shout.
It was inside the hood of my car again.
Plus pee all over it.
It's all your fault. You are taking care of these good-for nothings.
Leave them alone!
You shouldn't talk like that.
On top of that, your car is parked in a no-parking zone.
Don't make a big fuss over cat pee.
Shut up! Do you want me to give you what I'm planning to give the cats?
What's that?
SHOw time.
You...
STOP!
What are you kids?
We're the Youth Detective Squad.
Leave old ladies alone!
Granny,
If you let the cat under the hood one more time, you'll pay for it!
Bruce.
How many times do I have to tell you not to get inside the hood?
You naughty boy.
So cute
Thank you somuch, boys
Ref IPA You were so brave!
I was impressed.
Standing up for the homeless cats.
It's not something everyone can do.
Yeah, Granny is like a god for these cats
A godr. No way. kids
I don't deserve that.
I am a miserable person not worthy of them.
Are they all abandoned cats?
Yes: abandoned because of human whim
Mrs Omori is taking care of them while
Iooking for people willing to take them.
I'm just helping her out.
Tumi; why didn't you tell us.
We're all members of the Youth Detective Squad.
The Detective Squad?
Yeah.
We've solved mystery cases together.
Is that right?
Mysteries...
Something troubling you. Granny?
Huh? Well, nothing
Oh yes. Ayumi, will you please keep this for.me?
But. why?
Oh. I may not come tomorrow
You know, my arthritis pains
Arthritis? Idknow a hot springs place good for-arthritis.
Hot springs.
I used to go tO he hot springs in lzu before.
Oh, why not?
There-is an inn I know well.
I'm pretty sure they're safe with Ayumi.
Okay. see you tomorrow.
Bye. Granny.
Take care. See you tomorrow!
I don't see Bruce.
He's probably dozing off
IN the warm sunshine.
Granny is late.
She should be here by now.
Maybe she went to the hot springs.
Remember, she was complaining about arthritis yesterday.
I wonder.
She is not the type Vv to leave the cats she loves/neglected.
Is she in trouble?
Itike suddenly becoming ill.
Lét's go check her place.
What do you think, Conan?
Let's go.
There is something that had been nagging me yesterday.
Mrs. Omori. it's Ayumi!
Granny! It's Ayumi.
Granny!
Where has She gone?
Did something happen after we left?
You're being overly concerned.
But that man
He said he's going to make her pay.
That's all bluff.
Funny
The evening paper is still in the box.
That means, she hasn't been back here.
What! She hasn't been back?
Still, it's pretty difficult to imagine she left immediately for hot springs.
Something must have happened!
Anyway. call the fire department. Ayumi.
Mitsuhiko, call the police
ask whether-they have, u a person named ShizuOmori
WwW. Oeil ergo invove- in an acci en or carried by an ambulance to hospital
Genta, check out who the man-we saw yesterday is.
Gut how?
Looks like he's always illegally parked.
Someone in this area may have seen him.
I will check around the neighborhood to find somebody who knows her.
Okay.The Youth Detective
Squad to battle:stations.
I don't deserve that
I am a miserable person not worthy of them.
I hope what: I'm thinking turns out wrong
I've known Shizu for a very longtime.
Wand I think she doesn't have friends
Yd or relations she can stay with
That is why she can't resist taking care of those cats.
She's had her fill of trouble and probably» went to the hot springs for relaxation.
Trouble?
What kind of trouble?
Setsuko Nishiyama
FL DOF (62)
There's a house close to the park.
Which belonged to an old man, Ezak
Setsuko Nishiyama
FILE DOF (62)
FLEE DOF (62)
ShiZu was taking care of him.
But. about a month ago...
Poor Mr Ezaki.
He fell in the bathroom and hit his head very hard
It was very. bad luck.
That he hit his head on the faucet.
$0. thatis why Shizu was asked to leave
When Mr Ezaki was still alive, she called him Master Ezaki
and took great care of him, taking him to hot springs
The effort she put into his care.
Hot springs in zu.
Do you know where they stayed in lzu?
Oh, she hasn't told me.
Maybe you can find that out at Mr. Ezaki's house.
Hasn't he died?
His nephew lives there now.
His name is Mr. MochizukO. I heard he owns a company in Haitocho.
This is it! We got it, Conan.
The hot springs town in Izu she frequented with Mr. Ezaki.
She probably became nostalgic and went there.
Because we couldn't find her name
amongrthose involved In traffic Accidents or criminal gases.
The hot spring resort that
Uncle and Shizu frequented.
Toshio Mochizuki
FF) 5. (
The hot spring resort that
Uncle and Shizu frequented.
Toshio Mochizuki
= LL B88
2A ¥15 (50)
Yes, do you know where they used to stay in Izu?
Mr. Mochizuki,
do you want the locker moved out at two o'clock?
Yes, please do that.
The door is locked tight, and it contains things.
But it is all junk inside.
Please throw it away.
All right. I'll be back.
Hot springs in zu.
I haven't heard of any favorite inn.
Don't worry, she'll be back soon.
Is that right.
There are so many monkey figurines here.
Huh? Oh. yes.
They are all part of Uncle's collection.
Oh, that's "The Three Monkeys *
Hey, you're pretty smart.
See no evil, spea mg no eva . ear no evu .
That means don't get involved in matters that are no concern of yours.
I've been asking people all over,
but I couldn't find who he is.
IMI <B1l'Rdtels and inns in Izu. <
All over Izu?
There are théusand$d and théusands.
But I can't just sit here.
I want to know whether she's safe or not.
Hey, it's Bruce
What?
Oh, Bruce.
It is Itis Bruce
» - Bruce: We're in'trouble.
Granny's gone.
The scarf.
What is it Ayumi?
Bruce has Granny's sear around his neck.
Yeah
That means. he's with Mrs Ohmori
Wait! There is something written on the scarf.
I see eight "hi" characters on it.
What us that stain there?
Huh
This Is...
Blood stain!
Granny's been abducted and held
She hasn't gone to the hot springs in 1zu?
No. She tied the scarf with bloodstain around Bruce.
That means she's being held somewhere.
But, it means that she's 'hurt and can't move, right?
Then, she'd be writing where she is being held.
; The reason why she sent an encrypted message is
Encrypted message?
I get it
She did it so that the culprit won't be able to understand, if it should be found.
That means that we must decipher the message, right?
I've seen this somewhere.
What?
What? Somewhere? I
Granny-used to give me quizzes before Sailing to the cats.
One of them was a quiz about creating new Kanji characters
from the character "hi" by adding one more stroke.
A Quiz...
Mitsuhiko:. can you) guess?
Well.
Add one in the center, and you get "ME",
One vertical line and you get "TA",
Add a short one at the top and you get "SHIRO",
Come on, Mitsuhiko.
Anything else. Conan?
KYU, "YOSHI", "KOU", "TAN", "SHIN
K-kyu Yoshi
Kou.tan. shin?
Oh, sorpy I forget.
I'll write them down
The characters from left are.
ME", "SHIRO", "TA", "KYU,
YOSHI", "KOU", "TAN", "SHIN .
Wow.
Where did you get to learn them?
Th se tell us where she is being held?
The first three.
Do they mea ».some paddy in Mejiro?
Are there rice paddies 'n Mejiro?
Well
I get it!
The paddy became all white with snow.
And then?
Then, then...
It's so bright it hurts your eyes.
That's no clue to finding a place.
How about you?
Can't you think of anything ?
M-me
MESHIROTA KYUYOSHIKOU TANSHIN.
Y8u're just reading them in order.
Anyway, we need to find out the meaning of the last five characters.
Or else, we're getting nowhere.
The first character KyuTlis used to mean old.
The next "Yu" is a character used for the word reason
meaning reason for a happening.
Ko"suggests the turtle shell.
Tan" symbolizes the sun rising in the horiz
so it suggests sunrise or morning.
I've seen that one.
I saw it in New Year greeting cards!
Rights as in "Gain-Tan".
It-actually points to daybreak of New Year's Day.
New Year greetings?
Then that means.
The last character "Shin" suggests the "monkey"!
Monkey?
The character is used to symbolize the Monkey,
as in the Year of the Monkey.
Then, that suggests someone born in the Year of the Monkey?
Conan.
That character...
Isn't that read "dan", too?
What? As in "Dan-na. meaning master?
Now I know!
Yes. You told us Granny used to call Mr. Ezaki Master Ezaki.
Right.
That means these two...
point to the "old: or former. master,
that is, Mr. Ezaki.
But I thought Granny tried to tell"us where she is. not where Mr.JEzakKi is.
Well seems it-doesn't.
Do you remember her saying she doesn't deserve this, she's a miserable being?
I don't deserve that I am a miserable person not worthy of them
So, that means that she wasn't just being humble about; herself.
Right. Most probabi she learned a secret about Mr. Ezaki
and was abducted because of that.
And she sent'the, information in this encrypted message
Conan.
Doesn't this character suggest mouth" with a cross in it?
Yeah,
Then, this character "ta",
must be a mouth with aftross.
Meaning "Don't tell anyone
No, that's not it.
This means "make her silent".
That means "murder
What?
I'll show you.
If you put them-in this order...
Therreason why the former master was murdered,
That means Mr. Ezaki didn't die because of an accident.
He Th killed.
And the remaining four characters suggest the cause or the weapon.
The four are "ME", "SHIRO",
K@U", and "SHIN".
ME. SHIRO. KOU. SHIN
KoushRif.
Yes!
Koushin is just phonetic.
What, you mean "Koushin" points to "Koushinto"?
Yeah, there is 2 shopping street on the other side of the. tracks named Koushin
Yeah. Then, maybe someone-there
Koushinto that Mitsuhiko suggested frequently has a certain drawing on its
What drawing?
The Three Monkeys.
You mean that "see no evil, speak no evil and hear no evil"?
That means!
Yeah.
The Three Monkeys figurine welsaw at Mr. Ezaki's house.
That was the murder weapon.
Wait That what do
ME and SHIRO suggest?
Remember how the figurine looked liker
Huh
I got it
The Three Monkeys with white eyes! 7
Then. the culprit is that guy Mochizuki?
Most probably.
Anyway. we don't have time.
Granny will be moved out of the house at 2
What? You know where she is?
Certain a 3 can be.
We alerted the police, which arrived on time to rescue Granny.
From the locker that was about to be moved out of the house.
With her testimony,
Mr. Ezaki's blood was found on the figurine
And Mr. Mochizuki was arrested for murder, abduction and illegal detention
Original Comic Books By.
GO HO AOYAMA
Producers
MIGHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music
KATSUO ONO
(#haractef Designs-By
NL, Vv
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA y ad > >
TOSHIKI INO E
Ammdtion Dircalors.
MASAATOMO woo
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director
KENJI KODAMA
Produced By.
MS ENTERTAINMENT, LT!
In association with
YOMIURI TEDECASTING
CORPORATION
BETHCINEXCONAN
COSITOTHOY AWM SHOGARUR ANY IV TALS fl Rights Reserved
J Granny Shizu seems completely recovered and happy.
She's back taking care of the cats.
Great.
Heys that many
Isn't that the guy who threatened Granny the other day,
Yes.
Why I$ he apologizing to her?
What's going on. Ayumi?
Why is he apologizing?
That man almost had his car stolen.
What?
When the burglar was trying to steal it,
Bruce meowed inside the car.
He tried to check what was wrong inside.
While he was doing that, the guy came back and prevented the burglary.
Really, I owe it to the cat named Bruce.
I was saved. Thank you so much.
You were(lUst defending your own bed, right? Bruce.
Get out of here
Get out of here!
Hurry up and get out off here!
All this hassle about ghosts!
What a waste of time.
(If! 3:5)
AU AR)
Next Conan