Everyone's worried.
You caught a cold and didn't come to school...
Like a demon getting sunstroke, isn't it unusual for you?
It's just a cold.
Oh, my...
Look at those eyes moistened by the fever...
That's the charming Ran.
I want to show it to Shinichi-kun.
Well!
I'm headed home now.
Make sure to get some sleep.
Can't you stay longer?
I'm a bit afraid to be alone...
It's as if someone's peeking at me...
Could it be a stalker?
What?
No, it's nothing like that...
Then, what?
Don't laugh at me, OK?
What is it already?
It's definitely...
Definitely...
It's definitely a zashiki-warashi!
Zashiki-warashi: a mischievous, child-like spirit.
See, it just made a sound!
It's here...
Behind the door, a zashiki-warashi is...
Behind the door is?
Me?
Uh oh...
How odd—there wasn't anyone there, Ran.
But there was certainly a sneaky noise.
What should we do?
No need to worry.
Rather than a zashiki-warashi, it's just an annoying brat
It's fine, it's fine.
Office of Doctor Araide
There's no way there could be some zashiki-warashi these days, you know?
But...
So, Doctor, what's Ran condition?
She completely recovered from her cold...
And is in good health.
With such vitality, the spirit will surely run away.
Hey, by the way...
How's that old lady and the Kasefu-san I met before?
Those two have already gone to Aomori.
I see, you said something like that before...
That you'd be working in a hospital in Aomori.
So those two will be there with you?
But before I go, I need to reassign my current patients to other clinics.
It's impossible for me to leave before that, so they're there waiting on me.
And...
I have to testify in court regarding that case that occurred here.
I have to support Mouri-san's deduction.
Come to think of it, Araide-sensei...
He was standing on the other side of the door and heard my deduction.
It seems he unfortunately knows the truth...
But are you going to be all right?
Living in such a large house alone...
Isn't it scary?
Scary?
Because...
Like something could suddenly come out?
There you go again.
In these times when science and medicine have advanced so far, to go talking about ghosts...
They exist...
It's just that narrow-minded people can't see them.
Right now, there are monsters causing trouble in my apartment
Otonashi-san!
You came again?
Didn't I tell you not to come here?
There's no point in being so cold hearted.
I've already decided that you're my doctor for life!
Who's this old man?
Otonashi-san was one of the patients I looked after.
He doesn't want to go to the hospital I introduced him to.
Beyond all that, Mister...
Is what you said true?
About there being monsters in your apartment...
Hey, Conan-kun...
Oh, it sure is!
If you'd like, come and see, boy.
With a grudge and hard feelings so strong she cannot rest in peace...
The spirit of a young girl!
Geez...
I came here to see what kind of place it could be...
To see it's just some worn down apartment
But look, there's a park in front of the apartment
It's a nice and peaceful place, huh?
It's in this park that the the young girl's body was found.
The body of the young girl, burnt completely black.
A burnt body...
By the way, next to the apartment...
Its owner hung himself when the economic bubble popped...
And it remained in this under construction state and became an abandoned building.
It was originally a small graveyard.
Graveyard?
Let's continue talking inside.
I see.
This really is the best place for a ghost to appear.
Say...
Dad, let's go back!
Even if we're here, nothing good will happen.
You're noisy, just call a cab and go home by yourself.
It's scary to be home alone!
And Conan-kun's too excited about the ghost to want to go back with me...
Oh, this is rare...
I thought all the buzz about this building being haunted had passed.
But it seems we have some visitors.
It's been so long—they'll be excited tonight
Excited?
Oh, you know what they say.
"Ghosts are drawn to places where people gather," right?
Who's he?
The resident of room four, Banchou-san.
He works in a model shop.
He has a lot of strange dolls in his room.
Hey, let's go home after all!
What would we do if the ghost really appeared?
Wouldn't it be good?
If that happened, it'd liven the place up.
I've been lonely since they stopped appearing.
I wonder if they'll appear...
Just now was?
The resident of room two, Yotsuya-san.
He's a SFX maniac that's filled his room with those kinds of videos.
He and his university friends shot a ghost movie based on this apartment with an 8mm camera, but...
He's never let me watch it even once.
It's not worth watching!
To base a horror movie on ridiculous superstition is sheer stupidity.
It's completely foolish.
Oh, isn't your room number one?
The restroom on the first floor was occupied, so I had to use the one on the second floor.
Well, I don't care if you amuse yourselves with ghost stories...
Just please don't make too much noise.
I have a thesis I need to get done by tomorrow.
He is?
A graduate student, Botan-san.
He's the only one here who hasn't seen the ghosts.
Then again, the only people who have seen the ghosts and not moved out are...
That Banchou-san and Yotsuya-san you met earlier.
And me, living here in room five on the second floor.
It's just the three of us.
So half of the eight residents moved away due to the ghost's disturbances?
Yeah, that's right
It all started when I saw a will-o'-the-wisp floating in the building next door during the middle of the night
Originally, the other residents didn't believe me, but...
Then the water in the toilet turned red...
A person's shadow peered at us from the windows...
And we would feel faint and see horrific phantoms.
A succession of strange things happened.
Some television stations and magazines also ended up covering these events.
But why didn't you move away?
Nothing's frightening for an old person nearing their end.
And I have no intention of leaving this apartment I've lived in for so many years.
Well, just make yourselves at home.
Ghosts aren't likely to appear before it gets dark.
No, we should be leaving.
Don't give me that!
Hey, hey, we still have time.
Sounds quite interesting!
Geez...
Just until 7:00, all right?
Get out...
Quickly...
Leave this place!
Dad!
Dad, Dad!
Dad...
What is it, Ran?
Something happen?
There... on the television, a strange girl...
There's nothing on the TV.
No way.
Sure you didn't have a strange dream?
No, I really...
Hey, it's already this late?
When did we fall asleep?
Anyway, I'm going to the restroom.
Please wake this old guy up and let him know we're leaving.
Geez...
Ghosts, how ridiculous.
In the end, this was just a waste of time.
What's with this toilet?
It stinks, it's dark, and it's full of dead bugs!
Geez, we should have done like Ran said and gone home earlier.
Dad?
Come back.
He isn't waking up no matter what we do.
Wait a bit, I'll be right there.
What happened?
Blood, it's blood...
The water in the toilet is deep red...
No way!
What's going on here?
It's been noisy for a while now.
The water in the toilet turned into blood.
They came after all?
Really?
Ridiculous.
Surely it's just someone playing a prank.
Like putting red dye in the tank.
Seems that's not the case...
Maybe it was blood in your urine?
Absolutely not!
After I flushed, the water turned as red as blood in a flash.
After having fallen asleep, we were able to see a horrific phantom...
The water suddenly turned red...
Which means all that remains is a person's shadow peering in from the window...
Oh, it appeared!
What?
It appeared, it appeared!
What on earth is that?
Can't you tell just by looking?
This ghost that appeared...
That girl who was killed in the nearby park...
This is her dead spirit!
Huh?
It vanished...
Of course it did.
It's a true ghost...
She may have even entered this apartment!
What ghost?
Someone obviously climbed to the second floor and peered in from the window as a joke.
Step aside!
I'll confirm!
Hey, that window's...
You can't climb up here.
There's nothing like a veranda attached to this window.
Yes, that appears to be the case...
And that wasn't the shadow of any ordinary person...
The outline was moving in waves...
And its form started to dissipate before the window was even opened.
Just like...
Just like a demon turning to ash when it basks in the morning sun, right?
Old man...
I've seen it at this window before.
That pitiful woman...
It's no surprise it turned to ash.
It's probably the apparition of Tabuchi Rui-san, who was burnt to death in that park four years ago.
Tabuchi Rui-san?
Her license escaped the flames and was found on her remains.
The dental records also matched.
And until the two men who killed her are arrested, she probably won't be able to rest in peace.
Two men?
There was a witness?
Yeah.
During the night, someone who happened to be in the park saw it
Two guys were nearby watching the body burn.
Look, we can see it attached to the utility pole from this window.
The portrait of one of the two criminals.
With a big scar on his cheek and the look of a bad guy.
Since it was dark, the face of his companion wasn't clearly seen.
Well, by now the only one who lived here before the case occurred is that old man.
What, it appeared again?
An insect...
An insect on your arm...
We get moths around here quite often.
It came in through the window.
It seems that a lot are living in the park where the case occurred.
Since it's directly in front of this building, they come here often.
Geez...
Whining about a bug, it's tiresome!
Thanks to that, the ghostly mood has been ruined.
Really?
But it was a great scream...
Anyway, please don't make any more of a fuss.
That strange shadow we saw was likely only one of our reflections in the window.
Idiot!
This is a true demon's work!
That's right
That's why I told you...
Nothing good will happen here!
Come on, Dad!
Let's hurry home!
You too, Conan-kun, don't dawdle around!
Hey, Conan-kun...
What are you doing?
Say, Uncle...
Did the water in this toilet really turn blood red?
Well...
I don't know if it was blood or not but it really did turn red.
Thinking about it now, the water pipes are probably just rusted, causing muddy water to come out
Weird...
There was a strong odor earlier.
Isn't it the ventilation?
Since the door's been open since then.
That may be it
This smell is...
Alcohol?
Hey, don't mess around!
But, I wanna check everything thoroughly so I can tell everybody at school about it!
About how the famous detective Mouri Kogorou was scared away by some ghost stories.
Insolent!
Hey, Ran!
We're not leaving yet!
Why not?
There's no way there are ghosts!
Geez...
It's an optical illusion, an optical illusion.
The human shadow in the window had to be someone's reflection.
The red water in the toilet was just muddy water.
After being engrossed in this sinister environment, we just imagined things.
Then, are you saying it's the same for the girl I saw?
She was really on that TV!
The burnt girl said...
"Get out, get out"
That was also an optical illusion.
According to this newspaper's program schedule...
There weren't any ghost stories on at that time.
But...
Well, another explanation could be...
That, in order to make us believe his ghost stories, the master of this room played some strange video.
Are you talking about me?
I don't think that's it
Back then, I looked right after it happened and there wasn't a tape in the player.
The other thing I don't get is why everyone was asleep back then.
As I thought, it's haunted.
Idiot, there's no way that's possible!
If someone tried to climb up here, they'd probably slip and fall off.
The apartment is surrounded by a huge fence...
And this window faces the building under construction.
Conan-kun...
Why'd you open the window again?
Some bugs may fly in again.
I was wondering in which part of that building the old man saw the will-o'-the-wisp.
Oh, if that's what you're looking for, it was in the very center of the building.
A lonely red light floating in the air.
There are times when it's a pale blue light, too.
What's the meaning of this?
The spirit on the television after we fell asleep...
The water in the toilet suddenly becoming blood red...
They both have rational explanations.
But the two that remain...
I still can't understand the will-o-the-wisps and the person's shadow in the window.
Just what is it the culprit's trying to do?
Furthermore, is there really a culprit?
And if there is, just who is it?
Why are they doing this?