The distance between two
people's love and hate
Two people's deduction
and suspense
A surprise trick in a
questionable apartment
He sees through the one and only truth,
a child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
No case is left unsolved with Detective Conan.
We met a grandpa at Araide Clinic and
heard a bizarre ghost story from him.
Then we came to his
small old apartment house which
he said was haunted.
Incidentally, there is a building next
to his apartment house
The builder had committed suicide
after the bursting of the financial bubble.
There is a park in front of
his apartment house too,
where the burned body of
a young woman was previously found.
This place has many eerie stories
surrounding it,
and we fell asleep while
waiting in grandfather's room
for the ghost to appear.
Get out of here...Get out of here...
Get out of here
immediately
The toilet water turned red
A spooky figure looks in through
the window from outside
A sped \« figure looks in through
Besides,
a supernatural fiery ball
IS said to appear in the building next door.
What does this mean anyhow?
The ghost appearing on the TV screen
after suddenly fainting.
The toilet water suddenly turning red.
Both can be explained scientifically
but what about the other two phenomenon
the death candle
and the figure in the window?
I just can't seem to figure them out.
How did the culprit do them
Was there a culprit in the! first places
If one did exist
who could it be?
And for what purpose
IS the culprit doing all this for?
Truth of the Haunted House (Part ll)
Hey. Conan.
What're you looking
at with the window open?
The bugs will come flying in again.
Well, I'm wondering just about where that
gramps saw the death candle in
that building.
The spot where I saw it is in the darkness
around the center of that building.
The red light alone was looming and
moving about in the air.
At times it turned a bluish white light.
If you don't believe me, go ask
Houichi Otonashi
I ll') u
6 META
Mr. Yotsuya of Room #2 and
Mr. Bancho of Room #4.
Houichi Otonashi
5 WMMmMEA
Each of them said that
they once also saw the death candle.
Oh. yeah, I saw.
A red one and blue death candle as w
Iwahisa Yotsuya
Ne B22)
2 LoASM¢N AN
QQIEA
when I visited the room
where my senior at school was livin
Iwahisa Yotsuya
ma AM (22)
CILIA
SCHEME A
Your senior?
Yeah.
Just up there.
It's the room right above this one.
Room #6 is where my senior was living.
But since then,
he was unable to sleep properly
because he was seized with
fear of the death candles.
He finally moved out.
I was unable to sleep either,
not because of fright,
but rather. because of being overexcited.
Oh. yeah.
Hey. this is a 8mm movie projector. right?
I'm now using it to edit a movie filmed
by our film club in college.
But this room is bloody awful,
full of sick horror magazines and posters.
It's really scary.
I feel I'm going to have nightmares
just being here.
Still. all this is nothing
compared to
Room #4 where Mr.Bancho lives.
What?
Yeah, this room is really something.
There're tons of the
ghost and monster figures here.
Kikuji Banhou
&% BY 3% Xx (34)
4§I&A
You haven't seen anything yet.
Kikuji Banhou
FE BI BT Xx (34)
CS LQUOQL.
AB EEA
Kikuji Banhou
FE BY 5 Xx (34)
aiiéA
I turn the light off like so
Kikuji Banhou
ZE BY [ ox (34)
AMET A
I turn the light off like so
Yipes!
1. The figures...
are glowing various colors in the dark.
It's because of this black light.
The special kind of fluorescent
coating painted on the figures
reacts to black light making them
glow like a neon tube.
Hmm...You know a lot, sonny.
A toy store owner told me about it.
By the way,
you also saw the death candle, right?
Yeah, I did
but'l saw it through that window
not the window facing that building.
This window is located diagonally
below the window where
the figure appeared.
Hey. kid.
I think you better close the window now.
Do it for our sister's sake.
But, in fact,
a couple of moths have already entered.
If you don't believe
the ghost story I told you,
you better go talk with Botan of Room #1.
That-square grad student
with a square head.
Yeah.
I've never seen it before.
I believe nothing but
what I can comprehend scientifically.
Tsuyuhiko Botan
HR RE QR)
But you know
what I hate more than that now?
Tsuyuhiko Botan
HF mE (27)
<LI.
TS EREA
Tsuyuhiko Botan
HA BE (27)
kL} {IN
That building opposite here
that is still half done.
Tsuyuhiko Botan
HER REED
That building opposite here
that is still half done.
Which means?
All right, sO. get a load of this.
That goddamn building
shuts out the sunlight,
so the sun rarely shines into the room.
That's certainly true.
Mr.Otonashi's room diagonally
above is much better than mine.
Because it has a window
facing the street side.
So. why don't you move out?
Because the rent is so cheap and
my grandma told me that
this place had good feng shun.
Did you say you believe only what
you can comprehend scientifically, huh?
Excuse me. May I.
Smoke here?
Oh, sure, please.
But please leave
after you finish smoking the cigarette.
Sure.
Cigarette?
Ah".<... Ahh
D...Dad.... your arm!
A moth again.
Darn! Why always me?
Get them out of the room quickly! Now.
That's what I'm trying to do now.
I see.
The culprits were afraid that the murder
they committed would be revealed.
So they tried to destroy
the decisive evidence
of/the woman that
they burned to death 4 years ago.
They used ghosts
to cover up the evildoing.
What?Are you leaving already?
The night's still young
You may be missing out on seeing
one of the eeriest ghosts
you've ever seen before.
Too bad you're leaving.
Well, it'spperfectly all right with me
If you leave now.
That way I can get on with my paper.
buddy,
take it easy. say hello to the ghost for me.
Heigh-ho.
How unsociable they are.
Faugh.
Haunted by the ghost. my eye?
Making such a big fuss over illusion.
Hmm.? Where is Conan?
Oh. there he is.
Hey! We're going home now.
I've got to go pee. but
I'm a bit scared to go alone...
Hey. pops. please go with me?
Oh. man.
Come on , why should I?
All right, all right.
I'll be waiting outside then.
Phew.
I think I've seen him somewhere before.
Who's there?
Oh! Sonny!
I thought you went home.
We've got trouble.
Trouble?
Ook. That restroom is cursed
No doubt about it.
It's so stinky and I can't flush the toilet.
Huh
Oh, it sure smells. but
There seems no problem with flushing...
Wa-water is... Water is turning red
Tha-that...
That can't be true!
Oh. boy
Now, the TV in your room is cursed.
What!
Look. over there.
Get out of here...
The ghost! That's the ghost!
What should we do?
This can't be happening
What're you doing?
There is no tape inside
Who is it?
Who is doing this?
WwW. What?
Oh! So it appeared again! The ghost.
No. no way!
There must be something wrong here!
Because everything was...
Yeah...
They were all tricks to
make it look like the works of the ghost.
You're saying that nobody
but you could have set the tricks up
because you created them. isn't that right.
Mr. Bancho?
Tricks.
How can you say that?
Man. you're acting like
a detective or something.
De-detective?
Don't tell me
you are the renowned detective
Sleeping Kogoro.
Yeah, that's right.
Now I'm gonna unlock
the mysteries of
a lot of psychic phenomena.
First of all,
about the toilet water turning red.
What I noticed about it was that,
when I entered the restroom,
it smelled awfully of ammonia, and
that the toilet tank
smelled faintly of alcohol.
Ammonia and alcohol?
You know.
Perhaps you did an experiment in
science in your elementary school days,
didn't you?
When you add one drop of
alkaline ammonia water to the
colorless phenolphthalein
solution dissolved in alcohol,
the red color will appear like magic.
Do you remember the experiment?
Yeah, but,
I wonder if it would work out that well?
The color in the experiment isn't
bright red but pinkish red.
The color could never be mistaken.
Yeah, true.
But it would look like blood
in a dimly-lit restroom like here.
Well. even so
there is no chemical reaction with urine.
Because ammonia in
our urine Is acid or neutral.
Not alkaline.
Yes. that's why he needed
this ammonia liquid.
1S IS pourec IN 0 e wa er
in the toilet bowl
then phenolphthalein is poured into
the water in the toilet tank.
Then chemical reaction will occur.
And nobody would suspect the
strong smell of ammonia
seeing this dirty restroom.
Exactly
But.
Where did you get that chemical, sonny?
Pops asked me to look for it.
So when you were saying goodbye
at the entrance,
I slipped into the room and found it
in this room. Mr. Bancho.
I also found other interesting things
Iike phenolphthalein and chloroform.
And even a video tape of a Cary movie.
A scary movie video tape?
Yeah! The tape with a ghost woman
saying. Go home, go home!
He-hey
D.Don't tell me that
CC <oo
The real identity of the ghost my daughter
Ran saw on the TV screen are the
pictures Mr. Bancho
transmitted from the VCR in his room.
He-he sent the pictures!! How?
It's simple and easy
If you use
the public antenna of this building.
Plug the antenna cord into the output
terminal of the VCR in his room
and transmit video pictures to the antenna
Then the antenna sends the pictures
to the TV in Mr. Otonashfs room.
But.
In order to do that, you have to be
able to set the TV channel
to the appropriate channel to
receive the pictures
And you must turn on the TV first,
how do you think
It's a multi channel remote control
Mr @tonashi
Once you enter the name of
the manufacturer of
your TV or VCR into the device
you can operate any TV or VCR
made by the manufacturer.
So with the multi channel remote control,
you can operate the TV in
someone else's room on
without the owner realizing a thing
Well
after finding out how the trick worked
it was a piece of cake even for me.
Don't tell me.
This old man was the one who sent
the images to my TV screen a while ago.
Yeah, I got him to help me.
send the video I just borrowed from you.
You used the remote control
from outside
the window of Mr. Othonashi's room.
Facing the building under construction.
Using the wall as a foothold,
you could easily send
the signals to his TV set from there.
You didn't even need to watch
the TV screen since
the video was played repeatedly
All you had to do was listen to the
sound from the TV and set the channel.
And while the sun was still up.
You poured the chloroform
onto the windowsill
so that all of us who were in the room
would fall asleep
You thought you could make
one of us who suddenly fainted
and got up in the dark room, still
hazy in the head see an eerie illusion.
Isn't that right?
I see.
B-but, that was for real. wasn't it?
I mean the figure of a person
that has been looking this way!
Oh. that's not a figure of a person at all.
What?
Go over and look closer,
you'll see what it is.
This..this is
Moths gathered in large numbers.
Or, to put it more precisely
it's an aggregate of male moths.
He coated the screen in a human shape
with female moth pheromone,
that is also used as an insecticide,
and stuck eyes and a mouth
made from black paper on it.
The male moths that were attracted to
the scent of the pheromone,
clustered on it to make it
Iook like a human shadow was
Iooking inside through the window.
In fact, moths kept approaching
my arm several times.
When I almost fell from the window
where I saw the figure for the first time,
I found myself grabbing the screen,
and got the pheromone on my arm,
which attracted moths to me
So. that is
I simply removed the screen
on the second floor and
placed it by window on the first floor.
That's all.
Incidentally.
The reason why the figure
started on its own is disappearing
because Mr. Bansho's black light that
was activated by a timer
was emitted from the window
of his room diagonally below.
Moths are more prone to be attracted by
ultraviolet light emitted by the
black lights, than the pheromone
But the trick would be disclosed
if even one moth remains.
That's why Mr. Bancho hurried across
to the window,
as soon as the moths
began to fly out. then
opened the window and screen together.
The force of the impact knocked
the moths off the screen completely.
Mr. Bancho, you pretended not to notice
the moths even
when you got close to the window. right?
That's because you intentionally caused
this uproar over the ghost
But. I still don't understand
All the chemicals besides the
chloroform can be gotten easily. but why
Right.
Mr. Bancho could've easily made
the video himself,
by using his scary figures and his falsetto
Why'd he go through the trouble
of making up a ghost story?
He attempted to scare us,
Mr. Otonashi's guests.
To get Mr. Otonashi who refused to move
to decide to do after all this ghost scare.
Perhaps. in order to cover up
the crime four years ago
The crime four years ago?
You mean the murder of the the woman
burned to death in the park?
You say you saw the death candle
in that building under construction?
Yeah, that's right.
What was drifting in the air wasn't
the death candle, but a lit cigarette.
What was glowing bluish white
was the light of portable TV that was
secretly being watched.
What!? Don't tell me there's someone
in that building?
Yeah, taking advantage of the fact
the building is still under construction,
he's been living in hiding there.
He is one of the two murderers who was
witnessed four years ago.
That has a scar across his cheek!
Perhaps,
Mr. Bancho is one of the two murderers,
whose face wasn't witnessed.
As the light of the cigarette
was witnessed
and the fact that somebody
Iived here was about to be disclosed,
you fabricated and
accelerated the plot about the ghost girl,
you-chased the.residents of the condo
outione after the other.
Because they could look
inside the building from their room!
You did this all to keep your accomplice
rom going out into the world,
because if so, that accomplice would
turn out to be decisive evidence.
The reason that you're living here
IS to bring the guy with the scar across
his cheek, his food and drinks,
because his scar will give him away.
I guess you were planning to sneak out
after things settled down a bit,
but too late now.
See, you can hear it, can't you?
The footsteps of doom.
The siren of the police car that I called.
Damn it.
Darn it.
Out of the way, move!
@ut of the way, move!
Ran! Don't get pass you!
Out of my way. lady
or I'll curse you to death!
Ust what did you say...
If you're not a ghost,
you don't scare me at all.
Ac IS .
The police arrived there soon after.
The host of this haunted house
and the "death candle man
- ad -
ncing in ye ul cing were arres e
The case of the haunted house
scare together with the murder case
that occurred four years ago,
came to a close.
Incidentally, the murder four yeas ago
was committed
because of money trouble.
What a worldly case over money
behind an unworldly ghost case.
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO_AOYAMA
Original Comic Books By.
GCOSHOGDO AYANA
Pr 0 ( luc r S
MICHIHIKO SUWA
Background Music
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By.
MASATOMQ sum»
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
Scripts By.
KANJI KASHIWABARA
KAZUNA RI KDUCYHI ">
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INO E
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO, SUD
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
ea bd
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography.
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KEN]! KODAMA
Produced By.
MS ENTERTAINMENT, LII
In assocration with
YOMIURI TEDECASTING
CORPORATION
DETECIINVE CONANT
COSHO AY INTE SHOCARUK ANY TV TALS
PURITHISIROSCTITT
So. all those ghosts were tricks after all. }
Yeah
I don't give a hoot about them anymore
They Mm exist.
Bu no
What's wrong. Sonokor
He-hey. Sonoko.
Are you crying? Why?
Be-because
Because with you talking like that
I can't show my true self, can I?
I give myself credit
for this perfect makeup.
Ram's boogey phobia is
one of her charm points
SO it's A waste to cure it
Don't you think so?
Ye-Yeah.
I think you should do something
about your personality first
Officer Takagi?
What is he looking for?
Hey, hey, thatish t good