Two people's deductions and suspense
fill the gulf between love and hate!
Detective Takagi messed up!
Let's help him out, Detective Boys!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Guys! Big trouble!
What? Detective Takagi? Where?
In the park over there!
It's true.
He's trying desperately to find something.
A piece of evidence for a case?
No. If it were that, he'd be wearing gloves.
I bet I know what he's looking for.
It's got to be here... Where else could it be?
Y-You guys!
We're here to help!
Well, you'd do the same for us if we were in trouble.
I got it! You lost something that looked like this.
H-How did you know?!
We're the Detective Boys!
We can see through everything!
It'll be big trouble for you if you can't find it, right?
Yeah, it is! It's the second-most important thing to a policeman besides his own life!
Then the thing you lost that looked like this...
...wasn't your wallet after all?
Y-You lost your police notebook?
Keep it down!
Oh geez. That's a big problem.
It was this morning when I realized I lost it.
I tore up my apartment looking for it, but I couldn't find it...
Are you sure you had it with you
when you were working yesterday?
There's no question about it.
Afterwards, on my way home,
I happened to pass by this park...
Shut up! Damn liar!
Cut that out!
What're you doing?!
You cheat!
I should beat your ass right here and now!
Hey, hold up!
Break it up, you two!
Shut up! You stay out of this!
Police! Stop this fight immediately!
That's when I think I lost it...
So that's why you're looking for it around here.
Do you think maybe one of the two guys who were fighting picked it up?
You may be right!
It's very probable.
Do you remember their names, or their addresses?
W-Wait! Calm down!
Why can't you believe me, Hanzaki?
Hanzaki...
The younger one's name was Hanzaki!
Anything else you remember about them?
How do you expect me to believe you?
I'm telling you, my manager,
that I'm still a struggling singer
because all the jobs you got me were always crap!
That's because you gotta pay your dues in enka business, you know that!
Have a little more patience, please!
How many times are you gonna say that, huh?
I know you've tricked me for a long time.
Give me back my time up to now
and the money you owe me, damn you!
H-Hey, hold on, you guys!
So he's a struggling enka singer.
Do you remember what kind of shoes they were wearing?
Come to think of it...
That Hanzaki guy was wearing sandals.
I see!
He could live nearby, right?
Alright, then!
Let's look for him together!
But what if that man didn't pick it up?
Why don't we split up into pairs, then?
One pair goes and looks for this Hanzaki person,
and the other stays in the park and looks for the notebook.
Alright!
Paper, rock, scissors!
Too bad, looks like that's up to you.
Ugh.
No good... There's no such name...
What about asking recording studios?
I'm afraid that's impossible.
There's an awful lot of big and small recording studios.
OK, then we've got to go around asking one-by-one.
Excuse me, but do you know a man named Hanzaki-san?
He's a singer, and supposed to live around here somewhere.
Pardon me, sir...
I see... His police notebook...
Yeah.
I wonder... What if Detective Takagi can't find it?
Too bad for him, probably.
You fool!
You lost your police notebook, which is supposed to be the extension of a policeman's very soul!
Get out! You're fired!
Poor Detective Takagi...
Hey, you two!
This is no time for a snack! Gimme a hand here!
Oh, sorry.
Oh, they came back.
How did it go? Did you find him?
No...
We couldn't find him either by name or appearance...
We couldn't find it either.
Oh? Mr. Officer!
Jiro Hanzaki (30)
Enka Singer
What're you doing in a place like this?
I-I-It's you!
Y-You... Yesterday...
Sorry for the trouble last night.
So is this the man everyone's talking about?
Hanzaki-san?!
Why now? I just wish you'd
walked by sooner than you did.
Hanzaki-san, did you pick anything up last night?
Something of mine that looks like this?
No, nothing like that.
I don't think my manager did either.
I see...
You're looking for something that looks like this, right?
I'll look for it with you.
Uh, that's all right, you don't need to do that...
Just wanna pay you back for your kindness.
Last night, thanks to you, the manager and I were able to get back together.
Well, today we were going to meet over lunch.
But I waited for him at my apartment, and he never showed up.
He likes to drink, so he's probably been at home all day getting wasted.
That's the problem with him, really...
I kept calling, but he never picked up...
Which means he's gotta be home, dead drunk.
Er, if you think he won't show up no matter how long you wait,
why don't you go to his place yourself?
'Cause it takes an hour and a half to get there,
even if I drive with my foot to the floor.
It's a real bother.
Something's stuck on you.
Ah, it's shampoo.
A little while ago when I was cleaning my bathroom,
I accidentally stepped on the shampoo bottle.
By the way, can you tell me the time, Mr. Officer?
It's 1:00, 1:00 on the dot.
1:00 already?!
We've gotta hurry and find it!
You don't have to help me any more!
But...
Then let me buy you lunch at that restaurant!
It's just 2000 yen, and all you can eat for two hours.
Please?
Thanks, but I'll pass.
Are you sure?
You don't have to be so modest.
Alright...
I'll eat all I can for two hours!
Later, Mr. Officer!
Weird guy...
He's too weird.
If those two didn't pick it up, it should still be here somewhere!
I think that Hanzaki person's up to something.
Yeah.
I wonder why he bothered to ask what time it was.
It's hard to believe someone in this neighborhood doesn't know...
that clock.
But he went out of his way to ask Detective Takagi for the time...
What for?
I got it!
D-Did you find it?
Uh, no, I wasn't talking about the notebook...
Oh, I see...
Then what was that for, all of a sudden?
Hey, everyone, gather around.
That Hanzaki guy killed his manager?!
Are you sure, Mitsuhiko?!
No doubt about it. And he did it just now.
Hanzaki seemed to think he was still
a struggling singer because of his manager,
and held a grudge against him
for it, so he does have a motive.
But...
The drop of shampoo stuck to the bottom of his trousers, right?
He said he accidentally stepped on the
shampoo bottle while cleaning his bathroom.
First of all, I wonder why he lied about it.
Lied?
It goes without saying that you should roll up your pants,
so as not to get them wet while cleaning your bathroom.
But if he rolled up his pants, the shampoo wouldn't stick to the bottom of them.
Which means he wasn't cleaning his bathroom,
but he was in the bathroom for some other reason.
H-Hey, wait a sec, Mitsuhiko!
A-And then, then what?
This morning, Hanzaki-san called the manager to come to his apartment,
saying he wanted to make up with him.
That's enough.
I can't drink that much.
He cleverly convinced the manager,
a heavy drinker, to drink his favorite liquor.
After waiting for the right time, just before 1 PM,
he carried him to the bathroom in his apartment,
and drowned him in the tub.
Then he accidentally stepped on the shampoo bottle.
Then he rushed out of the apartment and came to the park
to set up his alibi!
To set up his alibi?
That's right.
He's going to carry the body out of his apartment secretly, perhaps tonight,
and sink the body in the bathtub of the manager's house.
That way the police will treat it as an alcohol-influenced accidental death.
And even if they treat the case as murder,
his estimated time of death...
was around 1 this afternoon.
That's right...
By the way, can you tell me the time, Mr. Officer?
It's 1:00, 1:00 on the dot.
Right when the manager was supposed to have been killed at home, Hanzaki-san was here.
It's an hour and a half drive there from this park.
As the real police officer,
Detective Takagi, proves his alibi,
nobody suspects Hanzaki-san!
It's the perfect crime!
Perfect reasoning, Mitsuhiko!
What part of that is perfect?
Poor Detective Takagi...
He lost his police notebook,
and was even used to set up a killer's alibi...
Hey, Mitsuhiko.
You said, "It goes without saying
that you should roll up your pants while cleaning your bathroom", right?
That's just a matter of common sense all over the world.
Old man Mouri doesn't roll up his pants because he thinks it's a bother.
W-Well...
Come to think of it, Doc doesn't either.
Which means he could have really been cleaning his bathroom.
And Detective Takagi came here to search for his police notebook because he happened to lose it.
It's quite hard to imagine that Hanzaki-san was relying
on such a coincidence to establish his important alibi, isn't it?
W-Well...
You completely missed the mark.
I won't forgive him!
A-Ayumi-chan!
Hey, cut it out, Ayumi!
But I can't forgive him!
He tried to use such a nice guy as Detective Takagi!
But my deductions were wrong...
What does that mean anyway?
What does what mean?
Look over there!
How strange...
He hasn't eaten anything yet.
You're right...
Why?
Is that man up to something?
He isn't eating anything, after all...
What a waste.
But all he cares about is the time.
Yeah. He's just watching the clock.
How weird.
If he's not hungry, what's he doing at an
"all you can eat for two hours" restaurant?
You're right.
Why?
Come to think of it...
You're looking for something that looks like this, right?
I'll look for it with you.
Then let me buy you lunch at that restaurant!
He was persistent about trying to be with Detective Takagi...
That explains it!
Mitsuhiko, your deductions were half correct!
Half?
As you suspected, he's trying to kill his manager.
So he went to this restaurant, and is pretending to be a customer to establish an alibi.
To establish an alibi?
If Detective Takagi hadn't sent him away,
he would have wanted to establish an alibi
by continuing to look for the police notebook.
But you said Detective Takagi just
happened to come to the park today.
No. He knew Detective Takagi would be there looking for it.
Perhaps, because he picked it up last night.
Then he still has the notebook?
No. Unfortunately, I'm afraid he's already thrown it out.
Yeah. There's no reason to hold on to something so dangerous.
I see...
The half of Mitsuhiko's deduction that was wrong was this.
The manager's time of death wouldn't be 1:00,
but later, around 2:00 or 2:30.
But it's just past 1:00.
Right.
His murder plot is moving forward at a steady pace.
Perhaps, in the bathroom of his apartment.
That's why he's so concerned about the time.
Anyway, it may not be too late to save the manager's life!
Right!
But do you even know where his apartment is?
He's right...
If we ask, he'll never tell us...
Let's split up and find it!
Yeah!
Even the Detective Boys gave up on me...
Oh, that struggling singer.
He's quite a character.
Last night he was picking up concrete blocks over there.
That's not what we want to know.
Do you know where he lives?
Well, I have no idea...
It's Hanzaki, Hanzaki! He's an enka singer!
He must live around here!
Hell if I know. I don't care for enka.
Later.
Hey! W-W-Wait!
Let's go over there.
Hello, hello? Do you copy?
We've found out where Hanzaki's apartment is!
Really?!
Yay!
It's the second floor of Park Side Heights, in 3-chome! Over.
Roger! We'll be there soon!
I'll go get Detective Takagi!
Good idea.
Hopefully, if he can prevent the murder,
it'll make up for the mistake of losing the police notebook.
The shop owner said Hanzaki
bought a big block of ice today.
And the concrete blocks he picked up...
Aha, I've figured out his trick!
And if Hanzaki leaves the body lying on the stairs,
he can make it look like the manager
slipped and fell to his death while drunk!
Oh, no! We've got to hurry!
A murder case?
I mean, he's gonna be killed soon, I mean...
I can't figure out what you're trying to say...
Sorry, but I have to find my notebook.
B-But...
I got this!
That Hanzaki guy actually picked up your notebook yesterday.
He did pick it up?!
He said, "I've got it at my apartment, so stop by to pick it up."
W-Where is his apartment?!
Conan-kun!
I managed to get a spare key from the landlord!
Hey!
Conan-kun!
Is this his apartment?
Yeah!
Where is it?
Where?
Where? Where? Where?
Where's my notebook?
Yay!
I'll untie you right now.
Thanks for saving me...
You're that guy from yesterday...
Sei'ichi Sugiyama (52)
Hanzaki's Manager
Yes. I'm Sugiyama.
You saved me both yesterday and today, Takagi-san!
How do you know my name?
I don't think I told you yesterday...
I saw your name...
written in here.
You found it!
Yay! You found it!
It seems like that Hanzaki person
didn't pick up the notebook himself,
but just saw him pick it up.
Yeah. Looks that way.
Saved... What a relief!
W-What are you doing here?
I'd like to know what you're doing here!
I've gone along with you for a long time
because I believed you had a special talent.
Why didn't you believe in me until the end, Hanzaki?
I'm sorry...
I'm Takagi, an officer from Metro Police Criminal Investigation Division 1.
Hanzaki-san...
Can you come with me to the police station?
Yes...
Takagi-kun.
I heard you prevented a murder.
Yes, sir.
Well done. Your work is appreciated.
Yes, sir!
By the way, how's your headache?
How about your fever of 39C?
And your stomachache?
And the ankle you fell and sprained?
And how you hurt so bad you couldn't move?
Detective Takagi pretended to be sick so he could find his lost notebook.
Looks like it.
Then he was playing hooky from work?
You fool!
What were you thinking,
a policeman faking being sick?!
Get back to the police station this instant!
Y-Yes, sir!
On the double!
Yes, sir!
Uh, waihold up, Inspector Megure!
He did end up getting chewed out by him after all.
Huh? Isn't that the same woman from earlier?
What?
Next Conan:
What'll the next Conan be?
Curtain
Next time, it's him again!
I'm Jodie, who's this "Great Detective of the West"?