Suspense and deduction
closes the gap between
The love and hatred between two people.
Hattori Heiji has returned
He solves a mystery with Jodie
He sees through the one and only truth,
a child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Wh-what?
All the investigation records of the cases
that Detective Mouri helped solve,
were stolen from the Metropolitan Police?
Yeah.
Did Detective Takagi really say that?
Shh! Not so loud!
Hey, don't tell me that the thieves are
Yeah, Maybe they had a hand in this
If they heard rumors that I, who was
supposed to have been dead by that drug
and if they noticed something suspicious
about Kogoro Mouri's deductions,
It's possible.
And if someone among
the men in black found out that
Shinichi Kudo was advising Kogoro Mouri
Well, my disappearance
coincided with the time when
Sleeping Kogoro" started, so it wouldn't
surprise me if they thought it strange.
Hey, hey
Yet, rumors are rumors
Don't worry.
Shinichi Kudo isn't around anymore.
And no one could imagine
that the drug shrank me and that
I'm still solving cases by,
putting Pops to sleep.
Even if they did see me going around
solving cases behind the scenes,
they'd only think of me
as a super smart kid for my age
Besides, it hasn't been determined that
they're the ones who stole the records yet.
Yeah, but...
Oh, well,... it's definite
that someone is spying on Pops
Just in case,
I have a favor to ask you!.Doc.
Pugh!
You use me when you want and
then you ignore me.
Why don't you go ask someone
more reliable than me, huh?
Oh...So,
are you mad that I didn't tell you
about the stolen records?
Humph!
Hey, don't be mad at me, Doc.
I can't help it...
Because she was there at the time.
She? You mean Ail?
Yeah...
If she knew that somebody was snooping
something around here,
I'm sure she would refuse to go out again
That's why I gave her my word...
And told her not to worry,
because I'd would do everything I could
to help her if things start looking bad.
So you see, I can't have her worrying
Now, where's Haibaray
In the lab downstairs; I think.
All right.
Anyway, don't let her know about this
she's not as tough as
she pretends to be, you know.
Fool.
English Teacher -v-s: Renowned
Detective of the West" Part.
But there's something I don't get.
Huh? What is it?
The guy who stole the files
sent everything back
to the Metropolitan Police,
In a sealed envelope.
Well...
the culprit probably returned the files
because he or she already
finished examining them
That's nuts.
If they finished examining the files, then
why didn't they just throw them away?
Why would they
go out of their way to send the files back
and breed more suspicion?
That's true.
The most possible explanation is that
they are trying to relay a defiant message,
We're already on to all your tricks."
they're trying to lure someone out...
Well, in this case, the person
they are trying to lure out is Kudo...
You, that is.
Yeah... most likely.
What I don't get is if it's really a trap, then
why are they doing it in
such a complicated way?
Yeah, that's right.
There're a lot of ways
to lure someone out...
What...what are you doing here, Hattori?
This old man called me,
saying that if I, your BEST FRIEND,
came, I could help you.
Well, I was under the impression that
Shinichi was burdened with something
he had a hard time
finding a way out{from.
But I guess we're dealing with something
similar to grasping clouds,
so there's not much we can do
Wrong, old man.
Why{do you think Kudo came to
tell-'you such an important thing,
which he hadn't told you until now?
He came here either
because he found a very important
piece of information, or because
he has found a way
to counter attack them.
There
Hey, correct? Say something, will'you.
You face is telling me that I hit the mark.
Well, do you remember I told you before,
that I had a brush with them
at Haido City Hotel?
Yeah...
You went there with that
Iittle girl named Haibara
and hunted down the
old man named Pisco, right?
That's right
I've been wondering for a while...
Why did Pisco have
the handkerchief of the party,
which he wasn't supposed to have,
when he was questioned
at the police station?
There were seven suspects detained
for questioning by the police.
Of course, Pisco didn't think that
his handkerchief would be
checked by the police.
That means...
An accomplice.
Someone among the other six suspects,
who knew that he
was gonna be checked first,
secretly gave Pisco the handkerchief.
Besides
Pisco, the other six suspects were
Mika Nanjo,
Yasuo Mihei,
Yoshiharu Tahara,
Naoya Tarumi,
Naomichi Mugikura,
and Chris Vineyard.
All six of them are celebrities-
who appear frequently on the media.
But...
There is one person who
announced taking a break from work,
and disappeared since that case.
And that is...
Chris Vineyard!
The American movie star.
Chris...a second generation actress
Oh, that clever and
beautiful actress with big boobs.
Yeah,
the only child of the famous actress,
Sharon Vineyard.
I checked on a lot of things. buts
she's the most suspicious.
I didn't want to think so though
So, I want to ask a favor of you, Doc.
Huh? What is it?
An internet address?
Yeah...
It's a website uploaded by fervent
fans of hers wanting her to come back.
Can you access the site
and gather information?
Her biographical data, interests or habits
any hot topics, anything
that her fans know about her.
Going to the Internet Cafe any more than
I already have, as a kid,
checking out foreign websites is
going to make people suspicious of me
Okay. I-ll try, but.
What re you gonna do
with all the information?
Well, it may come in handy one day.
You have somebody, don't you?
Huh?
Theresa suspicious
foreign woman around you.
D.Don't be silly. No way!!
No joke?
Are you talking about Jodie, the teacher?
Jodie?
Who's she?
Um...She's...
She's a newly appointed English teacher
at Ran"s high school.
A newly appointed English teacher.
Fool. If you tell him things like that...
All right! Let's go to her house.
I knew it.
Do you know where she lives?
Well, we can ask Ran.
If things go well, we might get that
medicine called aho toxin.
It's Apotoxin
I'll bet you think
those guys are no big deal.
You can stay here and not go
If you don't want to, you know.
Heck...
Whoa. What a tall building
Are all English teachers really that rich?
I remember hearing from Ran that
her parents are very rich...
Okay, it's Room 4 on the 21st floor...
That way, eh.
ere. Jodie Saint:Emillio:
All right, Hattori.
You are here only
to gather information-today.
Don't get funny now.
So, what're you gonna say to her?
Why are we here?
What? You haven't thought of anything?
This is your idea, you know
What makes you think
I'dgknow what to say
when this is the first time I'm seeing her.
Oh, come on!
Never mind then, let's head on home.
We don't want her getting suspicious...
Get off it, fool!
We can't turn back after coming this far.
Huh!
Who 11t?
Shoots!
On, it-it's me, Conan.
Conan..Oh, the cool, kid?
What's u., Conan?
I Just came to see you.
OK. OK, wait a minute.
0, ON
Ye Wie
edd - A
All right, all right. I'm not drunk
I can walk on my own,
so let me go, Nakamachi!
Oh, look out, Mr. Kawakami.
I'm sorry
he gave you both a bad time
Chika Shimoda
FE F150 (30)
oes Lo LA.
No problem, Mr. Takai is always lik
that when he's drunk.
Michiya Nakamachi
BIB
{sh BT 81 (28)
Le LWA
=ilH
No problem, Mr. Takai is always lik
that when he's drunk.
Noboru Kawakami
trl Le LA
ii?LFl
I'll bet his true self shows
when he gets drunk.
Noboru Kawakami
fl Lo LA,
x {1 id
You also turn nasty when you're drunk...
Shut up!
What's taking her so long...
How*long do we have to wait?
Hi! Sorry to keep you waiting.
I was taking a bath. Sorry!
Oh, are you cool kid's friend?
Y-yeah
Come on in.
But I don't have anything
to serve you today
Shall-we go out for dinner?
Oh, oh...yes
I'll go get ready then
So, please.wait in the living room.
Um, before that, may I use the bathroom?
Oh, me too.
I've been holding back for a while
OK. The rest room is over there.
Thanks
So, you're also friends with Ms. Mourn.
That's right. Nice to meet you
But I was surprised.
I didn't know that cool kid and Ms: Mouri
had a foreign friend like you.
Foreign friend?
Your skin is quite dark for a Japanese.
And your Japanese is a bit strange.
Foo .
Osaka-Ben(Dialect is
authentically Japanese!
Osaka-Ben?
Is it some kind of Ben-to lunch box?
He-hey, teacher...
It's a dialect of Japanese
You know, there are also dialects
in the U.S. too, right?
Like the Southern drawl.
Oh, yes, yes there are.
Osaka-Ben is
authentically Japanese.
Look. It's the woman we just saw...
» Oh! She's my next door neighbor,
Mr. Takai's girlfriend.
What's she doing, taking photos here?
Huh?
What s that?
It's a cell phone.
Why would it be in a place like this...
It fell from above...
Instant death.
Yeah
But this guy
Where the hell did he fall from?
Perhaps... from the 21st floor.
How do you know?
Actually he's my neighbor, Mr. Takai.
What? You kidding
What? You kidding...
It can't be true?
It's Mr Takai!
So, she's Mr. Takai's girlfriend, right?
Yes.
11...Was Mr. Takai still in his ro
when you left with the two men.
What?... .Oh, yes
I'm sure was drunk and asleep in bed.
But why. Why did hh.) commit suicide?
Why?
How do you know he committed suicide?
Maybe, someone else In the
room pushed him to the ground...
Of course I know!
There was no one
but him back in the room.
1d I locked the front do
when leaving,
and besides that's the only key there is.
Moreover, you can't hear the doorbell
when you're in the bedroom.
There's no other possible explanation
but suicide
No...
It's doesn't necessarily have to be so.
Hey! Look at this!
This is Mr. Takai's cell phone, right,
He talked with someone named
Mr Kawakami just before falling down
And a minute before that,
he seemed-to have read a mail
from a man named Mr. Nakamachi.
Besides,
before Mr. Takai fell,
there was a strange woman
taking photos of this condo in the dark...
Oh, that was
Anyway,
can you tell us more about it later,
after we call Mr. Kawakami who mailed him
and Mr. Nakamachi who called him,
and the police as well?
Um oh, I see.
You were taking pictures of this condo
where your boyfriend, Mr Takai lived, \\\
because you wanted to show
its exterior to your friends, right?
This is the first time I came here,
And I was going to go back to
his room after taking some photos.
And then,
suddenly, a person came
falling to the ground
I didn't think it would be Mr Takai...
ut that's strange...
You left Mr. Takai's room around 5 P.M.
but he fell just after 6 o'clock,
So. were you taking pictures
for a whole hour?
No... »
I started taking pictures
after I drove the two men home,
Because they were both quite drunk.
Excuse me,
what is your connection with her?
We're working for the same company.
We were drinking in the afternoon
at Mr. Takai's room
to celebrate hisgpromotion
from chief to director...
We were going to drink until much later
But Mr. Takai got too drunk.
We had to cut the party short,
because that guy started taunting us,
saying, "If you want a promotion,
all you have to do is get rid of your emotions
and just continue looking up ahead
As long as you can't do so,
you can't move up the ladder
no matter how much you try."
Oh, he said, if you want promotion,
get rid of your emotions?
So, after Ms. Shimoda drove me home,
I sent an email to Mr. Takai,
Please don't forget to
take care of your subordinates too.
Because I remembered the incident
of Ms. Hiraya too
Ms Hiraya?!
Sumiyo Hiraya who committed suicide
Iastimonth!!
She was a co-worker of ours.
Sumiyo H
Suicide?
Yeah.
Ms Hiraya was two years Nakamachr's
senior in junior high school.
And, she and he were also Takai's,
as well as my junior in college.
So, Takai took a big-brotherly interest
in Ms. Hiraya and Nakamachi, but...
Did Ms. Hiraya join the company
In the same year as you, Ms. Shimoda?
Yes...
I see
Then why did she kill herself?
She suffered a nervous breakdown
caused by overwork and committed suicide
Mr Takai once threatened
Ms Hirai over drinks, saying
If you can't fulfill your quota,
you will be fired!
I think she took the joke seriously.
Takai seemed to have forgotten all about it.
So. after Ms. Shimoda
drove me back home by car,
I called and told him,
It's your fault she's dead.
You've earned your promotion
at the expense of her life!!
Even Takai seemed to be in shock
and at a loss for words
After that he suddenly hung up the phone.
I was told to come here,
and this is'what I see
Then why did Mr Takai jump to his death?
Yeah, that's right...
It's almost like I killed him...
But, Inspector...
I didn't tell him, "Drop dead right now!
I just told him the truth
I'm not going to be held
criminally responsible for killing him, right?
That's true .
Can we leave now?
We've already answered
the same questions twice!!
Twice?
We were asked the same questions
before you came here.
By a foreign woman,
a boy speaking Osaka-Ben
and a little kid with glasses.
Huh 2!
Don't tell me those three are...!/?
Do you know where they're now?
Oh, yes!
They took the key to Mr. Takai's room
and went to the 21st floor.
21st floor?!
Hmm...
So it'was you after all!?
Gosh» I'm really glad you held back
from entering the room!!
All right, you can go now, leave this to us.
What do you mean, huh?
Of course,
we-ve already checked the room thoroughly
I've also taken a bunch of pictures
of the room!!
Oh, I see
Had the front door been locked?
Yeah'ilt- was locked up tight!
Well, this room was locked up.
So. it must be suicide II'.
That is what I first thought too.
Until I saw the curtain of
the bed room window
from which Mr.Takai jumped!!
HUN.
It's pretty much definite that
he jumped from this window.
But. isn't it just that the curtain blew outward
because of the wind?
Look closer!!
The curtain was pulled down,
so the curtain rail is bent.
And 2 or 3 hooks seem to have come off.
This is evidence that
he involuntarily grabbed the curtain
when he came close to falling.
Would someone trying to kill himself do that?
If so this 1s not suicide. but
Murder...
This is a homicide case...
Original Comic Books By
GC SHO AOYAMA
Producers
MI@HIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNI@HI 11OKA
Scripts By
KAN]! KASHIWABARAF
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Ammon Dircclors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography.
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OK%DA
Chief Director.
KEN]! KQDAMA
Produced By
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
in 1ssociTtion with
I TELE
CORPORATION
BEitcinvEX ONAN.
CONSHO AOYAMA SHOGARURAN YIV IMS
ME 12894013 Sw ursad
I don't get it...
Me neither
I don't know how the culprit
Iead Mr Takai to jump from the window?
Memo?!
I see.
That was it...
No mistake.
Yeah, the murderer is that guy!