Love is hard to define.
And the reason is suspense.
This case's mystery is being solved.
Will it be Conan, Heiji, or Jodie?
Recognizing that single truth.
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is Detective Conan!
After Hattori suspected Jodie-sensei of being with the Black Organization...
We went to Jodie-sensei's apartment.
But while exiting the apartment building, we encountered a case.
What's it doing here?
It's from above.
From the 21st floor, he fell to his death.
So, the door was locked?
Yeah like they claimed.
Then, no one came in.
It must have been suicide.
Yeah, that's what we thought...
Before we entered Takai-san's bedroom and saw this curtain.
The curtain has separated from the rail.
And a few hooks are missing.
This shows that he fell unsuspectingly and grabbed the curtain.
Would someone committing suicide do that?
T-Then, this wasn't suicide but...
Murder.
It's a case of murder, right?
English Teacher vs. Western Detective, Part 2!
Oh!
And a locked room one!
A locked room murder just like you see in the movies!
But Sensei...
What are you doing here?
I live next door.
Ah, is that true?
Those two came to visit me, and just as we were exiting the building, Takai-san fell from here.
OK yes, that's right.
So, do you know the answer to this locked room murder mystery?
No, not yet.
But I'm pretty sure the strange mark on that window has something to do with it.
Strange mark?
Yeah, it does look like something came in contact with it.
But what was it?
Inspector Megure.
We just finished developing Shimoda-san's pictures.
Ah, that was fast.
Most are just normal pictures of the building.
But we zoomed in on one and discovered something strange.
It's in this picture.
This is...
Takai-san isn't it?
I knew he was hanging by the curtain.
Oh, isn't he throwing something inside?
Isn't that the cell phone?
That means the mark on the glass is from the phone.
But why did he throw it?
Maybe he was angry with the caller?
How could that be?
BE QUIET!
Leave this to the police! Civilians shouldn't be here!
Oh, if that's how it is.
What's got him so angry?
Jeez, someone is always interfering.
But even so, they usually end up solving the case.
But I don't understand...
Yeah. How did the criminal make him fall out of the window?
Shimoda-san was only taking pictures with her camera, so she could have used the flash.
And there was nothing peculiar about Nakamichi-san's mail.
Then we have Kawakami-san that called him.
I don't think someone would jump because they were told to die.
What I'm not sure about is why he tried to throw the phone back into the room.
The only possibility is that there is a clue on it and Takai-san wanted us to see it.
But the cell phone didn't break when it fell.
And there was nothing on the screen.
Hello?
What time is it?
What time... Is it?
What time is it? It's 8:00...
Then what time do you think it is!?
Kazuha...
Who is that?
Well...
Damn, I forgot I had to meet Kazuha today...
What are you doing? You invited me to go to that restaurant Otaki-san mentioned!
S-Sorry... I can't make it...
Wait, Heiji! Where are you
I can't hear you!
Oh no, a bad connection...
Heiji, are you there?
Yeah, well, I don't think I can get there.
Where are you now?
I'm in Tokyo... Tokyo.
Tokyo!?
Yeah, that's right.
I'll meet you as soon as I finish up here.
What do you think you're doing?
You said we would meet in front of Umeda Bigman at 7-00!
Umeda Bigman is a large television screen at the Umeda Station located in the north center of Osaka.
That's what I have in this memo!
Memo?
I see.
That's how it is.
There's no doubt.
Yeah, it's that person.
What? An experiment?
You want to do one now?
Yeah that's right.
If we reenact what those three did before Takai-san fell.
We may finally understand this locked room murder.
But wait...
Shimoda-san was only taking pictures.
Nakamichi-san only sent a mail...
And Kawakami-san only called Takai-san.
That means this wasn't a murder...
Well, let's check.
But we Ye missing something important for this experiment.
Something important?
What is it?
Alcohol!
Takai-san was drunk before he went to sleep, right?
That's true, but who is going to play the victim?
That's just it, officers can't drink while on duty...
What's this about?
And I'm underage.
So the only one left...
Me?
Right Sensei!
Would you mind doing it?
OK!
I'll do it.
But can you get the alcohol I love?
Ah, sure. What is it?
Ok good.
Very, very delicious!
[s that right?
Yes, it's very tasty.
Alright Inspector, can you give us a second to get ready?
Umm...
What is it, Nakamichi-san?
Didn't you cal! us up here to the scene?
And why is that foreign woman lying on Takai-sans bed drunk?
Please tell us!
No, it's just.
We re having an experiment to reenact what happened.
Did you get everything ready?
Yeah.
Jodie-sensei is asleep on the bed and I've put my cell phone by her pillow.
But we made a little change without her knowing.
What did you change?
Now, now, it's a surprise.
Let's begin the experiment.
First, Nakamichi-san sent a mail to Takai-san's phone, right?
Yeah...
Alright, so I'll send a mail.
Oh!
It's a mail?
Hey Sensei, did you get that mail?
Oh yes, it's a lovely mail.
Is that right?
Hey, Hattori...
What kind of mail was it?
It's nothing to worry about.
The next thing was Shimoda-san taking pictures of the building outside.
Alright Chiba-kun, go ahead.
Yes.
But, will all of this really reveal the trick behind the locked room murder?
That's something we'll know when it's over, right?
The last step is Kawakami-san's call.
It's useless.
Hello?
Ah, Sensei?
Let's just talk.
OK... what about?
Let's see, how about...
How about that mail I sent you?
OK.
But let me ask you something.
Who are you?
Tell me that first.
You're not a mere boy, are you?
Yes, yes. I'm just a normal high-school student.
Really?
It's hard to hear you, is something wrong?
Oh! This is apartment is so high up.
This often happens when I use my phone up here.
Hold on a second.
I'll go outside, you can hear me better from the balcony.
What!?
Help!
Help me!
Please!
What's wrong?
Help!
Jodie-sensei!
Are you alright?
Oh, thank you. Officer,
You mean...
That's right, we moved the bed.
I thought Jodie-sensei would go out onto the balcony to better the connection.
Sensei tried to get out onto the balcony from the bed
Anyone that had been drinking would go straight from the bed to the opposite window.
Just like how Jodie-sensei would have fallen like Takai-san if I hadn't told her about it.
Right the one who talked to Takai-san up to his final moment...
Kawakami Noboru-san?
Before, he moved Takai-san's bed from its original position, beside of this window.
To the opposite window that lacks a balcony.
I... I see.
While Takai-san was on the phone.
He left his bed and climbed out, falling to his death.
Yeah, that's right.
He probably moved the bed while Takai-san was drinking with the others.
After Kawakami-san likely claimed he was going to the restroom.
He snuck into Takai-sans room to move the bed.
And then, as Takai-san came in and passed out on the bed.
He placed his cell phone beside of his pillow to complete his plan.
Then all you would have to do is call and claim you couldn't hear.
It can't he!
No way...
What if Jodie-sensei had fallen during this experiment?
It's alright.
Because look...
At this.
We tied a rope to Sensei's waist without her knowing.
Oh, this is very clever.
Then I guess...
You should explain how you killed him to the police.
Ah if I did anything...
It wasn't murder.
What?
It's true that I moved the bed.
But he wanted me to change it around for him.
But I'm still surprised, that this is why he died.
I didn't even notice it until you mentioned it.
Goodbye, Takai.
What!?
You can apologize to Hiraya-kun from hell.
I was surprised...
That you left a message like this.
Kawakami-san...
You didn't notice it, then?
Takai-san held onto that curtain for awhile.
He pressed the memory button and recorded it.
The proof that you killed him...
Are the words you shared with him...
To avenge the death of your friend.
Here you are, your camera from earlier.
Yes.
I must thank you, for pretending you were tricked earlier.
Oh, it was nothing.
It was very exciting.
That's right...
I haven't got your name yet, have [?
Wouldn't it be more interesting to talk about your true identity?
What I want to know...
Why do you pretend you can't speak good English when you're actually great at it?
What do you mean?
You can't hide it.
When I asked you...
"You're not a mere boy, are you?" You said...
"Yes, I'm only a normal high school student."
You said "yes", because "yeah" means "no" in Japanese.
"Yes" is how a foreigner would reply, but you replied with a proper English "yes" because I'm foreign.
You probably answered in such a proper way...
Because you knew English is my first language.
I am an English teacher, you can't fool me.
Well actually, I wasn't pretending not to be able to speak English, but uh...
Did silence work better than your funnily disguised Japanese?
Your Japanese is perfect, yet it has an odd intonation.
It's obvious that you're disguising your Japanese to deter people.
Well, hopefully we can talk about it later.
Goodbye.
But if he already knew that much, why did he set up this experiment and get her drunk?
That's true...
You were right about her.
That teacher.
She took our pictures, and pretended about the bath...
Yeah.
Her hair and body were wet yet the hair dryer on the floor was warm...
The body lotion hadn't dried yet either.
She was probably taking a bath as we arrived.
But took a shower to buy some time.
Perhaps, but I wonder why she was...
Watching us during the entire case...
Hey, there's nothing to worry about.
I removed the film.
I'm sure Sensei's suspicious, but she doesn't seem bad.
And, her face was nothing like that American actress Chris Vineyard.
But they both do have big breasts.
Yeah, that's true...
If indeed...
That's really her appearance.
What do you mean?
That's right shouldn't you be gone?
Isn't she waiting for you?
Ah! I forgot about...
All about meeting Kazuha!
A-A-Anyway, be careful Kudo.
They're smart enough to steal from the police, right?
Right.
Gotta run.
If any other strange people appear, let me know!
You can always call me!
No...
Jodie-sensei isn't the only one.
There are others...
Two others.
Hattori Heiji...
An interesting boy.
The son of the Osaka Police Chief, Hattori Heizo.
And...
Like Kudo Shinichi...
Private Eye.