Suspense and deduction closes the gap between
the love and hatred between two people.
Watching soccer evokes different memories
they all coalesce to solve a mystery
He sees through the one and only truth
a child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult
no case is left unsolved with Detective Conan.
We, the Detective Boys, went with Dr. Agasa
to watch a soccer game for the first time in ages.
The match was won by our team, the Tōkyō Spirits,
who defeated Noir Tōkyō, winning the Tōkyō Derby.
The train on the way back was packed with supporters for both teams.
But when the passengers left,
a man's body was found, having been murdered.
Sir!
Don't move this train!
A man's been stabbed!
What!?
Also, please call the ticket control barriers connected to this platform,
and ask them to check all the tickets from Tokyo Spirits and Noir Tokyo supporters trying to leave!
Stop anyone who has a ticket bought before 5 PM from leaving.
But why?
Just do it! If you don't, the killer might get away!
The victim was a fanatic supporter of Noir Tōkyō,
a proud hooligan who often appeared in the news and TV due to the crimes he committed:
Kadotake Akano-san.
There were three suspects: Hasue Kira-san,
Mitsuaki Funato-san,
and Etsutoshi Ōba-san.
The only thing we know for sure is that they all rode in a packed train car.
But that's not enough to conclude anything.
There's gotta be something... There's gotta be something more!
Some other clue to solve the case!
Though...
How come that person...
That...
Oh?
Hey, where's Haibara-san?
She said she was going to the toilet.
Anyway, how's the match going?
You were following it through the radio, right?
Well...
In the congestion when getting off the train, I think I dropped the radio.
And I can't find it on the train, nor on the platform.
Man, you're such a klutz.
I'm sure someone must've found it.
We're still 0-0, and the match is now entering injury time.
Oh! Ramus made a splendid pass to the center.
Higo got the ball, and the defenders can't keep up with him!
It's a decisive moment!
Higo goes straight for the goal!
Now one-on-one in front of the goal, Higo shoots!
Ahh, he hit the goal post!
Have even the heavens themselves abandoned Higo?
Even so, there's an enormous booing...
Doesn't Higo-san remind you of someone?
Noir is French for black.
A traitor who abandoned black.
What are you on about?
Though, Haibara...
Higo-san had a reason to leave his team, just like you.
Higo-san has an older brother from a different mother.
His name's Rikuo Endō.
He was a substitute defender in the J-League for Noir until last year.
Of course, this isn't widely known information,
since they have different last names, and they've kept it a secret.
I found out about it two years ago,
when I was in a match during my third year of middle school.
Higo-san and his brother, who'd just signed up for Noir, had come to see the match.
Higo-san said something to me that day...
"Would you like to join Noir Tokyo too, and reach the top with us brothers?"
However, this year, Noir Tokyo told Endō-san he wasn't allowed to play.
In other words, the reason they let Endō-san, who didn't even stand out in J-2 into the team...
...was merely as bait to lure Higo-san.
Upon learning of this, Higo-san...
signed up for Big Ōsaka, who'd hired the retired Endō-san as a coach,
in order to fulfill their dream of winning the J-1 together.
Higo was knocked down!
This should be a yellow card...
But the referee doesn't show a card!
And even though their forward just suffered a foul...
Listen to the audience's cheering.
Has Higo been forsaken by all who supported him?
Is there no field in Japan where Higo can play?
Hold on...
If I recall correctly, today's Tōkyō Derby was...
As I thought...
The killer is the one who lied!
Furthermore, if my reasoning is correct, the killer...
...should still have the evidence!
Inspector Megure!
The train car where the crime took place has been moved to the garage...
And we're almost done inspecting the entrances and exits of the platform.
Then we've done all we can at this station.
All that's left...
...is to invite you three suspects over,
so we can record your stories.
Hold on! That's voluntary, right?
Hasue Kira (24)
Noir Tōkyō Supporter
Mitsuaki Funato (33)
Tōkyō Spirits Supporter
Gimme a break! I've got to get back to work quickly!
Etsutoshi Ōba (29)
Noir Tōkyō Supporter
Look, couldn't we do this some other day?
No.
If we wait too long, the definitive evidence will disappear.
Or do you have a concrete reason why you need to leave the murder scene as soon as possible?
Hey, Shin'ichi...
What was that, old man?
Don't talk like you're a detective!
Could it be that you figured out who the killer is?
Uh...
Of course. It became clear when I heard the three's stories.
The killer is the lying fake supporter!
Lying?
Fake supporter?
Of course!
It's this guy, right?
What?
Yeah, I remember you saying that you missed seeing the two wingers score the winning goal.
What about it?
The Hide-Naoki combo scored the winning goal.
They're forwards who move freely through the field.
They're not wingers, whose main job is to stay in the lines and recover the ball.
Is this true?
Yeah.
Furthermore, wingers are part of an old game tactic.
It's not really used in soccer nowadays.
Oh, well, I've only been a soccer fan for a short time.
And I thought I remembered someone saying Hide and Naoki were really good wingers...
Stop playing dumb!
You're the killer, right?
What do you mean?
It's just an honest mistake!
Right.
Referring to them as "wingers" is a mistake, but not a lie.
Then who...
I'm talking about the person who didn't watch the game,
but who acted otherwise.
Well, I'm not surprised.
Today's match was the Tokyo Derby, between the two greatest teams in Tokyo.
The stadium was packed.
If the killer had watched the game along with Akano-san, who was at the stands,
he would surely have lost sight of him among the crowd after the match.
Then where did the killer wait for him?
Probably inside the stadium's toilet.
He listened to the match on the radio, and as soon as the match was over,
he probably hurried over to the exit, and waited there for Akano-san.
But who's this lying killer?
May I ask them some questions, to verify if they really did watch the game or not?
I watched the whole thing.
I saw Naoki's shot from the front stand.
I was so annoyed with his shot that I ended up arguing with a nearby Spirits supporter.
I saw it too, from Noir's supporters' stand behind the goal.
Hide dribbled past all the defenders, and in front of the goal, he passed the ball to Naoki.
I was watching it from the Spirits' stand behind the opposite goal, but...
I got that call from work, so I wasn't able to see the goal.
But you did know that it was Hide and Naoki who scored the goal.
Obviously!
After the goal, the supporters around me cheered "Hide and Naoki are the greatest!"
If you think I'm lying, have a look at my ticket stub, here!
I've got mine too.
I've got mine too, see.
Either way...
For people who didn't watch the match, my explanation might be hard to understand...
So I'm going to ask these kids who watched the match.
Where were our seats?
The front stand.
It's right in the middle, so we could clearly see Hide dribble past four players.
Though we didn't see this lady in the front stand.
Maybe my seat was away from yours.
Whoa, wait. You can't think I'm a liar over just this!
Ah, no. It's not like that...
Then from what side and which way did Hide cross while dribbling past the four players?
From right to left!
Then from your point of view, the Noir goal was to your left, right?
Yeah, what about it?
I didn't remember until I saw my own ticket, but...
Today's Tokyo Derby took place in the Spirits' stadium, right?
Usually, in the J-League,
if you look from the front stand, the home team's supporters sit behind the left goal,
Front stand
Away
Home
whereas the away team's supporters sit behind the right goal.
Meaning that in today's match, the Tokyo Spirits' seats were on the left,
whereas Noir Tokyo's were on the right.
Now you see what I mean, right?
The strange contradiction that the lying killer doesn't understand.
Strange contradiction?
Can you explain it a bit more clearly?
Of course.
Like I was saying earlier...
If you look from the front stand...
The Tokyo Spirits were to the left.
Noir Tokyo
Tokyo Spirits
Front stand
And the Noir Tokyo supporters were to the right.
Hide dribbled the ball from right to left,
and Naoki, who received Hide's pass,
scored in the left-side goal.
Right in front of the Spirits' supporters.
In other words...
There's no way you would have said that Hide dribbled past the defenders and "approached"...
...if you were sitting in Noir Tokyo's seats on the right side, Ōba-san.
Most likely, you interpreted what you heard over the radio.
"Hide's approaching the goal!"
That's just wordplay!
Like him, I just made a mistake. I'm not lying...
I meant that Hide was approaching the opposite goal!
I just said it wrong because I was nervous!
If you want, you can check the seat on my ticket!
You'll see I was sitting in Noir's seats.
No, you weren't there.
Rather...
It's completely impossible!
Not if you were dressed like that!
Hey, hold on. That's...
Higo's shirt, the one who betrayed Noir!
If you'd gone to Noir's seats dressed like that, you'd have gotten lynched!
That said, Agasa-san,
this is all circumstancial evidence.
We need definitive evidence.
He should still have the evidence in his arm.
You mean the watch mark in his right arm?
All that proves is that he had his arms crossed in that crowded train.
I mean his other arm.
His other arm?
Think about it.
If he pulled a knife out of his bag in a packed train,
he would've looked suspicious.
Therefore, Ōba-san had his arms crossed while holding the knife,
therefore ensuring nobody could see it,
as well as allowing him to pull the knife out at any time.
Of course, he had a glove in the hand holding the knife.
Right. And if my reasoning is correct, there should still be something on his left arm.
After holding it for so long, the rare design on the knife's scabbard must've left a mark!
Indeed.
Then... it was you?
For my brother's sake...
I studied soccer, became a supporter,
and came up with this plan.
Who'd have known he was the one causing me to fail?
Your brother?
My twin brother.
A year ago, Akano killed him.
Killed?
On that day, a year ago...
My brother came home from watching a Noir Tokyo match...
covered in injuries.
He said he'd fallen down the stairs in the stadium.
But that night, he suddenly fell to the ground holding his head,
and lost consciousness.
He died three days later.
His death was caused by a brain hemorrhage from a crack to his skull.
I found out what really happened when I went to the Tokyo Hooligan site that my brother used to visit,
Akano's homepage.
I understood everything after I read his comments for the day.
Today, after the match, I beat the crap out of a moron who criticized my homepage,
and threw him down the stairs.
That's what he wrote.
But how did you know that was your brother?
Oh, I knew.
When I met Akano to be sure of what happened,
he saw at my face and said, grinning...
"So you're still alive?"
That's why I decided to avenge my brother,
with his most prized possessions.
Then that uniform...
Yeah. My brother always wore it to Noir games...
Higo's uniform.
I never imagined I would get caught over it.
Though, maybe this uniform was...
a warning from my brother in the afterlife.
Because if a Noir supporter had seen this uniform and commented about it...
Maybe it would've brought me to my senses from the thirst for revenge in my heart.
"What do you think you're doing?"
By the way, Haibara's taking a long time...
You're right...
Eh? Haibara's not back yet?
No...
Ah! There she is!
Look! On the other platform!
You're right...
What's she doing there?
The train to Beika's on this platform...
Don't tell me she's...
After all, there's no place for traitors.
It's his chance to forget everything and escape to a place where the booing won't reach.
No...
Haibara...
Haibara!
Damn it...
What's all the yelling for?
You thought I was going to run or something?
No...
Here you go, young lady. Try not to drop it again.
Yes.
A radio?
I was looking for the radio that Tsuburaya-kun dropped.
When I asked a worker, he told me one of the cleaners might've picked it up.
Oh...
You said it, didn't you?
"Don't run away. Don't run away from fate."
You'll protect me, right?
Yeah...
Well, I'm not some weak girl who needs to be protected all the time like you seem to think.
Oh, Haibara.
Higo-san did manage to score the winning goal in the end.
The stadium went wild calling for Higo.
Though I pretty much knew it already, but that booing was the motivation he needed to give it his all.
Why are you telling me all of that nonsense?
I'm not some soccer nut like you.
Man, she's stubborn...