This is where someone named Suzuki was killed.
The killer is...
The killer is Kurata and the victim is Suzuki.
You heard them address one another that way, right?
That's it exactly!
In addition, we know the culprit's truck's plate number.
It was Shinjuku 10-15 if I recall.
It's true this number was registered to a "Kurata Transportation Company".
Kurata Transportation...
The address indicates it's nearby.
Let's check it out
Yeah.
Apologies for the intrusion.
What is it about?
Uncle!
I know!
My name is Mouri Kogorou from the Mouri Detective Agency.
By Mouri Kogorou, you mean you're...
Amazing!
I'm a big fan of Sleeping Kogorou!
My, thank you very much.
I'll do whatever you need me to do.
The truth is, these kids claim they witnessed a crime scene last night...
So I have some questions for you regarding...
That's him!
Take this!
That man is the culprit, Conan!
Hey, you guys!
Miss, would that person be the company president, Kurata-san?
Yes, that's him.
Where is he now!?
Bring him here immediately!
We have things to ask him!
Hey, all of you!
Hold on, hold on!
All of you, stay calm!
President Kurata always comes to work after noon.
After noon?
He may be escaping as we speak!
I told you to calm down!
Is there someone called Suzuki working in this company?
Do you mean Director Suzuki?
If you mean Director Suzuki, look there.
There, in the picture we took during our company trip.
The man you're looking for is in the bottom-left corner, with a cigarette.
And...
Where is Suzuki-san now?
He went missing.
Kaori-san, what do you mean by that?
Oh, didn't I tell you?
I just received a call from the director's wife.
She said he never came home last night.
I wonder what happened...
Director Suzuki is usually so punctual...
Maybe he's just tired?
He also had a fight with the president recently.
Aren't President Kurata and Director Suzuki on good terms?
No way!
Although they built this company together twenty years ago, they're like cats and dogs now.
Rumor has it Director Suzuki wants to leave and build his own company.
Hey, Kaori-san!
It's all right—everyone knows about it.
Shinjuku number...
10-15..
There's no mistake!
There was some blood, right, Conan?
That's the definitive evidence!
I saw the bloodstain last night too.
This definitely proves the victim was inside this truck!
No.
That was paint.
Paint!?
No way!
You mistook it for blood because it was so dark.
But...
As I thought.
It was only your misunderstanding.
It was probably something that looked like a human, such as a mannequin.
It's because you like to play boring make-believe detectives that you were under such a delusion!
It wasn't a delusion!
It was the truth!
President Kurata really buried Suzuki-san in the mountains!
Then, did you actually see him burying the body?
The truth is that you didn't see anything, am I wrong?
My, my...
You made me get up early for nothing.
Forgive me for troubling you even when you're busy.
Don't mention it
All right, then.
I'm heading home to get some sleep.
Please return home as well.
Conan-kun...
You do believe us, don't you, Conan-kun?
Regardless...
We have to locate where the body was supposedly buried.
If we can find the victim, everything will be proven.
At 7:10 PM...
The truck containing the victim departed from this building.
It took about three hours total to make the trip and return.
In other words..
It would take around 90 minutes one-way to the mountains or forest area where Director Suzuki was supposedly buried.
Taking into account the mountainous forests 90 minutes from here...
He could have taken any of these three routes.
Do you know which direction he took?
Actually...
Unfortunately, we aren't sure.
Then, what were you able to see?
We couldn't recognize any of the areas, so I don't know.
I saw a "White Duck"!
White Duck is a big convenience store chain.
There are a lot of them in the city.
That's right!
There was the smell of eel rice on the way!
We'll find out for sure, I guarantee it!
Don't you have more reliable clues?
I counted the number of gasoline stands!
First, there was a Heart Gas on the right...
Then an MM Gas..
And another Heart Gas after that.
Those were all I could see.
Heart Gas, MM Gas, and another Heart Gas...
It could be this road.
That's right!
I saw Kamen Yaiba too!
Kamen Yaiba?
It was on a TV at an appliance store.
It was about to get to the best part when Yaiba uses his Miracle Kick...
But the truck started to move again.
You mean, the truck stopped at that time?
Yeah..
The stop may have been at a red light.
We were stopped for quite a while.
That's right, and...
Not long after the truck started to move again, we heard the sound of a train above us!
A train above you?
An overhead train!
That means the truck..
Went under the overhead train pass around 7:50 PM...
How do you know it was 7:50?
Because Kamen Yaiba's special move is always shown around 7:50.
You're right!
7:50...
That's forty minutes after the truck left this place.
At that time, the only place he could've passed under the overhead train and stopped at a traffic light is here.
And if we extend a line from that point to the mountain forests 90 minutes away...
It has to be here.
This place is scary...
Tire marks.
They're still fresh.
This way
The truck must've stopped here.
Look!
The ground under these leaves was recently unearthed.
There's no mistake.
Let's dig!
Seriously?
It's here!
As expected...
What is this!?
Conan-kun...
What's going on?
It amounts simply to this:
After President Kurata and Director Suzuki's scuffle at the scene...
Their roles were suddenly reversed...
The roles of killer and victim.
President Kurata became the victim.
Conversely, the killer is...
Right behind us:
Director Suzuki!
Did I get it wrong?
Director Suzuki.
I put it together after seeing the ashtray in the truck.
The pile of cigarette butts shared the same trait
The cigarettes were crushed at the tip and bent at an angle.
It's exactly like your cigarette butts shown on the picture of your company trip.
The brand was also the same.
After seeing that...
I was convinced the culprit who drove the truck for three hours yesterday wasn't President Kurata...
But was actually you.
I didn't intend to kill him!
This...
This was legitimate self-defense!
That will be decided by the courts.
Not us.
You... brat...
You're wrong again.
I'm no brat
I'm Edogawa Conan...
A detective.
And we are...
The Detective Boys!
He's the one to blame!
I'm not at fault!
Damn it!
Oh, that's right.
I forgot to mention it, but...
I took the liberty of calling the police.
Damn you!
Don't struggle!
Stay still!
You won't get away!
Why you...
Huh?
What happened to him?
He fell to the ground on his own and passed out.
Which means...
We did it!
The Detective Boys win big again!
Conan-kun...
Let's play!
Why don't we play make-believe detectives again?
Let's find our next case!
But this time, Conan-kun has to participate in the game too!
Hey, hey...
They never learn...