Suspense and deduction
closes the gap between
In a beautiful garden a mysterious
case occurs
He sees through the one and only truth
a child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
nojcase is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Thank you for the treat
Gee... This is such a great
garden that's true to your title
as the president of
the Kiyama Furniture Company
What a nice house you have!
This is the first time I've seen
a garden with a waterfall like this!
This garden somehow
makes me feel at peace
Glad to hear that...
You like my garden.
I'm glad I brought you up here too.
Michiyoshi Majima
you like my garden.
I'm glad I brought you up here too.
Michiyoshi Majima
DI DI all.»
O v9 fr C Let)
XLRI MR
you like my garden.
I'm glad I brought you up here too.
Le & &UL
w PF fr CC LoTOoD
KIRA T=
you like my garden.
I'm glad I brought you up here too.
I think it's about time to begin
Eh? To begin what?
You'll see.
Oh, Conan, look over there!
Water is flowing over
the basin of the waterfall!
Clio, Tl
The water is filling the garden!
What's that!
Hahaha Surprised. eh?
Let me explain how this works.
At 8am... 4 p.m. and 8 p.m. three times
a day, the water flows into the garden
But in doing so,
won't the sand pattern disappear?
Water is poured in slowly
so that the pattern is not lost,
then the water is drained in 30 minutes.
It's quite highly reputed.
The former president made this device.
Well, if you'll excuse me for a moment,
I'd like to get back to work
But make yourselves at home.
See you at dinner.
And don't worry about your car.
I'll get my secretary to pick it up tomorrow.
Thank so much for everything.
I'm sure you'd have done the same for me
if I were in your shoes.
OK then. I'll leave them to you, Ayaka.
Very well, President...
Boy oh boy, what ajtruly superb view!
It's really awesome...
Heck! What carefree jokers they are!
Don't they realize how costly
it is to maintain it!
The garden Kiyama made is
really nothing but a big nuisance for me!
Look, Conan!
Oh, my, we can see clearly through
the circles of white sand!
It's beautiful, Ran!
I'll bet it's especially romanticsat night
when the moon is reflected on the water
Yes, indeed.
We even have guests
who come here every full moon.
Wonderful to drink cold sake while viewing
a full moon rising from behind Mt. Fuji
Phew!
It's out of this world...
Hey, what's that?
Over there. Something's by the pillar...
Oh, that! It's a catching pole.
Catching pole?
You see, when someone drops
something on the white sand of the yard,
we lengthen this pole
and pick it up like this.
We can't step on the wave pattern
of the white sand, you see.
I see. It's well thought out.
Well,
since Mr. Majima became president, the -
gardener comes only once a month. So...
Pretty mind racking, isn't it...
Oh, the water's begun to drain.
Yeah, really.
Oh, It's amazing how well this works...
VA. AA.
HA AA
Mystery of the Japanese Water
Flowing Rock Garden Part
If you like, shall we go to the saloon
where aperitif will be served
Oh yeah, here we go!
You don't have money!?
Give me a break!
You still owe me 5 million yen,
no, 7 million yet including interest!!
Mr. Majima?
Pay back the money in full
by the end of this month!
Otherwise, you'll be fired!
You better dig in!
Pease wait! President...
Nd THIS WEST SWYIS
house 1s marvelous too!
Yes. It's truly splendid...
Please come on in...
Oh, well well...
Please come this way.
Oh, thank you, thank you
It's the man we saw just a while ago.
Yeah...
Can I get you something to drink, sir?
Sure, I'll take a beer!
I'll be right back
Hey, Dad!
It-s too early to be drinking yet!
Why not?
Ayaka!
Who're these people!?
They are Mr. Majima's guests.
His guests?
I don't know if we can be called guest,
because you see, we
actually ran out of gas on Sanbonzaka
Then, President Majima, who
happened to pass by, looked in on us.
Moreover, he kindly invited us
for dinner this evening.
The president is a nice
friendly person, isn't he?
Heck! He always puts
on a friendly face in public!
Can I ask you something.
Feo Theory coro yor aed To
PB OMAY Du wie TTL WY
be a private gathering
VOy Coat ner troy ss bes Whe Oy yeti (vy
Sa. SA tata LA
of Kiyama Furniture's first store?
All is well, Mr. Endo.
Mr. Majima invited them...
And besides.
The more the merrier for dinner, right?
I guess so, but...
If you will excuse me.
Well, I'd like to introduce everyone
This is the secretary to the president
Mr. Masayuki Hashimoto
Masayuki Hashimoto
+ BZ (37)
MasayukigHashimoto
ME BZ (37)
mBR Be
Nice to meet you...
Masayuki Hashimoto
££ & - JE
MA = (37)
Nice to meet you .
And this is the president of
the Kiyama Interior Company,
one of our affiliated
companies, Mr. Endo
Mr. Endo has taken part in the
National Sports Festival as an archer.
That's something!
But it was long time ago.
Now, it's a different story...
NobuakiEndo
But it was long time.ago.
Now, it's a different story...
NobuakiEndo
5 DU IQ
BR 5 (BAA (45)
Tr STE
And I'm Tomonori Kiyama,
a freelance writer.
Tomonori Kiyama
KL 8 AY (28)
DI-- SS
Are you Mr. Kiyama, the author of
Wandering Through Africa?
Yes, I am.
Wow! I thought so!
Do you know him?
Yeah! He is a travelogue writer
who travels to many countries.
I've read your
Wandering Through Africa!
Oh, thank you
How did you like it?
Oh...I was deeply moved!
Could I have your autograph,please?
Sure, my pleasure!
I tell you what
I'll be holding a photo exhibition
So if it's okay with you, please come.
Wow! Thank you, are you sure it's okay...
Thank you so much.
I'll sign my autograph now...
What an old fashioned fountain pen
you have!
This is the only thing
I have to remember my father by.
Although it's no great fountain pen
I just couldn't bear getting rid of it
So, I always keep it on me
I see .
OK, here you are
Thank you very much!
Please come with your friends.
Yes, I definitely will!
However, I didn't know you were related
to the family of Kiyama Furniture
My father built the company
from nothing into
a considerable business In
the course of his lifetime.
After his death, Mr. Majima
succeeded my father as president...
Oh, have you already
seen the Rock Garden?
Yes, we have! Patterns on the
white sand were so beautiful!
Exactly! That waterfall and white sand!
The garden you saw
was what my father kept working on to
complete, whenever he had time
to spare from his busy schedule,
putting his heart and soul into it.
Hey. how did you father die?
C-Conan! H.How rude!
No. It's okay.
He died in a traffic accident last year...
You never know what
destiny lies ahead...
Uh... There's a scenic site
with fantastic night view
So, I suggest you go there later.
Huh
It's very beautiful.
All of you really must see it
Shall we go up there, Conan!
Yeah!
I think I'll pass
I'd rather stay here and
enjoy a leisurely drink...
Come off it, Dad...
You must see it, too!
It-s'well worth looking at!
Unlike To \ 0::the stars seem so close
hat it looks like their
going to shower down on you!
Hmm... Stars...
Thank you for waiting.
Here comes the beer!
Wow! Thank you very much
If you like, we have
drinks other than beer too.
I'll bring you another cup
Thanks! Now, I can
drink my heart out .
Which one should I drink...
Hey! Stop it, Dad...
Ah... Oh. Hey. hey! Cut it out!
- Donrt spill it!!
What a waste!
Oh man, talk about addicted to liquor.
Here, havclanother one.
Oh. thank you.
Well, well, I've had enough.
Excuse me...
Mr. Majima!
Sorry I haven't been around
you to see you lately.
I came to tell you that I'm going
to holding an exhibition.
If you like, please come by
and look at my photos.
A photo exhibition...
Well, Tomonori, you seem to
really be working at it.
OK, I'll drop by.
President!
This is last month's sales report.
I hope-that the figures are accurate
at least, since this is your last time.
Now then .
Wait!
Dinner is ready, Sir.
Will you all please come
this way to the banquet hall.
Finally! Dinner party!
Well: yd like to propose a toast
for Kiyama Furniture's future prosperity!
Cheers!
This is the best meat I've ever tasted!
Yeah. .it.s-so-tender.
Care for a drink?
Oh, well, thank you.
Hahaha...You really do
Iike that, don You?
I really appreciate having the
opportunity to meet new friends like you.
So, if you like it, I'll sell it cheap to you.
Really!
Dad!
Hyahahah. You've go to be
joking...Hahaha...
H Hey. listen, Dad!
Huh
Hm...Come on!
So, please talk this over with your father
before you decide whether you
want to buy it or not.
If you'll excuse me, I'veggot to get going
since I still have work: left to do...
I guess I'll be going too...
OK, listen, I have a video
that I want to watch,
so I hope you don't mind going to see
the night view after I'm done.
Sure, no problem.
Well, I'll come and pick you up
around eleven fifteen.
So, please wait in your room.
Yes. I got it.
Wonder what kind of video it is?
It's a documentary film that he
wanted to watch about an adventurer
named Hiroyuki Sekiguchi.
I happened to find the
video so I brought it with
me to show it to him
Hmm, I see
Phooey! Documentary film about a
n adventurer, my foot!
Neeser FOR
watching videos like that
that's why the company's
taken over by Majima.
What a thing to say, Mr. Hashimote!
Mr. Majima is not that kind of person.
Oh. and what's come
over you, Mr. Endo.
How strange for you to be
taking sides with Majima
Making remarks like that
won't help at this point already.
I hear you'll be discharged next month
due to the firm's poor performance,
which you're held responsible for.
But, the debts of Kiyama Interior are. "I
essentially the debts of Kiyama Furniture
The fact is that the parent company
passed the buck to your company, right?
I also hear that you are just
taking out your misery on others,
shouting furiously
Why should I be fired for that...
So. everyone's worried saying, It comes
as no surprise if he killed Majima *
Hey, Mr. Hashimoto! You're really
starting to get on my nerves!
So, please excuse me too because
I have some work to do at my office.
By the way, you had better forget about
what you mentioned a little while ago...
What I mentioned a little while ago?
You mentioned the desk. Listen. At first
he approaches you looking very friendly
But once he gets you,
you can't get rid of him.
That's his way so don't get involved
with him! He's bad news!
Mr. Hashimoto!
Dad, let's go back to our room too.
Come on It wouldn't
hurt to drink a little more.
You know, our life could come to an
end tomorrow. So, drink when you can.
Now you re talking.
Hey, Dad!
Oh, it's this late already...
Mr. Mouri, I think we
have to call it a night
Dad, wake up.
Eh? What?
Let's get back to our room.
H-hey, wait! There's still a bottle of beer
to drink! Drink, drink while you can!
Is Mr. Mouri all right?
I'm really sorry for all the fuss...
I can still drink!
Here you are. This is
medicine for hangover.
Thank you.
I'll be here if you need any assistance,
so please let me know if there is
anything else I can do for you.
Okay.
Good night.
Phew..This will be fine.
I'm sorry for you father
I feel bad that I pushed
him to drink more.
Don't worry. This happens all the time.
Sorry for the trouble. Thank you too.
Good night.
Yeah, good night...
Ah, yes
I'll open the door now.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
No, not at all
Did you enjoy the video?
Yes very much. It was a superb
documentary with great power.
We're just taking a run
up to Mt. Prospect.
Don't be long.
Wow. It's so beautiful... like a dream!
Pop should have come here too!
Yeah.
I recall the days...when I was a child,
when my father and I used to come here
My father also liked this night view...
We're back now!
Welcome back!
How was the night scene?
It was so beautiful that
I was impressed. Right, Conan?
Yeah.
That's great.
So, Ayaka, good night!
Good night!
Good night
A picturerg
Thank you veryamuch!
I'm glad that you enjoyed it.
So, see you tomorrow...
Good night!
Aughhaaa
This voice!
Huh? Wh-what is it?
Ayaka! What's wrong?
Th-that!
What happened? Ah!
Ma...President Majima!
What? What was that scream about?
Mr. Majima!
Ran! Call the police HOW! *
Yes!
What's the trouble?
P...President!
You!. .Keep Out! This is a homicide!
Don't enter the garden! We've
got to preserve the crime scene!
What's with you. pushing.yourweight
around and giving out orders...
I'm Kogero Mouri, a private detective!
You're." Kogoro Mourn.
That:renowned detective!
You cot wt!
Don't you think that there's something
strange about the President's corpse?
Huh? Strange? What s strange?
Around the body...
there are no footsteps at all!
What?
Really...
So, how did the murderer
carry Mr. Majima up there?
Original Comic Books By.
GOSH A@YAMA
: Producers
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDGO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI I11OKA
Scripts By
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUGHI *
[UNICHI MW) mm
» ad '» »
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animition Directors.
MASATOMO SUD
HARUO QOOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYOD
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography.
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KEN]! KODAMA
Produced By
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
in association with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
I> 11 (010 Le IN ANT
GOSTIO VOY AMT SHOGARUR ANY TV TMS
Al Rights Resyrved
What? sscrape. it looks
Iike something was dragged
Strange...
If Pop is right. how can the dead
body be lying in that way?
But, if he is wrong
Why is this here?
Aha . I've got it...