What's that?
It looks like something was dragged there.
Mouri-san.
Isn't that you, Mouri-san?
Oh, Detective Yokomizo.
It's been a while.
But somehow, we keep meeting at places like this.
A famous detective makes his appearance at complex cases.
Must be pre-destined.
In any case, I'll be counting on you again then.
Detective Yokomizo.
The post mortum report.
The death was instant, caused by a snapped neck.
Time of death was approximately between 8:00 PM and 1:00 AM last night.
The corpse was moved immediately after the murder.
Taking into account that only his body that touched the ground is wet...
With him being moved here, and the water being drained from the rock garden at around 9:00 PM...
That means the time of the crime was between 9:00 PM and 1:00 AM.
I see.
Just as I thought.
You've already figured out the culprit?
There is no crime impossible for Mouri Kogoro.
Are you serious?
You know who the culprit is?
Who killed the director?
Well, well...
Please do not panic.
Mouri-san shall now explain.
Please go ahead.
First, let us run through everyone's alibi once more.
Now, Kiyama-san.
And you went for a drive with Ran at around 11:15 PM.
And returned around 1:00 AM.
Yes.
And following Kiyama-san, Hashimoto-san left dinner to return to his office around 8:10 PM.
Endou-san remained in the dining room with me until 9:30 PM...
And had remained in his room till morning.
Yes, that's correct.
The important point here is Ayaka-san's activities.
Ayaka-san finished cleaning up and returned to the main corridor at 8:45 PM.
She remained there until 2:00 AM.
So Kiyama-san, who had left to view the night scene, was the only one who left the mansion.
There are no signs of exit from the windows around the mansion...
And it's not possible to leave the mansion without passing by Ayaka-san.
That means, those who remained in the mansion between 9:00 PM and 1:00 AM, the time of the crime...
Endou-san, Ayaka-san, and Kiyama-san along with Ran, have valid alibis.
That is to say that...
Precisely.
That means the culprit is...
You, Hashimoto-san!
Me?
You were pressed quite harshly by Majima-san for the repayment of a debt, right?
Even so...
You, who had left the mansion to return to the company...
Snuck into Majima-san's room.
And there you killed Majima-san.
And then moved him to this room.
Moved him to this room?
Then used that.
What is that?
A picking rod.
For retrieving things that fall onto the rock garden.
Hey, hey, don't tell me that's...
Hashimoto-san carried Majima-san here...
And tied him to the rod like this.
Mouri-san...
Just stand back.
And then, Hashimoto-san, lifted the corpse like this-
Hey now...
Just a bit more.
Geez, Mouri-san.
Impossible, as I expected.
The only clue is that something was dragged there.
There are no signs that the rocks in the garden were moved.
Damn.
How was Majima-san placed there?
Pardon me, Detective.
Could we leave already?
Kiyama-san and I have alibis during the time of crime anyway.
Well, that's true.
Say, Mouri-san...
Mouri-san?
Shut up.
I'm thinking so just wait quietly.
Detective Yokomizo!
We found this in a trashcan in the dining room.
This is!?
Mouri-san!
If you don't want the records of your accounting fraud exposed...
Bring this note with you to the rooftop of the mansion at 11:00 PM.
What?
Mouri-san...
Majima-san must have been murdered in the mansion.
But...
Did you see Majima-san in the mansion, Ayaka-san?
Well, that's...
Don't tell me it was you who—
No, wasn't me!
Ayaka-san!
Please tell the truth.
The truth is, I am Tanuma's daughter.
Was Tanuma the driver who died in the accident with the previous director?
Yes.
I started working here after I heard rumors of Majima setting up the incident.
To confirm the truth.
Endou-san knows about that.
I think it was about 10:40 PM.
Endou-san?
He said to pay up if I didn't want Majima to know my identity.
I see.
At that time, she was looking at her father's picture.
Is that true, Endou-san?
So, what time did Endou-san leave?
Just a little after 11:00 PM, I think.
So, you couldn't have noticed if Majima-san was in the mansion.
Yes.
That's too much of a coincident.
I didn't do it.
Really!
Well, we will know eventually.
For now, let's have a look at the roof.
Yes.
Mouri-san.
Yeah.
The rock garden can be seen clearly here.
I know who murdered Majima-san.
So, the culprit is really...
You are the culprit, Endou-san!
You went to Ayaka-san and closed the curtains.
So that she wouldn't notice Majima-san coming to the roof.
Then you headed to the roof and killed Majima-san, who was waiting here.
And using a device you had prepared here, you moved Majima-san to the rock garden.
I see.
So, what's the device?
It's archery.
Hey!
You prepared an arrow with a loop at the end.
Then, pulled a long rope through the loop.
Retaining both ends of the rope, you shot the arrow to the big tree in the rock garden.
This is a simple task for a previous national sportsman like you.
You tied the rope to Majima-san and glided him to the rock garden.
But, Mouri-san...
Then, what about the rope?
That's easy.
Tie one end of the rope to the arrow.
And just shoot it toward the woods behind the rock garden, and the rope disappears.
I would even bet my reputation as a detective on this.
There should be an arrow with a rope attached to it somewhere.
Are you sure you should say that?
Found it!
We found the archery set in Endou-san's room.
And the arrow was found in the woods behind the rock garden.
That's amazing, father.
That's not possible.
That's strange.
If Uncle was right, the corpse wouldn't have ended up that way.
But, if that's true...
How exactly did the archery and rope-
This is...
A ticket to Kiyama-san's photo exhibition.
Why is this here?
I see.
That's what it was.
If my deduction is right, that person is still hiding that
It can't be disposed of easily, after all
Found it
Just as I thought
All that's left is proof.
What's that stain?
I've found it
Conclusive proof.
I was giving such an awesome display, what's with Conan?
Important matter, huh?
I'll take over from here, Uncle.
It's the truth!
I didn't kill him.
Yeah, I got it.
It wasn't me.
We'll talk at the station.
Wasn't me!
Detective Yokomizo.
What is it?
Mouri-san wants everyone to gather at the rock garden.
At the rock garden?
Something about finding the true culprit.
What!
Mouri-san, what is this about?
Wasn't the culprit Endou-san?
That pose!
Detective!
What you said was right...
I did think of killing Majima.
What?
I knew it.
But Majima never came.
It's true!
You liar!
I know that, Endou-san.
Someone else is the true culprit.
They knew of your plan and used that...
The true culprit, that is.
Well, don't you think it's strange?
The archery aside, if Endou-san was really the culprit...
Why would he throw away the threatening letter?
That's true.
The letter was taken from Majima-san's room and thrown outside to reveal Endou-san's plans.
Besides, if the corpse was moved from the rooftop as we had deduced earlier...
No matter how he was dangled from a rope...
The corpse wouldn't be lying face down with his hands and legs arranged.
It's not possible.
Then, how was it done?
Officer, if you don't mind.
Yes.
Detective Yokomizo!
Look at this.
An air mat.
What's that about, Mouri-san?
The crime was probably committed around 8:30 PM.
That's when the rock garden fills up.
Exactly.
The culprit tied a rope to the air mat, and floated Majima-san's body on the water.
Soon after, drainage began and the water receded.
And right before the air mat hit the sand...
They shoved Majima-san's body with the picking rod, while pulling back the air mat with all their might
With that, it was possible to place the corpse in the middle of the rock garden without a trace.
Incidentally, marks were left on the rocks at the edge of the pool when the air mat was dragged out
And, at that time, it probably washed out from Majima-san's pocket...
And a ticket to the photo exhibition ended up stuck in the drain.
Upon close inspection...
This scratch mark on the air mat was without a doubt from a button on Majima-san's pants.
So, who is the culprit?
The culprit probably panicked when we suddenly came by.
If Endou-san canceled his plans, it would have been all for nothing.
That was why when Endou-san was supposed to meet with Majima-san, the culprit took us outside.
So the culprit is-
Yes.
The culprit took Ran and Conan outside...
So Endou-san could carry out his plans.
Kiyama Tomonori-san.
It's you!
After Kiyama-san left the dining hall, he did not return to his room.
But went to the main wing of the house and killed Majima-san.
Ayaka-san was still in the dining hall, so there was no worry that he would be seen.
And to float the body in the rock garden, Kiyama-san just kept waiting...
For Endou-san to close Ayaka-san's curtains.
In brief, Endou-san intended to conceal Majima-san's movements...
But had assisted in Kiyama-san's criminal act instead.
I see.
So that air-mat was?
Yes.
It was found in Kiyama-san's room.
Hey, just hold it.
This is a trap.
There must be a culprit who's trying to pin the crime on me with the air mat.
So, you don't remember seeing the air mat?
Of course.
I've never seen this air mat.
Oh, that's strange.
Kiyama-san, could you take a closer look at the air mat?
T-That's-
Yes.
That's from the memento that you said never left your side...
Ink from your father's fountain pen.
I never imagined it would scatter on the air mat.
I thought I had wiped it all up.
But why?
Even if you hadn't done it, Endou-san would have gotten to Majima-san...
I heard him.
He proudly spoke of it with amusement.
Majima messed with the brakes...
And had my father fall to his death.
And while I was away, he made himself the director.
And took over my father's company.
When I learned of that, I thought...
I would kill this guy one day, with my own hands.
Endou-san gave me the perfect opportunity to do so.
And I consecrated his corpse to the rock garden that my father loved.
The perfect opportunity.
Out of gas again?
Father, not again.
What should we do on a mountain road like this?
Don't panic.
We'll just get picked up by some director again.
And get invited to a director's house.
I'll get to drink good sake again tonight.
Don't need beer.
What's this old man talking about?