Two people's deductions and suspense
fill the gulf between love and hate!
Today, it's Chinatown in Yokohama!
The surprising people Ran got involved with!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Who presented the "Opinion on Twelve Matters" to Emperor Daigo?
Kiyoyuki Miyoshi!
What's the term for a Pureland Buddhist painting that depicts the descent of Buddha?
Shoju Raigo!
Hey, hey! Can you knock it off?
That stuff gives me hives!
I've got no choice!
There's a big Japanese history test tomorrow,
and I've been too busy with karate to study for it!
Then you should've stayed home tonight!
And who won us that free meal at Chinatown Restaurant, may I ask?
And you're telling me to stay home?
Okay, okay! Just shut the book until we get home!
But I won't have time to study tonight!
There's a ton of great stuff on TV!
Reading in the car is gonna make you carsick.
Don't worry! I've got a tough semicircular canal!
It's starting to rain!
It really is...
It's raining pretty hard...
Rain...
For some reason, it brings back memories...
That man in the cap, standing in the rain...
But I can't remember where...
A back street in an unfamiliar city...
Why can't I remember?
Every time I try, I just see that image of him.
Oh yeah...
Standing in the rain, just like that...
And the look on Shin'ichi's face, kind but sad.
Why are you drenched in rain?
Why are you looking at me like that?
Tell me, Shin'ichi...
Ran-neechan, Ran-neechan!
What's wrong, Ran-neechan?
Your forehead went all wrinkly and your face got scary.
I just couldn't remember the answer to this question.
Um...
During the Cloistered Rule Period,
Kiyohira Fujiwara...
Nuts. Guess I have gotten carsick...
Talk about a pain!
Just as we're about to start filming,
our lead actress breaks a bone in a motorcycle accident!
Maybe we should just stop trying to make this movie.
Kaizo Isogami (52)
Movie Director
It seems to be cursed!
C'mon, we can't pass up an opportunity like this!
It's the sequel to a blockbuster, and it's already attracting buzz!
But, Kawabata-san...
Motohiro Ito (38)
Assistant Director
With our actress injured, we're stuck!
She's the only girl we've found who can play this role!
I agree...
Keigo Kitaura (29)
Original Author
If we keep trying to film this picture, the body count...
will only go up.
Anyway, I'm glad that actress pulled out.
She never fit my image of the heroine of my novel.
Kitaura-sensei...
Damn... Why can't we find her?
Shiro Kawabata (46)
Producer
A cute young girl, who can handle action scenes...
What do you mean, we can't use this gift certificate?
Well, you see...
But the restaurant's name is written right on it!
Yes, that's us... We issued the coupon.
But..
Then, why can't we use it?!
I demand an explanation and a clear one!
So, that's why...
Hey, kiddo...
What's your sister's name?
Who are you?
W-Who...am I?
Got it, kid?
My name is...
What kind of joint is this?!
Don't tell me you pick your customers.
N-No! Of course not!
You snobs think you can mess with me?
Excuse me, sir.
Let's take this outside.
Don't try to strong-arm us!
We're not going anywhere until we get an explanation!
Your sister's amazing.
Er, well...
T-The certificate says clearly...
it's not valid on Sundays or holidays.
Huh?
Hey, he's right! It's here in the small print!
Oops.
Oh no... I sincerely apologize.
I'm so sorry...
Oh, no. We're happy that you understand the provisions.
Geez, why didn't you check in the first place?
Say what? You're the one who rushed out first, saying that early bird catches the worm!
Say what?!
Well, young lady, that was a good kick!
How about you and me going to see a Bruce Lee movie?
Who are you?
Me?
Mike Hama
Private Eye
My name is Mike Hama.
I'm not kidding, either.
Mike Hama...
I've heard that name before...
This guy is Mike Hama?
I've got an office on the second floor of Yokohama Nichigeki in Kogane-cho...
Yes, I remember!
That second-rate private eye who has an office on the second floor of a movie theater!
Well... that's that!
Well, lady, call me when you feel like going out with me!
See you later, kiddo!
What was that?
Beats me.
Your dinner, sir... What would you like to do?
Well, actually...
Excuse me...
Why don't you join us for dinner?
We'll pick up the check!
A heroine in a movie?
Me?
You're perfect for the role!
If you're interested in the part...
Don't do it!
You'll just forget your lines and make a laughingstock of yourself!
Not everyone is blessed with my oratory skills, my power to entrance a crowd...
Your power to sleep, while I put on a show for you.
I guess you're right...
But if the movie's a hit, you'll be a star! You'll be in showbiz!
You'll hobnob with movie stars!
Not to mention baseball players, soccer stars, Formula 1 drivers...
You'll travel the world for the film. America, England, France...
G-Go for it, Ran-neechan!
Go for it! Take on challenges!
Y-You think so?
But if you're going to do it,
you'd better be prepared!
Right. Some filmmakers will completely ignore the original story
to add a racy love scene or similar junk...
L-Love scene?
Kitaura-sensei! You're not talking about me, are you?
On second thought, say no.
That's right. It's all wrong for you.
Y-Yeah...
Well, if doing one little love scene scares you, don't sign on for this picture.
Show business can be the death of you...
Hey, stop scaring her! This girl here is our golden goose!
No way... I'm nothing special...
I'm so sorry!
Are you okay?
I'm fine. I'll just wipe it up with my hot towel.
Excuse me! Can I get a new pair of chopsticks?
Of course!
What?
You've got a fever. Are you okay?
I'm fine! It's just a little head cold.
But what if you collapse like last time?
Last time?
Er, never mind...
Hey, don't listen to your hard-headed dad! Talk to me!
Tell me what you want and I'll bring it to you on a platter!
Um, okay...
Sorry for the wait.
Oh, thanks.
Hey! I thought I said not to order the century eggs or the crab omelette!
What's wrong?
Actually, I'm allergic to eggs.
I can't even stand to look at egg dishes.
Is that so...
Anyway, young lady, eat all you want.
Thank you. Well...
I want curry with rice!
Kid, this is a Chinese restaurant!
They don't have curry...
But I want curry! Curry, curry, curry!
If they don't have curry, I don't wanna eat here!
I think we should go home, okay?
Ran-neechan?
Well...
Here! Have some Chinese dumplings!
You really liked these the last time we had them, remember?
Oh, geez. Doesn't she care about my feelings?
Oh well. Where's the soy sauce?
Ah, in front of the old guy.
Alright...
Damn. It's in front of the old guy again!
This time...
Not again...
What is it, Conan-kun? Do you want something?
Um, the soy sauce...
Here!
Oh, thanks...
Okay, the chili oil is in front of that fox-faced guy...
Damn it.
Here! You want the chili oil, right?
Yeah.
How frustrating.
She has to do everything for me.
Here it is!
The Peking duck here is superb!
By the way, do you have any favorite actresses?
Yes, two!
One is Yukiko Fujimine-san.
She's the mother of one of my best friends,
and I've looked up to her since I was little.
And the other?
The other is an American actress...
Sharon Vineyard-san!
But she passed away a year ago...
Ah! A great actress.
Yes! I met her once and she was really nice!
Hey where'd you meet a star like her?
Nowhere you'd know, Dad!
Yukiko Fujimine and Sharon Vineyard? You've got taste, kid.
They're both legendary performers.
If she hadn't died, she might've become a legend like those two.
She?
The victim is Shiro Kawabata-san, age 46, a movie producer.
The cause of death seems to be asphyxiation caused by potassium cyanide.
Honestly. Potassium cyanide, arsenic, caustic soda...
How do criminals keep getting their hands on this stuff?
Did this guy put anything into his mouth before he dropped dead?
Yes. Peking duck.
The waiter wrapped the duck in crêpes and placed them on the plates.
The victim went into convulsions the moment he bit in.
So his last supper was Peking duck.
At least he went out on a high note.
But no poison was found in the Peking duck,
and the waiter didn't have any cyanide on him,
so the victim must've had the poison on his hands before he picked up the duck crêpe.
I see.
So the person who poisoned this guy...
is one of you guys who were eating with him.
How do you guys know the stiff?
We're in the movie biz.
The star of our latest project got in an accident before we started shooting,
and we were discussing what to do about it.
Should we find a replacement, or ditch the movie?
Then this girl and her family walked in, and Kawabata-san saw something in her.
He invited them to come have dinner with us.
Hey! You with the mustache! I've seen you before...
Of course you have! I'm..
You're an ex-con, right?
Or a wanted man on the run?
Huh?
Of course not! I'm Kogoro Mouri!
M-Mouri? You're kidding, right?
As in the famous detective?
That's me, all right!
Oh, that cheap con man called "Smoking Kogoro", right?
That's Sleeping Kogoro!
Inspector! We've got a cyanide reaction!
Yeah?
We didn't find any traces of poison in the other dishes,
but we've found evidence of potassium cyanide
on the chopsticks, plate and hot towel the victim was using.
Especially the towel.
Who was sitting next to the victim when he collapsed?
I was sitting on his right.
And on his left?
Me!
I was sitting to his left, eating dumplings!
Then this case is simple.
The murderer poisoned his own towel and switched it with the victim's.
It was you, Mr. Detective!
Me?
We can't suspect a little kid!
And you were on his right!
If the victim was right-handed, he would've placed his towel right next to you!
Hang on...
You knew he'd wipe his hands on the towel before picking up the duck crêpe!
Fess up!
Haven't I seen you somewhere too?
Don't try to change the subject!
Yeah, he looks familiar!
See?
We've never met! I just know your face from TV!
Inspector Yokomizo! Over here!
Huh? What is it?
Yokomizo?
I knew it! Inspector Yokomizo!
You were forced to shave your head because you screwed up a case, right?
No need to be embarrassed!
Don't worry! I like the new look better than that doofy old perm!
You're talking about my twin brother Sango! He works for the Shizuoka Police!
Jugo Yokomizo
Kanazawa Prefectural Police
Inspector
I'm Jugo Yokomizo, an inspector for the Kanagawa Police!
Y-You're brothers?!
No way...
My brother is easy-going and seems to respect you.
But I'm different.
I don't trust private eyes!
Er, Inspector...
Ah, sorry.
What do you make of this mark on the victim's jeans?
Looks like some kind of stain.
Oh, that's Kawabata-san's soup!
I spilled it on him when I was sitting next to him.
What? You were next to the victim?
I thought you and the kid were sitting next to him!
Kawabata-san switched seats. He forced himself between me and Ran!
Later, Conan sat next to him.
So before he moved, he was sitting between the girl...
...and me.
But I ended up next to him after Kawabata-san invited the detective to the table.
Before the detective and his family joined us, Kawabata-san was sitting between him and me,
but our chairs were pretty far apart.
I-I was on the other side of the table the whole time. I'm innocent, right?
We'll know after the investigation.
Why don't you check his trousers?
Kawabata-san changed seats after the soup was spilled,
and he used his towel to wipe it off.
If you check the stain, you can see whether the towel was poisoned!
Right, Uncle Kogoro?
Y-Yeah.
What? There's no trace of poison on his trousers?
Are you sure you checked?
Yeah.
Also, the waiter told us he gave the victim a fresh pair of chopsticks
after his first ones fell on the floor,
but we didn't find any cyanide on the chopsticks either.
That means the towel was poisoned after the soup was spilled,
the waiter brought the new chopsticks and the victim switched seats.
I'm afraid you're still the chief suspect!
That's crazy!
Why would I poison a guy I'd just met at a restaurant I'd never been to before?
I don't know.
But your story sounds too good to be true.
The minute you show up at this place, your daughter gets scouted for a movie?
Come on!
It's true!
It was a total coincidence that we came here the same time as...
Huh?
Rain...
After all, I met that man on a rainy night...
Who is he?
Maybe he just looks like somebody I know, like that inspector...
Why can't I remember?
All I can dredge up are three faces...
A smiling mouth...
Angry eyes...
and...
What?
What are you saying?
I can't hear you, Shin'ichi...
Ran-neechan...
Ran-neechan!
What's wrong? You look pale.
I-I'm okay! Just felt a little dizzy...
Have a seat! I'm sure Uncle will crack the case soon!
Okay. Thanks.
And don't get in the way, Conan-kun.
This is bad.
Ran's acting weird.
We have to get her to a hospital soon...
I see...
You took the towel into the restroom and poisoned it there!
Look, it wasn't me!
Can't even stand to look at them?
Was there anything else on it?
N-No, nothing...
Hm, I see... Nothing else on it, right?
Next Conan:
Hot towel
"Mike Hama, Private Eye", huh?
The old guy's got the same nonchalance, at least.