Two people's deductions and suspense
fill the gulf between love and hate!
The mysterious revolving Chinese table!
Ran's memories come back!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
With a gift certificate that Ran won in a drawing at a shopping mall,
we headed to Chinatown in Yokohama.
There, we met people in the movie industry.
Kaizo Isogami (52)
Movie Director
Film director Kaizo Isogami-san...
Motohiro Ito (38)
Assistant Director
Assistant director Motohiro Ito-san...
Keigo Kitaura (29)
Original Author
The author of the book, Keigo Kitaura-san...
Shiro Kawabata (46)
Producer
And the producer, Shiro Kawabata-san.
Circumstances led to us having dinner with them.
But, suddenly...
Kawabata-san died.
No poison was found on his clothing.
Because there was a chemical reaction on the plate and towel that he used,
old man Mouri, who had been sitting next to him, was suspected of planting the poison.
That's crazy!
Why would I poison a guy I'd just met
at a restaurant I'd never been to before?
I don't know, but your story sounds too good to be true.
The minute you show up at this place,
your daughter gets scouted for a movie?
It's true!
It was a total coincidence that
we came here the same time as...
Huh?
What's wrong? You look pale.
I'm okay! Just felt a little dizzy...
Have a seat! I'm sure Uncle will crack the case soon!
Okay. Thanks.
This is bad.
Ran's acting weird.
We have to get her to a hospital soon...
Anyway, the towel was poisoned after the soup was spilled,
the waiter brought the new chopsticks and the victim switched seats.
I'm afraid you're still the chief suspect!
Hey, hey...
Hey, Inspector...
Well, Ran—
Inspector!
We found this bottle in the restroom!
We think it contained the poison!
What?
I see. You took the towel into the restroom and poisoned it there!
Look, it wasn't me!
If that's true, Uncle Kogoro can't be the bad guy!
He hasn't been to the bathroom since we got here!
Like he said, Inspector!
And after Kawabata-san wiped off the soup,
he held onto the towel while he changed seats.
I don't think anybody could've switched towels on him.
No, there must be a way...
Some way to switch the towels without being noticed...
I've got it!
The murderer used the lazy Susan on the table!
He put the towel on the edge of the lazy Susan and skillfully rotated it
so it'd fall into Kawabata-san's lap!
How's that?
Even if you say "How's that"...
If something like that falls, everybody will find it strange, right?
So, that's why it has to be done cleverly so nobody notices...
If nobody sees it, the speed with which the lazy Susan has to turn
to drop off the towel would make all the plates fall off, too!
And why would he decide to use that towel rather than his own?
I guess not.
Wait a minute.
When I tried to get the soy sauce and the chili oil,
the lazy Susan kept revolving, so it was really hard to reach them.
If I remember correctly, the dishes on the table, moving clockwise,
were twice-cooked pork, pepper steak, crab omelette,
Twice cooked pork
Pepper Steak
Crab Omelette
century eggs and sweet-and-sour pork, plus the lid of the steamer.
Century Egg
Sweet and Sour Pork
Steamer Lid
The soy sauce was between the sweet and sour pork and the century eggs
Soy Sauce
and the chili oil was between the twice cooked pork and the steamer lid.
Chili Oil
Starting clockwise from the victim, Kawabata-san, the seating attangement was
Kawabata
me, Ran, Kitaura-san, Ito-san, Isogami-san, and the old man.
Conan
Ran
Kitaura
Ito
Isogami
Kogoro
The soy sauce kept returning to the old man,
and the chili oil kept returning to Kitaura-san.
Come to think of it, Kawabata-san said...
I'm allergic to eggs. I can't even stand to look at egg dishes.
Can't even stand to look at them?
Okay, work on this area with caution.
Yes, sir!
Excuse me, officer!
Yes?
There's something I'd like to ask you...
What's that, kid?
If you checked the dishes,
you checked the tabletop for poison too, right?
Yeah.
Then how about...
Well? Did you check that part?
No, we haven't looked there.
Uncle Kogoro just wanted to know if you had!
Sleeping Kogoro said that?
Oh, and did you find anything funny on the poisoned towel?
You mean apart from the poison?
Yeah, actually there was this light brown stain!
I took a whiff of it, but it's probably just soup.
You saw when Kawabata-san spilled soup on his trousers and cleaned it off with the towel, right?
That's how it got that stain.
What else?
Was there anything else on the towel?
N-No, nothing...
Hm, I see... Nothing else on it, right?
I'll tell Uncle Kogoro!
Oh... okay...
I knew it.
Kawabata-san didn't die from that poisoned hand towel!
The towel was planted after he was killed!
And I know who did it!
In that case, the evidence should still be there...
On the table...
Anyway.
The murderer went to the restroom,
poisoned his own hand towel,
and swapped it with the victim's towel during the meal.
And somehow he did it without me, Ran or Conan noticing,
even though we were right next to the victim.
That's what I don't get. How'd he pull it off?
I've got it!
All three suspects are from the movie industry!
The killer used special effects,
like invisible strings...
Get real.
Geez, the air conditioning's turned up way too high.
What is it, Inspector Yokomizo?
Huh? Oh, nothing. My brother told me
that Kogoro Mouri's deductions seem way off target at first, but he's just playing dumb.
He turns into a different person after he lets out a strange cry
and does this weird dance.
But I bet my brother was just making that up.
Oh, but...
Is that what you mean by a weird dance?
I think we've chatted long enough.
It's time for you to take your seats.
That's right... The people who were sitting at the table with the victim.
Ito-san, Isogami-san, and Kitamura-san, you three.
Then, I'll tell you everything about this case
and what happened during the fateful meal.
L-Look! It's Sleeping Kogoro's famous deduction routine!
Inspector Yokomizo, please take the victim's seat.
Then the rest of us. From his right, that's me and Isogami-san,
then Ito-san, and then Kitaura-san.
Oh, and could another officer take Ran's place?
Huh? Why?
My daughter isn't feeling well.
I'm fine!
I can do it.
Ran...
Conan, please sit between the victim and Ran.
Now that we're all seated, I'd like to talk
about the strange incident just before the victim's death.
Strange incident?
The lazy Susan! Somebody was playing tricks on me by moving the lazy Susan!
Look!
Do you see the bottle of soy sauce on the lazy Susan right in front of Uncle Kogoro?
Yeah.
I turned the lazy Susan to get the soy sauce.
But whenever I reached for it,
it turned again and the sauce went back to Uncle...
Over and over.
The same thing happened with the chili oil in front of Kitaura-san!
Each time the bottle came close to me,
it would go back right away to being in front of Kitaura-san.
This means that someone was having fun, giving me a hard time, right?
Hey, Mr. Detective, does what this kid's saying have anything to do with the case?
H-Hey, don't...
It's all right...
Uncle Kogoro told me the murderer will turn himself in! You guys don't need to do a thing!
T-Turn himself in?
Here you are, little boy. A pork bun!
Oh boy! Thanks!
Hey... why now?
Sorry! I was told that Detective Mouri wanted me
to bring the boy a pork bun while he discussed the case.
Yum! It looks great!
Don't eat that!
What's the matter, Isogami-san?
Think about it! We're sitting at a table where a murder took place just moments ago!
There may still be poison on the table!
You want this kid to eat something with his hands after he's been touching the table?
But, the people from the crime lab didn't find any poison.
No, Isogami-san is right.
There may still be poison left.
Somewhere we wouldn't notice.
Hey!
Enough with the tease!
Who's the murderer, and where'd he put the poison?!
How would you turn this?
What?
The lazy Susan.
How? I'd just put my hand on it like so...
What if the plates are close together and sticking out over the edge,
like the crab omelette and the century egg?
Well, i-in that case, I guess I'd have to...
I'd hold the edge of the lazy Susan like this...
Could it be...
The poison was on the underside of the lazy Susan?
No. There's no way to get the victim to touch a specific spot under the lazy Susan.
What if that spot was under a dish Kawabata-san didn't like?
What if it was under a dish
he didn't even want to look at?
Was there a dish like that?
Y-Yes! Kawabata-san was allergic to eggs.
Look carefully, Inspector Yokomizo!
When those two dishes are in front of the victim's seat,
where is the chili oil?
In front of Kitaura-san.
I-I get it!
The kid kept trying to get the chili oil,
and the murderer kept trying to move the lazy Susan back into place!
He wanted the victim to touch the underside of the lazy Susan
to move the two egg dishes aside!
That may have been true for the chili oil, but the soy sauce should've been right front of the kid.
Why did the table turn when he tried to get the soy sauce?
If you want the victim to touch the poison, you have to put the poison on the table first!
The murderer coated the underside of the lazy Susan with poison
right before the waiter brought the Peking duck.
If he'd done it earlier, somebody else might have accidentally touched it.
Then the murderer hadn't placed the poison when the kid tried to get the soy sauce?
Right.
I'm guessing the murderer saw the waiter coming out with the Peking duck
and started to put the poison in place under the egg dishes.
But then Conan turned the lazy Susan. The murderer had to keep turning it back
to apply the poison.
In other words, the person who had the egg dishes in front of him
when the soy sauce was in front of you...
Right. In other words, that's the person who poisoned Kawabata-san.
You did it...
Isogami-san!
Then where'd the poisoned towel come from?
It was Isogami-san's towel from the start.
He took it to the restroom, put cyanide on it, went back to the seat,
and pressed it against the underside of the lazy Susan.
After Kawabata-san collapsed, he used the confusion
to switch his towel with Kawabata-san's.
He also stained his towel with soup to make it look like Kawabata-san's,
after he had wiped the soup off his trousers, so nobody would realize it'd been switched.
But you forgot one thing.
Kawabata-san was wearing blue jeans!
That's right. Kawabata-san's towel, which you still have on you,
has both a soup stain...
and a faint blue stain from the jeans.
I see... If Isogami-san has this towel,
it's clear evidence that he's the murderer!
No. It isn't solid evidence.
There's a possibility that someone else planted it there to pin the crime on Isogami-san.
But I think it's time you confessed, Isogami-san.
You stopped Conan from eating that bun
after touching the poisoned lazy Susan.
That means you still have a conscience.
A conscience?
If that guy had one of those, he wouldn't have let Rika die,
and I wouldn't have been forced to take revenge.
Rika? The actress who died last year?
But that was an accident at a film shoot...
That was no accident!
It was murder!
The last action scene was supposed to be done by a stunt woman,
but Rika took her place at the last minute.
And Kawabata let her get killed.
N-No way!
Yeah.
After she died, he told me with a smirk that he'd just given her what she wanted.
Thanks to her work, the movie was a big hit.
He had every opportunity to stop her.
I-I don't get it. You always complained about her... said she was an amateur.
You fool.
A director's job is a sad one...
Don't you see how easy it is to fall for a star when you see her through the camera lens?
It doesn't matter how poor her acting is.
If you don't understand that love,
you'll always be an assistant director.
Okay, let's go.
You can tell us the rest at the station.
Mr. Detective, I'm sure you wiped the poison off the table.
But what were you going to do if I hadn't shouted at the kid, and let him die?
What if I were a heartless guy like Kawabata?
In that case, I was going to interrogate you with stronger words.
Words you'd never be able to talk yourself out of...
What a shame.
I oughta complain to God for giving me a conscience.
As a film maker, I'd have loved to have seen a real performance from you.
But I've never been the kind of guy
to believe in God or Buddha...
God...
Does this world even have a God?
Whose voice was that?
A calm female voice... Who is it?
R-Ran-neechan?
Rain...
The sound of the rain is dying down...
...need a reason?
I think I can hear what he's saying...
Do you need a reason?
Does this world even have a God?
Are you Japanese?
At least, no angel ever smiled on me.
Beat it!
Not even once...
Sharon...
I remember... It was back then...
I met him...
When I went there with Shin'ichi...
Ran!
Hang in there! Ran!
What is it, boy?
R-Ran is... Ran-neechan is...!
W-What's this? She's burning up!
Hey! Call an ambulance!
R-Right!
Ran! Ran!
Hang in there! Ran!
Who is that? Shin'ichi?
Is that Shin'ichi?
Next Conan:
Stage costume
Next time, the stage is the New York of my memories!
It's a somewhat nostalgic case.