Lila Sanchez (32)
Stage Actress
Akane Nilsen (27)
Rose Hewitt (28)
Stage Actress
Night Baroness
Everith Hamilton (30)
Stage Actress
«For the Fairest»
Heath Flockhart (33)
Stage Actor
Two people's deductions and suspense
fill the gulf between love and hate!
I'm with Ran in New York.
A case begins with a movie actress!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Ran...
Rain...
Do you need a reason?
Does this world even have a God?
Are you Japanese?
At least, no angel ever smiled on me.
Get out of here!
Not even once...
Sharon...
I remember...
It was back then...
I met him...
When I went there with Shin'ichi...
Ran!
Ran-neechan!
Hey! Ran!
Hang in there! Hey!
Ran...
Hey!
Hang in there!
Ran!
What is it, boy?
R-Ran is... Ran-neechan is...!
W-What's this? She's burning up!
Hey! Call an ambulance!
R-Right!
No, wait!
Tell the hospital we're bringing in a patient!
But, Inspector!
To what hospital?
There's an emergency hospital just past the Bay Bridge, isn't there?!
Right!
Oh?
What's going on?
I...
I know a doctor there.
We'll definitely be able to get her a bed,
and we can be there in less than ten minutes if we take the squad car!
Got it.
Get the car ready! I'll be there in a sec!
Right!
Oh?
Ran!
Hang in there! Ran!
Ran...
Who is that?
Ran! Hang in there! Ran!
Shin'ichi?
Is that Shin'ichi?
It's embarrassing...
He saved me again...
Just like back then...
Whenever I'm depressed...
He seems to be able to see right through me...
I hate to admit it.
But it made me happy...
Shin'ichi...
Wait...
Isn't that...
"Statue of Liberty."
Or the "Goddess of Liberty," as we call it in Japan.
I've heard that New Yorkers call her "Miss Liberty", though.
Geez, why didn't you wake me up?
I was really looking forward to seeing Manhattan at night from the Brooklyn Bridge.
And now we're almost across it!
Hey...
If you'd slept on the plane,
you wouldn't have fallen asleep now.
How could I sleep after that guy was killed?
Not everyone can just drop off to sleep with the satisfaction of having solved a big case!
Hey, I'm not satisfied.
Not even a lifetime will be long enough for me
to reach the pinnacle of deduction and analysis, my dear Watson...
Now, now, you two.
This place is the greatest date spot, and the delight of lovers throughout the world.
And you're arguing on it? I'm jealous.
It's your fault, mom.
We weren't supposed to be in New York until tomorrow.
You're the one who made us get on another plane as soon as we reached LA.
Didn't have a choice.
I suddenly managed to get tickets to a musical that I'd given up on.
Oh? A musical?
Look, that one.
The Golden Apple? I hear it's popular right now.
Right. At Broadway's Phantom Theater.
At 8 PM.
I'm so excited!
Aren't there a lot more patrol cars than before?
Yeah. They're probably after that serial killer.
Killer?
A serial killer that only targets young girls.
They say he's Japanese, but I dunno.
Don't worry.
That man apparently only attacks after midnight.
So long as we get to the hotel before then, we'll be safe.
And it's not even six o'clock.
Don't you mean seven? Because of Summer Time.
I forgot about Summer Time!
I was supposed to set my watch ahead on the first Sunday of April!
What's the big deal?
It's only 40 minutes by car from here to Broadway, right?
It's not quite seven yet,
so we've got plenty of time.
I'm supposed to meet up with the friend who got the tickets for me!
She said if we got to the theatre an hour early, she'd show us around backstage!
I guess you're just gonna have to forget about it.
This so-called "English Lady" you bought because you fell in love with it
will never get you there on time, mom.
Now you've done it, Shin'ichi.
Ran-chan, grit your teeth and hang on tight.
S-Sure.
The people at the Jaguar company put everything into this E-Type when they built it.
H-Hey...
Don't underestimate me!
Are you sure about this?!
This car was in the shop for repairs just last month!
You just got it back the other day!
Don't worry, the mechanic was a pro. This car's as good as new!
They gave her back her 276 horsepower engine,
along with the steering and suspension that won Le Mans!
Hey!
What do you think you're doing?
There's tons of patrol cars here!
Don't worry! They were in the opposite lane,
so they only got a glimpse of her killer curves before she vanished into the night!
By the way, Shin-chan, can you and Ran-chan do me a favor?
It's pretty tricky up ahead...
...okay?
Will you do it for me?
Geez.
All right!
Well, Ran, can you come here for a bit?
What?
Don't worry, don't worry. It's only scary at first.
Wait, S-Shin'ichi...
Hold on tight!
Wasn't that big a deal, right?
How is this not a big deal?!
Exactly an hour early.
See? We got here in one piece. No sweat!
Or maybe not...
Your license and registration, please!
OK, OK!
40 miles over the speed limit! Are you playing Dirty Harry?
Oh, we were in a hurry...
You look familiar.
Well, you might...
You might have met her in some case.
Because she works with us.
Captain?!
She's an undercover agent.
She seems to have missed the criminal...
Who is this man?
Radish.
Yūsaku met him when he solved a case.
That's how they became friends.
He's Radish Redwood, a captain on the New York police force.
His Japanese is pretty good since his wife's from Japan.
Thank you, Radish. You saved me.
No, no.
You're thanking the wrong person.
The wrong person...?
If you want to thank someone...
...thank me.
Sharon Vineyard.
Sha... Sharon!
Why...
That police agent is a fan of mine.
I was talking to him while waiting for you when it came over his radio.
That a silver Jaguar was coming here at an unbelievable speed.
That's when I had the idea to disguise myself as Inspector Radish.
You better be thankful.
This men's coat was quite expensive, after all.
Thanks.
But is it all right? Everyone's looking this way.
It's fine. There's no problem.
I told everyone we were filming a movie here.
Aw... I love you, Sharon!
H-Hey, mom, tell me.
Who's she?
Shin'ichi, you don't know her? She's one of America's most famous actresses!
That's why...
Why is such a famous actress disguising as an inspector?
Oh? Didn't I tell you?
When I'd just started working as an actress,
I got a part as a spy girl.
And for that role,
I learned some disguise skills from Japan's most famous magician.
She'd gotten a similar role, so she was learning from the same magician, too.
Well, I can't disguise myself as someone else quite as well as Sharon.
Yeah, everytime you put one of those things on, it looked more like a clown suit than a disguise.
Sorry if it's not good enough for you. I did my best.
But it's amazing, meeting someone so famous.
Especially here in New York!
I should thank God for it.
Is there such a thing as God in this world?
If there really were a supreme being,
all righteous, hard-working people would be leading happy lives...
Right...
At least, no angel ever smiled on me.
Not even once...
Maybe that sad smile on her face was an omen...
of the tragedy about to unfold.
I never wanted to remember... that awful case...
W-What do you mean by that?
About no angel ever smiling on you?
She's just trying to say she's had a tough life.
Isn't that right, Sharon?
That's right. My life's just been misery after misery.
On the day of my screen début,
after struggling for years in the biz,
I lost both of my parents in a fire.
And my husband died the day after I won my Oscar.
Then there's Chris, who made her début so easily just because she was my daughter.
Everything was handed to her on a silver platter. What a difference between us.
Don't exaggerate. I know you're proud of her. You put everything into raising her.
That child... I don't consider her my daughter anymore.
Can you believe it?
While I was placing flowers on my husband's grave,
she came up behind me, disguised perfectly as him.
Don't you think that joke was a little too black?
Come to think about it, Sharon, you once told me...
You taught her the art of disguise because she kept begging you...
I haven't spoken to her in... almost ten years now.
I think she fell in with a bad crowd.
But enough about that. Go park your car in the parking lot.
It's about time we went backstage.
Our audience is beginning to catch on that there's no camera rolling.
Why'd we have to show up an hour before the musical starts?
Couldn't we have come by earlier, when the actors wouldn't have been so busy?
Then we could actually talk to them.
Don't be silly.
If we'd come here earlier, the performers would still be just regular people.
But right before the show starts...
If it isn't Sharon! You really made it!
I guess our director does say the truth sometimes...
How exciting, I feel like I'm dreaming!
I'm surprised you found the time!
Are you free today?
Let's go eat later!
I get it.
Yes, let's!
This is when they've got their stage makeup on and they really look like actresses.
Everybody admires her.
Yeah. She's friends with the theater's director.
She said she wanted to come and give them her support,
and was given the tickets, just like that.
Oh? Could she be...
Right.
The popular female TV detective...
The Night Baroness!
Yes!
"Night Baroness?"
That's what they call Mom here.
Since she's the wife of the Night Baron's creator, Yūsaku Kudō.
And she was once invited to a local investigation show on TV,
since she's married to a deduction genius and all.
She analysed the crime then, and everything she said fit,
so they arrested the criminal right away.
That's how she got the nickname of the popular woman detective Night Baroness.
Though, that deduction was really just repeating what Dad said
every day when reading the morning paper.
Then those two are your kids?
He is, but she's not.
Well, she might be my future daughter-in-law.
How marvelous!
Congratulations.
My, my.
And here I thought the Night Baroness'd come to solve
the mystery of the strange present.
But I see she's only here to greet us.
What a disappointment.
Strange present?
Yeah.
Three days ago, a packet was delivered to the company.
An apple covered in gold spray. A Golden Apple.
With a message in animal blood: "For the Fairest."
I see.
That explains why I felt so much tension when I entered this room.
Now, now, calm down, my goddesses.
It's probably just a prank.
But Heath...
Who's he?
This theater company's top star, Heath Flockhart.
But since he got a part in a movie, today's his last theater play.
Okay, everybody cheer up.
Let's all give Sharon and her friends the backstage tour.
But is this really all right? There's only 40 minutes left, should we be doing this?
Don't worry. The first 20 minutes of the play are a narration,
where the narrator talks about Greek mythology.
What's that up there?
The costumes for the play.
They're up there so they won't get in the way.
Look out!
The armor!
No!
Ran!
Ran!!!
What?!
Mom, take care of Ran!
S-Shin-chan!
Damn it...
Figured I wouldn't make it in time.
A bullet casing?
This is...
Next Conan: Shin'ichi Kudo's New York Case (The Deduction)
Next Conan's Hint: Feather
さぁ、バリバリ推理するぞぉ！
次回じゅうに解決しないと、また小さくなっちゃうわよ♪