Two people's deductions and suspense
fill the gulf between love and hate!
The shining stages of Broadway!
A big case with Ran and my mom!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
After we solved the case in Yokohama's Chinatown, Ran suddenly collapsed.
In her delirium, she remembered a case from the past.
It was when my mom convinced us to attend a musical in New York.
In front of the theatre, Mom's old friend, the famous actress Sharon Vineyard, was waiting.
She was going to give us a backstage tour, but as we walked through the wings before the show...
What's that up there?
The costumes for the play.
They're up there so they won't get in the way.
Look out!
The armor!
No!
Ran!
Ran!!!
Hang in there, Ran...
We're almost there...
We're almost at the hospital...
Ran...
Ran!
You okay, Ran?
I knew it! Someone... someone's after my life!
I don't think so... The rope must have broken since it's so old.
Geez, who put such an old armor up there?
But it could've been worse.
We're lucky that large mirror wasn't broken.
Yes. It's our guardian angel.
Hold on, you two. You shouldn't be thanking a mirror or any god.
You should be thanking her.
Thank you! You saved me!
You're welcome...
By the way, we need to get ready.
We'll see you after the play.
Sure!
I cut myself...
Let's see, do I have a bandage...
Here.
I knew it, there's no such thing as God.
If God existed, this wouldn't have happened.
I'm going home, Yukiko.
Not staying to watch the play, Sharon?
Nah.
I was planning to, but I've got business elsewhere.
And it looks like a storm is rising.
So I think I'll pass.
It's gorgeous!
It is, isn't it?
You don't see shows like this in Japan.
But someone doesn't seem to agree.
Hey! At least try to pay attention!
What's so interesting about it?
All they did was turn a Greek myth into a romantic comedy.
Then what Greek myth is this based on?
The Golden Apple.
A long time ago, there were three goddesses: Hera, Athena and Aphrodite.
They were invited to a banquet,
but Eris, who wasn't invited,
got jealous and sent the three a golden apple with a message...
"For the Fairest."
Then, back then...
Yeah.
Anyway, the three goddesses decided that
the prince of Troy should choose who should get the apple.
Each of them tried to bribe him with promises if he picked her...
See, the guy we met before is playing the unfortunate prince of Troy.
The actress playing the wife of the rich man is Zeus' wife,
Hera, the goddess of matrimony who promised him he'd be the world's most powerful man.
The Japanese-looking actress with a lot of character is Athena,
the goddess of wisdom who promised him victory in the war.
And that sexy actress is the goddess of beauty,
Aphrodite, who promised him the world's most beautiful woman.
And the one in the last scene with the grim look, who was jealous of the other three
is the one who gave them the golden apple: Eris, the goddess of strife.
In this version of the story, the rich lady offers the guy money,
the smart lady offers him a great job,
the babe offers him a date,
and the golden apple has been changed
to a jewelled apple-shaped necklace.
So who did the prince choose?
Aphrodite.
According to legend, that's how the Trojan War got started.
But that's the Greek myth.
This musical is quite different.
When you see the prince's identity...
...you're going to be surprised.
Behold, sinful humans.
I am Michael!
Michael? The archangel?
You've gotta be kiddin'.
Carefully listen to my answer.
What?!
Heath...
Tell me this isn't happening...
R-Right... This must be a joke...
No. It's not a joke. It's a murder!
A handgun...
He was shot with a handgun?
Yeah, that's what it looks like.
We should probably evacuate too.
Mom, take care of Ran!
Shin-chan!
Damn it...
Figured I wouldn't make it in time.
A bullet casing?
This is...
Good Lord!
I can't believe it! Heath Flockheart!
You know him, Captain?
My wife's a big fan of his.
So, what's the situation?
We've asked the actors to wait in their dressing rooms,
but most of the audience has fled.
He was shot straight in the heart.
The bullet's lodged into the wings in his back.
The wings in his back?
You mean this?
From the bullet's entry wound, I'd say he was shot from a 40° angle.
40°...
That's a pretty sharp angle.
Of course.
Because the killer was probably up on that terrace.
He used a laser sight to aim.
The Night Baroness?
Is that you, Yukiko?
What are you doing here?
I just happened to be watching the play.
I had no idea the musical would turn into a mystery.
He was shot during the climax where the angel appears.
During that scene, smoke is released,
The actor is lifted while the projection in the mirror slides up,
making it look like he's emerging from the mirror.
It's set up in a way to make it look real.
So basically, the killer shot him from that terrace as he was rising from the mirror?
Yeah.
After that, he threw the gun onto the stage,
to cause a panic, and therefore be able to escape.
But are you sure about this? The killer being in the terrace, I mean.
Of course. Thanks to the smoke on-stage,
I could clearly see a red beam of light pointing to the stage from the terrace.
My son saw it too.
Son?
Look, he's standing right next to you.
So you're the real one.
So this is the son you're always talking about, Shin'ichi?
Yeah, isn't he Yūsaku's spitting image?
They're just as big pranksters, too.
Captain?
Hold on.
What is it?
Hey, Shin-chan.
Please behave yourself.
Yeah, yeah.
Yukiko!
Seems you were right.
A suspicious person reserved every seat in the terrace a month ago.
But this person was wearing a scarf and hat, so we don't even know if it was a man or a woman.
Then that must be the killer.
But why pick that seat?
Aren't those seats expensive?
The angle from that terrace isn't very good, so they're probably cheap.
And it's easy to leave an impression if someone with their face hidden asks for an entire area,
which is exactly what the killer wanted.
But I don't get it.
What are these two strange marks?
Strange marks?
Yeah, in the neck. Doesn't it look like a burn?
And there's blood in his right hand.
Could the blood be from grabbing his chest after he was shot?
No...
The problem is that it's smudged, like someone tried to clean it.
He must have touched his hand somewhere after it got bloody,
but there's nothing in his clothes, nor is there anything he could've touched in the air.
So, has the Night Baroness solved this mystery?
Ehh... Not yet.
Why not ask Yūsaku? I bet he'd have some ideas.
No! Yūsaku's locked in a hotel room in LA, working.
What a shame. A celebrity murdered,
and I don't have a single lead.
I'll be hearing it from the public, the commish and my wife...
Excuse me...
Then maybe Shin'ichi might be able to solve it?
Shin-chan?
Yeah, right.
He's just a kid, he's never investigated a real murder before.
But he solved a case while we were on the plane.
Oh, I'm sure after the crook was caught he told you he'd known who it was all along.
He loves to brag...
No, he was involved in the investigation from the very start.
He was?
Yeah.
He lined up all the suspects and told them how it happened with that smug look of his.
Just like Holmes or Poirot.
Is that so, Shin-chan?
What? The killer's one of the four actresses?
That can't be.
Right as this case took place, I ran over to the terrace.
I found a bullet casing, but it wasn't hot.
This proves someone planted it in advance.
But you saw it too, right?
A laser sight's red light coming from the terrace to the stage.
Yeah, I saw it.
But we can't know which it was coming from or which it was aimed at.
Right.
That laser sight was probably aimed not from the terrace, but from the stage.
In order to make us believe the gunshot came from there.
In other words, the masked person purchasing the tickets, and the strange present
were just a ruse to lead us to suspect someone was threatening the actresses.
Oh, really?
I see...
Of course, this is part of the trick, too.
This is where that armor fell before the play started, right?
Look carefully at the floor.
There's a fishing line tied to a nail.
And next to it, there's a mark, as if something had been cut.
It looks like the fishing line was attached to the armor.
Then someone did it intentionally?
Yeah. The killer probably had a knife or similar in his shoe, and used it to cut the line,
bringing down the armor.
The killer knew that we, Sharon's friends, would come this way during the guided tour.
That means that the killer is one of those who was with us when the armor fell,
as well as one of the actresses who was on-stage with Heath.
That way, she could aim the laser sight at the terrace, as well as shoot him.
One of the four goddesses.
It could be any of them.
But Heath is six foot three.
How could any of those women shoot down at him?
Besides, he was behind that mirror!
That's right! How, Shin-chan?
Er... I haven't figured that out yet.
I see.
Hey, is that true, Lila?
Yeah.
Heath and I were dating.
For about five years now.
Then you were dating my boyfriend behind my back?!
Calm down, you two!
You shouldn't be talking about this in a day like this!
My...
You should be the angriest of them all.
Since your boyfriend apparently had two others.
Then... Rose too?
You were dating him too?
I see.
Apparently all four had a motive for killing Heath.
What do you mean?
I understand that he was involved with all three, but...
What reason does Everith have?
Unlike the other three, she doesn't have a photo of him on her mirror.
Actually, Heath and Everith were married.
Sharon told me while we were touring around the place.
They kept it secret even from the other actresses, in case it might affect their popularity.
So that's why she kept glaring at him when he was flirting with the others...
But right now, we have to figure out how the killer shot him from that height.
Rose was the closest one to the mirror,
but she was acting as if she'd collapsed from seeing the angel.
Everith was sitting,
and Akane was on her knees as if praying.
The one who could shoot from the highest was Lila who was standing and holding her head,
but unlike the other three, her hands weren't hidden by the smoke.
People would've noticed if she'd pulled out a gun.
Could Heath have been crouching?
That's impossible.
Those wings were bound to his feet, making it completely impossible for him to crouch.
Hey, Shin'ichi? Have you thought of something?
Wait, Shin'ichi!
You thought of something, right?
Tell me what you came up with.
Hey, Ran.
How tall are you?
160 cm.
So, five foot three...
This pamphlet is about 12 inches tall, or one foot...
Sorry, but could you put this on your head and stand in front of the mirror for a bit?
Wait, Shin'ichi.
What are you trying to prove with this?
H-Hey...
A crack...
kizu
There's a crack.
A crack?
Look, up there.
There's a tiny crack.
That's odd. This mirror's been with the theater for years, and was their guardian angel,
and they'd supposedly get bad luck if they broke it.
That's what Sharon said.
Hey, hey...
It looks like they glued it together. Were they really taking care of it?
Doesn't this curtain look a bit twisted?
Maybe somebody ran into it when trying to get away.
C'mon, Shin'ichi, let's get back. Your mom's going to kill us...
A feather?
How did it get stuck in here?
This flip door isn't used for anything.
Blood!
I see. I understand it now.
The killer used this stage's tricks to commit the crime.
A bloody murder, committed by someone as crafty as the goddess Eris.
From those positions, you four couldn't have shot him from above.
Who turned off the lights?
That's why the killer made use of something in the stage.
Then the killer's...
Right.
Only one person could do it.
Next Conan: Shin'ichi Kudo's New York Case (Case Closed)
新一「蘭、次回のヒントなんかすんげぇムカツク・・・(--メ)」
蘭「野生の勘ってやつ？」