Two people's deductions and suspense
fill the gulf between love and hate!
Spending time with Ran in New York,
turning rain and mystery into memories.
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Mom took Ran and me to see a musical in New York.
But while we were there, being given a backstage tour,
we met actor Heath Flockheart, who wound up getting shot to death!
A feather?
How did it get stuck in here?
I see. I understand it now.
From those positions, you four couldn't have shot him from above.
Then can we go change?
Yes, the GSR test came back negative.
This means it was somebody from the outside.
I can't deny it...
Who turned off the lights?
It was me, it was me.
Some call me the legendary beauty of Japanese showbiz...
others, the wife of the world's greatest mystery writer.
But I like to call myself
the lady detective with the hot grey matter...
The Night Baroness!
Sorry, shine the light here.
Yukiko...
That's me!
The smoke has cleared, Captain,
and now we can see the truth of this case!
Hey, mom, try not to screw up the deduction.
Don't worry, I'll say everything exactly as you told me.
Geez...
Hey, are you sure about your deduction?
If you're wrong, then your mom's going to be really embarrassed!
Yeah.
Don't you think it's strange?
Heath's height was 6 feet and 3 inches, about 1.90 metres.
About the same height as you, when you put that pamphlet over your head.
And when I measured you, the pamphlet was visible over the mirror.
Furthermore, Heath's head would've stuck out, since couldn't crouch with those wings,
which means he couldn't fit behind the mirror.
That's why the killer made use of something in the stage.
The actors use it to appear and disappear from the stage.
A trap door.
But there was no trap door behind the mirror.
Only thing that was there was a weird iron thing on the floor.
Moron.
If there's an iron door, then there's gotta be a hole under it.
One of the feathers from Heath's wings was caught in it,
causing his blood to make two semi-circles below it.
And taking into account the donut-shaped floor
and the twisted curtains, there's only one possible solution.
All you have to do is shift the donut-shaped floor...
and the hole will appear.
I'm sure that if they check it,
they'll find more feathers, blood from Heath,
and the bullet casing from the gun.
You mean he was shot at close range?
Yeah. Heath was waiting in the hole for his scene,
so the killer waited for him to come up and shot him.
The door was set against the back of the mirror,
so she just had to put the gun below the mirror and through the grid.
Then the killer's...
Right. Only one person could do it.
The one lying down next to the mirror...
Rose, it was you.
Rose!?
No way... it can't be!
None of us were told that the trap door was going to be used!
That can be explained. It's because...
They didn't tell you because they couldn't.
That the mirror that everyone saw as their guardian angel, was broken...
Rose must have damaged it in secret.
When the staff saw it was damaged,
they cut off the damaged part and glued it back together,
so the actors wouldn't notice the damage.
But due to the shorter frame, Heath's head stuck out.
If they'd put it on a platform, the actors would've noticed something's wrong.
That's why they decided to use the trap door and hide Heath's body.
And that's why they hid it from all but Heath and Rose.
But why would the staff tell Rose?
They had to. Moving the donut-shaped floor would hide the hole, but not the door.
Unless Rose closed the door from below the mirror, the audience would've seen the door.
Then what about the gun?
The gun fell from above, right?
She couldn't have done that if she was lying down.
It can be done.
If you consider that the angel, Heath, was going to be suspended.
Remember how Heath had a burn mark on his chest?
That's because Rose put the gun in his suit right after firing it.
Riding on his clothes, it would've fallen off from the recoil when he stopped being raised.
What she didn't count on, was for him to grab her hand while doing so.
The blood on his hand being smudged proves it.
So it should still be there... On her right arm, inside her right glove.
Heath's resentful, bloody handprint.
She likely put her gloves on inside out.
And after shooting him, she put them back.
That way, she'd be able to pass a GSR test.
But Shin'ichi, how did you know there was blood under the glove?
Because in the dressing room,
she was going through a lot of effort to open the can of juice with the gloves on.
All she'd have to do would be take off her glove.
But she didn't, which told me she was hiding something.
Well, that's when I found out her motive for killing Heath, too.
Motive?
Lila and Akane had pictures on their mirrors, right?
They were alone with Heath on them.
But in Rose's pictures...
Angel.
Just pictures of Heath dressed as an angel.
She wasn't actually in love with him,
but with his role as an angel.
Yeah. That's why I sealed his life while he was Michael.
I couldn't stand the idea of another man playing him.
I couldn't allow it!
But he was only leaving the role because he got a part in a movie...
But it was his choice.
He killed Michael.
When I told him I loved the angel he was playing!
But I was blessed by God, anyway.
Since He saved me when my dress got caught on a nail and the armor fell.
Thank you, sweet angel...
You helped me do it...
All right, Shin-chan,
I have to drop by the police for some questioning.
Get a taxi and check into the hotel for us.
No prob.
Oh, and watch out for that serial killer.
He's a Japanese guy with long hair.
Yeah, yeah.
Later, Shin-chan!
Geez. Everyone still treats me like a kid,
even though I'm in high school.
Oh, well. It's like Holmes said.
"If we went round the moon,
it would not make a pennyworth of difference to me or to my work!"
What's wrong, Ran?
Don't tell me you're like that over what Rose said.
You understood what she said?
She was speaking English so quickly I couldn't understand it.
Nothing important, wasn't much.
Also, close your window or you'll catch a cold.
Didn't you say you felt feverish?
I'm fine now.
And if I closed the window, I couldn't see the lights of New York.
But if the rain gets in here and wets the seats, the cabbie's gonna get angry.
Don't worry. I'll wipe the seat with my handkerchief before leaving.
Oh geez.
Excuse me, please stop.
Stop, please!
Strange...
I could've sworn it'd fallen here.
Was it blown away by the wind?
Forget about it.
Isn't it just a handkerchief, anyway?
It's not just a handkerchief!
It's very important, Sharon gave it to me!
I knew it, there's no such thing as God.
Isn't that it?
Look, the white thing in those stairs.
Seems to be an abandoned building.
I'll be right back.
Wait for me in the taxi, Ran.
If God existed, this wouldn't have happened.
Thank you, sweet angel...
You helped me do it...
Could Sharon have known...?
That Rose was going to commit murder, and that I'd saved a murderer...?
What now?
It's all my fault.
If I hadn't saved her back then, Heath would still be...
It's all my fault!
It's all my...
A long-haired...
Japanese man...
A gun...
No...
My body won't move...
Hey! Hurry up. Jump in!!
He must be the serial killer, come on!!
Shit!
Wait!
Are you Japanese?
I asked, "Are you Japanese?"
Yes.
Have you seen a suspicious man?
A Japanese man with long silvery hair and a beard.
No...
I haven't seen anyone.
Did you find him, sir?
No... I found only a tourist.
I guess he hasn't been to this street.
The gunfight against us excited the beast.
He couldn't have gone without catching her.
Anyway, this place is dangerous.
Take a right in this corner and you should get to the main street.
You can take a taxi from there.
Wait...
I'm waiting for a friend.
He's a boy my age.
Then I'll tell you and your friend this yet again.
Get out of here!
Get out of this area, right now!
Can we leave her alone?
No problem.
Every crossing to this street is already secured.
Then it's true.
The serial killer's here.
Hurry, Shin'ichi, we have to run!
Shin'ichi?
Hey...
What was that?
I just saw something red...
Blood!
Could it be Shin'ichi's...?
What happened here?
What happened to Shin'ichi?
Shin'ichi!
Oh no, my cold's back.
Come on, Ran! Gotta hold on for a bit more...
It's your fault Shin'ichi went to get that handkerchief!
Right... It's all... it's all my fault.
It's all my...
Somebody's coming!
Shin'ichi?
Si... Silver hair?
Blood...
Get away, Ran!
He's that serial killer everybody's talking about!
That's right, little girl.
I was hiding out here, but that kid found me.
If you want to blame someone, blame God for putting you in this position.
What are you doing?
Quick, grab my arm!
Quick, the rain's...
Shin'ichi...
Damn, you really are trouble.
Why?
Why did you save me?
I don't understand it.
Do you need a reason?
I don't know what can lead a person to kill another...
But for a person to save another...
...you don't really need a logical reason, do you?
I see...
He's right, isn't he?
I should've realised earlier...
Really...
I'm...
Hey, Ran!
Stop that.
You're injured, so the cops are nearby.
If you shoot us without a silencer, you'll get caught.
Similarly, I can't do anything to catch you.
I'll let you go for now.
I'll catch you next time we meet.
I'll find all the proof necessary to send you to Hell.
I'll make sure you're put away.
Yeah, didn't you see it in the news on TV?
They found the serial killer.
Shin-chan reported him.
But when the police got there,
he'd already killed himself with his own gun...
Oh, Ran-chan's fine.
She had a fever last night,
but after getting some rest, she's much better.
She's pretty much forgotten about what happened yesterday.
Hey, Sharon...
Did you know?
That Rose was going to do something like that?
Yes. I've always had a sixth sense for these things.
But I had no idea she was going to kill someone.
By the way, can you give Ran-chan a message from me?
She was right. There is an angel watching over me.
Oh, did something good happen to you?
Sort of.
You're not having a relapse from the cold, are you?
No, I'm fine.
Let me just check your temperature...
I told you I'm fine...
It's true! Her fever's gone down, just like the doctor said.
You're awake, Ran!
He said your fever was caused by exhaustion.
I guess you'll have to go easy on the studying and extra-curricular activities now!
By the way, you were muttering funny stuff during your fever.
Something about saving people and logical reasons...
No! Those words are my...
That's right! Those words are precious to me!
I don't want to hear them coming out of you!
What's that supposed to mean?
Anyway, I'll be taking you home tomorrow.
Try to get a good night's sleep!
Sleep tight, Ran-neechan!
I see...
I'd forgotten all about that day.
That was the day.
The day I knew.
About Shin'ichi...
How could I have forgotten something so important?
I guess all the bad memories stopped me from remembering the good parts.
I went through so much and met so many people...
That's right...
The man in the black knit cap was there too. Who was he?
FBI?
So you were in bed because of a fever.
That explains why you didn't answer the text I sent you.
You were worried about me, Shin'ichi?
I was worried your phone might've gotten shut off.
What's that supposed to mean?!
So you're feeling okay now?
I'm perfectly fine.
Because of the cold, I remembered what happened in New York.
Oh, that was a horrible case...
Are you okay, though? That case left you feeling really bummed-out.
I'm fine.
I remembered some good things too.
By the way, whatever happened to Sharon's handkerchief?
Remember? You went into the abandoned building to get it for me?
Oh, that?
I have it.
Uh oh. I wonder where I put it...
Two murders happened that day...
I didn't want to bring back those memories, so I put it away.
Two murders? I thought the serial killer committed suicide.
Yes, that's what the police report said.
The blood stains and fingerprints that should have been there had been wiped clean.
If you were going to kill yourself, would you go through all the trouble of covering your tracks?
I'm pretty sure somebody shot him just before he was going to make his getaway.
Somebody got to him before the police arrived...
Since he brought a day's worth of food and his wallet, that means...
Don't worry.
With the Tracking Glasses, we should be able to find him soon.
Officer Yamamura from the Gunma Police?
The guy I met in Osaka is in this forest?
Next Conan: Mitsuhiko's Mystifying Forest (Part 1)