Love and hate are brought together...
Through both reasoning and suspense!
It's the first Detective Boys episode in a while!
Mitsuhiko's acting kind of strange.
Seeing through to the one and only truth...
I look like a child, but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
First, let's raise our arms way up high and stretch our backs!
All right!
One,
Five,
Five, six.
Now, move them in a swinging motion!
One,
One, two,
One, two, three...
Four,
Four, five,
Four, five, six, seven,
Four, five, six, seven, eight.
Jeez...
One,
I really can't believe we're spending summer vacation doing these exercises with the 5th graders...
One, two,
One, two, three,
One, two, three, four...
Five,
Five, six.
Arms in circles!
What am I doing here?
Keep going!
You're doing great!
Five,
Five, six,
Five, six, seven,
Five, six, seven, eight.
Mitsuhiko's Mystifying Forest:
Part 1!
To the left.
Hey, Conan. Do it properly.
Radio exercising is an important symbol of summer, you know?
Symbol of summer, huh?
Yes, yes.
If you don't exercise properly, you'll regret it when you're older.
High blood pressure, diabetes, high cholesterol.
You could even get cardiovascular disorders or ischemic heart disease.
One, two, three, four!
Well, it's true that it will be good for the Professor.
What's this about a "newspaper of summer"?
The symbol of summer.
It makes you feel like summer is here!
Don't you remember the professor talking about it on our way home from the fireworks?
There aren't that many symbols of summer in the city anymore.
Fireworks and radio exercising are some of the few symbols that haven't disappeared over the years.
Speaking of disappearing...
Tsuburaya-kun isn't here today, either.
I wonder what happened to Mitsuhiko-kun...
He hasn't come for the past few days.
He probably overslept and decided to ditch.
That's odd.
Unlike Genta, who's loose about time, Mitsuhiko is the type who always comes early.
That's right.
Loose?
How am I wrinkly?
Those are loose socks!
Then why don't we all go to Mitsuhiko-kun's house later to check on him?
He might have a summer cold or something.
Yeah, let's do that.
Huh? Mit-chan didn't go?
That's weird...
He said he was going camping with everyone after radio exercising.
Camping?
Yes. He was packing up last night, and seemed really excited about going.
He was putting some sasa-dango in his backpack, and was planning to share it with everyone.
Note: Sasa-dango is a Japanese rice cake wrapped in bamboo leaves.
Sasa-dango?
Yeah! A kind lady next door gave us a whole bunch!
But I guess you aren't going camping?
Eh? Well, yes...
Since you're Mitsuhiko-kun's sister, do you have any idea where he might be?
Any secret hiding places or any place like that?
I don't know. Mit-chan is usually hanging out with you guys.
Oh, I know!
Do you want to look inside Mit-chan's room?
He usually leaves a note there when he goes somewhere.
Huh?
That's strange.
I guess he didn't leave a note, after all...
His wallet is missing, too.
His wallet?
Since he brought a day's worth of food and his wallet, that means...
He must have gone somewhere far away.
H-Hey, you aren't suggesting...
There's a possibility that he ran away.
Ran away!?
Eh, oh my gosh, seriously?!
This is just like a TV drama!
Why are you so happy?
Well, even if he didn't run away, he was definitely planning something.
Look. Mitsuhiko's radio exercise stamp card shows he only skipped on Sundays.
You're right.
Does he have something to do on sunday?
Maybe he's going on a date with someone!
No way...
Date?
Oh yeah, Mit-chan talked about some older girl...
She helps out in her parents' flower shop on Sundays.
I remember him telling me that middle-school girl said he was "very cool."
Could it be that she invited Mit-chan to go to the beach with her?
Why the beach?
When he was packing last night, he came and asked to borrow my sunscreen.
I went online and ordered this awesome sunscreen from overseas!
But...
The Mitsuhiko-kun that we know...
With a girl...
At the beach?
Eating sasa-dango.
There's no way...
Asami-san, may a have a minute?
If you don't hurry, you'll miss your piano lesson!
I'll be right there, Mother!
Note: She addresses her mother politely as "Okaa-sama" instead of the usual "Okaa-san."
My parents are both school teachers, so they're really strict about speaking politely.
No wonder Mitsuhiko always acts so formally.
Well then, if you get any juicy information, call me on my cell phone, okay?
I want to know about Mit-chan's love life too!
Her brother is missing, yet she doesn't seem to be worried.
Kind of unusual, isn't it?
Sure is.
Eh? Mitsuhiko?
Oh! You mean that Tsuburaya Mitsuhiko-kun, don't you?
He didn't come today.
Not even at 6:30 in the morning?
This shop opens at 7:00 AM, and I was radio exercising at that time, so I don't know.
Oh, yeah...
But I saw him standing at a bus stop last Sunday on my way to radio exercising.
Some old guys were yelling at him.
Yelling at him?
Yeah. They were saying things like
"I can't tell you," and "you can't have it."
What did they mean by that?
Can't have what?
I don't know.
He was saying the names of some ancient warlords.
Let's see...
Uesugi and Takeda?
No...
Was it Toyotomi and Tokugawa?
T-Tokugawa?
Could it be that he found Tokugawa's buried treasure?!
Note: They are referring to an urban myth about members of the Tokugawa Shogunate burying many historical Shogun-ora artifacts.
It's probably hidden at some beach!
And so Mitsuhiko-kun went to look for it!
Darn that Mitsuhiko! He should've invited us!
And, it's starting all over again...
Is Tsuburaya-kun missing?
Yes. He seems to have gone somewhere this morning.
Then maybe that kid I saw this morning was him.
I saw a boy at the bus stop.
A hat was covering his face and he was carrying a backpack.
He smelled strange for a boy, too.
He looked like Tsuburaya-kun, so I called out to him...
But he ignored me and got on the bus.
A strange smell? What did he smell like?
Well, it wasn't exactly strange...
I'm pretty sure it was a lemon citrus smell.
A lemon smell?
Oh yeah, I remember him!
The boy with the hat that smelled like lemons, right?
Was he a runaway, as I thought?
Uh, no, we're not sure.
Usually, kids like to look out the bus windows to view the scenery.
But that boy just sat at the back of the bus and stared straight forward with a serious face.
He seemed scared and acted like he was hiding from something.
A serious face?
Hiding from something?
He ran away! Mitsuhiko really did run away!
Calm down.
Hey, do you know where he got off?
Hmm, I think it was...
Beika Station?
A boy that smelled like lemons?
Was there a kid like that?
He was wearing a hat and had a backpack on.
Ah, could you be asking about that one kid?
You know, the one who bought an adult ticket by mistake.
Oh, the one who was in a hurry to change tickets.
He was in a hurry?
Yeah, it was almost like he was being chased by someone.
Do you know which train he got on, or where he went?
Hmm, well...
It was 1900 yen ($21 USD) for an adult ticket...
The only places that would cost that much are the Chiba Prefecture...
Or even the Gunma Prefecture.
No luck.
None of the station workers saw him.
So that means he's probably transferred trains already.
This is this train's last stop.
Yeah, he was here
Really?
Yay!
Unlike the city, we don't have automated ticket barriers.
Since we have to check each one by hand, I wouldn't forget a boy like him.
He got off last and seemed to be hiding from something.
It looked like he was headed towards the mountains.
Well, well.
With the information about the scent of lemons, the hat, and the backpack, we made it to the mountains.
The sun's starting to set.
Hey, hey, wait a minute.
There's nothing here...
How are we going to find him.
Don't worry.
See? Mitsuhiko's detective badge is responding.
He's definitely somewhere in this area.
Thank goodness.
Hold on... If Mitsuhiko has his badge, why don't you call him?
I've been trying, but he's not responding.
Well, with these glasses we should be able to find him soon.
But doesn't it make you wonder?
What is it that made Tsuburaya-kun, the serious and considerate one...
...turn his back on us for the first time and travel this far into the mountains?
D-Do you think he really ran away?
Now, now, cheer up.
He's probably got a good reason.
Maybe he fell in love with a girl he saw and chased her here.
Love can make a person do some crazy things.
Fell in love?
You know what they say...
"First love tastes like lemons!"
Let's go, guys.
We need to find him before it gets dark.
H-H-Hey!
It looks like he's somewhere in this forest.
And? You still can't get in contact with him?
Yeah.
Mitsuhiko's probably not answering because he hears the tracker's beeping.
Hey, there's a big crowd of people over there!
Then, let's ask if they saw Mitsuhiko-kun!
Wait here. I'll go ask them.
Everyone stay here and—
Hey! Wait!
You don't know if they are dangerous or not!
Hey! You bunch of old guys over there!
Officer Yamamura from the Gunma Police...?
Oh? Aren't you the kid who's always with Detective Mouri?
What are you doing all the way out here?
W-What, you ask?
Hello.
No time for small talk.
This place is dangerous!
I have to ask you to leave this place immediately!
Dangerous? Are there bears around here?
A man way more scary than a bear is hiding in this forest.
A man?
Well, actually...
And I don't want him to hear me say this...
But one of the elder officers wasn't paying attention, and let him escape.
The serial killer, Numabuchi Kiichiro.
W-What?>
That can't be!
Come now, and no sudden moves.
Hey!
Hey, are you all right?
Get the hell out of my way!
The guy I met in Osaka is in this forest?
That's why you need to leave quickly.
But in this forest...
Hey, Conan.
We have to hurry and tell Mitsuhiko-kun about this, or else...
Damn it! Why aren't you answering, Mitsuhiko?
A child is in this forest!?
In this forest, where there's a murderer on the loose?!
Yes, that's right.
Why didn't you keep an eye on him?
You brought him here, didn't you?
No, I didn't...
Mitsuhiko came here on his own without even telling us.
And then, we got a whole bunch of information from the train station workers that led us here.
We ended up in this forest, thanks to the transmitter in his Detective Badge showing his location.
I used my Tracking Glasses.
A "Detective Badge"...
And "Tracking Glasses"?
When I was a kid, my parents bought me gimmicky little detective toys like that too!
Like a magic invisible ink pen and a magical playing card that turns into smoke when you rub it.
And a memopad that melts in water.
But one day, I asked myself...
How do these gimmicks help investigations in real life?
You know?
Now then, if your information concerning the whereabouts of that boy is based on some silly detective toys...
Go play somewhere else!
Uh, no, those aren't toys...
They're really for real!
We're absolutely sure Mitsuhiko is in this forest!
Fine, then show them to me...
These so-called "Tracking Glasses" of yours.
See? All you have to do is press this button on the rim.
Crap! Out of batteries?
Told you so!
They look like an ordinary pair of glasses to me.
Uh, it's out of batteries.
What?
Hey, Yamamura! What are you doing?
C'mon, we gotta find Numabuchi!
But these children...
It's your fault Numabuchi got away!
So take this seriously, man!
Um, actually it was you who...
Anyway, take the children to a safe place and then come back to help look for him.
Yes, sir!
Honestly now...
The murderer got away because Senpai had to pee and left his post.
I thought he was next to me, so I wasn't paying attention.
So it was your fault, after all.
I-If you want to put it that way.
Oh, brother.
Hey, Mitsuhiko!
Where are you?!
Stop hiding and come out
Hey!
How much longer do you intend to scream your lungs out?
I bet that boy already went home.
You should go home, too.
If it gets any darker, you'll get lost even if you know this place well.
We're not scared of the dark!
We have these!
He, they sell really convenient things these days.
We didn't buy these.
The Professor made them for us.
Professor? Made them?
Yes, I invented them for the children.
Along with the Detective Badges and Tracking Glasses that we were talking about earlier.
S-So, wait a second...
Could it be... that you were telling the truth about a child being lost in this forest?
Of course it's true.
That's what we've been trying to tell you all along.
Then, why didn't you tell one of the elder officers?!
We told you.
Anyway, I have to inform Senpai of this immediately.
Shoot! I left my cell phone back in the patrol car!
I'm a failure.
First, I let a criminal escape.
Then, I fail to tell the others about a lost boy. I'm gonna lose my job for sure...
I wanted to be a policeman ever since I saw a police drama on TV when I was little.
Now that my dreams have finally come true, I guess I'm not fit for this role...
As an officer...
That's not true!
It's okay, you don't have to try to comfort me...
But Officer-san, you've solved so many cases before!
The case with Yabuuchi-san...
The case with the lawyers in Karuizawa...
And the one in the Kashiragami forest!
You've helped everyone so much!
Is that true, Conan?
Wow!
R-Really?
Well, it was actually my dad or I who solved those cases.
Now that I think about it, your wide forehead even makes you look really smart!
You're the epitome of an intelligent policeman.
You think so?
Officer Yamamura, cheer up and let's look for him. We'll rely on you since you're familiar with this forest.
No, Agasa-san.
From now on...
Please call me Yama-san.
Yama-san?
He's definitely watched too many police dramas.
It's beeping again.
It must be Conan-kun!
As I thought, Conan-kun and the others came to look for me!
But if I answer the badge now, this whole trip would become a waste.
No. I definitely won't let that happen.
There's a chance that Numabuchi Kiichiro has already killed him...
What?!
Hey, Ai-kun...
Well, isn't it possible?
After all, he committed three murders in three consecutive days.
Hey, Mitsuhiko!
Where are you?!
If you can hear my voice, answer me!
This forest is dangerous!
There's a serial killer on the loose!
Next Conan: Mitsuhiko's Mystifying Forest, Part 2.
Please look forward to the next episode!
When are you coming back, Mitsuhiko-kun?!
Think about your situation a little, Tsubura-kun.