The distance between love and hate is
filled as the two solve mysteries together.
Lost in the forest
with a cold blooded killer.
Everyone's emotions shine brightly.
He sees through the one and only truth,
a child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult,
No case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
- - Faia .
>Ummer vaca ion is) ere
0 Mitsuhiko has skipped the morning
exercises and everyone is worried
SO we go his house to check up on hm
but according to his sister Asama.
He told her he was going camping with us
and he packed his backpack with
sasadango and sun screen
then snuck out of the house
early in the morning
thinking it suspicious,
we start to ask around about him.
We finally track him to
a forest in Gunma Prefecture
I try many times to contact him on his
detective badge but he doesn't respond
and while we're trying to
figure out what to do.
We run into Detective Yamamura
of the Gunma Prefecture Police
The truths.
I can't say this out loud but.
That veteran officer let a criminal escape
during the crime scene investigation,
it's that serial killer... Kiichiro Numabucht
A. are you serious!
That killer we met in Osaka is
here in this forest...
That's why you've got to hurry and
B. but one of their friends is
somewhere in here...
Come on Conan
We've got to let Mitsuhiko know
about this right away
Rats! Why aren't you
answering. Mitsuhiko?
It's beeping again, it must be Conan,
I knew they'd come look for me!
But if I answer them now...
all my effort would have been in vain
(13 ha)
MITSUHIKO LOST IN THE WOODS
PART II
Still no answer from Mitsuhiko?
No...
Maybe he fell asleep some place?
Or maybe Numabuchi's already got him...
Hey don't say that kind of stuff...
It's not completely impossible, you know
The man hiding out in these
woods is a cold blooded killer,
he went on a three day killing spree...
How do you know all that?
There was a big article
In the newspaper about it...
He murdered three people.
It's four people.
During the interrogation, he
admitted killing four people
He said he buried the
fourth victim here in this forest
his mother is from this area...
So he was brought here from Osaka and
we were inspecting the
crime scene since this morning...
but he couldn't remember
where he buried the body
so we had to dig and dug
but we couldn't find it...
The detectives from Osaka
Ieft Numabuchi in our charge
and left to buy lunch,
that's when it happened
You let him escape...
I'll bet he was planning
his escape all along!
But he didn't act like he intended to...
He was telling us about how
he'd always come to this forest
to play when his mother
came Oo VISI er amily...
Eh? What happened?
It's so cold!
It's a river.
Hey. you alright?
Yes...ll just got a little scratched.
Don't worry, you'll be fine.
The water that flows through this forest
IS clean, when we were kids,
we used to drink from this river...
Yessir...my friends and I used to
play here a lot when we were kids
that's why I had an easy
time talking to Numabuchi
And you let him get away,
you're a sorry excuse for a cop
What a mess...we don't
have a single clue,
how can we find him,
even I don't know where to start
Well, uh...l don't know
if this will help. but...
You have three clues!
A lemony smell...
The names of the generals .
And the sasadango!
What are you talking'about?
Mitsuhiko got scolded by
some strange men
for mentioning the names
of those generals,
he packed his backpack with sasadango
and came here smelling like lemons
Nothing you're saying makes any sense
But the lemon scent is a sure clue!
The smell's probably
from lemon grass or citronella,
it's a common ingredient
In insect repellant!
Insect repellant?
Bug spray!
Remember what his sister Asami said
She said Mitsuhiko took the sun screen
she'd bought on the
shop channel, with him!
You don't see it in Japan
but in some foreign countries,
they sell insect repellant
that doubles as sun screen
I see... Mitsuhiko applied the cream not
to protect himself against the sun,
it was to keep the bugs away...
Which means he meant to come
here from the very beginning.
But why? I don't understand
the sasadango or the generals' names...
Kibidango" would point to Momotaro...
Nu. Nu, Numabuchi!
Rats! I'll get him!
Wait! He knows this forest
and besides, it's too dark!
We'll get lost if we go after him!
Our first objective is to find Mitsuhiko!
Right!
I didn't feel it just now...
I didn't feel a thing...
but why?
Amazing. he was hiding out
Na ree, '\es I ea mon ey...
Yes, he is...
when he was a child...
he told me he used to
jump from tree to tree.
He said he pretended
he was learning to be a ninja.
A ninja?
No. it couldn't be... he!
Doctor! Look after everyone!
Co. Conan.
Don't worry. I'll bring Mitsuhiko
back with me, just you wait!
It's NO use...
I can't go any further...
I should just give up, contact Conan and
the others and let them know where I am
Hey. Mitsuhiko!
That's Conan's voice!
I'm over here!
Over here! Conan!
Conan...
Wh. who are you?
Guess we're the same...
You and I...
we're the same.
Hey Mitsuhiko!
Where are you!
If you can hear my voice.
Pick up your detective
badge and answer me!
It's dangerous in this forest!
There's a killer on the loose in here!
Give up what you're doing
and answer me!
Mitsuhiko!
Rats! Where are you...
If my theory's right...
he's somewhere along this river
Is, is it possible...
he's already come across that guy
What's this?
You're the kid that was talking to
Yamamura just a little while ago...
D. detective...
Didn't you leave this
forest with Yamamura?
But...l think my friend's
Iost some place around here
Your friend?
Uh. Sir!
Sir. so here you are!
Hey! Why didn't you report
that a child was lost around here?
Well, uh, so many things
were happening all at once.
And by the way, sir! Big news!
What?
Kiichiro Numabuchi's been located!
Really?
Are you sure?
And? So where is he?
Has he been captured?
Aw come on...
you know I can't capture him all by
myself he got away from me so easily
So tell me, where was he hiding?
On top of a tree
He climbed up the tree like a monkey
when our eyes met, he
jumped down and ran away!
And he ran off into the forest!
Isn't that right. Yama-san?
Yama-san?
And then Conan said
he'd go after him all by himself
I wasn't chasing him! I just had a
idea where Mitsuhiko might be.
He's somewhere along this river!
Along the river?
What's along the river?
Are you talking about the treasure?
No. I just assumed that's where'd he be
Conan's right. it looks like
he was by this river
but I don't think we
should go by that theory anymore
See. this is the cap I borrowed from
Mitsuhiko at the last soccer game
he didn't stop to pick it
up after he dropped it,
which means he was in a big hurry...
You mean, Mitsuhiko's...
That bad man's caught him and...
We've got to find him!
Okay. We've got to be careful, that
boy might be his hostage,
relay this message to the others!
Yes sir!
This is terrible, if Mitsuhiko's
running away, how do we find him...
Well... he couldn't have gotten too far
The perspiration on the
cap's not dry yet, and it's still warm
But Conan, you were yelling
to him, weren't you?
Why didn't he answer you?
He probably couldn't...
Mitsuhiko probably
arrived here just before noon
we had to ask around so
we got here in the evening.
If Mitsuhiko got lost and
was calling for help all that time
I'm sure his voice would be hoarse by
now. he wouldn't be able to call out
Th, that's terrible...
But he's got the detective badge,
he doesn't need to talk so loud
I know. if he contacted us with the badge
we'd have been able to
find him right away
But that's if he could use his hands!
What?
Are you saying he's hurt his hands?
Calm down now, don't get
so excited. let's find him first!
If he's around here, I think
we should start looking already...
But Mitsuhiko can't talk, and maybe
he's been captured by that bad man,
right? How're we going to find him?
Then let's go look for that killer!
But it's so dark
and I didn't get
a really good look at his face!
Let's see, according to the
news, Numabuchi's characteristics are...
His thin eyebrows. sunken eyes
hollow cheeks, upturned nose, his
face is skeletal, just skin and bones
his postures bad but
he's agile and fast, like an animal.
Then all we've got to do is look for
somebody who looks like a skeleton!
Guess so...
B. but Al. how
do you know so much about him.
Hey. you don't mean. Numabuchi's...
Yup. That's right...
Kiichiro Numabuchi,
was once a part of that group...
he was once one of
your so called Men in Black...
but then he was just one
of the small potatoes...
the organization hired
him because he was agile,
I think they intended to train him
to become one of their hit men...
But he turned out to be useless so
they were going to send him to me
so I could use him as
a guinea pig. to test my potions
Are you serious?
That's why I know him so well...
Before he became a test subject
they sent me his file, complete with
photos and personal data...
He escaped before being sent to me and
since I dropped out of the organization,
we never did get to meet though...
He escaped?
I guess he got scared. He realized
how big the organization was...
and so he ran and
kept running from their influence,
poor guy. he killed three people because
he thought they were from the
organization and they were after him...
But then I feel no
sympathy towards him because
because I heard he killed some people
for fun before joining the organization.
I remember when he got arrested.
he yelled into the television cameras
It's their fault!
Yes. but no one believed him and since
he wasn't deeply involved with them
the organization
washed their hands of him...
But I don't understand...
Didn't you tell me once that you could tell
when someone from the organization
was around because of their smell...
That's right, that's why I'm worried,
I didn't feel anything back there.
My sister gave off a
smell even before that incident
that was my only danger barometer...
I must be losing it, I'm getting too
accustomed to this normal life...
I guess I'm getting soft...
Good for you!
What?
That proves you're becoming
a normal human being, right?
Come on! We've got to
hurry and find Mitsuhiko!
His probably dying to see the smiles on
you and Ayumi's normal faces!
Me and Ayumi's?
Yeah, because the reason he
came here in the first place is
Listen, don't you hear that?
That sounds like the detective badge...
It's getting louder!
It's getting closer!
Hey Mitsuhi...
Nu...Numabuchi!
Kiichiro Numabuchi!
I, I've got you!
Turn all those lights off!
Those lights are going to scare them off!
Them?
What do you mean,
are you saying your gang's here too?
That's right, be careful,
cause there's a whole bunch of them!
We're not falling for that one!
Good grief! We were so worried!
You sound bad...
I see your badge is working...
Why didn't you respond to our call?
I know but...
My hands...
What's the matter!
You're hurt or something?
A firefly?
Yes, a summer
spectacle not seen in the city
The old men who were scolding
Mitsuhiko at the bus stop were probably
the conservation group who come to this
forest every Sunday to protect the firefly
Mitsuhiko probably asked them for the
Iocation of this forest so many times
they were afraid a lot of children would
come and trample through the forest
they'd worked so hard to clean
ip. that's why they got angry.
Because fireflies only live in clean water
But Mitsuhiko was desperate,
he had to find this place
so he followed them.
"See."...
That's why he was acting so suspiciously
on the bus, he was following them
Yes. he inadvertently pressed the same
button they did when buying the ticket
at the train station,
that's why he bought the adult ticket
But this doesn't have anything
to do with any General's name!
Remember, what the girl
at the florist said?
She said it was either Uesugi and
Takeda or Toyotomi and Tokugawa
either way. they're rival generals. right?
And another group of famous
rival generals would be, Genji and Heike
Which brings us:to Genj)
fireflies and Heike fireflies!
What about the sasadango then?
He'd moisten the
sasa leaves then spread them
out in the bug container
making a firefly holder
He was going to put the fireflies inside
and bring them back with him
Mitsuhiko did indeed manage to catch
some fireflies but then he got lost...
His badge started to beep
and he knew we were here
Iooking for him but he
couldn't use his hands
Isn't that right. Mitsuhiko?
Oh brother, If you were coming to
catch bugs, you should've told us!
Don't be stupid!
He wouldn't have been able to
surprise them unless he kept it a secret...
On the way home after the fireworks
display, Ayumi and Al said
they'd like to see fireflies
at least once in their life!
Eh? You mean he...
He did for us...
Thank you!
It was beautiful!
But why'd Numabuchi...
He knew he'd be caught. so why'd
he bring Mitsuhiko to us?
Who knows...
Maybe it's because he came here for
the same reason Mitsuhiko did...
What do you mean?
He was in the tree listening to us,
he probably figured out that a kid would
come into the forest looking for fireflies
and once he saw Mitsuhiko had his
hands full, he'd know for sure...
He probably lied about burying
the fourth victim here,
he probably wanted to see them one
more time before being executed...
See the old friends he used to play
with here when he was a child...
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MIGHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUQ ONO
sharact r Designs By
Cov .
Story Editor.
JUNICHI I10OKA
Scripts By
KANIFKASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUGHI
JUYICHIMIYASHIIA
YUICHI HIGURE
I SHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chroet-Director.
KEN] KODAWIA
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD.
Ry a ssBCra tron with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CONAN
OVID AOYAMA HOGAKUKAN-YIV- IMS
All Ri} Reserved
Hey Ai, didu ou see
the news on TV yesterday?
There's so much excitement
about a great discovery!
Oh really, did they find Tokugawa's
hidden treasure or something?
Of course not! It's a legendary
animal'OmSomebody-stseen-it:
I forget what it's called. .it wasn't
takenoko and its not "kananoko
Tsuchinoko?
Yes. that's it!
I don't know what kind of animal it is
since they switched to another subject
but wouldn't you like to see one too. Au?
I guess so.
Tsul
Tsuchinoko...
If my memory serves me right,
there's been sightings in Gifu Prefecture I
as well as Okayama
Prefecture and Hyogo Prefecture
IYjust remembered, I'm going to
go visit my uncle in Gifu soon...
Ana! I bet you're thinking of finding
one so you can look good!
And what's wrong with that!
Wouldn't dot if I were you.
The Princess sleeps...
NANBHLHUtn A...
I wonder what's keeping Mr Taira...
Ms Taira!
Ms. Taira!
Ms. Taira...
Princess: of the Isolated Island and
the-Palace-of the-Dragon«King-Part-Il