Two people's deductions and suspense
fill the gulf between love and hate!
Summer! The sea! An island in the south!
The entrance to a case is written in the sand!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
'Kay, what about the chick over there with the short light hair?
Hm. She's letting her roots show, so she doesn't care much about her looks.
I say a modest one-piece swimsuit.
Nah. She's a little on the chubby side,
so she's wearin' a black bikini that makes her look thinner.
See, what'd I tell ya? I win again!
You sure suck at these kinds of deductions.
Back off.
What're ya two talkin' about?
K-Kazuha!
Ran-neechan!
Playin' "guess the swimsuit" with a grade-school kid...
I bet your mom an' dad would just love to hear about this one.
It ain't my fault! The kid begged me to play! I just went along!
Heiji-niichan's on a roll today!
He guessed you'd be wearing a swimsuit with tiger stripes!
Z-Zip it!
T-Tiger stripes?
Do these look like tiger stripes to you?
They're zebra stripes! Zebra!
Tiger, zebra, same difference.
The only stripes that matter in Osaka are tiger stripes!
I-I guess so...
Kazuha...
Don't tell me you're still mad at me for keepin' ya waitin' at Big Man in Umeda!
What're ya talkin' about?
Would I get mad just 'cause some loser left me hangin' for four hours?
I ain't mad at all! Not even a little bit!
S-She's mad.
Well, can't blame her.
Well, Hattori-kun invited you to Okinawa to make up for that!
Heiji didn't invite me on this trip!
I came here with your ol' man, Ran-chan!
With Sleepin' Kogoro-san!
It's tomorrow, right? The battle between the great detectives of the east and west?
How confident are you?
Confident?
I don't have any confidence at all.
All I know is that Kogoro Mouri will never lose to a rookie punk from Osaka.
That I'm sure about!
That ol' dope...
Staff! Gather 'round! Rehearsal starts now!
Rehearsal?
Yeah. We're making a run to the island you and Detective Mouri will be visiting tomorrow!
Masao Taketomi (42)
TV Director
That deserted island where the corpse and message were discovered.
Want to join us, sleuth of the west?
Well...
It ain't fair to get a headstart.
But it'll tick me off if Kudo helps the ol' man solve the mystery ahead of me...
Sure! I'll tag along!
Hey!
T-That's fine...
What are you talking about?
We're gonna put our heads together and solve the case right now,
an' prove to the audience once an' for all that Tokyo folks ain't got nothin' on Osakans!
I'm from Tokyo, you know...
There it is!
Funaura Island, where they found the unidentified body!
Locals call it Onigame—"Demon Turtle"!
Onigame Island?
Check it out!
The tip of the island looks like a turtle's head!
So? Why'd you agree to this deduction match against the old man?
It's a plan for revivin' the islands.
Kaneshiro, the mayor, said they've had serious trouble with crime, like kidnappings an' robberies.
The tourist trade's dried up, so now they're tryin' to improve their image with this TV special!
The mayor runs both the islands here.
I don't think footage of a dead body is going to improve their image with tourists.
Anyhow, the only professional TV guy here is Taketomi-san.
The rest of the film crew's just locals who know the sea an' the islands.
Where are you from?
Tokyo?
T-That's right.
I'm from Osaka!
Why don't we go for a swim together after the shoot tomorrow?
Yoshitsugu Kume (25)
Crew
Noburo Ikema (24)
We live here, so we know some great spots!
No way, no way, no way!
These chicks're booked today, tomorrow an' the day after!
Unlike you guys, we ain't got time to splash around the water
wearin' penguin flippers an' tubes in our mouths, so scram!
Who the hell are you?
That kid your girlfriend or something?
No! She's my...
His what?
My loud-mouthed, no-good childhood friend I barely know.
So hands off!
That didn't come out quite right.
So who are you?
What're you doing on this boat? You're not on the crew, are you?
Heiji Hattori, the sleuth of the west.
Yoshie Taira (26)
Crew
He's one of our featured guests, Kogoro Mouri's opponent.
This guy?
But he's just a kid!
That's what makes it a great story!
The rookie teen detective challenging Kogoro Mouri!
Hey, that dork challenged me!
Whatever. Let's get this over with and head back.
Mikihiko Daito (47)
Crew
They say the emissary of Gusō comes for your mabui after the sun sets 'round here...
Right, Captain?
Takashi Shimoji (38)
Crew
The emissary of Gusō?
Comes for your mabui?
Gusō means the afterlife, and mabui is your soul.
It's an old Okinawan folktale.
If a woman is up working late at night...
An emissary of the underworld dressed all in white will rise out of the water to suck her soul away...
Don't remind me!
I was planning to take a swim once I got to the island!
White...
I bet that gal's wearin' a high-cut white swimsuit!
You don't say.
Hey, captain! Don't make so many waves!
Try a black wetsuit.
Huh. That's funny.
I heard the sea around this island is...
Heiji!
The director's calling you!
Better get to work!
Uh... Yeah...
Hm...
"The princess sleeps in the kō and not in the otsu."
They found the body in front of this pillar?
That's right.
The corpse was leaning here with its back to the carving.
It was a year ago. The man had died from lack or food or water.
Around that time, a series of huge typhoons swept this area,
so the locals think he was from the crew of a boat that sank near here.
But this strange carving...
Hey...
Who built a house on this deserted island?
Kaneshiro-san, the mayor.
It used to be rented out as a vacation cottage.
But it got torn apart by the typhoon.
They only recently fixed it.
I knew it! White!
Yeah, it looked completely different last time I was here.
I feel like Urashima Taro.
Last time... Do you come here often?
Yeah.
Until about two years ago, I used to watch this island from my ship.
This area's a great place to catch amberstripe scad.
Amberstripe scad?
You guys know this place too, right?
Yeah. There's a great diving spot a little past the island.
But after they found the body,
a lot of our friends stopped coming.
They said it was too creepy.
Okay! I'll be here discussing the special with Hattori-kun.
You scout around the island for locations!
Anything that looks mysterious or spooky!
Okay!
This guy doesn't really think
we can crack the case, does he?
"The princess sleeps in the kō and not in the otsu"...
Kō, otsu and hei are old ranking terms—first, second, third...
It means the princess is sleepin'
in number one, and not number two.
Hey, Kudo, ya figgered anythin' out?
No, nothing.
You're not pretendin' to be stumped
so you can help Tokyo win, are ya?
Of course not!
Maybe it means, "The princess is number one when she's asleep!"
No, hang on!
Maybe it means, "The princess is number one, but she don't look that nice when she's sleepin'!"
Like that old saying, "don't know which is kō and which is otsu."
Good one!
Will ya two shut yer yaps?!
Argh, damn it!
Hey, I wonder what's taking Taira-san so long.
You're right...
The others got back an hour ago.
Maybe she went out for that late dive.
Maybe...
Oh no...
Hey!
Heiji!
I'll search this side of the beach!
Got it! I'll search the other side!
Hey, lady! Are ya here?
Taira-san... Taira-san!
Hey!
T-Taira-san...
Taira-san!
"I am the emissary of Gusō"
Taira-san's been murdered?
N-No way...
You've gotta be kidding!
She was killed about two hours ago.
Strangled to death with some kinda thin rope...
She got these little scratches all over her arms an' legs
while she was strugglin' to escape as she was bein' strangled.
That means the murderer killed her in the woods, dragged her body down here
an' ran off not too long ago,
leavin' this sick message in the sand...
"I am the Emissary of Gusō"?
Yo, Mr. Detective.
How do you know all that?
How can you tell the killer was just here?
It's easy!
Here, look.
Since the sand is wet up to that line,
the waves reached that point at high tide, right?
The writing is just clear of the waves now.
If the murderer had written it any earlier, it would've been underwater!
Thing is, this is the opposite end of the island from the pier where we're docked.
An hour ago, we were all waitin' for this lady in the boat.
Me an' the kid were the first to go lookin' for her.
We split up an' circled the island, then found her body.
That means somebody else is on this island.
The murderer who strangled this gal to death!
No way...
Someone besides us?
Kazuha, you've got a digital camera on ya, right?
Er...yeah. Right here.
Kudo, lemme borrow that shiny watch of yours and one of your sandals!
I understand the watch, but why the sandal?
I get it.
You want something in the photo for a size comparison.
I've gotta get the evidence down now, 'cause once the tide rises the waves are gonna wash it away.
Hey, what is this? You didn't need my watch.
Guess not.
Okay, move her down to the boat before she gets washed away too!
G-Got it.
But why Taira-san?
Maybe it was something in the ocean.
In the ocean?
Remember how Taira-san wanted to go snorkelling right after we got to the island?
She had to have a reason for going diving in water like this...
Like what?
I don't know, but I think it'd be better if we got back to the boat now,
and wait until it gets light before we investigate.
Knew ya'd say that.
What was that for?!
Did he get me to take off my sandal so I couldn't run after him?
Somebody, stop Heiji-niichan!
He's going to dive into the sea!
What's wrong with goin' for a dive?
I bet he's after some clue in the water.
He's got guts, I'll tell you that.
It's dark, and the water here has powerful tidal currents.
Even a pro diver can get pulled under if he's not careful.
It was around here, wasn't it?
Heiji! Come back!
It's dangerous!
Heiji!
Huh? What's that?
There's somethin' down there...
Somethin' big an' black at the bottom of the sea...
A-An anchor!
Heiji!
There he is!
You're one fast swimmer...
The current swept me away, ya dope!
Are you sayin' ya knew about the currents when ya went in?
Yeah!
That guy said this area is a great place to catch amberstripe scad, remember?
That's a migratory fish that stays in areas with fast tidal currents.
An' I noticed a ton of seagulls goin' after those fish.
That's why you got so worried when Taira-san didn't come back from diving?
Right.
I was afraid she'd gotten swept away by the currents.
Too bad the truth was even worse...
Knock off the cool guy act, Heiji!
You shouldn't have gone swimmin' in such dangerous water!
Oh, shut it! I just wanna close this case!
That's right!
It's not like he's trying to cheat on the contest
by gathering extra clues before Uncle Kogoro, right, Heiji-niichan?
Yeah... 'Course not...
W-Well, we can talk about that after we get Taira-san's body back to the cruiser.
Get back to what?
Like I said, the cruiser...
Hey!
The cruiser's gone!
That captain! I bet he freaked out and made a run for it because of the murder!
Ya kiddin' me? We're the only people who knew about it!
Well, us an' the murderer...
Then the captain's the killer!
After we all went looking for Taira-san,
he went around the island in the boat,
killed her, wrote that weird message and booked it!
Can't be! Me an' the kid went all the way
around the island along the beach!
One of us would've seen the cruiser passing us!
Well, whatever the deal is,
it looks like that captain holds the key to this mystery.
Well, anyway, we just need to hold on until a rescue ship comes!
T-That's right...
When they realize their crew hasn't come back by nightfall,
the people at the TV station will come looking.
Er, actually...
We were supposed to scout this location yesterday,
but renting the boat took longer than I expected.
I took us out today without telling anyone.
Wait a minute! You mean nobody knows we're here on this deserted island?!
Y-Yeah. I told the producer we'd finished scouting yesterday.
Maybe you and the captain are in this together...
to add a little drama to your TV special!
No way!
Don't panic!
Once Ran-chan's dad realizes we're missin', he's sure to launch a rescue!
Let's just wait in that house!
This awamori is the best!
I prepared it specially to give you courage for tomorrow's deduction match.
I need you to solve this case, Detective Mouri.
Hyogo Kaneshiro (63)
Mayor
I don't care what you find, as long as you put the mystery to rest.
I wonder what's taking your daughter and Hattori-kun so long...
Don't worry about them!
They just don't wanna see me before the match, that's all!
Buncha scared kids...
Forget those whippersnappers!
Let's drink 'til sunrise to muster our strength!
Gimme some more-ee of that awamori!
We're in trouble, ain't we?
Oh yeah.
Oh, this is interesting.
Take a look at this teacup!
It's been used as an ashtray.
Different brands of cigarettes...
And the water they were doused in hasn't evaporated yet.
That's right, and there wasn't just one or two of them.
These "Emissaries of Gusō"...
Next Conan:
Automatic pilot
Next time, it's riddles on riddles!
Ah, you can leave riddles to me!
You'd have to be better at them for us to do that.