Two people's deductions and suspense
fill the gulf between love and hate!
An uninhabited island and the bottom of the sea!
Conan and Heiji's deductions explode!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
A TV show pitting the best detectives from the east and west
brought us, along with Heiji Hattori, here to Okinawa.
We went with the film crew to an uninhabited island,
where an unidentified body and a mysterious message were found.
Then Yoshie Taira-san, a female member of the film crew,
was found, with a mysterious message next to her body.
Then the boat we came on, and the captain, vanished!
What? An anchor?
You found an anchor at the bottom of the sea where Taira-san was diving?
Yeah.
A rusty anchor, with a broken chain.
It must be from the ship of that guy who died last year!
Yeah! He dropped anchor here and was waitin' for the typhoon to pass,
but the chain on the anchor broke an' his ship got washed away!
Oh, no, no.
That anchor had shells and seaweed all over it.
It's gotta have been there at least four or five years.
Four or five years...
Come to think of it, that was around the time that strange stuff happened at the mayor's house.
Yeah...
What kind of stuff?
Noburo Ikema (24)
Crew
Five years ago, the mayor's only daughter, Miss Miyako, was kidnapped.
A year later, burglars broke into the house
and stole a golden folding screen that had been the family treasure.
The mayor and his butler got calls from the criminals both times.
They think the kidnappers and the burglars were the same people.
Then? What happened?
The mayor wouldn't meet their ransom demands.
Yoshitsugu Kume (25)
Crew
The criminals were never caught, and the young lady and the golden screen are still missing.
The mayor's had a hard time of it.
Masao Taketomi (42)
TV Director
His daughter was kidnapped around the same time he lost his wife to an illness.
Then the burglars killed his housekeeper, and his butler got scared and quit.
People called him heartless for refusing to pay the ransom.
Then a man starved to death on this island, which he owns,
and that strange message was found next to the body.
And now a murder.
It really feels like the Emissary of Gusō is after him...
Hey.
The message said, "The princess sleeps in the kō and not in the otsu", right?
Maybe the princess is the kidnapped daughter!
You think she's been killed and is buried somewhere on this island?
That's right!
Then she came back from the dead as the Emissary and strangled Taira-san!
If you're scared of the emissary, take that knife.
Mikihiko Daito (47)
Crew
The legends say a woman should put a sheeg, a knife, between her lips
mabui = soul
sheeg = knife
to keep her soul from being pulled out through her mouth.
And if that doesn't work,
you can use it to stab someone.
This is interesting.
Take a look at this teacup!
It's been used as an ashtray.
Different brands of cigarettes...
And the water they were doused in hasn't evaporated yet.
You're sayin' somebody was in this cottage before us.
That's right, and there wasn't just one or two of them.
Whoever killed that girl, Emissaries of Gusō or common criminals,
they're hiding out on this island.
Come on! Are you serious?
You think the person who killed Taira-san was part of a gang or something hanging out on the island?
I'm just saying it's a possibility.
Maybe there are Emissaries all around us, after our mabui—our souls.
N-No...
Could they be in the cottage right now?
No way! We searched the place when we got here and it was empty, right?
But a lot of the windows are broken.
It'd be a piece of cake to sneak in while we're yappin' away.
Well, let's split up and search again.
Sure. Ain't no point sittin' here shiverin' in fear.
Kume-san, Ikema-san, Daito-san,
you take the second floor.
Okay.
We'll search the first floor with Taketomi-san.
R-Right. There's two girls, but you're the only guy, so you'd be at a disadvantage if you got attacked.
Are ya mental?
You're the one they'd be protecting.
Oh, really?
You're a karate champ?
Yeah.
Well, I won a city tournament...
I'm a second dan in Aikido!
Wow... That's reassuring...
Thanks!
If the killer appears, leave it all to us!
Good thing I asked that guy to stick with us, huh?
Yeah, he'd be toast on his own.
A-All right, Hattori-kun... t-this is the last room...
Don't keep us hangin', hurry an' open it!
Maybe this wasn't such a good idea after all.
Hey... Anybody here?
Hey!
It looks deserted.
Yeah...
This is a lot bigger than the other rooms.
That's because it's the mayor's wife's bedroom.
See, here's a photo of the mayor and his wife.
It's really rusty...
What're ya doin', Heiji?
There are two photos in this frame...
What's this? A picture of the mayor with a young babe!
I betcha this guy was havin' an affair!
No, no!
That's his only daughter, Miss Miyako!
She was a lot like her mother, beautiful, with pale, silky skin, and very kind and gentle.
The whole island talked about who she'd end up marrying.
But while she was at junior college, she was kidnapped and disappeared forever.
I thought you were from a TV station in Kyushu.
How come you know all the local gossip?
Oh, Yoshiko Matsumoto-san, the mayor's housekeeper, was my cousin.
She told me all about the family.
Was your cousin the housekeeper who died?
In the burglary?
That's right. Four years ago, one of the burglars killed her.
Speaking of cousins, Ikema-kun's mother was the mayor's wife's sister,
so he and the young lady were cousins.
Hey, what's that castle in the background? I don't recognize it.
That's not a castle! It's the mayor's house!
It's a big mansion, isn't it?
From what Yoshiko-san told me,
Miss Miyako was a little girl when the house was built, and she loved it.
She felt like she'd turned into a real princess...
T-The princess...
Of the castle?
Maybe the "princess" in that strange message really does mean...
The young lady?
There are strange words on this pillar too.
I think that young lady wrote these.
See, three of them...
You're right. Looks like they were written in crayon or somethin'.
At the very top is "Brother Chiyo"...
About 20 cm below that is "kaa-chan"...
An' at the very bottom it says, "me".
Judgin' from the number of marks around "me",
the young lady kept comparin' heights with the other two when she came here as a kid.
Geez. Don't scare me like that.
It's funny, though. "Kaa-chan" is a weird thing to call your mom.
Especially a rich, well-bred little girl like Miyako.
I don't think "kaa-chan" is her mother.
Look at this! It's starting to fade,
but there's more writing on the door using the same crayon.
"Mama's room"...
You're right!
So who were they?
This "Kaa-chan" and "Brother Chiyo"?
Dunno...
Maybe they were friends from school.
I don't think so! Look how tall they were!
Do these look like preschool friends?
You got a point.
Hey, these doors have "Kaa-chan" and "Brother Chiyo" written on 'em!
That room over there is "Brother Chiyo's Room"...
And this here is "Kaa-chan's Room".
That ain't all.
There's a funny doodle next to the writin'.
The one next to "Kaa-chan" looks like a bird.
An' the one next to "Brother Chiyo" looks like an eel.
Looking at old kids' drawings in the dark...
Is kinda creepy...
At any rate,
if these folks had their own rooms in the summer cottage,
they musta come out here with the young lady pretty regular.
After we get rescued, I wanna ask the mayor who those two were.
Maybe they've got somethin' to do with this case.
What was that voice?
I think it was Kume-kun!
Somethin' happened on the second floor!
Could it be the killer?
Damn!
Hey, what's wrong?
Didja find the murderer?
No!
This guy suddenly screamed like a banshee and fell back in a panic
after seeing this painting that was behind the curtain.
Hey, isn't that the young lady, the girl in the photo?
You're right.
She looks just like that photo.
The mayor's wife must've painted it.
Yoshiko-san told me she was quite the artist.
Yoshiko-san?
Y-Yeah, my cousin. She was the mayor's housekeeper.
That means there are four people here
with some kind of connection to the mayor.
Four?
Yeah. My mother was the younger sister of the mayor's wife.
The director and the mayor's housekeeper were cousins too.
Kume and the young lady were classmates all through elementary, middle and high school.
And Daito-san here was a childhood friend of the mayor's wife.
A childhood friend?
Yeah.
I visited her grave with my mom last year, and he was there.
When my mom asked him about it, that's what he said.
But my mom said she didn't remember him, so maybe it was all a lie.
It's no surprise. Your mom was just a little kid then.
Hey, since your mother and the mayor's wife were sisters,
have you been to this island before?
Nope. My mom and I hardly ever visited the mayor's house either.
We always felt out of place in those fancy digs.
I only saw the young lady a few times
when she was very young.
But why was Kume-san scared of that paintin'?
Beats me. Maybe he thought it was her ghost?
Everybody keeps talking like she's already dead...
A-Anyway, it doesn't look like there's
any suspicious people hiding here,
so let's huddle up together in one room
and wait for the rescue ship!
Hey. Don't you think it's taking a little too long?
Yeah.
You know that dumb lug.
Probably off gettin' blitzed an' hittin' on girls...
That ol' dope.
What was that?
C-Could it be...?
I knew it! It's the rescue ship!
We're saved!
Hey!
We're over here! Hey!
There's somethin' up!
The boat's just sitting there with the lights out!
I am the Emissary of Gusō
This is one mean way to kill a man.
The murderer bashed the captain's head in with a lead pipe or somethin', over an' over.
Even after he was obviously dead.
O-Oh, no...
Then he wrapped a rope around the stiff's neck an' hung him off the side of the boat.
"I am the Emissary of Gusō"...
Talk about a grudge.
But who?
There's somebody other than us on this island!
There's some kind of gang hiding out here that gets off on murdering people!
He's right. When that boat crashed into the dock, we were all inside the house.
Whoever was piloting this boat is still around here, I'm sure of that.
Yeah. A crazy serial killer who calls himself "The Emissary of Gusō".
No. That might not be the case.
C-Conan-kun?!
I just looked around the boat.
There's this funny thing that looks like a little TV next to the steering wheel.
I think it just told the boat to go around in a big circle from the dock!
I-I see... The autopilot! The killer wouldn't have to be on board!
Sorry, kid, but with the tidal currents around here,
you couldn't set the autopilot to make an accurate docking. It'd get knocked off-course.
Nah, it wouldn't have to be accurate.
To deal with tidal currents, an autopilot can be set
with a margin of error of about 50-100 meters.
If the boat was set to hug the shore on this side,
it coulda made it 'round the reef an' had a good chance of smashin' into the dock.
Look! Scrape marks on the side of the hull!
The boat was movin' along the edge of the coral reef!
In other words, the murderer coulda used the autopilot
to send this boat out from the dock hours ago
with the body already hangin' from it!
Any one of us coulda done it.
Hey, now, don't tell me...
A-Are you saying one of us could be the murderer?
Right.
Y'all followed us outta the boat after we rushed out to look for Taira-san, right?
The very last person who left the boat coulda done it!
Who was that?
I-It wasn't me!
Me neither!
I was the last guy off the boat.
T-Then you...
But anyone could've snuck back on board after I left.
And aren't you forgetting something, kid?
Think back to when we found that Taira girl's body...
That's right! You said it yourself!
Those words in the sand next to Taira-san...
None of us had time to write them, because we were on the other side of the island!
They were written right at the edge of the receding tide,
so the murderer could only have written them minutes before we found the body!
And the same words were written
next to Taira-san and the captain,
so it's gotta be the same killer, right?
The murderer couldn't be one of us!
What if the killer is part of a group?
One of us could be an accomplice.
Maybe that's just another of his tricks.
Maybe he wants us to get suspicious of each other and fight.
Well, at least we've got the boat back.
Right. We can figger out the details
once we get off this island!
Nope. I checked the boat when I brought the body down, an' the fuel tank's nearly empty.
That ain't all. The radio transmitter was trashed an' our bags are gone.
That means...
The murderer wants to keep us
on the island. He's up to somethin'.
U-Up to something?
Like another murder?
Yeah. If you don't wanna get killed, let's get back in that cottage an' wait for rescue!
Geez. How long are we gonna have to wait for a rescue ship?
I don't know...
Anyway, Heiji, we'll see you back there later.
Right.
Be careful.
Don't worry.
Ya know, Kudo, this case just don't make sense.
Yeah.
The murderer carefully folded Taira-san's hands an' closed her eyes after killin' her.
But the next victim, the captain,
got beaten to a pulp.
Maybe there's more than one murderer.
The methods are too different.
What also bothers me is the weird final acts of Taira-san and the captain.
Right. Taira-san insisted on going diving at night in dangerous waters.
And the captain was sailing around in his boat
when he was supposed to be
getting ready to take us home.
There was sonar equipment on the boat.
I think he was off searchin' for somethin' in the ocean around here.
Whatever was on the other end of that anchor I saw
at the bottom of the sea.
By the way, Kudo, didja notice the bottoms of the chairs in the room we were just in?
Yeah. A child had written on them with crayons.
The chair I was sitting on said "me",
and the chair Ran was sitting on said "mama".
But for some strange reason, the bottom of the chair I was sittin' on said...
"Kaneshiro-san".
The young lady wrote those, right?
Then Kaneshiro-san was her dad.
So why didn't she write "daddy"?
And those were the only three chairs with names on 'em.
It's strange we didn't find chairs for
"Kaa-chan" and "Brother Chiyo",
the people who were comparing heights with her.
Yeah. If they had their own rooms,
how come they didn't have chairs?
"Kaa-chan" and "Brother Chiyo"...
Who were they?
Found somethin'!
Rice crackers an' karinto!
What was that sound?
Dunno...
It sounded like dripping water...
Oh no! It's coming this way!
It couldn't be...
T-The Emissary of Gusō!
Next Conan:
Castle
Next time, the solution at last!
The killer is you!