Two people's deductions and suspense
fill the gulf between love and hate!
The surprising secret on the secluded island!
An unexpected ending for the deduction showdown!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
A TV show pitting the best detectives from the east and west
brought us, along with Heiji Hattori, here to Okinawa.
We went with the film crew to an uninhabited island,
where an unidentified body and a mysterious message were found.
Then Yoshie Taira-san, a female member of the film crew,
was found, with a mysterious message next to her body.
Then the boat we came on, and the captain, vanished!
With no other choice, we waited at the mayor's cottage on the island for help to arrive.
What was that?
C-Could it be...?
I knew it! It's the rescue ship!
We're saved!
There's somethin' up!
The boat's just sitting there with the lights out!
Sheesh, it's five in the morning.
No wonder I'm getting hungry.
We haven't eaten anything for half a day.
I'm thirsty too...
Let's check out the kitchen!
Maybe there's some canned food or drinks.
Okay.
Should we let those two go alone?
They'll be fine!
They're really tough!
Found something!
Rice crackers and karinto!
Those will make us even thirstier...
Beats eatin' nothin', right?
What was that?
Dunno.
Sounded like dripping water.
Oh no! It's coming this way!
It's... It's...
T-The Emissary of Gusō!
What're ya doin' there?
What's with them knives in yer mouths?
H-Heiji...
We thought you were the Emissary of Gusō!
Remember what Daito-san said?
We should put knives in our mouths to keep our souls from getting sucked out!
Hey, why're you all wet?
Oh, this?
Heiji-niichan went for another dive!
Since the killer threw our bags overboard,
Heiji-niichan thought he might be able to find the one with his cell phone in the reefs just offshore!
So did you find your bag?
Nah. The currents musta washed everything away.
"Kaa-chan" again...
It says "Brother Chiyo" on the bottom of this stool!
Hey, could it be...
that Kaa-chan was the housekeeper, Yoshiko Matsumoto-san?
I see! "Kaa" is short for kaseifu—"housekeeper"!
She must've used this stool here in the kitchen!
So who's Brother Chiyo?
Hey, there's some faded writing!
It was rubbed off, and "Brother Chiyo" was written on top.
It's pretty hard to read clearly, but I think it says "Dojō-san".
Guess the drawing under "Brother Chiyo" was supposed to be...
a loach, then?
dojō
But what's "Brother Chiyo" got to do with a fish?
I get the bird drawing if it's supposed to be a crow.
You know, crows say "kaa, kaa"!
A crow...
Or maybe she just copied the bird from that folding screen?
In that case, it'd be a white heron.
A heron?
The director told us
the golden folding screen that was stolen from the mayor four years ago had a white heron on it.
It was rated as a national treasure and was worth 200 million yen...
Crow... white heron... loach...
Damn it, what's the connection?
Tigers for Osaka, hawks for Fukuoka,
carp for Hiroshima...
If it was sea bream and flounder, it could be about that Chinese restaurant, Dragon Palace...
Dragon Palace?
That's it!
Say. That Conan-kun's one weird kid.
Ya sure he ain't lyin' about his age?
I-I don't think so...
Kazuha! What'd ya just say?
I'm askin' ya what you just said!
A-Are ya sure he's not lyin' about his age?
H-Heiji!
Conan-kun—!
It's currently ten minutes to 6 in the morning.
It's been more than 12 hours since we found Taira-san's body!
If our deductions are correct, it should still be there!
Yeah... It's got to be!
I-It's gone...
Damn it! The killer erased the evidence!
No. He missed something.
That little footprint over there is mine.
Then this was a trick all along.
Yeah. And we fell for it.
So what now? We know who did the deed, but we've got no proof.
If we can't find proof, we'll have to drag it out...
in this forest where the princess sleeps.
Yeah. But I think the princess is cryin' right now.
Yeah.
H-Heiji!
Conan-kun!
Where have you been?
We were worried sick!
Quit your yappin'! I solved the case!
Y-You did?
You mean...
That's right.
We know the trick the murderer used.
An' we know the murderer...
has been hidin' among us, playin' innocent the whole time.
It's one of us?
Who is it? C'mon, spill!
Not yet.
I've gotta interrogate the suspects before I know for sure.
All right, Kume-san...
Let's start with you.
I've only got a few questions.
While we're gone, figger out who goes next.
Hey. What's taking them?
It's been half an hour...
It shouldn't be much longer.
He said he only had a few questions.
Hey, come back here!
Heiji?
What's wrong?
Nothing's up! That guy just made a run for it!
M-Made a run for it?
Then he must be the killer!
This is your fault, Heiji-niichan!
You shouldn't have said, "I'm gonna turn into Urashima Taro waitin' for you to talk!"
What was I supposed to do?
He wasn't cooperatin'!
Well, let's split up an' look for him!
Don't let him dive into the sea
an' drown himself or nothin'!
Hey, Kume!
Where are you?
Kume-san!
Hey!
Don't look so shocked.
You're the one who taught us...
If ya don't want the Emissary of Gusō to take your soul...
Keep a sheeg—a knife—in your mouth.
Ain't that right?
Daito-san?
Kume-san, the guy you were trying to kill, is still in the house.
He's taking a little nap.
I borrowed his clothes to pretend to be him and lure ya out.
You killed Taira-san an' the captain,
and you were waitin' for Kume-san to show up here so you could kill him.
All three of 'em were in the gang that kidnapped the young lady,
stole the folding screen and killed the housekeeper, am I right?
Come on, what're you talking about?
I was just looking for Kume.
When I saw you acting suspicious, I thought you were the killer!
And I never had the opportunity to kill Taira, did I?
Those words on the beach were written right after the tide lowered,
so those of us who were on the other side of the island couldn't have written them.
You're right.
If those words were written before the tide went low, they'd be underwater,
so it would've been impossible to leave 'em there.
But that's only if the tide really was low.
Quit joking around, kid!
You saw it yourself!
The sand was wet for about a meter past the body.
The waves reached there at high tide, and when we got there the tide was lowering...
Yeah, that's what we thought, but only because we fooled ourselves into believing it.
We assumed that just because the sand was wet,
the sea got that far up at high tide. That's not true!
That's right.
It was actually high tide when we found Taira-san.
That way, everything makes sense, right?
All you had to do was write those words just above the high water mark
an' leave Taira-san's body next to 'em!
Then let's look for those words in the sand!
It's been half a day since we found the body.
If the message was written in a spot the waves never reach, it'll still be there!
Nah, it's gone.
You musta gotten rid of it after we left.
Yeah, right.
But my footprint's still there!
The only time I took my sandal off was when Heiji-niichan was taking photos.
I was standing next to him.
My footprint from then hadn't been washed away.
But kid, the whole beach was soaking wet!
You think I went over the sand with a bucket or something?
It wasn't a bucket.
It was the cruiser we came here on.
You knew the cruiser'd be kickin' up waves and soakin' the sand further than high tide.
You just used that to your advantage.
After all, ya knew the captain was goin' around the edge of the island
searchin' for you-know-what.
W-What are you talking about?
What else?
That anchor I found at the bottom of the sea.
The "princess" was chained to the other end to keep her in place.
Princess?
Remember the carvin' on the pillar of the house?
"The princess sleeps in the kō and not in the otsu."
Don't seem to make sense, does it?
Remember the fairy tale "Urashima Taro"?
Things start to get clearer when you remember we're on Demon Turtle Island.
kō
Kō means a turtle's shell.
otsu
Otsu stands for Oto-hime, princess of the Dragon King's Palace under the sea.
In the story, Taro rides to the palace on the back of a turtle.
The message is sayin', "The princess is on the island, and not under the sea!"
"Princess" was the gang's code for this.
They had sunk it to the bottom of the sea, but it got washed ashore by the typhoon a year ago.
This golden folding screen!
After stealin' it, the burglars musta had trouble findin' a place to fence it.
So they put it in a sealed box, loaded the box on a rowboat,
sank it to the ocean floor with an anchor,
and decided to wait 'til things cooled off.
But one year ago, a huge typhoon swept the area.
One of the crooks dropped by the island to check up on the "princess"
an' found the rowboat washed up on the beach.
Unluckily for him, the boat he'd come in on was swept away by another typhoon,
and he got stranded.
He left that carving to tell the rest of the gang what'd happened to their treasure.
You figgered out what the message meant,
an' decided to use our "Sleuth of the East vs. Sleuth of the West" TV special
to take revenge on the rest of the gang!
You realized the crooks would be lookin' for the screen
an' that they'd try to infiltrate the TV crew.
B-But how could I know who they were?
Urashima Taro.
Hey, you said it, didn't you?
You said, "I feel like Urashima Taro."
You knew only members of the gang who had sunk the screen in the ocean
would understand what was written there.
You killed Taira-san after she went into the woods to look for the treasure.
You offed her the same way you just tried to kill me.
Clever story, kid.
But anybody on the boat could've done that.
Nah, it was you.
The captain was bludgeoned to death, but Taira-san's body was treated with care.
That's 'cause the killer knew...
Taira-san was really Miyako, the girl who got kidnapped five years ago!
The kidnapping was a sham!
The young lady herself was a member of the gang!
I realized that when I figgered out why the burglars called the folding screen "princess",
and the meaning of the names "Brother Chiyo" and "Kaa-chan"
she left in the house when she was younger.
They're all nicknames based on famous Japanese castles!
"Princess", or hime, comes from Himeji Castle, also known as "White Heron Castle"!
White Heron Castle
Himeji Castle
Kaa-chan
Crow Castle
The "kaa" in "Kaa-chan" is the cawing of a crow.
It stands for Matsumoto Castle, the black palace known as "Crow Castle"!
Matsumoto Castle
It was her nickname for Yoshiko Matsumoto-san,
the housekeeper who was killed by the gang!
Chiyoda Castle
Brother Chiyo
"Brother Chiyo" is for Chiyoda Castle, another name for Edo-jō!
Edo-jō
Edo-jō, or Edo Castle, is a big castle in the east.
tō
(East)
dai
(Big)
Ain't that right?
Daito-san, you were the family butler!
At first, she was callin' ya "Dojō-san", by takin' away the "e" from Edo-jō.
do-jō
Dojō
I figgered you used to be a butler 'cause you always stood by the door without sittin' down.
You have a room but your stool is in the kitchen.
And ya opened the china cupboard to look for a cup to use as an ashtray.
You already knew there were no ashtrays in the cottage!
You planted that teacup with the cigarette butts
to make it look like there was more than one killer.
I bet you're tryin' to think of a way to talk your way outta this an' still kill Kume-san.
Forget it.
That rope you're holdin' right now should perfectly match the rope mark on the young lady's body.
But there's one thing I still don't get.
You figgered out Kume-san was one of the crooks after he freaked out at the young lady's paintin'.
But how'd you know the captain was in on it too?
You couldn't have done any of this if you hadn't known
that the captain'd be circlin' the island lookin' for the treasure.
I'd never forget that face.
I saw it during the burglary four years ago.
That monster killed the woman I was going to marry.
Then Matsumoto-san, the housekeeper...
Yes. We were engaged.
I asked the master for a leave of absence to get revenge.
I changed my appearance and put on a ruffian act to get close to the gang.
But I never imagined his daughter was one of them!
So you didn't know?
No. She'd completely changed her hair and skin tone.
I only realized it when she uttered her last words...
I'm sorry, Brother Chiyo...
After seeing her dead, I finally understood.
She set up the sham kidnapping to test the master after her mother died.
She knew he wasn't her biological father.
When he refused to pay her ransom, she stole the folding screen to get back at him.
She was the child of his wife's first marriage, huh?
Indeed.
And now that I think of it,
the master must have suspected from the start that she was involved in those crimes.
When I asked him to give me leave, he said...
This is probably all my fault.
I'm begging you, stop going after the gang and take your grudge out on me.
After all, this case was just like the master said...
A box that should never have been opened...
The golden screen shone sadly,
as if it were trying to speak to him.
The paint, oxidizing in the air after being sealed away for so long,
trickled down like tears.
What?!
T-The case is already solved?
Are you serious?!
Yep. I solved it while you were drunk an' feelin' good...
B-B-B-But what about my TV appearance? What about my fee?
How should I know, dope?
Make some crimes for me to solve!
Anything! A dine-and-dash!
Oh, geez.
Hey! Good idea!
Wow! Detective Mouri is already on his twelfth bowl!
An all-sleuth eating contest?
This is what you guys went to Okinawa to do?
W-Well, sort of...
Yeah, no.
What should I do?
I have to hurry and tell someone!
Cell phone, cell phone.
Where's my cell phone?
Ran-neechan disappeared?
Hey! Answer me, Ran!
I-It got cut off.
Next Conan:
E-mail
The next episode's stage is Kumamoto, the land of fire!
A tennis tournament at the foot of Mt. Aso!
Is that a-so.