Suspense and deduction
closes the gap between
the love and hatred
between two people
Tennis concert in the
Iand of Kumamoto
Cellphone and mail. Ran's in trouble!
He sees through the
one and only truth
a child in appearance
with the IQ. of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Mt. Asosan
I 35.50
Vv Na \
We are on board our
plane flying to Kumamoto.
We headed there to enter a tennis
match that Genta won in-arlotteny.
Ran and Pops is with us
as our guardian and
Sonoko has also come along
paying her own way.
Just as would be expected of the
daughter of the Suzuki financial group...
And, this time there is one more
person who came along with us
It's not usual for her to come
along on something like this...
Want anything?
Oh, well, no
Okay then
I was just-wondering why
you came along this time. because
you usually say you're not interested
in stuff/like this. and don't join us
There's no special
reason why I came along...
It's because Dr. Agasa
kept bugging me to go.
And besides, unless I stay near you,
you can't protect. me, can you?
What?
I was joking
Oh boy...
(Bik)
Smash of Love and Resolve
Part 1
Here we are!
It's Kyushu!
It's Kumamoto!
It's alcohol
Just as expectedpof your dad. Ran.
Come on dad, let's hurry and
rent a car and go to the hotel!
Hey. wait up!
We bring to you the Land of Fire Charity
Tennis Tournament,
playing the semi-finals will be,
It's Kyohei Mabuchi!
I WV»
What?
You're right!
His awesome!
You're still kids
The one who "3 really awesome is. #
Same from the Kumamoto-area,
TachikawarMasato'and from England...
Masahito!
We could never beat him though...
What are you saying Genta...
We're participating in the ¢*
Jr tournament. those guys aneypros!
The .@ is no way
we are going agaisnt them!
Wait, really?
That's right Genta!
Well that sucks...
I was hoping to play agaisnt them...
Your joking. right!
Kumamoto Ninomardl Park
It so spacious and feels good!
Yup!
Kids sure are active
no matter what they do...
Really training 1s
soon as they get here!
It's so nice to6'be young...
You're talking like you're some
middle-agediwoman or something!
Genta, what are you doing!
You guys are too fast!
Let's rest a little...
Just what are you talking
about. the match is tomorrow
Kumamoto to win. you know.
But, where's Mr. Mourn?
You're right. Air's not around either
Well, I do have an
idea where they are though
Spicy lotus root,
raw horse meat and shochu!
Wow! Viva Kumamoto!
I can't go on...
Let's take a 5 minute break then. Ny
Only 5 minutes?
Are you serious!
Of course!
Hey. Mitsuhiko.,
since we came all th way to Kumaméto
, we call it a day for
training and go look around.
I agree. I agree!
I'm starving too!
Hey. Mitsuhiko?
Besides, we don't want anybody
to Overwork them and get hu -t
or something just before
the match." do we?
But. Ran...
Participating in the game is what counts.
Have you ever heard this phrase?
I think it's more important
to give it all we've got
and to try our best,
rather than we win the game or not
Alright .
All right!
Let's go eat eels over rice!
What are you talking about?
Tonkotsu Ramen is what
Kumamoto is famous for!
Ran...
You'll become a good mother...
Kumamoto:Castle
Kumamoto Oastle
Suizenji Park
THEA I CORA
kAIF2. HA
What is it. Sonoko?
Look what I found!
Isn't that a cell phone?
We've got to turn
it into the police Fight away
Wow lit's vibrating]
A mail?
Yeah. I think-so. \
shall we take a look at it?
No. we shouldn't peek
into other.people"s mail
Who cares. besides, it may be, from the
owner of this cell phone, right?
Hey. don't!
What
Sonoko! I want to see you! It says!
Wow. it's a love ma lk
You're blushed.
Hey, what's up, Sonoko?
You see...
Oh it's nothing. really
This is not kid's stuff!
Better watch out; the-police may scold
you for looking at,other people's mail!
The ether kids:are waiting for you
- over there. Hurry andgo onsover there!
At any rate, we've got te hurry
andstake it to the police
What re you talking about!
We're going to deliver this in person
tomorrow to the person
who sent this mail!
Wait, but, we've got the
tennis match tomorrow
Don't worry!
This Prefectural Athletic Park is where
the tennis matct ris-going "O be held!
See?
So it won't Kurt to leave for just a while!
I guess so...
Then it's decided!
Tomorrow wejll see how this love
as well as the tennis match goes!
Finally, tomorrow...
Are going to be okay? \
I'll do it!
We will now begin the First Land of Fire
Cup Charity Tennis Tournament.
We will now begin the First Land of F
1stannual-Land.of Fire Cup
3, Charity Tennis .Toulinament.Jr. Stadium
JM-BXDEN yTRBT RAKE = I
1steannual. Land of Fire Cup
ChairiityO tennis Tournament Jr. Stadium
m- BE AXXO >» TEES - RIXEeil
Before the start of the game, I, Kenzo
Narimasu¥Chairman of this tournament
would like to give a
welcome speech to the guardians
Kenzo Narimasu
chairman
would like to give a
welcome speech:to-the guardians
Kenzo Narimasu
chairman
O (TAXED
Hill:
of the contestants as well
as all the spectators here.
Kenzo Narimasu
chairman
TT PAL
Ri 48 - (GO)
of the contestants as well
as all the spectators here.
Kenzo Narimasu
chairman
of the contestants as well
as all the spectators here.
I am being suspected by the Diet
at present for something that I
have no kn Wledge of whatsoever. but... «
What's with that man?
He's talking about same
totally irrelevant to tennis
He looks awfully familiar, though...
You probably some him on TV...
He's Kenzo Narimasu, a congressman
who was elected from Kumamoto
that has recently been talked
about a lot regarding his corrupted acts
O@Oh. yes. I've heard of him!
The other day. his secretary called Saikl 7
took on all the guilt
and committed suicide. right?
Yeah.
So. in order to gain back
his reputation with the public.
He offered to be sponsor
for this tournament
The usual stuff...
WOW...
We did it!
Really..l don't believe it!
Great victory for
theilYouth Detective Squad!!
the Youth Detective Squad!!
Good work and welcome back everybody.
Were»you watchinglus. Ai?!
ies. you're all, pretty good
Now, we get to. go on, to-the semi-finals!
We've already come this far...
idly
Victory of the Y(Tith Detective Squad!!!
Hey. Where are Ran and Sonoko?
I wonder, they went sneaking off
just a while ago
Oh...
Café Athlete
NIO-PAR)
There's nobody who looks te-be*the owner.
WORO
Should we mail him?
Dont. Sonoko.
Just joking. only joking.
But, this is so exciting.
I think I kind of got too nervous
that I have to go te the ladies' room.
Sorry, Ran, I'll be right back...
I tell you...
Sonoko sure is late.
Huh
Yeah, she wasnst for it to begin with so...
That's why we decided to meet
and talk it out, right?
Yeah, but if Sonoko doesn't come...
If so, we wait outside until
she succeeds and run for it together.
After all, today's the only chance
we got to kill that guy!
What shall I do,
I've got to get somebody, quick...
ell phone. cell phone...
where's my cell phone...
You heard us, didn't you?
Hey. isn't that Sonokoss cell phone...
No doubt about it. It's Sonoko's!
How come you have it?
MM. My friend picked it up...
so, I was/going to return it...
You mean Sonoko dropped it...
Which means maybe
she didn't read our mail...
Either way. we cant let you go. like this.
Oh, you were here?
What do we do about this girl?
Just like Akira says,
we can't let her go as is.
Let's take her-to the factory for now.
Yeah. I guess so.
What?
EXIT XA I57Cene
Right, she disappeared while
I was in the lady's room .
Are you sure she's" not back
at the hotel room sleeping?
I called and asked, but was told
she hasn't come back yet...
I wonder what happened...
That's cause for worry
Hey. did you try callingffRer cell phone?
Ran's cell phone?
Yep. but no one answered
I wonder if she has it on manner mode
and doesn't know it's ringing...
Or, it could be that...
she's in a situation that she can't answer
™4%1l
I can't tell if it's an accident
or an incident, but...
Where is this?
Why am I here...
You heard us talking. didn't you?
Hey. isn't that Sonoko's cell phone?
No doubt about it. It's Sonoko's!
How come you have it?
Either way, we can't let you go as is.
Maybe I...
D. Don't tell she was kidnapped...
§unh >!
It.It can't be?
Y! you guys
What's with that bummed out
Iook ontyour faces?
I get it, you guys lost?
Oh no. it's not that...
Ran.»
may have been,kidnapped
W. What!
There!
H. Hey hold it!
Are you sure about this kidnap thing?
Maybe she's lost somewhere near here?
But, she's Not answering her cell phone...
She's not back at the hotel either.
But that's not enough to go on...
It's from Ran!
See. how dare you worry me like that.
Hello hey. 'Ran,
just where the hell are you now...
Sorry, Sonoko.
It's seems as if I've been kidnapped.
Huh?! You've been kidnapped after all!
What?
Lend it to me!
Me . Ran!
Oh, Conan.
Do you know where you are?
Where?
It seems to be the locker room of
an abandoned factory or something...
CER you look.ou 'the window?
Do you somet,ing-that can serve as a hint
to where you are... Anything will do.
Do you something that can serve as a hint
Okay. hold on...
How-about it: Ran?
Sunflower...
Right, there are a lot of
sunflowers in bloom here.
Anything else?
On the other side of the sunflowers
there is a building that is not in use...
There is a sign.
What's written onithe:sign?
Hirukomachil.
Hiruko Town is what's written!
That's Hiru for bloodsucker
and Ko for child!
0c:\'...
Okay! Hirukonfchi. right!
And about the kidnappers.
The kidnappers are the ones
who sent the mail to Sonoko!
Huh? The-enes who mailed Senoko?
In. [l1
Conan, please listen to me!
Conan. please listen to me!
Those people were saving that
they're going to kill somebody today...
Hey, Ran! It's me!
Can you hear me!
Hey! Answer me, Ran!
The line's been cut
What!
Maybe the kidnappers found her
talking on the phone?
What shall we do?
She could've contacted the police...
Maybe we should drop
the whole idea after all...
No, we won't let anybody get in our way.
Not anybody!
Thank you for waiting
I am officer Tamana from Kumamotc
Prefectural Police Department.
Officer Tamana
I am officer Tamana from Kumamotc
Prefectural Police Department.
Ficer Tamana
OEITAAT GD
I am officer Tamana from Kumamot
Prefecture! Police Department.
Ficer Tamana
I am officer Tamana from Kumamot«
Prefectural Police Department.
This is Officer Kato.
Hello.
Sorry for, troubling you,
my name is :Mouri Kogorou
Oh./I've heard-a lot about you
/Well, please sit down
Yes .
I'm sure you're very worried,
because I was contacted by Inspector
telling me to handle the
situation with great care
Please do let us handle
this case completely.
Yes, but...
Mr. Mouri
I understand how you feel
I don't think that you are in a situation
to judge things objectively right now.
This case involves the life
of your daughter,
SO please bear with us for
now and let us handle this.
All right...
I appreciate it.
Now, as to the current situation.
Yes, Sir.
As a result of our inquiries
within this athletic park,
the said woman victim seems to
have been carried away by two men
That's it!
Also...
And about the Hiruko Town that
the victim had mentioned
Currently around the
Kumamoto prefecture...
such a town does not exist.
What!
Are you serious?
What the hell is going on...
I'm sorry Mr. Mourn...
If I didn't pick up that cell Mane...
Don't worry about it,
you're not to blame.
The kidnappers are the villains!
This is no time to
be playing tennis. is it?
Yea...
We've got to give
up the tennis match...
Yep. Ran is more important
I don't think
Like Ran was saying. the whole I
point Is to participate In the game!
She was for us through and«through!
We can't give up the game now!
Of course I'm worried about Ran too!
But there's nothing we
can do by staying here either.
I think it's way better to show Ran
our victory trophy when she
comes back and make her happy!
Yeah, but...
He's right.
Just like Mitsuhiko says,
we can't do anything here anyway.
Let's participate'in the game.
Right, Pops?
Huh? Yeah. right.
The police is working onthe case-and
you guys made it to the finals, right?
If so, go for it.
Okay. we'll do our best!
Oh, okay. then.
I'll give it my beSt shot!
Oh. okay. then.
I'll give it my best shot!
Okay.
@kay, then let's all 'do our best
show Ran the champion trophy!
Shinichi, I'll bet you have no intention
of participating in the game, do you?
You're planning to go
search for her alone. aren't you?
Yeah, although I feel
bad for those kids
You're really something...
If you will excuse me.
Hello. this is Tamanna
What!
Then what?
Okay. do that. will you!
What's up? Don't tell me
something happened to Ran
No. the kidnappers seem to have called
the station directly demanding ransom.
What!
An officer is on his way here with the
recording of the phone conversation.
Damn those guys.
Row dare they do this to Ran...
They're not going to get
away with this!!
What the hell s going on?
Why, weuldithey call the
DOO Elicit) ose wtf
Maybe this is no usual kidnapping.
If sow-what are they actually after
The last words of Ran"s call was...
They were saying, they re
going to kill somebody today
They're going') to Kill somebody today...
Maybe Ran?
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers
CT THI siwA
SA. 12333533 nA
Background Music.
KAT -UQ ONO
Charact r Designs By
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
Scripts By.
KANJ1O* ASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUGHI
JWUNICHI MIYASH HA
run,» r MURI:
TOSHIKI INOUE
Scripts By
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
CHI HIG
OSHIKI INOUE
Animation DiFectors
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
yo eR «ax YC
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OX DA
Chief I rector.
KEN]! KODAMA
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
in association with
YOMIURI TELECASTINC
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CC NAN
COWL AOYAMA HOGCAKUKAN YIV:-1A1S
50.000.000 yen is totally impossible.
Po s...
You don't like it, do you
You're thinking that it's not just
a plain kidnapping case. right?
Yea...
881d news!\\.
Conan 1s nowhere In sight!
Come to think oft neither is Al
Al too?
Maybe they both went
to look for Ran...
Smash. of Loverand Resolve
Part ll