Love and hate are brought together...
Through both reasoning and suspense!
This abduction case is more than what it seems.
But as we look into the mysteries, their motive becomes clear!
Seeing through to the one and only truth...
I look like a child, but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan
We went to participate in a tennis tournament at Kumamoto.
After finding a cell phone that someone had dropped, Ran and Sonoko...
Went to give it back to its owner.
But there, unable to defend herself...
Ran was kidnapped by someone!
The Smash of Determination and Love
The Smash of Determination and Love:
Part 2!
We kidnapped a high school girl by the name of Mouri Ran.
If you want her back, prepare a ransom of fifty-million yen.
With the ransom in hand, board the
Amakusa Fair Line cruise ship that departs at 3:00 PM.
Once there, we'll coll with further instructions.
Damn it!
It's impossible to get fifty million!
Not to mention that we only have two hours until it's 3:00 PM!
Uncle...
Mouri-san, about this case...
Authoritative locals heard that you were involved, and offered their assistance.
I want to thank you for that.
That's why I'd like to be the one to deliver the ransom money.
But that's...
Please, allow me to do this much.
I can't bear to sit here doing nothing.
Very well.
But please, follow all of our instructions, and refrain from taking any careless action.
Of course. Thank you.
Why the troubled look?
Haibara.
I take it you also believe that this isn't just a mere kidnapping.
Yeah...
Why did the culprits call the police and give them the ransom instructions?
That's true.
An ordinary culprit usually tries to avoid the police as much as possible.
On top of that, they gave us two hours until the ransom exchange.
It's as if they're waiting for the investigation to progress.
Sounds like it.
And there's another thing that bothers me.
The last words Ran said over the phone...
I overheard those people say —they're going to kill someone today—
So...
This ransom might just be a smoke screen.
It's very possible that Ran was kidnapped simply to keep their murderous plan under the radar.
That would mean that giving them the ransom money doesn't guarantee her liberty.
Yeah...
But the culprits went to the trouble of kidnapping her instead of simply killing her on the spot.
That means her chance of survival isn't zero.
You're right.
For now, we have to find out where Ran is being confined.
Everything should become much clearer after that.
T-This is terrible!
I can't find Conan anywhere.
Now that you mention it, I don't see Haibara-san either...
Haibara-san's gone too?!
Honestly! The semi-finals are about to start!
Could it be...
Could it be that they both went to look for Ran-san?
It's no use.
I couldn't find a single clue that could lead to the culprits.
And no one's even heard of a "Hirukomachi."
Damn it!
I searched on the Internet and found a few things...
But they're all too far away to be what we want.
Ran gave us a call about an hour after she was kidnapped.
If we assume they traveled by car, they have to be within a 40km radius.
And since there is no Hirukomachi within that range...
We're most likely reading it wrong, or it's someone's name.
Haibara, can you look for any towns with a similar spelling?
I'll start looking in the phone book for anyone who goes by that name.
Hiru... Hiru... Hiru... Hiru... Hiru...
Hey, guys.
Finally found you.
You... What about the match?
That was mean! We're worried about Ran-san too!
Don't take us for idiots.
Sonoko-san was crying at the hotel, too.
That's it!
Ran... Ran...
Answer! Please!
Come on! Aren't you a detective's daughter?
Ran!
Oh... It's just you, Conan-kun.
Sonoko-neechan, it's about the cellphone you found.
Did you notice anything else besides the text message?
Huh?
Now that you mention it...
I got another text right before we got to the cafe.
You should have said that earlier, damn it.
What?!
Oh, nothing.
Anyway, what did it say?
Well, it was really weird.
"Sonoko, if something happens where I can't make it today, could you burn incense at her grave without me?"
You can also offer her some of the sunflowers that bloom behind the Yokomachi factory."
That was the text I got.
On the other side of the sunflowers, there's a billboard.
Note: The kanji 4?ST can be read as either "Hirukomachi" or "Yokomachi"
It's Yokomachi!
Yokomachi... Yokomachi...
There it is!
It's written as "hiruko," but it's actually Yokomachi Clinic.
I found it!
Conan-kun! What's going on?
Hey, ore you still there?!
What's his problem? Just hanging up all of a sudden?
Wait a minute...
Ran said she saw sunflowers...
Th-This is terrible!
I'm coming for you, Ran.
At last, we're coming up to the final match.
Who will be the victor of this tournament?
Will it be Tachikawa Masato?
Or will it be the gifted Mabuchi Kyouhei?
They now come together for a firm handshake.
While Tachikawa Masato always keeps a cool head...
Mabuchi Kyouhei plays with furor.
How fitting that the finalists of the first annual tournament are two Kumamoto natives.
Don't you move!
If you move, I'll have to... use this!
Thanks for the ride!
Sure thing, take care!
There's the sunflower field!
All right, Detective
Boys...
1 Yeah!
Yeah
Win! You gotta win!
Never fear, for the Detective Boys are here!
Are you okay, Ran-neechan?
Thank you, Conan-kun!
Thank goodness.
We're glad you're safe!
Sorry for the delay.
Thank you, everyone!
Oh yeah, something terrible is about to happen.
They were saying something about today being their only chance to kill someone.
We have to inform the police!
Today's their only chance?
W-What?
Hideki, you...
Y-You lost to a girl?
Damn you!
Ow.
This is payback!
All right, now just leave him to me!
Don't try to resist!
Looks like the jig is up for you guys.
Yes?
What? Really?
Understood, we're heading there right now.
Mouri-san, you don't need to board the ship anymore.
The police sure are taking their time...
Yeah,they are.
By the way, who were you two planning to kill?
Well, if you won't say, I'll figure it out myself.
Since today is your only chance...
He has to be someone connected to this tournament.
The fact that you're watching the match on TV right now proves that.
When I looked up directions to get here, this map didn't have much information about this place...
But the man who gave us a ride clued me in.
This steel factory is owned by none other than the sponsor of the tennis tournament, Narimasu Kenzo-san.
Is it possible that he's your boss too?
There's no way in hell we'd work for that bastard!
Keep your mouth shut, you idiot!
In other words, you were planning on killing Narimasu-san, weren't you?
What is it?
They hit my head when they abducted me, and the pain's starting to get to me now.
Hey, are you okay?
Conan-kun, there's one more culprit!
The guy who hit me is still out there!
What?!
Is that someone named Sonoko?
No, I think it's a man.
I remember hearing a third man's voice before I blacked out.
You don't think that he's still...
He's still trying to kill Narimasu-san!
What?!
Suspend the tennis tournament and focus on protecting Narimasu?
Yeah.
There is another culprit in addition to those who are here.
And that person's after Narimasu-san's life!
W-W-W-Wait a second!
So are you saying that they didn't kidnap Ran for the ransom?
Yes, but we don't have time to talk about that right now.
If we don't hurry, Narimasu-san's life will be in danger!
I got it! But I'll have you explain later.
Inspector Tamana.
Understood. I'll get right on it.
Don't shit with me!
My political life depends on this tournament.
And you want the police to stick their noses into this?
B-But your life may be in danger...
I don't care!
After all, I pay these men a fortune for a reason!
I will not cancel the tournament!
Let the match continue!
That's odd...
They're still playing.
I wonder why.
Hey, Conan?
Norimasu-san.
This turned out to be an amazing match.
What's your opinion as a sponsor of the tournament?
I'm really blessed for being a sponsor.
I heard that someone's trying to kill me today, but...
I'm not one to fear a threat like that!
/, Narimasu, am willing to risk my life for the people of my hometown, Kumamoto.
Unbelievable...
5-So, let's watch and see who will win and receive the prized Cup...
From the tournament committee chairman, Narimasu Kenzo!
Will it be Tachikawa Masato or Mabuchi Kyouhei?
What do we do, Conan?
Too bad! So much for your effort.
I'll let you in on something.
Narimasu doesn't care if his life is in danger.
He hires bodyguards, and pays them a ton of money to make sure he doesn't get killed.
Of course!
If they're simply trying to kill him, they could do it any other day.
Especially since he still has bodyguards protecting him right now.
But Ran heard them say that today is their only chance.
Why?
Why today?
Sonoko-san.
Can't Sonoko-san stop the murder?
Didn't you say that Sonoko-san didn't like the idea?
This whole plan of yours.
Maybe you all really wanted Sonoko-san to come and stop you.
And that's why you sent her those text messages.
Shut up!
We're taking revenge for what he did to that person'.
And Narimasu caused Sonoko the most suffering out of all of us!
So this is also for Sonoko!
But maybe Sonoko-san was trying to put it all in the past.
Isn't that why she's been against the murder?
Say, about that person you mentioned...
Would she happen to be Saeki-san, the one who committed suicide when she was Narimasu-san's secretary?
So I was right.
Today is the anniversary of Saeki-san's death, isn't it?
And haven't you visited her grave together every year?
Don't you think Sonoko-san's waiting for you there?
She believes that you've stopped the plan, and she's waiting there for you guys!
She's waiting for you!
It's too late.
It's true that Sonoko can stop the murder.
But it's already too late.
Hey, Hideki!
The match is almost over.
You idiot!
What?
Whether you like it or not, it's the last game.
Tachikawa is serving for the set. Start!
I see! Now I understand!
That's why today is their only chance!
S-So, let's watch and see who will win and receive the prized Cup...
From the tournament committee chairman, Narimasu Kenzo!
In the tournament, there's a short moment when Narimasu-san's bodyguards aren't around.
But which one is it?
Which one's the culprit?
They are both from this town.
And they're both around the same age.
Which one?
Which one's the culprit?
Damn it!
What's that?
This is...!
I found it.
The culprit is this guy!
It's a helicopter!
It must be the police.
Ran! Hey, Ran!
Are you okay, Ran?!
Yeah, I'm okay!
I'm sorry, Ron! You must have been so scored.
Sonoko!
Say, I know your motive for wanting to kill Narimasu-san...
But there's something I still don't get.
It's not like you brats could understand how we feel.
Yeah, I don't even want to know...
Why people like you feel the need to kill someone.
Who do you think you are?
I'm Edogawa Conan, a detective.
Inspector, we need to hurry to the tennis courts.
I know who the other culprit is.
W-What?
We need to hurry or we'll be too late!
We now award the victor with the trophy.
The winner, Tachikawa Masato-dono.
In the first annual "Volcanic Cup" Charitable Tennis Tournament...
You have proven yourself to be a master of tennis.
To celebrate your victory, we grant you a commemorative trophy.
Tachikawa-san, to the stage please.
Congratulations.
It's been a while, Narimasu-san.
Where have we met?
I was working under Saeki-san at your factory ten years ago.
I'm Tachikawa.
T-Ten years ago?
Saeki?
D-Don't tell me, you...
So you finally remember?
I was working my ass off at your factory, but you barely paid me enough to survive!
That Tachikawa Masato!
Don't move!
I was worried for Saeki-san when I heard she was hired as your secretary after you became a member of congress.
You made Saeki-san bear all your sins and killed her!
N-No, Saeki commited suicide!
You made her commit suicide!
Damn it.
She was such a good person.
When we were running off from your factory ten years ago...
Saeki-san stopped us when we planned to kill you!
But we should have really killed you back then.
If we had, Saeki-san wouldn't have died.
Stop! Please spare me!
Beg Saeki-san for forgiveness in the other world!
Tachikawa Masato!
Drop your weapon and release him!
Shut up! If you get any closer—
Please stop, Masato!
It's me, Sonoko!
S-Sonoko!
Haven't you done enough, Masato?
Today is the anniversary of Saeki-san's death!
Saeki-san's feeling lonely without us there!
Come on... Let's go there together!
Please!
Sonoko...
Please, no!
Saeki-san loved watching you play tennis!
Don't destroy that!
Saeki-san was so happy when you became a professionals
Please don't make her cry up in heaven!
Masato...
Three days later, Congressman
Narimasu was arrested on corruption charges.
And the headlines of every newspaper in the country revealed the truth behind Secretary Saeki's suicide.
Our post-tournament celebration didn't last long...
As Haibara and I are being held responsible for missing the final round...
No, we actually only missed the semi-finals.
My, my...
Conan, you weakling!
Do your best!
You only have three more laps to go!
I'll run with you.
Oh, okay.
Well, looks like it's time for me to run too!
H-Hey!
Haibara-san, good morning!
Well then, how about we join in on the fun?
Wait for me!
Let's go!