Suspense and deduction
closes the gap between
the love and hatred
between two people
I es fishing, fireworks. and yakata boat!
Accident turns into crime
and fireworks lighting up!
He sees through the
one and only truth,
a child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Sayori'Unabara
Sayori Unabara
AR 93 )RD
FST SA) (48 - (TR
Kazuyuki Ka
T+ EEG
DUT Le
Is xt
Welcome! The entrance is this way.
Unabara Maru, that's the one!
Welcome!
The entrance Is this way.
Well, Mr Kawai, thank
you or mvu mg us over
Same here.
You've been so much help to me in
SO Many ways that.its<s" no big deal
Getting to watch the fireworks
on.a houseboat, is §6 fantastic!
It sure is rare that they're having
fireworks at this time of season.
Hey, come on, @onan!
Hi there, sorry to keep
you all waiting!
Had 2 big transaction to take care of
Mr. Yamazaki,
I'm sorry that I suddenly asked
you to come despite your busy schedule
I've got your fishing
equipment ready too.
Tsuneo Yamazaki
* 208
Li es} 183 (60)
reset iu
All you can eat, all you ean drink,
and watching fireworks too
Tsuneo Yamazaki
ec 28s
Liwi} {ER ( 0)
PAL NHN
EX FER GE Tada VAX
All you can eat, all you can drink,
and watching fireworks too
To top things off I also get to go fishing.
I couldn't possibly refuse.
Captain, please sail the ship
out because we're all here.
Yes sir!
Houseboat Fishing Shock
- cat LU 1}
This ship is*so spacious, and
yet we're the only ones on board?
The fact is, I reserved
this boat for our company's
pleasure trip, but
urgent work came In...
I couldn't cancel the
trip at this point, so
I asked Mr Yamazaki and Mr. Mourn,
whom I'm always being helfid by
to come along.
Hank you for waiting!
Oh! Here's the food!
Finally, at last!
Go ahead everybody~helpgg,
yourselfrto your hearts content!
Here, Mr. Kawai, have some too.
How do you like this fishing pole?
So that's the carbon type new model
fishing pole that is your pride and joy?
It's light as well as steady so
even a big catch is no big deal.
Please use this tonight.
And? What about you. Mr. Kawai
No need for worry. I brought
one of the same type with me.
Is that so.
Wouldyyou like'to come along™
with us too, Mr Mouri?
What?
I'm talking about finishing.
But, I don't have a pole for Mr. Mouril
You may use the one we have
ere, if it's-okay with you
We have several fishing poles
here just in case..for our customers.
EC. J
You're really service
minded. howithoughtful.
Mr. Mouri, are you
interested in fishing
Fishing...
I think I'll pass!
Lim more interested
in drinking moreibeer!
Hello, we're almost there!
The scenic point for watching fireworks
IS also a great spot for fishing!
Just the other day; a super
Iarge sea bream was caught here.
The tides are good today so
I'm sure you'll get a good catch.
It makes me so excited!
I wish you both the best of luck.
Yeah, I'll get
a big one folsure!
The same here
This-is~-amazing!
It<s-soOo«pretty!
Tamaya!
Are you enjoying yourselves?
Yes, watching fireworks in
Ala utumn is quite fascinating too.
Here, have some more...
Oh, thank you.
Sayori, will you please
bring us more beer?
Yes, Sir.
Bring some for Mr. Kawai
and his guest too.
Yes. Sir.
What was that?
What seems to be the matter?
Th... That...
Mr. Kawai, please get
a hold, of yourself! Mr. Kawai!
WwW. Where's Mr. Yamazaki?
Are you okay, mister?
Don't touch!
Stay out of the way!
No good. he's already dead...
1 He's got burns on the
palm of his hand.
What is this .
The lights on the ship
went out a while ago
Yeah...
He said this fishing
pole is made of carbon
Just as I thought!
This part of the. electrical
Iighting is exposed!
Which means...
Right...
Mr.Yamazaki was holding a carbon type
fishing pole that conducts electricity
His feet is soaked with the
seawater that was in the bucket
Mr Yamazaki's fishing pole probably
accidentally touched the
part of the electrical wiring
that was exposed while
he was fishing.
Therefore, he was electrocuted.
That accounts for the
burn on the palm of his hand.
Mr. Kawai probably collapsed
when he tried to help Mr. Yamazaki.
Please call the ambulance
and the police Sayori.
Yes, sir!
Captain, please take the
boat back to the harbor.
Yes, Sir.
And. what is the cause of his death?
We can't really say until the
coroner finishes the autopsy. but
According to the paramedics...
Lets see, the victim's heart seems
to have stopped instantaneously
That is what the report said.
Just asl thought .
But why did Mr. Yamazaki's fish. ng
pole touch the electrical wiring?
There were practically no
waves today and it was quiet,
so the boat didn'trsway as
mu MW either. did it?
Tiha 8 true...
Mr. Kawai, can" you
tell us what happened?
Yes, well the thing is, I happened to
get a big bite on my pole
It was so big that I
couldn't handle it alone, so...
I asked Mr. Yamazaki to help me
We were pulling the pole
together when suddenly...
The line cut and we fell
backwards holding the fishing pole
Then, everything went black...
It's as if I had
murdered Mr. Yamazaki
If only I didn't ask Mr Yamazaki to help
me the, this wouldn't have happened!
Please calm down
It was an accident.
It's not your fault. Mr. Kawa
About Mr. Kawai's testimony just now,
when this case took place...
Accident!
O@h, lim-sonry...
The captain of a boat that was sailing
nearby also witnessed the scene
Yes, I saw it. It looked as if they
were both trying to pull up a fish
Takeshiu
ANAL) RD
I think it was just when they were
about to pull the fish up when
Takeshiu.
AA FT (> UL. C
Lh ow 28
LARA] ROY
It looked to be that the fishing
Iine was so close to
TakeshiU.
AH FF LC
MER) AK
It looked to be that the fishing
Iine was so close to
Takeshiu
the rim of the boat that it was
virtually rubbing against it.
Then, the fishing line suddenly
broke off and they both fell.
We sailed pass them right after that,
so I don't know what happened later
This was what he saw...
J Seel So, it Was an accident after all!
You even got a witness
But both of them got electrocuted, «
and why was only Mr. Kawai okay
Mr. Yamazaki had a weak
heart to begin with so he
was going to the
hospital on a regular basis
Come to think of it, he was
also taking medication
I was just luc
By the way, Mr Unabara, was that
electric wiring always exposed like that?
I always check the
en ire oa ee ore sal ing o
but I didn't notice any
abnormalities at that time.
I also checked: so
there's no mistake about it.
Part of the vinyl covering of the'electrical
wiring was pr bably deteriorated
and wh " the fishing pole touched it,
it completely peeled off.
So it was an accident after all...
But, if so the responsibility of
this accident/will fallflupon
Captain Unabara, who left the electrical
wiring in such a dangerous condition
That's not fair!
I'm sorry. I was just
mentioning a possibility
I'm sorry, will you all,please explain
things in a little mor ) detail?
Of course
Thank you.
Shall we start then
Ouch!
This is...
What's this?
The plastiis melted as if it's been burnt
Strange...
Drops of the malted plastic should
be somewhere, yet, there's none...
I get it, that's why he...
I've figured it out.this was no
accident that happened by accident.
It's homicide!
All right then, Mr. Unabara, Mr. Kawai
I'd like to submit a
formal report of the accident.
SO although I know it's
inconvenient for you.
Please come with me to the station.
Yes. Sir.
As to the rest of you here,
you may go for tonight
wait! Conan's not here!
I tell you, going here,
there and everywhere all the time
I'm here.
Just what were you doing?
We're going home
¥ Wait, I gotta to the restroom!
@h bey. oh boy...
Please waitdeveryone!
This is no accident that
happened coincidentally.
B.But, Mr. Mouri, you just mentioned
a while ago that it was an accident
Yes, but there is
something that's bothering me
Mr. Unabara,
can you show everyone the tip of the fish
Iine that is cut, that Mr. Kawai was using
Yes...
Mr. Unabara, what do you
think, seeing that cut line?
What do I think?
Wait, this is strange this
doesn't look to have been pulled apart
It looks as if it's been cut
by a knife or something
Really?
Officer
Yes?
Please check the brim
of the left shipboard.
The blade of a cutter
knife is embedded.
And, a fish hook is hooked on
the body of the ship underneath it.
Okay.
I'll go along too.
There it is!
It's the blade of a cutter!
Officer!
See, over there!
It's the fish line!
Mr-Moun!
It's exactly as you said.
The blade of the cutter
and fish hook are still here.
When I gleaned the ship before
departing, they weren't there.
Sure they weren't, because
Mr. Kawai set it up after sailing out to
the sea, in order to kill Mr. Yamazaki
W.What a thing to say. Mr. Moun?
When just Mr. Yamazaki and you
were the only ones on deck,
ou embedded the blade of the
cutter into the brim of the ship
when Mr. Yamazaki's
eyes weren't on you
As well as, hook your fish
hook onto the body of the ship
You pretended to have caught a big one,
and urged Mr. Yamazaki to help you
When Mr. Yamazaki
grabs your fishing pole
the blade inserted in the
brim of the ship cuts the line
Finally, you pushed
Mr. Yamazaki down
so that the fishing pole would
touch the electrical wiring.
D.Don't be ridiculous!
I was electrocuted 100, you know!
I was almost: Killed myself too!
Yes, if you.were barehanded
and barefooted like Mr: Yamazaki.
Just what.do you mean, Mr. Mour...
Mr. Kawai, will you show me
what's in your pocket?
1.l really don't have
anything inside
Mr. Kawai, will you please
show us what's inside?
What is it? I...
Please!
Mr Kawai...
A flesh colored rubber glove?
Mr. Kawai...
That's a pretty odd glove to
[xa mst de ting, Hot v 669
It's up to:me what kind of a
glove I want to use; isn't it?
Besides, this just so
happened to be in my pocket.
I was bare-handed when
that accident ocSlrred
Or is it that somebody
saw me wearing gloves?
The same.goes: for
the blade of the cutter.
I'll bet you don:t
have proof that: did it!
It was just an mere coincidental
accident that Yamazaki died!
I'm sure you had an
intention to kill him!
What?
Think:-about it.
+ When:you pull a fish line that almost
rubs against the brim of the ship,
you'd have to pull it
vertically against the brim
If the fish line was suddenly cut,
they would've fallen
perpendicular to the brim of the ship
But in order for the fishing pole
to touch the electrical wiring,
they would have to fall
horizontally to the brim of the ship.
In other words, the moment
the fish line was cut,
you pushed Mr. Yamazaki horizontally
against the brim of the ship.
You did so to make the
fishing pole touch
touch the exposed electrical wiring
with the intention to kill him.
D:Don't be ridiculous!
You're only letting your
imagination run wild!
How can you be so sure that I
pushed Mr. Yamazaki down?
How rude can you get!
Please present more
undeniable evidence!
I have evidence.
Will somebody light
rr. awalrs igrer.
No good.
It doesn't work.
Mr. Kawai,
you lit your cigarette with that lighter
before;we departed, didn't you?
Why won't it light now?
Seems to be what looks to be the burnt
remains on-the wick of the lighter.
That adhered when he burnt the
coating of the electrical wiring...
Mr. Kawai used the liter to melt the
coating of the electrical wiring
in order to expose the
electrical wiring on the inside
He then, probably wore
the robber boots
that were lying around
on the floor of the deck,
and after wearing the
flesh colored rubber gloves
on his hands and insulating himself
he electrocuted
Mr Yamazki and killed him.
He then removed the
boots lying dewn,
and hid the rubber gloves:in his pocket,
and pretended to be passed out
How about it, Mr Kawai,
am I wrong somewhere?
Yamazaki, Yamazaki
tried to take over my company
by lending money at an unreasonably
high amount of interest.
Not only that, as collateral
for the money he lent me,
he insisted that I get
myself an expensive
Iife insurance policy
with him as the beneficiary
If. didn't kill him, hé would:ve
killed me one day anyway
Some a...
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers
hi, Nga oe HK
Background Mus:
KATSUOQ ONO
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDO
7 Story Editor.
Scripts By.
KAN] I"KASHIWAB ARA
KAZUNARI.KOUGHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITIA
YUICHI HIGURE
I@OSHIKI INOUE
Scripts By
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONQ@BU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chit Director.
KEN]! KODAMA
roduced
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
In association wath,
YOMIURI TELECASTANG
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE Ct NAN
(>) J AOYAMA 11 CAKUKAN YTV
All Ri I Reserved
Mr. Mourn...
Thank you so much the other day.
If that incident was closed
as an accidental case,
I would've had to take responsibility
for negligence of duty and
close down my business.
It's all thanks to you. Mr. Mouri
<< - A
If the investigation was carried
Ou onyon »1e.sur ace,
the case couldn't have been
genuinely solved at all.
Just as expected of the renown
detective. Mr. Kogoro Mour!.
Absolutely!
There-is«no-case that I cannot solve!
Oh come on. Pad. you were
probably just in good shape
Yeah, as for being in good shape,
you're sure doing-just as good
as those fireworks up there
Ta-maya!
Erisissto blame for taking
on a-case like this
The defendant has a motive
for Killing the victim, and moreover,
his fingerprints were detected super
clearly on the dial of the safe.
How the heck does she expect
to defend somebody like that?
Just as I thought!id
I can't see Pops from here at:all
because the partition is in the way!
Whatldidnyou-say!
(BIH)
\Battle in Court Kisaki vs.:Kujo /
Part 1