Filling in the distance between hate and love...
The deductions and the suspense of two people!
A difficult case in search of the truth.
A courtroom clash between Kisaki and the prosecution!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
An onsen, huh?
We haven't been to one in so long, have we?
And it's fall leaf-viewing season now, isn't it?
That's right!
I recommend this open-air bath.
They say this onsen is really good for the body!
Mom, you have to take a break from work once in a while and just relax.
You're right.
Kuriyama-san!
What does my schedule look like for next month?
The current court case is scheduled to be resolved next week, so...
What's left depends on what you decide as far as the issue of the duty roster...
That's right...
There was that.
If you would bring the documents for that...
Yes, ma'am!
What's a duty roster?
Sometimes there are defendants who cannot employ the services of a lawyer due to financial reasons and such.
That's when the government appoints an attorney, but when none of us wants the case, it's left to the duty roster.
Thank you.
I've only given the case a quick glance-over, but...
I wonder why no one chose to take it on?
It looks like the defendant has a decent case here...
I wonder if it's because the opponent is unfavorable?
The opponent?
The one heading this case is Prosecutor Kujou.
I see.
The Madonna of Prosecutors, huh?
COURTROOM CONFRONTATION II: KISAKI VS KUJOU
(PART ONE)
What should we do?
Should we say we're occupied and refuse it?
Say, Kisaki-sensei...
What kind of a case is it?
It's something that occurred about a month ago.
The body of a company's president was found in his office in Haido City.
From the fingerprints and the articles left inside the room...
They were able to apprehend the defendant—a habitual offender that had broken into many establishments.
It doesn't seem like a case that would end up in court...
That's true...
Since the defendant had already admitted to breaking in, being discovered by the victim...
And against his better judgment, hitting the victim in the head with the ashtray during the struggle.
he problem is with the charge listed on the indictment.
The charge?
On the indictment, it is charged as a robbery-murder.
Murder?
But in that case, wouldn't it be an accidental death?
Yeah.
I find it hard to imagine Prosecutor Kujou would have made such a mistake, though.
Kuriyama-san...
I already have the prosecutorial and fact-falsehood memos, but...
I still lack the conditional examination papers—could you get them for me?
I'll also need a copy of the autopsy report.
Mom...
Sorry, Ran.
Due to this, the onsen will have to wait for another time.
Tokyo Detention Center
Let me confirm once more with you.
On the night of the incident...
You broke the window to the Ootsu Real Estate Company's office on the second floor of the Nomoto Building...
Inoue Takashi (55)
Suspect
And proceeded to enter the office.
While you were searching around the office, and trying to open the safe in the company president's office...
You were discovered by the company's president, Ootsu Toshiyuki, when he returned for business purposes.
Then, during the struggle, you used the glass ashtray to strike him in the head.
All this resulting in death.
This is all correct, yes?
Right.
What happened to the money in the safe?
I don't know.
However, according to testimony from the company employees...
The 12,000,000 yen in cash taken in that day from a real estate transaction had disappeared.
The prosecution believes that, after you killed President Ootsu, you opened the safe and stole the money.
It wasn't me!
I really don't know anything about it.
It's certainly true that the money wasn't found in your room, but...
Given that your fingerprints were found on the dial of the safe, the prosecution's suspicions aren't entirely baseless.
I really didn't take the money...
And about that person...
That person?
Did you know the victim beforehand?
How many times did you strike the victim's head?
Dunno.
Was it one time?
Two times?
I don't remember.
After all, I was surprised and discovered unexpectedly.
According to the autopsy, there are traces of the victim having been struck three times.
And it was the third that proved to be the fatal blow.
If it were a single time, it'd be best.
But with two or three times, the possibility exists that you would be regarded as having intended to kill him.
I really don't remember.
I see.
I am your ally, so even if it's unfavorable towards your case, please tell me everything honestly.
Let me confirm once more.
You really didn't intend to kill the victim, correct?
That's right.
I understand.
In court, we shall press that one point in our argument.
Thanks.
Tokyo District Court
The defendant Inoue Takashi, at approximately 20:30 hours on the night of the incident...
The Case of the Robbery-Murder of the Real Estate Company President
First Public Hearing
On the second floor of the Nomoto Building in Haido City Block 3-2-9...
Broke the window of the Ootsu Real Estate president's office and trespassed.
While searching for money and other goods...
He was discovered by that company's president, Ootsu Toshiyuki, who had returned to attend to business matters.
Using a weapon in his possession...
He threatened that same person to open the door of the safe in the room...
And utilizing a glass ashtray that was also in the room, struck the victim's head three times until he was dead.
He then stole the 12,000,000 yen deposited in the safe, and escaped.
Therefore, we request that the defendant be charged under Article 240 of the Penal Code, Robbery-Murder...
And sentenced to life in prison with hard labor.
Does the defendant admit to the prosecution's accusation?
Or do you deny it?
I only entered to steal...
As far as intention to kill...
Your Honor!
Proceed, counselor.
The accusation is robbery-murder...
But the defendant did not intend to murder the victim.
Therefore I would like to raise an objection.
So he denies the charge of robbery-murder?
I believe it would be more appropriate to change the charge from Article 240 to Article 205, Assault Leading to Death.
The defense appears to have an objection with the prosecution's accusation.
Do you have any concerns?
Yes, just one.
The reason the defendant chose Ootsu Real Estate...
Why was that?
It was just that while I was looking for a building to enter and steal from...
I happened to come across that building by chance.
If that's the case...
It was just a coincidence that you chose to steal from Ootsu Real Estate...
And you contend you had no existing grudge whatsoever against the victim Ootsu Toshiyuki.
Is all of this correct?
Yes.
I wonder what Prosecutor Kujou is trying to say...
Your Honor!
The prosecution's aim with this line of questioning is unclear!
Well then.
The defendant is familiar with a female by the name of Endou Noriko, correct?
Well?
There's no reason you would forget your only daughter.
Only daughter?
Here it is!
She was only eight years old when he divorced his ex-wife twenty years ago.
But I wonder what that has to do with this?
Is it that you can't answer?
Objection!
The prosecution only seeks to put the defendant at unease by bringing up the name of a blood relative!
Is that daughter relevant to the court in any way?
Yes.
Endou Noriko runs a snack stand in another building that Ootsu Real Estate manages.
It has been rumored that she was involved with the victim, Ootsu Toshiyuki.
You're saying it was not by coincidence the defendant broke into the building that became the crime scene?
Yes.
We also have testimony to the effect that the defendant held a grudge against the victim because of his daughter.
That's wrong!
I don't know anything about that!
If that's the case, shall we ask the person in question?
Since she is in the visitor's gallery, after all.
We can have her come out here.
Endou Noriko (28)
Inoue Takashi's Daughter
Daddy...
Noriko...
So this is the card the Madonna had hidden up her sleeve?
If it's necessary, we are prepared to have Endou-san testify as well.
So it's true what the prosecutor said?
Yes.
I was deceived by that man.
He said sweet things such as how he would allow me to keep the shop, and took terrible advantage of me.
When did you get into contact with your father?
I reunited with him nearly two years ago when my mother passed away from illness.
Ever since, he would occasionally stop by my shop.
And you told him about Ootsu-san then?
He said he'd get consolation money out of him for me.
Well, it's certainly turned into an unfavorable situation.
Why's that?
Because, if he held a grudge against the other party and hit him as many as three times...
No one would believe him even if he said he didn't intend to kill the victim.
I see.
Lastly, I'd like for you to answer me truthfully...
Do you also think your father murdered Ootsu Toshiyuki-san?
No, Daddy likes stealing, but he's not someone who would kill a person!
I see.
It looks like the battle to come will be an intense one this time...
Geez, Dad...
Dozing off again!
I was just resting my eyes while thinking!
Who's dozing off?
Then, have you hit upon it?
A good idea you can use to help Mom.
Well...
Taking on this sort of case, it's Eri's own fault!
The defendant had a motive to murder, and on top of that his fingerprints were clearly on the dial of the safe.
How is somebody supposed to defend against that?
But I wonder why the dial on the safe was the only place his fingerprints were found?
As for that, he probably snuck in wearing gloves!
But, since gloves get in the way when it comes to precise tasks such as turning the dial on a safe, he removed them.
That's when the victim came in, and so using the ashtray...
If that's the case, his fingerprints should also be on the ashtray since it was the weapon, right?
Yeah.
Since he'd taken his gloves off.
But there were no fingerprints left on the ashtray.
Well, of course he wiped his fingerprints off afterward!
Let me see that!
Read this part carefully!
Isn't it written here that there are traces of it having been wiped down with an oil-stained cloth?
If that's so, why didn't he wipe down the safe as well?
No, that's because...
He accidentally killed someone, so in his haste, he fled and forgot about it.
I see.
But I wonder when he stole the money from the safe?
Well, after he committed the murder, he opened the safe again, and...
Didn't you just say he fled in haste?
Well...
Somehow, it seems mismatched, doesn't it?
Idiot!
Criminals do all kinds of things that don't make sense!
Isn't that just a sophism?
Shut up!
I'm getting out of here!
Wait, Dad, where are you going?
Geez...
List of Articles Found at the Crime Scene
1. Glass Ashtray
2. 1 Pair of Army Cotton Gloves
3. Eyeglasses screw
4. Golf Ball
Oh, Dear!
Oh, it's you.
What are you doing here?
No, just something...
You came to the scene of the crime to see if there was anything you could do to help Kisaki-sensei, right?
Shut up!
Enough!
Mr. Great Detective sure has a lot of free time, doesn't he?
What's that!?
Kisaki-sensei, you came to investigate the crime scene as well, right?
That's right.
I'm getting permission from the building manager right now.
Akiyama Takuya (56) Building Manager
Thank you for waiting.
This way, please.
Mister, you were the first person to discover the company president?
That's right, my boy.
Could we hear a detailed account of what happened at that time?
Yeah.
On that night, at around 9:00, I was watching a baseball game on TV when...
Arima-san!
Have you seen Dad—no, I mean, Mr. President?
When I made my rounds at 8:00, no one was in the office...
That's strange.
When he left my restaurant a bit ago, he said he was coming back to the office.
In that case, he must've come in through one of the emergency exits.
But, the door to the office is locked, and there was no answer even though I called for him many times.
Wouldn't he be in the rear office?
I came to drop off the reading glasses he left behind.
Sorry, but could you come and open the door for me?
No problem.
The Arima-san you mentioned was President Ootsu's adopted son-in-law, correct?
Yes.
He runs a nearby Italian restaurant.
So it was this door that was locked, right?
I used this spare key to open the door.
It sure doesn't look like he's here.
Dad, you there?
It's me, Masahiko!
Strange...
Huh?
There's someone there!
Oh no!
What's wrong?
Someone inside is being beaten!
What'd you say!?
The key for the door!
The company president is the only one with the key to this door!
Damn...
Move aside please!
Dad!
Hang in there!
Akiyama-san, please hurry and call an ambulance!
Yes!
The company president's office is over there, correct?
Hey, this door is locked.
Arima-san is in possession of the key to this room.
Here he is.
Arima-san...
This is Kisaki-san, the attorney I mentioned on the phone and...
I'm Detective Mouri Kogorou.
Arima Masahiko (35)
Proprietor of an Italian Restaurant
You're the famous...
Well...
Arima-san, apologies for interrupting your work.
We were wondering if you would let us take a look in the company president's office.
Say, is this room not being used right now?
Even though the police have already completed their investigation...
Since it was the room in which Dad died under such circumstances...
It's hard to say what we'll do with it from now on.
Go ahead.
It's just as the police left it.
Thank you.
So, Arima-san...
Where was it that the victim fell?
Let's see...
It was right around here, in front of the safe.
He was on the floor, cradling his head in his arms.
I see.
So that's how it was.
"That's how it was"?
Most likely, Inoue was discovered by the victim as he was trying to open the safe.
The defendant had already stated as much.
What's important is what happened afterward.
Inoue used a knife or something he had hidden on him to threaten the victim into opening the safe.
And then, when it was opened, he used the ashtray, and from behind...
Struck him down.
You're not saying the defendant is lying, are you?
Well, if he wanted you believe that he was innocent, that's probably it.
There's no way to defend a defendant if you don't believe him, is there?
You can say all the neat phrases you want, but you're only going to get thrashed by that Madonna!
Say Mister, where you saw the culprit from...
Was it this tiny window?
That's right.
Really?
Hey, Conan.
Just what are you up to?
Uncle Kogorou, could you stand in front of the safe again for me?
Geez...
What is this about?
Around here?
Just wait there for a bit.
As I thought.
Ah-le!
From here, Uncle is hidden by the screen and I can't see him at all!
What'd you say?
Akiyama-san...
What's the meaning of this?
Oh, no...
What I saw wasn't over there.
It was just the shadow of a person I saw reflected over on this wall.
A shadow reflected on the wall?
Yes.
At that time, the lights in the room were off...
And I saw the culprit's shadow reflected by the neon lights shining in from the window.
The shadow of someone hitting Ootsu-san over and over.
And after that, I also heard the sound of Ootsu-san falling to the ground, so there's no mistake!
I'm going to ask you one more time.
You did not, then, see Defendant Inoue actually striking the victim, correct?
But, Miss Attorney...
It's not an important difference, is it?
The culprit even said that he struck him.
No, Arima-san.
Merely seeing a shadow of someone striking another...
Is completely different from seeing the actual person striking him.
No matter the circumstances, until the defendant is tried and a guilty verdict comes down in court...
He is still considered a defendant, and not a culprit.
When such sad feelings are involved, everyone tends to confuse the two.
Sorry about that.
Say, Mister.
This clock's stopped, you know.
It was a prize that the late company president won in a golf tournament.
It was placed there as a commemoration ornament, and isn't usually used.
Arima-san, if you could come over here a moment.
Yes, ma'am.
What's the matter?
The combination to the safe in question...
Did anyone else know it outside the victim?
No, only my father knew.
For security reasons...
He didn't even tell the accounting heads.
You're in the way, just loitering around!
This is...
I see, I understand it now...
The trick behind this case!
The shadow of someone beating someone else that Akiyama-san supposedly saw...
And the sound of something having fallen...
Using this trick, it could all be manufactured!
And the one who set this trick up...
Gould only be that person!
COURTROOM CONFRONTATION II: KISAKI VS KUJOU
(PART TWO)
Thank you very much for your assistance.
Not at all.
Did you find anything that'll help you in the trial?
Arima Masahiko (35)
Proprietor of an Italian Restaurant
Well, since the police and the prosecution have already investigated everything thoroughly...
It's not like we could have found out anything new.
That's true.
Oh, right!
How about having dinner at my restaurant?
I'll bring out my best wine!
Oh, no thank you.
Since he's offering, let's give it a try!
Dear...
Isn't Ran waiting at home?
Your daughter?
If that's the case, she is welcome as well.
Sorry to trouble you!
Not at all.
Meals taste better when eaten as a group, after all.
Then we shall accept.
This wine is quite magnificent!
I'm honored that you find it to your liking.
The atmosphere of your restaurant is also lovely.
Thank you very much.
I've also been called to appear in the next hearing as a witness.
Please go easy on me.
I believe you discovered your father when you went to deliver something he left behind, right?
He had left his glasses behind after having taken his meal here.
Glasses?
Reading glasses.
Well then, please take your time and enjoy your meal.
Somehow, the pasta doesn't seem quite up to the standards of a fine restaurant, huh?
Seems so.
There's a little too much olive oil.
Anyway, how is it going?
Have you thought up a strategy for the next hearing?
It's pretty difficult.
It's impossible unless you change the legal system.
What do you mean by that?
It's impossible to overturn it from being a robbery-murder.
His daughter can already confirm that, because of his feelings as a parent...
He had a reason to hold a grudge towards the victim.
So you're saying to confirm the prosecution's version of events...
And try for a lesser sentence due to the extenuating circumstances?
There's probably no other way.
This isn't a joke!
The defendant says that he had no intention to murder the victim.
You'll get trounced by the Madonna exactly because you're still being taken in by that!
I don't remember you ever having gone into a courtroom battle.
I don't know why I ever wanted to help you in the first place!
Come on, stop it you two...
How did we come to this?
If I remember correctly, in the list of articles left at the scene...
It should be here.
I found it!
The decisive evidence!
Conan-kun?
What's going on?
Looking at the court documents...
There was just something that bothered me...
Something that bothered you?
List of Articles Found at the Crime Scene
1. Glass Ashtray
2. 1 Pair of Army Cotton Gloves
3. Eyeglasses screw
4. Golf Ball
See, in this list of articles left at the scene of the crime...
Give me that!
Once again you're going through important documents without permission!
Geez.
If you're going to be like that, you'd better come up with something to help Mom out!
I don't even care if that stubborn woman gets beaten to a pulp by the Madonna!
You're saying that, but you really don't have any confidence you can win against that Madonna, right?
Idiot!
That kind of little girl, I could take on two of them at once!
If that's the case, how about if you become the defense attorney, Uncle?
That's not possible.
Dad doesn't have the qualifications to become a defense attorney.
But if he were to become a special counsel, it'd be all right, wouldn't it?
What do you mean?
It's a policy in which, as long as it is at the request of the defendant...
h person who only possesses ordinary qualifications can represent them in court.
Let the people at the court hear one of your great deductions, Uncle!
One of my great deductions, huh?
No matter how hard the case, in my hands...
If it's insisted upon, I guess I'd think about it.
That person is going to become a special counsel?
Yeah!
He said that he absolutely wants to be of assistance to you, Mom!
Thanks, but no thanks.
But...
It's so rare that Dad gets this kind of idea...
Even so, I can't think of any way that person could be helpful.
But...
I have a message from Uncle, for Kisaki-sensei to go to the crime scene tonight, with the building manager.
To that building?
He said you'd be able to see something that would influence the direction of the trial!
The direction of the trial?
Sorry for all the trouble!
I don't really mind, but...
Just what do you want with me?
Well, even I don't know exactly...
Mr. Building Manager...
Could you once again do what you did on the night of the incident?
Hey, Conan-kun...
Where is our man?
He's just outside, making preparations.
Got it, got it.
Akiyama Takuya (56) Building Manager
Do the same thing again, right?
Let me see, on that night we came into this office and no one was here, so...
Arima-san peeked into the company president's office through this small window...
And said, "There's someone there," right?
That's right.
And then when I peeked in...
That...
Could it be...
No way...
Is someone inside?
Why in the world...
Kisaki-sensei, why don't you confirm it with your own eyes?
This is...
I recreated the trick like Uncle told me to.
Trick?
Then, could it be that the culprit is...
Uncle said he'd explain everything in detail at the trial.
The Case of the Robbery-Murder of the Real Estate Company President
Second Public Hearing
If Mom and Dad are joining hands, there's nothing to fear, huh?
Inoue Takashi (55)
Suspect
Honestly...
I never would have expected her to request for Mouri Kogorou as special counsel.
Counselor Kisaki must be at a total loss.
All rise!
Akiyama-san...
You're testifying that you saw, from the small window in the door to the company president's office...
The victim was being beaten by the culprit, correct?
Yes.
How many times did the culprit hit the victim?
From what I saw, it was three times.
And right after that...
You heard the sound of the victim falling to the floor, correct?
No further questions.
Counsel, you may proceed with the cross-examination.
Akiyama-san...
About your witnessing of the victim being struck...
Did you see the face of the person doing the striking?
No, I didn't see the person doing the striking directly...
If you didn't see the person directly, what did you see?
The culprit's shadow reflected on the wall from the light outside the window.
Silence!
What you saw was only the culprit's shadow, correct?
Yes, that's right.
It's the same thing.
Even if it was his shadow, as long as.
hen, I'll ask you one more time.
Akiyama-san, was the defendant here the culprit that you saw?
No, the only thing I saw was the shadow of the person doing the striking, so...
So you don't know whether the person doing the striking was the defendant or not, right?
Thank you.
No further questions.
What is Dad doing!
He's been sleeping the whole time!
His performance is up next, Ran-neechan.
Really?
Moving on, we call witness Arima to the stand.
Arima-san...
Along with the building manager, you heard the sound of the victim falling, correct?
Yes.
There's no doubt about it.
And then you rammed in the president's locked office door, and plunged into the room.
Yes, but...
It was after the culprit had already fled through the window.
My father—I mean President Ootsu—was on the floor.
What was the condition of the safe at that time?
It was left open.
No further questions.
Go ahead, Counsel.
All right, I guess it's about time for me to overturn this trial.
Dad, do your best!
First, we'll take a look at Uncle's skill.
All right, special counsel, please begin your questioning.
Yes, sir.
You went to Ootsu Real Estate at about 9:00 at night in order to deliver something the victim left behind, correct?
Yes.
In order to deliver the reading glasses that my father left behind in my shop.
However, the door to the office was locked, and you couldn't go in.
That's right.
But really, the door wasn't locked, was it?
And the victim was in the company president's office, checking the money in the safe.
What are you saying?
You don't mean that I...
No, just that you also had the chance to commit the crime.
That's ridiculous.
Why would I do that to my father-in-law?
When money is involved, even direct parent-child relationships are pushed to the side.
Surprisingly, Uncle has struck a good point.
The question is obviously nothing more than conjecture!
Objection sustained.
If the defense could please develop their argument on the basis of clearly defined evidence.
But...
From my seven years of experience, it happens very often that the first person to discover the body is the culprit.
Then, using your seven years of experience...
How would you explain the articles left at the scene of the crime...
And the defendant's fingerprints on the dial of the safe?
When the witness and the victim were arguing over the money...
The defendant took in the situation from outside the window.
This is again unestablished.
And further, after the witness beat the victim down and left...
The defendant snuck in and went to steal the money in the safe.
If that's the case, then who was this culprit the building manager witnessed?
In actuality, the victim was not yet dead.
And so he regained consciousness, got into a struggle with the defendant...
If that's the case, then as we were saying, the one who murdered the victim was the defendant, correct?
I guess that's what it comes down to, then...
What are you talking about?
Aren't you here for the sake of defending the defendant?
I am here as a Great Detective in order to shed light on the truth of this case!
I was a fool to rely on you.
That's enough.
Get back here!
Right now?
I'm still in the middle of this important...
It would be appreciated if the marital spat could be conducted elsewhere.
Dad sucks!
I guess that's about as far as Uncle can go.
Anyway, just sit down and shut up.
What am I, an ornament?
I retract my previous statements.
Your Honor!
That's enough already!
The defendant snuck into that room before Arima-san entered, not afterwards.
And, as he was about to open the safe, he was discovered by the victim.
Without thinking, he struck the victim down and immediately fled.
The problem is with what happened after that.
The defendant was convinced that he accidentally killed the victim, but in actuality the victim only lost consciousness.
And immediately after that, the victim was murdered by someone who came to the scene of the crime.
Are you saying that's me?
You testified the victim forgot his reading glasses at your shop, correct?
Does he need his reading glasses even while he's eating?
Without them, he can't even read the menu.
Isn't that strange?
In the indictment, it is written that the victim was forced by the culprit to open the safe.
If he didn't have his reading glasses...
I wonder how the victim turned the dials on the safe?
In that dark office in which only the neon signs from the neighboring building were shining.
Huh...
I have no idea either.
Wasn't the victim still alive up until you delivered the reading glasses?
Are you there?
What's wrong?
You have a wound on your head!
Leave it!
It's nothing!
It was after he had discovered the robber.
After he regained consciousness, what he should have been the most concerned about was the money.
If you're looking for your glasses, here.
When you saw that money...
A murderous urge was born within you...
And you murdered the victim with the toppled ashtray.
Prosecutor!
I was called here as a witness, but now I'm being treated as the culprit!
Mouri-san...
You have forgotten one important fact.
That the witness has an alibi for the time of the crime.
That's right.
During the time when my father was being struck down and fell...
I was on the outside of the door!
Along with the building manager!
You probably didn't hear the building manager's testimony.
He is saying that he didn't see the culprit.
But...
The shadow of the assailant...
The shadow reflected on the wall, correct?
After you committed the crime for the sake of money...
You desperately tried to think of a way to make it seem as if it were the result of a robbery.
That's when a certain mechanism came to mind.
A mechanism using a clock in the president's office that had a decoration attached.
Your Honor.
This is a clock in the same shape as the one in the company president's office.
We believe that the culprit probably set this clock to ring...
And set the doll up so that its movement was reflected on the wall using the light from the window...
An optical illusion that lead the building manager to misunderstand the time of the murder.
And the sound?
What about the sound?
The building manager and I, we heard the sound of my father collapsing!
That's a simple trick.
You most likely took a golf ball with a string attached to it...
And put it under the leg of a desk in the company president's office.
Having prepared the end of the string to stick out under the door...
You pulled the string as the building manager was peering in the small window and being taken by surprise.
How's that for a pretty simple trick?
Do you have any proof?
That kind of trick...
Anyone could have done it, couldn't they?
Show me evidence that I was the one to do it!
Exactly as the witness said!
If you're going to go as far as to claim that, I would like to see evidence!
As far as evidence, Prosecutor Kujou...
It's in the list of articles recovered from the crime scene.
In the list?
List of Articles Found at the Crime Scene
1. Glass Ashtray
2. 1 Pair of Army Cotton Gloves
3. Eyeglasses screw
4. Golf Ball
There's an eyeglasses screw in that list, isn't there?
If it's from the victim's reading glasses, I wonder when it fell there.
He should have left his reading glasses at the restaurant, after all.
There's no other way to think of it except that it came off when the victim was struck down by the culprit, is there?
Also, Arima-san...
You used your work apron to wipe the fingerprints off the ashtray, didn't you?
According to the forensic examination of the ashtray, the fingerprints had been wiped down by an oily cloth.
I request a complete analysis comparison of the oil on the ashtray against the olive oil used in Arima's restaurant.
Arima-san...
After the incident, you repaid a debt of 5,000,000 yen to a money lending company, correct?
We can recover that money, and examine the fingerprints from it.
Dad deserved it...
That abusive man!
That's great, isn't it, Dad?
That the money was untouched...
Do you want this money?
But look here.
If you don't return the money I lent you by next week...
I'll evict you from that shop, even if you are my adopted son-in-law!
It's as Mouri-san said.
The one who killed my father was me!
Your Honor!
We revise the indictment against Defendant Inoue from Robbery-Murder to Attempted Robbery...
And additionally would like to prepare an accusation against suspect Arima.
How does that sit with the defense?
That is appropriate.
Then, we conclude the trial for this matter.
Kisaki-san!
For helping me realize the error of my conclusion...
Thank you very much.
I was merely carrying out my duties.
Well, see you at the next trial.
Say, in celebration of the conclusion of the trial, why don't we all go out to eat?
Now that you mention it, I am hungry.
Delicious wine and Italian food, no...
Maybe we should go with sake and fresh sashimi!
No, wait...
Cold beer and tempura so hot you'd have to blow at it while you eat it—that'd be great!
Or even Chinese food and old Chinese wine...
Will he ever come to a decision?