Filling in the distance between hate and love...
The deductions and the suspense of two people!
A difficult case in search of the truth.
A courtroom clash between Kisaki and the prosecution!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
An onsen, huh?
We haven't been to one in so long, have we?
And it's fall leaf-viewing season now, isn't it?
That's right!
I recommend this open-air bath.
They say this onsen is really good for the body!
Mom, you have to take a break from work once in a while and just relax.
You're right.
Kuriyama-san!
What does my schedule look like for next month?
The current court case is scheduled to be resolved next week, so...
What's left depends on what you decide as far as the issue of the duty roster...
That's right...
There was that.
If you would bring the documents for that...
Yes, ma'am!
What's a duty roster?
Sometimes there are defendants who cannot employ the services of a lawyer due to financial reasons and such.
That's when the government appoints an attorney, but when none of us wants the case, it's left to the duty roster.
Thank you.
I've only given the case a quick glance-over, but...
I wonder why no one chose to take it on?
It looks like the defendant has a decent case here...
I wonder if it's because the opponent is unfavorable?
The opponent?
The one heading this case is Prosecutor Kujou.
I see.
The Madonna of Prosecutors, huh?
COURTROOM CONFRONTATION II: KISAKI VS KUJOU
(PART ONE)
What should we do?
Should we say we're occupied and refuse it?
Say, Kisaki-sensei...
What kind of a case is it?
It's something that occurred about a month ago.
The body of a company's president was found in his office in Haido City.
From the fingerprints and the articles left inside the room...
They were able to apprehend the defendant—a habitual offender that had broken into many establishments.
It doesn't seem like a case that would end up in court...
That's true...
Since the defendant had already admitted to breaking in, being discovered by the victim...
And against his better judgment, hitting the victim in the head with the ashtray during the struggle.
he problem is with the charge listed on the indictment.
The charge?
On the indictment, it is charged as a robbery-murder.
Murder?
But in that case, wouldn't it be an accidental death?
Yeah.
I find it hard to imagine Prosecutor Kujou would have made such a mistake, though.
Kuriyama-san...
I already have the prosecutorial and fact-falsehood memos, but...
I still lack the conditional examination papers—could you get them for me?
I'll also need a copy of the autopsy report.
Mom...
Sorry, Ran.
Due to this, the onsen will have to wait for another time.
Tokyo Detention Center
Let me confirm once more with you.
On the night of the incident...
You broke the window to the Ootsu Real Estate Company's office on the second floor of the Nomoto Building...
Inoue Takashi (55)
Suspect
And proceeded to enter the office.
While you were searching around the office, and trying to open the safe in the company president's office...
You were discovered by the company's president, Ootsu Toshiyuki, when he returned for business purposes.
Then, during the struggle, you used the glass ashtray to strike him in the head.
All this resulting in death.
This is all correct, yes?
Right.
What happened to the money in the safe?
I don't know.
However, according to testimony from the company employees...
The 12,000,000 yen in cash taken in that day from a real estate transaction had disappeared.
The prosecution believes that, after you killed President Ootsu, you opened the safe and stole the money.
It wasn't me!
I really don't know anything about it.
It's certainly true that the money wasn't found in your room, but...
Given that your fingerprints were found on the dial of the safe, the prosecution's suspicions aren't entirely baseless.
I really didn't take the money...
And about that person...
That person?
Did you know the victim beforehand?
How many times did you strike the victim's head?
Dunno.
Was it one time?
Two times?
I don't remember.
After all, I was surprised and discovered unexpectedly.
According to the autopsy, there are traces of the victim having been struck three times.
And it was the third that proved to be the fatal blow.
If it were a single time, it'd be best.
But with two or three times, the possibility exists that you would be regarded as having intended to kill him.
I really don't remember.
I see.
I am your ally, so even if it's unfavorable towards your case, please tell me everything honestly.
Let me confirm once more.
You really didn't intend to kill the victim, correct?
That's right.
I understand.
In court, we shall press that one point in our argument.
Thanks.
Tokyo District Court
The defendant Inoue Takashi, at approximately 20:30 hours on the night of the incident...
The Case of the Robbery-Murder of the Real Estate Company President
First Public Hearing
On the second floor of the Nomoto Building in Haido City Block 3-2-9...
Broke the window of the Ootsu Real Estate president's office and trespassed.
While searching for money and other goods...
He was discovered by that company's president, Ootsu Toshiyuki, who had returned to attend to business matters.
Using a weapon in his possession...
He threatened that same person to open the door of the safe in the room...
And utilizing a glass ashtray that was also in the room, struck the victim's head three times until he was dead.
He then stole the 12,000,000 yen deposited in the safe, and escaped.
Therefore, we request that the defendant be charged under Article 240 of the Penal Code, Robbery-Murder...
And sentenced to life in prison with hard labor.
Does the defendant admit to the prosecution's accusation?
Or do you deny it?
I only entered to steal...
As far as intention to kill...
Your Honor!
Proceed, counselor.
The accusation is robbery-murder...
But the defendant did not intend to murder the victim.
Therefore I would like to raise an objection.
So he denies the charge of robbery-murder?
I believe it would be more appropriate to change the charge from Article 240 to Article 205, Assault Leading to Death.
The defense appears to have an objection with the prosecution's accusation.
Do you have any concerns?
Yes, just one.
The reason the defendant chose Ootsu Real Estate...
Why was that?
It was just that while I was looking for a building to enter and steal from...
I happened to come across that building by chance.
If that's the case...
It was just a coincidence that you chose to steal from Ootsu Real Estate...
And you contend you had no existing grudge whatsoever against the victim Ootsu Toshiyuki.
Is all of this correct?
Yes.
I wonder what Prosecutor Kujou is trying to say...
Your Honor!
The prosecution's aim with this line of questioning is unclear!
Well then.
The defendant is familiar with a female by the name of Endou Noriko, correct?
Well?
There's no reason you would forget your only daughter.
Only daughter?
Here it is!
She was only eight years old when he divorced his ex-wife twenty years ago.
But I wonder what that has to do with this?
Is it that you can't answer?
Objection!
The prosecution only seeks to put the defendant at unease by bringing up the name of a blood relative!
Is that daughter relevant to the court in any way?
Yes.
Endou Noriko runs a snack stand in another building that Ootsu Real Estate manages.
It has been rumored that she was involved with the victim, Ootsu Toshiyuki.
You're saying it was not by coincidence the defendant broke into the building that became the crime scene?
Yes.
We also have testimony to the effect that the defendant held a grudge against the victim because of his daughter.
That's wrong!
I don't know anything about that!
If that's the case, shall we ask the person in question?
Since she is in the visitor's gallery, after all.
We can have her come out here.
Endou Noriko (28)
Inoue Takashi's Daughter
Daddy...
Noriko...
So this is the card the Madonna had hidden up her sleeve?
If it's necessary, we are prepared to have Endou-san testify as well.
So it's true what the prosecutor said?
Yes.
I was deceived by that man.
He said sweet things such as how he would allow me to keep the shop, and took terrible advantage of me.
When did you get into contact with your father?
I reunited with him nearly two years ago when my mother passed away from illness.
Ever since, he would occasionally stop by my shop.
And you told him about Ootsu-san then?
He said he'd get consolation money out of him for me.
Well, it's certainly turned into an unfavorable situation.
Why's that?
Because, if he held a grudge against the other party and hit him as many as three times...
No one would believe him even if he said he didn't intend to kill the victim.
I see.
Lastly, I'd like for you to answer me truthfully...
Do you also think your father murdered Ootsu Toshiyuki-san?
No, Daddy likes stealing, but he's not someone who would kill a person!
I see.
It looks like the battle to come will be an intense one this time...
Geez, Dad...
Dozing off again!
I was just resting my eyes while thinking!
Who's dozing off?
Then, have you hit upon it?
A good idea you can use to help Mom.
Well...
Taking on this sort of case, it's Eri's own fault!
The defendant had a motive to murder, and on top of that his fingerprints were clearly on the dial of the safe.
How is somebody supposed to defend against that?
But I wonder why the dial on the safe was the only place his fingerprints were found?
As for that, he probably snuck in wearing gloves!
But, since gloves get in the way when it comes to precise tasks such as turning the dial on a safe, he removed them.
That's when the victim came in, and so using the ashtray...
If that's the case, his fingerprints should also be on the ashtray since it was the weapon, right?
Yeah.
Since he'd taken his gloves off.
But there were no fingerprints left on the ashtray.
Well, of course he wiped his fingerprints off afterward!
Let me see that!
Read this part carefully!
Isn't it written here that there are traces of it having been wiped down with an oil-stained cloth?
If that's so, why didn't he wipe down the safe as well?
No, that's because...
He accidentally killed someone, so in his haste, he fled and forgot about it.
I see.
But I wonder when he stole the money from the safe?
Well, after he committed the murder, he opened the safe again, and...
Didn't you just say he fled in haste?
Well...
Somehow, it seems mismatched, doesn't it?
Idiot!
Criminals do all kinds of things that don't make sense!
Isn't that just a sophism?
Shut up!
I'm getting out of here!
Wait, Dad, where are you going?
Geez...
List of Articles Found at the Crime Scene
1. Glass Ashtray
2. 1 Pair of Army Cotton Gloves
3. Eyeglasses screw
4. Golf Ball
Oh, Dear!
Oh, it's you.
What are you doing here?
No, just something...
You came to the scene of the crime to see if there was anything you could do to help Kisaki-sensei, right?
Shut up!
Enough!
Mr. Great Detective sure has a lot of free time, doesn't he?
What's that!?
Kisaki-sensei, you came to investigate the crime scene as well, right?
That's right.
I'm getting permission from the building manager right now.
Akiyama Takuya (56) Building Manager
Thank you for waiting.
This way, please.
Mister, you were the first person to discover the company president?
That's right, my boy.
Could we hear a detailed account of what happened at that time?
Yeah.
On that night, at around 9:00, I was watching a baseball game on TV when...
Arima-san!
Have you seen Dad—no, I mean, Mr. President?
When I made my rounds at 8:00, no one was in the office...
That's strange.
When he left my restaurant a bit ago, he said he was coming back to the office.
In that case, he must've come in through one of the emergency exits.
But, the door to the office is locked, and there was no answer even though I called for him many times.
Wouldn't he be in the rear office?
I came to drop off the reading glasses he left behind.
Sorry, but could you come and open the door for me?
No problem.
The Arima-san you mentioned was President Ootsu's adopted son-in-law, correct?
Yes.
He runs a nearby Italian restaurant.
So it was this door that was locked, right?
I used this spare key to open the door.
It sure doesn't look like he's here.
Dad, you there?
It's me, Masahiko!
Strange...
Huh?
There's someone there!
Oh no!
What's wrong?
Someone inside is being beaten!
What'd you say!?
The key for the door!
The company president is the only one with the key to this door!
Damn...
Move aside please!
Dad!
Hang in there!
Akiyama-san, please hurry and call an ambulance!
Yes!
The company president's office is over there, correct?
Hey, this door is locked.
Arima-san is in possession of the key to this room.
Here he is.
Arima-san...
This is Kisaki-san, the attorney I mentioned on the phone and...
I'm Detective Mouri Kogorou.
Arima Masahiko (35)
Proprietor of an Italian Restaurant
You're the famous...
Well...
Arima-san, apologies for interrupting your work.
We were wondering if you would let us take a look in the company president's office.
Say, is this room not being used right now?
Even though the police have already completed their investigation...
Since it was the room in which Dad died under such circumstances...
It's hard to say what we'll do with it from now on.
Go ahead.
It's just as the police left it.
Thank you.
So, Arima-san...
Where was it that the victim fell?
Let's see...
It was right around here, in front of the safe.
He was on the floor, cradling his head in his arms.
I see.
So that's how it was.
"That's how it was"?
Most likely, Inoue was discovered by the victim as he was trying to open the safe.
The defendant had already stated as much.
What's important is what happened afterward.
Inoue used a knife or something he had hidden on him to threaten the victim into opening the safe.
And then, when it was opened, he used the ashtray, and from behind...
Struck him down.
You're not saying the defendant is lying, are you?
Well, if he wanted you believe that he was innocent, that's probably it.
There's no way to defend a defendant if you don't believe him, is there?
You can say all the neat phrases you want, but you're only going to get thrashed by that Madonna!
Say Mister, where you saw the culprit from...
Was it this tiny window?
That's right.
Really?
Hey, Conan.
Just what are you up to?
Uncle Kogorou, could you stand in front of the safe again for me?
Geez...
What is this about?
Around here?
Just wait there for a bit.
As I thought.
Ah-le!
From here, Uncle is hidden by the screen and I can't see him at all!
What'd you say?
Akiyama-san...
What's the meaning of this?
Oh, no...
What I saw wasn't over there.
It was just the shadow of a person I saw reflected over on this wall.
A shadow reflected on the wall?
Yes.
At that time, the lights in the room were off...
And I saw the culprit's shadow reflected by the neon lights shining in from the window.
The shadow of someone hitting Ootsu-san over and over.
And after that, I also heard the sound of Ootsu-san falling to the ground, so there's no mistake!
I'm going to ask you one more time.
You did not, then, see Defendant Inoue actually striking the victim, correct?
But, Miss Attorney...
It's not an important difference, is it?
The culprit even said that he struck him.
No, Arima-san.
Merely seeing a shadow of someone striking another...
Is completely different from seeing the actual person striking him.
No matter the circumstances, until the defendant is tried and a guilty verdict comes down in court...
He is still considered a defendant, and not a culprit.
When such sad feelings are involved, everyone tends to confuse the two.
Sorry about that.
Say, Mister.
This clock's stopped, you know.
It was a prize that the late company president won in a golf tournament.
It was placed there as a commemoration ornament, and isn't usually used.
Arima-san, if you could come over here a moment.
Yes, ma'am.
What's the matter?
The combination to the safe in question...
Did anyone else know it outside the victim?
No, only my father knew.
For security reasons...
He didn't even tell the accounting heads.
You're in the way, just loitering around!
This is...
I see, I understand it now...
The trick behind this case!
The shadow of someone beating someone else that Akiyama-san supposedly saw...
And the sound of something having fallen...
Using this trick, it could all be manufactured!
And the one who set this trick up...
Gould only be that person!