Filling in the distance between hate and love...
The deductions and the suspense of two people!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
-
COURTROOM CONFRONTATION II: KISAKI VS KUJOU
(PART TWO)
Thank you very much for your assistance.
Not at all.
Did you find anything that'll help you in the trial?
Arima Masahiko (35)
Proprietor of an Italian Restaurant
Well, since the police and the prosecution have already investigated everything thoroughly...
It's not like we could have found out anything new.
That's true.
Oh, right!
How about having dinner at my restaurant?
I'll bring out my best wine!
Oh, no thank you.
Since he's offering, let's give it a try!
Dear...
Isn't Ran waiting at home?
Your daughter?
If that's the case, she is welcome as well.
Sorry to trouble you!
Not at all.
Meals taste better when eaten as a group, after all.
Then we shall accept.
This wine is quite magnificent!
I'm honored that you find it to your liking.
The atmosphere of your restaurant is also lovely.
Thank you very much.
I've also been called to appear in the next hearing as a witness.
Please go easy on me.
I believe you discovered your father when you went to deliver something he left behind, right?
He had left his glasses behind after having taken his meal here.
Glasses?
Reading glasses.
Well then, please take your time and enjoy your meal.
Somehow, the pasta doesn't seem quite up to the standards of a fine restaurant, huh?
Seems so.
There's a little too much olive oil.
Anyway, how is it going?
Have you thought up a strategy for the next hearing?
It's pretty difficult.
It's impossible unless you change the legal system.
What do you mean by that?
It's impossible to overturn it from being a robbery-murder.
His daughter can already confirm that, because of his feelings as a parent...
He had a reason to hold a grudge towards the victim.
So you're saying to confirm the prosecution's version of events...
And try for a lesser sentence due to the extenuating circumstances?
There's probably no other way.
This isn't a joke!
The defendant says that he had no intention to murder the victim.
You'll get trounced by the Madonna exactly because you're still being taken in by that!
I don't remember you ever having gone into a courtroom battle.
I don't know why I ever wanted to help you in the first place!
Come on, stop it you two...
How did we come to this?
If I remember correctly, in the list of articles left at the scene...
It should be here.
I found it!
The decisive evidence!
Conan-kun?
What's going on?
Looking at the court documents...
There was just something that bothered me...
Something that bothered you?
List of Articles Found at the Crime Scene
1. Glass Ashtray
2. 1 Pair of Army Cotton Gloves
3. Eyeglasses screw
4. Golf Ball
See, in this list of articles left at the scene of the crime...
Give me that!
Once again you're going through important documents without permission!
Geez.
If you're going to be like that, you'd better come up with something to help Mom out!
I don't even care if that stubborn woman gets beaten to a pulp by the Madonna!
You're saying that, but you really don't have any confidence you can win against that Madonna, right?
Idiot!
That kind of little girl, I could take on two of them at once!
If that's the case, how about if you become the defense attorney, Uncle?
That's not possible.
Dad doesn't have the qualifications to become a defense attorney.
But if he were to become a special counsel, it'd be all right, wouldn't it?
What do you mean?
It's a policy in which, as long as it is at the request of the defendant...
h person who only possesses ordinary qualifications can represent them in court.
Let the people at the court hear one of your great deductions, Uncle!
One of my great deductions, huh?
No matter how hard the case, in my hands...
If it's insisted upon, I guess I'd think about it.
That person is going to become a special counsel?
Yeah!
He said that he absolutely wants to be of assistance to you, Mom!
Thanks, but no thanks.
But...
It's so rare that Dad gets this kind of idea...
Even so, I can't think of any way that person could be helpful.
But...
I have a message from Uncle, for Kisaki-sensei to go to the crime scene tonight, with the building manager.
To that building?
He said you'd be able to see something that would influence the direction of the trial!
The direction of the trial?
Sorry for all the trouble!
I don't really mind, but...
Just what do you want with me?
Well, even I don't know exactly...
Mr. Building Manager...
Could you once again do what you did on the night of the incident?
Hey, Conan-kun...
Where is our man?
He's just outside, making preparations.
Got it, got it.
Akiyama Takuya (56) Building Manager
Do the same thing again, right?
Let me see, on that night we came into this office and no one was here, so...
Arima-san peeked into the company president's office through this small window...
And said, "There's someone there," right?
That's right.
And then when I peeked in...
That...
Could it be...
No way...
Is someone inside?
Why in the world...
Kisaki-sensei, why don't you confirm it with your own eyes?
This is...
I recreated the trick like Uncle told me to.
Trick?
Then, could it be that the culprit is...
Uncle said he'd explain everything in detail at the trial.
The Case of the Robbery-Murder of the Real Estate Company President
Second Public Hearing
If Mom and Dad are joining hands, there's nothing to fear, huh?
Inoue Takashi (55)
Suspect
Honestly...
I never would have expected her to request for Mouri Kogorou as special counsel.
Counselor Kisaki must be at a total loss.
All rise!
Akiyama-san...
You're testifying that you saw, from the small window in the door to the company president's office...
The victim was being beaten by the culprit, correct?
Yes.
How many times did the culprit hit the victim?
From what I saw, it was three times.
And right after that...
You heard the sound of the victim falling to the floor, correct?
No further questions.
Counsel, you may proceed with the cross-examination.
Akiyama-san...
About your witnessing of the victim being struck...
Did you see the face of the person doing the striking?
No, I didn't see the person doing the striking directly...
If you didn't see the person directly, what did you see?
The culprit's shadow reflected on the wall from the light outside the window.
Silence!
What you saw was only the culprit's shadow, correct?
Yes, that's right.
It's the same thing.
Even if it was his shadow, as long as.
hen, I'll ask you one more time.
Akiyama-san, was the defendant here the culprit that you saw?
No, the only thing I saw was the shadow of the person doing the striking, so...
So you don't know whether the person doing the striking was the defendant or not, right?
Thank you.
No further questions.
What is Dad doing!
He's been sleeping the whole time!
His performance is up next, Ran-neechan.
Really?
Moving on, we call witness Arima to the stand.
Arima-san...
Along with the building manager, you heard the sound of the victim falling, correct?
Yes.
There's no doubt about it.
And then you rammed in the president's locked office door, and plunged into the room.
Yes, but...
It was after the culprit had already fled through the window.
My father—I mean President Ootsu—was on the floor.
What was the condition of the safe at that time?
It was left open.
No further questions.
Go ahead, Counsel.
All right, I guess it's about time for me to overturn this trial.
Dad, do your best!
First, we'll take a look at Uncle's skill.
All right, special counsel, please begin your questioning.
Yes, sir.
You went to Ootsu Real Estate at about 9:00 at night in order to deliver something the victim left behind, correct?
Yes.
In order to deliver the reading glasses that my father left behind in my shop.
However, the door to the office was locked, and you couldn't go in.
That's right.
But really, the door wasn't locked, was it?
And the victim was in the company president's office, checking the money in the safe.
What are you saying?
You don't mean that I...
No, just that you also had the chance to commit the crime.
That's ridiculous.
Why would I do that to my father-in-law?
When money is involved, even direct parent-child relationships are pushed to the side.
Surprisingly, Uncle has struck a good point.
The question is obviously nothing more than conjecture!
Objection sustained.
If the defense could please develop their argument on the basis of clearly defined evidence.
But...
From my seven years of experience, it happens very often that the first person to discover the body is the culprit.
Then, using your seven years of experience...
How would you explain the articles left at the scene of the crime...
And the defendant's fingerprints on the dial of the safe?
When the witness and the victim were arguing over the money...
The defendant took in the situation from outside the window.
This is again unestablished.
And further, after the witness beat the victim down and left...
The defendant snuck in and went to steal the money in the safe.
If that's the case, then who was this culprit the building manager witnessed?
In actuality, the victim was not yet dead.
And so he regained consciousness, got into a struggle with the defendant...
If that's the case, then as we were saying, the one who murdered the victim was the defendant, correct?
I guess that's what it comes down to, then...
What are you talking about?
Aren't you here for the sake of defending the defendant?
I am here as a Great Detective in order to shed light on the truth of this case!
I was a fool to rely on you.
That's enough.
Get back here!
Right now?
I'm still in the middle of this important...
It would be appreciated if the marital spat could be conducted elsewhere.
Dad sucks!
I guess that's about as far as Uncle can go.
Anyway, just sit down and shut up.
What am I, an ornament?
I retract my previous statements.
Your Honor!
That's enough already!
The defendant snuck into that room before Arima-san entered, not afterwards.
And, as he was about to open the safe, he was discovered by the victim.
Without thinking, he struck the victim down and immediately fled.
The problem is with what happened after that.
The defendant was convinced that he accidentally killed the victim, but in actuality the victim only lost consciousness.
And immediately after that, the victim was murdered by someone who came to the scene of the crime.
Are you saying that's me?
You testified the victim forgot his reading glasses at your shop, correct?
Does he need his reading glasses even while he's eating?
Without them, he can't even read the menu.
Isn't that strange?
In the indictment, it is written that the victim was forced by the culprit to open the safe.
If he didn't have his reading glasses...
I wonder how the victim turned the dials on the safe?
In that dark office in which only the neon signs from the neighboring building were shining.
Huh...
I have no idea either.
Wasn't the victim still alive up until you delivered the reading glasses?
Are you there?
What's wrong?
You have a wound on your head!
Leave it!
It's nothing!
It was after he had discovered the robber.
After he regained consciousness, what he should have been the most concerned about was the money.
If you're looking for your glasses, here.
When you saw that money...
A murderous urge was born within you...
And you murdered the victim with the toppled ashtray.
Prosecutor!
I was called here as a witness, but now I'm being treated as the culprit!
Mouri-san...
You have forgotten one important fact.
That the witness has an alibi for the time of the crime.
That's right.
During the time when my father was being struck down and fell...
I was on the outside of the door!
Along with the building manager!
You probably didn't hear the building manager's testimony.
He is saying that he didn't see the culprit.
But...
The shadow of the assailant...
The shadow reflected on the wall, correct?
After you committed the crime for the sake of money...
You desperately tried to think of a way to make it seem as if it were the result of a robbery.
That's when a certain mechanism came to mind.
A mechanism using a clock in the president's office that had a decoration attached.
Your Honor.
This is a clock in the same shape as the one in the company president's office.
We believe that the culprit probably set this clock to ring...
And set the doll up so that its movement was reflected on the wall using the light from the window...
An optical illusion that lead the building manager to misunderstand the time of the murder.
And the sound?
What about the sound?
The building manager and I, we heard the sound of my father collapsing!
That's a simple trick.
You most likely took a golf ball with a string attached to it...
And put it under the leg of a desk in the company president's office.
Having prepared the end of the string to stick out under the door...
You pulled the string as the building manager was peering in the small window and being taken by surprise.
How's that for a pretty simple trick?
Do you have any proof?
That kind of trick...
Anyone could have done it, couldn't they?
Show me evidence that I was the one to do it!
Exactly as the witness said!
If you're going to go as far as to claim that, I would like to see evidence!
As far as evidence, Prosecutor Kujou...
It's in the list of articles recovered from the crime scene.
In the list?
List of Articles Found at the Crime Scene
1. Glass Ashtray
2. 1 Pair of Army Cotton Gloves
3. Eyeglasses screw
4. Golf Ball
There's an eyeglasses screw in that list, isn't there?
If it's from the victim's reading glasses, I wonder when it fell there.
He should have left his reading glasses at the restaurant, after all.
There's no other way to think of it except that it came off when the victim was struck down by the culprit, is there?
Also, Arima-san...
You used your work apron to wipe the fingerprints off the ashtray, didn't you?
According to the forensic examination of the ashtray, the fingerprints had been wiped down by an oily cloth.
I request a complete analysis comparison of the oil on the ashtray against the olive oil used in Arima's restaurant.
Arima-san...
After the incident, you repaid a debt of 5,000,000 yen to a money lending company, correct?
We can recover that money, and examine the fingerprints from it.
Dad deserved it...
That abusive man!
That's great, isn't it, Dad?
That the money was untouched...
Do you want this money?
But look here.
If you don't return the money I lent you by next week...
I'll evict you from that shop, even if you are my adopted son-in-law!
It's as Mouri-san said.
The one who killed my father was me!
Your Honor!
We revise the indictment against Defendant Inoue from Robbery-Murder to Attempted Robbery...
And additionally would like to prepare an accusation against suspect Arima.
How does that sit with the defense?
That is appropriate.
Then, we conclude the trial for this matter.
Kisaki-san!
For helping me realize the error of my conclusion...
Thank you very much.
I was merely carrying out my duties.
Well, see you at the next trial.
Say, in celebration of the conclusion of the trial, why don't we all go out to eat?
Now that you mention it, I am hungry.
Delicious wine and Italian food, no...
Maybe we should go with sake and fresh sashimi!
No, wait...
Cold beer and tempura so hot you'd have to blow at it while you eat it—that'd be great!
Or even Chinese food and old Chinese wine...
Will he ever come to a decision?