Suspense and deduction closes the gap between
the love and hatred between two people.
Travel mysteries are so popular,
mystery churns in the ocean.
He sees through the one and only truth,
a child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
You two should thank me!
I've gota golden arm!
Alright already
You'rexsopersistent, dad...
Youtkn OW SI ir
you really are kind of talented.
In lotteries, at least.
=xlcanstibelieve you won the first
prize again=which was this trip
What do you mean kind ofjtalented
Iym=-a~-genius!!
What, you want to kill yourself?
Gonahead then, go on, I dare you!
Seiji Hario
Go ahead then, go on, I dare-you!
SeqiHano
> = La
TIT FE )55C1 \JU}
I've always done things this way
that's my style!
I get rid of anything I don't like!
Next stop Shin-Shimonoseki.
Shinislhimonoseki!
You may exit through the left
BH WE +» B
(B1%R)
FRIENDSHIP AND MURDER AT THE
KAMMON STRAIT-PART I
Kaikhyou':-Yume! Tower
AB IRDDH FD
Conan, look!
KaikhyoLfiYume Tower
AS IERKD ED 57 DD
You can see the entire city of Shimono
You can see the entire city of Shimono-
Floor 30
H3IOWARER
Wow, this is great!
Floor 30
ou TA IF
H3OWRER
Wow, this is great!
Look over there, that's
Ganryu Island, that's
Ganryu Island
ob Ded UR
$13.5
where Musashi Miyamoto and
Kojiro Sasaki fought that famous bat
Ganryu Island
Siw Ded LS:
It's smaller than I expected
Ganryu Island
oh Ded UR
It's smaller than I expected
Hey Ran, isn't that Kyushu over there?
(Yes its.
TheiKammon
Strait is pretty narrow, isn't it
Says here the narrowest
area's only 700 meters.
If you ran across it,
you'd reach Kyushu in 5 minutes!
Oh for goodness sakes. how are
you going to run across the ocean
oh. uh, your right...
Oh dad. you're so, embarrassing .
He's right, you can run across
\&, Ia
Oh, are you talking about that bridge?
No. that's the Kammon Bridge.
It's.only. for -cars'
but there's an underwater tunnel
directly under it for human traffic
e Otsuba Touru Okit
It's nicknamed The Peopleis Tunnel
You sure know a lot
We grew up in this neighborhood
No wonder
Wait...
Akane Isak
(30) ix 2% (30)
Aren't you Kogore Mourn?
Akane Isak
(30) 335 I 30)
Yes, 'am
I knew it!
He's that famous private detective!
Oh, my name's Akitatan:
I'm Keisuke Otsubo
I'M Akane Isaka I
I'm Eiko Nojima
We're all fans of yours, Mr. Mourn
Aren't we? Aren't we?
We sure are...
Really, how nice.
Yup. everyone knows ole Kogoro
only for his name and his face
which means...
if it's, not an imposition,
would you join us for dinner?
Great idea!
We'd really like to hear your stories!
Knew it
Well.
They were nice enough to offer,
shall we accept?
Besides, they're locals sO they probably
know where the good restaurants are
We were raised here but she and
I have been living in Tokyo Since college
How.:do you all know each other
We were all in the same
class in high school
High school classmates!
That's O nice.
12 years have passed since you
graduated but you're all still so close
graduated butiyou're all still so clos
Kaikkyou Yiume.Square
12 years have passed since you
graduated but you're all still so clos
I Kaikkyou Yume Square
BROIL MR
I guess it'sibecause we all
have such different personalities
KaikkyouYume Square 1.
ABER [118
I guess it is because we all
have such different personalities
rm strong but Not very smart. Otsubo"s
Otsubo's
smart but he's a coward
You've got some nerve!
Akane's smart too but
she's pretty mean
You've got some nervy
Eiko's, sweet but shy
Actually, there used
to be one more in our group
another close friend of ours
Another member?
His name was Kazuyuki Hongo.
He could draw really well, he
wanted to go to an art college.
in our senior year of high school...
he went to the Kammon Bridge
and killed himself...
He committed suei '@? «
I see, he was talented
but he probably felt he'd
already given it all he had
and nothing left
You're wrong!
His dream...
his dream was. taken from him!
His dream?
He broke his arm
And it didn't heal right
see...
Yesterday was .hisl1*3th
memonrnial service
So that's why you all came from Tokyo
Well, that was part of the reason
These two wanted t ) make an
announcement to Eik and me.
It seems they ve gotte engaged
That:s wonderful!
Congratulations!
Well, you see, I realized one day, [
that she was the only:single one left
How dare you! I'm'majryinggyou
onlylbecause I feel sonny for yon
I'tRink you two make aggreat couple!
So doe If
You've gotito be kidding!
Hey, come on...
Hey Conan, look over there!
It's sO cute
It's a whale!
Well, well I see you're all together
Hario!
Kiyoharu!
Akitatani, I want to talk to you,
alone but I guess this is a bad time
I'll be A re for 3 to 4 days
I'll see you later
Who was that?
A friend of yours?
That's Kiyoharu Hario!
He was also one of our classmates
Him too?
I wonder'whatihe came back for anyway?
Probably for the memorial service.
MaYb ) he feels responsible?
What do you mean?
It's that creep's fault. He's the one
who broke Hongo's arm 12 years ago!
He's the one...
I'm sornpy. I have to excuse myself
I think I've worn myself out.
I'm going home
.III
I'm terribly sorry.
I promise to he there for dinner though.
Excuse me...
I hope she's alright.
She didn't look very good
Kazuyuki was Eiko's boyfriend
I guess she can't forget him...
she's still in love, with Kazuyuki
That's why she's still single
it's been 12 years already...
Is Touru married?
No. Why?
I was just curious!
So we'll see you all later for dinner
Yes. please enjoy yourselves
Since the olden days, I
Shimonoseki has a history
of being a port city
open to foreign ships
Really?
Look Conan! Doesn't this place loo
Iike the Dragon King's palace?
Look ConanlwDoesn't this place loo
Akaiwwe-Shrine
Look Conan! Doesn't this place loo
Iike the Dragon King's palace?
Kame Shine
FRAME
Akame Shrine
fiillflfifi
You're right!
Akame Shine
Br BE LAM ECD
IRAWME
You're right!
Ganmon Bridge
ne Sled ad
Boy. this sure is a big bridge
Look. that must be the tunnel
Mr Akitatan: told us about!
Look, that must be the tunnel
Mr Akitatani told us about!
Shimokitaga
Ad ST)
Let's go inside!
Shimokitaga
ABBR)
Okay!
Shimokitaga
All kX)
Gindou tunnel
Shimokitagawa basement 3rd floor
AIN RIVTRAIB TIME
Gindou tunnel
Shimokitagawa basement 3rd floor
Loouey
All b2XIVTRRIET 36
I wonder if there's a possibility
this?place might spring a leak
Oh for goodness sakes dad. don't worry
Iook at me!
I'm standing in two
prefectures at the same time!
Peace!
Can you believe this!
We just walked across
thefKammon Strait!
Yeah!
Mojikou 'Retro town
PIE) LO
Mbojikou Station
PY E] BAR
This ferry takes only 5 minutes...
and even.if you go through that
tunnel we took and walked slowly.
It takes only 15 minutes one way
Honshu and Kyushu
are very closejarent they
This is one of those things you
can:t telljust b. looking at maps
Yeah!
The locals call balloon fish
fuku instead of fugu?
Yes. Fuku, not fugu
I see
fuku for happiness
Your fathers so funny
I guess...
Excuse me.
Hario!
Akitatani, give your company up!
Give it up?
I'm a consultant for
a food manufacturer now.
They told me they want
to buy your company
they'll pay good money.
Sounds like a fair deal. don't you think?
You've got to be kidding!
My father started.the company
and he worked hard for it!
I'm not letting go of it so easily!
I could crush your company
right now if I wanted to.
soot!
you're nothing. you're just garbage!
What'd you say!
I'll give a day to think about it.
I'll call you again tomorrow.
Kiyoharu: wait!
Did you come-back to
Shimonoseki to tell him that?
Didn't you come for
Kazuyukl s memorialiservice?
Who's that? I don't know any Kazuyuki
Kiyoharu!
Hey!
Come back here Hario!
Have you no heart?
Answer me. Kiyoharu!
Apologize to Eiko!
Don't touch me with your filthy hands!
Keisuke!
I don't know what you're talking about!
Are you alright?
Dang it!
He's so mean, so mean...
EIKO.
Next Day
They're all'such nice people. that's w
NextyDay
They're all.such nice people, that's w
They're all,such nice people, that's w
Former Akita Company
Bed BR Lid BW
IBA Bi
Former Akita Company
V2 WE Rk Lad
IRnmlmeE
"kind of. feel sorry. for them...
Former Akita Company
Wood BT Kt Lad PLY
Oh, you mean
Mr. Akitatani and his friends?
Yes. but there's nothing
we Cc Nn doe to help
Bey you two!
I just found out it's 2a 1% minute
bus ride to Chefu from here
Do we have to go y
to that "Mouri Residence
@f course we do!
The famous Mototsune Mouri is
my- ancestor, his descendant lives there!
Are you really related to
the famous Mototsune Mourn?
I didn't know myself until today...
I thought se...
I wonder if there was an
accident or something
I guess my ancestor will have to wait)!
The victim's driver's license
Kiyoharu Hario, 30 years old,
the add esstis in, Tokyo
Did you say Hario?
It canst'bel
Excuse me sir, who are you?
The: name's: Kogoro Mouri,. I'm
a 'private detective in To \ 0
Mouri, the famous private detective!
Yes. I suppose I am
I've heard all about you. I'm Kusuda
with the Yamaguchi prefectural police
I'm Anzai with the
Shimonoseki police department
Do you recognize him?
Is the victim a friend of yours?
Yes, sort of...
not well though
He died of a cerebral contusion caused
by a blow to the back of the dead
the murder weapon
appears to be this rock but
we may not be able to
get any fingerprints off of it
Approximate time of death is-between
SO AM and 11 AM or thereabouts
They've been scraped
on the ground pretty hard
I wonder why?
Ouch!
You again!
Keep out of the way!
There're no signs of a struggle
andnnothing=s beenistolen
Which means the murderer is someone
who knew him and-held a grudge
Yes, we think so too.
Whoever did it must have hated
him a lot too, he was hit twice
I've got it!
I Know how he got those marks
There's four people I think we
should talk to.-can you.get them here?
Do you have an
idea who the killer might be
Dad, youscan't be serious, you don't
think one of them did it do you?
I don't want to suspect thém either
But this guy had a lot of enemies,
he would've been very, very careful
I'm sure he came back to
Shimenoseki without telling anyone.
Which means he got someone mad after
he arrived in Shimonoseki: yesterday
and then remember the scene
we witnessed last night,
put them together and those
four start to look prettyfsuspicious
I don't believe it...
Shimonoseki Police Station
TRHRRERE
Il see...
Shimoenoseki Police Station
SOE S52 05 IL" CD La
THRORRERE
so that's what happened between you
people and Mr Hario last night
Sure, we were all mad-at.him,
but not enough to killlhim
Okay. I understand, but for the record
I need a statement from each one of you
as to what you were doing this morning
Mr. Akitatani, let's begin with you
At 9 AM this morning.
I went.to the office for awhile
but I was worried about what Hario
told. me yesterday about the buy-out
so I went to the beach alone and sat in
my car thinking about what to do.
After that. I went to which is one of our cu. mers
After that, I went to which is one of our cu. mers
ME -~ THiS
I'm pretty-sure I
got.there:a. little before 11
I, I was out¥for a drive in my
car all morning. alone
then I got a call from Akane
and I went to meet her at Kaikyokan
I think that was about 10:50
Kaikyoukan
DLY BED DA
43 IE
The two of us went to see the
performing-seals show at 11
I was with Akane until 10,
we were shopping in Moji
we were shopping in Moi
Mojikou Retro Plaza
I was with Akane until 10,
we were shopping in Moi
Mojikou Retro Plaza
MER LU OE
MER LU ~O&
Then we parted company,
I came back to Shimonoseki but
I realized I'd forgotten something
so I headed back to Moji
on the 11 o'clock ferry.
Oh and remember seeing
Akane and'Eiko at Kaikyokan
Right?
Yes!
We were in a hurry because the
show was going to start though
kook. it's Keisuke
Over there, at the ferry landing!
Let's see...
Keisuke Otsubo, we're always
keeping an eye on you.
If you don't believe me,
Iook over at the Kaikyokan!
You're right, he's waving
Right?
Yes...
I see, according to your statements, ,
at the time of Mr. Harm's
estimated time of death which
isssomewhere around 9 and 11,
Mr. Akitatani, until past 9 AM to 11
and Mr. Otsubo and Ms. Isaka,
you parted company at 10
so for that one hour,
you all have no alibis
for a sh 'F span of time
Pad...
Now wait a minute
Did you say between 9 and 117
at 11, Hario was still alive,
he called me on the phone
What did you say!
He called you at 11?
Yes.
It can't be...
Are you sure, Touru!
It was a weird call...
he said Kazuyuki's ghost'was after
him and he wanted me to help him
A ghost was chasing him?
Kazuyuki's ghost?
Yeah...
He sounded like he was crying...
What do you mean his ghost!
That's stupid!
What's the matter?
Nothing. it was just a prank call.
I hadn't been with the
customer very long
when the call came so it
must've been about 11.
No mistake...
I wonder where he
called me from though?
The sound of his footsteps and his
voice seemed to have a strange echo
A place near the murder scene
which would produce an echo
the pedestrian tunnel?
There's supposed to be a
surveillance camera there
I'll go check!
Amg 0
Mr.Mouri if th victim
did indeed make-the-alltati1:1,
then that means he was killed-after-that!
And that.means
'=> en
(ki)
They all have alibis for that time
Yeah, I remember
this guy!
He was running all around the
place inside the tunnel
I thought somebody
was chasing him
but I didn't see anyone
so I just figured he was strange
Do you remember what time it was?
I'm pretty sure it was about 11 AM
He's sure about that?
Yes! He said it was so strange,
he checked the time
so he could» make a report.
The call he claims he got,
must've been from there
So the murder took
place after that, after 11
Okauy I got it
We've verified Mr. Akitatani,
Ms. Nojima and Ms, Isaka's alibis
And Ms. Nojima and Ms. Isaka
saw Mr. Otsubo at the ferry landing
So you're all in the clear, so to speak
Sorry to have kept you here so long.
We've verified your alibis
sO you're all free to go now.
I apologize for the inconvenience
I'm so happy. they've been cleared
Yup!
See you later Eiko.
See you later
I'll call you later
Okay
I've got it!
I know how to break their alibis now!
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKO_SU WA
MA AHITO YOSHIOKA
Producers.
MICHIHIKOnSL/WA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music. -
KATSUQ ONO
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Scripts By
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
AN Fe » a NA
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
CHI HIG
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSFT
TAKAHISA OWAGA
oo SoeO
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KENJI KODAMA
Produced By
ms ENTERTAINMENT,- in)
1ny associtation with
OMIURLTLLECASITING
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CONAN
CC GONHIAOY WAY SHOCGAKURKAN-YIV TMS
Hey listen, thatisurveillance camera
yourmentioned: ist the.ceiling type?
Ceiling type...
But Mr. Mouri, what if
this man isnrt really Mr. Hario?
You're right, the might have
been killed way before this
which means, anyone of-those four
could have committed the murder.
FRIENDSHIP AND-MURDER AT
KAMMON 'STRAIT-PART II