Love and hate are brought together...
Through both reasoning and suspense!
Today is our 300th episode!
One with a sharp resolution full of thanks!
Seeing through to the one and only truth...
I look like a child, but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
While we were taking a trip to the Kanmon Straits, the connection point between Honshu and Kyushu...
We met a group of four friends, who've known each other since they were high school classmates.
But, the next day...
The body of Hario Seiji-san, another one of their classmates, was discovered.
At first, the police suspected the culprit was among these four.
But all four had seemingly valid alibis, so they were finally excluded from the suspect list.
However..
I see! So that's what happened, huh?!
If that's true, then that person's alibi completely falls apart!
The Kanmon Straits of Friendship and Murderous Intent
The Kanmon Straits of Friendship and Murderous Intent:
Part 2!
Something about this bothers me...
But what is that something?
Hey, hey...
Wasn't the "surveillance camera" you noticed earlier mounted in the ceiling?
The one you made a "peace" sign in front of, Uncle.
W-Why, you...
T-That's unnecessary.
Ceiling?
Peace!
Ail
What did you say?
So there's no way to clearly see his face?
No, because the cameras are only filming from above.
Even so, make no mistake...
Those were the exact the same clothes as the ones in the picture you showed me!
But, you know...
If you didn't see his face...
You can't be sure it was really Hario-san, right?
Conan! When did you get here?
But, Mouri-san...
If we assume that the man in the tunnel wasn't Hario, then...
Yes...
In that case, it's probable that Hario-san was killed a lot earlier than we thought.
In other words..
The possibility that one of those four people killed Hario-san, still remains.
Sorry to have called you here.
No problem, but why me?
Dad is cruel! It looks he's suspecting you four again.
Is that so?
But, don't you think Hario-san is just as cruel?
Between him destroying your relationship with Hondou-san...
An now saying e doesn't even know him...
He's why Hondou-san can't rest in peace, isn't it?
Ah, sorry.
No, that's fine.
I really am weird, aren't I?
Calling you all the way out here, only to talk about this...
You also have someone you love, don't you, Ran-san?
What?
Um, well...
Oh!
I wonder what those people over there are doing...
That lighthouse is called "The Lover's Lighthouse".
The Lover's Lighthouse?
It's said that if a couple waves at each other from those two platforms that are close to us...
They'll be stay together forever, no matter what hardships may occur.
Eiko-san.
Note: Mt. Hinoyama literally means "Fire Mountain", and is named such because war beacons used to be lit from the mountain.
Have you rode the ropeway yet? The one on Mt. Hinoyama, that is...
Huh? N-No..
How about we go try it?
Okay.
Yes, I'm sure of it.
If I remember right, Akitaya-san got a call right after we met.
I think that that call came just before 11:00 AM.
Since that was right around the time we met, you see
As you said, Akitaya-san's testimony is flawless.
And the Kaikyoukan Aquarium?
It's toward the piers, about a five minute walk from here.
S-So, the Karato Marketplace where Akitaya-san was...
The piers where Ootsubo-san got on the ferry...
And finally, the Kaikyoukan Aquarium where Eiko-san and Akane-san were...
They were all in the same general vicinity?
Yes, I remember these two people well.
They were both very pretty...
They received a call from someone in this passage...
Afterward, they went to see the Sea Lion show that started at 11:00 AM.
So, that means..
Say, say, young lady!
The man you just talked with told me to ask you something he forgot to ask.
Why of course, young man.
It seems the employees from this food company don't remember having seen Ootsubo-san.
As I thought.
But Mouri-san..
We know for a fact that Ootsubo-san rode the ferry which left at 11:00 AM...
Since Isaka Akane-san and her friend saw him from over there.
However, Akane-san and Ootsubo-san are engaged.
But Nojima Eiko-san also testified that she saw him.
That's the part I can't understand..
Huh?
Conan!
You were following me again?
Eiko-san only wears glasses while driving.
G-Glasses?
When she left the police station yesterday, she had glasses on while she was driving.
What?
I asked the lady from the aquarium and she told me she wasn't wearing glasses at that time.
In that case, wouldn't it be difficult for her to distinguish something far away?
I see!
Eiko-san was used!
She was used?
What do you mean?
Oh, is that so?
Exactly!
Ah, this is amazing!
Did you used to come here on dates with Hondou-san?
Yes.
Hondou-kun and I didn't like lively places much.
Even so, Akitaya-kun, Ootsubo-kun, and Okane were always gently watching over and helping us.
That's great.
You all were really good classmates, weren't you?
To suspect someone among such good people...
My dad really is cruel!
I'm the cruel one.
What did you say?
Akitaya-san, Ootsubo-san and Isaka-san all cooperated to murder Hario-san?
That's right, and then the three of them created an alibi...
By using Nojima Eiko-san.
What?
The person Eiko-san saw from here was not Ootsubo-san, but an impostor!
It was a substitute.
A substitute?
But why would only those three act as accomplices?
Isn't it more natural to think that Nojima Eiko-san is also an accomplice?
She just met Isaka Akane-san in front of the Kaikyoukan Aquarium.
That was verified by someone uninvolved with the four, so it must be true.
Even if we suppose she was an accomplice, wouldn't she have come back from the crime scene with Akane-san?
Since coming together would have made it easier to stick to their planned schedule than coming separately.
I see.
Can you please gather those four one more time?
Then I will reveal the whole truth behind this.
Understood.
Yes, this is Azae.
What did you say?
What is it?
I've just been told that Nojima Eiko-san admitted she was the one who killed Hario-san!
Nojima Eiko-san?
What does that mean?
I think it was around 10:00 AM.
I went to the hotel where Hario-kun was staying and called him...
Then led him to a spot close to the Kanmonkyo Bridge.
The place we saw 12 years ago, where Hondou-kun took his own life...
Because of how Hario-kun stole his dream.
I... begged Hario-kun.
One word would have been sufficient.
I just wanted him to apologize to Hondou-kun.
But, Hario-kun refused.
Wasn't it his choice to commit suicide?
Why should I apologize to a piece of trash like him?
Before I knew it..
Hario-kun slowly fell to the ground and stopped moving.
He was hit, then fell and stopped moving?
If that's the case, then why...
Why did you decide to confess?
I didn't want Akitaya-kun and the others to be suspected anymore.
It was my fault, so now I will no longer cause them trouble.
On second thought, please gather the other three together and bring them here one more time.
You still think those three committed the crime together, Mouri-san?
If not, there are too many points that don't fit.
Then, why did Nojima Eiko-san turn herself in and say she was the culprit?
To cover for them..
Huh?
Her former classmates and friends, that is.
But, I don't think covering for them is a sign of friendship.
I see!
If I think about it like that, all the pieces can come together!
And once that happens...
Oh? When they got the call on their cell phone, they were that surprised?
Yes...
They quickly rushed out of the shop, both of them.
Just as I suspected.
If that's the case, the true culprit can only be that person'.
Nojima Eiko-san turned herself in, admitting that she killed Hario Seiji-san.
But I don't believe her.
Akitaya Tooru-san, Ootsubo Keisuke-san, and Isaka Akane-san...
All three of you are the true culprits!
Please wait a minute!
Please stay quiet!
Refrain from commenting until after hearing his explanation.
Akitaya-san...
Because he suddenly demanded that you had to ' sell your company, you were fed up with Hario-san.
That is probably your motive for killing him.
And as you're close friends, Ootsubo-san and Akane-san supported you in your murder plan.
A few minutes after 10:00 AM, the three of you called Hario-san.
And killed him under the Kanmonkyo Bridge.
And then you created your alibis like this:
Ootsubo-san played Hario-san's role...
And Akitaya-san played Ootsubo-san's one.
Then, Akane-san called Eiko-san on her phone asking her to meet up with her.
At 10:15 AM, Akane-san met Eiko-san at the Kaikyoukan Aquarium, where she asked her to come.
Ah, that's Ootsubo-kun!
Huh?
Akane-san called "Ootsubo-san" at 11:00 AM when it seemed he was boarding the ferry, effectively fooling Eiko-san.
However, the person who was on the pier at the time...
Was actually Akitaya-san wearing Ootsubo-san's clothes.
What?
They took advantage of the fact that your vision is poor, Eiko-san!
Of course, Akitaya-san neither boarded nor rode the ferry.
He hid Otsubo-san's clothes somewhere...
And hurried to the Karata Marketplace.
And to further distance yourselves from the problem, at 11:00 AM...
Ootsubo-san called Akitaya-san with the phone he had stolen off Hario-san's body.
What's this about ghosts?
Even if you're bored, don't toy with me.
Making us think that Hario-san was killed after 11:00 AM...
Giving you all seemingly valid alibis.
In summary, Ootsubo-san disguised himself as the already deceased Hario-san.
In order to fill in for
Ootsubo-san's role, Akitaya-san took his place...
While Akane-san took advantage of Eiko-san's poor vision
That's what happened.
No, that's wrong!
That's awful!
Even though she's your friend, you all too advantage of Eiko-san!
That's not true, Ran-san!
You're wrong, Mouri-san.
I was the one who killed Hario-kun!
But you see, Eiko-san...
What happened, Mouri-san
Could this be the rumored "Sleeping Kogoro"?
But, the truth is already...
90% happened exactly as I told you just now...
However, some points need correction.
So, you mean...
Akitaya-san and the other three weren't accomplices?
I also thought they were at first, but that's not true.
Not true?
Conan!
Well, you know...
Ootsubo-san and Akane-san got a call on their cell phone while shopping at Moji yesterday until 10:00 AM...
And according to the store lady, they got very surprised and left in a hurry!
Ootsubo-san, Akane-san..
That was a call from Akitaya-san, wasn't it?
Saying Eiko-san killed Hario-san.
Akitaya-san had probably went to see Hario-san to reject his company acquisition offer.
That was when he saw Eiko-san, who got there before him, accompanying Hario-san.
Worried about Eiko-san, Akitaya-san went after them...
And then saw it happen.
After finding out what happened from Akitaya-san's call, Ootsubo-san and Akane-san...
All rushed tot e crime scene.
There, the three worked together to think of a way to cover for Eiko-san...
Creating an alibi for her with the tricks I just explained to you earlier.
You did that for me
Because we're friends, right?
So the true culprit is?
That's what I was telling you from the beginning!
Did you hit him twice?
What? Twice?
From looking at the body, I noticed signs of being struck in the head twice.
Impossible, I only did it once!
Eiko-san, it's true you struck Hario-san in the head...
But at that point, Hario-san wasn't dead yet.
Thinking you had killed him...
Hario-san resumed breathing after you fled the scene.
Isn't that right, Akitaya-san
Hario-san was really killed...
By receiving another blow to the head...
After he had resumed breathing.
And the only person who could've done that...
Was the one who was still at the crime scene after Eiko-san fled.
Akitaya-san...
Akitaya-san... it can only be you.
Damn her..
That bitch, Eiko...
I'll get you for this...
It's as you said.
I was the one who killed Hario.
But...
How? How did you know he had started breathing again?
When I inspected his body, I noticed there was a lot of dirt and grass stuck in his nails.
And there were scratches on the palm of his hand, almost as if he had struggled to get off the ground.
According to Eiko-san's testimony...
Hario-kun slowly fell to the ground and stopped moving.
But if that was really the case, those scratch marks wouldn't be on his palm.
That's when I understood that..
Hario-san had started breathing again after Eiko-san fled the scene.
He held the part of his head that had been struck with his left hand...
And put all his strength in his right hand.
That had to have been a heck of a challenge to lift his body off the ground.
That's most likely when you gave him the final blow, wasn't it?
My company...
I'll be damned if Hario forced me to sell my company...
So I..
Really?
What?
Is it really only because of that?
If you had left things alone, Hario-san would have probably have reported Eiko-san to the police.
You wanted to protect Eiko-san!
Isn't that right, Akitaya-san?
Akitaya-kun...
But no matter what provoked you into doing such a thing...
No matter what kind of person he was...
Stealing another person's life isn't something that's forgivable!
Shinichi?
Shin...
Ran-neechan!
Conan-kun!