Two people's deductions and suspense
fill the gulf between love and hate!
Metro Police detectives
and the Detective Boys!
Love and mystery are
both about to explode!
He sees the single truth
for what it is,
and looks like a kid
but has the mind of an adult!
His name?
Detective Conan!
Ain't that Hide?
Where? Where?
I can't see...
It's not.
They just said on TV that Hide
was going to be in the back-most car.
Oh, they did?
But soccer victory parades are rare.
What did you expect?
Every year, people get excited about Tokyo Spirits
being the front contender for the championship,
and this year, they finally managed
to win their first J1.
And even the deciding match was
a dramatic come-from-behind victory.
Right!
While the clock was running down in
the second half, they were losing 0 to 1,
and Hide made it a tie!
Right after they went into overtime,
Naoki scored the winning goal!
They were so cool!
But with all these people,
we can't get a good view of the parade.
Yeah.
Too bad, because I made sure
to bring my camcorder.
Didn't I tell you?
We should've just
kept watching on TV.
Now, now.
I got the VCR going,
so we can all watch it afterward.
Hey! We might be able
to see it from over there!
Over there! Over there!
Oh, yeah!
If we get on top of that empty can bucket,
we might get a better view!
Let's go!
Yeah!
How is it?
Can you see?
Gimme a sec.
Sometimes I can see their heads,
but not their faces.
Ow.
Hey!
Damn it! If it were
just a bit higher, I could see.
But I don't think there's anything
higher than that empty can bucket.
No, not anywhere.
That's it!
Oh, good grief...
There he is, way over there!
It's Hide!
And Naoki's right
next to him!
Looks like he's facing
over here and waving!
Really?!
C'mon, lemme see!
Give me a second,
it's just getting good!
Hey!
You know better than
to be climbing up there!
I-I'm sorry.
I'll get them down
right now.
Just a bit longer won't
hurt anything, old lady.
Hey! Don't call me
an old lady.
If you don't listen to me...
I'll put you under arrest!
Detective Sato!
What are you doing
dressed like that?
I got it!
You ditched work to come down here
and watch the parade, didn't you?
Aha, that's why
you're disguised!
T-That's not it!
I've got my reasons!
You're here on a date,
isn't that it?
With Takagi-kun.
Y-Yumi!
I just happened to see...
See what?
Takagi-kun in the boys' room
earlier, picking out a wig.
Going on a stealth date in disguise
while you're on duty, that's pretty slick.
That's not it!
This is...
That means you ain't got
no place to talk.
Is it all right for
police officers to do that?
It's against regulation.
What's Japan coming to?
I-I told you,
you've got it all wrong!
It's just work.
There's no date.
Inspector Shiratori!
Why are you also
in disguise?
We got a weird fax
at HQ just a bit ago.
It read,
"I am Anti-Spirits."
"Something interesting is going
to happen at the victory parade."
That fax was a lot like one
I'd dealt with in a previous case.
That's why we're here from
the First Criminal Investigation Division.
But the person in question
knows what we look like,
so right now we're investigating
while in disguise.
Well, I think it was just a lame prank
by a fan jealous of the victory.
Aw, so it wasn't a date...
That's right.
Besides...
The date in question...
It's supposed to be
next week, isn't it?
I figured there was no way you could wait
until next Sunday, so you got rash,
but maybe I was
just overthinking it.
Hey, h-how did you find out?!
Oh, everyone knows.
You were going to Tropical Marine Land
that just opened, weren't you?
Everyone?
Don't underestimate
the Japanese police.
When he books a holiday
on your day off,
it's not hard to read
between the lines.
I hear they all dragged Takagi-kun into
the interrogation room to grill him,
and he just up and confessed.
C-Confessed?
Uh, well...
Well, anyway, be careful, okay?
Looks like a whole bunch of guys
have been gunning for that day off.
Oh yeah.
Come to think of it,
there's been a lot of reservations
to rent police binoculars
and radio equipment that day too.
D-Don't tell me they're
planning to stake us out?!
Sounds interesting!
Then why don't we go
to Tropical Marine Land too?
Let's go! Let's go!
N-Now see here...
I'm just taking Takagi-kun
to thank him for helping me before.
So, it's not a date.
Really?
I don't believe you.
I'm really, really telling
you the truth. Believe me!
So, are you going to give up
and watch, Shiratori-kun?
No... I'm not just going
to wave the white flag
just because she
rejected my proposal.
They still address each other
with -kun and -san.
I still have room
to make my way in.
Besides, I'm the one
taking charge of this stakeout.
I see...
Date! Date! Today is a date!
Tomorrow's a date!
Then the day after tomorrow...
Come on, Yumi,
give me a hand here!
Good luck!
Oh? Look who's coming...
Y-You dummy!
Showing up at a time like this...
Matsuda-kun...
It's Detective Takagi!
We saw through that disguise
from a mile away!
So my cover has
been blown, has it?
But I didn't expect
to see you guys here.
But we surprised
all three of you officers.
Really?
Y-Yeah, k-kind of...
What about you, Sato-san?
This disguise suits me well,
doesn't it?
Er... Sato-san?
I know Inspector Megure gave you orders
that you didn't need a disguise.
R-Right...
But I figured...
So why did you show up
looking like that?
I-I-I'm sorry...
If you understand, get out of that disguise
and go back to your post.
Got that?
R-Right...
Er, I wonder if I did something
I shouldn't have...
Nah. You just looked
like him then.
"Him"?
Before you were working at HQ,
that detective had been placed at the First
Criminal Investigation Division for only 7 days.
Hide!
Naoki-san!
There it is!
The car Hide is in!
Then let's push our way
to the front and get some video!
But since I've been taping
all this time, there's not much...
You didn't bring
any extra tape?
I did!
So put it in
and get a move on.
Right!
C'mon! Hurry! Hurry!
Hang on, please!
But I wonder if things
will be all right.
You got that weird fax, right? The one that said
something would happen at this parade...
Yeah. But all signs are suggesting
it was a prank after all.
S-So what are you
doing here, Yumi-san?
Giving out tickets
for illegal parking.
Lots of people leave their cars on
the streets around here to watch the parade.
You should probably hurry up
and move your own car, Takagi-kun,
or you'll be getting a ticket.
I'll go do that right now...
Congratulations!
Guys?
Where did you go?
Excuse me...
Somebody...
H-Hey!
Congratulations!
Aren't you a fan
of Big Osaka?
I didn't think
you'd come to this parade.
I came to hex it,
so they wouldn't win next year.
Yeah, right.
Hey, where did you go off to?
If you don't hurry and get some video,
the car'll be gone.
W-Well...
Er, key, key...
Oh, geez.
Today must not be my day...
Someone stole your camcorder?
Yeah, in the midst of the crowd...
What's this?
"Unknown number"
What?!
My word...
Cancel the parade right now,
and evacuate the civilians!
R-Right!
W-What just happened?!
A bomb.
Looks like one car blew up.
That car...
It wasn't Detective Takagi's car, was it?!
T-Then Detective Takagi got...
It's possible.
I saw someone earlier go up to the car
through an opening in the crowd.
Damn!
H-Hey! Conan!
Inspector Shiratori!
W-Where's Detective Takagi?
It exploded right when he came up
to the car to remove it.
One does not ordinarily survive
getting caught in such an explosion.
Then Detective Takagi is...
Oh, no!
I did say "ordinarily".
W-What's that
supposed to mean?
I got away by the
skin of my teeth,
so don't talk like
I didn't make it!
Detective Takagi!
You're safe!
Yeah, somehow...
I happened to see
a paper bag under the car
that wasn't there when I parked.
I was just about to take it back to Inspector
Shiratori and ask if it might be a bomb,
and it exploded.
But it's a good thing you recognized that there
might be a bomb inside the paper bag.
Well...
It only makes sense.
I just told you about
the fax we got at HQ
that was like one in a case
we had dealt with before, didn't I?
If a detective were to have info
about that serial bombing case,
and yet fail to notice that,
then something is quite wrong.
Speaking of failure to notice,
look at her.
She doesn't seem to have
noticed that you're safe.
Let's stop her!
S-Sato-san!
Takagi-kun... Takagi-kun!
Don't, Sato!
It's too late!
Stay back!
This is dangerous!
But he's still...
He's still...
He's still in there!
Hey, Miwako!
What do you think
you're doing?!
I-I'm trying to lift up the car
and get him out...
Takagi-kun's fine. Look.
S-Sato-san!
You burned the palm
of your hand!
H-Hey, we've got to get that
looked at right away...
You're right.
I'll leave this to you, then.
Tears...
It seems that the one Sato-san
was really trying to save was...
Yeah.
Probably Matsuda-kun...
Matsuda-kun...
The bomb type is
a plastic explosive.
It's not a time bomb,
but a radio-detonator type.
Most likely, a cellular phone
or the like was used to set it off.
T-Then, don't tell me...
Yeah.
The bomber was probably watching
from somewhere near you,
from where he could
hit the trigger.
That's right.
And that means that even though
the bomb was of a different type,
just like the case
from three years ago,
there is a good chance that the bomber
intends to kill police officers.
Keep that in mind, and be careful
but make a quick investigation,
and put everything you've got
into catching the—
Excuse me...
What is it?
I might have gotten
the bomber on tape.
Mitsuhiko-kun was taping
really close to where the bomb was.
You were?
Yeah.
And then someone in the crowd
of parade watchers stole the camera.
Right.
S-Stole?
Yeah. But the tape's fine.
There wasn't much tape left, so just before the
camera got stolen, he switched the tape.
The video camera's fine too.
Just the tape was missing. It was thrown in
the trash at the nearby subway station.
That means whoever stole the camcorder
wasn't interested in it,
but just the tape, right?
The only person who would do
something like that at that time
would be a hardcore fan
of the Spirits,
or someone who didn't
want to be filmed,
like the bomber, right?
Looks like we've got it hooked up
to a big monitor for now.
It's mostly just Mitsuhiko-kun's feet.
Come to think of it, I forgot and left the camera
running while it was pointing down...
I can hear you guys
talking about something,
but I can't see...
I know Inspector Megure gave you orders
that you didn't need a disguise.
Who's that?
Oh, sorry.
That's me...
Why did you get
just that on tape?
Sorry, I just happened
to tape it...
Hey. It looks like
Sato-kun is crying.
U-Uh, well, it's just...
I can see someone behind Takagi-kun,
next to his car.
Seems to be just a passer-by.
And from this distance it's hard
to tell one person from another.
Oh, darn! The camera's
pointing down again.
And so, the video ends...
Seems like the footage
we were hoping for,
of the one who put the bomb in the paper bag
under Takagi-kun's car,
wasn't shot.
Maybe something was recorded
at the beginning, while I was in the crowd?
So let's rewind the tape
and take another look!
Yes, this is Megure.
What?!
Another bomb went off?!
That's right.
This one was at a phone booth
in front of the park in Haido City.
Fortunately,
there were no casualties.
Judging by the type of bomb,
it's probably the same person behind it.
Got it.
Continue your investigation.
Hey. The way to get from the
site of the first explosion
to the park in Haido City...
I-It's the Spirits'
victory parade route!
In other words, the suspect is
not targeting the police.
It's just someone who took his hatred
of the Tokyo Spirits way too far.
S-Sato-san!
Are you all right? How is
your hand? I heard you burned it?
There is no problem.
I'll go.
All right, we've figured out
the bomber's objective.
And there's a good chance
he's set up other bombs too!
Mobilize all officers in the area,
get to the front of the route
and evacuate the nearby civilians,
apprehend the suspect,
and put everything you got
into finding the explosives!
On the double!
Right!
Just in case, Shiratori-kun,
contact the bomb squad,
and have them standing by.
Understood.
And Takagi-kun,
stay here and check the tape.
If you figure anything out,
get back to me right away!
But I want to go
to the crime scene...
No. You wait here.
S-Sato-san...
And after this,
we need to talk.
That's weird...
Just what is the bomber after?
Pretending to be the bomber
from three years ago,
sending a fax to the police,
and blowing up the car of
a policeman who was dispatched...
Then right after that, he blows up a phone booth
that has nothing to do with the police.
Is it really just about
hating the Spirits?
Besides, this videotape
that Mitsuhiko took...
Is there something on it
that will identify the bomber?
If so...
Just what will it show?
Were you even watching?
I've watched it three times.
If you think someone in the crowd is suspicious,
everyone will look suspicious,
and if you don't think anyone is suspicious,
nobody will look suspicious.
Maybe the bomber thought
he had been filmed?
Even though nothing
was actually filmed...
Nothing filmed...
Aha!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Mail Van
Next time...
The case and the love come to a conclusion?
Isn't love prohibited?
Looks like a new year's almost here!