"Hate" and "love" are both depressing...
But reasoning and suspense are between them.
The police detectives and and the detective boys...
Love and mystery are on the verge of exploding!
Perceiving the one and only truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan.
Isn't that Hide?
Where? Where?
I can't see!
It can't be!
On TV, didn't they say Hide would be on the last car?
I see...
But, with this being soccer, it's strange to have a victory parade.
Why wouldn't they?
Even though the Tokyo Spirits have always been one of the strongest teams...
This is the first time they've won the J1.
Not to mention how dramatic the final game was.
Right, right!
Hide scored a tying goal from zero in the second half to send it to overtime!
Then, Naoki scored the winning goal right when overtime started!
That was so awesome.
But we can't really see the parade through this crowd, though.
Yeah...
It's too bad, because I wanted to film them with my video camera.
Didn't I tell you?
We'd have been better off watching on TV.
Now, now.
I set a video tape to record it before we left.
We can all watch it later.
Hey, maybe we can get a better view over there.
Over there!
There!
Oh, I see!
We can stand on the trash can!
Let's go!
Yes!
How is it?
Can you see?
Wait a sec...
I can see some of their heads, but...
None of their faces...
Hey, hey...
Damn, if only it were a bit bigger I could see.
But a platform bigger than that trash bin...
Where could one be?
That's it!
Hey, hey, hey...
PARADE OF MALICE AND SAINT
(PART ONE)
I can see them out there!
There's Hide!
There's Naoki right behind him!
They're waving this way!
Are they really?
Hey, hey, let me see, too!
Just give me one more minute, it's just getting good.
You shouldn't be standing up there.
Sorry about this, I'll get them down.
What's the problem, old lady?
Hey, why're you calling me "old lady"?
If you don't obey...
I'll arrest you.
Detective Satou!
Why are you dressed up like that?
I got it!
You called in for work so you could secretly watch the parade, right?
I see!
That's why you're disguised!
That's not it.
It's because I'm...
On a date, right?
With Takagi-kun.
Y-Yumi...
I just saw him.
Saw him?
Takagi-kun was trying on wigs in the restroom.
It's risky to date on duty even if you are disguised.
You two aren't so bad.
That's not it!
Won't you get fired for that?
Is it OK for police officers to do that?
That's a violation.
This makes me worry about the future of Japan...
I told you, it isn't like that!
It's work.
Just work.
It's no date.
Inspector Shiratori!
Why are you disguised as well?
Someone faxed a strange message to headquarters.
"I am anti-Spirits. Something of interest will occur at the victory parade today."
The fax resembles a message we received for a case a while ago.
So, our division is on the move.
But, we had to disguise just in case the criminal from that past case remembers our faces.
Still, it's probably just a prank pulled by someone who isn't satisfied with the team's win.
What?
It isn't a date?
That's right.
Besides...
The date in question is.
Actually next week, isn't it?.
I thought you two pushed the date ahead because you couldn't wait for the next Sunday.
I thought too far ahead...
Hey, where did you all get that!?
Oh, everyone knows now.
You're going to the new Tropica Marine Land, right?
Everyone?
(wouldn't underestimate police officers.
e asked for the day off on one of your scheduled off days.
It's a simple conclusion.
I heard Takagi-kun told everyone when he was taken into the interrogation oom and interegated.
"Interrogated"?
Um...
Well, you should be careful.
It seems a lot of others have asked for that day off as well.
Right, right.
Now that you mention it, all of the wirelesses and binoculars are reserved for that day...
They're doing a stake out!?
That sounds so fun.
Then, why don't we go to Tropical Marine land as well?
Let's go! Let's go!
I'm taking Takagi-kun there as thanks for saving me earlier.
So, it's not a date.
Is that really it?
I don't believe you.
I told you, that's really it.
You gotta believe me.
What about you, Shiratori-kun?
Have you given up on the marriage?
No, no.
I won't raise the white flag just because our match-up didn't work out.
If they are still using "kun" and "san"...
I'm still in the fight.
Besides, I'm the overseeing director of the stake out.
Really now...
Date! Date!
It's a date!
Hey, Yumi...
Save me here.
Good luck!
Oh, if it isn't the man of rumor...
If he comes now, they will...
Matsuda-kun?
It's Detective Takagi!
Even with a disguise, we'll recognize you instantly!
I knew I'd get caught.
I didn't expect you guys to be here, though.
All three of you officers were surprised.
Is that true?
Well, kind of...
What do you think, Satou-san?
Of my disguise.
It's not bad, is it?
Um...
Satou-san?
Inspector Megure told you...
There's no need for you to have a disguise.
Yes, but I thought...
Then why...
Are you dressed like that!?
I-I'm sorry...
Now get that disguise off and get in position.
Understood?
Y-Yes, ma'am...
Did I...
Just do something wrong?
Just then, you looked...
Like him.
Him?
Before you were promoted to our division...
There was a guy with us in Division 1 for only a week.
That detective...
Hide!
Naoki-san!
Look over there!
It seems Hide's car is finally here!
Then, let's jump in there and film them!
But, I've been recording for so long that my tape is almost spent.
Didn't you bring extra tapes?
Oh yeah!
Then hurry up so we can go.
Yes!
Come on!
Hurry! Hurry!
Wait on me!
But is it safe?
You said someone faxed a threat about something happening at this parade?
Yeah...
So far, it seems like it really was just a prank.
But what are you doing here, Yumi-san?
I'm invo ved in a parking violation enforcement.
We thought a number of those here for the parade would leave their cars on the side of the road.
1'1 cite you as well if you don't move yours.
Get on it.
I'll do it now.
Everyone, where are you?
Excuse me...
Could someone...
W-Wait!
Congratulations!
But aren't you a Big Osaka fan?
I'm surprised you came to this parade.
I came to place a curse on them,
So that they won't win next year.
Hey, where were you?
Hurry and film the car before they're gone!
You see...
Let's see...
Keys, keys, keys...
There.
Jeez...
This just isn't my day.
Someone stole your video camera?
Yeah, in the crowd just then.
What the...
This is bad.
Halt the parade and evacuate everyone!
Yes, sir!
W-What was that just now?
A bomb.
It looks like a car's been blown away.
But isn't that car...
Isn't that the car Detective Takagi was driving?
Then, could Detective Takagi have...
It's possible.
Earlier, I saw someone approach the car from the crowd.
Damn!
Hey, Conan!
Inspector Shiratori!
Detective Takagi...
The explosion occurred when he approached the car.
Usually, I wouldn't imagine anyone could survive such a blast...
Then, Detective Takagi...
No way...
I said "usually."
Hey, what's that about?
I barely escaped that alive...
Let's not talk like that, please.
Detective Takagi!
You're fine!
Luckily.
At that time...
I noticed something under the car by chance.
The paper bag wasn't there when I parked.
I decided to go ask Inspector Shiratori if he thought it was a bomb...
And that's when it exploded.
But I'm surprised...
That you knew a bomb was inside.
Oh, that's...
Nothing unusual.
Don't you remember?
We mentioned that the fax we received today is similar to one from a past case.
As such, any officer who was briefed on that case would find it strange.
It seems she...
Doesn't know that you're not injured.
Let's stop her.
S-Satou-san!
Takagi-kun!
Stay back, Satou!
It's too late!
It's dangerous!
Please stay back!
But he's still...
He's still...
He's still in there!
Wait, Miwako!
What are you doing?
I'm trying to get him out of the car!
Takagi-kun is doing fine.
S-Satou-san!
Are those burns on your hand!?
Hey, we need to get that treated.
You're right.
Then, I'll leave this to you...
It seems the one Satou-san was trying to rescue this time...
Yeah.
That could have been Matsuda-kun.
Matsuda-kun?
The type of bomb was a plastic explosive.
The explosion was triggered by a wireless detonator.
Most likely...
By a cell phone or a similar device.
T-Then, that means...
Yeah.
The bomber may have been watching you approach the car.
When you got to it, he triggered the explosion.
That's right.
In other words, the bomb was triggered by a wireless.
Just like the case from three years ago...
It's likely they are after the ves of police officers.
Everyone on this case needs to remember to work cautiously, yet swiftly, in order to get the bomber.
Um...
What is it?
I may have recorded the criminal on video.
Mitsuhiko-kun was recording around where the explosion happened.
Were you really?
Yeah.
Someone in the crowd ended up stealing the video camera during the parade, though.
S-Stealing?
Yeah, but the tape is fine.
He changed tapes right before the camera was stolen.
The video camera is fine as well!
The thief discarded it at a station nearby after removing the blank tape.
That means the tape, not the camera, was what he was after, right?
The only one who would bother is a big Spirits fan that wanted to film the parade all himself...
Or the bomber who was caught on tape against his will?
ot seeing anything even on this big screen.
02:32 F
The only thing Mitsuhiko-kun was filming were his feet...
Oh yeah...
I put the camera down without powering it off.
I can hearyou all talking, but...
There's no incriminating shot.
Inspector Megure told you...
There's no need for you to have a disguise.
Who is he?
Oh, sorry...
That's me.
Why did you only tape this part?
Sorry, had to.
Hey...
Satou-kun seems to be crying.
No...
See...
Isn't there someone by the car behind Takagi-kun?
Looks like someone just passing by.
It's too far away to make an identification.
Oh no, the camera's pointed down at the ground again.
And that's the end of it.
I guess the bomber wasn't caught on tape placing the bomb like we hoped.
But maybe there's something unusual in the crowd from when I was first filming.
Then, let's rewind and watch it again.
Yeah, Megure here.
What!?
There's been another explosion!?
Yes.
This time we're dealing with a telephone booth that's near a playground in Haido.
No one was injured by the explosion.
I got it.
Keep watching out over there.
Hey...
Doesn't the road from the intersectio lead to that playground in Haido?
I-It's the path of the Spirits parade!
That means their aim wasn't to kill police...
It was to interrupt the victory parade of the Tokyo Spirits.
S-Satou-san...
Are your hands all right?
Weren't they burned?
It's nothing.
I'm ready.
All right!
We know what the bomber is after.
But, there may well be more bombs out there.
Every officer in the area needs to get on the parade route and evacuate the civilians.
Afterwards, stop at nothing to find the rest of the bombs!
I want a bomb squad ready in the event of an emergency, Shiratori-kun.
Understood.
Oh, and Takagi-kun, stay here and review the video.
Let me know if you find anything.
But I'd like to...
You can't.
You should stay here.
S-Satou-san...
And...
We need to talk later.
Just what is the criminal after?
The bomber from thre years ago...
The fax the police received...
The bombing of the police...
Furthermore, there's that...
Why did they draw the police to that telephone booth?
Was their aim really to disrupt the Spirits' parade?
And...
Mitsuhiko's video tape...
Capture the image of the criminal on it?
What is it they're after?
PARADE OF MALICE AND SAINT
(PART TWO)
Look!
That one! That one!
Isn't that lady suspicious?
See how she keeps looking back at the camera?
It's true.
She really looks aggravated.
She was probably concerned about Mitsuhiko holding a camera at such a low angle near her mini-skirt.
Hey, no!
I didn't mean to do that!
Then what about this guy with the moustache?
That's true, he's been looking at the ground for awhile.
Get a closer look.
Don't you see that he's holding a kid's shoe?
Most likely, he probably came with his family to the parade.
At some point, one of his child's shoes fell off while he was carrying them...
So he got down to find it.
I see.
Detective Takagi, tell us what you've noticed too.
We need to talk later.
Detective Takagi!
Are you even watching?
I've seen it three times now.
But watching it isn't helping.
In a crowd, someone is only suspicious if you want them to be.
It all depends on how you look at them.
He's right...
l^he criminal knewthis,too...
But yet, he stole the video camerato get the tape...
Why is that?
Could it be...
The criminal just thought he was recorded?
When he actually wasn't...
Wait a second.
If it wasn't that...
I see!
Hey, Conan-kun...
What did you see?
Nothing at all.
Then, it was useless after all.
No, that's not it.
They wanted to destroy tape not because something was on it...
But because there was nothing on it.
What do you mean by that?
Before that, something else has to be confirmed.
Hey, Conan!
What do you mean by "it's suspicious if nothing was filmed"?
Why is it useful for the criminal to take the video tape if there was nothing on it?
Wait, Conan-kun!
Hey, Conan!
The post office box?
Is something wrong with it?
Can you tell me what time Mitsuhiko was on top of it?
No one can remember the time.
Doesn't the video tape keep the time?
Can't we get it from there?
That's true.
Let's see...
It was around when I was filming Hide with zoom on.
Got it!
It was 2:23 PM!
And, since then and through the time Detective Satou came...
We were near this post office box until 2:38, when Mitsuhiko stopped filming, right?
B-But...
What does that mean?
Well, see for yourself.
Look at the pick-up times for this particular post office box.
On holidays, it says the mail is picked up at 14:30.
That equates to 2:30 PM, doesn't it?
Yeah.
If that's so, then we couldn't have seen something we weren't supposed to, could we?
I see!
The mail car!
That's right.
They never came for the mail.
But then...
Isn't it possible that they didn't make it due to the parade?
The parade route was determined in a way to allow it to not disturb the public.
Actually, only half of the lanes were taken up by the parade.
So, the mail should have still come.
But, still...
Wasn't an eight minute delay expected for all traffic?
That can't be the reason.
There wasn't any traffic anyway.
Besides, the delay on the box itself says five minutes.
No mail car came even fifteen minutes afterwards.
Unless something happened, how else can we explain it?
But, didn't you say the bomber was the one who stole Mitsuhiko-kun's video tape?
That's right.
What does the mail have to do with this?
Not to mention, why did they just steal my video tape?
If they're going that far, why not keep the camera, too?
And, by stealing it, they proved there was something unusual about the tape.
Right, and they wouldn't have bothered...
If we were only normal children watching the parade.
I-I see!
You mean Yumi-san's patrol car.
Whoever it was wanted to get the tape because you were talking to a police officer next to this post office box.
Right.
They knew the police would examine the tape if a bombing happened nearby.
They were afraid the police could get the tape quickly.
That is, since it was clear you all knew us already.
They were afraid you'd get it immediately.
Most likely, they didn't see Mitsuhiko with his video camera across the street...
Until after they had already planted the bomb under Detective Takagi's car.
Since it was already too late to retrieve the bomb from under the car...
They decided to go for the tape instead.
But I don't get it...
Didn't the criminal send a fax to announce the crime?
Y-Yeah...
So even after they drew the police ere and blew up one of their cars...
They didn't know the police would come after them immediately?
Maybe their intention was to distract them...
By using the case from three years ago.
You don't know what kind of incident it was, do you?
Just like the case from three years ago...
It's likely they are after the lives of police officers.
You looked like him...
Just then.
It seems the one Satou-san was trying to rescue this time...
We need to talk later.
What's left is the motive, right?
Their target isn't the police...
Nor is it the Spirits.
If my deduction is correct...
They must be after...
But still, I don't have any solid evidence.
I'll need you guys and Detective Takagi to investigate.
Yeah!
You can count on us!
Detective Takagi, are you listening?
Y-Yeah...
I heard...
I heard him.
Ayumi here!
I found a post office box, Conan-kun.
All right.
Where is the box and what's the pick-up time?
It's located near the bridge two lights from the first box.
As for the pick-up time...
It says they come at 14:35 here.
Got it!
This is Mitsuhiko.
There's one two blocks away outside a convenience store.
The pick-up time here is 14:45.
T-This is the Captain.
I found one three blocks away near a playground.
The pick-uptime here is 14:55.
Hey, Genta...
Why are you whispering?
Didn't I mention it?
I took a shortcut through someone's garden to get here.
And now, I'm hiding from this woman...
She must think I was trying to steal her underwear.
I see.
Good luck with that.
Last one is Ai-kun.
Yeah.
Here we go!
This is the Woman in Black.
Hey...
This post office box is near a bus stop 150 meters, three blocks away.
The pick-uptime here is 16:25.
I can see you two now.
See me?
This last one here at the post office is picked up at...
16:30, it seems.
That means, if I put this all on the map...
This would be the route of the mail car.
It seems it's just as you said, Shinichi.
The postal route gets further away from the parade.
Not to mention that today is Sunday, the 24th.
Even though 'm still waiting on Detective Takagi...
If there were no accidents or construction in this area today...
The reason no mail car came today...
Um...
What is it, Tsuni-kun?
The col ected mail goes to the back...
Oh, no...
There we e some unusual objects in the rest of the mail...
I'd like to everyone to take a look.
Could you open the front entrance for me?
Y-Yeah.
No problem, I'll open it now.
I'm sorry about this, really.
Oh, don't mention it.
Say...
What are those unusual objects?
W-Well...
H-Hey!
What is this!?
My bad, my bad.
Let me show you something nice instead.
It's this little thing brought along.
A-A gun!?
All right!
Everyone get your hands in the air and get over here!
We're here to rob this place!
Now hurry!
Come on!
Now!
Did you not hear me!?
Now, get the money for us.
You must have a lot ready since it's the day before they come to collect.
I see.
The reason you chose this day is because it coincides with the Tokyo Spirits parade.
You knew there would be fewer clerks with it being a holiday.
Then, you sent a fax acting as the bomber from three years ago to lure out the police.
Next, you make sure to mislead them into thinking the Spirits' parade was your target to keep them busy.
And then, after diverting their attention, attacked the mail car and this office.
Well, I wouldn't say it's a very smart plan in the end.
Hey, what the hell are you saying!?
Hurry and get over here!
You heard the man.
Everyone, come out.
All right, quickly now.
Hey!
What's going on!?
Why...
Why are there so many clerks here on a Sunday!?
Oh, you didn't know?
While we're both civil services, the post office has holidays.
But us, we work twenty-four hours a day all year.
Cops!?
Inspector Megure!
The postal employees restrained in the mail car are safe!
All right!
Bastards!
Please, don't.
What you're about to do would benefit no one.
Shit!
With that, the robbers were apprehended...
Along with their accomplices who planted the bombs that were awaiting their return.
And, later that night...
But it was impressive.
You know, how you saw through the bombings and the robbery.
No, the children helped me out with that.
You mean Conan-kun, right?
That boy is really something, isn't he?
Y-Yeah...
That's right...
I'm really sorry about earlier.
When I hit you, I mean.
It hurt, didn't it?
Oh, no...
I deserved it for not following orders.
But what about you?
Are you OK?
Do the burns hurt?
Yeah, a little...
I mean, they're still bad, but they'll heal soon!
R-Really?
That's great to hear!
U-Um...
Satou-san?
What was it you wanted to talk about?
That, huh?
S-Satou-san?
Let's cancel it for next week...
Our date.
Seeing as how I'm cursed.
Y-You're cursed?
You know, because everyone I care about goes away.
And then, there's him...
I don't want to feel that pain again...
So, I just want us to be police comrades like we've always been!
S-Satou-san...
Takagi-kun?
Go, Takagi!
Go, go!
Don't back down, Takagi!
Um, you know...
You're pushing me.
Takagi-kun?
I'll never...
We aren't a good match anyway!
You deserve a much sweeter girl than me!
How can that be?
Yep, yep.
What a loser.
Well...
Pardon my leaving.
S-Satou-san...
Satou-san...
What's wrong, Detective Takagi?
You don't look good today.
Are you eating enough?
Let's get our statements down for the post office robbery case already.
You must be upset over getting rejected the other day.
H-How did you...
Yo, Takagi!
How's it going?
I'll take down theirstatements if you're a little ill.
Oh, no...
You looked a little tense, Takagi.
You want some coffee, Takagi?
I've got some food if you're hungry, Takagi!
Amazing!
Detective Takagi is everyone's favorite around here!
Nah, I wouldn't say it's him...