Two people's deductions and suspense
fill the gulf between love and hate!
We've almost figured out
the truth about the bomb case!
The Metro Police
detectives' love story!
He sees the single truth
for what it is,
and looks like a kid
but has the mind of an adult!
His name?
Detective Conan!
At a victory parade for the Tokyo Spirits,
we, the Detective Boys,
ran into Detective Sato and her
fellow officers, who were in disguise.
They were conducting an investigation
because a fax had arrived at HQ
warning that something was going
to happen during the parade.
And then,
Detective Takagi's car...
What's this?
What?!
Inspector Shiratori!
W-Where's Detective Takagi?
One does not ordinarily survive
getting caught in such an explosion.
Then Detective Takagi is...
Oh, no!
I did say "ordinarily".
W-What's that
supposed to mean?
I got away by the
skin of my teeth,
so don't talk like
I didn't make it!
While we were trying to figure out
if the bomber appeared
on the video that Mitsuhiko
was recording near the crime scene...
What?!
Another bomb went off?!
That's right.
This one was at a phone booth
in front of the park in Haido City.
Judging by the type of bomb,
it's probably the same person behind it.
In other words, the suspect is
not targeting the police.
It's just someone who took his hatred
of the Tokyo Spirits way too far.
Is it really just about
hating the Spirits?
Besides...
This videotape
that Mitsuhiko took...
Is there something on it
that will identify the bomber?
If so...
Just what will it show?
Look! Over there, over there!
Ain't that chick
suspicious?
She's just been
glaring at the camera.
Yeah, she's got this really
annoyed look on her face!
That's because she's mad that Mitsuhiko's
camera is pointing up at her miniskirt.
No, well, that wasn't
my intention...
What about this dude
with the mustache?
He's been looking around
with his head down, hasn't he?
Take a good look
at his hand.
He's holding a child's shoe,
isn't he?
He probably came with his wife,
who was holding their child,
and both of the child's shoes
happened to fall off,
so he was looking for them.
I see.
Hey!
If you notice anything,
Detective Takagi, speak up!
And after this,
we need to talk.
Detective Takagi!
R-Right...
Were you even watching?
I've watched it three times.
B-But it's the same
every time I watch.
If you think someone in the crowd is suspicious,
everyone will look suspicious,
and if you don't think anyone is suspicious,
nobody will look suspicious.
Trying to pick the bomber
out of this is impossible.
He is right.
No doubt the bomber
thought the same.
But the bomber made sure to take the tape
out of the camera when stealing it...
Why, though?
Maybe the bomber thought
he had been filmed?
Even though nothing
was actually filmed...
Nothing filmed?
Wait, if nothing
was filmed...
Don't tell me...
Aha!
S-Say, Conan-kun.
Did you see something?
Not really.
Then it's no good,
isn't it?
No, that's not it.
The bomber might not have done it
because something was on the tape,
but to destroy the evidence that
there was nothing on the tape.
What do you mean
by that?
First, there's one thing
I need to confirm.
Hey! Conan!
What do you mean by that?!
About nothing on tape
being suspicious...
If there wasn't anything
on the tape,
wouldn't there be no need
for the bomber to steal it?
Wait up! Conan-kun!
Hey! Conan!
I knew it.
It's exactly
as I thought.
I-Is there something
wrong with the mail drop?
You know what time it was that Mitsuhiko
climbed onto the mail drop, right?
I don't remember
nothing like that!
We can find that out
from the videotape, can't we?
From the timestamp
recorded onto the video.
Y-You're right!
Let's see...
Starting from when I zoomed in
on Hide in the distance...
Found it!
2:23 PM.
And after that, we ran
into Detective Sato.
Until Mitsuhiko stopped
taping, at 2:38 PM,
we stayed right here
next to this mail drop, right?
W-What's important
about that?
Well, take a look
at this.
The pickup timetable
posted on this mail drop.
Under "Holidays" it says
"Approximately 14:30."
So that means it says
around 2:30 PM, right?
Huh? Oh, yeah.
That means we didn't see something
we should have seen, right?
Aha! The mailman's car!
Come to think of it,
he never came by to pick up the mail...
Though...
Maybe he couldn't come because
the parade was blocking the street?
No, the parade route was chosen
so as not to interfere with official business.
Currently traffic is one-way
because of the parade,
so he should still
have been able to...
But...
Wouldn't the road being blocked
make him at least 8 minutes late?
Not really.
Even if there weren't any
particular traffic bottlenecks,
the posted mail pickup times
are in increments of 5 minutes.
If there were a discrepancy
of more than 5 minutes,
they would think that something
must have happened, right?
But it was the bomber who stole
Mitsuhiko-kun's tape, wasn't it?
That's right!
What would postal vehicles
have to do with this?
And why go to the effort
of stealing the tape?
If it were left alone,
nobody would have noticed anything.
But now, it's like coming out and saying
that there's something on the tape!
Yeah. I don't think
they intended to take it.
If it were just us kids
here to see the parade...
T-That's it!
Yumi-san's mini-patrol car!
They saw you chatting with her
in front of the mail drop,
so they tried to
destroy the evidence!
Right.
If a bombing
happened right there,
the bomber could possibly
have been caught on tape,
and naturally, the police
would check it out.
And since we know
the police,
it would be an especially short time
before the video was checked.
That's what they
were afraid of.
They probably noticed
Mitsuhiko's camera
only after planting the bomb near
the drop box, under Detective Takagi's car.
They couldn't grab the bomb
from under the car,
so they had to steal
the tape instead.
But I just don't get it.
Didn't the bomber send a fax
to the police hinting at their crime?
Y-Yeah...
If they went to the effort of getting the police together and blowing up the car,
wouldn't they know the police
would search desperately for them?
Maybe they meant
to distract the police...
by making it look like the same
bomber from three years ago.
Though I don't know what
kind of case that may have been...
Just like the case
from three years ago,
there is a good chance that the bomber
intends to kill police officers.
You just looked
like him then.
It seems that the one Sato-san
was really trying to save was...
And after this,
we need to talk.
That leaves the question
of the bomber's objective...
Yeah.
Most likely, their target
wasn't the police,
and it had nothing to do
with a grudge against the Spirits.
If my deductions
are correct,
their target is...
But I don't have
proof yet.
So I'd like you and Detective Takagi
to check on something for me.
Leave it to us!
Detective Takagi,
are you listening?
Y-Yeah...
I-I'm listening,
I'm listening...
Ayumi here!
I found it, Conan-kun!
I found a mail drop!
All right, what's the location
and collection time for that mail drop?
Under the foot bridge,
two lights past the other mail drop.
The collection time is...
It says about 14:35.
I copy.
And... Mitsuhiko here.
I found one in front of the
convenience store on Block 2.
The collection time is
about 14:45.
C-Captain here.
I found one.
Next to the park on Block 3.
The time is 14:55.
Hey, Genta.
Why are you talking so quietly?
I have to!
I took a shortcut
through someone's yard.
She thought I was a thief
and chased me,
so now I'm hiding from her.
I see. Good luck.
That just leaves Ai-kun.
Yeah.
There she is!
Woman in Black here.
Oh, geez.
The location of the mail drop
is about 150 meters left
of the Block 3 post office,
next to the bus stop.
The collection time is 16:25.
I can see you guys
from here.
Do you copy?
Yeah.
And finally, the pickup time at the mail drop
right in front of the post office is...
16:30.
So if I check everyone's info
against the map,
it looks like this
is the mail pickup route.
It looks to be exactly
as you said, Shin'ichi.
It seems to be going further and
further away from the parade route.
Besides, it's a Sunday
right before bills come due.
Now we just have to wait
for Detective Takagi to contact us.
If there aren't any accidents
or roadwork in this area today,
the reason the mail van didn't come
to get the mail is probably...
E-Excuse me...
What's the matter,
Tsutsumi-kun?
If you're dropping off the mail
you picked up, go around back and—
Uh, no...
There's a whole bunch of
weird stuff mixed in the mail.
I-I'd like everyone to
take a look at it,
so could you open
the front door?
S-Sure.
Got it. I'll do that
right now.
T-Thank you.
Sorry for the trouble.
It's no trouble
at all.
So...
What is all this weird mail
you were telling me about?
W-Well...
H-Hey!
What are you doing?!
My bad, my bad...
What I want to show is...
This, Mr. Postal Worker...
A-A handgun!
Hey! You in the back, stick 'em up
and come up here!
Don't mess around
or you're dead meat!
Now, get a move on!
You too!
Get the lead out!
Quit dawdling!
All right, now
hand over all the money.
It's the day before bills come due,
so I bet you're loaded.
I see.
That's why you picked the same day
as the Tokyo Spirits victory parade.
A day when there wouldn't be
as many workers at the post office.
And you used the fax and bombs to pretend
to be the bomber from three years ago
to lure away the police.
You made it look like an attack on the Spirits
to throw the police off the trail,
so they would follow
the parade route,
while you attacked the post office
with your stolen mail van.
But it wasn't a very well
thought-out plan.
Hey! You over there!
What are you
yapping on about?
Hurry up and
get up here!
You heard him.
Everyone, hurry up.
Speed it up!
Hey! What's going on here?!
Wait...
Wait, how are there so many
people here on a Sunday?!
Oh, didn't you know?
We may all be civil servants, but unlike
the post office, which has holidays,
we're open 24/7,
365 days a year...
The police department!
It's the fuzz!
Inspector Megure!
We've released the postal workers
who were tied up!
All right!
Damn you!
Give up.
I wouldn't try
anything funny.
D-Damn it all!
And so, the post office
robbers were arrested,
and with the rest of the group, who had
been out elsewhere placing the bombs,
were also caught.
And that evening...
But I'm surprised
you were able to figure out
that the bombers were actually
planning a post-office robbery.
Actually, the kids
gave us the hint.
You mean Conan-kun,
don't you?
He's definitely
no ordinary kid.
T-That's true...
Anyway,
sorry about earlier.
About slapping you
out of the blue like that...
It hurt, didn't it?
Well...
It was my fault
for ignoring orders.
What about you, Sato-san?
Are you all right?
You burned your hand...
I'm fine.
Well, it does still...
I-It still stings a little,
but a little spit
and it'll be all better!
I-I see...
W-Well, that's good to hear!
E-Er...
Sato-san...
What did you want
to talk to me about earlier?
Oh, that?
S-Sato-san...
Let's call off our date.
I'm cursed...
C-Cursed?
Well, I always wind up losing
everyone who's important to me.
My dad...
My grade-school
gym teacher...
My senpai from
baseball club...
And...
And him too...
I don't want to go through
anything that painful ever again.
Sato-san...
So for now, let's just remain
fellow police officers.
S-Sato-san...
Takagi-kun...
That's it!
Go for it, Takagi!
Push! Push!
Push, Takagi!
You guys
are a bit heavy.
Sato-san... I...
Takagi-kun...
I'll never...
Y...
Y-You're right... We were never
a good match to begin with...
Yeah! You'll find someone so much cuter,
someone who's a better fit for you.
You really think so?
Sure!
You coward.
Well, catch you later.
S-Sato-san...
Sato-san...
What's wrong,
Detective Takagi?
Your face looks pale.
Ain't you been eating?
Come on, we're here for questioning
on the post office burglary case!
Looks like you haven't
gotten over getting dumped.
H-Hey, Ai-kun...
H-H-How'd you know
about that?!
Yo, Takagi!
How's it hangin'?
You look tired!
Want me to handle the questioning?
Uh, well...
Oh, Takagi, let me
massage your shoulders!
How about some
coffee, Takagi?
Er...
If you're hungry,
I've got some rice crackers...
Hey! Eat up!
Uh, thanks...
Wow! Detective Takagi
sure is popular!
No, I don't think
that's what it is...
But when we arrived, she had such
a shocked and scared look on her face!
It didn't look like she was
pretending at all!
I wonder if what
he just said is true...
It is kind of hard
to believe.
A mistake?
I've got it!
The culprit is...
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Recycling
The next episode is the last broadcast of the year!
For us...
In a 2-hour New Year's special...
It's our time to shine!