Love and hate are brought together...
Through both reasoning and suspense!
Can a case like this really happen?
Crimes cannot be recycled
Seeing through to the one and only truth...
I look like a child, but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan
That day, I went to Akebono with the rest of the Detective Boys to apprehend a thief.
We'll definitely catch him together! Won't we, Conan-kun?
Doesn't it make you feel a little uneasy?
Other people reuse materials that can still be put to use.
It's an amazing system, in which we are able to help preserve our limited resources.
Oh! You're talking about recycling.
But you don't know what kind of person used it before.
Right, Conan?
It's okay.
There aren't many people that wipe their boogers on everything, unlike Genta-kun here...
Oh my gosh, Genta-kun!
Is that true?
I-Idiot!
Don't say things like that.
Stop it. I'm just stating what I see...
Hey! It's the bus to Akebono!
Ah, it really is!
The Victim Who Came Back!
It's too quiet. There's no one around.
Maybe that's because there's a thief around.
Anyway, watch out for anyone suspicious-looking.
What am I doing here?
It came from that room!
Hey! Wait up, Conan!
What happened?
Excuse me!
Is this okay, Conan?
This is...
She was struck on the back of the head and died from a brain injury.
We estimate the time of death to be around 2 to 3 PM yesterday afternoon.
Furthermore, she was not carrying any form of identification.
Hosono-san, please give us a description of the body when you found it.
Yes...
I bought that sofa yesterday evening at the recycle shop in Beika.
And it was delivered this morning at 10 o'clock.
I noticed the seat cushions were lopsided, but when I tried to fix them...
The old lady was there.
I see.
Did you know the victim?
No, I did not.
Well then, where were you yesterday from 2:00 to 3:00 PM?
A-Are you suspecting me?!
No, not at all. I just have to take every last thing into consideration.
I was at the movies all afternoon.
Were you with anyone?
I went alone.
Do you think Inspector Megure suspects her?
Yeah.
I can think of only two possibilities.
Either Hosono Sanae-san killed the victim...
And made it look as though the body was in the sofa when it was delivered...
Or, the body really was already inside the sofa.
But, when we arrived, she had such a shocked and scared look on her face!
It didn't look like she was pretending at all!
Right?
Yeah.
It's our job as police to consider all possibilities.
But...
Hey, hey, Inspector...
I wonder why the old lady inside the sofa didn't have her shoes on.
It means she might not have been wearing them when she was murdered.
I see! So that means she was murdered inside a room and moved later, right?
If she is the culprit, then the murder had to have taken place here.
Takagi-kun, please go question the neighbors.
Yes, sir!
Inspector.
What?
The apartment next door?
Excuse me. What is your name?
I-It's Tokunaga... Did something happen?
Actually... Your neighbor, Hosono-san, found a dead body inside her sofa.
Tokunaga-san, were you in your room yesterday between 2 and 3 PM?
Yes.
I work in the evening.
Did you notice any strange noises, voices, or anything out of the ordinary next door?
Please think carefully and try to remember.
Now that you mention it, I think I heard someone arguing.
So you did hear something?
Y-Yes.
What did you hear?
I'm not sure... I couldn't hear it very well.
Is that right? Thank you very much.
I'll come back later if I need anything else.
Okay.
I wonder if what he just said is true.
It's kind of hard to believe.
In this case, she may have been lying about going to the movies.
Excuse me, Inspector.
What is it?
I'd like to look into that recycle shop.
I can't stop thinking about what the children said.
Officer Takagi...
I suppose.
Sure. Go ahead.
Yes!
If you're inquiring about that sofa, we received it as a donation from a customer yesterday.
Y-Yesterday? And you immediately put it up for display?
Yes. Hosono-san came right when the sofa was being brought here.
I told her that it would take a few days to mend, but she told me she was in a hurry and couldn't wait that long.
And what about after she bought it?
It was in the store until closing time...
After which, we loaded it into the delivery truck.
Could anyone else have gotten near the truck?
That's not possible.
The truck was parked in the garage...
And we locked it right after the sofa was loaded on it, of course.
I see...
Which means...
The old lady was already in the sofa when it was bought.
So the culprit was the previous owner of the sofa?
To be honest, I didn't receive that sofa as a donation.
But Hirose-san...
Didn't you say that a customer came and gave it to you for free?
I'm sorry.
Yesterday afternoon, I drove around to pick up unwanted items.
It was around 4:00 PM, and I was on my way home...
What's wrong, Hirose-san?
Isn't that a waste? It looks like it could still be used.
You're right!
You picked it up at a dump?
Yeah.
Because it looked like it was still in good condition, and I felt sorry for it.
Um...
I'm sorry for lying.
No, I understand your feelings about not wanting to let it go to waste.
But, now that we know it was picked up at a dump...
There's no way we'll find the culprit.
Yeah.
But, Officer Takagi...
Isn't it hard to believe that the culprit would move it there from very far away?
I see!
Which garbage dump did you find the sofa in?
I think it was in...
...Akebono, on 3rd Street.
Akebono?!
We're back to where we started.
So that old lady...
Yeah...
She was left here yesterday at 4:00 PM.
Then was picked up and taken to the recycle shop...
And, finally, was returned here via the delivery truck at 10:00 AM.
The culprit most likely lives in this area.
But, how are we going to find him?
Also, why would someone put the body in an old sofa?
Isn't that obvious?
Yeah! They didn't think anyone would bother an old sofa in a garbage dump.
But...
You're starting to do that "but" thing again!
You have a bad habit of denying the truth, don't you?
Look who's talking.
Some people just creep me out!
This morning, Tokunaga-san was alone at that restaurant drinking beer and laughing.
Oh? That guy actually laughs?
He always seems so serious when I see him.
That's why I think something big must have happened!
Tokunaga?
Isn't that the man we saw this morning?
Hosono Sanae-san's neighbor?
What are you doing over there?
Oh! Inspector Megure!
Why are you here?
Hosono-san's alibi was able to be confirmed.
Someone at the movie theater remembered seeing her.
Thank goodness!
But if that's the case...
Tokunaga-san most likely mistook something else as those voices.
A mistake?
Actually, while we were trying to find where the sofa came from, we ended up back here.
The victim was definitely put in the sofa here.
I'll search for some witnesses!
I'm leaving it to you, then.
I know who the culprit is!
Really, Mitsuhiko?!
Yes.
Tokunaga-san didn't mishear the argument.
Most likely, there never was one.
But Inspector Megure said...
Isn't it obvious?
The culprit is Tokunaga-san!
He's the culprit?!
Those women were right, after all!
She said that Tokunaga guy was in a really good mood this morning!
Now we know the truth.
Tokunaga-san is definitely the culprit.
Conan-kun, for what purpose do murderers hide their victim's bodies?
So the body won't be discovered.
If it was discovered, it would be identified.
The police would investigate around the area and eventually find the culprit.
That's why you would hide it.
That's right.
However, you would have a better chance if you hid the body in the mountains or in the ocean.
Why didn't the culprit do that?
Yeah, I don't get that.
True...
There's only one solution.
Tokunaga-san actually wanted to go to the mountains or the ocean.
However, it was impossible for him to do that.
Why was it impossible?
Remember what he said?
He works during the evenings.
That's why he wouldn't be able to go far away.
I see. Adults can't skip out on work. Right, Officer Takagi?
Yeah...
Tokunaga-san placed the body in the sofa, only intending to hide it there temporarily.
"Temporarily?"
Yes.
After work, he was planning to hide it properly.
But after work, when he came back to get it...
The recycle shop's delivery truck had already picked it up!
That's right.
When he returned from work, Tokunaga-san was probably shocked to find that...
The sofa had disappeared.
Then, his shock turned into utter joy.
After all, someone took the body away for him.
Since he didn't have to get rid of the body, he was able to celebrate.
However, upon returning home, he found that the unthinkable had occurred.
The body that he thought had disappeared was found next door.
However, the police's primary suspect was Hosono Sanae-san, who discovered the body.
Tokunaga-san took advantage of this and decided to lie.
Now that you mention it, I think I heard someone arguing.
That wasn't a mistake.
He lied to try and frame Hosono-san as the culprit.
Everything makes sense now, Mitsuhiko!
You're amazing!
Oh, it was nothing...
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
Even if he had to go to work, why would the culprit need to move the body?
Yeah.
He could have just left it in his room, locked the door, and no one would've been the wiser.
I see. I guess that's true...
What did we come to Akebono to do today?
To look for the thief who's been robbing homes around this area.
Tokunaga-san was afraid the thief would break in!
Oh! If the thief saw the victim, he'd report it to the police.
Exactly.
So that's why he couldn't leave the body in his room!
That's a perfect deduction, Mitsuhiko.
No. That's impossible, Mitsuhiko.
Listen. Think carefully.
Don't you think the chances of someone seeing him hide the body are greater than the thief breaking in?
And would he really be happy to see his sofa gone?
Wouldn't a person normally be worried that the police might have found it?
Also, he could have simply called in sick for a day, right?
In other words, you simply assumed Tokunaga-san was the culprit.
Cases aren't that simple. Let's thin this through again.
Conan-kun! I'll say this now, but...
Who is the one assuming things?
And you keep saying "normally," but a lot of people are really wary of the recent robberies.
He probably felt lucky to find the body gone.
And someone who never misses work would fear they'd look suspicious if they missed even a single day.
Aren't there weak-hearted people who go to work every day just because they can't speak up for themselves?
According to the janitor, Tokunaga-san owns a small bar.
Despite the financial difficulties, he works everyday.
He's a serious, timid person...
Or at least that's what the janitor said.
Just as Mitsuhiko predicted.
He has to get the store ready, so he leaves at this time everyday.
3:00 PM, huh?
Still...
He wouldn't know for sure if the thief would break in. Would he really be that wary?
Attention citizens!
There have been a number of burglaries in this area.
Please be sure to lock up your house before you leave.
Once again, this is the Akebono Police.
W-
W-Wait!
Stop!
I'm Officer Takagi.
Did you drive around this area yesterday?
Yes. If I remember correctly, we were here ten minutes earlier yesterday.
Officer Takagi!
So that's what happened!
After Tokunaga-san murdered her, he heard them...
The voices from the patrol car!
This is the Akebono Police.
There have been a number of burglaries in this area.
After hearing this, you put her body inside a sofa and carried it to a dump.
Isn't that right, Tokunaga-san
Owed that lady money.
A-And when I asked her for an extra week to repay it...
She barged into my apartment and told me that if I didn't pay her back in time, she would revoke my bar license.
That's why...
That's why I lost my senses.
I'm very sorry.
Tokunaga-san, please follow me to the police station.
Yes.
Good job, Mitsuhiko!
Good for you!
Mitsuhiko...
You deserve some kudos for your great deductions this time!
Eh?! The thief in Akebono was caught a long time ago?
Yeah. A man who was arrested for theft last week just confessed to the other burglaries as well.
What's with that?! We wanted to be the ones to catch him!
I wasted all of that money on the bus fare, too.
So, could it be that Tokunaga-san didn't even need to bother with hiding the body in the sofa?
That's true, but our culprit didn't think things though, and slipped up because of it.
What a hopeless criminal.
I know, right?
Hey, hey. You guys...
Mail she can't erase?
Has it already been three years since then?
They've heard it.
The whispers of the demon.
Matsuda-kun!
You can't, Sato!
Don't! You'll set off the bomb's mercury lever!
Conan-kun
Next 2 Hour Special:
A Shaking Police HQ and 12 Million Hostages.
Next Conan's Hint!
Map symbols.
Please look forward to the next episode!
Next time will be a two-hour New Year's special!