Happy new year!
Detective Conan is going into its eighth season.
We've recently passed 300 episodes.
We'll keep doing our best.
The TV series...
The movies...
And Shōnen Sunday...
Please keep supporting them!
Evacuation of residents in a three-block
radius has been completed.
Defusal at area 1 is now in progress.
Defusal at area 1 has been completed.
A fog proof lens and refrigerated breathing ducts on the helmet.
I'm riding with Matsuda's
team, leaving for area 2.
Designed to shield a body from a bomb blast.
Constructed to the inch with hairline precision.
Pockets in various places and metallic
plate protection for the head.
With such large-scale gear, it cannot
be put on or taken off without help.
Weight: 40 kg.
The bomb blast suit is hot even in winter.
To put it simply, you can't wear it for more than five minutes—it's outright impossible.
All police units, all police units.
Disperse from area 1.
Proceed to secure area 2...
All units in city limits, watch
out for suspicious vehicles.
That is all.
DC unit 80, roger that.
AV unit, roger that.
Citizens, please do not panic.
Please do not take any belongings
with you and evacuate quickly.
Please be careful not to push others.
There is no need to rush.
The building residents have all been evacuated.
Roger.
Kenji Hagiwara
MPD Riot Squad —
Bomb Disposal Unit
Well, then...
Shall we get started?
Jimpei Matsuda
MPD Riot Squad —
Bomb Disposal Unit
Good work, Matsuda.
How's Hagiwara?
Well, analysis shows a photosensitive trigger.
A white cord from a mercury
tilt switch. From the LCD panel...
Matsuda? What do you want?
Hagiwara! What the hell are you still doing?
Hurry up and dismantle it already!
Hey, hey. Don't get all pissed.
The timer's been stopped.
So did you finish?
Yeah, once I opened it up, the device was
simple. For something like that...
"I can take a toy like this apart in three", right?
So how are you doing?
Well, this looks like it's going to take
a bit longer than 3 minutes.
It's simple in principle, but
there are traps everywhere.
Looks like this one is the real thing.
Yeah.
By the way, you're wearing
your blast suit, right?
I can't move in that thing.
I couldn't wear that.
Moron! You trying to get yourself killed?!
Well, if that happens,
it's up to you to avenge me.
Are you trying to piss me off?
Just kidding, man. You know
I'd never screw up that bad.
Anyway, finish up and come down.
I'll be waiting for you at the usual place.
Hey, sounds good.
With an invitation like that.
I'll run all engines at their fullest.
What the—?
What's wrong? Hagiwara!
Everyone, run for it!
Get out of here!
The timer started again!
Hagiwara?
Hello?
Hagiwara!
Hagiwara...
How? How did you know?
I asked the kid with the glasses.
Ah, I see.
Oh yeah, Shin'ichi. What are doing about
the national mock exams tomorrow?
The national mock exams?
You can't make it, right?
You'll probably say "I've got some case I can't
get away from," or something, right?
Hey, what is this?
How did you do that?
Gotcha!
Geez...
Dad! Conan-kun!
Hurry up, breakfast is ready!
Come on, Dad!
You sure are noisy in the morning!
It's afternoon already.
I promised Sonoko I'd study with her
for tomorrow, so finish eating quickly.
Your problem, not mine.
Didn't you have a report to deliver to a client today?
Oh, Conan-kun, didn't you promise to go with Ayumi-chan and the guys to Haido Shopping Mall?
Yeah.
Haido Shopping Mall?
Oh, that place with the huge Ferris wheel.
Yeah.
Monday, 6th of January.
Winter break was almost over.
Little did we know the next two
days would be a nightmare.
Satō-san, what do you
think about my disguise?
Pretty spiffy, huh?
Satō-san?
Is something wrong?
Miwako...
Hey, Miwako!
Miwako!
Oh, Yumi.
What is it? You seem out of it.
I'm okay, just a little tired.
I'm going out for a bit.
Hey, didn't you have
paperwork all day today?
There's just something bothering me.
Don't forget about the karaoke tonight.
Oh, right. What time was it again?
9 PM. I sent an e-mail to your mobile, didn't I?
Huh?
Umm...
Oh, sorry. I erased it.
You have to stop automatically deleting your e-mails right after you read them!
It's just that I have to keep clearing spam out of my inbox! I keep the important mails...
Oh? So, my mails aren't important?
Now, now.
Geez.
Well, see you at nine.
Don't be late!
Roger.
Mail she can't erase?
Haido Shopping Mall
Wow, it's so high!
You're right! Cool!
This huge wheel is 125 metres tall—it's the largest in Japan.
One turn takes 18 minutes.
I could make six cups of ramen!
A turning diameter of 105 metres
and a period of 18 minutes...
...means we must be moving at
30 centimetres per second.
Come on, don't you have
anything better to think about?
Oh, you mean like the electricity
necessary to turn this wheel?
Never mind.
Has it already been three years since then?
Let me introduce you.
This is Jimpei Matsuda-kun.
He's been assigned to the first investigation division, criminal investigation section!
Until last year, he was part of the riot police, and he's quite exceptional.
Let's cut the crap, Inspector.
I ain't no transfer student from the boonies.
There's no point standin' around makin' chitchat.
I was stuck here by the higher-ups passin' me around.
Err, right. Satō-kun, you can show him the ropes.
What? Me, sir?
Don't be like that.
My superior asked me to take special care of this one. He's been through a lot.
Look after him for me, okay?
Yes, sir.
You call that an inquiry?
Nobody's gonna open up if you shove them around like a gangster!
Geez, you've been in our department for six days now!
It's time you straightened up and listened!
E-mail?
You're pretty fast.
Yeah, I've always been pretty nimble with my fingers.
Texting your girlfriend?
Nah, to a buddy of mine...
But he won't get it, no matter how many times I send it.
He passed on four years ago.
What do you mean, you're not going?!
I'm gonna hang out at the station today.
You don't need my help to transfer an old man from another station.
Now, hold on.
You guys get a message every year on the 6th of January, right?
That prank fax the HQ's been getting over the past three years?
It's just a big number every year, isn't it?
"3" three years ago,
"2" two years ago, "1" one year ago.
It's pretty obvious...
It's a countdown for a bomb.
If it's gonna happen, it's gonna happen today.
Inspector, our annual greeting.
A fax with a number on it, right?
What number is it this year?
It's not a number this time.
'I am the knight of the round table.
To the stupid but sly ladies
and gentlemen of the police.
At noon and at 14:00 hours today...
In memory of my comrade's head, I plan to set off some interesting fireworks.
If you want to stop me, then come and see me.
I'll keep the 72nd seat open for you.
What does this mean?
I don't know.
Hey! Where are you going?
Don't you get it? The knight of the round table is keeping the 72nd seat open!
The only thing around here that's round with 72 seats
is the giant Ferris wheel at the Haido Shopping Mall!
Please, go ahead.
Damn, we're too late!
But we still have 30 minutes
until the deadline.
I'm with the police. What's going on?
The control panel suddenly exploded, and the Ferris wheel went out of control!
It's okay, though! We evacuated the passengers.
Where's gondola #72 right now?
Oh, it should be about to come down.
Matsuda-kun!
Stand back!
The knight of the round table isn't here.
But there is an odd little something under the seat here.
You mean... a bomb?
W-Wait! Matsuda-kun!
It's okay.
Leave this to a pro.
Wait! Matsuda-kun!
What pro?
Until last year, he was a member of the Bomb Squad in the riot police.
He said he had a friend who died...
That's most likely the bomb squad member who died in the line of duty
four years ago on the 6th of January while trying to dismantle a bomb—Hagiwara-kun.
Two bombs had been set
in two separate locations.
Matsuda-kun dismantled one, but
Hagiwara-kun didn't make it in time.
The bomber still hasn't been arrested.
Matsuda-kun often hoped to get transferred to a team in charge of bombing investigations.
Most likely to take this
case and avenge his friend.
To cool him off, they transferred
him to Homicide instead.
More importantly, Inspector,
what should we do?
It's only six minutes to the deadline.
It will take at least ten minutes
for car 72 to come back down.
We can't help that. We have no
choice but to trust Matsuda-kun.
It stopped!
Put out the fire!
Well, now this is getting bothersome.
Hello, Matsuda-kun? Are you okay?
Yeah!
But that jolt caused a strange switch to activate.
A mercury tilt switch.
Mercury tilt switch?
With a slight vibration, the mercury bead in the centre will roll,
and if it contacts the wires, I'm history.
If you don't want bits and pieces of me rainin' down on you,
don't start the Ferris wheel till I've disabled this bomb.
But you've got less than five minutes before it blows up!
I can take a toy like this apart in three—
"Brave police officer, I commend you for your courage and present you with a reward..."
Huh? What are you talking about?!
'A clue to the whereabouts of my second, larger firework
will be displayed three seconds before the explosion.
Good luck.'
Those words just came up on the LCD.
Looks like if I dismantle the bomb, we won't get the clue.
This means the bomber was planning to lock a cop in this gondola from the start.
So the explosion earlier was because the bomber knew you were in the car?
But that means the bomber's still nearby!
I don't know if you can find the jerk in that crowd.
But I have a rough idea where the next bomb is.
The fax said "my comrade's head".
The knights of the round table
were from medieval Europe.
And knights of that time wore helmets with crosses on 'em.
You get the hint?
The map symbol for a hospital!
Bingo.
Once I've seen the next clue, I'll know which hospital it is.
You'll contact me? But the clue's set to appear three seconds before the explosion!
My battery's almost out. See ya.
Matsuda-kun? Matsuda-kun?
Matsuda-kun...
I think we can make an
exception for today.
We've only got one minute left!
Everybody evacuate the area!
Matsuda-kun!
Don't, Satō! It's too late!
B-But...
Stay back! This is dangerous!
But he's still...
He's still in there!
Sorry, Hagiwara. Looks like I won't be able to keep that promise...
What now? The fax said
there's still another bomb...
I know that!
Beika Central Hospital...
That's where the other bomb is.
Jimpei Matsuda
Beika Central Hospital
Send the bomb squad right away!
He was like a cold winter wind.
Leaving nothing but a sad e-mail behind... Have my future dreams disappeared?
Detective Satō!
Oh!
Eh, so that's what happened three years ago.
Yeah, if Satō-san's still hung up on
him then we don't have a chance.
I know.
I suppose we could live up to him if we died in the line of duty too.
H-Hey, don't even joke about that!
Oh, Satō-san?
Ah, Takagi-kun, Shiratori-kun.
What happened? Conan-kun
and the kids are here too?
I just bumped into them.
I thought I'd treat them to a snack
for solving the last case.
All the cake we can eat!
So, what are you guys up to?
Oh, yeah. We were told there
was a strange informant here.
But when we checked the restaurant, there was nobody there.
Looks like it was just a prank.
I'm going out for karaoke with Yumi later. Wanna join us?
Yeah, sure.
You go on without me.
I'm not in the mood today, so I'll pass.
Hey, let's go!
Yeah!
Say, what kind of informant was it?
We got a strange tip that a bomb
was in this restaurant.
Since today's the 6th of January like the bomb cases seven years ago and three years ago,
we came to check it out, but...
A bomb threat prank...
I'm a fast-pitching, strong-slugging Major Leaguer.
Batter up—let's start the extra innings.
Don't tell me—
Shiratori-kun!
What's going on?
Another bomb?
S-Shiratori-kun!
Shiratori-kun!
It's dangerous. Get away, hurry...
Are you okay, Shiratori-san?
Yes. But I'm not as good as you at dodging an explosion...
Takagi-kun, seal this road off
and call an ambulance!
Got it!
But if you can talk this much, you must be okay.
No. He's bleeding from his right temple and his left arm and leg are paralysed.
I think it's...
Acute subdural haematoma.
If he can't get to a hospital fast, he's in big trouble.
No way...
If the gasoline catches fire, there could be a second explosion!
Let's get Inspector Shiratori away from
the car and wait for the ambulance!
You're right.
You know, this is horrible.
Yeah. Who could have done this?
I don't know who the bomber is, but it's clearly someone out to get police officers.
First the bomber lured the police out here with a false alarm about a bomb in the restaurant.
And then, while the detectives were searching for the bomb in the store,
the bomber planted the real bomb in the cop's car.
The bomber probably used the crowd in front of the restaurant to hide from the officers.
Judging from what I've seen,
I'm guessing the bomb's safety unlocked when the car's door was opened.
And when he opened the door to get out, it triggered the explosion.
The question is why Inspector Shiratori tried to get out of the car so fast.
Here...
What?
I had to show you as soon as I could...
That nightmare you've never been able to forget—this is your chance to get over it.
"I'm a fast-pitching, strong-slugging Major Leaguer.
Batter up—let's start the extra innings."
"The game will start at noon tomorrow and end at 3 in the afternoon."
"Don't bother trying to get a good stopper ready, 'cause at the end I'm going to turn the game around."
"If you want to stop the game, come and see me."
"I'll be waiting for the police to climb onto the bloody mound at the steel batter's box."
W-What?
That's...
H-Hey...
Could it be?
This is...
I am the knight of the round table. To the stupid
but sly ladies and gentlemen of the police...
Leave this to a pro.
It's him... It's him again!
A-Are you serious?
Shiratori-kun was wounded
in a bomb explosion?
Yes, sir. We just sent him in an
ambulance to a nearby hospital...
He's badly injured.
What's your status?
Every police station in the city received a fax with the same words you just read to me.
The place is in an uproar!
Everybody's saying this could be the bomber from those unsolved cases three and seven years ago.
Well, they guessed right. I don't
think there's any doubt about it.
Please report that to Superintendent Matsumoto.
Only the first half of the fax from three years ago was made public.
A copycat couldn't have
written anything so similar.
Satō-san, here's your car!
Thanks, Chiba-kun.
I'm heading over to investigate.
Hey, Satō-kun? Satō-kun!
He's not getting away. Not this time.
I'll take him in myself.
This is an urgent order to every officer in the MPD!
We've received a bomb warning, but we do not yet know the location!
The bomber claims there are two bombs, and they'll go off at noon and 3 PM tomorrow!
Judging from past cases, we believe the threat is real!
Everybody is to show utmost caution while attempting to apprehend the bomber!
Extra innings? He's toying with us.
Megure!
Sir.
We can't allow this game to proceed any further.
I want you to take care of this. Understood?
Understood, sir.
This is your chance...
That nightmare you've never been able to forget—this is your chance to get over it.
That's right. I have to get over it!
I have to arrest that bomber and put the past behind me!
Forget...?
So your dad died in the line of duty and you kept his cuffs as a lucky charm, huh?
Hey, give those back!
Go ahead—tell me I have to forget about him and move on or something.
Nah, I don't think you should forget him.
It's up to you whether you move on or not.
But if you forget about your dad, that's when he'll really be dead.
Matsuda-kun...
Hey, will you tell me something?
Why does this bomber hate cops so much?
C-Conan-kun! When did you get in the car?
Well? Answer me.
There were two bombers involved in the case seven years ago.
The bombs were set in two
nearby blocks of flats.
The bombers demanded a billion yen in ransom.
They said if they'd blow up the blocks if even one resident tried to escape.
The police managed to disarm one of the bombs in time, but not the other one.
They had no choice but to agree to the bombers' demand.
The bombers stopped the timer remotely.
We evacuated all the residents, and the case seemed to have come to a close...
But half an hour later, we suddenly received a call from one of the bombers, saying...
"What do you mean 'the timer is still running?!"
The bomber must've heard a recorded report on the news
and thought we were still trying to disarm the bomb.
We thought it would be the perfect time to catch the bomber.
Drawing out the call, we traced him
and spotted him in a phone box.
But we had no luck.
The bomber panicked and ran, getting hit by
a truck in the process. He died on the scene.
So how did you know there were two bombers?
Because...
After the first guy was killed, the bomb started ticking again and exploded.
Everyone, run for it!
The timer started again!
We discovered where the dead bomber lived,
and found evidence that he shared the place with another person.
The other bomber must've thought we leaked fake information to the news
to lure in his friend, which ended up killing him.
That's a crummy reason to hold a grudge!
They shouldn't have setup a bomb
and tried to steal money!
That's right!
Well, that's all I know about the case. Can you kids get out now?
But we want to help!
The more the merrier, right?
But if my superiors find out I'm carting a bunch of minors around on a criminal investigation...
But children are often better than adults at deciphering childish riddles ike this.
Or maybe your problem is actually that you
lost Edogawa-kun and ended up stuck with us?
Is it?
Is it?!
IS IT?!
That's not what I...
But why did the bomber bother sending this riddle in the first place?
Yeah, if he didn't say anything at all
then no one would ever find them.
If you hid some treasure, and someone came
looking for it, what would you do?
I'd watch them quietly with my heart pounding...
But what if you'd hidden the treasure in a deadly booby trap?
Well, in that case...
I'd give small clues and...
Oh, I get it!
Yes. This bomber is like a child. A spoiled brat with some rather explosive toys.
Hey, Ran! Phone!
Geez, Dad, why don't you get it?
But both my hands are busy!
Geez...
Hello, this is the Mouri residence.
It's me.
Oh, Dr. Agasa.
Ah, Ran-kun. Conan-kun's saying
that tonight he'll sleep at my place.
At your house, Doctor?
Yeah, the kids are all hooked on a new video game I designed.
Then Ayumi-chan and the boys are staying too?
Yeah, that's right.
They're saying since it's near the end of winter break and all, they'll return tomorrow evening.
Yes, but...
Okay, talk to you later.
Now to call Ayumi-kun's house.
Please, Doc!
We want to avenge Inspector Shiratori!
Yeah, we wanna avenge him!
Please, Doctor?
I'll make sure things don't get out of hand.
Geez, I'll be in trouble if anyone finds out.
And I was making Conan-kun's favourite dinner, too...
Don't worry about it! Those nationwide
mock exams are tomorrow, right?
That way you can study without having to look after that brat, right?
Oh, yeah, Ran-chan!
Can I have another bottle?
What, you're gonna drink more?
Oh, it'll be fine.
Honestly, looking after this drunkard is way harder.
I wonder what this code means.
The only thing that's really clear is the time.
Anyway, the bomber has to be a foreigner.
Because he calls them "major leaguers".
Not necessarily! There are more Japanese major leaguers recently.
Oh, yeah. But the bomb has
to be set in a baseball field!
Yeah, cause he wrote stuff like
'mound' and "batter's box".
It's in South Haido Station.
South Haido Station? The Tohto Central line?
That's right.
What are you talking about? There's no
baseball field near South Haido Station.
It's a code. "Mound" and "batter's
box" don't really mean those.
So you broke the code?
Yeah.
Three years ago, the places the
bombs were planted were...
South Haido
Station
Tohto Line
Beika Central
Hospital
Haido
Shopping
Mall
The Ferris wheel at Haido Shopping
Mall and at Beika Central Hospital.
Both of the roads in front of those locations extend to South Haido Station.
...Tohto Line's South Haido Station.
Punning "extended lines" with "extra innings"...
Extended Lines
Extra Innings
Slow, aren't you? If the roads cross by a train, you'll find the "stopper" there.
"Stopper"?
Stopper?
What's that?
Oh, I see! I know what!
It's the railroad crossing stoplight!
Then the steel "batter's box" is...
A steel box—the train.
We're supposed to climb onto the bloody mound—the red Tohto Line Train.
Oh no! I've got to tell Satō-san and the others!
It's all right, I heard everything.
We came to the same conclusion here.
The first bomb is probably inside the Tohto Line Train,
which goes up through Tōkyō from South Haido Station.
I'll contact the Inspector and have him send a
search team. You call the bomb squad.
And hurry!
Yes.
What? South Haido Station? Are you sure?
Yes. Yes. And then?
Okay, got it.
Yes, we'll evacuate.
Everybody, calm down! Evacuate the station in an orderly fashion!
Just trash...
What's this?
It's... a bomb!
Everyone, get back... There's a bomb!
What the?
What the heck is this?
What? A decoy?
It wasn't the real bomb? And then?
Looks like the bomber expected us to search the station.
Yes. Our misbehaving boy is toying with us.
Yes.
Understood.
But even so, it doesn't seem he's doing
this because he's after money.
Yes.
Yeah. He probably wants revenge on the police,
and has taken the 12 million people in Tōkyō as hostages.
Tohto Line —
South Haido Station
FAIL!
What? Another decoy?!
What kind of search are you running?!
You haven't confused them with
the real one, have you?
No.
We've searched every red line train that runs through the city,
but all the bombs we've found were fake.
I see. He's probably trying
to throw us off the scent.
At any rate, don't let your guard
down and keep looking.
Understood.
Superintendent Matsumoto!
What is it?
We've heard from Ozaki's team. They're at the baseball fields.
And, what about them?
Yes, sir. We searched the major baseball stadiums in the city, but found nothing.
We're now searching the smaller ones as well.
Well, it looks like the stadium lead is a dead end.
Listen up! Stop every red line train in the city!
I want everyone who was searching the baseball fields reassigned to staking out train stations!
We still have five hours before the noon deadline.
It's possible the bomber hasn't even planted it yet!
Yes, sir!
"Still have five hours", eh?
If anything, I should be saying we only have five hours.
Yeah.
I'm sleepy.
It's odd.
The bomber must've known we'd search baseball fields given this threat, but there's no decoys there.
He probably figured nobody would be there.
It's off season, and there are no big games scheduled.
I guess. Still, it wouldn't be unusual for there
to be a few fakes to throw us off though.
Anyway, we can't drag these kids around with us anymore.
Yeah, that's right.
Oh, did you check in on Shiratori-kun?
Yes. Yumi-san's staying with him.
She said the operation was a success and they're just waiting for him to regain consciousness.
Whew, what a relief.
Look, Takagi-kun. Don't let Miwako do anything dangerous.
If this bomber is the guy who killed Matsuda-kun three years ago, she's going to be out for blood!
You're the only one who can protect her!
But why me?
Because you're just like him—like Matsuda-kun.
Just because I looked like him in that disguise...
Nah, he was five... No, ten times cooler than you!
T-Ten times?
But there's something about you. Something in your scent or spirit. You feel like him.
And I think Miwako picked up on that too.
Say, Takagi-kun?
Hey, Takagi-kun!
What were you thinking over so seriously?
Did you figure out where the bomb is hidden?
Ah, no...
Then what?
Oh, it's nothing important.
Well, never mind.
I'm going to continue the investigation. Take the kids home.
After that, get some rest at the office, and help Inspector Megure once you've rested up.
But I was going to continue the investigation.
Forget it! A groggy cop shouldn't be out on the streets! Got that?
Yes, ma'am.
I won't let you take him from me.
Not now...
Not ever!
A test right after New Year's...
Feels like a university entrance exam.
Uh-huh.
After all, New Year's is supposed to be fun!
Well, why aren't you out having fun?
I just don't want to have any regrets.
I guess this is all I have left to rely on.
Eh? Could that be...?
No! Look.
It's just a photo of Kyōgoku-san.
When I look at it, I feel stronger.
Even if my test scores are bad, I won't feel bad!
As long as I have Makoto-san's love, I don't need to score 100%!
Oh, I'm so embarrassed!
Yeah, yeah.
Well, I'll take you home now,
so tell me where you all live.
You're taking us back home already?
But we're so close to solving the riddle!
You all haven't slept in a long time.
I can't keep dragging primary school kids along on police business.
But what happened to Detective Satō?
She's continuing the investigation.
Oh, I see. She told you to send us home, right?
You do anything she tells you to do, don't you?
I have to! She's two years older than me and she's my senior officer!
Are you still going to let her push you
around after you get married?
M-Married? That won't happen. She just dumped me the other day.
U-Um, Satō-san?
What did you want to talk to me about?
Oh, that.
S-Satō-san?
Can we call off our date?
I'm cursed.
Cursed?
I lose everybody I care about.
My dad, my primary school PE teacher,
the guy I liked in the baseball club...
And...
And him too.
I just don't want to go through that again.
Satō-san...
So, let's just stay as co-workers.
Huh?
S-Satō-san.
Takagi-kun.
Sa—
I guess I was never the right person for you.
Right. I'm sure you'll find yourself a much cuter girlfriend!
R-Really?
So there's no way we'd get married.
And you've already given up?
What a wimp.
That's so weak-willed.
It's not like I want to give up...
But?
But, you know...
Because you can't hope to live up to Detective Matsuda
who gave his life to save a hospital three years ago, right?
Where'd you—
Detective Takagi, watch the road.
That lady in the mini-patrol car told us!
Yumi-san?
She acted out the whole story for us.
And then Detective Matsuda risked his life to
find out where the next bomb was located!
"Oops, looks like it's about time. See ya." *click*
"Wait, Matsuda-kun! Matsuda-kun? Matsuda-kun!"
It was a sad tale to hear and to tell.
Oh, I see.
I wouldn't blame you for giving up.
When someone is gone, their loved ones enshrine their memory
in an idealised form that remains with them for the rest of their lives.
Just like a certain someone.
Hey, lay off. I'm not dead yet!
So how did you do on the math exam?
I feel like I'm dying.
I wish I had a guardian angel like you to help me out.
A guardian angel?
Don't play dumb. I saw you staring at Shin'ichi-kun's empty seat throughout the test!
"Help me, Shin'ichi! Why can't I integrate this equation?" —
like that.
That's not it! I was looking at his seat because...
Because?
Because...
Ha! You're turning all red.
It's bad luck to blush during a test.
Speaking of red, I've been hearing police sirens go by all day.
Yeah, now that you mention it.
I wonder what's going on...
Red, red, red.
Something wrong with red?
This line about "climbing onto the bloody mound" is bugging me.
You didn't think it's the red line trains?
It just doesn't fit.
But wait, if this is the same
pattern as three years ago,
the first bomb should be set in an
obvious place to lure the police.
I have to think more simply.
Things associated with red? Mailboxes, fire engines...
Red devils, Little Red Riding Hood...
Tomatoes, strawberries, watermelons,
apples, cherries, chilli soup, salmon...
Red... Climb... Steel... Box.
Genta-kun only thinks about food.
All this thinking makes me hungry.
Me too. I'm thirsty, too.
Shall we get him to stop at a rest area...
Say, that's red too, come to think of it.
Look, you can see it over there.
You're right.
T-That's it! Red, climbing, a box of steel.
Tohto Tower
Has something already happened?
What's this?
There's smoke coming out.
Was there a bomb here after all?
I'll go find out what happened.
You guys wait in the car.
Okay?
Today was supposed to be the broadcast of
the Tohto Tower Mascot, Tohto-kun, but...
We have an unexpected schedule change due to a sudden accident.
Excuse me, what happened here?
Oh, you see...
What? The bomb is in Tohto Tower?
Yes, I'm sure of it.
Explain what happened.
Just before I got here, there was a minor explosion and the lift stopped.
The bomber must've seen us coming and set it off before we could discover it!
The control panel suddenly exploded, and the Ferris wheel went out of control!
It's the same as last time...
Well, I'm going in to check the situation with the stuck lift.
Don't! That explosion is a trap
to lure a cop inside!
What? A trap?
I'll be there in five minutes, so stay put. Got it?
Ah, okay.
Hey, we got trouble!
There's a little girl trapped in the stopped lift!
What did you say?
Satō-san, there's a child trapped in the lift!
Calm down. We have over two hours until the deadline.
It's my duty to check out the situation!
Don't worry! I'll take care of it. You stay there.
B-But...
Look, Takagi-kun. Don't let Miwako do anything dangerous.
I'll get that kid out of there!
But...
She's going to be out for blood!
Do you hear? That's an order! Stay where you are until I arrive!
Understood, Takagi-kun?
Takagi-kun! Can you hear me?
Respond, Takagi-kun!
Takagi-kun!
Please, Takagi-kun! Don't go!
Sorry.
I'm going to check the situation inside.
T-Takagi-kun!
Listen, guys, I have to go in the tower for a bit.
Be good and wait here inside the car.
Okay?
Okay.
I'll be right back!
Will he be okay?
Haibara, look after the kids.
Hey, Conan!
Conan-kun!
You're going too, Conan-kun?
I'm just going to check it out for a sec.
You guys guard the car and don't let
anyone suspicious near it, okay?
But...
You can't let the bomber
get to a police car again!
Don't worry! The Detective Boys can take care of things fine without me, right?
Uh, I guess.
No prob.
See ya!
Be careful, Conan-kun!
According to Detective Takagi's
report from the scene...
Fifteen minutes ago, a small explosion occurred
in the Special Observation Deck in Tohto Tower.
This caused a lift to stop near
the Main Observation Deck.
We don't have any confirmation on whether the explosion was due to a bomb or an accident.
No, it's too similar to what happened three years ago for it to be an accident.
I agree.
This is very likely to be the one.
Urgent! Urgent! This is an
announcement from Police HQ.
There is a high probability of an explosive
device in Minato Ward's Tohto Tower.
All units proceed to Tōkyō Tower and take all measures necessary
to seal off the area and evacuate the inhabitants immediately!
Takagi-kun.
We sincerely apologise to our guests for the
inconvenience, but we will be closed for today.
Please follow our personnel's directions
and exit the hall in an orderly fashion.
There's no need to rush. Please evacuate slowly.
Excuse me, I'm a police officer. Let me through.
Please don't panic.
I'm with the police. Where's the stuck lift?
Ah, it's the rearmost one.
Akemi-chan! It's all right, don't be scared!
It's okay, don't be afraid and come out.
I'm with the police. Is this the
lift with a girl trapped in it?
Akemi-chan, Akemi-chan.
Yes.
It was coming down from the top floor...
Akemi. Akemi.
and was on the verge of arriving here at the
Main Observation Deck when it stopped.
Akemi. Akemi-chan.
Akemi? What are you doing, Akemi?
Hurry on out!
Look, over here.
Akemi!
A small girl was inside, but she's so scared that she won't even respond to her mother.
That gap's too narrow for
an adult to get through.
Then give me a lift.
I'll fit, right?
C-Conan-kun!
Reporting live from Tohto Tower.
Today at about 9:45 AM there was an explosion
of unknown origin within the Tohto Tower.
Fortunately, there were no injuries, but a tower lift stopped from the shock of the explosion...
...trapping a four-year-old girl who
was the only person aboard.
Currently, the cause of explosion is being investigated.
Conan-kun, are you okay?
Yeah.
Hi, Akemi-chan.
I'm coming in now—just a sec, okay?
That's a cute bear, Akemi-chan. What's its name?
Jam-chan.
Wow, what a cute name! Is it a boy?
Yup.
I'd like to go over and say hello
to Jam-chan. Is that okay?
Yeah, it's okay.
Okay, then I'm coming over now.
According to information we just received...
...a police officer has entered the lift to help the girl.
What? They sent another child in?!
And then, Mum bought me Jam-chan for my birthday.
Really? Well, your mum's waiting for
you outside, do you want to go?
Okay.
Good. Good girl.
Mum!
Akemi!
You too, Conan-kun.
Conan-kun!
Damn!
You ignored me and gallantly rode to the rescue, and now you're trapped in a lift with Conan-kun.
I'm sorry.
Are you absolutely sure there's no bomb in there?
Well, there's nothing like that inside the lift. We're about to check out the roof.
Also, do you know exactly where you are?
Well, most likely...
When the cables broke, the emergency brakes stopped us
somewhere between the Main Observation Deck and the first floor.
Is that right?
Looks like we'd better climb on top of the lift and wait for the recue team.
Don't! If you climb up here, you'll activate the mercury tilt switch!
Mercury tilt switch?
Mercury tilt switch?!
With a slight vibration, the mercury bead in the centre will roll,
and once it touches the wire, I'm history.
Conan-kun, what's a mercury tilt switch?
It's a part of a detonator.
A bomb big enough to blow up not just this lift, but the entire Tohto Tower.
A bomb?!
O-On top of the lift?
A-Are you sure, Conan-kun?
Yeah, I have seen bombs like this on TV.
It's made from two liquids that are safe on their own,
but when they come together, they create a powerful explosion!
Then we'd better pray the rescue team shows up soon!
Didn't I just say it was hooked into a mercury tilt switch?
It must've been triggered when the lift slammed into a halt.
Even the slightest motion will set this thing off.
So, if you try to climb up here, or if the rescue team tries to climb down, it'll blow us all sky-high!
It's that sensitive?
This mercury tilt switch?
Mercury tilt switch...
I knew it! It's the same bomber from three years ago!
But that means... That means...
How about we have them lower a rope from the lift shaft above us?
I don't think that'll work.
There's a wiretap near this bomb.
Therefore...
The bomber's probably listening to every word we say.
If we leave and he can't hear our voices,
he's going to detonate the bomb.
So we're damned if we do,
and damned if we don't.
No, there's one way out of this.
I have to defuse the bomb. That is, if you get them to lower some bomb handling tools from above.
I repeat: All residents living near the Tohto Tower...
Please follow any instructions from the
police and evacuate without delay.
We're running away?
Conan-kun and Detective Takagi are still in there!
Don't worry, they're okay. Both of them
will be heading back here soon.
So, Chiba-kun, drive the kids to a safe place.
Got it.
You're going to have those two
defuse the bomb, aren't you?
That's why the Bomb Squad is outside waiting for orders.
It's fine.
We've learnt that the bomb is just like the one planted in Beika Central Hospital three years ago.
So I'm sure those two can dismantle it!
Yes, I'm sure they can.
As long as they don't let the devil whisper in their ears, like three years ago...
Lower it. Gently, now.
Gently, gently.
All right! All right!
Is everything okay?
Okay, I have it.
Roger.
Equipment delivery complete.
Good. Let's get started, Takagi-kun.
O-Okay.
You fool!
Man up and stop panicking! The kid with you is the one who's doing the actual work!
If you get flustered, you might make him anxious, which could cause careless mistakes!
Yes, sir.
If you take it easy and just follow our instructions, this'll be over in no time.
Stay calm.
Understood.
Good. First, let's try taking out
the photosensitive trigger.
Yes, sir.
Exactly one minute from now, we'll shut off the lights in the lift, so put on the infrared scope.
When it gets dark, take off the cover
to the right of the mercury tilt switch.
Be careful not to touch the switch.
S-So first we take off that cover, right?
That's right. We're turning off the lights now.
Did you hear all that, Conan-kun?
C-Conan-kun?
Here we go, the photosensitive
tube. If I cut its cord...
That's one down.
Conan-kun? Can you hear me?
Yup, go ahead and keep talking.
Uh, okay. Let's see. Once you take off the cover
there are probably a lot of weird looking devices.
Near the top there should be a weird looking thing
that senses light called a photosensitive trigger.
First of all, cut the cords coming
from that photosensitive trigger.
If I short circuit this one...
Oops, the electricity's on! That was close!
Well, then, I'll just put a plastic stopper in this gap...
Stopper?
The riddle said, "Don't bother trying to get a good stopper ready".
A good stopper means the pitcher has a good earned-run average.
But why a Major Leaguer? This is Japan—he could just have written pro baseball player.
Wait! Extra innings. Earned-run average.
Turn the game around. Major Leaguer.
D-Don't tell me that the other bomb's...!
We still have time, but unless I figure out where it is...
Tell me when you finish with that
Conan-kun, 'cause next is...
Say, Detective Takagi.
Huh? What is it, Conan-kun?
There's something I need to talk to you about.
Hey... What is this? This time it's a TV helicopter!
Did something happen after all?
Hey!
Crap!
No talking during the test!
It's now 11:40! Only 20 minutes left to the announced explosion time!
The police officer and the little boy who were trapped in the lift have yet to be rescued!
Minute by minute, they're running out of time.
Will the little boy and the detective be destroyed along with the symbol of Tōkyō?
What do you mean, you can't cut the wires? There's only three left!
First the yellow cord from the LCD display.
Next, the white cord from the mercury tilt switch.
And finally the black cord to the remote detonator and mobile phone.
After that, the bomb will be completely defused!
You've come this far, why can't you follow these simple instructions?
Let me have that.
Takagi-kun! What are you doing?
Hurry up and cut them!
It's no good. We can't.
What are you saying?
You've only got ten minutes!
"Brave police officer..."
"I commend you for your courage and present you with a reward."
"The clue to the whereabouts of the large firework that will end this game"
"will be displayed three seconds before the explosion.'
"Good luck."
Conan-kun said those words just came up on the LCD panel.
I wish I could at least get Conan-kun out of here.
But to prevent the greater tragedy...
Conan-kun will look at the hint and I will tell you
the location of the other bomb by mobile phone.
There's no other way.
Sorry about this.
Takagi-kun...
But... I know that you'll understand.
You jerk...
Four more minutes until the explosion!
The timer's still running.
If the terrorist is watching this and you still have a heart, please stop the bomb!
A heart, huh?
I can't believe it! I never
thought it'd go so smoothly!
Let's hear what the TV replay on the
radio is saying about our heroic tale.
The bomb is still active! Somebody stop it!
It sounds like the remote didn't work!
Forget about it—we got the dough!
I gotta call the cops and tell 'em...
Hey...
How to defuse it!
Hey, wait!
Those scumbag cops!
They took advantage of his soft heart, and then...
I feel sorry for the kid.
But if the bomb goes off, it's the cops' fault for putting him in harm's way.
And if they chicken out and stop the bomb,
they won't get the clue they need to save hundreds of lives.
Once I release the details to the mass media,
the whole world will know about the police force's incompetence!
Whatever happens next, the cops are done for!
Oh! That's what the riddle means!
Keep it down or the bomber will hear us!
But there's over 400 of them in Tōkyō!
Yeah. You can't search them all without the bomber noticing.
And if we tried to evacuate all 400 places at once...
The bomber would probably detonate the bomb by remote control.
Therefore, the only way to save everybody is...
...to look at the clue, do a pinpoint search
at the right place, and locate the bomb.
Just like Detective Matsuda did.
Right?
Yeah.
Plus, she might be there.
The most important person in the world to me. I can't let her die.
Sorry about this, Detective Takagl.
Oh, it's okay.
Say, Conan-kun.
Tell me one more thing.
W-Who are you, really?
If you really want to know...
Then I'll tell you.
In the afterlife.
Only one minute to go, and the victims are still trapped in the lift!
Hey!
What does that mean? Conan-kun and
Detective Takagi are still in there!
Ah, no...
The riot police have been ordered to evacuate the area!
Take this car back to Tohto Tower!
I can't do that, it's dangerous!
Take us back! Hey, Chiba, take us back!
So you listened to the devil's whisper. Just like three years ago.
The Detective Boys can take care of things fine without me, right?
C-Conan-kun!
15 seconds left.
You ready, Detective Takagi?
Yes.
I've punched in your entire deduction.
All I have to do now is type in the clues you read out and send the text.
Here we go. The message starts with...
The letters...
E...
V...
I...
T...
No!
Get out... Get out of there!
Get out of there, Ran!
Shin'ichi?
Ran!
Takagi-kun!
C-Conan-kun, hurry with the next...
W-What are you doing?!
The vibration will make the bomb—
Huh?
I was too scared to die, so I cut the final wires and disabled the bomb.
Sorry.
But the clue—
All we got is "EVIT". Don't think that's enough to lead us to the next bomb.
Well, nothing we can do about that now. Let's call the rescue team and get out of here.
I knew they'd get scared.
The public will think the cops made the kid stop the bomb.
They'll believe the police sacrificed hundreds of lives to save their own hides!
Listen to these cheers! The bomb has been safely defused!
And amazingly, the work was done by the young boy trapped in the lift!
Let's get a comment from the boy.
Weren't you scared, little boy?
Live From
Tohto Tower
The Hero!
A Primary Schooler
You bet!
S-Shin'ichi?!
But the policemen told me which wires to cut, so it was easy!
Live From
Tohto Tower
The Hero!
A Primary Schooler
Takagi-kun.
U-Um, Satō-san?
Silly, don't blame yourself.
We still have two and a half hours to find the second bomb!
Umm, actually...
I'm so glad you're okay!
I knew you could do it, Conan-kun!
I'm proud to be your boss!
You made the right choice.
There's no point sacrificing your life for the sake of people you don't even know.
Yeah, you're right.
I bet the bomber thought the same thing.
Whew! Only one test left!
What's wrong, Ran? You look depressed.
The next test's "comprehension". You're good at that.
Yeah, I was just watching those weird trucks that keep coming and going.
They're probably bringing in
ping-pong tables to the gymnasium.
The big city ping-pong tournament's gonna be held at our school.
I hope they move out all those oil drums while they're at it. I hate those things!
What do you mean?
You didn't know?
There's five of them sitting there.
They're such a pain when we get out the tennis nets.
They won't find them.
Even if they do, it's too late now.
Only five seconds left.
Four...
Three...
Two...
One...
Zero.
Boom!
W-Why? Why didn't it explode?
Well, never mind. I'll just detonate it remotely.
Sorry, but that number is no longer in service.
The bomb squad entered the school quietly so you wouldn't hear them through your wiretap
and dismantled all five of the bombs hidden in those oil drums.
Hmm? Your face is asking me "But how
did you know where they were?"
From various sentences in the code and in the hint given by the bomb in Tohto Tower, it goes like this:
"I'm a fast-pitching, strong-slugging major leaguer.
Batter up—let's start the extra innings."
"Don't bother trying to get a good stopper ready,"
"'cause at the end I'm going
to turn the game around."
"Major Leaguer" means the
keywords are in English.
A good stopper refers to a player with a good earned-runs average.
Extra Innings [enchōsen]
So the first keyword is "Extra Innings".
And earned-runs average can be just called "ERA".
Take away the "useless stopper" letters
"ERA" from "Extra", and it becomes "XT".
And finally, there's the letters "EVIT" that showed up on the first bomb's LCD screen.
It was going to be the English word "detective" written backwards, right?
"Detective" is tantei in Japanese. If you write the kanji backwards, you get teitan.
Teitan has a primary school, middle school, high school and university,
but the only one that would have a lot of students during winter vacation would be...
...Teitan High, because of their mock exams.
Incidentally, you didn't place
any fake bombs in ballparks
because you didn't want the police searching schools with baseball fields.
And now, because you got cocky spying on Teitan High out here in the open, it's all over.
Watch out!
D-Damn it!
Satō-san!
Damn it.
O-Oh, no!
Satō-san!
W-Wait.
I-It wasn't me!
D-Doesn't it happen a lot?
I heard a kid's voice inside my head telling me to kill the police...
Actually, kill anybody!
T-That's right!
It wasn't me!
This is him...
This is the guy...
This is the guy!
Satō-san!
What do you think you're
doing? Get out of my way!
Don't do it, Satō-san!
Let me go! Let me go, damn it!
That guy... It's his fault! So let me go!
What do you think you're doing, Satō-san?
What are you always telling me?
Take pride in serving our country and its people!
Don't give in to fear or hatred, and always respect citizens' rights and perform duties justly!
Isn't that what you always said?
But... But...
You better hope Detective Matsuda wasn't watching you just now.
You jerk.
Jerk, jerk!
I want to forget him.
Just let me forget him!
You jerk.
I don't think you should forget him.
Not if he's important to you.
When people die, they can only live on through our memories.
Takagi-kun.
Hey! What was that gunshot I just heard?
Well, umm...
I fired a warning shot.
kizu
Was he wounded?
kisu
We weren't kissing!
But, you know, I'm surprised
that you were able to stop it.
You had less than three seconds left, didn't you?
I had the wire cutter in hand in case I figured out the clue midway.
I couldn't just let Detective Takagi die.
But I'm surprised you were able to figure out "EVIT" was "detective" spelt backwards.
Same here!
Are you kidding? That was
the first thing I thought!
Because in my heart I kept
hoping that it wouldn't be there.
Hey, Satō-kun! We're on our way to visit Shiratori-kun!
Yes, sir. Coming.
Bye-bye, Matsuda-kun.
But...
But, I promise I'll never forget you.
Wait, by Ujō-san, do you mean...
The former number one
refreshing actress, Ujō-san?!
Then...
We're gonna meet Ujō-san too!?
Whoa, it's really her!
Ruri-ppe!
Ruri-ppe...
On the next Conan: The Unseen Suspect (Part I)!
Next Conan's Hint: Door Glass!
How did you like this fast-paced,
heart-pounding two hour special?
Watch Conan every week this year too!