Filling in the distance between hate and love...
The deductions and suspense of two people!
Today, we're on the set of a drama.
The members of the cast are human too!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Good evening, everyone.
I am Detective Mouri Kogorou.
Today's stage, far away from human habitation...
Is this western-style house.
A mystery in which love and hatred entwine.
The point of the case is color.
It's unconsciously chosen every time a person shops...
Their own favorite color.
Also, even at the scene of a crime.
Well then, let us meet again at the end of the program.
This has been Mouri Kogorou.
All right, cut!
Wonderful!
Mouri-san, it was perfectly OK!
Dad, you were so cool!
Is that so?
Though that last wink might have been a little much...
THE UNSEEN SUSPECT
(PART ONE)
You really saved us on this one!
The big-name actor who always does the opening prologue for this program...
He caught a cold, so we got thrown for a loop.
No, no, please call me in to pinch-hit anytime!
If that's the case, I'm also willing to appear in this mystery drama as a special guest.
No, that's...
That's impossible, Detective-san.
Because, in the story this time...
There's the widow that serves as the head of the household, her bitchy daughter, the decrepit butler...
Kazami Yoshiki (28)
Role of the Detective
Then, aside from the daughter's murdered husband and my role as a detective, no one beyond those five appear.
Hold on!
What's this about "bitchy"?
She isn't bitchy!
Namihara Kasumi (26)
Role of the Daughter.
She's just established as a character who likes to be flashy, right?
She's bitchy because you're playing the role.
What'd you say!?
Also, Kazami-kun...
Nagumo Akira (60)
Role of the Butler
Regarding the "decrepit" part, could you stop that?
I only just turned 60, you know.
It's not the age.
It's your acting that I consider decrepit.
What now!?
Although I hear you may have been a famous actor ages ago...
Now, now...
Dad, calm down.
Nagumo Nobuharu (31)
Role of the Daughter's Husband
Let's not quarrel before filming!
Nagumo Nobuharu (31)
Role of the Daughter's Husband
Kazami-kun, you keep your cool too.
At any rate, Ujou-san's late, isn't she?
Wait, by Ujou-san, do you mean...
The former number one refreshing actress, Ujou Ruri-san!?
Yeah...
Then...
We're gonna meet Ujou-san too!?
Meet her?
She's the one who nominated you as our stand-in on the prologue!
I don't know about being the former number one refreshing whatever, but...
I don't want to be refreshed.
Not by that old spinster lady.
Oh, I would refuse it as well.
With a washed up...
Ujou Ruri (37)
Role of the Female Head of Household
Urine-smelling little boy like you.
Whoa, it's really her!
Amazing!
She's even prettier in person than on TV!
How do you do...
I'm Mouri Kogorou, it's nice to meet you!
Since it seems it was you who requested me for this...
Oh, it's not the first time, is it?
Have we met somewhere before?
Come on...
Even after seeing this beauty spot under my lips, you don't remember?
Kogorou-chan!
Beauty spot...
Do...
Doigaki Ruri?
Bingo!
Is that you, Ruri-ppe?
It's been such a long time!
Yep!
Since middle school, isn't it?
No way... They're acquaintances...
I had no idea it was you!
Not with this new surname!
And, back then, you wore those coke-bottle glasses!
Well?
Did I become a fine woman?
You certainly did!
But how come Ruri-ppe isn't married?
A beauty like you could have anyone you wanted!
Silly!
It's because I've always been head-over-heels for you, of course!
Uhm, please stop joking—he'll take you seriously!
Oh, that child is...
Ah, no, just some kid from the neighborhood, you know...
I'm his daughter, Ran!
Then, you're Eri-chan's-?
You know my mother?
Yeah.
Because we were together from kindergarten all the way to middle school!
But it's still a mystery, isn't it?
Why the school's most talented girl, Eri-chan...
And the school's naughtiest boy, Kogorou-chan, were so much in love...
That they even got married.
That's for sure...
They were in love for that long?
That's right!
Because Eri-chan, who was always cool toward others...
Would get really upset when the opponent was Kogorou-chan and rush at him!
That's why everyone around would make fun of them and say, "The lovers' quarrel has started again!"
They're still going at it even now.
But it's surprising!
That the vulgar Kogorou-chan is now a renowned detective!
Here we go! Scene 134, camera rehearsal!
Ready!
Start!
The body in front of the fireplace is covered by a gray tablecloth.
And hanging on the chair from this table...
Is the victim's black coat.
Also, found next to the body after rolling there, is...
The weapon that was used to bludgeon the victim to death:
A golf club with a white cover attached.
Naturally, I've already solved the mystery.
What kind of airs are you putting on?
Please tell us already!
Just who is the culprit?
If we were really doing it, I'd reveal the trick at this point, but...
Hey, those lines aren't in the script...
Tonight, Detective Mouri...
Might I have you solve it?
First, why did the culprit cover the body with a tablecloth?
That's probably...
Probably...
Because the culprit loved the victim...
So they thought that just leaving the body like that would be hard to endure...
But there's a coat hung on the chair.
Why did they go to the trouble of using the tablecloth?
Ah, the reason for that was...
Because the gray tablecloth seemed warmer than the black coat!
Hey, hey, you're not saying that's your answer, are you?
Didn't you just say the hint in the prologue?
In any case, why would gray seem warmer than black?
You don't think so?
Even your friends didn't amount to much...
Dad, do it seriously!
Come on, spit out the truth, Kogorou-chan!
Impossible, impossible!
After all, this man...
For this degree of...
Man...
It appeared!
Sleeping Kogorou!
Ah, excuse me.
It was so simple a deduction that, against my better judgment, I acted as if it were difficult...
What?
The point is, it wasn't that the culprit wanted to cover the body with the tablecloth...
But rather that the culprit didn't want to cover the body with the black coat...
Since black is their favorite color.
Most likely...
The culprit subconsciously believed that utilizing items of their favorite color...
Would unintentionally draw suspicion towards them.
Please, take a close look at the golf bag propped against the fireplace.
Only the head of the club with the black cover has been caught and is sticking out, right?
This is evidence that the culprit was going to use the club with the black cover as the weapon, but...
In the middle of pulling it out, stopped and switched to white.
Furthermore, if you recognize the fact that this room's furniture and curtains are uniformly black...
With this being due to the tastes of the head of the household...
The culprit is the one that's even wearing a black dress...
Ruri-ppe, the female head of the household that you're playing.
Isn't that right?
Amazing!
As expected of Sleeping Kogorou!
You decisively hit the mark!
Just as the rumors say, right, Kogorou-chan?
Yeah...
Geez, it would've been better if you'd just taken it seriously from the start!
As expected, the real thing is different!
A corpse doesn't move!
Hey, what are you doing!?
Are you all right, Nobuharu-kun?
Kasumi, did you switch to this guy as the next one after that scriptwriter?
Oh, my bad—I guess that's still off the record.
Bastard!
If you don't shape up...
Old man, is it really smart...
To say something like that to me?
I know all about it...
Your secret meetings every night with your young lover!
Who that woman is or where she's from I don't know for certain yet, but...
I've already got a pretty good idea.
A pretty damn good idea.
Let go of me!
What's with those faces?
If that's how it is, I don't care if this program fails.
So annoying.
I'll be sleeping in the back room until the heat dies down, so just film scenes I don't appear in.
What's with that guy?
He's the son of the main sponsor for-this program, a newspaper company.
I see...
So that's why he knows all kinds of secret information.
Yeah.
Between the bad terms of the contract and that delinquent character becoming popular...
They're taking in quite a sum.
Actually, I didn't want to appear in a program with that guy as the star either, but...
An order came down from the agency telling me to appear due to the high ratings, so I reluctantly...
Well, I was able to see Kogorou-chan for the first time in a while, so I guess it's all right!
All right!
Let's take a break for 30 minutes and start again after we're all relaxed!
Yes, sir!
They had a big quarrel over Worcestershire sauce versus soy sauce?
Dad and Mom did?
Yep.
Back in elementary school, during the training for Home Economics...
They had a big battle over which to put on top of sunny-side-up fried eggs.
Eri-chan said that, because sunny-side-up fried eggs were western food, it should be Worcestershire sauce.
Kogoro-chan declared that, for the Japanese people, it should be soy sauce!
It gets less and less understandable...
Why they got married.
But then, when it came time to eat the food that was made...
They ate in exactly the same order, and the whole class had a big laugh.
After that, they both said, "Stop copying me," and began to quarrel over that.
Really, I can't say whether they were right for each other or not!
That's enough stories from long ago...
No, please keep telling more, more!
Hey...
What is it?
Snow.
Look, it's snow!
Now that you mention it, the weather report did say there was a chance of snow.
Hey, why don't we all go outside and see it?
But there's only five minutes of the break left...
It'll be all right, even if it's only five minutes!
It's the first snow of the season!
That's true...
Now then, let's hurry!
As expected, it's great, isn't it?
Snow, that is...
Right, Conan-kun?
What's wrong?
I don't see Ruri-san anywhere...
Hey, where's Ruri-san?
I thought we came out here together, but...
Ruri-ppe!
Damn it!
Kogorou-chan!
It's no good—his pupils are dilated...
He's already dead...
Ran! Contact the police!
But who was it?
Who did this horrible thing?
Who knows.
He was the type to make enemies, so...
But, in this situation...
Wouldn't it be the case that the first one to discover the body would be the first to be suspected?
That's not it—it wasn't me!
When I came in here, he was already covered in blood!
It's true!
Believe me, Kogorou-chan!
Yeah, I believe you.
Don't be fooled by her tears!
An actress' tears are one of the tools of her trade!
Hey, hey, Kasumi-chan!
But, if it keeps going like this, we'll end up being the ones suspected!
It's all right!
It's gonna be fine!
The victim is Kazami Yoshiki-san, 28 years old.
The cause of death is exsanguination as a result of damage to his left carotid artery.
He was probably attacked while sleeping on this sofa...
When his neck was sliced with a blade.
The approximate time of death was between 7:50 PM, when the victim came to this room to take a nap...
To when his body was discovered at 8:20 PM—an interval of 30 minutes.
I think it's shorter.
Because, that man...
When we came into this room while touring the house, he was snoring, sound asleep!
Hey, Conan-kun!
That was just around 8:00, wasn't it, Ran-neechan?
Yeah...
Because Dad looked at his watch and remarked that he had fallen sound asleep within ten minutes.
Ran-san and Conan-kun, isn't it!?
So that means, perhaps...
Ohhh, Mouri-san!
You're here, aren't you?
I heard you had to look after my little brother the other day!
No, it was nothing.
That kind of case...
Kogorou-chan, is he an acquaintance of yours?
Yeah.
How very nice to meet you!
I'm Yokomizo from the Shizuoka Prefectural Police!
It's great to finally be able to meet you, Mrs. Mouri!
Am I wrong?
No...
Well, you can say it's wrong, or you can also say it's not so wrong...
It's totally wrong!
It's a just a joke, a joke!
You, by some chance...
Aren't you the actress, Ujou Ruri-san!?
Yes!
Hey, now that I think about it, you're also...
And you!
What the heck's going on here?
That so many actors and actresses are gathered...
It's as if this is the filming of a drama!
That's because... That's exactly what this is.
Oh, so it was like this, huh?
At this western-style house in the recesses of Mount Fuji, you were filming a mystery drama when...
A real murder case occurred, right?
It's like the story where the mummy hunter himself became the mummy, isn't it?
Ah, yeah...
And? In the 20 minutes after 8:00 PM, the time that the murder was thought to have happened...
You had taken a break from filming and all the staff had been in groups of two or more, and thus have alibis.
Those without an alibi are...
The person who discovered the body, Ujou Ruri-san, and...
Those who claimed they were alone in their rooms checking lines in the script...
Namihara Kasumi-san!
Nagumo Akira-san!
And Nagumo Nobuharu-san...
It could only have been one of you four, huh?
Then, Ujou-san...
In detail, tell us the state of the room when you discovered the body!
All right.
During the break, along with Kogorou-chan—no, Mouri-san and his group, we were taking a look around the house.
Then, because snow started falling, we invited the staff to go outside to see it.
Because the snow was so pretty, I wanted to show it to Kazami-kun, and came to this room...
Kazami-kun had become angry and sullen over some things that happened during filming...
But, when I opened the door, he was bloody and collapsed on the floor...
I thought it was a joke, so I shook his body...
But there was no response.
When I finally realized he was dead, I screamed...
I see.
After hearing that scream, you three rushed here?
Yeah.
That's right.
Then, for the time being, can we have you four undergo body searches in separate rooms?
Why?
We can't find it.
Despite looking everywhere in this house...
We haven't found the approximately 10-centimeter long blade used to slit Kazami-kun's throat.
Inspector Yokomizo!
Did you find the weapon?
As for that, none of the four had anything like that...
Just in case, we also searched the staff's belongings and thoroughly searched the other rooms, but...
The only items in the kitchen that could have been the weapon were carving knives, a fruit knife, and...
A box-cutter from inside the staff toolbox.
There was no luminol reaction from any of them.
All the victim had on him was a pack of cigarettes, a lighter, and his wallet...
They're still searching the drainage outlets and the area around this house with a metal detector, but...
There's been no report that they've found anything.
Damn...
Even though we found what we think is the golf glove and the coat that the culprit used during the crime...
Why can't we find the weapon?
Moreover, since the glove and the coat were both props that were used for the drama...
No one was in the room where they had been left because of the break.
So you're saying that anyone could have taken them easily?
All right, where are the four suspects now?
They're in the room with Mouri-san, awaiting further orders.
If the criminal is one of these people...
Transporting the weapon somewhere far away is impossible in the short time frame of the crime.
Even though that's the ease, why is it?
Why can't the weapon be found?