With the rhythm of the wind, deductions become clear.
Figuring out the alibi trick!
Recognizing that one truth,
A child with the mind of an adult,
His name is Detective Conan!
-
Damn it...
Kogorou-chan, you smoke?
Yeah.
You don't, Ruri-ppe?
Oh, have you forgotten? About my father.
Ujou Ruri (37)
Actress
Now that you mention it, he was pretty famous in the neighborhood for his hatred of smoking.
That's right! As a result, his outlook toward smoking transferred to me.
Then, that makes you the same as me.
Nagumo Nobuharu (31)
Actor - Nagumo Akira's Son
Well, my mother was the one in my house who disliked smoking.
Nagumo Akira (60)
Actor
She even got my father, who had been a heavy smoker...
To quit smoking as soon as I was born.
But what do you do for scenes in dramas where you have to smoke?
In those cases, I just hold a cigarette in my lips.
Yep, yep—when we're forced to by the director or the producer, right?
That's why, no matter how much time goes by, you'll always be a second-rate actor.
Namihara Kasumi (26)
Actress
Kasumi-chan!
Well, for a certain someone who sells herself as being a refreshing actress...
It might be good for her healthy image.
Kasumi-chan!
What's with her?
She's jealous.
Of me, who can converse with him so easily.
Isn't it cute?
I see.
It's as the murdered Kazami-san said...
It seems that those two are lovers off-screen as well.
So that means...
That the lover that this person is secretly meeting with...
Hey, do know who the culprit is yet...
Mr. Great Detective?
No, not yet...
Excuse me, Mouri-san.
A moment?
Conan-kun, where are you going?
To the restroom!
Don't bother the police, all right?
All right!
What did you want to talk to me about?
What are your intentions?
Regarding your courtship of her - I'm asking what you're intending to do!
Oh, about Ruri-ppe?
I'm not courting her - we're just childhood friends...
Is it really just that?
It really is just that, right?
If that's the case, fine.
But if you do anything unsightly, I won't forgive you even if you are a great detective.
Hey, hold on.
This feeling...
It's like I've had this feeling before...
I think it was...
It was...
Hey, little boy, what are you doing?
This toolbox was left unattended in this room along with the golf gloves and the coat, right?
That's why I was thinking that, besides a box-cutter...
There might there be something else in here that could be used for cutting.
If you want to play detective, that's fine.
Just know the police already searched that toolbox top to bottom.
Even this tape measure?
Yeah.
Hey, who did this?
Spiking a place like this...
If I recall, spiking is...
It's using sticky tape to mark a place on the floor.
Like where to put set furniture and where the actors should stand.
Well, the filming will probably be canceled, but...
: Just in case, I guess I'll remove it.
Wait!
There's something strange about this sticky tape!
It's bulging a little, and something's stuck at the edge...
What is this?
Cotton?
I see, now I understand...
What the weapon was!
And the reason why it hasn't been found!
With the coat and the gloves having been left here in this room...
It was a simple task to commit the crime in this room 7 meters away.
What's left is who did it, but...
It really bothers me...
The behavior of Ruri-san...
Who saw snow from that window and suddenly compelled everyone to go outside to see it.
Damn! It's Uncle!
That brat, loitering around the scene of the crime again!
Brat!
Damn it...
Where'd he go?
I see! That's how it was!
Huh?
Where's Inspector Yokomizo?
He went outside a little while ago.
By the way, do you all smoke?
Oh, that's right!
I want to take another look at the evidence, so can I borrow some gloves from you?
Yeah, that's fine.
Let's see... This is the wallet, these are the cigarettes...
The coat, the gloves...
And this is...
The victim's lighter.
It's out of lighter fluid?
I've solved the case.
All that's left is to put Uncle to sleep with this tranquilizer...
Huh? Huh? Huh?
The tranquilizer dart isn't coming out!
That's right, I used it up during the camera rehearsal!
Oh no, what do I do now?
I can't produce "Sleeping Kogorou" like this.
It can't be helped.
Since it's like this, I'll have to give Uncle a lot of hints.
Hey, Uncle...
I noticed a lot of things, will you hear me out?
Perhaps it'll help you solve the case!
There's no need for that anymore.
But...
Solved the ease?
I've been looking for you, Mouri-san.
Where have you been?
Nowhere really.
I was just walking around this house looking for keys to solve this case.
And?
Have you solved it?
The mystery of the vanished weapon?
No, what I found weren't keys, but this brat.
I knew it.
Is that so?
Then well continue the search for the weapon, so if you there's anything you notice...
Yeah, I'll let you know right away!
Thanks for that!
If only I could use the tranquilizer...
His expression changed!
It's as I thought, Uncle...
He's figured out the culprit...
Ruri-ppe, I need to talk to you about something.
You're wrong! That person's not the culprit!
Damn, it can't be helped.
I'll have to hit Uncle on the head with something to make him lose consciousness...
Something to kick... Something to kick...
It's locked! Hey...
If it's locked, I can't go in!
Oh, what's the matter, Kogorou-chan?
Locking the door...
Could it be you want to seduce me?
Damn, I can't hear the conversation inside!
The most I can do is throw this transmitter through the gap under the door...
Or is it...
You think that I'm the culprit who murdered Kazami-kun...
And want to persuade me to turn myself in?
Yeah, that's right.
I definitely want to recommend confessing.
It's as I thought.
As usual, Uncle's in the wrong!
If I don't stop him soon...
I definitely want to recommend confessing.
It's as I thought.
As usual, Uncle's in the wrong!
If I don't stop him soon...
But the one I want to confess isn't you.
It's the one you're covering for...
Nagumo Akira-san.
What are you saying, Kogorou-chan?
Why would I have to protect Nagumo-san?
You saw it, didn't you?
Right before you noticed the falling snow outside the window...
What are you saying I saw?
At that time, the staff in the room next to the window opened the door and came out.
It should have been reflected in the glass embedded in that door.
The figure of Nagumo-san, who had just come out of the next room where Kazami-san had been taking a nap.
The figure of the murderer who was about to leave the room, but...
Upon noticing the staff, was surprised and shut himself back into the room!
Judging by that behavior, you suspected that he may have perpetrated some sort of act...
And by telling everyone to go outside to see the snow, you made sure no one went near that room.
I noticed that just a little while ago...
When Conan was by the door of the crime scene, and...
I found him before turning the corner of the hallway.
He was reflected in the glass of that door.
That boy was.
"As expected of the great detective," is what I'd like to say at this point, but...
The weapon hasn't been found yet, has it?
The blade that sliced through the napping Kazami-kun's neck.
Rather than the imaginary story that says I witnessed the murderer...
Shouldn't you first solve the mystery of the disappearing 10-centimeter long blade?
Everyone's been so fixated on searching for a 10-centimeter long blade.
Likely because no one considered that it could have been transformed into a 2-centimeter long lump of metal.
It's the box-cutter.
After murdering Kazami-san, the culprit broke the blade into small pieces, and hid the collected ones...
Inside the lighter that Kazami-san was carrying.
Amazing! You got it, Uncle!
But, Kogorou-chan...
Even if bloody box-cutter blades are found inside that lighter...
It doesn't necessarily mean that the weapon has been found.
The blade had to be 10 centimeters long in order to be able to cut so deeply into the neck, right?
If the blades aren't properly inserted into the box-cutter's grip, it wouldn't be possible.
And, as for that grip, shouldn't blood have spurted onto it?
If that's the case, they should have found a box-cutter grip that reacted to the luminol!
All right, come on Uncle! Counterattack!
That's right, isn't it?
Isn't it?
First you'd have to find the grip, right?
Damn it...
Hey, Conan-kun!
What are you doing here?
Ah, no...
That's right... Say, Ran-neechan...
Translator's Note: "Gamu teepu" means sticky tape. Conan is quoting the word "Gum," which in Japanese generally calls for the particle "te" after the quoted word or phrase.
"Gum"-te! Do you have any?
Gum... Te?
As far as anti-drowsiness gum, I think I brought it since Dad asked me to...
That's it!
(gamu teepu)
It's sticky tape!
If the box-cutter were wrapped with sticky tape from the grip to the end of the blade...
It would be possible to avoid having blood spurt onto the grip!
After the crime, he peeled off the blood-covered tape, and probably stuck it to the floor on the set.
Because, on that floor, there are sticky-tape markings everywhere which made it difficult to take note of!
But...
But why does that mean it had to be Nagumo-san?
With that kind of trick, I could have done it because I was the first to find the body!
Using the snow as a distraction, I could use the opportunity to kill him!
That's stupid! That you would kill anyone...
Damn it, how stubborn...
Sorry, Conan-kun, it looks like the gum is inside the rental car.
Say, Ran-neechan...
How do you put on a brassiere?
Because, I've never used one, so I don't know!
Look here! Boys don't need to know that kind of thing!
That's right, huh?
Ruri-ppe...
This crime is impossible for you.
Why?
Then tell me.
How would you hide the box-cutter blades in this lighter?
As for that, inside the cover...
There isn't anything under the cover.
Then, Kogorou-chan's deduction must be wrong, right?
Your saying that Nagumo-san is the culprit must be wrong too!
Ruri-ppe...
This type of lighter...
Is the kind where you add the lighter fluid onto the cotton that's inside.
That's why, without first removing the bottom, and then taking out the cotton that's inside to make space...
The blades of the box-cutter cannot be hidden.
As a smoker...
When I saw that the lighter wouldn't light, I realized that meant the cotton had been removed, but...
As for you, a person who hates smoking and has never used a lighter...
You'd never think that something could be hidden there.
If we consider that this person would not only think of that, but would also be someone you'd want to protect...
It could only be the ex-heavy smoker Nagumo Akira-san.
But I said it earlier, didn't I?
Why would I want to protect Nagumo-san?
I meet him every now and then for work, but...
We aren't that dose...
As for that...
He's your...
Lover, lover!
Real father, isn't he?
Seriously?
There wasn't a single item used during the crime that was prepared in advance.
Most likely, it was a haphazard crime that was thought up on the spot.
The cotton, heavy with the scent of the lighter fluid, was probably covered up by the sticky tape on the set, but...
It would probably be found as soon as someone looked.
After committing the crime, in a situation where anyone could have come in at any moment...
Taking the cotton out from the lighter and putting the box-cutter blades inside...
It would be impossible to do while still wearing gloves.
It's a certainty that fingerprints would have been left somewhere.
Now, before the evidence becomes known, have your father turn himself in...
That's right, Kogorou-chan.
Nagumo Akira is my real father.
I was conceived during the time that he and my mother were both members of a failing theater troupe.
Even though my mother was pregnant, she didn't realize it until after she had broken up with him...
And had started dating the man that you, Kogorou-chan, knew as my father.
It was something I never would have imagined in my wildest dreams...
Until I co-starred with him, and he said that I looked just like his own mother.
I asked my mother for the truth...
He had called asking to meet with me, so I went to complain to him.
I said, "It's too late for you to play the role of my father."
And he...
Right in front of me, he broke down and cried.
After that, I met with him every once in a while.
After all, a father is always a father.
His killing of Kazami-kun was for my sake.
If it was known that he was my real father, it would be a big mess for my family...
That's why...
That's why, Kogorou-chan...
As a big favor to a childhood friend, can you keep his crime to yourself?
Please.
Absolutely not.
I can't accept that sort of deal, especially since it's you.
Because I wouldn't want my childhood friend...
To be bound by such a heartbreaking, sorrowful lie for the rest of your life.
I thought so, Kogorou-chan.
That part of you hasn't changed.
Shut up...
Well, it can't be helped.
Since he called you over himself and told you the truth about our relationship.
No, at that time, he didn't say anything about that.
Then, how did you know we were father and daughter?
I realized it from Nagumo-san's manner.
It wasn't that of a man facing down a rival who was courting his lover, but instead...
The same feeling I had picked up on when I went to meet Eri's father.
It was a father's worry for his daughter.
Ah, as expected, it's Eri-chan.
I'm no match for her, am I?
No, it wasn't Eri, it was her stubborn father that I was reminded of...
Hey, did you know?
During middle school, the reason why I studied extra hard to the point where I had to wear glasses...
It was because I wanted to catch a certain someone's attention.
I was certain that you liked smart girls.
Thirty minutes later...
As a result of her persuasion...
Nagumo-san turned himself in...
And this real-life mystery drama came to an end.
Really? You met Ruri-chan?
She was surely even more beautiful than she seems on television.
Mom, you knew?
That she was the actress Ujou Ruri?
Of course I knew!
Because, unlike that person, I went to the class reunion.
That's right, I heard all kinds of things from Ujou-san!
Like how Mom and Dad had a big quarrel over soy sauce and Worcestershire sauce!
That was because he always puts Worcestershire sauce on sunny-side-up fried eggs when he's alone, but...
When he's with me, he gets embarrassed and forces himself to use soy sauce - it really bugged me!
Is that so...
Now that you mention it, Dad does always put Worcestershire sauce on his sunny-side-up fried eggs...
He's just that dense of a person.
Then why did you marry him?
That kind of thing from so long ago, I completely forgot.
Anyway, these gloves - which do you think are better?
Let's see...
If it were me, I think I'd go with the black ones.
I think these gray ones seem better.
Really?
Because gray is written "mouse color"!
A color with an animal's name in it, doesn't it seem like it'd be warmer?
Because the gray tablecloth seemed warmer than the black coat!
Oh? Did I say something strange?
Nope, nothing!
Come on, what is it?
You strange child...
What a strange old man...