Kaze no LaLaLa
"The Wind Sings LaLaLa"
Song by   Mai Kuraki
The rhythm of the wind brightens deductions.
We can even see the bonds of black come undone!
Somehow, this reeks of the men in black.
This time, we'll figure out the motive of the case!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Detective Conan!
Excuse me! Detective Mouri!
About this murder case...
When Mr. Nagumo was arrested,
he said he killed Kazami-san because he couldn't take seeing him attack his son, is that right?
His motive is none of my business.
All I did was reveal the trick he used,
and advise him to turn himself in while he had the chance.
That's all.
Ah, Mouri-san!
Tell us more!
Turning my back to the press...
I look so cool!
Oh, geez.
Now that he's actually solved a case himself, there's no tearing him away from the TV.
Well, I did make the old guy into a great detective
to get the attention of the men in black and learn more about them,
but so far, the plan's been a bust.
Let's watch that tape one more time!
They collect large sums of cash by repeating assassinations,
they force people like Haibara to make strange drugs,
and go around gathering competent computer programmers.
But... But why?
Hi, this is the Mouri Detective Agency...
I doubt they're planning to spend all that money to release a cool new video game...
What? A video game?
A software engineer is missing?
Yes... yes... and you want us to find him...
Hey! Tell 'em I'm out!
I've gotta retape today's rerun of Yoko-chan's TV drama so I can cut out the commercials!
Sure, come down to the office right away!
My dad seems to be free!
Hey, straighten your tie and shave!
Okay, okay!
A video game programmer is missing?
Don't tell me...
So this is Itakura-san, the programmer who went missing a week ago.
You said this isn't the first time you've lost him.
That's right.
He often disappears when we're close to a big deadline.
Well, we thought the same this time too,
but we can't sit around waiting for him to resurface any longer.
The last time this happened we called the police, and he threw a fit over it.
We thought you could be more discreet.
They don't seem to have anything to do with the guys I'm looking for...
If you manage to track him down, please call me...
Hey, you gotta be kidding! My place is dishing out the most cash!
Hey! Our company is the one who ordered a program from him first!
Er, you don't all work for the same company?
My company asked Itakura to create a virtual Go game. My name's Sugai.
Katsumichi Sugai (39)
Go Game Development Company Executive
Johei Naito (47)
Chess Game Development Company Executive
I'm Naito. He's developing a chess game for us.
Ryusuke Soma (44)
Shogi Game Development Company Executive
We hired him to create a Shogi game. The name's Soma.
Three computerized board games at once?
Can one programmer do all that?
That's why we want to find him!
To confront him about lying to us!
When we each hired him, he told us this:
"I haven't signed any contracts with anyone right now, so leave it to me."
How'd you find out he was trying to do three jobs at once?
A week ago, we all got this e-mail from him.
It hasn't been easy doing three jobs at once.
But lately my heart's been pretty strong.
I think I'll work away from my office for a while.
Keep your hats on, okay?
Hey, I know him!
I didn't recognize him in the photo because he was wearing glasses.
Isn't that Suguru Itakura-san, the famous CGI designer?
Yeah.
He wears contacts in public.
You know him?
His name's in the credits of all the big movies!
Three years ago his eyesight started to deteriorate.
So he changed his focus to computer programming and video game graphics.
If he's a big shot, maybe he's been kidnapped?
Get real!
No, it's possible.
A couple of years ago, I saw a suspicious character hanging around Itakura's office.
He was a big man with a mustache and a Kansai accent.
You guys must've seen him too.
He was at the big Mantendo ceremony a while back.
T-Tequila!
Hey, why was the big man there?
What were they talking about at the office?
Beats me.
When I was there, all I heard him say was, "I've got no use for you anymore!"
Is that all? Isn't there more?!
Hey, Conan-kun, what's wrong?
Damn! I've got to find this Itakura-san and ask him myself!
I know the guy you're talking about, he died in an explosion. So he couldn't be involved in this.
Now how can I find this person with just a photo to go on?
It looks like it was taken in a hotel room.
We called some local hotels, but they were all very protective of their guests' privacy.
He probably checked in under a false name anyway...
Hey, Ran-neechan.
Can we have sashimi, tenshinhan and beef stew for dinner tonight?
Huh? That's Japanese, Chinese and western-style food!
Not even a big family restaurant will have all that!
So, if I ordered all that stuff at once,
the waiters would think I was pretty weird, huh?
Weird?
Come to think of it, this guy's got a Shogi board, a Go board, and a chess board in his room...
Do you know if he took anything out of his office when he left?
One of his employees told me he took his laptop and a few computer disks.
And he didn't take anything else?
Right.
What is wrong with this hotel?
I'm sorry, who is this?
I'm the guest who borrowed a set of Shogi, chess and Go boards!
The phone in my room isn't working!
I'm calling from my cell phone, and I expect you to fix this problem immediately!
We don't loan out any board games to guests at this hotel...
Oops, sorry, wrong number!
Okay, next up is Hotel New Beika...
No one else would order a bunch of board games from the front desk
and hang onto them for a week.
A strange guest like that would be the talk of the hotel staff!
I'm calling from my cell phone, and I expect you to fix this problem—
Ah, yes. Itakura-sama in room 2004, right?
R-Right, room 2004.
I'll send someone up to your room right away.
H-Huh? It looks like the phone was just unplugged.
Never mind!
Hotel New Beika, room 2004!
Geez! Why are you two coming along?
You'll just get in the way!
But Conan-kun wanted to come...
No fair, Uncle!
After you get paid for solving the case,
you're gonna have a fancy meal at the hotel restaurant, right?
Don't worry about it, sir!
Once we find Itakura-san, we'll treat you all to dinner!
S-Sure.
So this is his hideout, huh?
One thing's been bugging me. Aren't you all business rivals?
Why'd you come to me as a group?
We found out from that e-mail that he took jobs from all three of us at once.
The three of us project leaders decided to talk to him together.
That's when I came up with the idea of hiring you, Mouri-san.
Hey, it was me! I said we should hire a detective!
But I'm the one who suggested Mouri-san!
Step off, both of you! I'm the one who called his office!
Like I said, I was the one who came up with the idea!
Oh, geez.
Aw, Yoko-chan's TV drama's already over...
My, wearing a cheap watch like that's sure to get some snide remarks.
Itakura-san's not going to like that cheap watch of yours!
That's why...see?
The rest of us too.
No way is that real!
To hell with you! It's brand-new, I just bought it five days ago!
I think yours is a knockoff!
Naito-san, would you press the button for the 20th floor?
Sure.
Er...
Itakura-san's going to be so surprised when he sees everyone.
Y-Yeah.
But is it okay to head for the hotel room just like that?
Itakura-san is someone who is involved somehow with Tequila, a member of the Organization...
I wonder if it's safe for Ran, the old guy, and these people to go to his room...
Those last words that Tequila said to Itakura-san...
"I've got no use for you anymore!"
Does that mean the Organization's trying to kill him?
What if those guys are hiding nearby
in order to get rid of Itakura-san?
Or maybe they're already in his room?
Nah, you're just getting paranoid. Get a hold of yourself...
Tequila said that two years ago!
If the men in black had wanted to kill Itakura-san, he'd be long dead by now!
And if Itakura-san were one of the men in black,
he wouldn't have let Soma-san into his office
while he was talking with Tequila.
Anyway, I'll just have to meet Itakura-san
and try to get him to talk about that meeting with Tequila.
I've got to find out why Tequila came to his office...
That's odd. He's got a "do not disturb" sign hanging on the door, and yet...
He must've gone out for a bite to eat.
We can wait here.
I'm so sorry about this!
The door locks automatically, so please remember to carry your room key!
Right.
Excuse me, mister!
Can you open my uncle's room too?
I guess he forgot we were coming to see him, and went somewhere...
Uh, but...
Hurry! I gotta go potty!
Okay, okay.
I gotta go, I gotta go!
Er... Thanks a lot.
Smart work, little boy!
If Itakura-san comes back and sees us out in the hall, he might try to run away.
That's okay, kid. Looks like we won't need to do that.
Looks like Itakura-san's napping at his desk.
Oh, geez...
Hey, wake up! Hey!
You can't escape us now, Itakura-san.
What?
Original Broadcast Date:
January 27, 2003
Based on manga:
Vol. 37 Files 5-8
Itakura-san! Itakura-san!
Save your breath. He's been dead for over a day.
You can't be serious!
I'll go call the police!
How could this have happened?
Looks like a heart attack.
There are pills scattered all over the desk.
He was struck by a sudden attack,
and reached for his medication, but he couldn't take it in time.
Geez. That's what he gets for cutting himself off from the world.
No, that's not it.
Itakura-san didn't die of an illness.
Somebody killed him!
But...why?
Why do I keep losing them just when I think I'm on their trail?
Damn it!
What's this?
A diary?
Itakura-san's diary...
If so, maybe there's something in it...
It could tell me why Tequila came to see Itakura-san,
and what the men in black are trying to do.
I'll find the answers to everything...
Hey!
Don't you dare touch the possessions of the deceased!
Geez, I can't take my eyes off you for a minute!
Damn! I can't do a thing about it after all...
If I want to read that diary, I'll have to make him understand
that Itakura-san didn't die of natural causes.
That heart attack was faked.
And there's a good chance it was one of those three people!
The deceased is Suguru Itakura-san, age 45,
a video game programmer.
And the cause of death?
We'll have to do a detailed analysis to know for sure, but I don't see any external injuries.
Judging from the fact that he took coronary dilators,
I'm guessing he was overcome by a sudden heart attack.
I estimate he's been dead for at least two days.
Inspector! I've contacted Itakura-san's doctor!
And?
Itakura had a very weak heart. He had to take medication three times a day.
He was scheduled for a coronary operation once he'd finished his projects.
That would mean...
Guess we won't need you this time.
Guess not.
But if he's been dead for two days, why didn't the hotel staff notice?
He hated having people in his workspace.
Oh, absolutely.
Once he flipped out at me because he thought the papers on his desk had moved 10 cm.
And he rarely changes his sheets at home either,
so he probably refused to have his bed made for him...
Who are those three guys?
Executives from game companies Itakura-san worked for.
They hired me to look for Itakura-san because he'd been missing for a week.
And you found him, but he was already dead?
Yeah.
Well, he locked himself away in a dirty, unhealthy environment
even though he knew he had a bad heart.
He brought it on himself.
Are you sure?
I think he liked to keep things really clean.
When we came into the room, he was face down at the desk,
but the desktop was dry! No drool marks!
Drool?
Look at all the drool on his face!
If someone drools as much as he did,
it would usually dirty the desk too, wouldn't it?
He must've wiped the desk clean!
Dumb kid! Why would a guy in the throes of a heart attack stop to clean off his desk?!
Then who cleaned it?
I-I don't know...
Besides, you didn't tell me you found him face down at the desk.
Oh, he fell when I shook him!
If that's true, there's something funny here!
The corpse's hands!
His hands are locked tightly against his chest due to rigor mortis.
They should have been pressed against the desk.
But I don't see any pressure marks on his hands.
Then maybe Itakura-san died somewhere else.
But, Inspector, his hands and legs are completely rigid in this position!
If so, unless someone tied Itakura-san to the chair, he couldn't...
I see...
Itakura-san was tied to the chair with his hands against his chest.
That's why he couldn't reach his medicine in time.
Then, you think this is...?
Yeah.
Something we know all too well...
Murder.
N-No way...
But if that's true, there ought to be rope marks on the body.
Well, coroner?
There aren't any clear markings,
but there are faint blood stasis marks around his shoulders and knees,
as if his body had been constricted there.
What does that mean?
Ooh, this blanket is so soft and warm!
Conan-kun, stop that!
But what's this? It's kinda sticky in places.
I-I've got it! The blanket!
Blanket?
The murder wrapped Itakura-san's body in the blanket, sat him in the chair,
then held him in place with duct tape or something similar!
A pillow or something was placed between his chest and knees
so his body would take the shape of the desk!
I see! That wouldn't leave any rope marks on the body.
To make it work, the chair would have had to have been fixed to the desk.
It seems to have been wiped off, but I can see traces of duct tape adhesive on the desk.
So the killer left Itakura-san there as he was until he died of a heart attack.
Then after rigor mortis had set in,
the killer returned, removed the duct tape and blanket,
and turned his body against the desk to make the death look natural!
All right, question the hotel staff!
Ask them if any suspicious-looking people have visited in the last two or three days!
Yes, sir!
The hotel...
Oh, nothing.
I found this room by calling the hotel and pretending to be Itakura-san.
I told them I was the one who'd borrowed Shogi, chess and Go sets from the front desk,
and the phone in my room wasn't working.
That's how I got the number of this room.
After that, the clerk on the other end started laughing, and said, "Again?"
What? You mean to say that someone else used the same trick to to find this place?
But it would take a brilliant deductive mind to rival my own!
Inspector, I've got it!
A few days ago, someone claiming to be Itakura-san
called the hotel desk and said the phone in his room wasn't working!
Never mind.
When a clerk went to Itakura-san's room, he shooed her away, saying, "It wasn't me!"
I think it's safe to say that was the murderer.
So how did you know Itakura-san had borrowed Shogi, chess and Go boards from the hotel?
His mail.
We saw a video e-mail that Itakura-san sent those three.
And in it, Itakura-san had a Shogi board, a chess board and a Go board in front of him.
I see. That means...
Any one of you could've used the same method as Mouri-kun to find him!
That's not true!
No way!
Ashita wo Yumemite
"Dreaming of Tomorrow"
When I hear your voice come from over the phone
Even though I'm strong, I feel like I want to cry
We hurt each other, but I still want to see you again
We always parted without being able to face each other
You're wondering how to reply, aren't you?
Whenever I remember that expression you could never hide
Dreaming of tomorrow... I want to believe you, though it's hard to do
Dreaming of tomorrow... I want to see you
I can still faintly see the sun through the leaves...
It looks like Itakura-san's been keeping a diary every day for the past five years.
That means it's there! It's there!
From when Tequila came to visit two years ago!
You don't mean—
That's right.
Itakura-san left it over there.
A dying message, pointing to the killer.
Next Conan: The Silent Testimony Left Behind (Part 2)!
Please look forward to the next episode!
Next time, the solution!
Let's solve this one ourselves, Inspector!
Alright, don't let Mouri-kun fall asleep!