Kaze no LaLaLa
"The Wind Sings LaLaLa"
Song by Mai Kuraki
The rhythm of the wind brightens deductions.
We can even see the bonds of black come undone!
After the unnatural last moments of the victim, an amazing message!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Detective Conan!
Old man Mouri was asked to find a game programmer,
Suguru Itakura-san, by some clients.
But when I heard their story,
I learned that Mr. Itakura had previously been in contact with the Black Organization!
We somehow located the hotel where Mr. Itakura was hiding, and went there,
but it turned out that he was already dead!
I see...
Itakura-san was tied to the chair with his hands against his chest.
That's why he couldn't reach his medicine in time.
Then, you think this is...?
Yeah.
Something we know all too well...
Murder.
N-No way...
Hang on a minute! Why are we under suspicion?
Katsumichi Sugai (39)
Go Game Development Company Executive
Ryusuke Soma (44)
Shogi Game Development Company Executive
We're the ones who hired Kogoro Mouri to look for Itakura-san in the first place!
Johei Naito (47)
Chess Game Development Company Executive
What kind of murderer would come back to the scene of a crime
with a master sleuth?
Good point.
If you insist on suspecting us, do you have proof?
Proof that we were here?
Now's my chance!
Hey, why don't you look at the diary in the bag?
That's his, isn't it?
Maybe he wrote about the people who visited him!
It does say "diary"...
Takagi-kun, how do you look at this?
Just load it into the laptop on his desk.
But, Inspector,
if I were the killer, I would've gotten rid of evidence like that.
Here it is.
It looks like Itakura-san has been keeping a daily journal for the past five years.
Which means... It's there, it's gotta be there!
An account of the day Tequila visited him two years ago is on that disk!
Got it! Here's the most recent entry!
Three days ago...
"The hotel staff said something weird to me today.
"One of those three guys may have figured out where I'm staying.
"Oh well, guess I'll have to change hotels."
Looks like he was on to you three.
Is there anything afterward in this diary?
No.
Then, I'll put it back where it was.
Um, okay...
All right!
No...
Let's send this down to the crime lab and have it checked out.
Good idea.
Uh-oh...
If they take it down to the police station, I'll never get a look at it!
I've got to find which of the three is the killer right now
and convince the cops they don't need that disk!
Okay, think... I must've overlooked something...
Some vital clue to the killer...
Look at this, Inspector!
What is it?
The victim's right ankle!
There's a blood stasis mark on his left ankle, where his sock was.
But look, his right leg has no sock mark on it.
On the other hand, on his right ankle,
there are traces of what appear to be scratch marks made by one of his left toenails...
Which means that Itakura-san tried to take the sock off his right foot...
But why was he tied up in such a place?
And why did he... take his sock off?
I see. Itakura-san wanted to leave this.
I've got it! I know who killed him!
And if I act fast, I can get that diary too!
Okay, coroner.
Go ahead with the judicial autopsy.
Yes, sir.
Takagi-kun, take the victim's diary down to the crime lab.
Yes, sir!
Now to figure out which one of you ordered Itakura-san to make the game software,
and who found his body...
You three guys from the same company who hired him...
You've got it wrong! We're not from the same company!
I'm Sugai! My company hired him to design a Go game!
I'm Naito! My company hired him for a chess game!
And I'm Soma! He was making a Shogi game for my company!
Please let us go already. We just happened to be brought here
to this room by Mouri-san who located where Itakura-san was...
Er... Inspector, what about me?
Well...
It looks like Itakura-san was murdered,
but we don't have enough evidence to hold any of you.
I'll have to ask all of you to visit the station later. You too, Mouri-kun.
Great!
I've got to check up on the TV show I'm taping.
I'll head home right now and—
On second thought, I think I'll hang around.
Oh, no, I mean, well... who was that?
After all, I don't want to let the killer escape.
Right now he's dancing with glee right in front of us,
because you're such a clumsy detective!
W-What?!
Hey, Dad! Be polite!
Pull yourself together, Uncle!
Fair enough, Mouri-kun, but I assume you know...
just who killed Itakura-san?!
Of course. The late Itakura-san told me himself.
Come on... You're not going to tell me you heard a dead man speak, are you?
No.
I saw his ankle.
You saw it too, didn't you, Inspector?
Itakura-san's right foot is missing the mark from his sock.
When the murderer came back to the room after Itakura-san had died,
he noticed that one of his socks had come off, and put it back on the corpse's foot
so it wouldn't look unnatural.
So why did Itakura-san take his sock off?
No idea. Why?
It's because unless he was barefoot,
he couldn't grab a certain something.
Grab... Grab what?
You don't mean...
Right.
Itakura-san used the time he had until his heart medicine stopped working
to write out with his right foot...
A dying message, pointing to the killer!
Original Broadcast Date:
February 3, 2003
Based on manga:
Vol. 37 Files 5-8
T-This is a dying message?
But what does it say?
To me it just looks like an unfinished game of Go.
I'll explain it with your help, Inspector.
Detective Takagi!
Please give the Inspector the disk with the diary and an unopened floppy disk from Itakura's bag.
Okay...
Once you get the disks, Inspector, sit down in front of the laptop.
B-But what does this have to do with the dying message?
I'll explain later.
Just boot the computer.
B-B-Boot?
B-Boot...
B-Boot?!
I-Inspector, to "boot" a computer means to turn it on!
Of course! I was just kidding!
Next, open the disk, drag it onto the desktop,
and copy the data onto the blank disk.
Open... drag... copy...
Look, he just wants you to make a copy of the diary!
Like this!
Hey, Mouri-kun,
don't tell me you're just doing this to poke fun at my limited tech skills?
Now please turn the computer off.
Even I can do that.
W-What's the matter?
Oh, that's...
Don't help him, Detective Takagi.
Hmph!
Even the fanciest appliance...
can be turned off like this!
You can't do that! If you unplug the computer while it's still on,
you can lose data or cause permanent damage to it!
But it wouldn't turn off when I pressed the button...
It's designed that way for safety reasons.
You have to hold the power button down.
Right...
Anyone who knows computers knows it's taboo to unplug it.
And only a person who knows computers can understand terms like "boot" or "drag".
Now do you know what the Go stones say?
Do you?
No...
Isn't there something strange about these Go stones?
What do you mean, strange?
In Go, you always discard a surrounded stone,
and it's taboo to place a new stone in an opened area.
T-Taboo?
Then the stones must mean something!
But what?
Good. While everybody's eyes are on the Go board,
I'll take the disk with the copy of the diary...
What're you doing, Conan-kun?
R-Ran-neechan...
Hey, are you hiding something from me?
N-No, nothing!
Then what are you doing?
I-I thought they sort of looked like the Go stones...
These stickers with the funny patterns stuck on the keyboard!
Patterns? Isn't that Braille?
Come to think of it, Itakura-san had bad eyesight like me.
He told me he was starting to learn Braille.
Braille...
I see!
So this is what Mouri-san meant by "words only people in the know can understand"!
Maybe this is written in Braille!
Is it?
I-I don't think there are any shapes like these in Braille...
But if I skip the white stones it spells out Japanese Braille characters!
And?
Let's see...
ha
The killer is...
n
ni
wa (ha)
KILLER IS
so
Soma...
ma
SOMA
sho
The proof is...
ko
wa (ha)
PROOF IS
the watch...
to
ke
i
WATCH
S-Soma-san!
No way! You killed him?
Hey! What're you guys talking about?
The killer must've planted that to frame me!
No, you did it!
You're the only one who doesn't know Go or Braille!
You're the only possible culprit, and you're still carrying the evidence—
H-Hang on, Mouri-kun!
Care to slow things down and explain things for the rest of us?
We need evidence, you know!
Don't rush things... Calm down...
I already have the copy of the diary in my hands.
Calm down... Calm down...
Okay. When Itakura-san left this dying message,
he knew the murderer would have to come back
to arrange his body and remove the evidence of foul play.
So he created a secret code he knew Soma-san wouldn't be able to read.
He knew that once his body was found, all three of you would be under suspicion,
and the police would probably show you photos of the Go board.
When that happened, Naito-san, who has such bad eyesight
that he has to use the braille on elevator buttons, would be able to decipher the code,
or else, that Sugai-san, who had hired Itakura to create the Go game,
would realize the layout of the board was wrong,
and figure out there was a secret code for the police to decipher!
I-I see...
But what's this about a watch?
It's the watch Soma-san's wearing right now.
Itakura-san disappeared and confined himself in this room about a week ago.
He liked fancy watches, and he had very bad eyesight.
When you first came to visit him at this hotel,
I bet he grabbed your hand and touched...
that expensive watch you bought five days ago!
I see! If his fingerprints are on the watch, it'll be solid proof!
Right.
If this is really the first time you've seen Itakura-san since he disappeared,
his prints couldn't possibly be on the watch.
Very well, Soma-san,
you won't mind me sending this watch down to the lab, will you?
Sure, take a good look.
I'm sure his prints are all over this thing.
I let him fiddle with this watch while I drugged his wine,
and he still had it in his hands when I wrapped him in the blanket.
Twenty years ago, when he was a no-name programmer
and I was just getting started in the game industry,
we were Shogi buddies at the same training academy.
After practice, we'd talk Shogi over drinks.
Our big dream was to create a computer program
that could defeat even a Shogi grand master.
But three days ago, when I tracked him down
and visited him at this hotel, he asked me,
"How many times should the player be allowed to take back a move?"
What kind of joke is that?
I collected cash from the master play games and kept sending it to him for 20 years.
And all I had to go on were his words, "The time is ripe."
I went into a great amount of debt investing in him too.
And yet, he has the nerve to say,
"wait" to a real master of shogi software
that was supposed to have been completed...
So I told him I'd get us a bottle of wine to celebrate,
and stepped out to buy wine, duct tape and sleeping pills.
When you guys came to me about hiring Kogoro Mouri to find him,
I had to go along, so I wouldn't look suspicious.
After all, I'd been complaining about his disappearance more than anyone,
because instead of getting around to making the shogi software.
he became famous as a CG designer!
I guess we drifted apart in those twenty years.
Being apart changes people...
Their hearts, their dreams... Everything...
If we could have take-back moves in life,
I'd go back to 20 years ago...
Back to when we both had the same dreams...
Ashita wo Yumemite
"Dreaming of Tomorrow"
Take care, Ran...
Your sleepy father and I need to talk a little.
You guys can catch a cab home, or...
Don't worry! It's just a half-hour walk home.
Bye-bye, Inspector!
It's here.
It's right here.
In my pocket.
A clue to those men in black...
Later, on the Doc's PC,
I'll go through this disk from one end to the other.
Hey, Conan-kun...
Do you think people change?
When you're apart from them, do people's hearts change?
It's pretty hard...
Just waiting like this...
It's okay. Shin'ichi-niichan's probably just like you remember him.
That's why there's no need to worry...
Conan-kun, sometimes I wish you were Shin'ichi...
Silly me. What am I saying?
Ran...
No...
I...
I'm really...
No.
I can't tell her.
Until I figure out who they are...
Until I've taken them out...
I can't tell her who I am.
Y-You're...
This disk with Itakura-san's diary...
I'm going to check this thing from end to end!
Their method...
Their true identity!
Let's see, two years ago...
Bingo! Got it!
T-This is...!
That's not it, Doc.
Next Conan: Contact with the Black Organization (Negotiation)!
Please look forward to the next episode!
Next time the men in black finally show up!
This time, they're not getting away!