The rhythm of the wind clears reasoning,
Always confirming that vital clue.
The secret behind the mystery is here!
We just have to get to the professor!
Recognizing that single truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is Detective Conan!
It's here.
It's right here.
In my pocket.
A clue to those men in black...
Later, on the Doc's PC,
I'll go through this disc from one end to the other.
Hey, Conan-kun...
Eh?
Do you think people change?
When you're apart from them, do people's hearts change?
It's pretty hard...
Just waiting like this...
It's okay. Shin'ichi-niichan's probably just like you remember him.
That's why there's no need to worry...
Conan-kun, sometimes I wish you were Shin'ichi...
I must sound so dumb. What am I saying?
Ran...
No...
It's me.
It's really me...
No.
I can't tell her.
Until I figure out who they are...
Until I've taken them out...
I can't tell her who I am.
You're...
Contact with the Black Organization: Negotiation Part!
Crying again?
Again?
You're always crying.
Always?
Is that a problem?
No...
You just reminded me of someone.
A woman who looked a lot like you,
who pretended to be calm, but secretly cried all the time.
A stupid woman.
A stupid woman?
Hey, Ran-neechan...
Do you know that man?
Yeah.
I met him when I went to New York with Shin'ichi...
When I was waiting for Shin'ichi in front of that old run-down building,
that guy came up to me and said,
"Have you seen a Japanese man with long silvery hair and a beard?"
The building where the serial killer was hiding!
But I don't think he's a bad person...
Why?
He was with a guy who had "FBI" written on the back of his jacket.
So probably...
FBI?!
Impossible!
What's the FBI doing here in Japan?!
Oh no, he's gone.
Hey, let's go home, Conan-kun.
Sure.
But was he really FBI?
Somebody murdered that serial killer and made it look like a suicide.
If the FBI had that area closed off,
there's no way they'd have done that.
And...
In the case when James-san was kidnapped, Haibara was getting bad vibes from him...
What if he's the one who killed that serial killer?
Maybe he's involved in Haibara's past...
Shuuichi Akai...
Could he actually be...?
Hey, Conan-kun, what do you want for dinner tonight?
Sashimi? Tenshin rice?
Your favorite beef stew?
I can't cook all three.
Huh? Conan-kun?
I promised to play games with the professor.
I'll be staying over there tonight.
- Conan
"I promised to play games with the professor.
I'll be staying over there tonight."
Games again?
Jeez, such a child.
My priority right now is this disk, not Akai Shuuichi.
This is the diary of someone involved with the Organization...
Itakuro-san had actually met with Tequila.
I won't miss a single bit from this disk.
I'll discover their objectives and their identities!
Their true identities!
Oh, Shin'ichi, perfect timing. I've invented a new gadget for you.
Also, here's a pair of extra tracking glasses, so
you don't have to recharge them anymore.
By the way, where's Haibara?
Ai-kun's in the shower.
That's great news.
Hey, Shin'ichi, don't tell me...
You plan to go peep on her!?
Really...
What?! You got your hands on a clue to them?
Really, Shin'ichi?
Yeah.
If Haibara finds out, she'll get paranoid,
so let's go through this while she's not here.
Let's see, two years ago...
Two years... ago...
Bingo! Got it!
March 7...
A man speaking the Kansai dialect came to see me unannounced.
He seems to want the operating system I've been developing.
But when he found out my eyesight got worse and I'd abandoned it, he left.
He was dressed in black from head to toe.
I never saw him again.
Hey, don't tell me that's all!
There doesn't seem to be anything written about that big guy in the diary entries afterwards.
So all I learned was that Itakura-san was developing some operating system that those guys wanted.
But this Itakura guy doesn't seem to be an organized guy.
Look, the spacing between diary entries is all over the place.
I'd never leave things this disorganized.
Come to think of it, that guy...
He said that Itakura-san would get angry if the papers on his desk were moved by even 10 cm.
That's not it, Doc.
It's not that he's disorganized...
Look!
If you put the cursor in the space...
then drag it to invert it...
T-This is...!
"I'm wiped out."
"At this rate, I'm gonna be killed..."
Invisible writing.
It's a method frequently used to hide information on internet homepages.
But, why would Itakura-san do this in his own diary?
He probably camouflaged it in case somebody looked at his diary.
Huh?
Shin'ichi, by "somebody" you mean...
Right. It has to be them!
Doctor?
I finished my bath.
Looks like he started using the invisible writing 10 days after the big guy's visit.
And the next one says...
March 17th.
"The pen on my desk had moved by 5 cm."
"It looks like somebody went through my office."
April 15th.
"Someone has broken into my house this time."
"The police won't take me seriously..."
"There was no sign of a break-in or anything taken, so I guess it couldn't be helped."
June 11th.
"I changed my locks and installed hidden cameras, but it's no use."
July 6th. "Who are you?! Show yourself!"
December 19th.
"I'm tired, and at this rate, will be killed in the near future."
January 6th.
"To rid myself of the terror I'm feeling, I left a message to the intruder on the table."
"I'll do what you want."
January 8th. "They answered me sooner than I was expecting."
"Instead of the message I'd written, the intruder had left a memo."
"An 'OK' written in red, along with a suspicious-looking phone number."
"This red was probably blood... I wonder if they were trying to tell me that... I'll lose my life?
January 23rd.
"After thinking for a while, I decided to call the number without telling the police."
"Surprisingly, a woman answered the phone."
"A presumptuous woman who talked as if she was a queen."
"She said she wanted to buy the OS I'd been
developing for a large sum if I could finish it in a year."
"She's likely with the same group as the big man from before."
February 13th.
"They changed the contact method to e-mail."
"I accepted their request, under the
condition that they pay me in advance"
"and that they stop lurking around me."
December 22nd.
"I can't."
"Like I thought, I can't do it."
"I decided to stop developing this OS, not just because of my vision getting worse,"
"but for the sake of humanity."
For the sake of humanity?
February 9th.
"The delivery date's coming up."
"I've decided to hide the unfinished OS
and the check they made to me"
"near the computer at my
cottage and disappear abroad."
"The e-mail stating when and where the delivery should take place"
"should arrive at midnight in five days. I have to get overseas by then."
This entry was written four days ago. It's
9 PM, so the e-mail should arrive in three hours.
It seems that Itakura-san planned to escape abroad before seeing that e-mail.
It looks like there's invisible writing even after the last day.
February 10th.
"Just what did they want to do with this OS?"
"I still remember the chilling words that the woman said during that first phone call."
"Right."
"I couldn't stand her presumptuous tone, so I flat out asked her"
"Just who do you think you are?"
"And she laughed at me and answered in English..."
"We can be both of God and the Devil,"
"since we're trying to raise the dead against the stream of time."
W-What does that mean?
"We are both God and the Devil."
"Since..."
"We're trying to raise the dead against the stream of time."
H-Haibara!
Ai-kun!
What's that?
Are you reading a fantasy novel about witches or something?
Yeah. T-That's it.
I got addicted to some of these western novels being serialized on the Internet.
And what are you doing here, Kudo-kun?
Ah, me? I'm—
H-He came to try out my new invention, right?
Y-Yeah!
I call it the "Anywhere Ball-Shooting Belt".
At first glance, it looks like a normal belt.
No, it doesn't.
But if you adjust the dial and press the button...
...a football pops out!
A-Awesome!
I'd be able to catch loads of criminals with this!
Well, more like a couple...
Due to the nature of the rubber,
it will only hold its shape
for 10 seconds after it leaves the belt...
Right.
It's very elastic though,
depending on the amount of gas that's put in,
it can become as large as an ad balloon!
Oh, that's unbelievable!
This is ridiculous.
I'm going to bed.
Now what do we do?
Isn't it obvious?
Now we go to Itakura-san's cottage, we get that operating system,
and we'll use the computer there to receive it.
The e-mail that they'll send at midnight.
How did you know Itakura-san's cottage was in Gunma?
Uncle asked the person from the game company who hired him to look for Itakura-san
about his house, his cottage, and the acquaintances where he might be hiding out.
But is this really a good idea?
What if they've set up an ambush for him?
It's fine.
Itakura-san made them promise they wouldn't follow him around.
They'd never break a promise they made to a guy who's so paranoid that he noticed
when a pen was moved 5 cm.
You have a point.
If they'd angered him before the OS was done, their efforts would've been for naught.
What happens if the news of Itakura-san's murder comes up on the TV or radio?
That's fine for now.
I've been checking the radio,
but all they've been talking about is the jewel thieves on the run.
What worries me the most are those words at the end of the diary.
Yeah.
"We are both God and the Devil,
since we're trying to raise the dead against the stream of time."
What did they mean by that?
Hey, Doc...
Don't tell me the poison Haibara was working on was actually...
No way...
Meant to make zombies?
Don't be impatient.
People can't go against the stream of time.
If they try to force it...
...they will be punished.
What?
What does she mean by "punished"?
We're finally here.
Now, how are we going to get in?
Huh? Where'd you get that key?
It was hidden behind the stairs.
Remember what the diary said.
"A friend who I hadn't seen in five years called me from my cottage."
That means the key was hidden somewhere so that his friends could come here when they wanted.
Ah, I see.
But isn't this dangerous?
That's why he left this here.
Because they'd never imagine that he'd hide the OS they wanted in an unprotected place like this.
And if he doesn't receive the e-mail they're going to send,
they'll eventually come looking for Itakura-san,
and they'll find the OS and the check.
That way, Itakura-san could sever his ties with them without needing to meet.
Right...
S-Shin'ichi...
It's almost time...
Yeah...
Come on, men in black.
Come out, you filthy rats!
The e-mail's here!
Okay, let's open it...
A password?
The count keeps going down!
Damn!
T-The e-mail's gone!
It's rigged so that if you don't open it immediately, it'll disappear!
Then...
Do you think they know the e-mail wasn't opened?
Yeah.
Not only that, they may even know it came from this computer.
What do we do? They may figure out that
something happened to Itakura-san.
S-Shin'ichi?
Shin'ichi?
Incoming Call
Number withheld
At this moment, we can't come to the phone.
Incoming Call
Number withheld
Please leave a message after the beep.
Yo, what's up?
Vodka!
You're there, aren't you?
We've been discovered!
They know we failed to open the e-mail in this cottage!
Yeah.
Or maybe they've been watching this cottage without Itakura-san realizing it.
What'd you say?
I was almost certain that they wouldn't expect Itakura-san to open the mail here,
Due to the insecurity of this place.
Hey, hey...
If that's the case, how are we going to escape?!
Incoming Call
Number withheld
Hey, answer!
I know you're in that cottage!
S-Shin'ichi!
You better pick up the phone, Itakura-san.
Incoming Call
Number withheld
Hey, what's up?
You hear me?! Hey!