Deduction flows with the «
rhythm of the wind
+ {26a
Dark.stains are rinsed
clean and exposed
The contact in which its life was risked
Gin and Vodka
The result of negotiation?
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan
Ve pn
7/23
Ve op
Vo MM
(2 -§ ° ¢
<< Mm
After-getting a clue from
Mr. ltakurawhe-had been murdered
of how to get in contact with
the Black Organization,
Dr. Agasa and I came to his villa...
PRS cc -Me QO
DFEETRWWDMILIG
CAD Be er 7 ED
Dr. Agasa and I came to his villa...
While we were there,
we get a call from Vodka...
Yoh, what's up?
You're there, aren't you?
I know you're there at the villa!!
Hurry up and"answer me,
will you, Mr. Itakura!!
Hey!!
Oh, sorry...
It's so dark in here that I was having
trouble picking up the phone...
Hey. hey, hey?!
I pretended to be Mr. Itakura
and talked Vodka into
making me promise
to meet him at the coin locker
Iocated in the basement of the
Kenbashi Subway Station at 4 o'clock.
All right, he fell for it!
But on our way there.
Doc's car went flat on'a mountain path
So. we got a car that
was passing through to give us a lift,
and was somehow able to
make it to Tokyo,
but...
Strange...
There's something fishy about them...
Don't tell me that...
they're...
CREE)
Contact with the Black Organization
(Desperate Battle Edition)
We're almost there, you guys...
Your destination. Kenbashi Station...
But, isn't that place still
under construction?
The train won't come
even if you go there you know...
We live near the station...
Oh- how convenient
Ha. ha, ha...
I guess so...
Hey. Shinichi, are you really going to go?
Yeah...
I've come up with something
I gotta do before that though...
Hey!
I don't know what you're up to, but
will you cut out talking secret in my car...
Oh. I'm so sorry...
Hey! I told you not to smoke!
Oh, that's right...
Sorry, sorry,
I'll throw it away right away
Hey!
Don't throw litter out of the window!
Throw it away in the ashtray...
Hey. hey, you got loose change mixed
with cigarette butts and ash!
No matter how rich you are, you'll be
punished for doing something like this...
I guess it can't be helped...
Because these two people...
are robbers...
WwW. What?!
Just what do you mean. Shinichi?
This car is probably...not his
They probably abandoned the car they
made their getaway with in the mountains
and stole this car from somebody who
happen to pass by...
The legal owner of this car
probably doesn't smoke,
so the owner was probably using the
ashtray as a place to put his loose change
so he could pay highway
tolls with ease...
He put his cigarette butt inside
the ashtray without realizing this,
so even after he did
he probably kept using it as an ashtray...
Gulp
Until they gave us a lift, that is...
N, No way, sonny...
I put the coins in there to spite him
because I hate smokers...
There's still other evidence that
this car is not his...
You drove from where you could judge
your position from the driver's seat
because you're not used to driving cars
with steering wheels on the left, right?
That's why you were driving
near the center line
and got honked at time and again...
When you backed the car up
you looked to the left where
Iooking behind was more difficult.
And that's probably the same reason
why you were having trouble shifting
gears with your right hand...
Moreover. when turning the curve
you turned on the wipers
instead of the blinker, right?
You forgot that foreign cars
with the steering wheel on the left,
have blinkers and wipers on the
opposite side as that of Japanese cars
There's still more...
When we first got into this car...
If you opened the left door,
I could've got in right away, but,
I was wondering why you let me in
from the door on the side of the road
But, I figured out why
at the checkpoint after
what Officer Yamamura said...
that the seat that you're
sitting on right now
IS stained with the
blood of the other robber,
the man whowas shot in the leg
and sitting there till a while ago
And that other man is
probably in the trunk...
He's probably hiding there
SO you could get through the checkpoint...
T.Then why did they give us a lift...7?
Of course if they were
just some ordinary car thieves,
they wouldn't have done so
But, they did so to help them
get through the checkpoint
They can throw the police off guard into
thinking that it's a family trip or something
if a boy and an old man
are with them, right?
That's how I figured out who they were
The only people who would give us a lift
despite stealing somebody else's car...
had to be the jewelry shop
robbers on the run
Oh~ You're pretty smart,
sonny, aren't you...
I'm not all that sure if being
too smart at your age
Is all that great...
SS. Shinichi...
Well! Now that you know,
we've got no choice...
We're going to need you to stick around
with us a while longer then...
So...
The problem now is, where
we get rid of this old man and kid...
Uh-huh
How about Kenbashi Station
that's under construction that
they wanted to go to?
There's nobody there and besides.
The construction workers won't be
coming uni a er ay rea...
By the way. sonny,
why didn't you tell the police
about us at the checkpoint?
You already knew by then, didn't you,
that we were the jewelry shop robbers...?
I didn't want to lose time...
If I turned you into the police at that time.
We would have to go through questioning
too because we were riding the same car
Then, I would be late
for my important appointment...
Besides, we could catch
you anytime anyway...
You sound pretty confident,
don't you, sonny...
I like people like you...
Talk as cheeky as you
Iike while you can...
Even if you cry "Help!"
I'm not going to forgive you
Don't you forget that...
H. Hey?!
He won't be getting up for a while
because I fired an anesthetic needle into him...
A. Anesthetic needle?!
Hang on!!
You brat. what a thing to do!
Cut it out...
You may have been able to deceive
the jewelry shop
with a dingy model gun like that,
but you can't fool me...
What the...
Who are you, anyway?!
Conan Edogawa...
a detective...
Detective...?
Oh, right,
be careful over there
Huh
It's a ball firing belt
Gas is inside a special rubber
and it turns into a soccer ball!
But this rubber is very elastic...
When you move the dial to maximum
H.Hey...
it inflates a large as an ad balloon...
I'll be on my way then
So. call the police. will you, Doc
And tell them that
we caught the jewelry shop robbers!
Hey, hey, are you really going
to the place of the deal?
Don't worry!
Since this is one station away
from Kenbashi Station,
even if the police were to come,
they won't call off the deal...
No. that's not what I'm worried about...
See you, then!
If something comes up
I'll contact you with the detective badge.
SO don't come near
Kenbash Station till then!!
H.Hey. Shinichi?!
It's almost time...
Are all the men in position?
Okay, don't let one mouse get through!
Hey. Itakura...
Tsk...ltakura,
that rat's not here yet...
Whew
Hmm?
A- check...?
This is the same amount
we paid ltakura...
This is the system software that
we asked ltakura to make.
What an idiot...
He gives back the money we paid him,
and went chicken leaving
just the stuff behind...
Spit!
Okay. I got him!!
Yeah, it's me...
That Itakura should be
somewhere nearby...
Go get him and bring him here!
What?
The only ones who entered the station
are a drunkard and a kid?!
It can't be! Look for him!!
Just what are you up to...?
B...Boss...
Gin!!
The deal's supposed to
be midnight tomorrow...
He complained that
tomorrow wasn't good for him,
so the time was changed...
So. you exchanged e-mails with him and
he used you to his advantage...
I'm the one who set the time...
He received the e-mail at his villa
and said that there was a black-out
so I talked to him directly on the phone...
I.1 couldn't get rid of him but
got a hold of what we were after...
and besides. he's got a
pretty badaheart?...
Heh. heh. heh...
He'll croak over soon either way...
Hey...
why do you think this was
stuck on with tape?
Huh 2!
To get your fingerprints...
You can't take off the tape
with gloves on, you see...
Huh
And...
if the one you're waiting
for doesn't show up,
you get irritated and light cigarettes...
If the saliva on this is checked,
they'd even be able to find
ut your blood type...
B.Boss...
Oo...
he's even trying to track down
the location of the base of our operations
Look...
There's a communicator on the inside
of the CD case...
He sure is some sly fox...
T, That Itakura...
No. it's not Itakura...
In a place where there is a
drastic difference in temperature,
the sympathetic nerves are stimulated
and a great load is placed on the heart...
I don't think a guy
with heart problems will go out
of he way to a villa
in the mountains in the blizzard...
Then...Then,
who was the guy that
I talked to on the phone...
Probably some wiz that
he hired or something...but
he made one mistake...
Huh
This case...
The fingerprints seem to have
been wiped off, but it's still warm...
» hich means...
Yeah...
he should still be
hiding somewhere nearby...
R.Rats...
If things keep up as is, they'll find me...
What now?
What can I do?!
Heh. heh...
The only place left is there...
A sly fox is no more
than agcornered rat now...
Cut out your blabbering...
Oh. boss...
There's nobody here...
So. what now?
H, boss...
Oh, boss?
There's no way a grown adult
could hide in a place like this...
evermind...
we'll change our appearance
and get out of here
He may have called the police...
Huh
You mean the guy who ltakura hired?
Yeah...
Be careful, there's no next chance...
It seems that some rat is
snooping around us...
A fox detective...
What now?
Should I go after them!
No, it's too early yet
They may be lying in wait
after pretending to leave...
But what is it...?
What are those guys
trying to do anyway...?
Ail said that they made her
make queer drugs.
But Mr. Itakura is a system engineer...
He has nothing to do with drugs...
A software that he abandoned making
for the sake of mankind...
What on earth...
what on earth...is it about...
Well~good work Dr. Agasa!
Huh?
Yes. well, I guess...
I'm sure you're tired,
but I'm going to have to ask you to come
to the station with me for questioning!
Oh...
Inspector! Excuse me...
I'll see you later, then...
What is it, Officer Chiba...?
About the wound of the suspect...
Shinichi...what's up...
Shinichi...
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers
MICHIHIKO_SUWA
MA AHITQ YOSHIOKA
Bicksround Music.
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By
MASATDMO" $000
Story Editor
Scripts-By.
KAN/PKASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUGHI
JUNICHI-MIYASHI IA
YUIGsHIT HIGURE
ITOSHIKI INOUE
Scripts By
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
\ZUNARI KOUCH
HI MIYAS
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWA "URA
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Gogol
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chic Director.
KENJIIKODAMA
Produccd By #
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
In-1ssotciation with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE ( ONAN
Os AOYAMA HOCAKUKAN- YTV: MA
All Ri .} Reserved
mm...? Footsteps...?
S... Somebody's... Somebody's coming...
D...Damn...My body...It won't move
Heave., heave...
VV / Ed
Just™ at are you doing
in a place like this ..7?
WwW. What. well...
And. what are you doing here yourself?
Both Doctor and you didn't come back
even after morning came,
so I used your spare pursuit glasses
and came Iookin- for both of ou!
It.It's morning?!
Little lady. did you find your friend?
Yes...
Okay then: you're getting in the
way of work so out you go
Ac h!
Hey. wait Shinichi?!
I see...
I fainted in there because
ff lack of oxygen...
And?
Just what are you doing
in a place like this
O.,Oh...1 didn't get to sleep.
So I was sort of taking a snooze...
Do you think that's
answering my question?
Oh. well, what's the difference?
Let's hurry home and get some grub
I'm starved
I'm starved...
Hey!
Wheres Doc?!
Doc's fine! He's at the police. station!
Now for the next news
Yesterday at about 5 p.m: the body of
a man was found at Hotel New-Beika...
The body was identified to
as that of computer graphic designer,
Mr. Taku Itakura, age 45...
Don't tell me...
Huh
Hey. what's up?
It's nothing...
By the way,
that old man's the minister to the left
and belongs on the fourth
row to the very right
Don't get it wrong now!
You're pretty informed
despite being a boy, aren't you...?
(Cr \
Y.Yeah...
Ran used to make me help her
all the time when I was a kid...
It seems that the granny it's.not the
only one that's disappeared!
Look.
The hanging scroll of the god
of thunder is also gone
Girls'Festival'Dolls:in'thé'Sunset"
Part 1