OP ve Fresns
Loop HTT,
Deduction flows with
the rhythm of the wind
Deduction: flows with
Dark stains are rinsed
clean and exposed
The seven tiered festival doll set.
And the mystery of the
robber who stole it.
He sees through the one and only truth,
A-child in.appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
<S>--
(K's;
- < - * -
ow (1 \
SOgc B
8 (»O Yeo
em Dy
Ve om
aw§da
Look, look at that hina doll!
How beautiful!
Oh, so Girls' Day Festival is »
right around the corner...
I always cat eel!
I really like that Hina doll
But, you've already got a nice
one at home, Ayumi
Hey, did you forget?!
Last year you dropped the girl hina doll
and its hands and
eck broke off, right?
Oh, that's right!
I'm sorry, Ayumi
But, I guess you can have it repaired.
Of course she did.
But while the craftsman
was repairing the
doll he got hurt and blood splattered
on the face of the doll.
When the doll was finally repaired,
Peach the dog next: door brought the neck
of the doll to Ayumi when she got home
But, the paint that was used to cover the
blood on the face was peeled off,
its hair was disheveled and it was
wearing a dreadful facial expression
Hey. hey, hey!
Seriously, that doll is cursed!
Yes, ever since then the doll set was
securely packed away in a box
By Ayumi's father who was worried
a 1e CO SS may »>ring upon mis or une.
I hear that Wt is still way deep
inside the closet...
It's not cursed...
Peach brought the doll to me wanting to
show it to me as soon as possible
And, the neck of the doll
just happened to fall off then...
<< 7 \
Hey, Ayumi!
/11)
Don't cry
ec we
477 )
Just playing
Peach's owner asked an
acquaintance of his for me,
so that person is going to
give me a set of
Girls' Festival dolls that she
Isn't using anymore!
It has seven rows of dolls and is
Iarger than the one I had!
She says I could have
the doll set if I can
Iine them up correctly without
% looking at anything for reference!
But you'd have to line up quite a number
% of dolls if the set has Seven rows to it
Can you handle it alone?
I'll be just fine, because I memorized
how the dolls are line up over and over!
And besides, I'm not going to do it alone.
QG-BET),
Girls' Festival Dolls in the Sunset"
Part 1
Oh, hi, Ayumi!
So, did you memorize how
the dolls are to be lined up?
You didn't look too confident
whenryou came last time so...
Yep, no problem!
Okay. then I guess I'll have
you line them up right now
Are these all boxes with
dolls in them?
Why do you have to memorize how the
dolls are supposed to be lined up, though?
Because she thinks that
Ayumi's going to make a mistake
The fact is, she doesn't
want to give it away.
That's not exactly it.
We're just checking to see if she's a girl
that will take good care of the dolls
Learning to line the dolls up correctly
will give rise to more
affection towards the dolls, no?
After all, they are very precious
dolls that were bought for me.
I wish you luck then, little lady!
Okay!
Oh, Genta. that's not right.
The man with the
bow and arrow belongs more to the top!
Yeah, but the more the merrier!
No! You've«got to line them
upicorrectly
And, while you're at it,
that old man is the
minister of the left andWbelongs on
the fourth step to the very right.
0 be 1000 ?
The young one that looks a loteO
Iike him is the minister
of the right and belongs on the
same step to the very left,
so don't get them wrong!
The left belongs to the right
and the right belongs to the left...
You know so much despite
being a boy.
I helped Ran a ot when I was a kid,
You used to line them up when
you, were a kid too, didn't you?
Oh, didn't I tell you?
I was sent off to the States to
study as early as I can remember
so this is the first time I'm
even touching these dolls...
It seems my parents got my older
sister Girls' Festival dolls but,
my parents died soon
after I was born too, so
Besides, my sister never took the dolls
out because they brought
back sad memories...
Hey, how did your parents die?
Well, it seems that my sister was told
that they died of an accident during
some research they were doing
Come to think of it,
I remembernthat Visco once mentioned
that your parents were scientists
Yess although my mother
was not all that well known
My father. Atsushi Miyano seems to
have been pretty well-know in the field
as a mad scientist who was
ousted from academic circles
As a mad scientist?
Hey, what the heck
are you talking about?
You developed that drug
because you took
over what your parents were
doing. didn't you?
Just what kind of drug was it?
A secret drug...
A secret drug that's
used to revive the dead...
Will this answer satisfy you?
Then, don't tell me that, the
stuff that was written in the diary was...
Just as I thought
The thing you were looking at on the
computer the other day was a
clue to those people, wasn't it?
And after you traced the clue, you found
out where they stopped by but,
aside from what you expected, while
you were waiting for them, you overslept,
I guess the ston went
something like this
Yeah, well, sort of...
Well, you don't have to worn
The goal of my research has nothing to
do with making a dream-like
drug like that.
Most of the people here
on earth would find
no value in the stuff
I'm involved in now
It's like the Girl's Festival dolls
that are important
LL ABA va
only for the girls of this small country...
Iet's go from thé3top,
the Emperor, the Empress
Three Court Ladies, the Five
Musicians, the two guardians
the Minister of the Left
and Minister of the Right-
O And on the fifth step are the
Three Pages expressing
the human emotions of
Iaughter, worry and anger!
You've passed with flying colors!
Then, are you going to
give me this doll-set?
Yes, I'll have it delivered to
you by courier right away!
All right!
Make sure you thank
grandma later, okay?
Okay!
Shall we start cleaning up, then?
We went out of our way
to.line them up,
and we're going to, put
them-away already?
It can't be helped. because it has
to be packed.to send out \
Oh, wait! Let's all take a
picture in front of it first!
I brought daddy's digital
camera with me!
Okay, 'here goes
Say cheese!
My. I wonder who it is?
Oh, Mr. Tsumagari of room 503.
Hello.
If it's about that thing, I'm sure my
husband already refused.
Yes, but I just can't give it up.
I brought an appraiser with me today,
and I thought I'd ask him one more time.
How do you do?
This way, please
This is really something
his is a fine Hina doll set
A famous doll craftsman in
Kyoto seems to have made it.
How much will you sell it to me for?
Are you buying these dolls?
Too late, mister!
They were already given to Ayumi!
No, I don't have a daughter so
I'm not interested in dolls!
What I want her to sell me is the
hanging scroll behind all of you.
That's the Thunder God
that was drawn by
an artist of the Edo era
named Tetsuyama.
I have the Wind God which is the
other half of this hanging scroll,
and I really want to make
it a complete set.
But, my husband says he has
no intention of selling it,
and besides, it doesn't
Iook to be something so valuable
Don't you know?
How valuable that hanging scroll is!
Do you have any idea
how much insurance
your husband's late
father placed on it?
Well, no...
20,000,000 yen, 20,000,000 yen!
That much?
I told your husband that I would
pay him double that.
Besides, I feel
sorry for this hanging scroll.
If kept in this manner, the value
of this scroll will go down
I think it'd be wiser to sell it to a
professional collector like
Mr. Tsumagari.
But my husband...
We will not sell it.
No matter how much
money you dish out for it.
Mother...
Okay. I'll be back again tonight just
about the time your husband comes home
I'm sure he'll agree to sell it.
If I mention the story about him
making a great loss in stocks
Let's put away the dolls and
hurry on home too, then
How nostalgic, it's already been
10 years since we last decorated them.
The dolls look happy that they were
taken out of the box
after such a long time too
Mother...
Ayumi, would it be okay to decorate
these dolls here
until Girls' Day Festival this year?
I guess mother wants to
say goodbye to them.
Sure!
But, can I stay here a while longer then?
Because I have one more
picture I want to take...
Why don't you have mother serve
you some sweet sake then!
I thought we were out of the ingredients
to make it from scratch?
This is troublesome.
I have to go out soon too
I'll go buy it then!
The supermarket is right there!
Thank you very much!
Ayumi, isn't it about time you tell us?
Just what do you
want to take a picture of?
want to take a Ricture of?
A picture of all of us having a good time!
We just took one like
that a while ago!
Something even better.
Which way was it? \
This way.
Okay, just a little while more to go!
Come on, let's go
Oh, okay!
I think it was just around this corner...
Isn't that the appraiser?
I thought you went home?
Well, I forgot my cell phone
I called my cell phone, then the lady
answered and told
me that it's in the living room.
She told me I could get
it when I go over tonight,
but I may get important phone calls so
I decided toe pick it up now.
But, it seems that no one's home...
You mean grandma isn't home?
Oh, he's right, nobody's home...
NO one is here...
Hey. the door's not locked!
I wonder if grandma went to sleep?
What is this sound?
I think it's the sound of the fax machine.
It's coming from this room...
What the heck is going on!
The room is super messed up!
The fax seems-to be from her husband
Hey everyone.
That doesn't seem to be the only place.
Burglary. A burglar
broke in after we left
By the looks of it, maybe the
other rooms are messed up as well.
Ayumi!
I'm glad the dolls are fine!
This room looks untouched.
I wonder where grandma is, though?
It seems that grandma's not the
only one who disappeared!
Take a look
The hanging scroll of the
Thunder God is gone too.
Let's call the police right now!
Call the police!
G,Grandma?
Oh, so I did miss you, after all.
Where were you grandma?
Well, when I looked I
found out that I had also run
out of sugar, so I went to buy some.
By the way, why are you all
Iooking pale faced about?
W. Well, the thing is.
Setsuko, I thought you went out...
I forgot my wallet so
I came back to get it...
The bedroom's...
Oh, my!
Oh. so we were just
about to call the police.
- Iv.
M.Mr. Tsumagari!
What happened?
I heard somebody scream.
Oh, well, the thing is...
A burglar, a burglar broke in .
Let's talk after the police get here.
I see, so from what a gather here,
those children came here to decorate
the Hina dolls; and after that,
Mr. Tsumagari who extremely-wanted
the hanging scroll thatflwas stolen,
brought appraiser, Mr. Mie with him...
Officer, please don't say it like that.
And after the two men left,
you five went out shopping.
Yeah. to buy the ingredients
for making sweet sake!
Ingredients for sweet sake?
Mother was going to make
sweet sake for everyone,
when I realized that we were out
of the necessary ingredients
Since I had to go out,
I asked the children to go get it.
After that you were here alone,
Grandma Yayoi?
Yes, exactly...
Did you notice anything then?
Like strange noise.
It was quiet, until the cell phone that
he forgot in the living room rang.
Y.Yeah...
Oh, you forgot your cell
phone in the living room?
We were shown into the living room first,
because the children
were in the Japanese room
But, we wanted to see the
hanging scroll as soon as possible,
so forced our way immediately
into the Japanese room.
And, after the phone call you seem to
have gone out shopping too, but for what?
I went out to buy sugar.
I realized that we were out of
sugar so I rushed out to get some.
Do you know about
what time it was?
Well, it was right after I hung up so...
Then, can tell what time it was.
Just before I hung up. I heard the sound
of the FAX on the other side of the line,
so if we look at the time the FAX was
sent, we can find out what time it was!
Who was the FAX from?
I think it was from my husband...
Then where is that original FAX?
In the living room.
My gosh, they really went all out
messing up the room
So this is the FAX
you received from your husband
3:218 PM.
What else was stolen
besides the hangingrscroll?
Nothing. Only hererand the
bedroom were ransacked.
Even the wallet that was on the shelf
above the TV was left untouched.
May I have a minute
with you, Officer Momose?
It seems that the burglar broke in
from the veranda facing this window,
Just as I thought...
Why do you think that this is
the way the burglar broke in?
We're on the 6th floor, you know!
It's a common target for burglars who
use a rope to get down from the roof
They seem to think that people living on
the top floor of condos are rich,
and most times the windows
aren't locked anyway
You sure know a lot, don't you Au!
Yes, because ll live with an old man
who likes to watch wide shows on TV.
If I'm not mistaken, you're the first ones
who realized that the
room was ransacked?
Yeah, when we got back from
shopping the front door was unlocked.
And when we heard the sound of the FAX
machine and came into the living-room,
It was all messed up! At that time
the clock on the FAX was 15:40!
Which means that the
burglary took place between
15:30 and 15:40 a
period of 10 minutes
I wonder...
The burglar went down on the veranda
and came in through thatswindow, rights.
If it were me,
I'd be tooascared to come in.
If you close the window, nothing is in view
from the veranda because of the curtain.
F the burglar opens the window
wanting to look inside,
the curtain would flutter in the wind,
and the lady on the phone would notice.
And, besides the time thezEAX
was sent out all show 15728!
Which means that the FAX kept coming
in all-the while we were out shopping
until we came back, right?
Do you think a burglar would break
into airoom where noise is
constantly coming from?
But, it's just the sound of the FAX...
The more so frightening
because it s the FAX!
Because if the FAX completes
coming in and the buzzer sounds
somebody in the house
may come to take a look at it!
I see...
Beside, it's strange that the burglar
didn't notice her wallet and
if the burglar couldn't
find what he was after,
wouldn't all the other rooms
be ransacked too?
True...
The strangest thing is, why only
the hanging scroll was stolen .
But, that hanging scroll is
worth 20:000,000 yen!
You fool, only a professional would know
if that scroll is really worth that price
Which means that the burglar knew
that the scroll was here to begin with.
«> <O »
Yeah, but if the burglar
was after the scroll,
\ = 49 . wed Pp
Yeah, but if the burglar
was after the scroll,
\Q- fl)
the other room wouldn't
have beenyransacked
Maybe the burglar messed up the
other room just to throw people off,
so that he's not suspected.
Which means that the culprit has no
definite alibi and on top of that had to face
the police reluctantly after the incident.
Furthermore, that person knows the
value of that hanging scroll.
Come to think of it,
you were loitering -around
in front of this house, weren't you?
LI just told you, didn't I?
That I came to get my cell phone,
but nobody was home
But, the door wasn't locked!
Well...
Did you lock the door
when you left the house?
Well, I think I did,
but I was in a rush so...
By the way. whyawere you at the
front door a while ago, mister?
I came to check things out because
Mr. Mie didn't come back for some time. #
Were you all here?
Then, he also knew that you
forgot your cell phone, right?
Yes...
Yes, he did, since he was by me until
@ I started talking to grandma
You mean you left
while he was on the phone?
LI just went to buygsome cigarettes!
In other words, just as this child just said,
you two do not have an alibi yet.
Hey, hey, will you cut
out just suspecting us!
Those two are going to get 20,000,000
yen too if insurance money comes in!
I'm just saying that even you two
can carry out something like this!
WwW. What a thing to say!
We sure are in a fix. All four of you
have motives, no alibi and
on top of that all of you are
capable of carrying out the crime
The key to nailing down the culprit is
in the Japanese room!
Original Comic Books By.
Producers.
IIHIKO .
Background Music
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By
MASXTQMO sum)
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HICURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animition Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
TSUSHI AON
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKA HI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chicf-Director.
KEN] KODAMA
Produced By.
TMSSENTERTAINMENT: LTD.
11ssotidtion with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE ( ONAN
COMO AOYAMAY SHOGARURKAN YTV - IMS
All RIEH Reserved
Hey, Conan...
Did you figure out who the culprit as'?
Oh, sorry, I'm in the
process of thinking now...
But we better hurry or
the steps will...
But the steps
Thank Ayumi!
I solved thee mystery!
GirlsFestivalrDollssin thesSunset"
Part?