With the rhythm of the wind, deductions become clear.
Figuring out the alibi trick!
The solution to the robbery case!
What is Ayumi-chan's real intention?
Recognizing that one truth,
A child with the mind of an adult,
His name is Detective Conan!
The, the Detective Boys, went along with Ayumi-chan to receive some festival dolls at Kanno-san's house.
Then, trying to purchase the scroll of the Thunder God, Tsumagari Mizutaka-san and
the antique appraiser, Mie Yoshiharu-san, arrived at the house.
But the grandmother Kanno-san refused to sell it.
However, while we went out shopping, the scroll vanished!
Also, look at this! The time on all of these faxes is 3:28 PM.
That means, before we arrived back here, the fax was running the whole time, right?
Would a burglar enter a room that's receiving messages, and risk being caught?
Moreover, a normal burglar wouldn't just leave the mistress's purse lying in the open in the bedroom.
And after looking in the bedroom, why didn't they look through all of the other rooms?
T-True...
And the strangest thing is, why did they only take the scroll?
But the scroll is worth 20 million yen!
Idiot, you'd have to be a professional to know how much it's worth.
So the burglar knew from the beginning that the scroll was here?
Yeah.
Except if they only wanted to take the scroll, they wouldn't need to go through the other rooms.
They went through the bedroom to create a crime scene and mislead the investigators.
Which means the culprit doesn't have an alibi and knew they would have to talk to the police about the case at the crime scene.
Furthermore, that person has to know how much the scroll is worth.
Festival Dolls Dyed in the Setting Sun
Festival Dolls Dyed in the Setting Sun...
Part Two!
Hey, Conan. We've been in the tatami room...
There were only festival dolls there...
Here, look. Hasn't it changed a bit?
Before we went shopping, something was different.
Where is there a difference?
I don't see anything.
Ah! I see it!
The Emperor and Empress dolls have switched places with each other!
It's true!
That isn't the only thing. Ayumi-chan, do you have your digital camera?
Yeah, here.
Look. Though it's a bit hard to see in the photo...
The other thirteen have also moved slightly, right?
It's true...
Most likely, when the culprit was trying to unhook the scroll,
They bumped into the stand and knocked the dolls over.
I see. I guess they were in a hurry, so they put the dolls in the wrong places.
And, who is the culprit?
Eh?
Hey, hurry up and tell us!
A-Actually, the truth is, I don't know yet...
Oh, is that so?
You looked like you knew everything!
But the dolls look so sad.
Look, this doll looked happy earlier, but now it's different.
We tried so hard to set them up, and they were knocked over...
That's it! I get it!
The culprit is someone who doesn't know how to order the festival dolls correctly.
That means, the culprit is Tsumagari-san, it can only be you!
Didn't you say that you don't have any daughters, and that you aren't interested in dolls, either?
I see! That's why you couldn't set them up correctly!
Now, just admit your crime!
The culprit is you, right?
No, that's wrong. It wasn't Tsumagari-san.
The real culprit is one of those two.
Those two are the only ones who could have done this!
But why?
Why would the dolls have to be set up again?
It would look more like a robbery if they were just left lying on the ground.
Then, Tsumagari-san, may we take a look in your apartment?
Of course, with your permission.
I understand! Search as much as you want!
But I'm telling you, you won't find anything!
Ah, also, we will do a body check on you three as well.
You could be hiding the scroll underneath your clothes.
Then let's get going now.
Hopefully, we can get this done quickly before sunset.
Yes.
It can't be! It's already this late...
But is Tsumagari-san really the culprit? I was only making a guess.
Hey, I was following your lead.
Hey, Conan-kun, do you know who the culprit is?
Ah, sorry, I'm thinking about it now.
But if we don't hurry, the stairs...
The stairs...
Thanks, Ayumi-chan! I've figured out the mystery!
R-Really? So you know who the culprit is?
Yeah, thanks to you!
Then 111 go call the officers back here!
Ah, Ayumi-chan?
What!? You know who stole the scroll?
Who figured it out?
You'll have to return to Kanno-san's apartment to find out.
Hurry, Officer!
Please...
So please, Mr. Sunset.
Wait a bit longer... Just a little...
I see.
You've been waiting for this sunset.
H-Haibara-san...
Looks beautiful, doesn't it?
You seem to have an eye for these things.
R-Really?
Now, hurry and solve the case, and bring them here.
Sunset...
The world begins to turn red...
The sunlight begins to fade...
Who knows how many times I'll see it again.
This sad color.
Well then, who managed to solve this case?
Could it have been you...
Ah, no.
It was me!
It was you?
Yeah, I've figured out everything!
The culprit who stole the scroll, as well as the location of the scroll!
The hint is the festival dolls!
After taking the scroll and trying to run away, they knocked over the stand and tried to put the dolls back in order.
But when they were putting them back, they accidentally swapped the Emperor and the Empress.
That means the prime suspect would be Tsumagari-san.
He wanted the scroll the most out of the four, and he's the only one who knows nothing about festival dolls!
You're wrong! It's the other way around!
Other way?
Here, look closely at the festival dolls!
When all of us first came here, we set up the dolls without any mistakes.
From that time, everything stayed the same except for the Emperor and Empress!
Is that right?
Yes, it's true.
When the children set them up, I checked it myself.
If the culprit had bumped into the stand hard enough to knock over the Emperor and Empress,
wouldn't the other dolls have been knocked over as well?
Someone who doesn't know anything about festival dolls
could not have ordered all of those correctly!
But why would they make the mistake of switching the Emperor and Empress...
What if it wasn't a mistake?
What if this arrangement of the dolls is the traditional Japanese way?
T-Traditional?
Yeah.
Japanese tradition states that left is ranked higher than right, and the left would wear dark clothes while the right wore red clothes.
In the festival dolls, the older Minister of Right is on the left, and the young Minister of Left is on the right, see?
With the emperor and empress, a male would be ranked higher than a female, so the man is on the left, while she's on the right.
Hey, Conan, you're getting right and left wrong! The man's on the right!
That's because from the doll's perspective^the Emperor is on the left instead of the Empress.
Ah, that's right...
But no one arranges them like this anymore.
Even all the stores do it the other way.
That's because it's Tokyo.
When European culture entered the country,
the importance of the right over the left also came with it.
So most of the department stores in Tokyo arrange their festival dolls the other way now.
Wow, you know so much for a boy.
Yup!
I love studying ancient history books!
U-Um, Conan-kun?
I have always been wondering...
How come you sound childish every time you talk to adults?
You sound sweet and cheesy.
I-Is that so?
It's kind of creepy.
I get it!
I'll speak normally, okay? Normally!
I think it's really cute...
You always make such cute examples!
So, who is the culprit, boy?
Uh... yeah...
The culprit is someone who arranges them by tradition.
So that could only mean the grandmother Kano-san or the appraiser Mie-san did it!
When the grandmother was a young girl,
people still set dolls the traditional way.
The grandmothers hometown is Kyoto.
In Kyoto, families still set them up the old-fashioned way today.
She was probably taught to set them up that way, right?
Also, Mie-san here, as an expert in many different ancient things, would know how to arrange the festival dolls from Kyoto.
He could have purposely set the dolls like this because he knew where they were from.
How would he know the festival dolls were from Kyoto?
The mistress Setsuko-san told Mie-san that.
But it wouldn't be difficult to figure out the festival dolls were from Kyoto, because he could've known that as an expert.
Then who's the culprit, and where is the scroll?
Maybe you don't know it yet.
I already know who it is.
Because of the hint Ayumi-chan gave about the stairs!
S-Stairs... Could it be...!?
The culprit climbed up the doll stand like a staircase, and then hid the scroll up there in the cupboard!
The dolls were probably moved slightly out of place as the culprit climbed up!
Wait, Genta-kun, don't be so reckless!
It's okay, because the scroll is most likely in this cupboard...
Nothing...
You're wrong.
The scroll is in here.
The culprit hid the scroll in this closet.
When he moved the stand aside, some of the dolls fell off.
If you go through the closet here, you can easily hide the scroll.
Huh?
There's nothing here but the boxes for the dolls...
Didn't the culprit bump into the stand while running away?
No.
The dolls didn't fall.
The culprit had purposely lifted all the dolls off the stand to find a place to hide the scroll.
Lifted them off?
Then could the scroll be...
Hey, help me take all these dolls off!
Y-Yes!
To hide a scroll somewhere convenient and hard to find...
That is...
Underneath the red felt of the Hina doll stand!
I see...
You can't see it unless you take all of the dolls off.
No one would think of looking here.
Also, Ayumi, when you said the doll looked sad,
It was because it was underneath this piece of wood.
If I place the doll on the edge of the scroll,
he tilts forward and his expression looks different, doesn't it?
So that's why it looked different!
Why was the scroll placed upside-down?
The piece of wood at the bottom of a scroll is always heavier than at the top.
It would be obvious that the scroll was there even if the red felt was over it.
The culprit hid the wooden pole behind the folding screen.
Wait a minute!
If the culprit hid the scroll here, then that means...
Yes.
The culprit was planning to pretend to c-lean up the dolls...
And take back the scroll after the police left.
Isn't that right, Grandmother Kanno?
Grandmother Kanno?
It can't be...
Really?
Yeah.
You probably thought of hiding the scroll when we went out to buy groceries.
You messed up the room to make it look like a burglary!
And pretended to buy sugar...
So everyone would think that the scroll was stolen while no one was home.
She even thought of opening the balcony door to mislead us.
They show that a lot on TV so she could have copied them?
I suppose...
But why, Mother?
Could it be you...
You wanted to claim the insurance money —
It's not like that. I didn't have any ill intentions.
This scroll has been the Kanno's family's guardian for so long.
Guardian?
Yes.
I was planning to hide the scroll until my son came home.
So that I could explain the importance of this.
I don't want to repeat past mistakes.
Past mistakes? You don't say...
Who figured it out!
It happened quite a long time ago.
From the day I entered the Kanno family, I noticed two ancient scrolls,
one of the God of Thunder and another of the God of Wind.
When he was still alive, my husband often said, "These two are the guardians of the Kanno family"...
If I remember correctly, the two gods were guardian deities of Kanno, the Goddess of Mercy.
When my son got married,
Our financial status was so dire.
So I had to sell the God of Wind scroll.
I didn't tell my husband, who was on a business trip.
A few days later, I heard that my husband was in an accident at sea.
They told me he had come upon a huge storm and the waves capsized his boat...
As if the God of Wind created the typhoon.
So that cursed scroll belonged to you,
and went through many hands before reaching mine.
I don't think it's cursed.
The Hina dolls used to be dolls put beside a child's pillow to protect her from bad spirits.
Every time I see a new stain on that scroll,
I thank the Thunder God that he's taken the place of a Kanno family in meeting with something bad.
So I will never sell this scroll.
Please understand.
And please do not ask for it again.
Er... Well...
Oh, I see...
Now I know why you desperately want the Thunder God scroll.
You believe in the strength of the two deities so you want their protection for yourself.
Ah, no!
One of them is enough for me!
Pretend this never happened!
Oh.
How disappointing.
I'll be back later, ma'am.
To show you how to properly take care of the scroll.
Shall we go, too, Inspector?
I'll follow you back to the station so you can wrap this case up.
Case?
Please...
Two rooms were messed up and something was lost.
If we called this a case,
then my boss will turn into the Thunder God.
With that aside, I'm sorry for putting you through all this trouble.
I'll help you pack the dolls.
Oh, you can keep them!
Don't you think that my Hina doll was broken because it had an accident in my place?
I'm going to ask my dad to fix it!
This way, I can thank it for protecting me!
I'm sorry, after all your hard worksetting the dolls up.
Oh, no...
Are you sure?
Yup!
Besides...
The Hina doll I really wanted was...
Really, actually...
Really... actually...
It doesn't matter to me, but...
You should hurry or you'll miss your chance.
It's really pretty right now.
Wow! It's amazing!
The sunset is beautiful!
I see! You wanted to get the sunset in the photo!
Conan, sit here!
Mitsuhiko, Haibara, and Genta, sit on the step below!
Here's the camera
Yes, yes...
Why are we taking a photo in this direction?
The sunset as the background would look much nicer...
It's okay, it's okay!
Smile, everyone!
Oh...
The stairs look red and with the cream-colored elevator behind you...
It seems as if you are all Hina dolls!
Wait, that means that Conan's the Emperor and I'm the Minister of the Left!
No, we're the three court ladies...
You're one to talk!
No, I...
Haibara-san, come and sit with me up here!
Move, Conan!
Stop-!
We're the five male musicians...