The rhythm of the wind refreshes the stream of reasoning.
Tricks and alibis are exposed at once!
Let's walk to the observation deck! The truth is hidden behind the accident.
I see one single truth.
I look like a child, but I have the mind of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
Mount Kotengu
"Nose of Tengu", observation deck
Tengu is a long-nosed goblin.
"It is illegal to pluck plants or catch animals, etc., on this peak." Park Control Service. Kotengu.
Hey, hey, it's not just the girls, there's not a soul to be seen here.
That's weird... And the guidebook said this place is very popular with young girls right now!
Oh, man, don't make jokes.
I get it, I get it.
We should just go, right?
Hold on, Hirai.
What?
You remember what this place is. Try to work a little more carefully.
Hirai Takaya (age 29)
Park Service employee
Yeah, it'd be bad if there's another accident.
Well, knowing you, you'd probably be happy if something happened to me.
Wait, Hirai!
I'm gone!
What?
Ah... good morning.
Kondo Eyitiro (age 39)
Park Service employee
There's a broken fence at the observation deck,
so please be careful.
Uh, okay.
Thank you.
Hey, let's take a break.
What? Again?
We just stopped the other day.
Come on, there's no rush.
I knew it, uncle, it's too much for you.
Shut up! I'm just a little tired from work.
Ran-neechan,
let's leave uncle here and go ahead.
Come on.
Hey you!
What beautiful scenery!
Aha!
Oh, it's that man.
That's right.
I wonder what he's doing out there.
We were told the fence was broken,
so he's probably fixing it.
I bet he is.
Oh...
I finally made it.
Oh, uncle.
Well done.
You fell!
What the heck?
Conan-kun!
It's dangerous!
What are you doing? What if I had fallen myself?
But...!
Anyway, let's contact the manager.
Okay!
Excuse me!
Did something happen?
A man fell off the observation deck.
What?
Really, Hirai?!
Yeah, I think so.
Anyway, how do we get to the bottom of the observation deck?
This way.
Ran, call an ambulance and the police.
Okay!
It's hopeless, he's already dead.
Hi-Hirai.
Hirai!
It's all my fault,
I...
What do you mean?
I'm the one who asked him,
I said: "The fence on the playground is broken, go and fix it."
If I had gone myself,
it wouldn't have happened.
What's that supposed to mean?
The ends of the ropes look like they've been tied up for a long time.
Dad!
The police and ambulance will be here soon.
I see.
Anyway, it looks like it was an accident.
We'd better leave it at that. We'll wait for the police to arrive at the manager's office.
Conan.
Let's go back to the office.
Okay.
What's that?
Isn't that...
a spider web?
Why is it in a place like this?
Where'd he pick it up?
That's what I thought.
There's no cobwebs anywhere.
Besides...
Where Hirai-san fell,
there's no sign of him slipping.
It's as if he jumped off on his own.
And there's another thing that's not clear,
the rope that fell near the body was twisted at both ends.
If the rope was tied properly,
why did Hirai-san fall?
And the way it was twisted...
It looks like it's been tied for a decent amount of time.
Why did Hirai-san need that rope anyway?
Oh, it's just a rabbit.
An animal trail...?
Dad, Conan-kun still hasn't returned.
Forget about him.
He's probably playing somewhere nearby.
But...!
Then I'll go look for him.
You never know what could have happened.
You just wait here for the police.
Don't worry, I'll bring him in soon.
Thank you.
What a nice man.
Dad!
That tree...
...growing right under the observation deck.
What's up there?
A piton and a ring?
It's a mountain climber's spike and a snap ring.
Something strange is going on.
Why, they're white-eyes.
What is there?
Damn, it's hard to see.
Those are...
shoe impressions.
And they're still fresh.
They're rope marks.
So that's what it all means.
Hey, Conan-kun!
What are you doing over there?
It's dangerous.
I found a white-eyes nest and decided to look at it.
I see.
But white-eyes are shy, so don't bother them.
Okay!
Anyway, hurry up and get down!
I'll be right down.
Okay, well,
everyone in the office is getting worried.
Uncle, your shoes look so old... Why?
Oh, these?
I bought them when I was a student.
They're so comfortable I don't want to change them at all.
The only drawback is they're a little heavy.
Now I understand.
It is, after all, a murder.
And the perpetrator...
Yes. None other than him.
He's the one who pushed Hirai-san, making it look like an accident,
with this trick.
I see.
Since there are so many witnesses... Mori-san, as you said,
it was undoubtedly an accident.
Yes.
However... if accidents continue to occur here,
you'll have to talk to the government officials, Mr. Kondo.
I beg your pardon...
What do you mean?
About a month ago, an employee here died falling off a cliff.
I see.
Excuse me!
We'd like to get the body out as soon as possible.
Yes, please.
Well, listen,
I'm gonna have to ask you to come down to the police station for a statement.
All right.
No, wait, please.
Dad?
Is something wrong, Mori-san?
The accidental death version seems somewhat controversial to me.
What did you say?
Ran, did you see the face of the man who fell off the landing?
No, I did not.
That's right, according to Conan, he didn't see him either,
and neither did I.
In other words, the man who fell off the platform might not have been Hirai-san at all.
But if it wasn't Hirai-san...
where did that man go afterwards?
I'm sure Kondo-san is aware of the one tree growing right below the observation deck.
What do you think?
Yes, it's there,
but its trunk isn't very thick.
I don't think you can accidentally get caught on it.
I agree, I don't think you can accidentally get caught in a tree,
if you really fall down.
What are you saying?
The man standing at the edge of the platform didn't fall off, he jumped off,
to simulate Hirai-san's fatal fall.
So this is...
Yes.
It wasn't an accident,
but a murder.
Mori-san, then who is the killer?
This man knew that Hirai-san was going to repair the fence at the observation deck.
He was also able to dress like Hirai-san.
In other words,
it was...
Kondo-san.
It could only be you.
So by pushing Hirai-san off the platform,
Kondo-san waited for you to come up and then jumped into the tree?
No. If that were true, Hirai-san's time of death and the time of Kondo-san's jump might differ greatly.
We came here to admire the view.
The fact that we ended up on the observation deck had nothing to do with Kondo-san's plan.
In other words,
after Kondo-san pushed Hirai-san down,
we could have walked for five minutes or an hour.
Then... how did he do it?
Thanks to the tree.
The tree?
Yes.
Hirai-san was in the tree below the observation deck.
As soon as Kondo-san came down from the cliff, he threw Hirai-san down from there.
That's how it is!
Indeed, then the fall times would be almost the same.
However... what a job you did!
Jumping straight off the platform was too dangerous.
No, it wasn't as dangerous as you think.
Right below the observation platform, Conan-kun found a mountain climber's spike with a snap ring attached above the tree.
That is, Kondo-san, as soon as night struck, attached ropes to the snap ring.
He hooked one end to a tree,
and left the other at the cliff to use as a safety net.
Then he waited for the other men to arrive to use them as witnesses,
and ordered Hirai-san to fix the fence.
After we left, Kondo-san...
ran out the back door and ran to the observation deck.
Since the usual path to the observation deck is long and winding, taking a straight cut through the mountains will get you there faster.
After finding Hirai-san, Kondo-san knocked him out,
placed his body in a tree...
...and waited for us at the edge of the platform.
Finally, he jumps down using the safety rope.
Then Kondo-san, hanging on the safety rope.
grabs the rope attached to the tree,
unhooks the safety rope by throwing it down,
and descends the tree.
And getting rid of the second rope the same way, he throws Hirai-san off the tree.
Stop this absurdity...
Stop this absurdity!
It's all your imagination!
There is no proof!
"Knocked him out and threw him off the tree"?!
Complete nonsense!
If there is evidence, show it!
The white-eye nest.
You know there's a white-eye nest in that tree, don't you?
Well, so what?
You see, the white-eye nest is usually attached to the grass or branch by cobwebs.
This web is attached to the right side of Hirai-san's body.
Indeed, there is a cobweb there.
Even so, what have I got to do with it?
Show me proof that it was me who did it!
There are also marks on that tree...
from climbing shoes.
Modern mountaineering boots don't require spikes on the soles to prevent slipping.
Kondo-san,
you've been using these boots since your college days, right? What do you think?
You don't happen to have spikes on your soles, do you?
Damn...
That Hirai...
From the very beginning, he's been illegally selling plants from the mountain to students.
The dead employee and I told him we'd find evidence, so we watched him.
And then one night...
we caught him in the act.
But...
While I was arguing with him,
my hand...
bumped into her body.
She fell off a cliff.
From then on, he kept blackmailing me.
I couldn't take it anymore...
But,
maybe it's for the best.
Now I can finally...
answer for what I did to her.
Is Dad still awake?
Looks like it.
Dad, what happened?
Let me see.
Hey, wait!
Uh... well...
What were you looking at?!
Dad!
It was an accident.
You looked through binoculars, what kind of "accident"?!
I told you, it was an accident.
And if Conan-kun was wondering, then what?!
Accidentally! I'm telling you!
You old pervert!
Hey! All kidding aside!
What would mom say about this?
Hey... Don't tell Eri...
I don't know...
Well, wait a minute!
What should I wait for?
Please, Ran-chan!
What did you see there, uncle?