The rhythm of the wind clears reasoning.
Alibi tricks are always uncovered!
The sun shines brightly and warmly like it knows no limits.
It can also nurture a surprising case!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
From what you said on the phone last night, I think I understand the situation, but...
Is Seizan-sensei really in that much of a slump?
Yeah, he hasn't drawn a single thing in the past three months.
Why is that?
Of course, he is a 70-year-old man, but...
Apparently, he can't picture things clearly.
The stress got to him, and as a result his hands have started shaking.
Kuroki Jirou (28)
Seozam's Apprentice
That must be hard to bear...
Lately, he refuses to eat much and gets really moody.
Sometimes he'll get really agitated, and other times, he'll refuse to speak a word.
And now he wants to commit suicide?
Yeah.
PLACE EXPOSED TO THE SUN
I brought you out here today because...
I thought it might cheer Sensei up a little bit.
Sorry to bother you when you're so busy.
It's not a problem—I'm always happy to help one of my old drinking buddies!
When he heard that an inn with hot springs and alcohol were prepared...
He just couldn't refuse—right, Ran-neechan?
Yep!
What was that?
But Sensei sure is lucky...
To have a student as thoughtful as you.
It's all thanks to him that I can accomplish so much.
A nightingale!
They live in the bamboo forest around here.
It's coming from over here!
Huh?
That person is...
Seizan-sensei!
How delightful we are, to meet friends from afar!
You said you came to visit on a whim?
When I saw the station I was at, your image suddenly popped out of my head, so here I am.
I'm glad to see you are well.
Hayakawa Seizan (70)
Japanese Artist
I guess you could say I'm as lively as ever.
I was just about to sketch the bamboos here.
He doesn't appear to be on the verge of suicide at all...
Don't you get it?
He's putting up an act so he doesn't look bad in front of others.
An act, huh...
Did you see that?
That's what's called a "nightingale's echoing song."
Actually, they chirp like that when they're distressed.
Sorry...
We'll be gone soon, so please forgive us.
This place is special to the nightingales, and must be cared for.
Well then...
Let's depart, so as not to disturb them any longer.
Yamamoto Noriko (35)
Hayakawa Family Maid
Welcome back, Seizan-sensei!
We have visitors...
Could you prepare something to eat?
Right away.
Who is she?
She's Seizan-sensei's housekeeper, Yamamoto Noriko-san.
Oh, is that so?
Mom!
Hey, look at this—it's good, isn't it?
Keiichi!
Noriko!
I'm truly sorry!
My mother can't look after him because she came down with a fever, so I...
No excuses!
I thought I told you never to bring kids here!
Yes, sir...
But it's just for today...
Absolutely not.
Send him home immediately.
Never let me see his face again!
Mom...
Take him home, now!
Understood?
By the way, is that a new piece?
It's a wonderful drawing of Mt Fuji!
That's a drawing I did recently at a client's request.
Say, Kuroki-san, do you draw?
It's been a long time since you became Sensei's apprentice, right?
I saw some of his work before, it was quite impressive.
Unlike Seizan-sensei's, it was very colorful, ight?
Yes, they're chromatic paintings.
By the way, isn't that art competition that you're presiding over starting soon?
You're certainly well informed...
The deadline for it is the day after tomorrow.
Kuroki-san, why don't you enter too?
From what I've seen, I'm sure you'll do well.
Right, Sensei?
You'd better not.
If you do, people will mock me, your teacher, Hayakawa Seizan.
Kuroki isn't skilled enough to participate yet.
Uhm, but, Sensei...
It's as he says, Mouri-san.
I still lack practice...
That's it, Ran-san...
Could you model for me?
So that lean practice...
Yeah...
Kuroki-san, wait a minute...
Sensei—can you draw her, Sensei?
Mouri-san!
When you were in Tokyo, you used to draw something for us on the fly, right?
Well, tonight is a bit...
Please stop, Mouri-san!
He's been drinking!
He would always draw while drunk before.
Please, Sensei!
I'm begging you!
It's no good!
My apologies!
I wasn't thinking straight!
No, I haven't been able to take in alcohol like I used to be.
Sensei, how about we go fishing tomorrow?
Mouri-san's group can come too.
That sounds great!
I'd be honored if you would join us, Sensei.
Fishing, huh?
I haven't gone in quite a while...
Will the rain be a problem?
The forecast said that it should let up early in the morning.
Excuse me, I'll be going to bed for the night.
Have a good night, Sensei.
Yeah, good night.
Dad, how could you be so rude to him?
Mouri-san!
Don't think badly of me, Kuroki-san.
I wanted to test his drawing abilities to see if you were really right about him, so I put up an act.
Is that so...
So this is where you work, Kuroki-san?
This one's cute!
Did you make it, Kuroki-san?
It's not finished, you see...
The colors are really pretty.
I use these powder paints to make my colors.
This white one is called "whitewash, right?
You know a lot!
The powder is made from crushing oyster shells to tiny pieces.
Oysters?
"Nightingale's echoing song," right?
Good morning!
Oh, Yamamoto-san.
What's wrong?
You look pale.
I didn't get much sleep because I was caring for my mother.
I'm off to get a doctor to examine her.
Mouri-san!
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Sensei hasn't woken up yet, so go ahead to the pier without us.
Is that so?
All right.
Seizan-sensei is not joining us?
Yeah, it seems like he's relaxing in the house right now.
Sensei, I'm giving the phone to Mouri-san now, so...
Yes.
Sorry, I'll have to pass for today.
Are you all right, Sensei?
Should we come check—
Then, I'll see you later!
Yes.
And look forward to our big catches.
It's best to leave him alone for now.
An octopus!
Cool!
A fish!
All right!
An old boot...
That's no good.
Yes, this is Kuroki.
Sensei did!?
A note...
Yes...
"I can't draw anymore."
"I'm sorry for relying on you—thank you."
Are you there!?
Come back right away!
It seems t at a suicide note was found when the maid went to clean.
Contact the police right away and have them search the nearby area!
Did you hearthat, Yamamoto-san?
We'll be there as soon as we can!
Seizan-sensei!
Is it suicide?
You are?
Mouri Kogorou, a private detective.
That famous one?
My name is Daimatsu from the precinct.
Since a note was found, this is almost certainly a suicide.
He probably tied the rope to the bamboo and jumped from the rock to strangle himself.
The estimated time of death is from 11:00 to 1:00.
Just about the time we were fishing, he tied the rope to the bamboo...
Hey, why are these other bamboo poles cut down?
Since there's no water in them...
They were probably cut this morning, after the rain stopped.
What about it?
Go play somewhere else.
It's way too soon to call this suicide!
So this is Seizan-sensei's atelier...
Seizan-sensei...
IHtmust have been trying to draw it rightth iswhole time.
Bamboo journal?
April 10th (Sunny), bamboo sprout grew 30 cm
April 11th (Sunny), bamboo sprout grew 60 cm - incredibly fast
April 12th (Sunny), the sprout grew 2 meters probably due to the rain last night - bamboos do shoot up after a rain
He's been documenting the growth of the bamboo...
I see...
If it's like this, then maybe...
Hey, Uncle!
There are expensive paintings here, so quit scampering about.
Look at this!
A sketch of Ran...
What about it?
Well, you know...
What?
I see...
I was just about to say the same thing.
Mouri-san.
I've taken their statements, so I was just about to report to the station.
Wait, please...
Don't you think it's too soon to call this a suicide?
What do you mean?
Last night, Sensei said...
This place is special to the nightingales, and must be cared for.
Do you think that a man like that would kill himself in that forest?
One more thing...
Last night, after dinner, he went to his room to continue drawing.
He probably intended to give this to us as a present when we leave.
I don't think someone like that would commit suicide.
Then, you're saying...
This was a murder disguised as a suicide.
The so-called "nightingale's echoing song" is because they are alerted by intruders.
Yamamoto-san!
This morning, heard the nightingales chirp right before seeing you.
You then rushed by, looking rather pale.
You wouldn't happen to have been in the forest during that time, would you?
You're wrong!
That's...
Conan-kun!
However, the time of death was between 11:00 AM and 1:00 PM.
She has an alibi for that time.
What?
I was at the hospital.
I heard it was a great hospital, so I took my mother there.
Oh, really...
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
Kuroki-san's painting is finished.
I bet he worked on it all last night.
Ran-neechan, Uncle asked for you to bring him this sketchbook and the painting.
When?
Right away!
Is that so...
She was always with her mother...
I understand.
It seems that your alibi has held up.
In that case, I guess Sensei really did commit suicide...
Well, I'll take my leave.
Daimatsu-san, please wait a moment.
Seizan-sensei...
Didn't commit suicide.
The culprit tried to disguise it as suicide, but it was actually murder.
The motive lies in this picture brought by Ran.
Kuroki-san, you planned to enter tomorrow's contest with this painting, didn't you?
However, Sensei would never allow this...
So you thought of a way to murder him.
Mouri-san...
What are you saying all of a sudden?
You said that Sensei was in a slump due to his inability to draw.
In order to cheer him up, you called me here.
However, that was a lie.
Sensei wasn't really depressed, nor did he have a reason to commit suicide.
But his hands would shake...
Yeah, that may be true...
But, the drawing of Mt Fuji in the guest room...
How would you explain that?
He said that he had drawn it recently.
Most likely, by following his rough sketch...
Kuroki-san...
You're the one who finished the picture.
That's not all.
All of his works from the past few years...
They're really your drawings, aren't they?
No way...
That's w y the idea of entering the contest and standing on your own two feet...
Are pretty detrimental to Sensei.
Last night, you suddenly asked Ran to be your model in order to induce me.
You knew that dad would take the opportunity to find out whether or not Seizan-sensei really couldn't draw.
That's right.
After seeing his condition...
Kuroki-san, I believed what you said...
And thought it wouldn't be strange if he did commit suicide.
By the way, Kuroki-san...
Early this morning, you brought him to the clearing in the forest, didn't you?
That's wrong—you talked to him yourself while he was on the phone, remember?
That was just a simple trick.
All you had to do was obtain a recording of his voice beforehand and set it to play as his answering machine.
But, like I said before...
I have an alibi!
What, that you were out with us on the sea?
Ran, show Daimatsu-san the sketchbook that I had Conan give you.
Here you go.
The bamboo in this forest actually grows a lot faster than I first thought.
It's true.
Can you tell us how much it grew on the third day?
Around two meters.
That's amazing!
The bamboo shoot began to sprout from yesterday's rain, and when the temperature rose it grew extraordinarily fast.
Kuroki-san...
You used that fact to murder Sensei.
Early this morning...
You gave Sensei sleeping pills and carried him into the clearing.
Then, you sat Sensei in front of the bamboo shoot that you chose, and tied a rope around his neck.
You then cut away all the surrounding plants.
That way, the bamboo that you tied to the rope would get a lot of sunlight.
This morning, we heard the nightingales chirping.
That, Kuroki-san, was because they were alerted by your presence.
When the sun came out, the bamboo continued to grow...
And eventually strangled Seizan-sensei.
This explains how you were able to kill Sensei while fishing with us.
The white stuff on your feet is the proof.
Isn't this just whitewash?
It doesn't prove anything...
No...
That isn't whitewash.
Look carefully...
It's the remnants left from the bamboo that you cut down...
In other words, sawdust.
I'm truly sorry.
It's all as you said.
I've been behind all of Sensei's drawings for the past few years, as per his order.
But...
I wanted to receive the credit for my own works instead of him...
Even if it was only once.
I wanted them to bask in the sun.
I wanted someone to acknowledge me.
So I...
All right, it's done!
Really?
Let me see!
Ta-da!
What's that supposed to be?
Idiot, don't you know anything about modern art?
How can you call that modern art? It's just a child's doodle.
What!?
I bet Conan-kun is way better...
Right, Conan-kun?
Don't compare me to a brat like him!
But it's the truth.
You just don't understand sophisticated taste in art!
I'm glad I don't.