With the rhythm of the wind, deductions become clear.
Figuring out the alibi trick!
Pro-wrestling and its masks.
Let's unmask the case at hand!
Recognizing that one truth,
A child with the mind of an adult,
His name is Detective Conan!
Touto Sudo Stadium
All right, let's have the Great Detective Mouri Kogoro-san answer this for us!
In the Teito pro wrestling match occurring right now, the masked man, Wolf-Face...
Out of these five, which one is he?
Well? Well?
Number three, I suppose?
Success, success, a resounding success!
As expected of Sleeping Kogoro, an outstanding deduction!
If you showed that to a real panel, they'd figure it out too.
THE SULLIED MASKED HERO
(Part 1)
Geez...
I took on this job because it paid well, but...
What a joke it turned out to be.
Why?
Right now, these types of hand-to-hand combat sports are really popular with young kids!
Even the guys in our karate club are joking around and discussing moves from pro wrestling!
Hey, hey...
Especially that one move!
The one-blow show-stopper...
Huh?
What was it called again?
No matter what they try to play themselves off as, it's still just a show put on to fool kids...
Three!
All right!
Hey, Ran...
When will the wolf mask guy from earlier come out?
He's gotta be strong, right?
Wolf-Face's match is the title match for the junior heavyweights, so as the main event, it's last!
Then, this guy's the champion?
That's right!
Ever since he announced during his debut that he'd take his mask off if he loses, he hasn't lost once in 65 matches!
But still, I kind of want to see him lose...
Why's that?
Because, if he loses, we can see what his face looks like!
Deliberately hiding his face with a mask...
I bet he's a super ugly guy, or he's balding...
Sorry for being such an ugly guy...
But, as far as balding, that's not the case, is it?
Then, could it be...
You...
Oogami Takaharu (27)
Pro Wrestler (Wolf-Face)
This is the true face behind the wolf mask.
But, is this all right?
Coming out here without your mask on...
It's all right!
Wolf-Face's identity is supposed to be that of a Mexican.
Plus, sometimes I compete in the opening matches like this.
As a result, everyone just thinks I'm a normal young wrestler.
Well, since I can't use Wolf-Face's moves, I'm more of a mediocre young wrestler.
Then, no one knows that you're...
Right.
No one but those affiliated with Teito Pro Wrestling know.
Of course, not even my parents or girlfriend do.
Because I originally debuted in Mexico as the Mysterious Masked Wrestler.
But it's not like you have a face that needs to be hidden...
I like it!
A masked man!
I've admired them ever since I was a kid...
Uhm...
Isn't it difficult to bear?
Deceiving everyone and hiding your identity...
I think your girlfriend would want you to tell her the truth as well.
If only Conan-kun were Shin'ichi...
I just told you, right?
That my identity as Wolf-Face is a secret to all those not affiliated with Teito Pro Wrestling.
If I don't tell her and my identity were to be leaked...
She's not one I would have to suspect, right?
But...
Not to mention, I don't want her to worry.
Wolf-Face's matches are broadcast during Golden Time.
There are times when the match turns intense, with more than enough injuries.
Well, I'm standing by my decision.
My identity will be revealed when I'm defeated, and sinking down into the mat...
When Wolf-Face dies, and leaves the ring.
But then, why did you reveal yourself to us?
Oh, well...
Actually, the girlfriend I mentioned is a big fan of Sleeping Kogoro.
I thought that if I were just an ordinary, young wrestler, I wouldn't be able to get your autograph...
If that's it, you could have asked me earlier, when you were wearing your mask...
That's true, except Wolf-Face can't talk to Japanese people without an interpreter.
I couldn't get something like an autograph addressed to a Japanese woman.
Plus, I thought that Mouri-san and company wouldn't be the type to leak my identity...
And shatter the dreams of the children out there.
Well, I suppose...
Oogami-san, it's about that time...
Then, my girlfriend's name is inside there, so if you could please sign it for me.
All right.
Identity only revealed upon death, huh?
Nagase-san!
Nagase-kun!
Please turn this way!
At last, you are to challenge the invincible Wolf-Face for his championship belt!
How do you feel?
How do I feel...
I only want to the audience to see...
My all-out fight...
And, after having been defeated by me and
getting his sheep's clothing peeled off...
Nagase Hyouta (25)
Pro Wrestler
That Japanese wolf's stupid face.
Japanese wolf?
Wolf-Face is Japanese?
Whoops.
Just a joke, a joke!
He's in a hurry, so let's have the interview later, huh?
Japanese Team Locker Room
Hey, Nagase!
What the hell was that?
Ushigome Iwao (36)
Pro Wrestler
You've been told, right?
Wolf-Face's identity is top-secret!
And that it's forbidden to leak it to anyone!
You know, right?
That right now, it's being said that Oogami is responsible for half of Teito Pro Wrestling's popularity!
Then, what is it, Ushigome-san?
I've been working myself to death, refining my techniques...
To amass my power and fame and get to the top for the first time, and become a participant in the main event...
Do you mean to tell me to lose the match on that sunny stage on purpose?
It's true that Oogami won't be able to take over your face...
But with your strength as it is now, there's no way you could triumph over him...
What are you talking about?
Wrestlers are nothing without their faces.
If it weren't for that, with your strength...
You'd be an especially popular wrestler, wouldn't you?
Hey, Nagase!
Sakuma Hiroyuki (25)
Pro Wrestler
You're speaking to your senior!
Oh now.
Do you intend to injure this precious body before the^match?
Well then...
I'm going to be in a separate room warming up as usual, so please call me when it's time for the match.
Well, after I win, I'll give all of you masks as a present.
So that you can hide your homely faces with it and become popular.
Right, there's no problem.
It's over 200% certain that I will win.
It's been kept a secret, but his left knee hasn't completely healed yet.
If I aim there, it should hinder his movement.
If, by some chance, it looks like I'm going to lose, it'll still be all right.
If I tear off his mask on the mat, it'll be over.
It'll go off without a hitch.
I had a youngster wear the mask and practiced it many times over...
A way to easily tear off his mask during the match.
Once his identity is revealed, the match will be called off, and I'll probably be fired, but...
Teito Pro Wrestlers' popularity will be halved.
And then, I'll be known as the unlucky wrestler who accidentally exposed Wolf-Face's identity...
Got fired from Teito Pro Wrestlers, and is then left with no place to go.
At that time, I'll be counting on you...
Worldwide Pro Wrestlers.
As expected from the boss of the Teito Pro Wrestlers!
At last, Wolf-Face is up next!
I'm gonna go to the restroom real quick!
Hurry up or the match will start first!
Let's see, restroom, restroom...
Oogami-san?
Awesome...
He's like a different person compared to earlier.
Hey, Wolf.
Leonardo Rossi (30)
Pro Wrestler (Nega Wolf)
Good luck.
Damn, I've gotta find the restroom quick, or...
Hey, kid!
It's authorized personnel only from here onward!
It's all right, isn't it?
I just want to go to that restroom...
No, you can't.
The public restroom is on the second floor...
Hey, Nagase!
What are you doing?
The match is about to start!
Hey, Nagase!
Hey!
What's going on, Sakuma?
Kiba-san...
What's wrong with Nagase?
Well, Nagase's not coming out of the waiting room.
I met with everyone earlier and they all said they didn't want to be associated with agase and be his 2nd, so...
With no choice, I decided to do t, and came to call Nagase, but...
Then why don't you hurry up, drag him out of the room, and stand him up in the ring?
But he...
If you just go in without permission, he'll get angry that his concentration was broken...
Half-asleep mutterings from a newborn that has only just gotten started...
Hey, Nagase!
Hurry up and get out there!
Nagase!
Hey, hang in there!
It's no use.
He doesn't have a pulse anymore.
What?
At any rate, hurry up and call an ambulance and the police here!
Yes, sir!
Damn, who the hell did this?
Don't you hear some sort of strange noise?
What?
It's a strange noise...
It's from inside this bag!
A hidden camera?
Could it be that the culprit is on...
Wolf! Wolf! Wolf! Wolf! Wolf!
Wolf! Wolf! Wolf! Wolf!
Wolf! Wolf! Wolf!
We apologize for the prolonged delay.
Due to unforeseen circumstances, the challenger for the Junior Heavyweight title match...
Nagase Hyouta, is now unable to make an appearance.
Therefore, the scheduled title match with Wolf-Face has been canceled.
What!?
No way!
The deceased is Nagase Hyouta-san, 25 years of age.
Under contract with the Teito Pro Wrestlers...
A pro wrestler, huh?
He was a popular wrestler who recently had been rising through the ranks in a flashy manner.
It appears to be a stabbing death?
Yes, sir.
He was stabbed in approximately three places: the lungs, the chest, and the abdomen...
It appears that the last stab, the one to the chest, served as the fatal blow.
How do you know that the chest was stabbed last?
Oh, well...
It was recorded that way on the video
I saw before you came here, Inspector...
Video?
A surveillance camera, or something of the sort?
No, it was a hidden camera set up in this room by Nichiuri TV, who holds the right to televise Teito Pro Wrestlers.
In order to secretly record Nagase's expression before he went into the title match.
Since, when we have matches at Touto Sumo Stadium, Nagase always warms up by himself in this room.
Then, could you please show the video tape to me as well?
Here it is.
If that's the case, it'd just be a matter of course for the case to be resolved...
The culprit is recorded on this tape, right?
Well...
A wolf man!
What—a wolf mask?
It's Wolf-Face!
He's a popular masked wrestler right now.
Senshu is a suffix that represents a player on a team or in a game.
He's the junior heavyweight champion, and was scheduled defend his title in a match against Nagase-senshu tonight.
Well, Wolf-Face had announced that he'd only reveal his identity upon his defeat, so...
It's also a fight where he's putting his mask on the line.
In short, that masked wrestler, in order to protect both his title and his identity...
Murdered Nagase-senshu before the match without realizing the hidden camera was there?
No...
That's not necessarily the case!
Those who knew there was a hidden camera set up in this room...
Seemed to be most of the Teito Pro Wrestlers personnel other than Nagase-senshu.
And if they put that wolf mask on, anyone could have become Wolf-Face, couldn't they?
Conan-kun?
So that means that the culprit could be Wolf-Face himself, or...
Perhaps it was a pro wrestler with a physique similar to his who wanted to pin the crime on him, right?
A pro wrestler with a similar physique...
Because, the culprit recorded in the video was about the same height as Nagase-senshu!
Wolf-Face and Nagase-senshu were about the same height, right?
Yeah.
Plus, this room is off-limits except to authorized personnel!
Only a pro wrestler could have stabbed another pro wrestler to death here!
Also, I found the knife that was used, as well as the culprit's gloves and jersey in the nearby restroom.
I've already handed them over to the forensics officers, so don't worry!
Is that so?
Then, Kiba-san.
Please call over that masked wrestler, and pro wrestlers that are similar in physique to him.
But, Conan-kun...
Why are you here?
I was going to the restroom, you know?
And then there was a big commotion about how Nagase-senshu wasn't coming out of his room...
So I came to check out the situation.
No, not that...
Just who was it that brought you here to this pro wrestling arena?
It was this Great Detective Mouri Kogoro, Inspector.
I thought so, you God of Death.
Well then, please let me take a look as well.
At that video tape that I hear recorded the state of the matter at the time of the crime.
Oh, it's you, huh...
This is it, then?
When the culprit entered the room?
Hey, hey, I don't have anything to talk with you about before the match.
Or is it that you want to ask me to lose to you on purpose?
Oh, the screen shook just now...
I think the culprit's foot probably brushed against the bag the camera was hidden in.
I thought I'd already told you.
I want you to hold nothing back tonight.
There, he's already holding the knife!
You...
First, he stabbed him in the back...
What are you...
And then, when the victim turned around, another stab to his abdomen.
Hey, doesn't the victim appear to be attempting to say something?
Yes, but his mouth is covered by the culprit, so he can't say anything...
Oh, he's grabbing the mask with his hand!
Speaking of that, the bloody mask I found in the restroom...
It was ripped about ten centimeters down from the right eye.
Then, perhaps the culprit's face is...
And then the fatal blow to the chest...
Damn, if only the culprit would turn this way...
But why does he keep glancing around like that?
He might be looking for something, or...
All right!
Stand up just like that!
If he does that, his face will be visible through the ripped eye!
What the...
Only the unripped left side of the face...
And then, just like that, he leaves the room...
But, if a man who was bloodie'd to that extent were loitering around, someone would have seen him...
Oh, yes!
hear a young wrestler saw a man with blood on his jersey in front of the restroom, but...
He went into the bathroom with a towel covering his head, so...
The young wrestler assumed it must've been a senior wrestler that had participated in a bloody opening bout...
And didn't take special notice of him.
I see.
So if he hid a spare jersey in the restroom beforehand...
He could change into it and then leisurely stroll out of the restroom.
So, the estimated time of death?
An official time of death is not available yet, but...
I think it was probably during Kiba-san's match.
Three minutes after the culprit left, Kiba-san's roar from when he won...
There, we should hear it soon!
Looks like it...
So that means, the time of the crime was...
Approximately 7:20, I suppose.
All right.
I've brought them here, Inspector.
The four people who are similar in physique to Nagase.
Well then...
When you figure out the culprit, please let me know first.
That's a promise, isn't it?
Inspector.
I understand.
Oh, he's coming out!
Kiba-san, is it true that Nagase-senshu has been killed?
Are the four that just entered suspects?
Please answer us, Kiba-san!
Kiba-san!
The cold shoulder, huh?
But this might be the end for Teito Pro Wrestlers...
Yeah.
Well then, starting from the right...
Please tell us your name and where you were at approximately 7:20.
From the circumstances, the culprit should be one of these four people.
Which is it?
Which one of these four murdered Nagase-san?