Touto Sudo Stadium
All right, let's have the Great Detective Mouri Kogorou-san answer this for us!
In the Teito pro wrestling match occurring right now, the masked man, Wolf-Face...
Out of these five, which one is he?
Well? Well?
Number three, I suppose?
Success, success, a resounding success!
As expected of Sleeping Kogorou, an outstanding deduction!
If you showed that to a real panel, they'd figure it out too.
THE SULLIED MASKED HERO
Geez...
I took on this job because it paid well, but...
What a joke it turned out to be.
Why?
Right now, these types of hand-to-hand combat sports are really popular with young kids!
Even the guys in our karate club are joking around and discussing moves from pro wrestling!
Hey, hey...
Especially that one move!
The one-blow show-stopper...
Huh?
What was it called again?
No matter what they try to play themselves off as, it's still just a show put on to fool kids...
Three!
All right!
Hey, Ran...
When will the wolf mask guy from earlier come out?
He's gotta be strong, right?
Wolf-Face's match is the title match for the junior heavyweights, so as the main event, it's last!
Then, this guy's the champion?
That's right!
Ever since he announced during his debutthat he'd take his mask off if he loses, he hasn't lost once in 65 matches!
But still, I kind of want to see him lose...
Why's that?
Because, if he loses, we can see what his face looks like!
Deliberately hiding his face with a mask...
I bet he's a super ugly guy, or he's balding...
Sorry for being such an ugly guy...
But, as far as balding, that's not the case, is it?
Then, could it be...
You...
Oogami Takaharu (27)
Pro Wrestler (Wolf-Face)
This is the true face behind the wolf mask.
But, is this all right?
Coming out here without your mask on...
It's all right!
Wolf-Face's identity is supposed to be that of a Mexican.
Plus, sometimes I compete in the opening matches like this.
As a result, everyone just thinks I'm a normal young wrestler.
Well, since I can't use Wolf-Face's moves, I'm more of a mediocre young wrestler.
Then, no one knows that you're...
Right.
No one but those affiliated with Teito Pro Wrestling know.
Of course, not even my parents or girlfriend do.
Because I originally debuted in Mexico as the Mysterious Masked Wrestler.
But it's not like you have a face that needs to be hidden...
I like it!
A masked man!
I've admired them ever since I was a kid...
Uhm...
Isn't it difficult to bear?
Deceiving everyone and hiding your identity...
I think your girlfriend would want you to tell her the truth as well.
If only Conan-kun were Shinichi...
I just told you, right?
That my identity as Wolf-Face is a secret to all those not affiliated with Teito Pro Wrestling.
If I don't tell her and my identity were to be leaked...
She's not one I would have to suspect, right?
But...
Not to mention, I don't want her to worry.
Wolf-Face's matches are broadcast during Golden Time.
There are times when the match turns intense, with more than enough injuries.
Well, I'm standing by my decision.
My identity will be revealed when I'm defeated, and sinking down into the mat...
When Wolf-Face dies, and leaves the ring.
But then, why did you reveal yourself to us?
Oh, well...
Actually, the girlfriend I mentioned is a big fan of Sleeping Kogorou.
I thought that if I were just an ordinary, young wrestler, I wouldn't be able to get your autograph...
If that's it, you could have asked me earlier, when you were wearing your mask...
That's true, except Wolf-Face can't talk to Japanese people without an interpreter.
I couldn't get something like an autograph addressed to a Japanese woman.
Plus, I thought that Mouri-san and company wouldn't be the type to leak my identity...
And shatter the dreams of the children out there.
Well, I suppose...
Oogami-san, it's about that time...
Then, my girlfriend's name is inside there, so if you could please sign it for me.
All right.
Identity only revealed upon death, huh?
Nagase-san!
Nagase-kun!
Please turn this way!
At last, you are to challenge the invincible Wolf-Face for his championship belt!
How do you feel?
How do I feel...
I only want to the audience to see...
My all-out fight...
And, after having been defeated by me and
getting his sheep's clothing peeled off...
Nagase Hyouta (25)
Pro Wrestler
That Japanese wolf's stupid face.
Japanese wolf?
Wolf-Face is Japanese?
Whoops.
Just a joke, a joke!
He's in a hurry, so let's have the interview later, huh?
Japanese Team Locker Room
Hey, Nagase!
What the hell was that?
Ushigome Iwao (36)
Pro Wrestler
You've been told, right?
Wolf-Face's identity is top-secret!
And that it's forbidden to leak it to anyone!
You know, right?
That right now, it's being said that Oogami is responsible for half of Teito Pro Wrestling's popularity!
Then, what is it, Ushigome-san?
I've been working myself to death, refining my techniques...
To amass my power and fame and get to the top for the first time, and become a participant in the main event...
Do you mean to tell me to lose the match on that sunny stage on purpose?
It's true that Oogami won't be able to take over your face...
But with your strength as it is now, there's no way you could triumph over him...
What are you talking about?
Wrestlers are nothing without their faces.
If it weren't for that, with your strength...
You'd be an especially popular wrestler, wouldn't you?
Hey, Nagase!
Sakuma Hiroyuki (25)
Pro Wrestler
You're speaking to your senior!
Oh now.
Do you intend to injure this precious body before the^match?
Well then...
I'm going to be in a separate room warming up as usual, so please call me when it's time for the match.
Well, after I win, I'll give all of you masks as a present.
So that you can hide your homely faces with it and become popular.
Right, there's no problem.
It's over 200% certain that I will win.
It's been kept a secret, but his left knee hasn't completely healed yet.
If I aim there, it should hinder his movement.
If, by some chance, it looks like I'm going to lose, it'll still be all right.
If I tear off his mask on the mat, it'll be over.
It'll go off without a hitch.
I had a youngster wear the mask and practiced it many times over...
A way to easily tear off his mask during the match.
Once his identity is revealed, the match will be called off, and I'll probably be fired, but...
Teito Pro Wrestlers' popularity will be halved.
And then, I'll be known as the unlucky wrestler who accidentally exposed Wolf-Face's identity...
Got fired from Teito Pro Wrestlers, and is then left with no place to go.
At that time, I'll be counting on you...
Worldwide Pro Wrestlers.
As expected from the boss of the Teito Pro Wrestlers!
At last, Wolf-Face is up next!
I'm gonna go to the restroom real quick!
Hurry up or the match will start first!
Let's see, restroom, restroom...
Oogami-san?
Awesome...
He's like a different person compared to earlier.
Hey, Wolf.
Leonardo Rossi (30)
Pro Wrestler (Nega Wolf)
Good luck.
Damn, I've gotta find the restroom quick, or...
Hey, kid!
It's authorized personnel only from here onward!
It's all right, isn't it?
I just want to go to that restroom...
No, you can't.
The public restroom is on the second floor...
Hey, Nagase!
What are you doing?
The match is about to start!
Hey, Nagase!
Hey!
What's going on, Sakuma?
Kiba-san...
What's wrong with Nagase?
Well, Nagase's not coming out of the waiting room.
I met with everyone earlier and they all said they didn't want to be associated with agase and be his 2nd, so...
With no choice, I decided to do t, and came to call Nagase, but...
Then why don't you hurry up, drag him out of the room, and stand him up in the ring?
But he...
If you just go in without permission, he'll get angry that his concentration was broken...
Half-asleep mutterings from a newborn that has only just gotten started...
Hey, Nagase!
Hurry up and get out there!
Nagase!
Hey, hang in there!
It's no use.
He doesn't have a pulse anymore.
What?
At any rate, hurry up and call an ambulance and the police here!
Yes, sir!
Damn, who the hell did this?
Don't you hear some sort of strange noise?
What?
It's a strange noise...
It's from inside this bag!
A hidden camera?
Could it be that the culprit is on...
Wolf! Wolf! Wolf! Wolf! Wolf!
Wolf! Wolf! Wolf! Wolf!
Wolf! Wolf! Wolf!
We apologize for the prolonged delay.
Due to unforeseen circumstances, the challenger for the Junior Heavyweight title match...
Nagase Hyouta, is now unable to make an appearance.
Therefore, the scheduled title match with Wolf-Face has been cancelled.
What!?
No way!
The deceased is Nagase Hyouta-san, 25 years of age.
Under contract with the Teito Pro Wrestlers...
A pro wrestler, huh?
He was a popular wrestler who recently had been rising through the ranks in a flashy manner.
It appears to be a stabbing death?
Yes, sir.
He was stabbed in approximately three places: the lungs, the chest, and the abdomen...
It appears that the last stab, the one to the chest, served as the fatal blow.
How do you know that the chest was stabbed last?
Oh, well...
It was recorded that way on the video
I saw before you came here, Inspector...
Video?
A surveillance camera, or something of the sort?
No, it was a hidden camera set up in th s room by Nichiuri TV, who holds the right to televise Teito Pro Wrestlers.
In order to secretly record Nagase's expression before he went into the title match.
Since, when we have matches at Touto Sumo Stadium, Nagase always warms up by himself in this room.
Then, could you please show the video tape to me as well?
Here it is.
If that's the case, it'd just be a matter of course for the case to be resolved...
The culprit is recorded on this tape, right?
Well...
A wolfman!
What—a wolf mask?
It's Wolf-Face!
He's a popular masked wrestler right now.
Senshu is a suffix that represents a player on a team or in a game.
He's the junior heavyweight champion, and was scheduled defend his title in a match against Nagase-senshu tonight.
Well, Wolf-Face had announced that he'd only reveal his identity upon his defeat, so...
It's also a fight where he's putting his mask on the line.
In short, that masked wrestler, in order to protect both his title and his identity...
Murdered Nagase-senshu before the match without realizing the hidden camera was there?
No...
That's not necessarily the case!
Those who knew there was a hidden camera set up in this room...
Seemed to be most of the Teito Pro Wrestlers personnel other than Nagase-senshu.
And if they put that wolf mask on, anyone could have become Wolf-Face, couldn't they?
Conan-kun?
So that means that the culprit could be Wolf-Face himself, or...
Perhaps it was a pro wrestler with a physique similar to his who wanted to pin the crime on him, right?
A pro wrestler with a similar physique...
Because, the culprit recorded in the video was about the same height as Nagase-senshu!
Wolf-Face and Nagase-senshu were about the same height, right?
Yeah.
Plus, this room is off-limits except to authorized personnel!
Only a pro wrestler could have stabbed another pro wrestler to death here!
Also, I found the knife that was used, as well as the culprit's gloves and jersey in the nearby restroom.
I've already handed them over to the forensics officers, so don't worry!
Is that so?
Then, Kiba-san.
Please call over that masked wrestler, and pro wrestlers that are similar in physique to him.
But, Conan-kun...
Why are you here?
I was going to the restroom, you know?
And then there was a big commotion about how Nagase-senshu wasn't coming out of his room...
So I came to check out the situation.
No, not that...
Just who was it that brought you here to this pro wrestling arena?
It was this Great Detective Mouri Kogorou, Inspector.
I thought so, you God of Death.
Well then, please let me take a look as well.
At that video tape that I hear recorded the state of the matter at the time of the crime.
Oh, it's you, huh...
This is it, then?
When the culprit entered the room?
Hey, hey, I don't have anything to talk with you about before the match.
Or is it that you want to ask me to lose to you on purpose?
Oh, the screen shook just now...
I think the culprit's foot probably brushed against the bag the camera was hidden in.
I thought I'd already told you.
I want you to hold nothing back tonight.
There, he's already holding the knife!
You...
First, he stabbed him in the back...
What are you...
And then, when the victim turned around, another stab to his abdomen.
Hey, doesn't the victim appear to be attempting to say something?
Yes, but his mouth is covered by the culprit, so he can't say anything...
Oh, he's grabbing the mask with his hand!
Speaking of that, the bloody mask I found in the restroom...
It was ripped about ten centimeters down from the right eye.
Then, perhaps the culprit's face is...
And then the fatal blow to the chest...
Damn, if only the culprit would turn this way...
But why does he keep glancing around like that?
He might be looking for something, or...
All right!
Stand up just like that!
If he does that, his face will be visible through the ripped eye!
What the...
Only the unripped left side of the face...
And then, just like that, he leaves the room...
But, if a man who was bloodie'd to that extent were loitering around, someone would have seen him...
Oh, yes!
hear a young wrestler saw a man with blood on his jersey in front of the restroom, but...
He went into the bathroom with a towel covering his head, so...
The young wrestler assumed it must've been a senior wrestler that had participated in a bloody opening bout...
And didn't take special notice of him.
I see.
So if he hid a spare jersey in the restroom beforehand...
He could change into it and then leisurely stroll out of the restroom.
So, the estimated time of death?
An official time of death is not available yet, but...
I think it was probably during Kiba-san's match.
Three minutes after the culprit left, Kiba-san's roar from when he won...
There, we should hear it soon!
Looks like it...
So that means, the time of the crime was...
Approximately 7:20, I suppose.
All right.
I've brought them here, Inspector.
The four people who are similar in physique to Nagase.
Well then...
When you figure out the culprit, please let me know first.
That's a promise, isn't it?
Inspector.
I understand.
Oh, he's coming out!
Kiba-san, is it true that Nagase-senshu has been killed?
Are the four that just entered suspects?
Please answer us, Kiba-san!
Kiba-san!
The cold shoulder, huh?
But this might be the end for Teito Pro Wrestlers...
Yeah.
Well then, starting from the right...
Please tell us your name and where you were at approximately 7:20.
From the circumstances, the culprit should be one of these four people.
Which is it?
Which one of these four murdered Nagase-san?
Touto Sumo Stadium
Is it true that Nagase-senshu was injured?
Tell us!
When will the police make a statement?
Well then, starting from the right...
Please tell us your name and where you were at approximately 7:20.
Yeah...
I'm Ushigome Iwao.
Ushigome Iwao (36)
Pro Wrestler
At around 7:20, I was in the stands watching Kiba-san's match.
Kiba-san gets mad if we don't watch his matches.
Was there anyone watched it together with you?
No, I was by myself.
Well, some of the guests may have remembered me, but...
Everyone was focused on Kiba-san's match, so...
I was also watching Kiba-san's match by myself.
Sakuma Hiroyuki (25)
Pro Wrestler
My name is Sakuma Hiroyuki.
But, after Kiba-san's match...
I immediately came to this room to call Nagase.
Nagase's match was right afterwards.
Is that true?
It's true!
I heard this person's voice saying, "Nagase, hurry and come out"
But, that was after the time of the crime, wasn't it?
Well then, next.
You in the wolf mask.
If you could take your mask off and speak.
Uhm, Inspector...
He doesn't understand Japanese.
Because Wolf-Face is Mexican.
Also, taking off his mask in front of a child and young girl is a bit...
I don't mind, Sakuma.
Oogami Takaharu (27)
Pro Wrestler
Because those children already know who I am.
If I remember correctly, you're the good-looking, but super weak Oogami Takaharu...
Yep.
That's absurd!
Because, isn't it even printed in this morning's Touto Sports...
Here!
A photograph of you and Wolf side-by-side!
Oh, that's...
Sakuma here.
He often stands in for me...
In order to confuse reporters and fans that stake out the gym and stadium trying to figure out Wolf-Face's identity.
So that's how it was!
But, the mask you just removed and the mask in this photograph...
It seems they're somehow different...
That's a mealtime mask.
It's made of a thin material, with fewer embellishments, and the mouth is made larger in order to make it easier to eat.
But, I never thought Wolf-Face's identity could have been Oogami-senshu...
Is this all right?
Y-Y-You, if I remember correctly...
You disappeared from the public eye after your loss to Wolf-Face in "Mascara contra máscara''...
Leonardo Rossi (30)
Pro Wrestler (Nega Wolf)
You're Leonardo Rossi, aren't you!?
Oh, yes.
Ma-Mascara?
Mascara contra máscara...
It's an unmasking match!
The one who loses has his mask removed.
How surprising!
I thought for sure that you'd retired...
Leo had decided to retire after he lost to me, but...
He was stopped by Kiba-san, and...
Re-debuted in Japan wearing a Wolf-Face mask with the coloring changed.
After that, people started saying he looked like a shadowed wolf, and he became popular.
After Nagase, it'd been decided that e'd be the next Junior Heavyweight challenger, but...
No one expected something like this to happen...
So where were you two at around 7:20?
Since it was right before the match, I was in the foreign wrestlers' locker room doing warm-up exercises by myself.
Because all of the other foreign wrestlers were out watching Kiba-san's match.
Then, you were also watching Kiba-san's match?
Yes.
In short, all four of you have no alibis, then.
No, Inspector.
This crime could not have been committed if the culprit could not obtain Wolf-Face's mask.
Thus, the culprit is one who could come and go from the foreign wrestlers' locker room freely—one of those two.
Oh, no.
Wolf-Face's mask is packed into a bag along with the spare masks...
And hidden in the restroom that is off-limits to all but authorized personnel.
So that the mask can be put on in secret.
If it weren't for that, I'd be suspected of being Wolf-Face due to going in and out of the foreign wrestlers' locker room.
I see.
Of course, I have already handed that bag over to the forensics officers.
Damn...
If only the victim had left some sort of dying message for us...
What's wrong, Ran-neechan?
Remember, I was saying earlier that a pro wrestling move was popular in our karate club?
The name of that move is similar to "dying message".
Could that possibly be, "Diving Body Attack"?
The one Mil Mascaras does.
Oh, no...
Then...
Maybe Bruiser Brody's Flying Knee Drop, or the Funks' Spinning Toe Hold?
I think it was a Japanese wrestler's move...
If that's the case, it's definitely Mutou-san's—
Well, anyhow!
We'll investigate here some more, so...
Please standby in a separate room with Takagi here.
Hey, Ran, you too—take that brat and go outside.
Sorry, Detective Takagi.
Not your fault.
It's a wrestler from a bloody bout.
Are you all right, Kayama-san?
You almost look like a mummy.
Oh, it's you.
I'm fine, this is nothing.
Anyway, is it true?
That Nagase was stabbed?
Yeah.
Hey, Detective Takagi.
I want to ask you about two things.
Well, about the masked...
Yeah, that's right.
I heard that it's like that for everyone at first...
Masks are generally like that.
Of course, that includes Wolf-Face's.
Conan-kun, where are you going?
I just forgot something in the room.
What are you here for?
I accidentally forgot something here.
Let's see, where did I put it...
The report from forensics has come in!
Oh, is that so?
The bloodstains on the mask discovered in the restroom matched the victim's blood...
And the hair, including from the eyebrows, inside the mask all matched those from the other Wolf-Face masks.
That means the mask was not worn by anyone other than the mask's original owner, Oogami-san, huh?
And the victim's fingernails?
They checked thoroughly, but found nothing.
That's strange.
If he grabbed at the mask intending to rip it off, some of the culprit's skin should have remained on his fingernails.
Then it's as I thought.
The culprit wasn't accustomed to being a wolf...
It was that person!
At any rate, Inspector...
It's an unshakable truth that inside the mask that the culprit wore...
Only Oogami-senshu's scalp and eyebrow hair were found.
With this, it seems we can't but think of him as the culprit.
But even so...
He should also have known about the hidden camera set up by the TV station in this room where the crime took place.
Why would he do something like wearing his own mask, knowing that it would bring suspicion upon himself?
It might have been his intention to have us think that way.
Using reverse psychology, making us doubt that he would have done such a thing on purpose.
Well, if we call Oogami-senshu in here again and ask him about it, I'm sure he'll confess!
Because he doesn't seem like such a bad person!
Ah-le-le!
There's something strange about this mask!
See, look!
The rear part of the mask the culprit is wearing...
Rear, you say?
The design is different from the one Oogami-senshu was wearing earlier...
The design?
Now that you mention it, the mask from earlier had tufts of fur on the back as well, but...
The mask from this video doesn't have them...
Then, could this mask be a fake?
It may be a reproduction that they sell in the fan shops, or something...
Oh, no, not that...
That's not it!
This is, perhaps, the mask from when Wolf-Face debuted!
Oogami-san had said that even the retired masks were inside the same bag, so...
It's possible that the culprit just happened to choose the old mask...
Hey, I thought I told you to keep watch over those four suspects!
No...
Conan-kun hadn't come back, so I was asked to come and take a look by Ran-san.
So that means that the design of the mask has absolutely nothing to do with this crime, then?
Yeah, probably.
Is that so?
That's why Iwas...
What are you all...
"Ah-le-le" about?
You idiot!
The irrelevant things you notice only serve to disrupt the investigation!
Understand?
I guess you're right.
No, hold on...
Oh, that's it!
So that's how it was!
Sorry, but...
After you set this room up in a manner I describe...
Could you please bring the four suspects that are waiting in the separate room here?
Then, could it be...
All right, let's strip it off, Inspector.
The sheep's clothing from the murderous wolf who stabbed Nagase-san to death in this room.
Hey,look!
Those four people are going back in.
Which reminds me, a little while ago Mouri Kogorou also went into that room...
Could it be...
Sleeping Kogorou's Deduction Show?
There's no way I'm going to pass this chance up!
Let us record it!
There's going to be a deduction show, right?
Let us in!
Chiba!
Don't let anyone in!
Wait, Conan-kun is still inside-
What's the meaning of this, detectives?
Calling us back here...
Could it be.
You know who it is?
The culprit.
That's, well...
No, we don't know yet.
Hey, hey, you just said...
But I think we'll find out shortly.
After you four disguise yourselves as wolves as the culprit did and walk towards me.
First, Wolf-Face himself, Oogami-san.
Please put on the mask you're holding in your hands.
Can we have you do that?
Yeah.
All right, come towards me.
That's right, closer.
Even closer.
Uhm, now what should I do?
No, that's fine.
And next, Sakuma-san.
Take the mask from Oogami-san, and do the same.
Yes, sir!
Inspector...
Can you tell the difference between the two of them?
Nope, not at all.
Let us in! Let us in! Let us in! Let us in! Let us in!
Please...
Yes.
Then, finally, Ushigome-san.
Yeah.
I just wear this, and go over there, right?
Mouri-kun!
You probably have some sort of plan in mind, but...
If you don't tell us where or what to take notice of...
We won't get it at all!
Are you all right, mister?
It's you, kid.
I'm all right.
Is that all right, Detective?
Yeah.
I'd already predicted as much, but now it's perfectly clear.
Ushigome-san...
The one who murdered Nagase-san—you were the culprit.
What'd you say?
It was the same...
As the culprit in the video...
You kept glancing around!
Glancing around?
That's right.
You'll understand if you try the mask on, but...
The field of vision on wrestlers' masks is narrower than it appears.
If you're not used to wearing one...
In order to fully grasp the situation before your eyes...
You'd unconsciously survey your surroundings, and trip over things in the blind spot at your feet.
In other words...
Oogami-san, who is accustomed to wearing the Wolf-Face mask...
Leonardo-san, who wears the Nega Wolf mask...
And Sakuma-san, who often stands in for Oogami-san...
Those three are excluded from being the culprit.
The one who is not accustomed to wearing that mask...
The only one remaining is you.
Just because I was glancing around and stumbled, you want to say I'm the culprit?
If you want evidence, it's recorded.
There, in the video.
There, where Conan pointed out earlier, on the back of the mask!
It's there, right?
Something extra...
The mask strings...
There are four of them!
I see!
The culprit was wearing the thin mealtime mask stacked under thafmask!
That way, the culprit's hair wouldn't get on the inside of the blood-splattered mask.
I see.
That's why, even though the victim tore the culprit's mask with his fingers...
There was no trace of the culprit's skin on his fingernails.
Wouldn't this be that mealtime mask?
Earlier, when you fell down, it came out of your pocket!
No...
That's just something I was carrying in order to surprise some of the young people...
It's not the mask the culprit was wearing...
Butthat's strange...
Wolf-Face's mask is only black and white, but there are red splotches near the right eye!
Because the right eye of the mask you were wearing on top got ripped, the blood splatter got on here, right?
This brat...
All right, that's enough.
Well get the rest at the station.
Shut up!
Wait, Ushigome-san!
I said, shut up!
hat's right, I killed him!
That fool who betrayed us, and was going to transfer to Worldwide Pro Wrestlers!
Ushigome-san, calm down!
And that's not all!
I wanted to pin the crime on you, the unpopular young wrestler, and take the mask for myself!
So that I could become Wolf-Face!
Did you hear a strange sound just now?
That's right...
If I just wear this mask, I can be...
You can't become Wolf...
Because even if you hide yourface with a mask...
Your soot-stained nature that treats pro wrestling with contempt cannot be concealed.
Uhm...
Conan-kun!
Youngster, what the hell do you...
Stop it!
Shining Wizard!
That's it!
That was the name!
'm so glad I was finally able to remember it!
Afterward, the culprit Ushigome-san received a silent reprimand from Kiba-san...
And was taken from the white mat to the dim and gloomy prison.
But, it'll be difficult for you all from now on...
You'll be attacked endlessly by the media...
They'll say things like "Pro Wrestling Murder Organization"...
It'll be all right.
We wrestlers are tough.
We're accustomed to being hit.
Well then.
Keep up the good work!
Right.
They're a group of extremely tough men.
They'll be abletto overcome this hardship.
And, as long as Wolf-Face continues to win, his identity will probably never be revealed.
And then, Oogami-san, from the top rope...
Oogami-san?
Weren't you just talking about Wolf-Face?
Yeah, ookami!
Ookami-san!
Oh, because ookami means wolf...
Wolf-Face's identity will... probably... never be revealed?
Probably...