With the rhythm of the wind, deductions become clear.
Figuring out the alibi trick!
The crime was caught on camera!
Conan's reasoning takes off the mask.
Recognizing that one truth,
A child with the mind of an adult,
His name is Detective Conan!
Ran and I accompanied Pops on the job to go see a pro wrestling match.
The main event of the day was
the title match between Jr. heavyweight champion Wolf Face and
young ace, Hyota Nagase.
However, just before the match...
Hey, Nagase!
Hurry up and come out!
Mr. Nagase was killed in the waiting room!
Coincidentally, the scene of the crime was videotaped
T-This is!
Wolf Face!
THE SULLIED MASKED HERO
(Part 2)
Touto Sumo Stadium
Is it true that Nagase-senshu was injured?
Tell us!
When will the police make a statement?
Well then, starting from the right...
Please tell us your name and where you were at approximately 7:20.
Yeah...
I'm Ushigome Iwao.
Ushigome Iwao (36)
Pro Wrestler
At around 7:20, I was in the stands watching Kiba-san's match.
Kiba-san gets mad if we don't watch his matches.
Was there anyone watched it together with you?
No, I was by myself.
Well, some of the guests may have remembered me, but...
Everyone was focused on Kiba-san's match, so...
I was also watching Kiba-san's match by myself.
Sakuma Hiroyuki (25)
Pro Wrestler
My name is Sakuma Hiroyuki.
But, after Kiba-san's match...
I immediately came to this room to call Nagase.
Nagase's match was right afterwards.
Is that true?
It's true!
I heard this person's voice saying, "Nagase, hurry and come out"
But, that was after the time of the crime, wasn't it?
Well then, next.
You in the wolf mask.
If you could take your mask off and speak.
Uhm, Inspector...
He doesn't understand Japanese.
Because Wolf-Face is Mexican.
Also, taking off his mask in front of a child and young girl is a bit...
I don't mind, Sakuma.
Oogami Takaharu (27)
Pro Wrestler
Because those children already know who I am.
If I remember correctly, you're the good-looking, but super weak Oogami Takaharu...
Yep.
That's absurd!
Because, isn't it even printed in this morning's Touto Sports...
Here!
A photograph of you and Wolf side-by-side!
Oh, that's...
Sakuma here.
He often stands in for me...
In order to confuse reporters and fans that stake out the gym and stadium trying to figure out Wolf-Face's identity.
So that's how it was!
But, the mask you just removed and the mask in this photograph...
It seems they're somehow different...
That's a mealtime mask.
It's made of a thin material, with fewer embellishments, and the mouth is made larger in order to make it easier to eat.
But, I never thought Wolf-Face's identity could have been Oogami-senshu...
Is this all right?
Y-Y-You, if I remember correctly...
You disappeared from the public eye after your loss to Wolf-Face in "Mascara contra máscara"...
Leonardo Rossi (30)
Pro Wrestler (Nega Wolf)
You're Leonardo Rossi, aren't you!?
Oh, yes.
Ma-Mascara?
Mascara contra máscara...
It's an unmasking match!
The one who loses has his mask removed.
How surprising!
I thought for sure that you'd retired...
Leo had decided to retire after he lost to me, but...
He was stopped by Kiba-san, and...
Re-debuted in Japan wearing a Wolf-Face mask with the coloring changed.
After that, people started saying he looked like a shadowed wolf, and he became popular.
After Nagase, it'd been decided that e'd be the next Junior Heavyweight challenger, but...
No one expected something like this to happen...
So where were you two at around 7:20?
Since it was right before the match, I was in the foreign wrestlers' locker room doing warm-up exercises by myself.
Because all of the other foreign wrestlers were out watching Kiba-san's match.
Then, you were also watching Kiba-san's match?
Yes.
In short, all four of you have no alibis, then.
No, Inspector.
This crime could not have been committed if the culprit could not obtain Wolf-Face's mask.
Thus, the culprit is one who could come and go from the foreign wrestlers' locker room freely—one of those two.
Oh, no.
Wolf-Face's mask is packed into a bag along with the spare masks...
And hidden in the restroom that is off-limits to all but authorized personnel.
So that the mask can be put on in secret.
If it weren't for that, I'd be suspected of being Wolf-Face due to going in and out of the foreign wrestlers' locker room.
I see.
Of course, I have already handed that bag over to the forensics officers.
Damn...
If only the victim had left some sort of dying message for us...
What's wrong, Ran-neechan?
Remember, I was saying earlier that a pro wrestling move was popular in our karate club?
The name of that move is similar to "dying message".
Could that possibly be, "Diving Body Attack"?
The one Mil Mascaras does.
Oh, no...
Then...
Maybe Bruiser Brody's Flying Knee Drop, or the Funks' Spinning Toe Hold?
I think it was a Japanese wrestler's move...
If that's the case, it's definitely Mutou-san's—
Well, anyhow!
We'll investigate here some more, so...
Please standby in a separate room with Takagi here.
Hey, Ran, you too—take that brat and go outside.
Sorry, Detective Takagi.
Not your fault.
It's a wrestler from a bloody bout.
Are you all right, Kayama-san?
You almost look like a mummy.
Oh, it's you.
I'm fine, this is nothing.
Anyway, is it true?
That Nagase was stabbed?
Yeah.
Hey, Detective Takagi.
I want to ask you about two things.
Well, about the masked...
Yeah, that's right.
I heard that it's like that for everyone at first...
Masks are generally like that.
Of course, that includes Wolf-Face's.
Conan-kun, where are you going?
I just forgot something in the room.
What are you here for?
I accidentally forgot something here.
Let's see, where did I put it...
The report from forensics has come in!
Oh, is that so?
The bloodstains on the mask discovered in the restroom matched the victim's blood...
And the hair, including from the eyebrows, inside the mask all matched those from the other Wolf-Face masks.
That means the mask was not worn by anyone other than the mask's original owner, Oogami-san, huh?
And the victim's fingernails?
They checked thoroughly, but found nothing.
That's strange.
If he grabbed at the mask intending to rip it off, some of the culprit's skin should have remained on his fingernails.
Then it's as I thought.
The culprit wasn't accustomed to being a wolf...
It was that person!
At any rate, Inspector...
It's an unshakable truth that inside the mask that the culprit wore...
Only Oogami-senshu's scalp and eyebrow hair were found.
With this, it seems we can't but think of him as the culprit.
But even so...
He should also have known about the hidden camera set up by the TV station in this room where the crime took place.
Why would he do something like wearing his own mask, knowing that it would bring suspicion upon himself?
It might have been his intention to have us think that way.
Using reverse psychology, making us doubt that he would have done such a thing on purpose.
Well, if we call Oogami-senshu in here again and ask him about it, I'm sure he'll confess!
Because he doesn't seem like such a bad person!
Ah-le-le!
There's something strange about this mask!
See, look!
The rear part of the mask the culprit is wearing...
Rear, you say?
The design is different from the one Oogami-senshu was wearing earlier...
The design?
Now that you mention it, the mask from earlier had tufts of fur on the back as well, but...
The mask from this video doesn't have them...
Then, could this mask be a fake?
It may be a reproduction that they sell in the fan shops, or something...
Oh, no, not that...
That's not it!
This is, perhaps, the mask from when Wolf-Face debuted!
Oogami-san had said that even the retired masks were inside the same bag, so...
It's possible that the culprit just happened to choose the old mask...
Hey, I thought I told you to keep watch over those four suspects!
No...
Conan-kun hadn't come back, so I was asked to come and take a look by Ran-san.
So that means that the design of the mask has absolutely nothing to do with this crime, then?
Yeah, probably.
Is that so?
That's why Iwas...
What are you all...
"Ah-le-le" about?
You idiot!
The irrelevant things you notice only serve to disrupt the investigation!
Understand?
I guess you're right.
No, hold on...
Oh, that's it!
So that's how it was!
Sorry, but...
After you set this room up in a manner I describe...
Could you please bring the four suspects that are waiting in the separate room here?
Then, could it be...
All right, let's strip it off, Inspector.
The sheep's clothing from the murderous wolf who stabbed Nagase-san to death in this room.
Hey,look!
Those four people are going back in.
Which reminds me, a little while ago Mouri Kogorou also went into that room...
Could it be...
Sleeping Kogorou's Deduction Show?
There's no way I'm going to pass this chance up!
Let us record it!
There's going to be a deduction show, right?
Let us in!
Chiba!
Don't let anyone in!
Wait, Conan-kun is still inside—
What's the meaning of this, detectives?
Calling us back here...
Could it be.
You know who it is?
The culprit.
That's, well...
No, we don't know yet.
Hey, hey, you just said...
But I think we'll find out shortly.
After you four disguise yourselves as wolves as the culprit did and walk towards me.
First, Wolf-Face himself, Oogami-san.
Please put on the mask you're holding in your hands.
Can we have you do that?
Yeah.
All right, come towards me.
That's right, closer.
Even closer.
Uhm, now what should I do?
No, that's fine.
And next, Sakuma-san.
Take the mask from Oogami-san, and do the same.
Yes, sir!
Inspector...
Can you tell the difference between the two of them?
Nope, not at all.
Let us in! Let us in! Let us in! Let us in! Let us in!
Please...
Yes.
Then, finally, Ushigome-san.
Yeah.
I just wear this, and go over there, right?
Mouri-kun!
You probably have some sort of plan in mind, but...
If you don't tell us where or what to take notice of...
We won't get it at all!
Are you all right, mister?
It's you, kid.
I'm all right.
Is that all right, Detective?
Yeah.
I'd already predicted as much, but now it's perfectly clear.
Ushigome-san...
The one who murdered Nagase-san—you were the culprit.
What'd you say?
It was the same...
As the culprit in the video...
You kept glancing around!
Glancing around?
That's right.
You'll understand if you try the mask on, but...
The field of vision on wrestlers' masks is narrower than it appears.
If you're not used to wearing one...
In order to fully grasp the situation before your eyes...
You'd unconsciously survey your surroundings, and trip over things in the blind spot at your feet.
In other words...
Oogami-san, who is accustomed to wearing the Wolf-Face mask...
Leonardo-san, who wears the Nega Wolf mask...
And Sakuma-san, who often stands in for Oogami-san...
Those three are excluded from being the culprit.
The one who is not accustomed to wearing that mask...
The only one remaining is you.
Just because I was glancing around and stumbled, you want to say I'm the culprit?
If you want evidence, it's recorded.
There, in the video.
There, where Conan pointed out earlier, on the back of the mask!
It's there, right?
Something extra...
The mask strings...
There are four of them!
I see!
The culprit was wearing the thin mealtime mask stacked under thafmask!
That way, the culprit's hair wouldn't get on the inside of the blood-splattered mask.
I see.
That's why, even though the victim tore the culprit's mask with his fingers...
There was no trace of the culprit's skin on his fingernails.
Wouldn't this be that mealtime mask?
Earlier, when you fell down, it came out of your pocket!
No...
That's just something I was carrying in order to surprise some of the young people...
It's not the mask the culprit was wearing...
Butthat's strange...
Wolf-Face's mask is only black and white, but there are red splotches near the right eye!
Because the right eye of the mask you were wearing on top got ripped, the blood splatter got on here, right?
This brat...
All right, that's enough.
Well get the rest at the station.
Shut up!
Wait, Ushigome-san!
I said, shut up!
hat's right, I killed him!
That fool who betrayed us, and was going to transfer to Worldwide Pro Wrestlers!
Ushigome-san, calm down!
And that's not all!
I wanted to pin the crime on you, the unpopular young wrestler, and take the mask for myself!
So that I could become Wolf-Face!
Did you hear a strange sound just now?
That's right...
If I just wear this mask, I can be...
You can't become Wolf...
Because even if you hide your face with a mask...
Your soot-stained nature that treats pro wrestling with contempt cannot be concealed.
Uhm...
Conan-kun!
Youngster, what the hell do you...
Stop it!
Shining Wizard!
That's it!
That was the name!
I'm so glad I was finally able to remember it!
Afterward, the culprit Ushigome-san received a silent reprimand from Kiba-san...
And was taken from the white mat to the dim and gloomy prison.
But, it'll be difficult for you all from now on...
You'll be attacked endlessly by the media...
They'll say things like "Pro Wrestling Murder Organization"...
It'll be all right.
We wrestlers are tough.
We're accustomed to being hit.
Well then.
Keep up the good work!
Right.
They're a group of extremely tough men.
They'll be abletto overcome this hardship.
And, as long as Wolf-Face continues to win, his identity will probably never be revealed.
And then, Oogami-san, from the top rope...
Oogami-san?
Weren't you just talking about Wolf-Face?
Yeah, ookami!
Ookami-san!
Oh, because ookami means wolf...
Wolf-Face's identity will... probably... never be revealed?
Probably...