Uae PON rod
mm iB; Let men 2
sDeesco os - LI . e [I
In {IIII III
Deduction flows with
the rhythm of the wind
DCT 2 AS
H= AH HHR O H= A HO
Dark stains are rinsed
clean and exposed
The strange action after a crime
Is an accidentora case? the hidden truth
Dark stains are rinsed
clean and exposed
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
no case.'is left unsolved
with Detective Conan
Oh no, not again
Why is it that all the cars
you rent always break down, dad?
We can't even use the cell phone
in the mountains like this...
We've got no choice but
to wait for the fog to clear...
Hey, don't smoke in
a small place like this!
Quiet! I'll open the window, okay!
Ghads, so what now...
Its nothing...
Ran, I'll bet you're scared?
That there's a mountain monster's
Iooking at us from somewhere
I can't hear you, I can't hear a thing!
Just as I though...
Ghads, hopeless...
Hmm?
Oh, It's a car!
Huh
Saved...
Huh?
It turned the corner...
Gee...
Wait sec
Was there side road there?
Huh
Pops that that mean
that the car we just saw...
Yeah
It could've been an apparition...
NO re
(B1%R)
The Cigar Case of Good Luck" Part 1
Hey, hey, let's not...
Don't worry
You saw the sign, didn't you?
It's a study facility
for a legitimate company...
The people of the company would
never be in a place like this at this time!
I'm sure that the car that we just saw
IS a robber's car or something...
Ghads...
I'll go first and check things out!
Be carefull!!
Oh, it's a car...
It still warm...
It's a cute car...
What a relief!
Bad people don't ride
cars like this, do they!
There seems to be a lot of other cars...
Coven
OS...
This one is warmer!
The car that came in here just a
while ago is probably this car!
This car is still warm too...
Which means...
There are people here for sure!
Let's go!
Okay!
Kooklong Health Equipment Corporation.
I've never heard of them
You two, mind your manners
Yes, sir!
Hello!
Is anyone in?
They couldn't be sleeping
at'"this hour yet. could they...
What it is?
I'm sorry to be intruding
on you at this hour,
but our car broke down nearby
Uh, so, you see,
we're stalled in this fog, so we
would like to ask you for some help...
Please go find someone else to help you,
because I'm going to get busy from now
Wait!
Please at least lend
us your phone! Please!
Agh!
Please wait!!
Wait!
Hey!!
What a guy
I promise that if I die,
I'll come and haunt you!!
Darn
I guess we'll just have to
go back:to the car...
it's cold
You seem to be in trouble.
Please do come in.
Wow, is it okay?!
Thank you so very much!
What a fix, eh.
This is a study facility for the company
that there's usually no one here?
The phone's over there.
Oh, thank you.
Are you sure it's okay!
What if they're spies?
Talk aboutzpush over,
//7//
or rather is it that
you have a lot-of-elbow room
because you-'re in the 1st
development-section...
I heard you all!
Oh, president...
Just what are you guys doing!!
We're sorry to be intruding on you,
but we're not suspicious people.
am a privae, e ecive
and my name is Kogoro Mourns
Mouri, you mean-that:
famous Sleeping?
Huh?
Yes, well.
This is my daughter Ran,
and the little one there is Conan.
Oh my,
I am very honored to be able meet you.
I am...
the president of Kuron Health
Equipment Corporation, Umetani.
Please make yourselves at home here.
Oh, that's right!
Mr. Mourn, please
become a monitor for us!
How about it?
We having an; in-company
competition -n a relax sheet,
We having an in-company
competition on a relax sheet,
An we wou - apprecia e
it if you could give us
your unbiased opinion
how you feel about it...
I'll
Oh...
Whoah
Aaaah
Fuheh, heh, heh
Aaagh
Agh,
right there,
Aaaaaaah
This is just great
It-feels so.good!
Gee, dad,
you're so embarrassing.
I've never experienced
a great massage/chair like this!
It fits right into the vital spot. /
the combination of
the softness of tanned hide
and the combination
of artificial leather for durability
makes for a sensation of perfect fit
Just as expected of the 1st
development section!!
Well done, Nakano!
But president
that artificial leather
you take pride in is made in.Italy!
Moreover
For the massager part high grade
silicone rubber isgdavishly used!!
Therefore, the production cost is too high...
What?!
What is the meaning of this, Nakano?!
The original parts«of the basic
components such as the rollers,
are of the same product line as
what we've used so far,
SO as far as that's
concerned, the cost is...
You fool!
Never mind durability!
even if we don't make
much profit so long as
we produce good items
and our customers like them,
then eventually...
Eventually is not what we're after!!
Make profit for me right this minute!!
Rather, what I mean is,
if we don't keep dishing
out new products,
the customers will give up on us
Ha, ha, ha .
Next!!
That president is kind of scary, isnt he?
Yeah...
Next for the 2nd development
section's Ecstasy One
This product is made for
the younger generation
Please take a look
This seat is a cover-type seat
There.are 7 color variations and
the color of the customer's choice
can be chosen to meet any type of interior
300 (77 *Y
IV) X-
The back part of the seat
can be reclined to any angle,
5 Aux,
and it can also be used
in the living room asia sofa
I see
it sure seems to be great for
a young person's room!
You move this device...
Using the remote controller
that is in the side pocket
First, let's start with full body massage...
Yawn
Are you. sleepy, Conan. 7?
Aaaagh
stop it already
What on earth is this?!
It's made for young people
SO maybe it's too
strong for you, Mr. Mourn?
I'll switch it to weak sleep mode...
No thanks!
Relieve my tiredness, my foot!
My whole body feels
as if it's going to fall apart!!
But.
Kasahara!
That's enough.
Oh, well...
Next!!
Hiramatsu!!
Ed od aaa
Hey, hey, what's this?
Are you going to beat up some monster...
I Huh ¥
Comdito think of it,
my child has a toy that
Iooks somethingUike this...
Really,
it looks like some robot.animation.
Well,
take a look at it please
Oh: yes, right-there!
Right, just'great; right there!
Typ fay Say
Dad?!
How does thing know just
where I want to be massaged...
That's exactly what th 1 main-feature
of this business type AIMS is allsabout!!
A micro sensor detects
the part of your body that is stiff
and massages with
the exact strength needed.
Sounds like a great function,
but I'll bet the cost is really high...
the only thing new is the program,
and the rest involves diverting
what was being used till now,
so I think the cost is less
than half of what your cost is!
Guah!
Besides,
with a function as good as that,
it'll probably sell even if
the price is a bit high.
Yes.
I'll think over which machine I'll sell
while taking a smoke...
Mr. Mouri, do make yourself at home too!
Thank you...
I donst want to come out just yet
what?, ha, ha!
Well,
it feels so good, I feel like-falling-asleep.
Dad,
you re interfering everybody
with their'work!
It's okay
because it seems
e's already decided so...
I'm sorry
Things are moving really
fast today, don't. ou think?
It seems like the rumor about behind the
scenes negotiations was true after all
It's probably because Mr. Mouri
played monitor for us.
President didn't even have to think about it,
but I guess he just wanted to
emphasize his importance...
I get it!
Maybe the rumor about the development
section going to be downsized is true!
Maybe he's thinking over which
development section to shut down now
By the way, Mr! Kasahara,
your seat pushes at the vital points
even if it isn't moving. .4
It's so lumpy!
What?!
How dare you...
Please calm down, Mr. Kasahara!
Thank you everyone!
May you all work together in peace.
I hope all of your inventions
end up being marketed.
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
It's all your fault!!
You're to blame for this...
Ric ht,
you do monitor for him,
representing the young generation, Ran!
No I'd rather not...
Huh? Where's Conan?
Conan!!
What are ou down ?
Don't touch things here!
Ism~t this a knife! It's dangerous!
But, I wonder if it's for real?
It's real!
The president is a famous knife collector.
There's a lot of talk about his collection
among the companies we deal with,
so he has a lot decorated
at the company too.
Sorry to keep you guys waiting!
I've made up my mind!
We're going to put AIMS of the
3rd development section on the market!
And,
we're going to consolidate: the first
and second development
sections into one section.
Huh /!
Will everyone except
Hiramatsu leave the room!
President!
I'll talk to you later!
Thank you so much also Mr. Mouri.
Please relax in the reception corner.
After we finish work
I'd like to talk with you over drinks.
that'd be just great!
Okay,
I'll be waiting then...
They say that they can't dispatch
a repair car until the fog clears up after all.
I'll bet ou're reall relieved
because you can drink all you like now!
Well,
I guess I'll go make some coffee then
Iet me help you!
I have to go to the restroom.
The restroom's beyond the room
we were in just a while ago
It's the second door to your left.
Okay
Please nullify my contract with you!
I'm fed up having to work under you'!
Phooey!
Do I look like a softy who would say,
Yes, off course, and nullify our contract?
No...
so I have already made
appropriate arrangements...
$0, that you would by
nO means refuse to do so
I'm definite thatyou won't refuse...
They're sure taking their time...
He's probably being threatened and
signing a ruthless contract or something.
Serves him right
A ruthless contract?
Yes...
Y. my
what-does it mean to nullify a contract?
Keep out of this kid!
Sonny,
did you hear Hiramatsu
y Say so to the president?
Don't tell me Hiramatsu's
planning to quit the company?
Which means that
you're all contract employees?
Nd nd awa
when the president finds
a talented developer
he forces the developer to sign
a long-term contract with him,
and makes it difficult
for the person to quit easily.
By force?
It's true...
The president's physique
IS as you saw him...
And besides he carries
a dan in karate...
Even if he doesn't really hit you
and stops justbefore hitting,
a weak hearted person would panic
and sign the contract immediately
Oh, no...
Oh well,
Kasahara and I have been here since
the previous president was our boss,
SO we've been spared
that karate scare...
but all the young staff are being
temperedhere at this study dormitory
Moreover,
he takes advantage of tax exemptions and
uses company funds to cover everything
funds to cover everything from his hobby of
collecting knives to giving gifts to women
Even on our way here, take a look at this!
Oh...
Huh, what's that?
Strange,
that's the sound ofia car...
it's Mr. Hiramatsu's car
I wonder what's going on...
The window on the other side!
It's open...
No way?!
Conan?!
This: us?
President?!
President!!
Please get a hold of yourself!
Please stay back!!
Mr. Umetani, are you okay?
He's still breathing!
President!!
Ran!
Get the ambulance and the police!!
Yes, sir!
Let's leave the rest to Ran
and go after Mr. Hiramatsu!!
The car in the foreground!!
I've got the keys.
It's the presidents but I drive it so...
Wait!!
There's a flat!
Huh?
This side is super flat too!
The tires of my car are flat too!
Darn!
In the mountains like this,
it's faster to take him to the hospital by car
than to wait for an ambulance but...
Oh, president.
President!
Mr. Umetani?!
President,
please get a hold of yourself!!
Huh
The knife fell off!!
What's going on...
Huh.
This is?!
The knife poked into the cigar case!
Which means that
the cigar case saved hislife?!
President!
Thank God!
Mr. Umetani, what in the
world happened?
Hiramatsu suddenly.
Stabbed me with a knife...
Whaaa
It seems that there was a thick fog
at the time of the accident
and besides this slope is
steep and the curve is very sharp...
It's most likely that he couldn't steer
fast enough while he was on the run
eah, most likely...
All the tires of the other cars were flat,
so there was no reason for him
to rush as much as he did, though...
If he could think on that line,
he wouldn't. have gotten
enraged and stab somebody.
Exactly!
Just as expected of you Mr. Moun,
very sharp deduction!
Huh.
Well,
the victim is only slightly hurt,
So we'llgbe able to get at the
motive of the stabber right away.
Ri ht!
Sonny!
What are you doing?
You shouldn't be inhere.
Whit,
what's this mirror?
Oh, that?
It's called a corner mirror
From here on down
it's the land of that company
and it's a private road
It seems that nobody is here now, though...
OCT,
there's the sign of the company
It says public welfare facility
Well, it's like a company villa
This large rock is really a pain and
it blocks vision when going in and out
making it really dangerous...
I On this side\there's this-sharp curve-tot)
There's a curve minor there
for the public road too
Because I'm in charge around here,
I wanted a cerner mirror,
for the private road!
Huh?!
The position of the mirror is not right...
It's good that they made a large one,
but I wonder if the wind
blows it out of place
It was okay in the day time!
I think it's better not to fix it
It could've been the reason
the accident occurred, right?!
Oh. no!
Mr. Mouri wants you to chec 4
the brakes of the car right away!
Mr. Mouri wants me-to?
See!
The brakes may have not been working
I'll ask using the wireless
so wait a while, okay...
Conan!
Just what are you
doing in a place like this!
Dad's angry because
he wants you to come back up
I'm sorry
Hurry. quick
Oh, wait
I'm .sorry to keep you waiting
I tell you!
+ Stop scampering about!
I'm going to leave you here!!
I'm sorry
Oh come now, Mr: Mouri
Mr. Mouril\
Hah,
#9 Oh, Inspector Yokomizo!
About your question a while ago...
It seems that the brake oil of the car that
got intopthe accident was completely gone
Huh?
What did you just say?!
I can't tell for sure whether it happened
because of the shock of the accident
or whether it happened
before the accident,
but the tube seems to have come off
Which means, Mr. Mouri
that the oil leaked out and thefbrakes
may not have been working...
It's only natural fordhim to have gotten into
an accident on this mountainous road...
Strange...
there are too many
strange things involved...
A person who gets enraged,
stabs someone and flees,
flattens the tires of everyone's car because
he doesn't want anyone to come after him...
This same person panics and
steers his car out of control,
and falls over the cliff to his death...
The curve mirror that
was facing the wrong way...
Brake oil that was completely gone...
omething smells fishy...
Very fishy!!
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKO SLJWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
Characlcr Designs By.
Mas/xromo sumo
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation DiFectors
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chicf Director.
KENJIJKODAMA
roducedt
IMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
it association with
YOMIURI TELE
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CC NAN
CLONHO AOYAMA SHOGAKURAN YTV CIM
All Ri } WReserved
A rope, a stun gun
and a death note
A death note?!
What's going on...?
Huh
What's this?!
What's wrong?
Ran,
please call Inspector Yokomizo and
the others and tell them to come back!
This is
a cleverly schemed
case of homicide!
TheOCigar Case:of Good Luck" 7
Part 2