Dark stains are rinsed
clean and exposed
One who is obviously the culprit
The vital point of truth
pierces through the paradox
He sees through the one and only truth,
A childiin'appearance
with the IT@&~ of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
ov ("ay @
«7 o>
an - > A
On our way back from lzu,
Pops car broke down again on
a mountain road covered with thick fog
We stopped for help at arstudy facility
of the Kuron Health Equipment Corporation
that happened to be nearby.
In the Presence of a tyrant
president-called Shiro Umetani,
everyone is in the midst ofsa company
competition lof massage chairs.
However
Mr. Umetani is suddenly
found stabbed with a knife.
Fortunately. Mr. Umetani's life is saved.
The culprit Hiramatsu flees with his car
and while fleeing, falls
over a cliff and dies.
It seems that there was a thick fog
at the time of the accident and
besides this slope is steep
and the curve is very sharp...
most likely that he: couldn't steer
fast enough while he was:on the run.
Yeah...
most likely...
Strange...
there are too many
strange things involved...
A person who gets enraged,
stabs someone and flees,
flattens the tires of
everyone's car because
he doesn't want anyone
to come after him...
This same person panics
and steers his car out of control,
and falls over the cliff to his death...
The curve mirror that
was facing the wrong way...
Brake oil that was completely gone...
Something smells fishy...
Very fishy!
(152%)
The Cigar Case of Good Luck" Part 2
Mr. Umetanl§~
at any rate,
we'd better get you to a hospital quickly.
I'll ask you for details there.
No, I really can't be doing that.
I've got to decide what te do since
something like this has happened... 4
A one-man management is
really a lotiof hassle at times like this,
Mr Umetani?
Think it's better for you to go
to the hospital after all...
This is really no big deal...
If I wasn't saved by this cigar case
I had in my chest pocket,
I would've been in the
world beyond by now...
If you think of it that way...
True...
It's indeed a cigar case of good luck...
Oh, how terrible...
The inside is wiped out .
That's a-rare looking type of cigarette...
Uh, how many cigarettes
do you smoke a day?
about:40 maybe...
Then, you must really have it
tough without cigarettes.
You can have mine, if it's okay with you...
No! thanks...
I've got some more in my car...
Besides I only smoke cigars.
Would you like to try one, Mr. Moun?
A cigar...
Uh. Mr. Mourn.
I'd like to ask about the accident...
Oh. right.
I've got something
good that may be of help.
Something geod?
AVvideotapedithe:competition we had.
What?!
Yourvidéortaped it?
Don:téitellimethat...
Yes .
I'm sure that Hiramatsu
stabbing me is on the tape!
Inspector!
Please come upstairs for a moment!
What is it?
The thing is...
We found this in the closet between
the mattresses in Mr. Hiramatsu's room.
A.rope, stun gun
and-a death note
A death note?
What's going one
Hmm,
What's this?!
Whatsszwrong,?!
What's this...
I've completely lost confidence
in Keeping this company going.
Please forgive me for my selfishness.
President of Kuren Health
Equipment:Corporation.
Shiro Umetani...
What?!
It's President Umetani's death note!
Absurd!!
I would never wfite something like this!!
There's no reason why
I should commit suicide!
Just as I thought...
Mr. Hiramatsu probably was scheming
to kill you using everything here...
There's no doubt about it!
Before all else,
Iet's take a look at the video tape!!!
I kept the video running just in case...
But: I sure had no idea
it would come in handy
in a situation like this.
How ironic...
Oh. there!
er youa e e room,
I tried AIMS out...
It was good. wasn't it?
I was definitely sure that
it would be a hit
Except for one problem...
Problem?
He demanded that
I let him quit the company...
And that unless: take In his request.
He refused to give AIMS to me...
He said that unless the password
is entered by midnight,
the program within
AIMS:-would perish...
So, what did you do?
I was sure that I could make
a great profit with AIMS...
But,
I was more afraid of him
going to another company
and developing
something better than AIMS...
So. you chose Mr. Hiramatsu?
Yes...
At first it seemedy
that he was convinced...
But hag-suddenly beoameienraged .
I wasisuddenly stabbed and fainted.
so)! don't remember
anything that followed...
I awoke
when you people woke.me«up.
After that Mr 'Hiramatsu.
Afraidsofteverybody finding out about
whatihappened fledfrom the window...
After he went through the
trouble -of preparing
to kill youunder the pretense of suicide.
Why would he lose his temper
and use a knife-because it was there...
That man+'had no patience.
He used to do only
what he wanted to do.
He used to always wear a blank look
and seemed like a quiet man
yet he easily loses his temper...
You're pretty hard on him, aren't you.
How about you, Mr. Nakano?
Oh. well...
it's true that he had that inclination...
I see...
This is the place that
Mr. Hiramatsu's car was parked...
Just as I thought!
Brake oil leaked.
Somebody removed the tube!!
Try it.will you.
The aroma is very
different from cigarettes.
Come on, have one!
Thank you, I'll have one then...
But. what a fine cigar case you have!
Yes.
It's my father's keepsake,
and this is a one and only...
Oh my god!
Well. well...
There's no mistake thatthis is
Mr. Hlramatsu's briefcase, is there?
Yes,
there's no mistake about/it.
It's just like Mr. Hiramatsu
to hide it in the closet.
What do you mean?
He was very secretive...
The 3rd development
room is a single room.
Therefore, the door was always locked,
and he wouldn't let anybody in.
The only time he ever talks
IS during the competition.
The »
did anyone know that he was
planning to kill the president?
How would we ever
know a thing like that?
We're the ones who'd want to kill him!
Huh?
Oh. well?
I mean!
We understand very well his feeling
of wanting to go independent!
Right!
Come to think of it, he was being
yelled at even this morning...
(QM?
Only Mr. Hiramatsu's AIMS was
delayed being brought here.
The president went to the 3rd
development room himself
and Hiramatsu was being
yelled at from morning.
After a while Hiramatsu
came dashing out
and disappeared off somewhere...
Talk about troublemaker...
But,
we finally find him and come back
BM only to find the president gone next!
He tells us that he can't take it any longer
I unless he, goes out for achange
and goes out to buy
that cheap cigar case.
Heck what the hell's going on...
Didn't any of you go out with your car?
Great, Pops!
Yes!
We went to eat and do some shopping...
Of course, Hiramatsu
didn't come with us.
The president said he was
going to stop by at the villa,
so I went with Nakano in his car.
We arrived here right aftenthat...
I see...
I get it!
I've figured everything out!!
It's this late already... +=
Since I've more or less
finished questioning-all-of you
I guess we'll call it a day...
Ugh!
Mr. Mourn,
if your car's not repaired yet,
et me give you a lift!
Well, well...
I guess I'll go try out that
relax seat one more time.
Hey, dad!
It wasn't much of a.case anyway...
Hey. just what do you
think-you-re doing?
Ran!
Call Yokomizo and the others
and tell them to come back!
Mr. Hiramatsu didn't die of an accident!
Huh
This is a cleverly s¢chemed
homicide as
What do you mean
that Mr. Hiramatsu's dedth
by accidentis a
homicide case, Mr. Moufli?
Well, the brakes weren't working. but...
Its true that the
malfunction.of the brakes
dosnot alwayslead to fatal death...
However, the killer set up another trap
to. make sure that he dies in the accident!
Huh
What kind of trick was it?!
Mr. Hiramatsu believed
that he killedthe president
and fled by car.
His brakes didn't work as
he drove through the thick fog.
And, the car just kept
going down the mountain.
Then
suddenly the headlights
of an oncoming car appear.
He loses control of the wheels
and falls over the cliff...
Please wait, Mr. Mour.
Was there an oncoming car?
The road uphill,
all except for the private road
that's.on the side here to this company
Iead-up to the top and is a dead end.
And besides,
after sundown this whole area
Is covered with thick fog
that there is always practically no one.
There doesn't seem to
have been such a car...
No: wrong...
The lights he thought were
of an oncoming car Was...
the headlights of his own car.
But unless there's a-mirror or something
in front it would be impossible .
Ach!
Yes.
Do you remember that there was
something at the sceneof the accident
that was reflecting the floodlight?
Yes! Yes!
The corner mirror that was
on the road leading to this facility!
I see .
The angle of the corner mirror was
changed to reflect the headlights!
When Officer Shimada of the
residential police boxsaw in the day time,
it seemed to be in the correct position...
And in the parking lot where
Mr. Hiramatsu's car was parked,
there were traces of oil leak.
The person who removed
the brake oil and
the person who flattened the tires of
the other cars is probably
one and the same.
Huh
Even if the brakes were
to be tampered with,
there's no guarantee that
Mr. Hiramatsu would fleewith that car.
Beside. If someone
goes. after Mr. Hiramatsu
and catches him before
he gets into the accident,
everything will go to waste!
Which means. Mr. Mourn...
someone here did ?
Here, you mean us?!
We don't have time long enough
to be alone, so it's impossible!
Only the president has time to himself, right?
You fool! I'm the victim!
Come to think of it,
Mr. Umetan,
after the competition you went te
take a smoke of cigar. alllby yourself.
And,
you seem to have come heme alone when
everyone went out to have
dinner, didn't you?
You went by the corner mirror
with your car then? didn't you?
Hey, hold it!
Have you forgotten that
I've extended my kindness to you?!
One more thing...
The Killer used a certain thing...
And, just what is that certain thing!
The other thing is...
he fog...
The fog?
Yes,
the thick fog that is unique to this area.
Without the fog.
It'd be easy to see through
the corner mirror trick.
In other words
the one thing that was necessary
to commit this murder was the fog.
And the only person who could
use this fog to his advantage was you!
President Umetani!
None other than you!!
Don't be ridiculous...
The fog is a natural phenomenon!
Besides the fact that
Hiramatsu would stab me
and flee is not something
I could've known beforehand!!
How dare you say something
irresponsible like that!!
No, You knew...
that Mr. Hiramatsu was
planning to kill you.
What!
I hear that you had it out with
Mr. Hiramatsu before coming here...
and Mr Hiramatsu
dashed out of the room.
You stayed back in the room
so I guess you saw, didn't you?
The inside of the briefcase!!
Therefore, thinking of getting back at him.
You went to buy yourself
a cigar case just before leaving.
Because the one that you're always using
IS a precious keepsake of your father...
Well, using all kinds of cigar
cases is good for a change!
Then why would a person like you
who smokes 40 cigars a day
choose a cigar case that can take
only 4 or 5. cigars placed diagonally?
And...
you keptipostponing
the competition for one reason
or another till the night
when a thick fog appeared...
In other words,
this homicide taking advantage
of and envisioning this fog
can only have been committed by you
Some renown detective you are.
All you said just now are
nothing but assumptions!
Where the hell is the evidence!!!
The evidence is on the video tape.
Please look closely at
Mr. Hiramatsu's facial expression.
When Mr. Hiramatsu demanded you I
to make a choice between AIMSOand him,
you selected Mr. Hiramatsu to I
ARASH didn't you, Mr. Umetani?I
Yeah, right!
Oh, stop right there!
If so.
Why would Mr. Hiramatsu who
couldn't get what he wanted be smiling?
Beats me.
Isn't it al fact that.you-agreed
to what he asked for?
Please move it on now.
he's saying something to you, isn't he?
I'm sure he's giving you the password...
The password to stop the program
of AIMS from being erased...
However
he is suddenly angered
and stabs you in the shoulder.
It's most likely that he realized that
you just pretended to take in his: demand es
Hey. hey:-cut/itiout already!
You just made up your story so that
it looks to fitswhatss
seen on:theVidéo tape!
Is thisiwhaty ou call evidence?!
This video -showsone more thing that is not
in keeping with what you're saying...
Not in keeping?
Please advance the tape.
Yes, sir!
Stop!
Thought you said that
you passed out at this point,
but'why.thén-does Mr. Hiramatsu stop
iniplace: as:if someone is calling him?
How should I know!!
Isn't this what you said
when you called out to him?
Come back!
If you donat finish me off, it's going
to be your turn next time around!
Or something to that effect...
And, you probably went on"like this...
If you stab the O" of Kuren,
you'll finish me for sure!
Because it's right on the heart!
MrHiramatsu, did exactly
as you provoked him to
and stabbed right
through the letter WO"...
On the letter "O" right
on top the cigar case
that you had put inside
your chest pocketly
Whata bunch of baloney!
It's alljjust your imagination!
Nothing like this is going
to serve as evidence!!
Inspector Yokomizo?
Yes. sir?
What time is it now?
One minute after midnight.
Mr. Umetan...
will you turn on the switch
for AIMS after midnight...
If you didn't get-the password
from him as you say,
the device is not su osed to work. is it?
Mr Umetani?
It's midnight!
Good evening.
President Umetan...
I appreciate our wise-choice...
Please make a lot of profit with my AIMS.
I guess we-ll never be seeing
each other ever again...
Goodbye
President Umetan...
Darn...
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKO_SUWA
MASAHITQ YOSHIOKA
Background Music
Kan-wt) ONO
Character Designs By
Story Editor
JUNICHI I11OKA
Scripts By
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
VA 0de JJ)
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
y Co Toe
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
ChictfiDirector.
KENJIgKODAMA
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
An ASSOCIATION within
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CONAN
CGOMIO AOYAMA LT SHOGARURAN YTV IMS
All Riv hi™Reserved
Good job, Conan!
More towards the shoulders!
It feels like I'm being
deliberately stepped on...
Phooey.
Popsiyou're right!
Let's buy a massage chair after all!
If you want"to buy something
expensive like that,
do work that will bring
in enough cash, okay!
I feel sorry for Conan. don't you?
I'll massage you, then...
No. .no thanks!
No-don- t;: not -that!!,
backbone in place
Iipromise~it'll make you feel way better.
I don't need anymore massage today.
I'm going to get delicious
food ready. then
Talk about scary...
Hmm?
I've figured out who the culprit is!
Huh
Mr. Tsukikata,
the culprit is your other disciple!
Alibi established...
Mysterious Centipede Ninja..."
The enemy is your friend and
your friend is your enemy.
One twist after the other...
Counterturn!
Counter...
Next Conan's hint
Ninja Technique of Alibi Scheme