Uncle!
Uncle, wake up!
So noisy...
Let me sleep...
Uncle!
Today's Sunday, isn't it?
We have a guest.
Good morning...
Detective Chiba?
Geez...
What could be important enough to worry about this early on a Sunday morning?
Sorry about this...
It's just that Inspector Megure said he wanted to speak with you...
Conan!
When did you...
THE ART OF NINJA ALIBI CRAFT
The cause of death is suffocation.
The estimated time of death is sometime last night, between approximately 7:00 and 9:00.
Because there are no signs of a struggle in the surrounding area...
We believe he was murdered at a different location, then brought here to North Beika Park.
Is something wrong?
No...
I'm just wondering why I'd have to be here...
What are you talking about?
Aren't you acquainted with him?
This was found in the victim's pocket...
My business card...
Why is this...
From the license that was also in his possession...
The victim was a resident of Koufu City in the Yamanashi Prefecture; Kusaka Yuuichi-san, 26 years of age...
Kusaka Yuuichi (26)
How about it, Mouri-kun?
Even with that...
I remember that person!
Conan-kun!
Sticking your nose into the case again...
Now, now, Mouri-kun.
Go ahead, Conan-kun.
This person was part of the group that came to our office with the novelist Tsukigata Ryuutarou-san.
Tsukigata?
Tsukigata...
That's right!
He was one of the two apprentices that came along!
Tsukigata Ryuutarou...
Isn't he the famous historical novelist whose specialty is in things related to the ninja?
Yeah.
About half a year ago, he unexpectedly came to my office to gather information...
He said he wanted to try penning a detective novel.
And at that time, you also handed out one of your business cards to Kusaka...
If I remember correctly...
He was undergoing training to become a professional writer while employed at his corporate job...
And since he happened to be in town at the time, he was brought along when they came to gather information.
And, the other person was?
What do you mean?
It was Saruhashi-san!
Saruhashi...
Saruhashi Masaru-san...
He said that, because he lives in Beika like Tsukigata-san does...
He was helping manage the collected information while he begins his own writing career.
All right!
First is Tsukigata.
Let's go, Mouri-kun.
Yes, sir!
Kusaka-kun was?
And that's why we were wondering if perhaps he was on his way here at the time.
Is that so...
Tsukigata Ryuutarou (63)
Novelist
He had an appointment to come here yesterday with the new manuscript he'd just written.
Hey, did Kusaka-san have that manuscript on him?
No, he didn't have any baggage on him.
Last night, at a bit past 8:00, he called from Teito Station...
Saying that he'd come visit at 9:00, but he didn't show.
I thought it was odd.
He called from Teito Station at a bit past 8:00...
Yes.
Inspector, the estimated time of death is between 7:00 and 9:00.
If he was at Teito Station at a bit past 8:00, then we can narrow down his estimated time of death.
Kusaka-kun called twice yesterday...
The first time was around noon...
From his home in Koufu.
He asked if it would be all right for him to come over and have me look over his new manuscript.
But since I had plans to head out...
I won't be back until about 9:00.
Around 9:00?
Well, I'll come visit around that time.
And the second time was from Teito Station at a bit past 8:00.
Since I was out at the time, the answering machine took his call.
Let's see...
It's Kusaka.
I've arrived at Teito Station.
I'm heading over now, so...
Teito, Teito!
Mama, hurry up!
I'll be able to visit with you at 9:00 as planned.
I told you it's dangerous to run, Ken-chan!
The train's about to leave, so...
Saturday, 8:10 p.m.
Would you mind playing it once more?
There is one message.
It's Kusaka.
I've arrived at Teito Station.
I'm heading over now, so...
Teito, Teito!
I'll be able to visit with you at 9:00 as planned.
Mama, hurry up!
I told you it's dangerous to run, Ken-chan!
I'll be able to visit with you at 9:00 as planned.
The train's about to leave, so...
Saturday, 8:10 p.m.
Kusaka-san was headed toward Beika Station from Teito Station by train.
That means there's no mistake, then.
But this phone call...
Something bothers me about it.
Departing from Teito Station at 8:10...
It's this train.
Then, it's approximately 30 minutes to Beika Station, so...
His arrival at Beika Station would be at 8:40.
The time of the crime was between 8:40 and 9:00...
The place was the area surrounding Beika Station.
It seems logical to view it that way.
I've got it, I know who the culprit is!
Tsukigata-sense, the culprit is your other apprentice!
Saruhashi-kun is?
You have some sort of basis for this, Mouri-kun?
Of course!
Since he lives right across from Beika Station, he's familiar with the area.
Not to mention, he has more motive than anyone to commit the crime.
I remembered...
Half a year ago, the two had a disagreement.
You want me to quit being Sensei's apprentice?
Saruhashi-san, you've been studying by Sensei's side for so many years already...
Isn't it enough already?
Now, now, you two...
Kusaka-kun, stop it at once!
I just want to study by Sensei's side!
But, you can't look after two separate apprentices, so please, choose me!
It's not that, Kusaka-kun.
As a salaried man, you have a stable livelihood.
No matter where it is you live, you're still an apprentice of mine...
There's a huge difference in the necessary studying possible, depending on whether one is at Sensei's side!
Saruhashi-san, please switch with me already!
That's for Sensei to decide!
The seeds of discontent were sown over the ranking of the apprentices...
That could be seen as a motive...
That's a childish motive.
It's too unreasonable.
It's Takagi.
Is that so?
All right.
That was forensics.
Kusaka's fingerprints were not found on the aforementioned lighter.
What's that?
What lighter?
It was dropped...
Next to the body, a lighter.
Sorry, excuse me...
This is a lighter I had given to Saruhashi-kun...
Then with this, on top of a motive, the evidence is lining up.
Could it be...
Saruhashi-kun was...
Saruhashi-san, do you recognize this lighter?
Saruhashi Masaru (29)
This is my lighter.
I lost it a longtime ago though...
You lost it?
When?
And where?
I don't know...
Please recall, Saruhashi-san!
I really don't know!
I think it was a longtime ago, but...
A key for a coin-locker?
Oh, right!
Sensei gave me that lighter as a present, so I was naturally really attached to it!
Kusaka must have been jealous, and decided to steal it from me!
Saruhashi-san!
Takagi-kun...
Saruhashi-san, where did you happen to be last night?
Well...
Until about 8:00, I was at a coffee shop in front of the station.
After that...
I came back here for a short while, and then from around 8:30,1 was at a bar in front of the station.
Was it really from around 8:30?
It wouldn't be later, at around 9:00, would it?
Kusaka-san's estimated time of death is thought to be between 8:40 to 9:00.
Kusaka-san called Tsukigata-sensei's house from Teito Station at 8:10.
As such, his arrival at Beika would have been...
At a time after 8:40.
I entered the bar at 8:30!
There's no mistake about it!
Please investigate it for yourselves!
Because I haven't lied at all!
Thank you for your time.
According to the coffee shop, he came in during the evening and left at around 8:00.
I also got the story from here.
They said he came in at around 8:30 and proceeded to drink all the way until midnight.
I guess that means Saruhashi-san has an alibi...
How can that be?
That story about the lighter was very evasive!
If Kusaka-san had stolen it, the fact that his fingerprints weren't on it is strange!
I know that.
The motive and the evidence line up...
But how does he have an alibi?
Hold on a second!
It's possible for him to have committed the crime!
He left the coffee shop at 8:00...
And entered this bar at 8:30.
There are 30 minutes in between that are unaccounted for, aren't there?
And so?
And so, assuming the story about him going back to his apartment was a lie...
He could have murdered Kusaka-san during that 30 minute interval.
8:15 <—
8:00
Teito <—
Beika
30 minutes
The scene of the murder was not here in Beika, but between Teito Station and Beika Station.
If he used the full 30 minutes, he could have gone to one of the stations in between...
He could commit the murder there, and return to Beika Station at 8:30.
The real time of the murder was not 8:40, but around 8:15.
Impossible, Takagi-kun.
Kusaka-san left Teito Station at 8:10.
Five minutes later, at 8:15...
8:15 <—
8:00
Teito <—
Beika
30 minutes
Kusaka-san wouldn't have reached an in-between station yet, and would still be around here.
In that 30 minute window, murder—especially murder by suffocation—is impossible.
Impossible.
As long as one of the ninja techniques that appeared in Tsukigata Ryuutarou's novels wasn't used, anyway...
Ninja Alibi Trick Technique?
Just what kind of trick did he use?
Just what kind of alibi trick did Saruhashi-san use?
TURNABOUT AFTER TURNABOUT!
THE INCREDIBLE CENTIPEDE NINJA
THE LONG-AWAITED NOVELS BY "TSUKIGATA RYUUTAROU"!
NEW ARRIVAL!
Tsukigata-sensei's new books...
The Incredible Centipede Ninja, huh?
Enemy becomes ally, ally becomes enemy...
Turnabout after turnabout...
Turnabout?
The opposite!
Because I haven't lied at all!
Kusaka-kun called twice yesterday...
It's Kusaka.
I've arrived at Teito Station.
Saturday, 8:10 p.m.
That's it!
That's how it was!
Beika Station West Entrance
Two Days Later
If that's the case...
The coin-locker.
They're rented out for private use, three days at a time...
Number 0101...
Please be there!
It's there!
As I thought...
The culprit was that person!
No matter how much I read, there aren't any hints...
What's this, everyone coming together...
What are you talking about?
Mouri-kun, wasn't it you who called us here by phone?
Called...
Yes, it was I who called.
Of course, it was because I wanted to talk about the truth of the Kusaka Yuuichi-san murder case.
Did you see through it?
The aforementioned ninja technique?
Yes, an alibi trick was used in this murder case.
Actually it was a very simple trick, but...
We weren't able to see through it.
Because the one who used it wasn't the culprit.
Not the culprit?
Then, who?
When we heard the answering machine message, I felt that something was off...
That is, even though he knew Tsukigata-sensei wouldn't be home shortly after 8:00...
Kusaka-san made his second call.
Why did he deliberately make that call?
Even though there wasn't anything important in the message...
Saturday, 8:10 p.m.
Right, it was to have it be thought that he was at Teito Station at 8:10.
To be thought?
In other words, he wasn't actually there?
Mouri-san, it was there!
Takagi-kun?
It was there, the aforementioned ticket.
Ticket?
A ticket from that day, collected at Beika Station, and one with Kusaka-san's fingerprints on it.
Detective Takagi, what time is printed on it?
Yes...
Let's see, it was sold at Teito Station...
7:30 PM?
What, 7:30?
Not shortly after 8:10?
As I expected.
If he bought the ticket at 7:30 and immediately got on the train...
He'd arrive at Beika Station shortly after 8:00.
Sorry for being late.
Chiba-kun...
I also asked Detective Chiba for a favor.
To take custody of the contents of the locker that had expired...
This...
Isn't this Kusaka-kun's bag?
This belongs to the victim?
There's no mistake, right?
Yeah...
Please put the contents of the bag onto the table.
Right.
Thank you.
Now, Inspector...
Please rewind the tape recorder a bit and play it.
I told you it's dangerous to run, Ken-chan!
This is...
It's the same as what was left on the answering machine!
That's right.
Upon arriving at Beika Station...
Kusaka-san used what he had recorded earlier in order to create an alibi proving that he was at Teito Station at 8:10...
The Ninja Alibi Trick Technique.
If you understand how this was done, it's a very simple matter.
So, the one who used this ninja technique wasn't the culprit, but the victim.
But, why would Kusaka-san do such a thing?
It was in order to murder Saruhashi-san.
After Kusaka-san left the message on the answering machine, he hurried to Saruhashi-san's apartment.
He probably told him in advance that he had something important to speak with him about...
Kusaka-san's plan was probably to murder Saruhashi-san, and immediately report it to the police by phone...
That way, the police would be able to narrow down the time of crime...
Since he had already set up his alibi to show that, from 8:10 to 8:40, he was on the train to Beika Station...
He would be excluded from being a suspect.
Afterward, he would show up to visit Tsukigata-sensei as planned at around 9:00, as if nothing had happened.
However, it didn't go according to plan.
Instead, he was killed by his intended victim.
Saruhashi-san, who had killed his would-be murderer...
After transporting the body to the park...
Went to a bar in order to have a witness as to his whereabouts at around 8:30.
I didn't lie!
That's right.
You didn't lie.
You only realized the police's error and made use of it.
So you really did kill Kusaka-kun...
I don't know anything about it!
He didn't come to my apartment!
No, he should have been there.
He had intended to murder someone...
So he couldn't have brought the tape recorder he used to manufacture his alibi, nor the manuscript.
Kusaka-san left those in the coin-locker at Beika Station.
If things are left in those lockers for more than three days, those in charge of them open the lockers with a spare key.
And today, when that time limit was up, Detective Chiba was able to take custody of it.
Kusaka-san's bag, that is.
But, how did you know the number of the locker?
That's the point.
When we went to your apartment, Conan found a coin-locker key in your room.
Number 0101.
It's an easy number to remember, even for a child.
You said that Kusaka-san hadn't come, but...
How could someone who hadn't come lose their key in your room?
He came to my room, but—
That's enough...
Saruhashi-kun.
Sensei...
I'd always been afraid of him...
Afraid that he'd snatch Sensei away from me...
I appreciate your admiration.
But, whether you become a professional or not is a matter of your own motivation.
It seems that both you and Kusaka-kun had forgotten that most important fact.
I'd thought we'd have to give up on this case, but...
That's Mouri-kun for you.
Inspector Shiratori's new informant, right?
There you go again...
Is this the Ninja Playing Dumb Technique?
You realized it?
I'm no match for you, Inspector!
Uncle's most skillful technique is the Ninja Feel Good Technique...