The rhythm of the wind clarifies all reasoning...
And causes alibi tricks to fall apart!
A kidnapping case with a ransom...
Just what happened inside that tunnel?
Seeing through to the one and only truth...
I look like a child, but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
The Vanished
The Vanished Kidnapper's Getaway Vehicle:
Part 1!
You know,.
I thought Yaiba was about to lose yesterday.
Yeah, that was really close!
The Yaiba Kick just kept on missing.
Jun!
How is it, Jun?
Is your leg healing up well?
He doesn't look very happy.
They're Jun's classmates.
They were always visiting Jun while he was recovering.
Is that right?
Thank you for everything.
We're
We're... his friends, aren't we?
Those guys always get like this whenever they meet a pretty girl...
Don't they?
Hey, Jun. Did you have an older sister?
What's that?
By "older sister," you must be referring to me.
Y-Yes...
I'm delighted.
This is Ezaki Sachiko-san, a fashion designer.
Fashion designer?
Amazing!
You came to visit Jun-kun, too?
That's right.
Let's have a lot of fun together from here on out, okay?
Please come by my house to play sometime.
You will be more than welcome.
Your house?
It's Jun-kun's house.
J-Jun's house?
What does that mean?
That's because..
Shouldn't you be leaving already?
Isn't it almost time for the fashion show rehearsal?
Ah, you're right.
Then, we should get going.
See you later, Jun-kun.
Jun seems to be very bored.
Please take your time with him.
Bye.
Jun-kun, you'll be able to leave the hospital tomorrow...
Just hang in there for one more day.
That lady we just met, Ezaki-san...
Is she your new mom?
You're so lucky...
Having such a beautiful woman become your mom.
She'd be a lot more beautiful if she were dead.
It's obvious that woman only married my dad for his money.
She married him for his money?
That's right.
I... heard her.
What? For me?
I'm so happy
Thank you.
What do you think?
They suit you well
So, when are we having the wedding ceremony?
I'd like to wait a little longer...
Until the end of my show in February.
Please?
Is it because you want to focus solely on the show?
Yes.
I want to succeed this time, at any cost.
And I'm ready to resign as a designer if it doesn't work out this time.
Understood
Sorry
It's fine.
And by the way, about your next show...
Do you have enough to pay your expenses?
If you need some money...
I'm fine!
But if that ever happens, I won't hesitate to ask you.
Keep the money ready.
Just don't eat me out of house and home, okay?
Hey, Jun...
Aren't you just making her seem bad when she's really not?
Such a beautiful woman couldn't possibly...
Genta-kun!
I can understand you being opposed to having a new mom, but surely...
Game corner?
There's one at the Haido district supermarket.
You want to go there?
R-Right now?
Please!
I just want to go there once to try!
But you're not yet...
I'm fine, I'm fine.
Don't judge by the cast on my leg. It's already healed.
See? I told you so.
Even if you say that..
Are you really sure you'll be okay?
Isn't it better to wait after you leave the hospital tomorrow to go there?
No way, no way!
That's absolutely impossible!
As soon as I get out of the hospital, I'll have my lessons with my tutor...
And between piano lessons and English speech practice, I won't have time to play games.
I feel sorry for all the activities you have to do.
That's why I'm asking you!
Today's my only chance!
We have two hours until the nurse makes her rounds at 12:00 PM, so there's no way...
There's no way anyone will catch us!
Hey, hey... What should we do, Conan?
Getting out of the hospital would be tough...
First, you'd have to walk by the nurse's station...
And there's also a chance that the nurse would randomly come to check on you.
That's why one of you guys can take my place...
And hide under the bed covers, so...
Hey, hey... Don't say absurd things.
But we're his friends, so we should do something.
Please, I beg you.
Since Jun-kun is begging us so persistently...
If we ignored him, we'd disgrace the name of the Detective Boys.
Right, Conan?
I-I know that.
Thank you!
So, let's play Rock-Paper-Scissors to decide.
Conan-kun!
R-Rock-Paper-Scissors?
What a guy!
I bet Conan-kun is so happy we picked Rock-Paper-Scissors!
We don't have much time, so let's hurry up.
Let's get some eel rice on our way back!
All right, but you're treating us, Genta-kun!
Exactly.
Thanks in advance!
Well, at least he'll be having a lot of fun there.
Ah! Crap!
Jun-kun?
J-Jun-kun?
Say, Jun-kun's bed is empty.
Would any of you happen to know where he went?
I don't..
Actually, it seems a group of kids went to see him about one hour ago.
Why don't we look for them?
It's me, Yoshizawa.
I kidnapped that brat, Jun.
Everything went just as you planned.
Huh, now?
Ah, he's in a deep sleep.
Where am I?
And why am I here?
You woke up, brat?
Get out!
And make it quick!
What, you still can't move?
Where am I?
What do you want to do with me?
Say...
Thanks to you, boy...
I'm gonna get a huge lump of cash off your parents from the ransom.
So I was kidnapped.
Well, that pretty much nails it.
All right!
Okay, that's enough.
Please do it like that during tonight's unveiling presentation.
Until then, break!
Wonderful!
Keep this up, and I know you'll be a top-class designer.
That would make me happy, but..
Please, believe in your talent.
Hello? This is Kataoka.
J-Jun?
Yes.
Understood, I'll go there right away.
Something happened to Jun-kun?
It seems Jun-kun disappeared from the hospital.
I'll go with you.
No, I'll go to the hospital by myself.
You have an important show to do.
But...
He's fine. He's probably just off playing around the hospital.
Don't worry.
I'll call you later!
He didn't go back home, and we also searched in the vicinity, so...
Do you know of any other places where Jun-kun might be?
I don't, but he couldn't have gone far with his injured leg.
S-Sachiko-san?
Do you know where Jun-kun is?
Sachiko-san, please go back to the ceremony hall.
Let us handle finding Jun.
What's the most important for you now is...
Jun-kun, not the show.
I will not go back until I see him safely returned.
Sato-san?
How did it go?
I asked the nurses, and it looks like the classmates who came to visit him were Conan-kun and the others.
Conan-kun and the others?
Four came and four left.
I see...
So he couldn't have left with them, could he?
This is Kataoka..
J-Jun? Kidnapped?
If you want the child returned, prepare 30 million yen in cash.
Jun- Is Jun all right?
Yeah, he's all right.
I'll let you hear the brat's voice now.
This isn't good, I don't have my voice changer.
Here, they want to hear your voice.
What's wrong?
Dad..
Jun!
Jun-kun!Jun-kun!
Your kid is too scared to speak...
Well, hurry up and get the money!
Please wait!
He hung up.
Kataoka-san, did his voice ring any bells?
No, that was the first time I heard his voice.
And Jun's voice was weak..
Is Jun really safe?
We really don't know...
But for now, please leave it to us.
I understand.
Inspector Megure, everything's ready.
Ah? Thank you.
All we have to do now is wait for a call from the kidnapper.
Inspector Megure!
Kataoka-san, please answer the call.
Yes.
Hello? This is Kataoka.
Have you prepared the money?
Yes, I've got it all.
And just to make things clear, you'll free Jun, right?
Bring the money to Ogane Park at 12:00 PM, under the clock tower.
To Ogane Park at 12:00 PM, under the clock tower?
I'll definitely be there.
But Kataoka-san, you're not going to be the one bringing the money...
I want Ezaki, that girl of yours, to bring it.
H-Her?
It'll be troublesome i you try anything strange...
A woman is safer.
Well, don't be late.
Inspector Megure.
I'll take Ezaki-san's role.
No, I want to do it.
Ezaki-san?
I'll go!
Sachiko-san!
The culprit asked for me to go...
So he definitely knows my face.
But if something goes wrong and you...
I'm begging you!
Jun-kun... Jun-kun's life can't be replaced!
Please let me go!
Inspector!
Inspector Megure.
I understand. Please do so.
Yes, sir.
Inspector!
I know what I'm doing.
Ezaki-san..
We'll be following approximately 500 meters behind you, so the kidnapper won't be able to see us.
I put this transmitter in your bag...
So we'll be able to quickly find the kidnapper's position.
And if something happens, please use this to report it.
Sachiko-san, don't try anything foolish.
I'll definitely bring Jun-kun back.
Sachiko-san..
Get in there!
This is your grave!
It's pointless to cry for help now.
I have to hurry up and get out of here!
Listen carefully.
When the culprit makes contact with Ezaki-san...
We'll surround him if he has Jun-kun with him.
And if we can't confirm that Jun-kun is there, we'll let the culprit leave freely...
And locate Jun-kun's confinement place.
Then, we'll free him after being sure of the operation's safety.
This is Sato in Ogane Park.
Roger that, we'll proceed according to those orders.
All right, and please be careful.
Takagi-kun!
Get closer to me!
No, I'm fine here...
You dummy, aren't we supposed to pretend to be lovers?
Um, yeah...
Come on, put your arm around my shoulder.
Well, if you say so...
Like this?
Jeez..
Do it firmly!
Inspector, Ezaki-san's car just arrived.
Inspector, a suspicious vehicle is closing in on Ezaki-san.
It's a small freight truck that has "Busy Bee Delivery" written on it.
That gaudy vehicle might be the culprit's.
It stopped next to Ezaki-san.
Can you see Jun-kun?
No...
We can't see her yet.
Where's Jun-kun? Is he with you?
I left the brat with my partner.
He'll let him free when I return.
Inform the police about that!
The culprit grabbed the bag off of Ezaki-san and drove away.
The truck's license plate number is Shinjuku 4-4, mi as in Mikasa, 3-2-8.
It has a big emblem on it that says "Busy Bee Delivery" over an orange-colored background.
Inspector, what should we do?
Don't rush.
Chiba-kun, please call the emergency squad.
Y-Yes, sir!
Sato and Takagi, track him from a distance.
Roger
Please be careful, a life's in danger.
Don't let that truck out of your sight.
Jun-kun, isn't it time to head back?
It's only a little past 11:00 AM.
See?
So, we can probably play for another 10 minutes or so.
I challenge you to this game next!
Genta-kun, are you good at this game?
Not at all.
What?!
Then, I guess I'll play this round out for you.
Sounds good!
Somehow..
I have to get out somehow!
Inspector, if we keep going in this direction, we're going to enter the Kembashi tunnel.
How long is the tunnel?
About one kilometer, so it only takes a minute to pass through it at our current speed.
Inspector, the suspect will soon enter the tunnel.
All right, go ahead and wait at the tunnel's exit.
Roger that.
I-It stopped!
It stopped in the middle of the tunnel!
It's no use...
This kid-sized body just don't have enough strength.
Damn it!
It's possible that the culprit abandoned his vehicle.
Do you see anyone suspicious-looking leaving?
No, we've only seen other cars coming out of the tunnel.
Not a single living thing left the tunnel by foot.
Why? Why isn't it moving?
Inspector, it's already been 10 minutes.
All right, go look inside the tunnel!
Yes, sir!
Damn it, I have to find a way out quickly.
The transmitter was tossed in the middle of the road inside the tunnel.
So, that means..
The culprit threw out the transmitter and fled with the ransom.
But the "Busy Bee Delivery" truck never came out of the tunnel.
Is that true?
Yes.
The helicopter pilots and I were watching the tunnel's exit meticulously...
But we didn't see the "Busy Bee Delivery" truck leave the tunnel.
Maybe he made a U-turn inside the tunnel.
No, he was driving at a high speed, so it would have been difficult to slow down and turn around.
So, the culprit's vehicle just disappeared in the tunnel?
There is another thing I don't understand.
How did the culprit know about the transmitter?
Sato-kun, I have something I want you to look up.
Yes, sir.
That's strange...
Conan-kun's not answering.
Did something happen?
Huh? What do you think could've happened?
When I asked the "Busy Bee Delivery" company, they told me the whereabouts of all their trucks.
Were there any trucks listed as stolen or hijacked?
There isn't any.
So, we don't have any clues to find the kidnapper?
Next Conan: The Vanished Kidnapper's Getaway Vehicle, Part 2.
Next Conan's Hint!
Plastic bottle.
What about next time?
Please look forward to the next episode!