Deduction flows*wiith the rhythm of the wind
Dark stains are rinsed clean and exposed
The truck and ransom that disappeared
The mysterious veil is peeled off by deduction
He sees through the one and only truth,
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult
No case is left unsolved with Detective Conan.
us? fir
wi¥e
Ve yy, mm wp - 8
» Ww Ya
Www. o
We. the Youth Detective
Squad went to visit
our classmate Jun Kataoka in the hospital.
But,
I was mistaken as being
Jun and kidnapped!
The police pursuesthe Honeybee Courier truck that appears' to get the ransom.
However,
that car suddenly disappeared inside the tunnel:of the expressway.
(527)
The Kidnap Car that Disappeared Part 2
Well, I couldn't help it...
because the battery went dead and I didn't know...
Everybody's probably worried...
Too bad...
We almost made it, and then...
Strange...
Conan's not answering...
I wonder if something's happened?
What?!
What do you mean something?!
Having a child's body is not bad at a time like this...
Inspector!!
We did exactly as the kidnapper told us to, didn't we...
Jun...
Jun's going to be returned to us, isn't he?!
We're doing the best we can
Sachiko?!
«ik & - - dig
What about the rehearsal?
What's up with your rehearsal?!
I explained to the staff that
I will be canceling the show...
Oh no!
You're future depends on it, you know!
Never mind us and go back there.
I'm so worried that I can't just do nothing!
I couldn't possibly do my thing even if I went back there...
And...
How's Jun?
Nothing...
I'm sorry.
We the police are doing all we can to
Iocate the Honeybee courier truck...
the whereabouts of the truck that fled.
Inspector Megure!!
Did you get any new report?
We contacted the Honeybee courier company and
found that all the vehicles are doing their usual rounds, and
all of them are accounted for.
Could the Honeybee courier truck have been stolen?
Are you saying that you have no clue as to the kidnapper?
Well, Inspector?!
Hmm.
Hmm...
excuse me for a moment...
This is Megure...
Officer Takagi!
What!!
Jun came back to the hospital!
Jun!!
PQW -
I'm-so glad, Jun!!
You're okay...
We were really worried about you...
How's your leg?
Nothing's wrong with my leg!
On...
That's good...
Officer Takagi!!
; Just what is the meaning of this?
Well...
The thing is they came back to the hospital on their own.
What?
were you with Jun all this time?
Yeah but .
Yes .
And?...
Where were you all this time?
Where...
Jun, you tell them...
I asked them the same question too. »
but they won't tell me...
It seems that Jun wasn't kidnapped.
Kidnapped ?!
Since he disappeared from the hospital,
we were all worried that he was kidnapped.
What?!
Well,
the bed was empt. you see.
And soon after that we got call demanding ransom...
The bed was empty.
Don't tell me that...
Yeah
Huh
What's the matter?
Big trouble!
Conan is the one who was kidnapped!
What?!
Since Jun said he wanted to go play games,
Conan stayed back at the hospital in his place!
I called him on the Youth
Detective badge several times
but he hasn't answered!
Maybe...
Maybe...what?
Conan?!
Okay,
& \ \ o all done
7 As ¢5
Thank you!
JT DD
You're welcome...
Okay...
Will you explain, Conan?
Yep.
The kidnapper mistook me for Jun and kidnapped me.
Just as I thought...
And?
Where were you after you were kidnapped?
There's this closed down factory-fin Okuhocho.
And was in the basement.
Did you see the kidnapper's face?
He had a mole on the side of his nose.
Officer Takagi.
Call Tomokawa right away and have him draw a composite sketch on the double!
Yes, sir!
I'm so glad everyone's okay
Although the money was taken,
it's-mo big deal if the children are all right.
Jun,
apologize to everyone.
Why 21
because everyone worried about you.
You all worried of your own initiative!
What should I care!
Jun.
Wait!
What do you think you're doing!!
Let me go!!
Ouch!
Darn! Let me go!
That's enough!
What a thing to say after you've done something selfish like this!
Ouch...
I'm sorry... Jun.
It hurt, didn't it?
I'm sorry.
But, Conan got hurt because of you.
But, I'm sorry...
That doesn't mean-that Its okay or me to hit you, does it
Inspector, I'm sorry...
Agh. I'm hun ry
Conan.
I guess we'll get going then
See you.
Yeah.
I've got to stay back and help with the composite sketch...
Huh?
The honeybee couriertruck that went into the tunnel...
Why didn't it come out of the exit...
Hmm...
Huh
It's the same compact truck... after all!
I see, I get it...
Officer Takagi!
Huh
What's the matter?
I've figure out
the mystery of the honeybee courier truck disappearing in the tunnel...
Huh? Really?!
Tell me about it, Officer Takag!!
Why did the kidnapper use such a flashy car
such as the Honeybee Courier truck?!
He probably did so to get our attention...
Yep, and then?
We the police
were only concentrating on looking out for this flashy Honeybee courier.
However
the kidnapper paints, the truck inside the tunnel @
and changed the design of the truck.
That's this compact truck! 2
It didn't disappear,
but rather, deceived us. 2
How long did that compact truck stay inside the tunnel?
About 10 minutes.
Then, wouldn't it be impossible?
It's not possible to paint an entire car in just 10 minutes O
Oh...
I thought it was a pretty good deduction, though...
Officer Takagi!
The body of a man who was strangled to death
was found by the riverbed of Teimusu River.
What?!
The victim is around his 40's and
has a mole on the side of his nose
According to Conan, the kidnapper also had...
Yep.
A mole on the side of his nose!
Then, it could be the same person!
It's possible.
Let's go!
Yes, sir!!
Uh, InspectorMegure.
Wouldn't it be better if I go along too?
Because I saw the kidnapper's face...
Oh, no...
But...
Hmm.
There's nothing to worry about my wound,
I'm just fine...
From the driver's license that the victim had on him,
he is Tadashi Yoshizawa, age 42...
He has strangulation marks on his neck,
so he probably died of suffocation.
'Ah-ls-
I...
And,
this is what we found onthe floor of the passenger's seat...
Huh
Earingh...
This car has been reported stolen 2 days ago.
>TO TO
Uh, Inspector Megure?
Huh?
The person who kidnapped me is this man.
Just as I thought...
And, when is the estimated time of death?
We think it is between 13:00 to 14:00...
So. he was strangled to death right after he made away bwith the cash...
And? What about the cash and all...
There was nothing of that sort anywhere...
Judging from the fact that the cash is gone,
ems most likely that he had an accomplice.
They probably got in to a brawl or something,
which ended up in him being killed...
We need, to do a thorough check this guy Yoshizawa's associates!
Inspector!
Huh
Oh, Officer Sato!
Inspector,
I'm sorry I'm late!
Did you find out anything more?
Yes.
While checking the people who are in close proximity to Mr. Kataoka,
I came across something that may be of concern.
Something of concern?!
Right.
Although it doesn't have the honeybee mark-on it,
this is the truck that was used to kidnap me.
Officer Takagi's deduction was
partially correct after all!
But, how in a matter of
10 minutes inside the tunnel...
es.)
this Is my earing...
I dropped)it somewhere
I was looking for it.
Where did you find this?
Before I answer your question,
I'd like to ask you something.
Do you know a person by the name of Tadashi Yoshizawa)
Yoshizawa?
4 He's man with a mole on the side of his nose, who is around 40 years old...
No, I don't...
What about him?
He was found dead in a compact truck
that was found abandoned by the riverbed of the Teimusu River.
Oh, my!
That earring was found near the corpse.
Huh!
According to Conan,
It seems that there's no mistake that
Yoshizawa is responsible for the kidnapping
Judging from the fact that the ransom was not found anywhere near him,
it Is most likely that he had an accomplice,
who he had a fight with, and as result was killed.
I see...
And, who is this accomplice?
After checking Yoshizawa's residence,
they seem to have found the date of
Jun"s discharge from the hospital tomorrow
marked on the calendar.
In other words,
Yoshizawa and the«accomplice carried out the crime
knowing that he would still be in the hospital
And Yoshizawa did not call
Mr. Kataoka's residence but rather,
called him directly on his cell phone.
And finally,
the tracking device that we put inside the bag with the ransom...
The people who knew about this besides us were very limited.
What are you trying to get at...?
$0, Yoshizawa's accomplice has to be somebody who is very close to you!
By the way, Ms. Ezaki,
we hear that you have debts?
Huh!
For the last two shows you had, you needed 20,000,000 yen,
and for preparation fees for this show you needed 10,000,000 yen...
That makes a total of 30,000,000 yen,
the same amount as the ransom demanded this time...
That's...
How do you intend to pay back your debts?
So if this show that is' to be held succeeds...
it doesn't succeed,
all you'll be left with are the debts.
Please wait!!
Are you saying that she kidnapped Jun because of her debts?!
I can't really say yet.
But it's true that the circumstances
Iook pretty bad for Ms. Ezaki.
"Haven't done anything!
I'don't_,know a person 'by the name of Yoshizawa either...
Anyway
we'll get the details from you at the station...
Will you please come with us?
All right
Just as I thought...
She was after the money after all...
Huh
Ms. Ezaki?
Yeah she came.
About what time? Do you remember?
Before 13-001 think it was...
rote
She came to say that the show today may be cancelled.
13:00...
Yoshizawa's estimated time of death is between 13:00 and 14:00...
So alibi barely makes it...
0° ON
I really don't want her to cancel it
because her designs are fantastic this time.
I'm sure it'll be a success!
Huh?!
Yeah,
Separating trash and throwing them away appropriately is manners, right?
Maybe...
- It's special so there aren't many companies that make it.
Do you know the name of the company?
Yes: of course...
That's right...
Until I get my part from you'.guys,
I can't die even if I wanted to...
Bring the cash and come to the place where the kid was confined!
I'll be waiting...
Wait: Officer Sato,
I don't think that's a good idea!
We can't afford to be going out at a busy time like this
just because Conan:is:itelling us to come
Dent worry, don't worry,
I'll take full responsibility!
Take responsibility, but...
Besides,
no matter how I think it out,
I can't believe that Ms. Ezaki is a culprit.
I feel the same too...
Well,
Conan sure notices a lot of things other people don't,
so he could help us find a lead to something, right?
On...
You said you remembered.something, what is it, Conan? -
This is the factory where you were confined, right, Conan?
There-he-is!
Huh? What?
Shh! Hide!
Huh? That car...
Mr. Kitayama...
Yoshizawa?
Hey, Yoshizawa?
Hey, Yoshizawa'?
It's me!
Mr. Kitayama!
What an unusual place to run into you.
What brings you here?
Nothing.
Really...
You seem to know Tadashi Yoshizawa.
- You came because Mr. Yoshizawa told you to come, right?
Huh
You were told to bring his share of the money
to the place the kid was confined. right?
But, Conan...
This place is known only to me and the kidnapper.
But he knows this place too, which means...
aren't you an accomplice of the kidnapper. mister?
What a thing to say?!
Ali 4 «In
1 OTC...
You would know Mr. Kataoka's cell phone number
and about the tracking device too...
Hey. wait a minute!
You used to work for a printing company before, didn't. ou?
Conan,
what are you trying to get at...
The advertisements that we see on the body of vehicles these days,
those are all printed adhesive seals right?
Are you talking about the wrapping bus?
Wrapping bus...
I see! I got it!
Huh
What?
Live-figured out the mystery
of how the compact Honeybee courier truck disappeared in the tunnel!
Yoshizawa wrapped the truck that he stole,
then he went to get the ransom
While he fled on the truck, he peeled off the wrapping in the tunnel,
pretended to be a different truck and got away
Mr. Kitayama,
aren't you the one who printed that seal?!
Well?!
This I's ridiculous!
Everything you're: saying is based on assumption!!
Huh
What's this...
bag...
Look, Officer Takagi.
There's so much money inside!
Mr. Kitayama,
we'd like to talk to you so could you come with iusato the station?
Darn!
Officer Sato!!
No way!
Officer Takagi!!
Move!
Hold it!
Goro Kitayama,
you're.under arrest for obstructing official duty and inflicting injury!
Ouch...
ou killed Tadashi Yoshizawa and
put Ms. Ezaki's earring near his corpse to confuse investigation, didn't you?
Isn't Yoshizawa alive?
What are you talking about?
He was found dead!
Who called me on the phone then?
What:ithe hell are you talking about?!
DISA SITIO SKS IS
WR 2 {SASHA
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
£202
- - foo
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
ScriptsBy .
KANJI KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI K@QUCHI
JUNI@HI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI a '0 ot, a >» ,
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chicf-Dircctor.
KENJIIKODAMA
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
Issocration with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CONAN
COSI) AOYAMA SHOCGCARURK AN YTV ATS
All Rid his reserved
Wow... How fantastic...
Ayumi, is this all there is to a fashion:show?
They serving us food and stuff part way, aren't they?
Gee, I tell you, Genta, of course not!
Didn't I tell you that
I'd be boring for kids...
Let me introduce you!
The designer of this collection, .
Sachiko Ezaki!!
' 9.) * 0
Thank you, Jun
The tuxedo looks really nice on you...
Dad told me to give you this bouquet...
Congratulations...
Mother...
But, it seems Heiji was waiting in front of this door for a long time.
Look on the side of the paper.
Isn't that the mark of the cap that Hell's always wearing?
But this tape...
A long time has passed since it peeled off.
In other words,
Kusukawa intended to come back right away,
but something came up and he couldn't
Next" Conanrs Hint
Heiji*Hattori,No Way-Out~, Part 1