The rhythm of the wind clears reasoning,
Always unveiling alibi tricks.
The Detective of the West is back in Tokyo!
He's forced to send an S.O.S.!
Recognizing that single truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is Detective Conan!
How's this, Kazuha?
Not quite, Heiji. More to the left.
The left? How's this?
Ouch! What're you doing, Heiji!? I said left!
Fool, be quiet or they'll hear us!
Damn, the pin fell between the flooring.
What do you mean? We can't do this without it
Don't you have some other type of wire?
No, that was the only one.
Damn...
Hey, wouldn't it be better to just solve this code?
They said they would release us if we did.
That's right.
If you wanna be outside enjoying the sun,
It's in your best interest to solve it quickly.
Or else...
Kusukawa-san!
You'll end up as cold as this guy.
H-Heiji...
Don't worry, they don't know that guy.
We can count on him.
That guy?
Right... That guy.
I know we can count on that guy!
Hattori Heiji's Desperate Situation, Part One!
They're late, Heiji-niichan and Kazuha-neechan...
Yeah.
It's already past 2:00, meaning they're already an hour late...
Then why don't you call them? Doesn't one of them have a cell?
Yeah, I tried, but it's off.
Well, maybe they forgot about today and overslept?
But Hattori-kun's mom said they got on a plane at 8:00 A.M.
8:00 AM, eh? That's an early flight, so they should already be here...
Oh, that's right, they did have somewhere to go.
They said they're meeting up with a friend of Toyama's, Kazuha-chan's father, who was once an officer.
They said his name was Kusukawa-san, who works for a detective agency here in Tokyo.
Could they have meant Kusukawa from the Haido Detective Agency?
You know him?
Yeah, he's a big gambler. I think he got discharged because of it
Hey, why did Heiji-niichan have to visit him?
Well, it seems that Kusukawa-san wrote to Kazuha-chan's dad saying they had to talk.
And since Kusukawa-san never responded, he's having them check up on him.
Well then, they probably just got caught up talking about her father.
You think so?
Well, I'll give him a call.
Sign: Haido Detective Agency
Yes, Haido Detective Agency.
Oh, Mouri-san! How are you?
Huh? Kusukawa?
Actually, we haven't heard from him a few days.
Well, he did mention he was working on a big case of his own. Maybe he's on a stake-out.
A big case?
You need someone to play Mahjong with or something?
Note: Mahjong is a game of Chinese origin usually played
by four persons with tiles resembling dominoes.
Ah, no, I was just wondering if two high school kids came around asking for him.
Oh, you're in luck. A boy and girl from Osaka, right?
They left after I gave them Kusukawa's home address.
Would you mind giving me that address as well?
Haido City, Arhito Building.
Jeez, this is ridiculous.
The hosts shouldn't have to search for the guests.
Oh come on, you weren't doing anything at home anyway.
As always...
I really hope the rain stops soon.
Conan-kun, you have a field trip, right?
Ah, yeah.
Ah, isn't that the Arihito Building?
Let's see... Kusukawa-san...
Room 202.
'202, eh?
Room 202...
Huh?
"I'll be back by noon. Deliver any packages to the landlord."
Hey, hey, it's way past noon.
Seems he's still unreliable.
Maybe he was here when they came by,
And they decided to go out for tea.
Maybe they thought they'd be back by noon.
Oh yeah, I saw a family restaurant on the way.
But Heiji-niichan stood here for a longtime.
Look, to the right of the note.
Don't you recognize that?
That wet mark has the symbol from Heiji-niichan's hat on it
It's true, that is Hattori-kun's mark.
I'd say he waited hours here waiting for him to come home.
What makes you say hours?
Because there's a mark at my height, too.
He probably crouched down because he was tired of standing, right?
That's likely.
Scotch tape?
I've seen this. It's used to see if anyone goes in before you.
Yeah, you see it a lot in detective and spy movies.
Well, since the tape's been peeled off, does that mean someone broke in?
Maybe Kusukawa-san saw it and was scared enough to go to the police.
But it's been awhile since the tape was peeled off.
Dust has even collected on the adhesive side.
Hey, hey...
Then, why the hell'd he post this notice?
That means Kusukawa-san hasn't returned yet...
From an errand he figured wouldn't take long.
Something must have happened while he was out...
Dad, what should we do?
What is there to do?
Ah, hey, Conan-kun!
The door's unlocked?
I knew someone broke in!
Hey!
I don't see any sign of intrusion inside this room or on the door.
Maybe he really did forget to lock the door?
He must have forgotten about the tape on the door and opened it
Huh, what's this?
Eh? What is it?
Look over here.
It looks like something was darkened in here by pencil.
What'd you say?
Maybe it was one of these sticky notes?
Look, it's a perfect fit
I see.
If you write hard enough, it'll impress your writing onto the page below as well.
The Osaka kid must have been worried since Kusukawa was missing and the door was unlocked.
He probably shaded it over to investigate.
Well, it's too bad he took the memo with him.
Now we'll never know what was written there.
But look, I can still get characters from the top sheet
I see, the shading for the second sheet made it go through to the third sheet as well.
Let's see, "Kenbashi City, Ito Residence."
I think there was a phone number as well, but it's unreadable.
But Hattori-kun and Kazuha-chan might have gone there, right?
Then let's go find them.
We can get all of the possible addresses from the police.
Sign: Ito Residence
Two high schoolers speaking kansai-ben?
They didn't come here. You some kind of cop?
Ah, no, we're just looking for those high schoolers.
Sorry for disturbing you.
No, no students speaking kansai-ben.
But aren't you Sleeping Kogorou-san!?
Osaka high schoolers?
I thought the Koushien happened already.
I don't know who you're talking about Don't come by again.
Sign: Ito Residence
High schoolers speaking kansai-ben?
No, I haven't seen them.
As I thought...
Sorry I couldn't help you.
That badge...
An attorney's badge?
Could you be Ito Misari-san, the attorney?
Really?
Yeah, that's right.
My mother has talked about you before.
She said you would represent anyone's case for a song.
Oh, so your mother is an attorney as well?
Yep!
Hey, that's about enough of that.
Um...
Do you know of any strange Ito residences in the area?
A strange residence?
Now that you mention it, I do remember one.
It's a western style mansion with an "Ito" nameplate, just behind an elementary school five blocks from here.
Children have been saying they see the same two homeless people enter and leave at night
There we go!
That's where they went
Let's go there.
T-There?
It'll be fine.
Let's go.
Thanks for your help.
No problem.
Now, now.
Let's go back inside.
Oh, I bet you're hungry.
But you'll have to wait just a little bit.
Mama's busy right now.
After I finish my lecture,
I'll feed you.
I have to go...
Teach this boy...
About how desperate his situation really is.
He'll learn to play by my rules from now on.
My, my, take a look at you.
Your handsome face is ruined.
This foolish brat thought he could call out for help.
Heiji, are you okay? Hang in there.
You'll have to hang in there.
Who would have thought a boy like you would know that famous detective Mouri Kogorou.
You're a popular one, aren't you, High school detective Hattori Heiji-kun?
Well, I brought you here because I believed you were rather clever.
Listen carefully.
You will solve the code this dirty rat of a detective made.
Don't you think he's one big joke?
That guy came here to lecture me.
"I have a tape which shows you are teaching top politicians and businessmen about tax evasion.
"You should stop now."
He told us the tape was in a rental locker at Teito Bank,
And that the seven digit pen number is encrypted.
It's unfortunate that he stopped breathing early, huh?
It was then that I got your call.
S-Sorry...
My ears are ringing.
Would you mind repeating...
Who you think is a dirty rat?
Heiji!
Shut up, brat!
You still don't understand, huh?
Since he has no use for them, cut off his deaf ears.
Heiji!
Stop!
Jeez...
Why am I getting so many guests today?
That kid from earlier?
Oh, boy. Do you need something?
Did you forget something?
It's just that something's bothering me.
K-Kudo...
What is it?
It's those shoe prints.
See, there are a lot of wet shoe prints here, so I figured you had a guest.
Ah, one of my clients visited me with his family.
They came while it was raining to thank me for winning their case, but I've been alone ever since.
But they're all going in.
None of them are coming out
Why?
That's right, because they're mine.
I haven't been outside of the house because they threatened me with a gun at the door.
Ah,
those are from my jogging shoes.
Yours?
Yep, they would be out here, but I was washing the mud off in the bathroom.
Conan-kun!
What're you doing?
We need to get going.
Well, they're calling for you, boy.
Don't you need to look for your male and female friends?
You wanna die right now!?
What was that noise? It came from upstairs.
W-Well...
You said you were here alone, right?
I'll go look, alright?
It may be a burglar!
The cat...
Well, look who it is.
That's bad.
Don't push stuff over the stairs.
She's a little naughty sometimes.
All she does is knock things over.
She must have made that noise earlier.
I have to be somewhere soon, but...
If it'll satisfy you, we can walk around the house.
Alright, come on.
She's trying to trick him like that?
That fool, Kudou would never fall for that
Is something wrong
Don't you want to come in, Detective-kun?
Nah, I gotta go.
Oh, really?
You don't want me to show you around?
Nope.
Seeya lady!
"Bye"? Hey, hey...
Bye, boy.
Looks like they're gone.
Heh, that was close.
It seems you're out of luck, your potential rescuer was a kid.
N-No! What's he doing?
He's really leaving!
He's thinking of how to rescue us.
See, he's in deep thought.
You fool, look closer.
He's embarrassed to be hugged like that, but he's happy, too. He has no idea...
What are you talking about? I meant Sleeping Kogorou-san.
Oh?
That geezer's probably listening to a horse race.
Alright, almost there!
We have no choice.
I'll have to break the glass so they'll have to...
What the hell are you doing!?
Geez,
This is becoming tiresome.
Well, are you ready to work?
You'll try hard, won't you?
To Osaka's renowned high school detective Hattori Heiji, this should be as easy as simple math.
Isn't that right?
Now hurry.
I want it before sunset
You don't want to be...
Beaten to death like him, right?
What's the hurry?
Why can't you take a little more time?
Or, could it be, there's something that's forcing you to do it today?
Yeah, there is.
This guy said that, tomorrow, at his detective agency,
A package would arrive which implicated a well known attorney in a tax evasion scheme.
It supposedly has a copy of the code and an explanation regarding the tape in the Toutou bank locker...
Which all points to me.
But he was a fool.
He thought that just because his friends knew,
He would be safe from me and couldn't be hurt
He said, "Start clean and I'll keep your sins to myself."
But it was obvious he was in it for blackmail,
Probably just so he could gamble it all away.
Gamble?
That's right, Dad did tell me...
Kusukawa-san is a well known gambler.
Fool, why didn't you tell me that earlier!?
Oh? You have something?
Yeah. If you give me a moment in peace, I can get it
Fine.
We'll have some tea downstairs.
You better get it
I'm sure you can get this.
Yeah. I'm 100% sure.
Alright, you can talk now, Kusukawa-san.
You're still alive, right?
The dust near your nose has been moving.
You're really just like your father...
I really was out cold until just now...
Well, keep pretending you're dead.
If they know you're alive,
They'll force you to give it to them by pointing the gun at us.
I must admit, this secret "code" is just like you.
It's just like him?
You know it, Heiji? You know the whole answer?
Yeah, it's easy to remember if you gamble.
Say, Kusukawa-san,
Is there really only one copy of that code?
Yeah, as long as they didn't make copies...
That's perfect
It perfectly fits the gamble we're about to take.