Deduction flows with the
rhythm of the wind
Beductio flows with the
Dark stains are rinsed clean and exposed
Danger-iséstilll in the air
We'll have to be sharp to
capture the criminal!
He sees through the one
and only truth,
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
(57a 3
(DH * X
Am 7 WW 4c
we 9%
We were supposed to meet with Heij
and Kazuha, but they did not ome.
We decided to go look for them .
We called on Mr. Kusukawa,
the detective,
and foundiout they went to a certain tou
residence on Kashikobashi street, but
Oh. You're hungry. aren't you. dear.
But could you wait a little while, dear.
Your mom is busy right now.
After I finish my work,
I'll feed you right away. dear.
I must let them know where they stand
and teach them a lesson.
Heiji Hattori No Way Out
Part 2
Nuts! Wherelar those Osaka kids!
Wandering around?
I'm completely tired out.
Cheer up, dad. Let's have lunch and
then start searchinglfondhe Item's again.
We could have passed them on the way
Why do I have to have lunch
at this old restaurant at this time...
It's no use complaining now, dad.
Besides I Kd of like
this house. It's old fashioned.
Old fashioned, it is.
You don't see a horoscope dispenser
so often any more thesexdays.
Make another phone call, Ran.
They may have gone
to my detective agency.
Yes, dad. I've tried
calling from time to time.
But the phone won't connect.
Hello?
It's me.
Hem?
What!?
Give me the phone!
Hey. you guys!
Where on earth are you?
SOD. SONY
I'm with Mr. Kusukawa.
In a coffee shop.
We've been talking about detective
business and forgot to
get in.touch with you
Then. is Kazuha there with you-too?
Don't worry about her.
She is alright.
By the way, pops.
I'd like to ask you a favor,
we have a cipher and
we want you to solve it.
A cipher?
Mr. Kusukawa made
the cipher and I promised
I tried everything but I couldn't solve it
so I thought of getting your help
while Mr. Kusukawa is out
Oh? Mr. Kusukawa is not with you?
One of his Mahjong pals
called him on the phone.
They need one more player.
He went outside to
tell them he can't make it
Well, I will mail the cipher
on the phone right now.
You send me the solution by sundown.
Let me know the seven
numerals hidden in that cipher.
Seven numerals?
If you can't-solve it, I can't
come to you, so hang in there!
Hey! Wait!
Dang it.
Smart kid you are to let Kogoro
Mouri think it over for you.
Thanks
Now we need to mail the cipher.
He soiled the paper with his blood
SO we can't read the lower half of it.
What!?
Didn't you make a copy of it?
No. After we got that cipher, were
busy interrogating Kusukawa.
I have memorized all of it.
49 numerals and the order
of the alphabets
Why, really? Then, tell me all 49
Ietters without looking at the paper
but if you give me even
one wrong number,
you will get stained with the
blood of that girlfriend of yours.
What's thisyy
I can't make any sense out of this.
Me, too.
Numerals and, four alphabets
Q A. K, J, these could be...
I have no idea what
they are supposed to mean!
But, Heiji said he won't budge
an inch until he solves this.
I don't care!
Oh, Conan? Did you find out anything?
A little
Oh. What's that?
You see? These letters, A. J, Q, and K
remind me of the letters on playing cards.
So I've changed them into numbers.
And, what then?
Then the numbers turned
out to be 64 in all.
Bu WM noticed that there is
onedllone number
Oh. That's the nine in the center.
There's' only one nine.
Yeah. Take that nine, and
the remainMg 63 numerals
will make 7 grips of 9 numerals.
If there are seven numerals
in this cipher,
each of the seven groups
should be a certain number
You can't s8lve it like math.
You've just made more numbers
that you don't understand.
Here you are, the diced steaks, sir.
This is just the thing
I've been waiting for.
Hi. This 1s the Kidrs Lunch Plate.
Say, pops. Can it be
Mr. KusuRawa who coded this cipher?
I see. That's why the
center is a nine.
Here is your omelet- Miss.
Oh! It"looks delicious.
Conan
It's rather simple, once
you figure out how to Give it.
Still, this looks strange. The first four are
numerals but the lastethree are not
Wait
I saw these somewhere before...
Now the time is up
We have to go, otherwise we won't make
it in time to use the safe-deposit box.
If you want to blame someone, blame it
on that incompetent detective of yours.
Wait! I may be able to
solve it overnight.
You can go to the
bank tomorrow before the
Ietter is delivered to the
detective agency.
We are not worried about it.
Because the letter will not be delivered.
Oh. Hey, you are not going to...
Yes, we are
We'll ambush the deliveryman in front of
the office and rob him of the letter.
We will keep paying the fee for using
the safe into the bank
account of Kusukawa,
and the tape will not
come out into this world.
We will take time
to solve the cipher.
Unlike you guys. I have
unlimited time on my side
Now. If you have anything
Ieft to say, I'll listen to you.
To listen to a person with genuine
concern is a duty for a lawyer.
Darn! Kudo, you dumbbell.
What are you doing?
You don't seem to have any concern
for this world, well then, as you wish
I do, I do. I have a lot.
I have so many things
to say that I was at a loss.
More than anything else, I want to
say a word to the girl behind me.
Wow. What do you want to say to her?
You know she will be
dead soon, don't you?
Very important things to say that I
wanted to tell her for a long time.
So. would you mind putting your
gun on the floor while I talk to her?
Well, well. After all, you are high
school kids. Excuse me for being dense.
This will do, I hope.
You can start telling her, dear.
Oh, don't rush me.
I am choosing the best words for her.
So she will be impressed and can go to
heaven with those words of mine.
They must be fascinating and,
wonderful words.
He's still alive.
Darn!
It's a pity, Heiji. It was such a good
strategy for taking the gun from me.
Trategy, was it...
Now get this!
But we are lucky to find the guy
who made the cipher to be alive.
Give me the answer to the cipher.
Or do you want to see the head
of your kid friend here blown apart?
Don't tell her, Mr. Kusukawa.
If you do, it'll only buy you a little
more time to go to heaven.
So let's make them regret
what they're doing.
You talk too much, brat.
Heiji!
Now hurry up! Give me the
answer before I count up to five.
We are running out of time!
So I won't hesitate
to fire at the first person.
Stop it please.
One!
I really mean it, Kazuha...
Two.
I really wanted to tell you before I die.
Three.
I tried to tell you many times...
Four.
When we were back to back
and I felt you trembling
I wanted to say...
Five.
Oh. A mail
From Kogoro Mourn?
They couldn't possibly have
solved the cipher so soon!
It doesn't look like an
answer to me.
Didn't they just send
back what we sent them?
No. Some of the numerals and
alphabets are in different order.
What!
Hey, give me the phone.
Oh. No. Uh. Could I take
a look at it, please?
There, take a look.
It looks exactly like the
cipher I gave you to solve.
Looks very much like it, yeah
But, this is an answer to the mail we sent.
This says they found the seven
numerals hidden in the cipher.
You are not making it up, are you?
Then tell us.
I can't tell you here.
Little one, you don't know what a
sorry pickle you're in, do you?
You don't know what pickle you're in.
Kogoro Mouri knows
the answer to the cipher.
Furthermore, he knows that Mr.
Kusukawa made the cipher, and also that
We are with Mr. Kusukawa.
If we three disappeared at one time,
that will make the detective
think hard and
he will find out the meaning of the
seven numerals hidden in the cipher.
And that the 7 digit number is an ID.
He will take less than a week
to find them all...
You sent your cipher to Kogoro Mouri
knowing what he will do all the while...
We'll be in big trouble, Miss.
We can kill them and run, can't we?
You talk too much...
You have only two choices.
You Kill us and let Mourn
get the tape and listen to it
Or let me go get the tape, and
exchange us for the tape
Actually, Mr. Kusukawa
can go instead of me,
but he can't possibly play the role
with that swollen face of his.
So I'm telling you I will go
instead of him for you.
And, listen, if as Mr. Kusukawa told you,
If you stop doing bad things
and promise not to kill us,
I won't turn you in to the police,
so don't worry.
You can't fool me.
You're going to get
the tape and rush it to the police.
One of you can come with
me to watch over me
and keep me from doing
anything funny.
You don't have much time to think.
If we don't get going now,
we won't make it in time for
using the safe-deposit.
I see. OK. I will accept your terms.
But if the answer to the cipher proves
wrong, you know what will become of you.
Now, Heiji can go with me,
and the young lady
can stay here with him.
Heiji!
What is it, Kazuha?
If, if we make it through...
If we make it through, will you tell
me what you were going to tell me me?
Sure. I'll keep on telling you until
you get tired of hearing it.
Help...
It's gasoline.
As soon as we get a phone call from her
saying that she's got the tape,
we'll set fire .
That kid will be surprised to learn
that you are not in front of
the house waiting for him.
But are inside the house
and that it's on fire.
Now=Heiji. dear.
Be quick about it.
Enter the seven numbers
hidden in the cipher.
Well, don't ou want to
know how to solve the cipher?
No. that can wait.
Since that cipher was made by
Mr. Kusukawa, the gambling man,
you can easily see that those A, J,
Q, and K are of playing cards.
-- OD) --
Change them into numbers,
And we have 64 numerals in all
Now, something bothers me
and it's a 9 in the center.
There are lots of 1 to-6
numbers but only one 9.
That's when it hit me
that if I take out the 9,
I can divide the remaining 63 numerals
by 9 and get 7 groups of numbers.
These 7 groups of numbers
can stand for a 7-digit number.
And all numbers are in 1 to 6.
For a gambling man, 1 to 6
means only one thing. doesn't it?
A die Of the dice
This means put the 9
numerals of 7 groups into
numeraso Qroups no
The form of dice of 3 by 3 squares.
4 A a4 ta @ su a )
J lll$fill
the form of dice of 3 by 3 squares.
But. what and where are the 7 numerals?
Let's change the
numbers into the dots of dice.
And imagine we are looking at the dice.
29464303
striking, now you can read the seven numbers
striking, now you can
read the seven numbers
So the number comes up to 3156204
Reading the dice, it's 3156204
Probably, the cipher was made into
squares with the center to be 9
because of the image
of dice and dots on them.
There! Look! It's opened.
So this is it! The tape you wanted to get.
Looks like it. Now give it to me fast.
Before doing so. you will
Iearn another interesting tale.
The lower half of the cipher I sent
to Kogoro. is:slightly changed.
The lower three numerals were
changed to stand for alphabets.
Al- Alphabets?
Right. One capital
and two small case letters.
Libra, the Balance. A Latin for the
balance scale shortened to I I B.
Libra?
You don't know? You wear it
on"your lapel, don't you?
The lawyers' pin in the
form of the balance.
Then. Kogoro Mourn
might go to my house.
He probably went and did it
cause he sent me back that mail of his.
A mail?
G-E-T THEM O-U-T,
Take them outside-the house to
reduce the number of bad guys
I can't believe it
You'd better believe it.
Because you have no...
Hands in this game.
Hey. are you there? Show up
guys. you're up there, aren't you?
Don't be so slow, come on up guys.
Miss. It's you?
So quick isn't it?
Did you forget something ?
Hey!
What's wrong?
It's a soccer ball?
Who... who is it?
I don't get it really, but
I called the police already...
and I just hope I did
something right for them.
The police arrived in time to securely
protect Kazuha and Mr. Kusukawa.
The dishonest lawyer and
her two men were arrested.
And the case of the cipher,
illegal tax;evasion.
And confinement was
solved and closed in anzinstant.
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers
MM SZHIFTOIYOXHIUKA
Background Music
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
Scripts 'By.
KANIPKASHIWABARA
KAZUNARIIKOUQHI
JUNICHI MIYASH TIA
YUICHI FIIGURE
Fa SHIKI INOUE
Scripts By
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
NARI KO
CHI HIG!
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
Art Director.
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chic Director.
KEN]! KODAMA
Produced By -
TMSIENTERTAINMENT, LTD
ny association with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE C NAN
OL GOMTO AOYAMA 1 SHOGAKUKAN YTV - [MS
All Ris,) Reserved
So you used that voice changer to. mimic
her voice and lured them to come out.
Then you used that anesthetic gun and
a soccer ball to knock them down, wow.
That was great, Kudo.
You can thank me for it.
I had to come out of the toilet of
a restaurant to go up to you.
If you didn't leave like
you did back then,
things wouldn't have gotten
as complicated as this.
I'have no idea that'd you'd be held up
by a middle-agedilady'like her.
Conan, are you alright?
Your Kid's lunch's gotten cold!
Oh. I'll be with you in a minute.
A Kid's lunch for you?
Ran sometimes orders it for
a nice kid like me.
Well, it served as a
hint for solving the cipher.
Yeah, the red circle on the flag and the
one on the die is the same.
By the way. why did Mr. Kusukawa
why did you go to her
to talk her out of doing wrong,
despite knowing thatyou'd be
great bait for the mass media.
Long time ago. Mr. Kusukawa's
mom got help from that lawyer.
His mother suffered;great losses in-a
fraud and that-lawyer
helped her at"that time,
sO his»mother is very grateful.
Because of this memory,
he went to her to talk her
out of doingillegal business.
I'm really grateful to you...
I was really in deep
water when you came...
What deep water
are you talking about?
You mean the time when you really
wanted to tell me something?
Kazuha!
What was it?
What did youswant to tell me-when you
felt me trembling against your back?
You better not hear it.
You told me you'd tell
until I get tired of hearing it.
What on earth was it?
That's uh... It was...
It was?
It's about...
Every time you trembled/~éhtod me...
your hair like a horse tail pricked me on
my neck'andsmade me so ticklish.
I'm really sorry for you
Drop dead for once!
A fire man?
From this year, there has
been multiple fire incidents.
Theres always this one thing he
Ieaves at the incident place
A red horse doll.
I know the next place
his going te burn down.
I have nothing to do this weekend.
I'll go visit that persons house.
Red Horse in the Fire
Part 1