Deduction flows with the rhythm of the wind
I08'?
Dark stains are. rinsed clean and exposed
In the midest of a slightly strange coldness
a fiery map will light the way through!
He sees through the one and only truth,
A child in appearance with the IQ. of an adult
no case is left unsolved with Detective Conan.
("A /
('Nu
(1+ 5)
Red Horse in the Fire
Part 1
So. I gave it to the lady!
I told her to cive in. That she had no chance of winning this game...
But, its, all thanks to Pops!
Because he solved the hidden message that
Heiji had put in the code and saved us!
What
Don't talk about the past
Pops. yourjglass is empty!
Here. have another shot!
You're the one who brought the subject up...
But. that lady was really the pits,
- S he tried; to) burn us to death...
Burn you to death?
She was going to set fire to her own house and tell the court that somebody
who held a grudge on her set fire to her house,
didn't make it out of the house in time and burned to death.
Well. that sure was dangerous...
If worse came to worse
it could've been blamed 0 Mhe arsonist that's been causing panic in this area
An arsonist?
From the start of this year there have been a series of arson cases
A series, which means that the method of arson is the same?
No, there's no similarity in the method ofiarson...
but there's always this one thing left at the site of the fire...
a doll of a red herse!
A.A red horse?
See, the arsonist is hinting on the code word of the police "Red horse
The arsonist is probably making fun of the police
and provoking the police,
I'm the arsonist, catch me if you can!
Well, but'itys:fortunate that nobody died in the three arsons committed so far.
And? Are the three cases connected in any way?
Well, it seems that these three cases are not connected at all
The addresses are scattered too...
The (first one was at Rizencho 1-chome
* 1 p-
1 v py
The second at Toriyacho 2-chome
E&Y A
FF IF= and the third at Okuhocho 3-chome
And the third at Okuhocho 3-chome
and the third at Okuhocho 3-chome
[371 - and the third at Okuhocho 3-chome
Which means the next arson will be in the 4-chome area somewhere.
Y, reah, If the arsonist
Is setting fire at random.
It's possible
so the police is keeping an eye on the 4-chome area within town
But, there are so many 4-chomes all over the place
But, I know of a house that may be a target!
I was asked by Mr. Kusukawa a while ago to go over to a person's house.
To take over investigation of a suspicious person that was seen
Iate at night loitering around a house near Haidocho 4-chome!
Well, I don't really have anywhere to go this holiday,
So, I'll take this kid and go to that person's house tomorrow!
You can take dad. but not @€@onan.
A field trip?
We may be able to get a clue to the serial arsonist and
you're going to go hand in handfon an excursion, you brat?!
What's the big deal. he's only a kid...
But, I wonder if the weather's going to be okay. It's still raining...
It'll be fine, because of this!
This sunny boy doll always cleared the weather
for Shinichi's important soccer matches...
Ran, you make me so jealous!
Oh, well; it's hard going to root for him in the rain besides
That's why it's most likely going
- - to be a fine day tomorrow, Conan!
Strange...
The odds of the rain clearing used to be 1000...
Maybe you didn't wish hard enough, Ran?
Because it's not for Shinichi...
D.Don't be ridiculous! That's not true!
Wait that's 'strang;...
When we'hung it out last night it was:-facing out towards the window
well, it can't be helped, the weather depends on the mood of the sun!
Don't tell me that he .
Wow, your sunny boy doll 's starting to take effect now?
WiWell, 1600.bad...
The heavens are going to punish you ne of these days...
We'll do some more shopping and go home
Heiji and Pops work hard at your detective job!
Yeah!
Let's get going now.
Those two really get along well. don't they
Oh, Kazuha; don't tell me that you're jealous of Conan?
That's not it!
And? What time and where in 4-chome?
Haidocho 4-chome at the
Moromizu residence at 16:00
Don't worry, 'cuz Pop's agency is not on 4-chome.
Oh, See...
There. here it is!
But-we're 30 minutes late for the appointment, what now
It's only 30 minutes... §
Mr. Kusukawa told me not to be late
because this person's really fussy-about time
good afternoon!
I don't need any.
Please leave!
I'm going to call the police if you don't!
Oh so like I told you, I'm- not here to sell anything to you.
I just brought some catalogs of the hanging
scrolls and vases that we sell in our store
I've been telling you for a while now.
I'm not interested in dusty junk like that!
Then I ll leave our catalog and a key holder that will bring about good business,
SO please stop by at our shop when you feel like it...
No need to worry.
I'm not is") hard up for money
that I have to rely on something like that!
\ Go on! /And! leave right this minute!
I.I'm sorry to have intruded on you.
And? Now what's with all of\ ou?/
Oh: well, we're detectives here in place of Mr. Kusukawa...
Never mind that case already
It seems to have been my imagination...
Hey, hey...what's the story?
It can't be helped because Mr. Kusukawa was confined from 3 days ago
But, isnt. it strange to say that-it was just her imagination
14/1 wheén{she was troubled enough to hire a detective?
Yeah, I swear there's something fishy.about that lady
Hello
Oh, you're early today, Sensei.
See! I did Just as you told me
From Fen Shui's »0int of view, it is very good to decorate ceramic ware,
which is said to be great for any direction,
at the front door of theghouse that is the entrance of good luck!
Well, let's talk inside.
Oh. he's just a teacher of Feng Shun
May I help you?
Oh, no, nothing really.
Talk-about a lot of make-up.
Hey, what's with you?! I thought
I told you not to come here anymore, Keiko!
Don't get angry at me. « oko.
I've been unlucky this month
$0 I wonder if you can spare 100.000 yen, no, 50,000 yen will do...
If you're unlucky, why don't you do some thing about it with your own fortunetelling!
She's a fortuneteller...
Dang, it's already been 2 hours.
Waiting in a place like this is going to get us nowhere
But the man that just went in hasn't 'come out yet!
I'll go check inside.
Hey, you!
What are you doing.
He seem to be looking for something...
Too bad!
It's not there, . no matter how hard you look.
It's a video tape that is proof of our relationship.
SO of course I hid it some place very special in this house!
I'm keeping it as a guarantee that-you will divorce
your wife and marry me instead. Sensei.
My husband will be coming home soc
ou re 90mg < run mg WI 1 your college friends, aren't you?
You may relax on the sofa till then.
Really, I don't understand adults, honestly
It's scary 'cuz even your relationship with your wife who you've been living
separately from all these years seem to look better...
Be quite.
Hey.
Isn't that guy from before?
I wonder what he's doing?
He's probably working overtime because he can't fill his quota
It seems her husband's finally come home
Ikm:home:
Oh my. hello dear.
Hello, Morosumi
Oh, Soga. you're here already
Yeah...
Let me use the bathroom
Can you get the engine running while you're waiting?
No! If you're going out drinking. walk!
Okay. And, would you like to come along too, for a change.
No thank you, because I can't drink
I also want to watch the soccer game that will be aired at midnight,
SHl'd like to take a short nap too...
Too bad.
The conversationthat the two men would have over drinks drew some interest but
How long do you intend to stay fooling around out there!
Hurry up and come on home!
We got a call from Ran, so we decided to head on home...
Hey, Heiji! Just what do you think you're doing!
I went out of my way 1 make dinner for you and it's all cold already!
Where are you now
The Morosumi residence where I accepted the work of the detective...
What? You just said you're headed home because you finished the job!
Yeah, that's what we were planning to do,
but we passed a fire engine on the way back.
We got concerned and headed back to the residence
and found it blazing outrageously...
The Morosumi residence...
It's this way, hurry!
RRyoko...
It seems like that woman didn't escape in time...
If we just kept watching, this wouldn't have happened...
But. isn't it strange?
Those two went outsto drink-right?
Not even-an-hour has past yet. and I wonder-why they:came back?
True
Maybe they had a premonition of some kind?
See, mommy, it came after all, didn't it?
A red horse that causes fire!
Hey kid! How come you knew that a red horse was coming?
Because I saw it!
When and where?
Hey. who are you people?
You really saw it?
I'm not lying! It was only the shadow of the horse, but...
Shadow?
Yep!
It was when I was watching
Kamen Yaiba in the living room!
When Yaiba's first song started,
it suddenly got bright outside
so I looked outside and was surprised!
A shadow of a horse about this big was on the curtain!
Which way I's your house?
On the right of the burning house?
Or, on the left?
To the right!
H Hey?
A horse, by the window!
There's a red horse!
Which means that the room ta boy was watching TV in, is this room
Yeah, the shadow, of the horse showed up on this curtain...
Kaimen Yaiba starts at 7:30 pm
If it got bright during the opening of the program and the shadow was reflected
The arsonist set fire and put-the horse in place a little after 7:30 pm
Yeah, at least we know that the arsonist was near this window about that time.
Uh, so the horse set the fire after all, right, mommy?
Two hours later, the fire that took the life of
"oko Moresumi W's finally extinguished
Will you let me in just for a minute?
No way!
Then, will you at least tell me where the fire first broke out?
What's the big deal giving out a little info?
I can't do what I can't do, even if it's for you, Mr. Mouiril!
Hey, hey, the scene of a fire is not territory for the homicide division, is it?
0.0ld man fire of the 1st division?!
Hey, Mouri! How dare you call your former superior old man fire!
Former superior?
Inspector Yuminaga of the Metropolitan
Police Arson Investigation
Division section 1!
I thought you belonged to the homicide division?
I used to be in the arson division for a little while...
You sure caused me a lot of agony.
Every time there's a fire you claim that it's arson and go out to the scene of the fire,
and step all over the personal effects left there...
God knows how many complaints
I got of you from the fire department
Right, hey!
The same goes for you too
This fire is undoubtedly arson
The red horse was found at the site of this fire too
We checked it out with the forensic officers and
found that it was a perfect match with the other three horses.
But Mr. Yuminaga,
isn't there a possibility that somebody who saw the
the incident in the newspaper or something tried copying?
You foo!
How can you make the exact same horse by just seeing it in the papers?
That plastic horse is made of the same mold.
And is not sold anywhere
so the arsonist probably took fun in making it himself
The arsonist was probably having fun challenging the police,
but somebody has been killed this time...
So, the fun's over...
And, where did the fire start?
Who's this boy here, your assistant?
Y.Yes, well, sort of...
The fire started in the hut beyond the right side of the house
The storeroom with the window where the red horse was placed
There were traces of kerosene poured on the floor.
So, the arsonist probably poured the kerosene
in from the open window and set fire
There were a lot of strange footprints by
the window of the room in the foreground of the storeroom.
If we check the footprints carefully
I'm sure we'll at least get to grab the tail of the arsonist
Oh, well, the thing is...
What!
Your footprints are mixed up in the footprints there?
I'm actually here because I was asked to come here by Mrs. Ryoko Morosumi,
the victim who died of the fire.
She asked me to come check on a suspicious person
who was doing something around her house late at night...
But the lady said that it was just her imagination and told
us to leave, so we were watching her for a while...
Then a strange character who seemed to be a Feng Shui Sensei came by,
so having no other choice.
We went into her yard and looked inside
through the window and saw a pretty bad scene
Pretty bad scene?
It seems that this man:was having an extra-marital affair with Ryoko,
and was ransacking the rooms looking
for the video that was evidence of their affair!
That act of yours sounds more than pretty bad to me...
Well, but I guess I'll have to take molds of your shoes later!
Don't tell me you think that we're suspects?
You fool! It's to discriminate your footprints with the arsonist's!
Is that man that had an affair with her, the only one that came by the house?
N.No, four people came in all.
That man who had the affair and Ryoko's husband
Ryoko's older sister who seems to be a fortuneteller.
A timid guy who came and left catalog of his store with her...
But, the Sensei of Feng Shui and
Ryoko's husband are not arsonists.
According to the testimony of the kid next door,
the red horse was placed by the window at exactly 7:30 pm!
The Sensei and her husband went out to drink at about 7:20 pm.
SO the two couldn't have done it...
And we were contemplating for about 5 minutes whether to follow the two or not,
but at that time there was No smoke nor fire at all!
The only concern is why those two came back so early despite having gone drinking
that's because a neighbor called the husband's
cell phone and told him there! as a fire.
Which leaves the older sister who is a fortuneteller and the timid man...
Talking of fortunetelling,
Then, the lady may be there!
Let's go!
What! Ryoko died?
Are you serious?!
Yes.
What a foolish child.
I warned her time and again to be careful because
I saw signs of disaster by fire in her!
Our father's funeral is not finished yet,
still why is everybody crossing over like this?
If you will excuse me asking. where were you at around 7:30 pm?
I was here!
Right?
Y.Yes, we are all under contract to start fortunetelling from 7:30 p.m
I'm SO sorry
The only one left is the timid man...
Do you remember any characteristics of that man?
His height was about 160 centimeters,
and he was wearing round glasses
He seemed to be .in his forties.
"Think he's an antique shop owner or something!
Since he was going around passing out catalogs.
'Think his shop is somewhere nearby
Mr. Yuminaga, does it ring 'a bell?
It can't be
He couldn't have
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers
MICH]HIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music
KATSUQ ONO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
Scripts By.
KANJ1*KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUGHI
JUNICHI MIYASHIIA
YUICHI -HI(GURE
T oSHIKI INOUE
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
CHI MIYAS
CHI HIG
TOSHIKIUNOUE
Animation Directors
MASATOMO SUDO p . ey 2 - \ sr Yr
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATDYUDITI /AUJINU)
AKIO KAWAMURA
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
Rsnumnsu 0181404
Chief Director.
KENJIJKODAMA
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD im=association with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
COR! ORATION
DETECTIVE CC NAN
CGOMIO AOYAMA YS SHOGAKURAN YTV TAM
All Ri he's erved
The four Red Horses that were. leftcat-the:serial arson sites!
I wonder why only the horse left at the first site is burntiblack like this?
Rabbit?
It. It can't be!
Hey, isn't this Guan Yu?
But, he was sure riding a. flashy colored horse
Well, after all, this is the
Red Rabbit Horse!
It's a super horse that is said to be able to run a thousand miles in a day!
The Red Horse-in the Fire
Part 2