Deduction flows with the rhythm of the wind
Dark st ins clean and exposed
Extra-marital affair. fortune-telling and Sangokushi
Many things connect to the crime
He sees through the one and only truth,
No case is left unsolved with Detective Conan.
( -% &
0v"?!
We SW 3]
Heiji. Pops andill go to the residence of Ryoko Morozumi
on Haidocho 4-chome to conduct investigation
on behalf of Detective Kusukawa»but...
She denied our help.
What?
You just said you're headed home because you finished the job!
Yeah, that's what we were planning to do.
But we passed a fire engine on the way back
We got concerned and headed back to the residence...
and found it blazing outrageously...
Huh?
Huh'?
The Morozumi residence...
(38 = 3)
32 ok)
Red Horse in the Fire
Part 2
I tell you, what the hell is that fool doing anyway...
I bought him a t-shirt that I thought would look good on him and then...
Come, come. they'll be home soon!
Huh?
What's this key holder?
Remember, a kindly looking old man gave it us on the bus
Oh the man who gave us his seat saying that we
Iooked to be carrying a heavy load...
Thank you so very much
Thanks
U.Uh. where are you girls living?
Are you trying to pick us up. mister?
Kazuha, stop it!
NN. No. I run an antique shop at Haidocho...
so I thought I'd like you to drop in one day...
Haidocho is nearby!
My house is right next to it on Beikacho 5-chome
O.Oh. . 5 chome...
Shall we go tomorrow?
Okay. let's!
Okay, I'll give you the catalog of my shop and a key holder...
P.Promise. okay...
I wonder what a key holder
that brings flourishing(business is all about?
Here you go, Mouri...
The four red horses... that were found at the serial arson sites!
I went way out to ask the forensic officers for it.
So you'd better find some sort of a clue, or you're going to get it!!
Well, I'm not the one who want to see the horses, they do...
How come...only this horse from the first fire 1s burnt black like this?
And only this horse has a stand...
Huh? There's something written on the back of the stand!
Rabbit?
Hey... A red horse and rabbit...
D:Donrt tell me that.+
Hey. isn't this... Kanu?
Kanuyis the military commander who appears in the story Sangokusht, isn't he?
Yep.
And Kanu is/also famous for being the god of prosperity for doing business
But. what a flashy colored horse he's riding
This is a "Sekitouba (Red Rabbit Horse)
It's a super horse said to be able to run a thousand miles in a day
Red Rabbit Horse?!
Are you saying that this red plastic horse is
a famous horse that appears in Sagokushi?
Yeah, that's right...
Try looking at the stand of this horse that was left at the first scene of the fire!
You-can't read the words above and under it because they re burnt,
but you can see the word rabbit. right?
Yes, true...
The only red horse with the word rabbit to its name is the horse
that ran around battlefields
WI 1S VICIOUS MI I ary comman er
on its back, Red Rabbit Horse, right?
But, why did the arsonist put the legendary horse that appears in an old Chinese story
at the sites he set fire to?
Yeah, why...?
China...
Feng Shui is also from China. isn't it?
The man who came to the
Morozumi residence before the fire,
didn't he say anything to Ryoko about the old Chinese story?
He didn't say anything about Sangokushi,
but that Sensei of Feng Shui's got a perfect motive
Huh
He was looking for the video tape of his affair
with Ryoko Morozumi who died in the fire.
It can't™be!
To get rid of the video tape he burned down the house?
Inspector Yuminaga!
Hmm...
Okay! If you find out anything more, please report to me again!
Yes sir
It seems that the ones with motive is not limited to that Sensei
Keiko Gondo. the fortuneteller that came to the house before the Sensei...
Seems that she's going to get a large sum
of estate from her parents being that she's oko's older-sister!
Come to think of it that fortuneteller-was saying that their father just died!
But, that lady came to borrow money from Ryoko
If she was going to inherit the estate of her father anyway,
why would she do something like that...
Her father was left to live alone when her mother died
His only living relatives were his two daughters Ryoko and Keiko
He seems to have left a will saying that
he would leave his entire estate to Ryoko who had taken a husband
I 888...
so if Ryoko disappears,
the estate that she originally couldn't inherit would be hers...
Yeah...
because there was nothing on the death note that said,
if the younger sister dies, don-t7give it to the older sister...
If so...
Ryoko's husband is clean!
If his wife dies he loses the estate and all...
No...not really so...
Her husband Akira
Morozumi is a psychiatrist,
and wanted to demolish that house
that they were living in and build his own hospital
But since Ryoko was opposed to it, he seems to have been in a fix...
He seems to have been given that land and house by Ryoko's parents...
On top of that, if he knew that his wife was having an extra-maritalzaffair,
he would have more than enough motive.
The problem is all three of them have an alibi...
Yeah...
the time the arsonist setfire and put this horse at the site was around 7:30 pm.
Her husband came home about 10 minutes before that but,
after that before even a minute had passed,
he went out drinking with the Sensei of Feng Shu
And at that time,
the fortuneteller was telling fortunes in a building in front of Haido:Station... =~.
the only suspect left is
the-man who was at the front door of
the Morozumi residence when we got there...
The man who tried to leave the catalog of the things in his store and
key holder that would help business prosper.
But was asked to leave...
The owner of the antique store, at timid looking man...
Unless we can figure out who and where he is...
I wonder what this is?
See, this horse that was found at the first fire site?
Only this horse has a strange protrusion on its body!
Isn't this the feet of a. human?
It's melted from the heat of the fire but...
Maybe somebody was mounted on this horse.
The military commander that was riding the Red Rabbit Horse was,
who was he...
K.Kanu!!
Huh, Kanu?
Huh. Kanu?
He's really suspicious after all,
that timid man with the round rim glasses!
Kanu is the god of prosperity in business!
The key holder box that the man tried to give away is
just the right size for this too!
There's no doubt about it!
The guy thatrwas riding the Red Rabbit Horse was...
We don't have time to waste!
Let's call all the antique shops in the vicinity of Haidocho!
We'd better hurry or he'll get away!
I hope:-that the man you guys say you saw isn't him...
Oh no! It's already past 23:00!
We're all supposed to go to
Tropical Land tomorrow and yet!
Maybe they aren't planning to come home?
Really, what are they doing dragging Conan around with them till this hour of the day?
They get me so mad!
Let's just forget about those guys and go to sleep!
Oh. wait...
Why don't we hang this sunny boy doll out
on the veranda of dad's room so that it doesn't rain tomorrow
Although it didn't seem to work last night.
I'm going to wish with all my might tonight so that it works!
Yeah!
I've found them. I've finally found them...
What?
He once came up as a suspect?
Are:you serious?
Yeah. his name is TakanorilGérita
He's running an antique shop in
Haidecho just as you assumed!
But. why'd, ou suspect him?
He was among the crowd of*onlookers at the fire site at Rizencho
He was mumbling something strange while watching the fire.
He was saying...Father ..Father
Father?
His father used to be a firefighter. and when he was still in elementary school,
his father tried to save a person who couldn't make it out of the fire'in time.
And was swallowed by the flames.
D.Don't tell me thatthe man 1s .
Yeah, we, the police thought so too...
That he set fire in memory of his father
That . maybe he thought that if he caused
a fire his father would come dashing to the scene!
I see, so not being able to give up hope, he started
setting fires from 1-chome in sequence,
and Kept chasing the illusion of his father
At 5.00 in the evening, he stopped by at the shop once and then went home?
Yes. he said he was tired
He's been distributing catalogs of our store and key
holders to people in the neighborhood from morning so
that key holder the one with a person riding a red horse
Yeah. it's his work of effort of the statue of Kanu
But, he changed it to another key.holder because it didn t take too well to others
What? He changed it?
The key holder that he distributed today should've been one of a beckoning cat.
Is something wrong with the shop owner, officer?
Oh, no not really
Don't get so angry. Ran, we can't go home for a while longer
Dang ou.
Oh yes, you were pretty knowledgeable about the story Sangokushi, weren't you?
Y.Yes...
The military commander who was mounted on the
Red Rabbit Horse was called "Ryofu right?
'Right! But. later the horse was given to "Soso
and in the end. it went to
Kanu', who was the last to own it!
Are you sure about it?
Yes, because the key holder I was iven of Kanu
today is also riding a Red Rabbit Horse!
Somebody gave you a key-holder. of
Kanu riding the Red Rabbit Horse?!
Hey Pops! What's the address of your detective agency?
I'm asking you what's the address?
What chome is it on?
F.Fifth chome...
O. Okay...
What's Pops doing?
I'm not sure. but he said for us to not go outside and stay in the house.
Oh great. I've been hearing strange noises from the front door
What?! Genda lives in Rizencho?
Yeah, what about it?
When Ryoko's husband came b ack home at about 7:20 pm.
We saw Mr. Genda near the house in Haidocho
The bus that Ran rode is probably the one that
goes from Haidocho via Beikacho and then to Rizencho
Although it's true that
Mr. Genda intended to go home once,
for one reason or another, he returned to that house!
Come to think of it.
Rizencho is the place where the first fire occurred, right?
Yeah, the house that burned was right near his...
The inhabitant seems to have been a good friend of his parents,
as well as a good customer of his shop...
Which means that the real reason he set fire to the house
was to hide the fact that the item that he sold was fake,
and before anyone found out, he burned the house down
Yeah...
But, I don't understand...
Why didn't you detain him at the station being as suspicious as he was?
I guess the intuition of a police detective within me
has gotten rusty...
The police car has arrived in front of the detective agency.
Hey. don't tell me that
G.Genda!
Heijr.
What? What happened?
After the phone call just a while ago. that man came here,
and asked to have the key holder that he gave us in the bus back.
We asked him why and he said...
There's going to be a fire...
I'm going to set fire again
Then, he broke down in tears.
Having no choice I called the police but...
Hey. Genda! Is it true?
Did you really do it?
I.I'm sorry!
Inspector Yuminaga!
We'll take the suspect over to the Beika
Police Department for now.
Y. Yeah...
Judging from the looks of it, it seems he'll spit it out right away
Hey. Hattori. doesn't this resemble
Yeah, I was just thinking the same thing.
The renown Detective Poalo series.
A masterpiece of all masterpieces!
It's just like The ABC Murders!"
The killer kills people who have the same initials as the name of the
place and kills them off one by one in order of ABC
Then an ABC time schedule is placed near the corpse to
make it look as if it were the doings of a serial killer
And finally he kills the actual target "C" that he is after.
He hides the orderliness of a planned murder under the guise
of a disorderly random murder.
It sure is similar!
Moreover. that timid man,
the arsonist, who was taken away by the police just a while ago
In that novel, he is arrested once because the real arsonist puts him under the
the illusion that he is the one committing the crime.
Genda sure resembles that character...
It seems that we'd better look into this a little deeper
We'd better check out the sites of the fire of 4-chome that smells of tricks involved
What?! You're going to Haidocho 4-chome where the fire occurred last night?!
From now?!
Yeah! There's something bothering me .
I'm thinking of taking him along too!
Never mind the fire!
We're all scheduled to go to
Tropical Land today, aren't we?
I don't know if it's topical or pickles, but this case(is sure
going to put us in a pickle if we don't solve it fast!
Case, but the arsonist was arrested
Iast night{ wasn't he
Yeah! The man with the round rimmed
glasses that gave us the key holder of the red horse!
No. maybe that man is being, mind controlled
Mind controlled?
Think about it!
Akira Morozumi is a psychiatrist
Mr. Misao Soga= is a Sensei of Feng Shun
And. Keiko Gondo is a fortuneteller!
All three of them seem to be able to manipulate the hearts of people,
and have the motive to cause the fire.
Don't you think something smelts?
But...
Those three have alibis...
Right, so let's go check it out again!
Ay -e a super ee ICIous Ss ory IS hidden behind all this. right?
It's kind of eerie.
Really, I can't understand the feeling of somebody who
wants toicome to a scary place like this
Don't come then!
I can't help it!
I want the case to be solved as soon as possible, and go to Tropical Land.
e were a > concernec about the case too
Hey. hey.
You've gota huge family accompanying you today. don't you?
Oh. hello.
Oh, hello.
And. Did Genda confess?
His answer is an unchanging,
I don't know."
I don't know?
According to him, he says there's another him within himself
and that guy may be going around setting fire.
He seems toghave had the habit of sleep-walking since he was a child.
And that habit seems to have reoccurred recently,
so he'sgbeen seeing a doctor for treatment
A.And don't tell me his doctor is...
Yeah, Akira Morozumi.
He seems to have prescribed a tranquilizer and gave it to Genda
But, he looked really surprised at hearing that Genda was the arsonist
Come to think of it, the man called Soga also looked surprised
Soga and Genda used to see each other a lot at the antique marketplace
And Sega seems to be the one who
recommended Genda to go to Morozumi's hospital
Misao Soga is an odd character who quit the medical university part
way and got absorbed in Eeng Shun
The reason why Genda was in that area that day was because Soga had told him that
if he goes 10 the houses; there, the direction is good.so he might-find some luck...
Then, just as Hieji had said, he had some connection with Mr. Genda!
Which means that Genda may have some connection
with the fortune éller KeikoGondo too...?
No. I haven't gone that far yet. but...
that lady smells fishy...
When Ryoko was found, I saw her gripping this small cushion really hard .
I had them all come this morning to headquarters and asked them
if this looked familiar to them,
but only that woman Gondo turned pale and left in the wink of an eye...
Isn't that a dying messagej?
Why did you let her go?
The arsonist had already confessed.
And that lady already had an alibi
SO we couldn't detain her...
Well, that's only if the time of the arson is correct as you both insist.
Well, would you like to confirm for yourself?
The one who testified is the boy next door...
Really. it's really true!
I saw it!
When the opening song of Kamen Yaiba started
I saw a large shadow of a horse on the curtain of the living room!
Is it true ma'am?
I wonder...
because I entered the living room at 7:30 ind turned on the lights right away...
so I'm not sure if there was a shadow there or not...
I'm not lying!
Will you show us that room?
It's this room. eh?
If so.
The shadow of the horse was projected on this curtain...
True...
But, why was your:ison watching
TV in a dark:room 7 .
It seems all the kids in this neighborhood do so now.
It's like watching a movie and really cool!
But sonny... make sure you turn on the'lights whenfyou watch TV. okay!
Otherwise, our eyes will go bad really quickly!
Just like him?
Maybe the shadow of the horse was already projected before 7:30...
The shadow that is createdyby flames get light and dark and sways a lot too. so
you can't tell if it's a horse or not at times.
That's not true!
Because I was watching baseball all the while
until the clock on top of the TV struck the time for Kamen Yaiba but...
It got really bright outside the window and I saw the shadow.
It was time for the Kamen Yaiba song.
'Hen were you watching the baseball game with the room dark too?
But; if it's dark you can't see the time of the clock. right...?
I could see it because it was dimly light outside the window...
Besides. the shadow of the horse wasn't swaying.
Hey, Heiji!?!
Conan.
Look really closely for it Hattori!
I'm sure it's somewhere!!
Yeah...
The evidence that will prove our deduction, is here some place for sure...
I found it!
It's an incandescent electric light bulb!!
I've found one here too!
Here and there in burnt places, there are burnt remains of tissue paper...
Which means that...
Yeah, if this trick is used,
you don't have to be here to set fire to the place!!
All we need to find out now is how the culprit manipulated Mr Genda...
We've got to find proof of that...
Original Comic Books By.
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers
MICHIHIKO™SUWA
MASAHITOO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
raracfer I ZSsions 3
1ASATOM JD) SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography.
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWACGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KEN JIJKO DAM A
Produced By.
TMSIENTERTAINMENT., LTD.
Arr 1ssocration with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CONAN
CHCLONMTD AOYAMA AHOGARUR ANY TV TMS
All Ri I Reserved
This is Mr. Genda's shoe print...
It's the same shoe that's in the shoes cabinet!
There's something strange in the waste basket!
Huh
A soiled pair of socks and a burnt shirt...
No...
It's not a wire tap!
But. something unbelievable!
Red Horse in the Fire
Part 3