Ple Tne endo tn
Deductionsflows with
the rhythm of the wind
Dark stains are rinsed clean and exposed
This is the case closed
episode of a 3-part story!
The sharp twosome, extinguish the flames!
He sees through the one and only truth,
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
ad QQ
o> 2a @
U101
Vy. J
w % 43)
( 3 QR
an Te. Tom o>
The Morozumi residence that Hattori,
Pops and I went on behalf of Kusukawa,
to investigate caught fire
and Ryoko Morozumi dies.
Like all the other serial arson sites
a red horse! doll is left behind at the site.
A red horse doll is left behind at the site.
However, one of the suspects
Takanori Genda, admits to the crime,
and the case seems to have closed. but...
(8% 25)
Red Horse in the Fire
Case Solved Part 3
Ash?!
Oh no! It's already 3:00 pm...
I guess we'll just have to forget
about Tropical Land.
I see...
It's true...
that if we do as you-say,
fire could be ignited automatically...
But the burn on that light bulb...
Could be something that coincidentally
got there during the fire...
If that trick were to be used...
any of the three could've done it,
couldn't they?
The owner of that house
Akira Morozumi, of course.
That womanizer Misao Soga.
As well as Ryoko's older
sister. Keiko Gondo
seem to have frequently gone
in and out of the house!
We came to Mr. Genda's house
to find out who the culprit is,
so let's hurry and go into the house!
Yeah. right!
We may find a diary or something
that could be a key to the case!
you don't even have a search wainrant,
and-yet you have-the keys-It's amazing...
I told Genda that
I would prove his innocence.
Then he broke out in tears
and lent«it to me...
It sure is a big house for
Mr. Genda to be living in alone.
Yeah...
He was living here with his mother
after his father passed away...
but last year his mother also
passed away of an illness...
By the way. Mouri,
did you notice the
shoe marks in the corridor?
Yes...
they're here and there...
the shoe marks of someone...
These are Mr. Gendas shoe marks...
It's the same as the shoes
that's in the shoes cabinet!
Which means that.. Mr. Genda...
Hey...
take a look at this!!
There's something strange
in the waste basket!
Soiled socks and a burnt shirt...
If Mr. Genda's sleepwalking habit
was getting worse, maybe his saying.
The other me did it". is not
all that much of a lie...
He's not that kind of a guy...
He's not the kind of man that
would set fire to other people's houses...
Yuminaga...
Hey! Kudo!!
Come here a minute!
It's the telephone bill that wD
on top of the shoes cabinet...
It says 30.000 yen a month!
Isn't it a bit too much?
It's true that it's strange for a guy
who's living alone but...
Ran also talks to Sonoko
for a long time over silly things
and the bill totals to about that much...
Come to think of it...
silly Kazuha does the same thing...
She talks for a long time with mom.
I wonder why women like to
talk on the phone so much...
Well. I'm so sorry!
That our phone calls are so silly!!
Hopi?
Conan!
Huh
Don't tell me you guys were
eavesdropping from the front door?!
We wouldn't do something
Iow class like that!!
You fool!!
We were listening to the car radio
when we heard ou cu s talkinc!
Right
Radio?!
=Itvs inside this vase!!!
Here it is!!
Look!!
It's a wiretap!
Huh ?
That's...
exactly the same as the vase that is in
the front entrance of the Morozumi's. isn't its?
We heard other things too...
Something about the wastebasket
Hey. wait!
There's got be one near
this waste basket too. a wiretap!
Huh? A crystal ball...?
Hattori!
I found it!!
This time inside the cushion
under the crystal ball!
Oh. I've seen that!
Huh
It's the crystal of good luck
that the woman fortuneteller
at the building in front
of Haido Station is selling!
She's known for being pretty good...
Hey! That small cushion...
It's a different color.but similar to the one
Ryoko was holding. don't you think?
No...
Could it be in here too?!
Hey...
No...
It's not a wiretap!!
But. something else has come out instead!
Yes...
Iithe guyfGenda-confessed.
But suddenly refused to say anything...
The red horse was indeed
hand-made by Genda...
But, he refuses to say anything
about the serial arsons.
And. we're at Gendafs. house right» now.
But can't find any vital evidence...
Genda saying that he has a habit of
sleepwalking is probably a lie too...
Well, the forensic officers
will be here tomorrow
so I'm sure something will come out...
When something more concerning
the investigations: come up.
I'll contact you again...
Whew...
Was it okay. sonny?
Just great. Inspector!
But...what are you up to anyway?
Making fake calls like that
to all three suspects?
Fake calls?
They're fake calls, aren't they?!
You found wiretaps in
the vase at the front entrance
as well as something in the cushion.
There is proof everywhere that Mr. Genda
had a habit of sleepwalking...
Well... I'll explain everything later...
And us being here too.
Won't that make more work
for the forensic officers?
Yeah!
I'm sure our hair is on
the floor somewhere too!
Then,
what should we do to erase
all evidence that we were here?
Hat should we do...
Go all out and clean the place. what else?
If you didn't have time to do so. then what?
Well .
Ag hi?
Maybe...
Shh~~~!
Aren't you forgetting to leave
this red horse behind?
Mr. Arsonist?
Mr. Morozumi...
Yeah...
this. key holder of the red horse that
Mr. Genda made was the start of everything.
This red horse, that is supposed to
bring prosperous business...
I don't know what caused
he first fire in Rizencho,
but this horse was found
at the site of the fire because
e Owner oe use was
a good customer of Mr. Genda's store...
Mr. Genda probably gave that person
this key holder inside a box...
But, before the person opened
the box. the house caught fire...
The box and Kanu both burned leaving
behind only the Red Rabbit Horse .
Of course the owner of the house would
have no knowledge of the horse
And Red Horse is a code word
for the police meaning arsonist!
So, the press began making
a fuss writing articles
such as "The Start of a Series of Arsons. "...
On the other hand.
Mr Genda who was shocked at
hearing the person saying
she knew nothing about
the horse that he gave her...
got worried that his sleepwalking habit
when he was a child had occurred again,
and went to your hospital,
where he was taken advantage of!
And. when you heard Genda's story.
You made him believe that
he was a sleepwalker who had a habit
of committing arsons...
and took note of the fact that
the first fire occurred in 1 chome.
Then after, you set fire to
2-chome and 3-chome in order...
You burned your house on 4 chome,
and killed your wife, Ryoko.
You cut the Kanu and
stand off the key holder
and left the red horse at the site of the fire
to make it look like the serial arsonist did it,
and framed Mr. Genda up as the arsonist!
You made a spare key for
this house and snuck in here
night after night to corner
Mr. Genda up against the wall
You left shoe prints.
Burnt shirts and dirty socks in his room
to make him come under
the illusion that he was the arsonist!
But...
Mr. Genda came of his own
initiative to my hospital
saying that he had a habit of sleepwalking.
But. that's...
when he was a child. right?
I saw on TV that there are many cases,
when a nervous child unable to cope with
all the excitement during the day
sleepwalks around at night!
A psychiatrist should know
something like that right off the bat, no?
But. Mr. Genda~was loitering around nearby
when my house caught fire, wasn't he?
I would never know something like that,
even if I were his doctor, would I...
You heard Genda and Soga
talking on the phone. didn't you.
With the wiretap that you set up inside
the underside of the telephone
that you took out a while ago!
After hearing Soga say. If you go
to the houses on that day]
Your fortune will take a turn for the better.
you picked the date to set fire!
All you had to do was change the beckoning
cat key holder Genda was supposed
to pass out to the neighborhood
that day. to the Red Rabbit Horse.
You knew that Mr. Genda would
come to retrieve the key holders
when he finds out that he had
passed out the wrong ones and that,
the people would become
suspicious at seeing him do this.
Since it was the day that
Ryoko had called the detective,
you figured that if things worked out well,
the detective would remember Genda
Please wait!
The fire was set at past 7:30 pm... right?
Went out to drink with
Mr. Soga before 7:30 and
he also testified to this!
Or, ares ou saying the boy next door who
testified to the time of the arson is lying?
Huh
What's this?
The tissue paper is wrapped around
the light bulb and taped on!
And there's something poked in
between the tissue paper too!
Wait
Agh! It's a match!!
The surface temperature of a light bulb
of 100 watts is 218 degrees...
Wrapping tissue paper around
some ng I e a an
moreover, poking a match between it...
it's not hard to figure out
what will happen. is it?
In other words...
it's a time-igniting device
to set fire to your house while
you are out drinking with Mr. Soga!!
You did the same thing to
the light bulb in the storeroom,
poured kerosene on the floor
and stuck a red horse between
the window beforehand.
Then, before you went out drinking
with Mr. Soga you turned on the light!
So. 10 minutes later, the match would ignite,
the tissue paper would fall to the ground
and fire would break out...
You shouldn't do stuff like this...
Then, the boy next door as usual
watches TV with the room dark.
When the tissue is wrapped
around the light bulb,
the light is still weak, so the silhouette
of the horse will not project.
But after the tissue paper burns off,
the silhouette of the horse is projected
as if the arsonist had left
the horse behind at that time.
You deliberately created this illusion!
Next. you were probably
planning to sneak in here
and burn this place down: to erase
traces of you having been here...
But. there is still other evidence.
It's the stand of the key holder with
the words Red Rabbit Horse on it that
Ryoko was holding on
to at the time she died!
The cut part matched the leg that
was left back at the fire site on 3-chome
Now all that needs to be done,
is to see if the fingerprints that are on it
match your fingerprints.
You cut off the stand and Kanu because
you didn't want anyone to know it
was what Mr.-Genda had made.
You didn't want him to get
caught before you kill Ryoko...
It seems she knew what
you were up to though.
She probably asked the detective
to come and investigate
the suspicious person
Ioitering around at night
but found out that it was you,
experimenting on the trick!
After realizing it was you,
she checked your belongings
and found the red horse and the stand.
And was convinced that
the serial arsonist was you.
She probably asked us to leave, because
she was planning to threaten you to...
Right!
She threatened to divorce me
and kick me out of this house!!
All I wanted to do was...
burn the house and build a hospital...
Hey. hey...
Only if this stand wasn't found...
If I didn't get deceived
into a trap like this...
This was supposed to be a perfect crime!!
You fool,
we knew from before you came here.
Don't lie!!
Soga could've done it and
so could Ryoko's older sister!
Yeah...
Those two also sold objects
with wiretaps in them to Genda
and? ere wiretapping him...
They probably wanted him
to believe in Feng Shui
and fortune-telling by telling
him stuff only he alone knew,
and sell him more expensive stuff...
We found out from the telephone bill
that the phone was wiretapped!
When you wiretap
using the telephone line,
it has to be connected all the while
so the telephone bill sky-rockets...
So. how can you tell that
I'm the one who set it up?!
It could be either one of the two!!
You still don't realize?
Huh
You understand that in order to
set up a wiretap in the phone
you have to sneak into the house, right?
Yeah...
As for the other two.
If they were to sneak into the house
they would first of all remove the wiretap
from the things that they sold Mr. Genda,
because otherwise. they'd be suspected.
You probably came across
committing this crime
after reading Agatha Christie's
The ABC Murders but,
\~why-didn't you realize then that
no matter how hard you think out the plan.
The one who gets to laugh at
the end is not the killer...
but the old man with the gray brain...
See you then, Mourn!
Thanks for everythig.
H... no not at all...
No...rather.
Maybe I should be thanking these boys?
By the way...
What will become of those two?
Hmm?
It's not that they sold something
outrageously expensive to Genda yet.
And all they did was sneak
In to collect their wiretaps
because they didn't want to be
suspected as arsonists, so...
We'll let them go after we give
them a good lecture at the station.
Why did you believe
Genda was innocent...
Yeah...
When Genda came up as a suspect,
I called him out to the park
and talked to him...
stayed with him for 30 minutes,
but he hardly talked
So, we decided to talk again
some other time and
I got up from the bench.
I turned to look back at him
from a distance... and saw him
Iooking desperately for something
in the grassy area around the bench.
It began raining a little while
after he left the bench...
After seeing the look of relief on his face,
I finally understood...
that he was looking for the cigarette butt
that I threw down on the ground...
Because that was what caused
the fire that took his father's life...
I just couldn't believe that a guy like him
could; set fireito anybody's house...
Neither:did I want believe he could...
It's as simple as that...
See you... Mourn!
Yes sir
Original Comic Books By.
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHTHI O SUWA
MA AH{TOS OSHIWKA
Det IT QUITIUI VIII «
gore
Character Designs By
MAS'AT@MO sumo
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
CHI HIG
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
» - ey bh «Lr LL. N
IS NNICWERWAYE NEN VAVIVEY FE VAW
HARUO OOGAWARA
TSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor
TERUMITSU OKADA
2d oD
Chief Director.
KENJI KODAMA
Produced By.
TMS:-ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
in-assocration with
YOMIURI TELECASTINC
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CONAN
CGOMO AOY MAT SHOGAKUKAN YTV -TATS
All Ris hReserved
Hey. come on, a little cheaper!
I came all the way here to buy
from you to cheer you up, you know!
But that watch is made
by a famous craftsman...
No matter how famous...
if it doesn't move unless you wind it
It's practically useless
in this day and age. right?
Hunk but...
Okay!
Give me this too and as500~yenzdiscounti
How's about-it!
Heir,
we better hurry or we won't make it
in time for the planevgoingsback .-home
we better*hurry or we won't make it
in-time for the plane going back home
Come on. mister
hurry and wrap it up:"will you.
Simple wrapping will do.
Hey. Kazuha?!
Oh, yes. thank you very much!
Never mind giving him a discount already
SO can you give me this
antique jewelry for free!
Okay. mister?!
Are you guys really trying
to cheer him up or what...
Please. mister!!
Oh- this is just great!
Ranan;ambulance!
Callan ambulance!
Oh. okay!
Get the police too!
Stay away everybody
Don't touch anything on the table!
Next Conan's:Hint
Mystery of the-Birthday.Wine"