Déduction:if lows- with
the Fhijthin of the Wind
Deduction flows with
Dark stains are rinsed clean and exposed
The fragrance of murder and
the blotches of a love affair
Wine glass which includes many things
He sees through the one and only truth,
A child in appearance
with the l.Q. of an-adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan
K/fl
my SS eC
An - >
Yes-!'" Who is it?
It's Ran Mourn...
Oh, okay! One moment...
What s up, Ran?
Yuki
thanks for the'books!
How-did you like it?
Well... my heart was pounding
excitedly from beginning to.end...
$0. you thought so too?
You came all this way just to return it time?
Thank you'd
Ohl... No. well not really...
I was on my way 0 a restaurant
with my father and family
so I just dropped by on the way...
Hello!
Thank you for being nice
tozmy daughter always.
Oh no, I've done nothing.
Thank you too...
Hey. Kojima!
Which plate should I put out?
Please wait.
Oh. that's right!!...
We're holding a birthday
panty-for a friend now.
Why don't-you all join us. Ran?
Huh? But...
Please do so by all means!
There are only going to be
three of my university friends.
So/you do Tt have to be hesitant!
Besides, being able to meet
the renown Detective Moun]
IS a birthday present that can't be beat!
If it's okay with you... right, Ran?!
Dad!!
I'll bet all you want to do
Is get free booze.
Mystery of the Birthday Wine
Yuk!
Huh?
Where shall I put thus?
Can you put it in the kitchen for now?
Okay.
Ouch!
My. are you okay?
Ouch...
Fm fine.
I'm sorry...
this chair is a little broken.
The chair that: Keiko, the star of
today sits on goes way: inside, right?
Yep,
and oh, this bag of yours,
will you-put it in the kitchen
It's kidd of in the way here.
Huh?
Y right away, ma
@kay... right away, ma'am.
Are you really okay?!
You're not hurt, are you?
Yep. I'm fine!
Yuki, is there anything else
you'd like me to do?
Hmm - No. I guess that's it...
I'm sorry to have made you help me...
Oh. no problem at all...
Oh, that chair's broken Togash.
O@h. no problem,
because I'll sit in it.
It's Keiko and the others...
Yeah...
Yes!
Good evening.
We've been waiting for you, Keiko!
Hello!
Hi. thanks~for coming!
Hi Nonaka, you're late!
So sorry, the roads were jammed.
I'll go park the car then... Keiko...
Okay.
And... Keiko,
has the day you're going abroad as
an exchange studentObeen decided...?
I'm leaving next week Tuesday!!
$0. I'm sort of busy with this and that!
You mean. you're leaving that soon...?
Mr. Moun
please move a bit more to the left...
You mean like so...?
Yes, okay. Here goes
One plus one is...
Twol!
I'm so happy
to be able to take a snapshot with
the renown Detective KogoroJMdun...
Well, well .
Huh? Tihe glass 'cups are.already out.here.
Yeah...
On. Nonaka. will you get the
you know what out.
Huh
Oh.right...
This.
Is my gift to you!
I bought it when I went to
Germany some time ago...
just for your birthday...
It wasn't.Cheap. youzknow.
Oh. wow, thanks so:much!:-
Hey, hey, I dished out my half
for it toe. you know
you did?
Heck!
First, for the birthday girl...
Thank you...
I hope you like it...
Thank you
Nice color...
Hey. Nonaka. leave some for me too.
Shoots
there's still some more left...
Here you go.
Like they say. Save the best for last "
Oh, just enough...
Here:s a-toast to our dear friend
Keiko Sawaguchi's 20th birthday
as well as her study trip
abroad to the States...
Cheers!
Cheers?
Thank you!!
It's delicious!!
Really...
It's so refreshing...
Oh! This is really good!
Everybody
please don't forget.
I dished out...
Just what do you think
you're doing Togashi!!
Sorry... sorry!
I'd completely forgotten about this chair...
Keiko, it didn't spill on
your clothes, did it?
I think I'm fine...
I spilled the wine of the birthday girl...
The bottle's already empty too
so if you want my drink you can have it...
Go ahead and pass it around.
Nonaka...
Yeah...
I tell you, you're hopeless...
Togashi
I'm sorry.
Please bear with that...
Okay...
thank you...
I almost forgot the cake!
Yeah, I'll bring it.
UW Pah up
Hen Ks
Oh. will you please...
Wry B Fday
UW bah op
Hobs [
Read ?
I'm going to turn out the lights.
Ppt Poach dag?
KH KT
Well, Keiko
Happy birthday!
It's really good!
Art...
Okay. I'll cut the cake. then
Keiko?
Keiko. what's the matter?
Keiko, what the matter?!
Get a hold of yourself!!
Keiko!!
\ Keiko?!
Ran!
The ambulance!!
Get the ambulance!!
Oh. okay!
Get the police too!!
Okay!
Stay back!
Don't touch anything on the table!!
FN Eire,
Inspector!!
Poison was found from the cup that
the victimudrank out of after ally,
And...
what about the other glass cups?
No poison was detected from the other
four glass cups or the empty wine bottle.
And...
on the cup that was used by the victim,
Ms. Sawaguehi, her fingerprints,
as well as those of
Mr. Togashi, Mr. Nonaka
and Ms. Kojima were also found.
The fingerprintsrofiall fouZpeople?
I see...
the glass cup that Ms. Sawaguchi
drank from was the one that
Mr. Togashi had passed around to
Ms. Kojima and Mr. Nonaka,
and finally passed around to
Ms. Sawaguchi. the victim...
if you want my drink you can have it...
Go ahead and pass it around.
Nonaka...
Yeah...
I tell you, you're hopeless...
Togashi.
Yes.
And... who opened the wine bottle?
Pulled the cork off the bottle.
Then, I poured wine for
Keiko, the birthday girl,
the guest Mr. Mourn
Yuki and myself...
Then I finally took the bottle from Nonaka
and poured wine for myself.
Inspector...
maybe someone had put poison
in the glass cup beforehand?
But...
Mr. Togashi. you said that you took
a sip of wine from your glass
before you gave it to the vietim. didn't you?
Yes...
And, how do you feel?
Just fine.
Then
the poison must've been
inserted after he drank the wine.
Maybe he just pretended
to drink and didn't YN
e c- ran ou o us cup or sure,
I saw him drink after the toast...
Quiet, kid...
If there were ice cubes in the cup,
then maybe...
poison could ve been put in
the ice cubes beforehand .
I donst think .
People ever drink wine-on the rocks.
True...
And after he took a sip, Mr Togashi
gave that cup of wine to...
me. and I gave it to Mr. Nonaka.
He couldn't have put poison in the cup
since everybody was watching...
Fl SQQ...
I was watching him too...
Inspector.
When Ms. Sawaguchi blew out the candles.
The lights went out for an instant.
Huh?!
I see, if then,
I guess poison could've been put in...
Oh...
I see.
If then maybe it would've been possible...
Inspector Megure.
How about having everyone
take his seats again?
You want to replay the scene of the crime,
Will you help us out everyone?
Yes.
Sure thing!
Let's start. then
So. you all sat in this order?
Yes. that's right.
So, the glass cup that the victim
; received from Mr. Togashi goes
here? Is this correct...?
Yes.
I put it there. so there's no mistake about it
After that. the candles were blown out.
The roomygot dark, and the lights were
switched back on again right away?
I turned the lights back on with
that switch over there
How long was it pitch dark?
I think it was no more than 4 {05 seconds.
because I got up and turned on the lights
right after the candles were blown out...
Do you all agree. .?
Well.
I think so too.
Then. the answer is simple.
The only one who could pour poison in
the cup within a period of 4 to 5 seconds
would be the one who was
sitting to the right of the victim
That is.
The one who was nearest to the cup.
No one oth&r than you, Mr. Nonaka!
Dad!
It doesn't have to me.
Even Yuki could've reached
the glass if she leaned over.
Why should I do something like that?!
Inspector!
It's true that from where Ms. Kojima
was seated she could've done so too...
Oh no...
I couldn't have done it.
I'd have to climb over to the table
or something to reach the.cup...
Or. you went around behind everybody.
Came all the way here and»
went back to turn on-the lights...
4 to 5 seconds isn't enough time.
Even if {Were dark; I'm sure somebody
would've sensed you do so if you did.
Which means...
That Mr. Togashi couldn't
have done it after all.
Inspector!
I guess it would be safe to say that the
Killer is either Mr. Nonaka or Ms. Kojima.
No...
Why.
Why did that person take
such a strange attitude...
Wait a sec...
If that method is used...
I got it!
Ffigured out the method of
how thé'poison was put inside the cup!
w/a .
Inspector Megure!!
Huh?
I checked the belongings of the three...
And found this is in Mr. Nonaka's bag...
Oh. .Just-what is it?
That's the bottle that I...
There could be poison inside...
We'll check it out right away.
Please do.
So. Mr. Nonaka...
Will you please explain
the bottle that we just found?
I know nothing about it!
That's my bag all right,
but it's the first time
I've ever seen that tiny bottle!
That's what they all say...
I know nothing of it!
It's the first time I've seen it!
Officer Takagi!
What is it, Conan...
Um...
What?! The same thing?!
Yes, sir
as to the detailed substance, I'll go
back to headquarters and analyze it.
This was found in Ms: Sawaguchi's glass
and this was found in the tiny bottle.
The reaction of both is exactly the same.
Mr. Nonaka
we'd like to hear more
details from you so...
I didn't do it!
Please calm down, Mr. Nonaka!
Please come with me to the station!
No good!!
Please hear me out. Inspector!
I've never seen that bottle, honestly!
Please believe me!!
Please wait. Inspector!
Huh
What is it... Mr. Mourn...
Inspector!!
Hey. that pose...?!
It's... the Sleeping Kogor
I've figured out who the real killer is,
Inspector!!
Real killer...?!
He's not the one?
Are you saying that it's her?
Who? I didn't...
No! It's not her.
Then, is it Mr. Togashi?!
But I thought you said
he didn't have the chance
to insert the poison just
a while ago. didn't you...? Dad...
The poison was not inserted
afterwards but rather,
was in the glass to begin with!
Cut it out.
I drank out of the cup myself, but I'm alive
and kicking as you can see for yourself!
That's just it, Mr. Togashi!
That's the very reason why
I was suspicious of you to start with...
What?!
When someone who
drank the same wine
as you starts to suffer in agony
even if you didn't drink the poison,
you would be worried nonetheless...
and get sick for real.
I see...
Come to think of it. that's true...
But. you acted differently!
Ms. Sawaguchi drank the poison and
collapsed right before
your eyes, yet you...
No. I'm fine.
Al '/
You were completely sure that
you didn't drink the poison...
Why? Because you're the one
who used a trick
to poison Ms. Sawaguchi
So. there's no mistake about it.
Mr. Togashi!
- - Cut out the gibberish!!
If the poison was in there to begin with
I would've been poisoned too.
Right. Yuki?!
Just a while ago Conan found
one empty container of gum syrup
from the basket in the kitchen...
The thing is
the murder is possible
if gum syrup is used
Even if the poisoned wine
were to be drunk...
The first sip can be drunk
without drinking the poison!
Is that true. Mr. Mouri?!
Yes...
First gum syrup is put into the glass
then the poison. and the liquid is stirred.
Ac en, None oo Ye Ive g asses 1a
Mr. Togashi brought from the kitchen
gum syrup was inside!
The bottom part of
that glass was colored...
Therefore, there was
no worry of anyone noticing it.
I see...
Moreover, he poured the wine in slowly.
Even if you pour wine over the gum syrup
which is heavier than the wine,
they won't mix and the wine
stays on top of the gum syrup.
In other words, the poison
won't mix with the wine!
See...
It's the same principle as
when you put gum syrup into iced coffee
and it sinks to-the bottom of the cup.
Then after the toast.
Mr. Togashi drank the wine
for everyone to see...
After which he deliberately tipped
over Ms. Sawaguchi's wine glass.
By giving her his own glass
He made her drink the poison that
was at the bottom of the glass cup...
Togas!
No. it's not me!
Mr. Mourn
all you just said is based
only on assumption!
Do you have any proof that I did wt?!
Did you get the fingerprints
I asked you for,
Officer Tome?
Yes...
There were no fingerprints
on the sides of the bottle...
But, Conan's fingerprints were
found on the bottom of the bottle.
What?!
Before the party started.
I goofed and turned your bag
upside down, Mr. Togashi...
And at that time.
A bottle just like that one came rolling out
so I put it right back into the bag...
Like this. so it wouldn't drop.
Huh?
But, it's strange...
I put it back inside Mr. Togashi's bag and
yet. why is it in Mr. Nonaka's bag...
Conan. thank you!
There's nothing strange about it.
Huh. why not?!...
Because he sneakedgthat
bottle into Mr. Nonaka's bag!!
That's right. isn't it. Mr. Togashi!
Mr. Togashi
you must've worked very carefully
not to leave your fingerprints behind...
That's why you didn't bother to
wipe of off the fingerprints at the end
I used to go with Keiko 2 years ago.
During that time she kept on
asking me to get her expensive presents...
Kept giving her stuff despite
having to go into debts...
Then. in the end
she. had the nerve) to; switch,
over to Nonaka. that broad...!
She dumped me as if I were
worn out rag or something...
I've been waiting for today!!
Her 20th birthday...
I planned it out carefully to poison Keiko...
and then schemed to frame you,
Nonaka. up as the killer...
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers
MICHIHIKO_SUWA
MASAHITO YO -HIOKA
Background Music
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI I1OKA
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
CHI HIG
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
VB DYUDNITTT /VUJINU)
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography.
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief-Director.
KENJIJKODAMA
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT; Tn)
arr 1ssocrirtion with
YOMIURI TELECASTINC
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CONAN
CONTHO AOYAMA SHOGARUK AN YIV 1 YS
All Ris:! Reserved
Oh. right'! I almost forgot.
Dad!!!
Sonoko came back from
Germany yesterday and
she brought a bottle of wine as a souvenir!
Would you like'to drink it?
Wine...
Sure!!!
Huh?!
It sure is . good!
I'm so lucky that it tastes just like
the one we had last week...
Ran!
AN pt
What?!
Oh. you-re right!!
Well... expensive things
sure suit my taste buds...
I made a mistake and gave you
the cheap wine I got at a shop nearby!
Cheers!!!
Who cares. since he seems
to be enjoying himself!
Cheap stuff is just the thing
for Pops' taste buds...
Then, when you passed here about 7:00.
There was nobody lying on the road?
A bicycle...?
This is...
Let's go see the place where
you all say you were
watching the fireworks!
There are bicycle wheel traces
near the broken fence...
Friendship Tom. Apart Part 4