The rhythm of the wind clears reasoning.
Alibi tricks are always uncovered.
Today's a case on a summer camping trip.
The Detective Boys investigate!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Hello, Megumi-chan?
This is Ayumi.
See, Megumi-chan, I'm kind of going out this weekend.
Can you take care of the class rabbits for me?
It's Conan-kun, isn't it?
I bet you're going camping with Conan-kun and the others.
It's not like that...
Don't worry, I'll do it.
On one condition: You have to tell me about your trip.
When you go somewhere with Conan-kun, you always experience something interesting.
I' I tell you everything!
Thanks a lot, Megumi-chan!
All right!
Camping! Camping!
We're going camping!
Why isn't Haibara-san a "chan" like everyone else?
Even though she is a very mature transfer student...
She's still my friend.
A FRIENDSHIP THAT CAN'T BE BOUGHT
(PART ONE)
Jeez, the professor and Haibara...
What're they waiting for?
The professor has put us behind schedule again.
Alright, when I see Haibara-san, I'll say "Good morning, Ai-chan."
But Haibara-san may get mad...
But then again, Haibara-san may say, "Good morning, Ayumi-chan!"
That would be great!
I could say Haibara-senpai...
I can't treat her specially, I must treat her just like all of my other friends!
Hey, Professor, get out here!
We're already gonna be late!
Sorry, sorry.
It took me a while to pack.
You never seem to be on time.
Well, you know how it is...
I'm pretty sure it was the cleaning, not the packing, that took you so long.
I came out and saw quite a few garbage bags.
Good morning...
Ai... Ai... Ai...
I think you didn't get enough sleep last night, Haibara-san.
Well, I'm most active at night.
Oh well, I'll have another chance later today.
Camp! Camp! Camping today and camping tomorrow!
Hey, Professor...
Did you figure out that diary?
Diary?
Our lead to those guys in black...
The one they hired to develop a system: the computer programmer, Itakura-san.
The one who used spaces between diary entries...
That trick he used to conceal what he knew of the Black Organization.
That secret key.
Especially around the end, when he talked to the mysterious caller.
Oh, you mean...
We can be both of God and the Devil.
That woman who called about raising the dead against the stream of time?
Since we're trying to raise the dead against the stream of time.
I still don't know what she meant, but...
I did learn that she hates cats.
Cats?
We had to stop reading because Ai-kun came along...
But there was more to it.
"The cat's yelping in the background got louder when the woman said that.
"She hung up shortly after."
That doesn't tell us anything.
She may have hung up because her cat was annoying her.
Being allergic to cats isn't uncommon either.
If only you knew Haibara's father, that scientist Miyano Atsushi.
Miyano Atsushi?
Oh, I know Professor Miyano.
I met him at a number of conferences.
You know that outlawed mad scientist!?
Mad scientist?
Professor Miyano was a very polite man.
He even praised some of my inventions.
Who I thought was suspicious wasn't him, but his wife.
I think her name was Elena.
Elena? His wife wasn't Japanese?
Yeah, I heard they met when she came from England to study here in Japan.
But really...
I never thought she would turn out to be Ai-kun's mother.
I see.
That's why she doesn't seem Japanese at all.
Now that you mention it, Professor Miyano never even mentioned his own research.
Hey, watch out!
What just happened?
That was close...
Be more careful, Professor.
They came out of nowhere.
Such a big car.
It's amazing.
It must be a camping car.
How can they get so excited over one of these?
I don't see anyone inside.
It'd be great to go camping in one of these.
Hey, you all!
Fukuura Reiji (21)
College Student
Don't put your hands all over it.
Shirafuji Yasumi (22)
College Student
That car's important to my best friend.
Right, Haruka-san?
Yeah.
Tendou Haruka (21)
College Student
But, if they were just looking...
My uncle, who let us borrow it in the first place, wouldn't really mind.
You're sure being nice to those kids.
Especially compared to when I smoke on there.
You smoke too much, Reiji-kun!
It's that kindness that made you fall in love with her, right?
Shut up.
Oh, we were just looking at your car.
We didn't mean to disturb you.
We were just attracted to it.
Sorry.
But, our hands aren't dirty.
We understand, boy.
Sorry for that.
Hey, Yasumi-chan!
Can you come look at the food?
Meshiai Takuto (23)
College Student
I think it's almost ready.
Wow, this looks great!
That meat must've been expensive, right?
You guys wanna join us?
We've got some extras.
Can we really!?
But, that's for dinner...
Stop being selfish!
We can always use Haruka-san's money and get more from the supermarket.
Right, Haruka-san?
Yeah.
We'd be glad to have you.
All right!
Oh, so you guys are a college group?
Yep, we're the Outdoor Club.
The mountains, the sea, anywhere.
We even went to Hawaii once.
Well, it's all thanks to our sponsor Haruka-san, right?
That's not true.
Yasumi-san's a great cook...
Reiji-kun's an impressive driver...
And Meshiai-kun has a real eye for eatable plants in the wild.
Since I don't have any real talent...
All I can offer is money.
"I'm just a princess who can do no wrong...
"The only thing I can do is give out money."
That's something I'd like to be able to say!
That's not it...
Really, she's too good for a womanizer like you, Reiji!
Would you just shut up already?
The way she relates to that "princess"...
It's just like Far and Sonoko.
Are you sick?
It doesn't look like you have much of an appetite.
No...
It's just the way it should be.
All right, ready?
Well?
Great—10 minutes, 31 seconds.
More than 10 seconds.
For real?
I was sure I beat it this time...
Maybe next time.
Hey, that belt...
It looks like Okino Yoko-chan's belt.
That's right.
It's just like hers.
But I'm the first one to get it.
Yasumi-chan's been wearing it a lot lately.
Yep, makes me look like an idol, right?
I know! For letting us eat lunch with you, why don't you join us for dinner?
Oh, really?
Oh, that would be great, little girl.
Well, we should go ahead and get back.
You're right.
How is it, Conan-kun?
Not bad.
Can I have the first batch?
You already ate half of the last meal.
I know that.
Then, I'll go ask that group if they want to join us.
Let's go, A-A-Ai...
Ai-Ai—Ice cream, they'll come for that, right?
I guess.
Wow, this is some great curry!
Let's have our cook try it out.
Huh? Where is Yasumi-chan?
I haven't seen her in a while.
The bike from the car is gone, so she may have went off somewhere, but...
We're pretty far from any stores.
Maybe she decided to go ahead and get up to that spot already.
"That spot"?
It's our special place.
It takes about five minutes by car.
Well, we should go.
You guys wanna come up to our special place?
Well then, well follow you all in my Beetle.
Actually, we could go together.
Would you like to, in the camping car?
Of course!
Awesome! Awesome!
This is so comfy!
They've got TV!
A toilet, too!
And even a shower!
It's like a hotel room!
It's definitely nice.
What's that noise?
Wow, looks like it's already started.
Reiji-kun...
Please open the sunroof.
A sunroof?
Well, want me to give you a lift so you can see?
What is it?
Well, I'll have to show you.
There, look!
Fireworks! Fireworks!
Hey, can I see?
It's behind the mountain now.
Well, ready to go back in?
Yeah.
It's all right, just wait until we get to the top.
Be careful, Fuukura!
Is something wrong?
I just hit something that was in the road...
Hey, what was it?
It couldn't be...
Could it be?
What's this?
A piece from a fence!
Whew, that was close.
I thought it was Yasumi.
It must have fallen from above.
Let's hurry and get moving!
We don't wanna miss the fireworks!
Yeah.
So amazing!
Fly!
This really is a great spot for enjoying the fireworks.
Yeah.
We found this spot by chance while camping four years ago.
It's our special place, since no one else knows about it.
Well, this will probably be the last time everyone comes together, since we're graduating soon.
That reminds me, where's Yasumi?
I found some bicycle tire marks over here.
What?
Over here where the fence broke.
Wait, does that mean Yasumi-chan went...
Don't be foolish.
We would have seen her on the way up here.
But...
Maybe someone came up here and broke her bicycle.
Really?
Sure, she could be that unlucky.
But I wonder where Yasumi-chan went.
I was sure she went up there.
Yeah...
Does Yasumi-san do this occasionally?
Yeah. Last summer, she biked up to the spot to beat us.
She sounds kinda selfish.
You'd say that, Genta-kun.
Hey, Fuukura!
What is it now?
I... I found...
Yasumi...
Yasumi-chan?
Where?
The road...
The victim is a college student, Shirafuji Yasumi-san, age 22.
Judging from the blood loss near the head, it is my belief that death occurred on impact with something.
The fall was the cause?
I believe so.
What did she hit?
Well...
Only a bit of blood has collected here, despite the massive head wound.
Is that so?
And the estimated time of death?
Likely between 5:00 and 6:00 PM.
That can't be right.
You guys, again?
What're you all doing here?
We were driving on this road to get to the top after sundown.
No one was in the road then.
We found Yasumi-san's body on our way back down.
It's not possible that you all just missed her?
No, we met these people at a campsite nearby.
We spent the evening with them.
Afterwards, they offered to let us ride in their camping car to go watch the fireworks.
And Yasumi-san wasn't with you?
Yeah.
We passed by here to get to the fireworks show, which had already started.
That was about 7:00.
Around 9:00, the show ended so we came back down...
To find our friend Yasumi lying in the road.
But, you're sure no one was here when you drove by at 7:00 PM?
Yeah, all that was here was a piece of a wooden fence.
A wooden fence?
Look, from that wooden fence of there.
We were watching the fireworks up there.
Part of the fence had fallen down here, so I hit the brakes...
But, I couldn't completely avoid it.
Was it really just part of a fence?
Of course.
When I looked at it, it seemed someone had broken it...
At first, I thought Yasumi-chan had fell after breaking through the fence on the bike.
Bike?
It's a detachable bike from our camping car.
After seeing it was gone, we came up here to where we thought she'd be.
She always liked to get a head start and get here first.
But even then, we didn't see Yasumi-chan or the bike...
So it didn't really occur to me.
Anyway, let's head up there—to where everyone was watching the fireworks.
There are some bicycle tire marks here near the broken fence.
It's likely she crashed here.
Why didn't you look into these tire marks earlier?
We didn't think it was that bad.
Inspector Megure!
What is it, Takagi-kun?
We found a bicycle!
It was jarred in a bush on the other side of the guardrail.
Oh, I see.
Bring it up here so we can confirm it's the right one.
Yeah, no doubt about it!
This is the one from the camping car.
That's it!
All right, go confirm that the tire marks match.
The marks match perfectly.
I see, so that's what happened.
Yasumi-san first took the bike to beat the rest of you here.
Since it was so dark, she wasn't able to hit her brakes in time...
And went through the fence.
She went over the hill...
And then rolled into the bush the bike was found in.
And while you all were watching fireworks, her body fell from the bush it was stuck in...
Only to be discovered by on your way back from the fireworks show.
It was an accident, then.
Yeah, your reasoning explains why the road where she was found didn't have much blood on it.
Oh, really?
It seems that Yasumi-san also came here last year.
She should know the size of the place and that there is a cliff beyond the railing, right?
Then, why would she crash into the railing?
That's because it was too dark for her to see anything.
Wouldn't she be more careful since it was dark?
She knew that it was dangerous.
That's...
It must be because Yasumi-san was so happy to be the first to arrive that she didn't brake in time.
Right, right—it was too late when she noticed, and that's why she went over.
Then, why...
That's dangerous, Conan-kun.
If Yasumi-san fell from here, you should be able to find it on the road below, right?
The blood from where Yasumi-san hit her head.
How about it, Takagi-kun?
Now that I think of it, we only found fragments from the broken light...
But absolutely no blood anywhere.
What now?
Inspector, perhaps Yasumi-san didn't fall to her death, but rather...
A murder in which someone created the bicycle tracks to give the false impression that it was an accident.
If that's the case...
The culprit must be someone who could take the bicycle from the camping car at any time.
Yeah.
The probability that one of Yasumi-san's three traveling companions was responsible is very high.
And, who was driving the camping car?
The one who is the best at it and has been trained, Fukuura.
Hey, hey, if it's just making it move, any of us three could do it!
So that's how it was...
And this trick requires a high level of skill...
It's that person!
A FRIENDSHIP THAT CAN'T BE BOUGHT
(PART TWO)
Next time is part two!
Will Ayumi-chan finally be permitted to say "Ai-chan"?
It's "chan, chan."