Alibi tricks are always uncovered!
The end of a friendship and sorrowful doubts.
Happiness just can't be bought.
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Together with Professor Agasa, the Detective Boys went on a camping trip.
And it was there that we met four university students from an outdoor club with a luxurious camping car...
Fukuura Reiji-san...
Shirafuji Yasumi-san...
Tendou Haruka-san...
And Meshiai Takuto-san.
And, while everyone was enjoying the barbecue...
Shirafuji-san disappeared.
To look for her, we took the camping car to a viewing platform on a hill, where fireworks could be seen...
But she wasn't there either.
But, on the way back down...
In the middle of the winding road...
We discovered Shirafuji Yasumi-san's body.
If that's the case...
The culprit must be someone who could take the bicycle from the camping car at any time.
Yeah.
The probability that one of Yasumi-san's three traveling companions was responsible is very high.
A FRIENDSHIP THAT CAN'T BE BOUGHT
(PART TWO)
Hold on a second, Detective.
Why do we need to provide alibis?
Wasn't Yasumi's death an accident?
It's just a precaution.
At any rate, since Yasumi-san died between 5:00 and 6:00 PM this evening...
Could you please relay what you were doing at that time?
Tendou Haruka (21)
College Student
Even if you ask...
We were off on our own...
Meshiai Takuto (23)
College Student
I was fishing alone.
Fukuura Reiji (21)
College Student
No one would be keeping an eye on their watch while camping, would they?
And, who was driving the camping car?
The one who is the best at it and has been trained, Fukuura.
Hey, hey, if it's just making it move, any of us three could do it!
Meishiai and I usually take turns.
Not to mention that Haruka-san was the one who drove it to the meeting place.
Uhm, why are you asking us this?
Ah well, because if you can't drive, you would not be able to move the body to that spot.
You really are suspecting us, aren't you?
Yeah, that's right.
The culprit put Yasumi-san's body in the middle of the road beforehand.
When ascending the mountain, they acted as if they did not see the body and drove past it.
And, on the way down, pretended they had just discovered it.
And, with so few cars on this mountain road...
So long as no one is in the passenger seat while the driver goes up the mountain...
Indeed, it's true that there wasn't anyone in the passenger seat...
But if the angle is changed...
The view outside the window will change, and even those in the back will notice.
Avoiding a body without changing direction, especially one lying in the middle of the road, just isn't possible.
Also, while passing this place, we opened the sunroof and peered out.
There wasn't anything on the road.
You looked out the sunroof?
Yeah.
When we came here last year, we saw fireworks between the mountains after we looked out.
That's why—we just wanted to show the kids as well.
Well, we could only see for those ten seconds we were turning.
But, you know...
If you only opened the sunroof after you avoided the corpse...
Didn't I say that it was impossible to avoid?
That's right.
Before or after the sunroof was opened...
The camper didn't seem to meander.
What's that?
There's a strange line on one end of the sunroof...
Could it be...
Conan-kun?
Hey, Conan!
This line is...
It's blood.
The clotted blood took the shape of a line...
I see.
So that's what it was.
I've solved the case!
And this trick requires a high level of skill...
It's that person!
The flashlight...
Thank goodness.
Thank you, Genta-kun.
Are you all right?
Thank you...
A-Ai...
Please be careful.
The wind is really strong tonight.
The camper is also inclined because of the hill.
But, you know...
It isn't bad to be on top of this.
You get to see such a beautiful night scene.
It was right here...
That I saw the fireworks from inside the camper.
From here?
Wait...
In that case, the trick I thought of just now...
Hey, you guys!
It's dangerous to climb up there.
Conan--kun!
Hey, Conan, where are you going?
This isn't good...
I nearly fell for the culprit's trick.
The real trick was...
There it is.
This is it.
Hey, did you find something?
Yeah.
A plastic sheet.
And there's blood on it.
What'd you say?!
It's true...
We have to hurry and report this to the inspector.
But this has gotten troublesome.
Anyone could have used this trick...
And there's no evidence that points to the culprit.
If that's the case, we can only show them the sheet...
And observe their reaction.
What?
A plastic sheet with blood on it, you say?
Yes.
It was at a place about 50 meters from here...
Caught on the guardrail.
I see.
Those are definitely blood stains.
Hey, isn't this the plastic sheet we usually use when camping?
What?
Can I trouble you all to confirm this?
It definitely is.
Yeah.
We haven't used it recently because there's a hole in it...
But, why is it here?
This is bad.
There's nothing abnormal about their reactions.
In that case, I'll have to go look around the mountains for more evidence.
So that's what it was!
The blood got onto the culprit's clothes!
I know the culprit committed the murder in a panic, but...
It won't be easy to avoid...
This critical mistake.
Haven't we repeated this a few times?
When we passed by this spot with the camping car at 7:00 PM...
There was nothing on the road.
It was only when we came back two hours later...
That we found Yasumi in the middle of the road.
When we were coming up the mountain, all that fell down was the wooden railing.
Besides, didn't that officer just tell us?
Where the railing was damaged and where it landed...
Formed a straight line with the spot where Yasumi-san was found.
And up there at the damaged part of the railings, there were also tire tracks.
The bicycle was also found caught in the trees under the guardrail.
Most likely, when Yasumi-chan cycled up the mountain...
That means she crashed into them and fell over, right?
As for why we didn't see Yasumi-san on the road while ascending...
Yasumi-san was caught in the trees at that time, along with the bicycle.
She fell down before we descended.
That's what you said, right?
Yeah, but...
Then, isn't this an accident?
Why do you insist on suspecting us?
The lack of a blood stain.
There isn't one where Yasumi-san initially landed.
If she went through the railings and fell down...
And yet, there's no blood there...
Don't you find that strange?
No way...
That means Yasumi-chan was...
This point and plastic sheet...
If this blood stain turns out to be from Yasumi-san...
This will have a vital connection to the case.
A very important connection.
Agasa-san?
Professor!
With the sunroof closed, it will probably be difficult to hear my deduction.
Can you open the sunroof for me?
Sure.
But, why did you climb onto the roof?
I just wanted to experience...
How the dead Yasumi-san felt while being transported this way.
How the dead Yasumi-san felt while being transported...
Then, you mean that the culprit actually placed Yasumi-san's corpse on the camper's roof?
That's right.
The culprit pretended to look for Yasumi-san...
And rode with us on this camper.
Along the way, the body on the roof was thrown onto the road.
The method used for murdering Yasumi-san likely went like this...
The culprit first asked Yasumi-san to get on top of the camper to clean the sunroof.
And then, they got behind the one who had fallen for their trap...
And used a rock or something to hit her head to kill her.
The evidence is this red line on the sunroof.
The culprit wanted to wipe away the blood left behind after killing Yasumi-san...
But this red line was left behind.
Hold on, old man.
How could Yasumi-san's body be thrown onto that particular spot?
All of us were in the camper.
Fukuura...
When you came upon the broken railing on the road, you were able to brake in time, right?
Yeah, what about it?
I see.
He made use of the the inertia from the sudden braking...
To throw the body over the guard rail...
And have it land on the road below.
The broken railing was used as a marker for when to brake.
That's why the body was found on the way back.
Wait!
There are several sharp curves in this area!
The body would have fallen off if nothing was holding it down.
Was there rope or tape found near her body?
About that...
That's right, that lady's belt...
It looks like the one Okino Yoko-chan wears!
There were somethings fluttering on it...
But, how was it done?
Oh, you didn't notice?
Of all the decorative tassels on her belt...
Only one had a knot in it.
Yeah, I saw that as well.
I thought it was just something fashionable.
Oh, there is something I forgot to mention.
Detective Takagi...
Can you close the sunroof for me?
Oh, sure.
Look at this line of blood that was just mentioned.
Isn't it just a small distance from the edge?
Why do you think that is?
That must be because, when she was killed, the sunroof was slightly open.
But why did the sunroof need to be slightly open?
"Why"?
I see!
Using the knot on Yasumi-san's belt that was just mentioned...
Exactly.
The culprit held the knot with the sunroof...
In order to secure the body in place.
That's why the body was folded into a U-position.
The reason the criminal opened the sunroof slightly before the murder...
Was to allow the murder to be much smoother.
If they had not done that, after killing Yasumi-san on the roof...
They would have to go back down to open the sunroof from the driver's seat...
Climb back onto the roof to put the knot in place...
And then finally go back down again to close it.
That's because the button to open it can only be found on the driver's seat.
Come to think of it...
You all said that, while ascending the mountain, you opened the sunroof to see the fireworks...
Who opened it?
Of course, it was me—the driver.
But the one who asked me to open it was Haruka-san.
N-No...
I just wanted them to see the great things we did last year.
I see.
If that's so, it's possible to predict someone would want to open it again this year.
Even if that weren't the case...
As the driver, it's possible for you secretly open it, if only just a bit.
Hey...
And so, you opened the sunroof in order to free the knot.
With the body freed...
You could use the inertia from braking near the piece of broken fence...
To throw the body onto the road below.
In other words, the only one able to manage this trick...
Would be the one with training and skills as a drift driver, which means it could only be you.
You think so too?
But that's actually not the case.
Of course, I thought that initially as well...
But I had missed two points.
The first is that this stretch of road is uphill.
The second is that this is the exact place the sunroof was opened.
Only when I saw the blood stain on the plastic sheet did I think of it.
So long as it is in place, below the body...
The plastic sheet will reduce the friction as a result.
Even if nothing else was done...
The instant the sunroof is opened...
The body will slide right off the inclined roof.
It also means that any of you three could commit the crime.
I'm very sorry...
But I'll have to trouble you by hauling all of you down to the station.
We can find the culprit without doing that.
Because the culprit overlooked the method of wearing clothes.
The method?
Will you three please stand up for me?
It can't be helped.
What exactly can you see from this?
What is it, Ayumi-chan?
Look, at her belt!
It hasn't been properly put through the slots in the pants.
Then, could it be...
You're the culprit?
No, I'm not—I just left home in a hurry.
Ayumi-chan...
You took a photo of everyone with your digital camera, right?
I recall a picture that caught this lady from behind.
Hold on.
Not this one...
There it is.
It should be this one.
But, in the picture, her belt was ran through properly.
It was in place then.
So why isn't it now?
That's because I took a shower here in the camping car earlier.
It must have been then...
Oh?
Is there a reason to take the belt out of your jeans for a shower?
That's because I changed into another pair of jeans.
Another pair?
Yes.
Can I see that for a second?
Sure.
These pairs of jeans are pretty similar.
The jeans you're wearing in the photo...
And the ones you're wearing now.
Not really...
Then, excuse me, but may I see them?
The jeans you changed out of.
About that...
You wouldn't be able to see them even if you wanted.
Those were the jeans she wore when she killed Yasumi-san.
Along with the blouse she had on, they've both likely been thrown somewhere on the mountain.
Those jeans had Yasumi-san's blood on it.
But...
It was her who let us ride the camper to see the fireworks.
That's right.
If she was using the camper to move the body, why did she let us ride along?
No.
She had to let us ride in the camper.
If we had followed behind in my car...
We would see the body fly off, wouldn't we?
But, but...
She's the daughter of a rich family...
I'm not some rich daughter.
I'm just an ordinary university student from the countryside.
If I didn't pretend to be rich, no one would befriend me.
It was tough.
I worked so hard, and even resorted to getting loans...
Just to rent this expensive camping car...
So we could take it to the mountains or the beach.
But, since they were my first friends, I did my best...
Well, I thought they were friends...
Until I heard Yasumi say...
You didn't know?
It's a complete lie that she's the daughter of a rich family.
I noticed it immediately.
I even followed her home.
Her apartment was so run-down.
Then, we've been deceived for four years?
Then, shouldn't we tell her we know, and ask that she stop pretending?
Isn't she your close friend, Yasumi-chan?
Close friend?
She's only my financial supporter.
Why else would I pretend not to know for four years?
It was tough trying not to laugh.
I mean, if we tell her now...
What will we do if she gets angry and asks us to return the money from the past four years?
I don't think she's that kind of person.
But Reiji, what a pity.
Weren't you hoping for a big catch?
Well, I'm disappointed.
I'll say "bye-bye" after graduation.
But, before then, let's have her keep contributing.
This "rich daughter" Haruka.
I honestly believed it.
I honestly believed we were friends...
So you killed Yasumi-chan...
And framed Reiji.
Yeah!
I got my revenge!
On that woman who trampled all over "friendship"!
That's not a friend at all!
You were never friends, even from the beginning...
Yeah, she's right.
It's like an automated vending machine for canned juice.
You'll get what you want so long as you have the money, but...
You get nothing in return without it.
You can't buy your way into the hearts of others.
But that last line that Ai-kun came out with was splendid.
Yeah!
You said everything that was in my heart.
Haibara also says the right things when she has to.
It's nothing.
I'm just using what I've learned...
From a certain someone.
I think that's usually the case.
There was a time when Ran rejected an invitation from Sonoko to go skiing.
When I asked her why...
She told me sadly that she didn't have enough pocket money for the month.
At that time, I asked her why she didn't let Sonoko pay for her, since she's rich.
She replied to me with anger.
That's out of the question!
I want to be friends with Sonoko for life!
Or so she said.
So, to stick around her because she's from a rich family...
And use her money for granted...
It seems the relationships between them are a little fake.
But you were really cool...
A-Ai...
You can call me by my name.
You wanted to call me that, didn't you?
Really?
Ai-chan!
Then...
We'll call you that too!
Ai—
Not you guys.
Yes, ma'am...
But I wanted to see Sonoko-neechan's villa in Karuizawa too!
And, besides, that Sonoko...
She wouldn't have any great plans anyway.
Huh?
She's not in here.
SUSPICIOUS CURRY
(PART ONE)
Curry rice
Next Episode's Hint
Next time is...
Tennis after camping!
A net after a tent!
And hot curry for adults.