Deduction flows with the rhythm of the wind,
and causes alibi tricks to fall apart!
Sonoko's world of Karuizawa!
After all, there's trouble with a spicy case!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Hey, Ran! Hurry up!
We're running late!
Okay, I'll be right there!
Now, now, old man, it's nothing to get heated up over.
Is that so? Why the heck do I, Kogoro Mouri, have to serve as a driver for two brats?
Hey, you're from the Suzuki Financial Group, don't you have your own chauffer?
No way! I don't want a chauffer driving me around on vacation.
I hate feeling like I'm being watched!
Oh, is that so...
That's how it is!
Well, there's one kid who's got a cold,
so be careful you don't catch it.
Eh? Conan-kun has a cold?
Thanks for waiting!
It took me a while to get Conan-kun ready.
Are you going to be okay, Conan-kun?
You have a cold, don't you?
I'm fine, just fine. I just got the sniffles!
Okay, now that we're all set, off we go to Karuizawa! All aboard!
Yeah, yeah.
Suspicious Spicy Curry
(Part 1)
Are you okay, Conan-kun?
I'm fine...
Alright, but If you start feeling bad, tell me right away.
Geez, with that cold, why didn't you just stay home?
The manager at Poirot offered to watch you for the day.
But I want to go to Karuizawa to see Sonoko-neechan's villa too!
Geez...
And besides, if I know Sonoko for who she is,
she'll probably think up some no good plan like always...
We'll do just great!
Maybe we'll get a really good guy!
What? We're going to play tennis to get guys?
Of course! Around this time, the tennis courts near our villa
are full of college students!
Geez, if you do something like that, Kyogoku-san will get mad at you!
What do you mean?
Of course, Makoto-san's the only guy for me...
You're the one who's going to get someone today!
You'll use a tennis outfit to show off your body and wow a guy,
then you'll take a photo with him,
and send it as an e-mail attachment!
You'll do all this to get that boyfriend of yours, Kudo-kun, jealous!
How about it?
I don't think Shin'ichi will get jealous...
I knew she was up to something...
B-Besides, the only thing I have
is a track suit from Teitan High.
I don't have tennis wear!
Don't you worry!
I bought you tennis wear and brought it along.
Tada! Super mini, and cute too!
S-Short!
H-Hey! I could never wear something like that!
I didn't bring spats with me either!
I see. I guess there's no choice then...
Well, you'll just have to wear your plain panties.
P-Plain panties?!
Damnit! I'd love to see that, but not if other people see it too!
Hey, I don't know what you guys are up to,
but if my daughter is embarrassing herself
for that detective brat, I'm turning around.
I wouldn't mind...
But there will be lots of university babes there too!
University babes!
It was so nice in the morning...
W-Where are all my university babes...
Looks like we can't play tennis then.
I don't know if I should feel happy or sad over this...
Aw, I was looking forward to seeing Ran's panty flash shots that I hadn't seen in a while today...
Too bad!
Well, I guess it's for the best...
Huh? Somebody's on the tennis court...
C-Could they be, a university babe?
Oh, it's just a guy...
Excuse me, is there something wrong?
Wow, he's hot!
Hiroto Akashi (32)
Tennis Instructor
Oh, no...
I was just recalling memories of when I first met my wife here.
Oh, he's already taken...
Hey, if you guys came to play tennis,
would you like me to coach you?
I'm a tennis instructor, you see...
My house is nearby, so if you're interested...
Thanks for the offer, but I'm afraid we're busy...
I'm sorry...
I see. That's too bad...
Goodbye then.
Aw, so we couldn't catch any men after all.
In that case...
let's catch some fish instead!
Hey, hey, what's with this turn of events?
Just you wait! I'll catch us some delicious fish for dinner!
At the villa, the cook and my big sister are waiting with dinner already...
Hey, isn't the river water rising?
Aw, the fish took my bait and tackle off again...
That's because you don't tie it right!
Fish lines are smooth, so unless you tie them like this—
Wait! Your rod, it's being pulled!
What?!
H-Hey, I must have hooked a big one!
Oh?! That's my rental car!
No way!
It's been washed into the river!
Didn't I tell you,
you parked the car too close to the river?
Come on...
Dad!
Damnit! I'm not letting the river take the car!
Just give up, dad!
Hey, are you okay?
I'm fine, but my right wrist hurts a bit.
Maybe you sprained it...
You probably landed on it when you fell into the river.
Well, it's way better than being stranded in the water!
This is no time for jokes!
Okay, I'll stop...
But, what do we do now?
All of our things were in the car.
Our cell phones are all out of range,
And it's getting dark after all of this walking.
On top of all that,
do you think we might be lost?
W-Wait! You mean you've been walking around not knowing where we were?
W-Well, I've just been following my intuition...
Geez, what do we do now?
Oh? There's a light.
See, over there.
Y-You mean people are living out in the mountains like this?
In the mountains? It must be a mountain witch!
Then let's have her take us in for a while.
We've got to get a change of clothes for this brat, remember?
Hello? Sorry to intrude at this hour,
But is anybody home?
Sorry!
A monster!
You guys are the ones who are monsters...
Hiroto's Father
So are you guys more solicitors?
Even if you brought kids, you can't trick me!
Ah, no. We're not...
Go home! Go home!
This is no place for swindlers like you!
Who is it, dad?
Huh? You guys are...
What a funny story!
You guys fell into the river while trying to fish out your car that drifted into it.
It's not a laughing matter...
Sorry, sorry. But he'll be alright.
With this sling, and a splint to fix his wrist in place,
he'll recover in no time.
Wait, please turn this way and let me look inside your mouth.
Your throat is red and your voice is getting hoarse,
so try to avoid using your voice too much.
Otherwise you might get acute laryngitis.
You sound like you're a doctor.
Yeah, I used to be a personal trainer and a coach for a pro,
so I learned a lot from when I did that...
Anyways, how do the clothes from my childhood fit you?
Are they the right size?
They fit perfect!
That's good to hear.
Do I smell curry?
Yeah, it's just leftovers from last night though.
By any chance, do you guys want some?
I-If you don't mind...
Oh! This is delicious! Restaurant quality!
Yeah, this is really good!
Because of your sore throat Conan-kun, you get eggs over rice, okay?
Okay...
I like the spiciness of this curry!
Your wife must be a good cook!
Ah, no...
The one who made this was me.
My wife passed away 3 years ago today...
I see. That's why you were at the tennis court recalling memories of her.
Well, back when I was a trainer,
I made healthy meals for my players, focusing on nutrition.
So I was a better cook than my wife.
Well, I'm going to go take some curry to my father upstairs,
so help yourselves to seconds.
Thanks!
Dad, I brought you some food.
Okay.
Hiroto-san sure is taking his time.
It's already been 40 minutes.
This is really bothering me.
Huh? What is?
This long pull string hanging from the light above!
It keeps getting in the way of me eating...
Stop complaining! You've already had two plates.
That string is for my father.
He wanted a string he could reach with his hunched back.
Oh, I get it.
But you sure took a long time, considering all you did was give him curry...
Yeah, my father started saying some strange things, so we started talking to each other...
"I'm not going to eat because I want to die."
Want to die?
Since his wife and his daughter-in-law died before him,
he thinks that he has a curse placed on him by God.
Well, he seems to be fine now that he got some curry,
since it's his favorite food.
What? The road is blocked due to a landslide,
so you can't come pick us up today?
Are you serious?
In that case, you can stay here for the night.
We've got some spare futons.
Well, we appreciate it.
Oh, I almost forgot.
Can you go get my father's dish for me?
Yes, of course!
Oh, keep in mind, he's a slow eater and can be uncooperative.
If his light is still on, he's still eating,
so just come back down quietly, okay?
O-Okay.
The room's light is...
It's still on.
Quietly, quietly...
Weeping?
Not like that.
This is a stance for a forehand.
He must be done eating by now...
I'm going to go back up to get his dishes!
Oh, thank you!
Ah, I'll go up with you!
Quietly, quietly...
Alright, the light is off!
Huh? He's not on his futon.
Ran!
He's bleeding from his mouth?
Ran! What's wrong?
F-Father...
It can't be...
Hey, what's going on?
He's still warm, but his toes are starting to stiffen.
I estimate that he's been dead for around 30 minutes.
I'm sorry Hiroto-san, but can you call the police?
S-Sure!
I guess the Gunma police officers will be coming...
Wait, the Gunma officers?
O-Oh no...
I've been summoned so here I am, ta-daaah!
For you Mouri-san, I would go through fire and water!
The rain may have blocked the roads, but when you called I came immediately!
Does the Gunma Police Station have nobody else to dispatch?
So? What kind of murder case is it this time?
What's the weapon? Any evidence?
You're going to do it, right?
The Sleeping Kogoro deduction show!
Stop smiling all over the place here!
Have some prudence!
Besides, we're don't even know if this is a murder case yet!
There's the body over there.
D-Don't tell me, this is...
The deceased is the owner of this house, Iwao Akashi-san.
The body was discovered by
my daughter Ran, who came to clear his curry dish.
When she found him, the room's light was turned off.
But when she checked hour and a half earlier, the light was on,
so she thought he was still eating his curry and didn't enter the room.
Also, I checked immediately after the incident,
and he seemed to have been dead for about 30 minutes.
There were four of us in the house,
but we were all in the living room downstairs for at least 2 hours, so we all have alibis.
Well, I wasn't in the living room then, because I was taking a bath.
T-That means, the one who committed the murder,
would be you, Mouri-san!
Remember, the first time I came to this house was today!
I don't even know where the rope is kept, so I couldn't have done it!
A-Ah, got it...
Well, it's a bit concerning that the victim is bleeding from his mouth,
but since this is obviously a suicide—
Huh? What makes it concerning?
I thought people who die like this always bleed from their mouth?
Yes, yes, I've seen it all the time in movies and on TV!
But that's not right...
A doctor told me once that when something is wrapped around your throat,
your face gets swollen due to the blood circulation stopping, so you don't bleed from the mouth
unless the inside is cut or something.
So in movies and on TV, I think they do it to make it visually obvious that the person is dead.
Oh no, don't try to talk.
You'll strain your throat with your cold.
But, if it's as the boy said,
I wonder why he's bleeding from his mouth...
I think it's due to him going to the dentist.
He said he went to go to the dentist about a hurting cavity.
May I ask who you are?
I'm Iwao Akashi's son, Hiroto.
He adopted me when I was a child.
His right molar has been pulled out...
It seems that after he died,
it bled from here, causing blood to come out when he drooled...
Hiroto-san, do you know when and where your father went to the dentist?
N-No... he went to it by himself two or three days ago...
What difference does it make?
We already know this is definitely suicide.
He probably used this stepladder here.
He got on here and pulled the rope around the thick beam there...
No doubt this is suicide.
According to what Hiroto-san told us,
his father was saying that he wanted to die...
I-Is that so?
What will I do then?
I told everybody at the station I was going to videotape Sleeping Kogoro's deduction show!
Good grief...
What will I tell everyone when I get back to the station?
Well, it's not all bad.
If it's a suicide, you don't have to bother with investigating further.
W-Well that's true, but...
Hey, don't you think it's strange?
This old man is bent over and only about 30 centimeters taller than me, yet...
See, the string for the light here is made to fit the old man's height,
I can't reach it even if I stretch my arm!
The kid is right.
Then, that means this isn't a suicide?
W-Well, a while back when my father got up late at night,
the string got in his face and he hated it.
So the light pull string in my father's room is short.
Oh, I get it.
So, it is suicide after all...
Yeah...
Well, we'll be waiting downstairs in the living room,
so call me if you need anything.
I'm sorry.
Getting all of you dragged into something like this while on your vacation.
Oh, it's fine.
Hey, you like fishing too?
Because...
This book, "Fishing for Beginners".
Ah, my wife was the one bought that book.
Your wife who passed away of illness 3 years ago?
Yeah...
But, I never saw her go fishing,
so maybe she was planning on doing so after she recovered.
Something's strange...
Something's strange about this guy.
The way he made Ran go all the way upstairs for the dish,
the length of the light's pull string,
and the story about him going to the dentist.
If he knew that he got his teeth treated 2 or 3 days ago,
why did he make something like curry?
If when he was a trainer,
he made food and focused on nutrition,
he should have noticed that detail.
And the curry,
he made far too much for just the two of them.
He couldn't have known beforehand that we would come here.
Also,
the knot tied on the pull string.
No question...
This case... has something fishy behind it!
Come to think of it, what?
It's not much, but when I went in front of the room the first time,
I heard the old man weeping "Uuugh..."
I get the picture... of this trick!
Okay, now that I know...
Oh no!
I lost my voice!
On the next Conan:
Suspicious Spicy Curry
(Part 2)
Electric Cable