Deduction flows with the rhythm of the wind
Dark stains are rinsed clean and exposed
The case in the big house
Smash with the deductive!
He sees through the one and only truth,
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult
no case is left unsolved with Detective Conan.
Ran, Pops and I are invited by Sonoko and head for her villa in Karuizawa...
On our way, our things together with the car sink into the river
when the water level rises.
We end up being able to spend the night at a house in the remote mountains
that we finally manage to get to
However, that night,
the owner of that house,
Mr. Iwao Akashi dies in has room upstalrs!
Suspicious Spicy Curry" Part 2
This is Yamamura from the Gunma Prefectural Poltce Station
U-Uh~~excuse me...
I'd like to ask you a question...
Uh, yes... what can I do for you...?
There are traces of something having been wrapped areund your father's wrists
Do you have any idea what it could be?
Hey... is that true...?
he had been tied up by someone?!
I think those are traces of rubber bands...
Father had a habit of bunching everything and anything up with rubber bands,
and always had rubber bands round both his wrists...
Oh, just as I thought...
Just as you thought...?
Y-Yes...
We found a lot of rubber bands under his pillow, so
I thought maybe...
Is there any thing else that you recall?
Like having seen someone suspicious around your house,
or having heard strange sounds or volces...?
Oh, come to think of it...
Come to think of it, what?
Oh, it's nothing,
but when I went in front of that room the first time I heard...
the man weeping, "Uuugh..."
What?
You heard him crying...?
He was probably crying after deciding to commit suicide...
Uh, didn't you see anything else in that room?!
C-Conan!
You shouldn't be talking...!
on the floor...
I think he wiped his mouth with it while eating curry,
because there was a little curry on it...
D-Don't tell me that...
If my deduction is correct...
Agh!
Mr. Akashi didn't go to the dentist...
The reason why he was bleeding from his mouth was...
probably because...
Huh?
Hey, sonny, what's up...
Oh! Hey!
D-Don't touch!
T-This is...!
I see... So, it's just as I thought...
If he had his tooth pulled out
his gums would've started to close like the not yet opened bud of a flower...
But his gums are still opened with no signs of closing up.
Neither are there signs of blood that would be
in the opening of the gum having dried up or anything!
he just got his tooth pulled out...
Moreover, the other teeth around it
This means that whatever he was clenching with all his mouth
between his teeth was pulled out with great force...
I get the picture... of this trick!
But, why...
If this trick is what I think it is, at should be somewhere in this room...
How come it's nowhere in sight...
Hey, what do we do?
Huh?
This half-eaten curry over rice?
Well, there wasn't any poison in it...
so shall we have them put it away?
Oh, that...
Huh? What is it?
Don't tell me... you want to eat it?
Huh?
H-Hey, stop it!
Y-You gotta be kidding? Hey, kid?!
F-Found it... This is it!
No doubt about it...
Hey, isn't that... a tooth?!
Huh?
What're you talking about?!
What, a human's tooth?
...Looks like it...
No doubt about it...
The one who killed Iwao created
created his own alibi,
and that person is Hirohito Akashi!
Okay, now that I know...
I've got to get everyone to come here
and start the usual
Sleeping Kogoro deduction show!
U-Uh...
What shall we do with this tooth...?
Well...
I guess we better report this to Officer Yamamura...
...Right
O... Oh, no...
No voice...
Darn!...What do I do now?!
After I figured out the case and all...
I can't use the voice changer to reveal
the truth of the case to anyone in this situation...
I would write but...
but with this sprained wrist I can't...
Only if they'd solve it themselves somehow...
My only hope is that
(So, what I think is...)
But, with the members here...
Hey, Conan, just where were you?!
(I,I've lost my voice!)
Oh no?! You mean you lost your voice?
You were told not to talk because you'd lose your voice, weren't you?
This case is plain to see!
At the time that Mr. Iwao Akashi passed away in his bedroom
around 7:30 p m. Ran, Conan, Sonoko and Hirohito, who were in this house
so we all have an alibi...
I was taking a bath, but have no motive
and had no way of getting the rope ready either...
Moreover... an hour before we discovered the corpse,
the light of the bedroom was on,
but when we discovered the body, it was turned off...
No matter how you look at it this is suicide!
Iwao turned off the light of the room
and then committed suicide!
So, I'd advise you to stop investigating right now and go on back to the station!
I-I guess so...
No, wrong...
This is homicide...
He used a trick to make it look like
The killer is Iwao's adopted son, Hirohito.
But what can I do?!
Without a voice...
how should I accuse him?!
Okay, although this is going to be a bit bothersome...
What?
Huh?
Hey, Conan, just what're you doing?
Isn't he gesturing?
Ripe crackers...
14 pieces of rice crackers?
(No, no...)
Crack, one... four?
(Close, close!)
Okay, could it be...
crack code one...?
Oh, I got it!
Crack this code... once and for all... right?
(Yes, yes!)
But, what is there to crack?
It
Huh? That curry?
Is something wrong with the curry?
It was spicy but good
Right
(No, no)
Huh, that's not it... What is it?
Me...
Sonoko...
Hiroto...
Huh? The old man upstairs?
A circle?
One...?
Me...3?
Are you talking about my age?
I'm a little over 33 already...
Ran was born when I was...
Are you talking about the amount of curry we all ate?
Hirohito, his father, Sonoko and I had one serving each,
but dad ate 3 servings!
(Right, right!)
So, what's wrong with that
It sure is strange!
Because you and your group just happened to come by
to this house tonight, right?
Moreover, Hirohito usually lives here only with his father.
There are just the two of you here, is that right?
Y-Yes...
Then, curry enough for 7 people is a bit too much
for just two people living together, don't you think?
It would surprise the Indians in India too!
Now that you mentioned it...
Don't tell me that you...
You must like curry?
I actually love curry too.
Oh... Well...
I made quite a lot because
I usually invite the students
that I've become friends, over!
They really seem to like the curry I make...
I would think so...
Too bad there was nobody at the tennis court today
because it rained...
Oh...
Tooth...
curry...
no good...
For the tooth... curry... no good?
(Bull's eye!)
Oh, could it mean...
That after a tooth is pulled out,
eating something too spicy is not good?
Remember when you had your decayed tooth pulled out,
the dentist told you so, right?
Y-Yeah...
But, then it's strange...
You knew that
your father had his tooth pulled out
2 or 3 days ago, didn't you, Mr. Akashi?
Y-Yes...
But, I had no idea that he had his tooth pulled out...
Officer Yamamura. could I speak to you for a moment...
Huh? Is that true?
is something the matter?
Well, the coroner is here checking on the corpse...
and he says that Iwao's tooth seems to have been pulled out
just a while ago, not 2 or 3 days ago...
And the tooth that was pulled out seems to have been found in the bedroom.
It seems to have been found for some reason in the half-eaten curry dish...
There must've been very tough meat in the curry,
because the teeth near the tooth that had come off all seemed to be shaky too...
I don't think such tough meat was in it...
He...
bit...
something?
You mean...
that old man?
I'm sure he was...
He was eating curry, you know,
Huh? You want me to sit?
Bring the tied part of the necktie around behind...
bring the end of the necktie to the front...
and bite?
I got it!
That old man
while biting on the rope!
(Bingo!)
If so.
he would eventually get tired
then he'd be strangled!
His tooth probably flew into the curry dish at that time because of the impact!
Since his mouth is blocked with the rope, he probably couldn't yell out either!
You mean that voice that I heard back then was
not him weeping, but him groaning...
But there were no traces of the rope by his mouth...
That's probably because...
T-The handkerchief!
Remember, the handkerchief with the curry on it was near the corpse,
Remember, {The handkerchief with the curry on r14 was negwthe corpse,
wasn't it?
He was made to bite the handkerchief together with the rope!
...If so...
then traces of the rope wouldn't be left around his mouth...
But, his hands weren't tied when he was found.
If he grabs the rope with both hands,
he can free his mouth so he could've shouted,
"Somebody help!"...
Hm...
Besides.
The bedroom light that was on an hour and a half ago, was turned off
when the corpse was found, wasn't it?
All during that time,
nobody went to that room, so how could the light have been turned off...
H-Hey...!
U-Uh, Conan?
Hey! Don't play around with it!
Both his wrists were tied with the string of the light fixture in a bow tie
and the edge of the string
was connected to the string
Then when he becomes exhausted
the rope will pull away from his mouth,
his body will slide down choking his neck, and at the same time
the string of the light fixture will be
The string that is tied to his wrists will untie...
and the body will be in the exact position as we found at!
Which means that the narrow lines that were found on Mr. Iwao Akashi's wrists
were marks that were left from his wrists being tied!
But these light fixtures have three levels
and unless you pull the string 3 times like Conan just did
it won't get dark, right?
Pulling just once would only turn off the fluorescent light on the outer part,
and pulling the string twice will still leave the miniature light on.
Phooey!
If the brightness is adjusted to the 2nd level and the miniature light is loosened,
then pulling on the string just once will turn off the light right then and there!
...But, is it possible to untie it...?
See, this part that is tied to make the string longer...
In order to tie the hand of someone who is struggling,
it would be impossible to do so while the
Then, this knot would have to be untied once...
But, this looks to be a complicated knot...
Hmm...
T-This is called "Tegusu Musubi!"
What's that?
The way a fishing line is tied!
A slippery line has to be tied like this or it'll get untied!
I see!That's why Hirohito's wife went
She wanted to know how to tie the string of the light fixture firmly in place...
But, why was the bedroom string different then?
The string in the bedroom was tied into a regular knot!
I see, that's why the string of the light fixture of the bedroom was shorter...
He was unable to untie the knot, so he had to cut it using scissors...
And the string was tied into a regular knot
because the killer didn't know how to tie it fishing line style!
Isn't that right Mr. Hirohito Akashi?
The trick you used goes like this.
You took the curry to
Iwao's bedroom upstairs.
While he was eating the curry, you probably covered his mouth
with the handkerchief from behind,
and tied him up with the light fixture string that you cut with the scissors!
After putting the loop of the rope around his neck, you made him bite the rope
partway along with the hankerchief, and left him suspended...
Of course you threatened him saying
that if he lets go of the rope from his mouth he would choke to death!
Finally all you had to do was tie the string of the light fixture that both of
his hands were tied with onto the string of the light fixture... and walla!
Then, you make somebody go to the bedroom to pick up his curry dish
You warn that person saying,
If the light is on he's still eating so don't go into the room."
You first ask the person to go get the plate 10 somewhat minutes
after you bring the curry to his room
he most likely is still holding the rope in has mouth...
Then you ask that person to go and get the plate again after a while
goes in and encounters the dead bedy!
Since you were with us right through in the living room
you most definitely have an alibi!
Then, are you saying that Hirohito was at the tennis court
in the rain to invite someone to witness his alibi?
He deliberately made curry for a lot of people...
O-Oh no..
Which means if we didn't come here
this wouldn't have happened...
even if you all didn't come here today,
I was going to kill him tongiht...
...It's true that today is the anniversary of my wife's death...
My wife was found lying on the ground
L-Lying on the ground?
Yes...
It was when I went out to work at a court in Tokyo on a rainy day...
My father suddenly woke my wife who was asleep with a cold
and made her go shopping...
He told her that he wanted to eat mushroom rice...
She should've refused, but she didn't
She walked with unsteady steps over to a supermarket about 3 kilometers away
and on the way back, just as expected, fell to the ground and...
But, that's no reason for you to kill him
No...
I decided to kill the day after my wife's funeral...
Umaware that I was behind him,
father was mumbling the following words towards the altar of my mother...
Dear... she finally broke down...
Next time I wish he'd get himself a healthier wife...
A toy that is more durable like Hirohito...
O... Oh, no...
Y-You mentioned that you were adopted...
Yes. until I heard him say that,
I believed him...
thinking that his being selfish was proof
that he acknowledged me as his real son...
Yes... We built a house in the forest and began living here,
my father, wife and I, because of my father's selfishness saying
that he wanted to live apart from the rest of the world...
Of course the same goes for the string of the light fixture.
He suddenly lengthened the string of the light fixture of his room
and ordered all the strings of the light fixtures
in the other rooms to be lengthened
Huh? So, the string of the light fixture in that room...
Yes...
father tied the string in his room himself...
Talk about not knowing how to tie knots...
If that was a knot... that my wife had tied...
I couldn't have cut it...
and maybe would've had second thoughts about carrying out this murder...
- \'fi-R~igh_b,R0sq5y 'd
41! -Righ_1,~,Rc~cr,v1-¢I
It sure was an uncomfortable case...
Well, after all, a person passed away so...
The combination of Sleeping Kogoro and deduction queen Sonoko,
sure can close a case in a jiffy!
Aaagh!
I forgot to video tape the deduction show,
because you started it wuthout going to sleep!
It's not my problem!
...I got double tired this time...
What's the matter, Ran...?
It seems that I received a call last night,
but the number has no caller I.D...
if you're talking about the call that came in when you were using the restroom
he took it...
It was a wrong number call...
S-Shinichi?!
Wasn't that call from Shinichi?!
Oh, that look on your face, it must've been
What, what?
What did he say?
Ghads...
I'm sorry to have worried you
No more X-size cups for bras?!
X-size cups means the difference in size
with the under bust is about
70 centimeters
Were your breasts that big?
Of course not! I'm not a cow, you know...
...I guess!'ll mail her later...
10,000,000 yen?!
Something about there is someone who is after the left of her husband
and she says if we can nail that person, she'll pay us 10,000,000!
This case would be closed in no time if we use our heads just a little bit!
M-Mom?!
H-Hey, both of you...!