Friendship, love, and mystery!
We're able to give it all we've got because we have those promises.
Both Ran's and my mother together!
Uncle's beer deduction competition.
Seeing the one and only truth,
The appearance of a child, but the intelligence of an adult.
His name is: Detective Conan!
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Scallop ravioli in a broccoli puree.
Ah, it looks delicious!
This sure is a 3-star restaurant.
Ah, Boy-san.
For today's meal, could you choose an expensive wine?
Very good.
Hey, Dad, is that okay? What about the money?
It's fine, it's fine.
I got an easy, well-paying case.
You got a request like that?
It came today while you were at school.
It was a rich married woman.
She said that it seems like there is someone in the household who wants to kill her husband.
I'll be paid ten million as long as I figure out who that person is.
-Ten million!?
No way!
They signed the contract and made the down payment of 500 thousand.
I'll just have to collect evidence about the actions of the family members.
As long as you use your head, these kinds of eases are a piece of cake.
The Similar Princesses! Part 1!
And so...
Did he find him?
The person who wants to kill the husband?
W-Well...
After that, Father went to the house by himself, but...
He said that the evidence wasn't good enough.
Right now he's exhausted and is drunk, asleep on the sofa.
Geez, if he has time to drink, why not use the time to go over there and reject that request?
But, you see...
Before he got home, Dad and the neighbors had spent 3 million.
T-Three million?!
Then I guess it can't be helped.
I'll raise the money somehow.
Well, uh...
What? Is there still more?
Yeah... When Dad tried to earn back the money...
Excuse me.
What!?
He lost 5 million from horse-racing?!
Someday, I knew this old guy would do something stupid.
To pay it all back, it's 8 million and 57 thousand.
What do I do, Mother?
Leave that man alone and come over here right now!
But...
Dad said something in his sleep...
Eri! Help me! Eri!"
Hey, Mom, are you listening?
Mom?
I got it! I'm on my way over. Just wait!
What
Sensei!
You have a meeting with Nakanishi-san starting at 3 PM.
Reschedule it for next week.
She's just coming over to complain about her husband.
Let her know I have some trouble to take care of 'cause of my husband.
I think she'll understand.
Yes, ma'am.
See you later, Kuriyama-san.
I'll leave the rest to you.
Yes, ma'am!
It really can't be helped.
H-Help me!
I can't take any more.
It's been like this for awhile.
Geez...
It's impossible...
Here, I'm here.
Wake up, d-
I'm so full.
Yoko-chan!
What's the meaning of this?
Earlier he really was saying "Eri, Eri."
Maybe it's 'cause of the TV.
Okino Yoko's four minute cooking.
See you next week.
So it's like this...
Umm. Mom, you won't get angry and go back, will you?
No, I wouldn't do something that childish.
But please don't misunderstand.
I'm doing this for your sake!
Not for this dumbass here.
Geez, I said I didn't have an appetite.
Just like a child.
Oh! The one whose life is being targeted is that Fujieda Mikio.
Huh? Mom, do you know him
Yeah. I've heard all kinds of rumors.
He seems to have done a lot of bad things.
He cleverly caught a wealthy young heiress and married into her family.
He used that money for unlawful businesses, a real terrible person.
So the client is that rich woman?
No, I thought I heard that his rich wife died half a year ago.
Maybe he remarried?
Eh, it hasn't been long since his wife's death.
Well, anyways.
It's true we aren't the type that can protect his life.
We've been expecting you.
Are you representatives of Mouri Kogorou-sama?
Yes.
I am Ueki Souhachi, the butler of this house for the last 50 years.
Let me know if need you anything.
Excuse me.
Do you have a cold?
Ah, no, it's just asthma.
Sorry for interrupting you.
Well then, this way please.
It's a beautiful garden.
It must be well maintained.
Yes.
The late madame really liked gardening.
The gardener, the madame, and I used to work on it.
It's a wonderful garden!
Don't pay any attention to him.
He isn't like he was before.
Ever since the master came here,
He has only spoken to me and the madame.
And lately, he hasn't responded to anything I say.
He probably really liked that person.
My deceased older sister.
This is Shigeru-sama, the late madame's younger brother.
And who are these two beautiful ladies, and the little boy?
They are representatives of Mouri-sama.
Well, actually, we are...
I am the consulting attorney for the Mouri Detective Agency, Kisaki.
We've come to hear more details about the situation.
We, Mouri-san's two daughters, are very interested in it.
I'm not interrupting, am
,you're welcome.
Ueki-san, a moment.
Excuse me for just a minute.
Well then, see you again.
Hey, why didn't you say you were Mrs. Mouri?
If they knew. I'd only be looked down upon.
And that guy doesn't seem too bad.
Mom!
Oh, is it you?
To say someone's targeting my life.
I can't take investigating a stupid prank seriously.
Or the representatives of that stupid detective.
Well, this is only a measure of precaution.
Well, go ahead and search out for the criminal to the best of your ability.
It's the doing of someone that doesn't like me anyway.
For something like this to cost ten million...
He's just like I thought he would be.
Exactly.
'm so sorry.
It seems he's in a bad mood today.
Oh, are you the daughter?
No way! What are you saying?
I'm Mikio-chan's wife, Fujieda Motoka, your client.
You're so young.
As long as there's love, age is not a problem.
Something like this should be a crime.
Oh, I'm so relieved.
That you're the representative of Detective Mouri.
Oh! Why is that?
Because.
If such a beautiful girl like you were the lover of Mikio-chan,
Motoka wouldn't be able to win.
Hey Ran, should I be happy?
Have some pity.
Anyway, could you show us
The evidence that shows that your husband is being targeted by someone.
I cleaned it up and put it in the study, come with me.
Printed on a word processor, "Watch your back."
And, "Take it easy." On memo paper.
And a single bullet.
These were all under your husband's pillow, three days in a row?
Exactly, scary isn't it?
It's a bit much for a practical joke, isn't it?
Then?
Did you have the police check the fingerprints?
Yes!
But Mikio-chan got mad and shouted, "Who did this?"
Then he showed to everyone in the house.
So everyone's fingerprints are on it. Nothing could be found out.
With this, the old man might not be the only ones to give up.
Yes?
Madame, a young lady wants to see you.
Huh, what kind of person?
That is, a beauty as pretty as the lawyer.
This time it must be the real mistress who came.
C-Conan-kun!
It seems you don't know her.
Would you like me to send her off?
Wait! I'll go meet her; she's at the front door, right?
Hey...
There's surveillance cameras everywhere...
After that happened, we installed them just in case.
I said that we should install more, but...
He said it was the action of someone within the house, so...
This many is enough.
Besides, he said it would be useless to waste money on a house that will be demolished soon.
Demolished?
You thieving cat!
What did you come here for? Get out!
I know!
You're Mikio-chan's lover!
You're just here for the inheritance.
But I won't give you a single cent!
Didn't I say that you're mistaken?
Oh?
Eri?
Yukiko?
M-Mom?
Still making yourself up to look young as always.
Just what I would expect from the Teitan princess I couldn't beat.
Oh, I'll just have to return those words to you.
The conservative mature queen.
Hold on, you two...
Yukiko-chan, long time no see.
Yeah, how are you?
It's been ten years.
The last time we met was before you and Kogorou-kun split up.
Don't be a fool, that was only to get some air, we still see each other.
But the last time I was called a princess, i
Was back during the high school festival.
Doesn't that bring back memories
During the time of the Miss Teitan Princess and Queen's competition.
Miss Teitan, is there such thing?
Oh yeah, Sonoko told me once...
20 years ago.
There was a legendary Miss Teitan High School beauty competition that shook the school.
In the competition, there was a lovely and gifted actress.
Her first debut attracted media from around the world, the Princess of Teitan High School.
The one with a gifted mind and who got a perfect on the Todai entrance exams.
At the age of 16, she was recommended to study abroad at Harvard.
Gifted with both beauty and intelligence, the Teitan High School Queen.
But to think that those two were you two...
Hey, out of those two, who won?
Oh, yeah! The two were famous.
There was pressure from fans throughout Japan.
They canceled it before there was a panic.
I see, so no one became Miss Teitan High School.
E-Excuse me...
Who is this person
It seems she's an acquaintance of yours, but...
If you are Mikio-chan's lover then...
As his wife, that's a problem for me.
Is that true?
No way, I was asked to come here by Yuusaku.
Oh, by any chance are you Yukiko-san?
Yes.
I had asked Yuusaku-kun to uncover the secret,
My name is Fujieda Shigeru.
That guy said he couldn't lend a hand and asked if his wife could come in his place.
Who would have thought it she'd be such a young beauty?
Oh my.
Don't you know?
She's the former star of the silver screen, Fujimine Yukiko.
Oh. I'm so sorry. 1 wasn't aware.
I had met Yuusaku-kun at a mystery writer's party.
It was by coincidence that we met the other day in LA,
And we discussed this case, p
Then, you're also a mystery writer?
Yeah, but unlike him, I've yet to write a best seller.
So, ever since my eldest sister passed away, I've been a house guest here.
I'm different from Niizuma Motoka-chan who can pay ten million to Detective Mouri to protect her husband.
In my case, can you please help without payment?
-Ten million
Kogoro-kun can earn that much?
It would be better if he could earn it.
Eh, no way!
He already spent 8 million?
That's why I came as his representative.
So, where is he?
Lying on the couch at the office, drunk and asleep.
Well, even if he wakes up he can't do a single thing.
What the...?
Hey, hey...
Wait a...
Hey!
Ran, are you there
I see...
It's true, it doesn't seem like a regular practical joke.
But, the only evidence is these 3 items.
It'll be a miracle to figure out who the criminal is with this.
But...
If this kid is here, that miracle may just happen.
That's right, I heard you were with Conan-kun during a case earlier.
Yeah! His reasoning is spot on.
That's how incredible my--
My?
My...
My grandpa's sister's daughter's cousin's uncle's grandson.
Eh, is that so?
Anyway, we should see Mikio-san first.
And ask if he has a clue as to who's after his life.
It seems that we haven't had that conversation.
That's impossible.
At the moment, the master is in the audio room listening to classical music and reading.
It'll be a one hour wait.
If anyone interrupts him while he's reading, Mikio-chan will get super mad.
Really?
He's so relaxed even when someone's after his life.
But... Is it safe to leave him alone?
Well, if you want, we can go watch what's going on inside.
There's a surveillance camera installed in the room.
Even though the installations only provide minimal coverage, the equipment is pretty good.
Even so, there aren't hardly enough.
It sure is hard to cover such a big house.
So, this is the audio room and this is the monitor room.
No matter what happens, it'll be hard to get to the room.
Who usually checks the monitors?
The maids and I.
Look! There's someone in the garden!
Look here. A shadowy man wearing a knit hat.
Ah! That's the gardener, Doi.
But what's he doing this late at night?
He's probably maintaining the flowers,
Because tomorrow is the birthday of my late sister.
Well, I have to go finish my manuscript no matter what.
Ueki-san, I'll leave the rest to you.
Understood.
I really wanted to be surrounded by the young ladies' beauty but,
What a pity!
It really is a pity.
What is?
Weren't both of you competitors in the Miss Teitan competition?
It was canceled before the results came out.
Oh?
The results came out.
We both tied with 10,000 votes a piece.
But wasn't it strange?
When the match began, there were 20,001 ballots.
Only one wasn't turned in.
It's too late to look for that one vote now.
That's why they never held the awards ceremony.
How convenient.
But if that one vote was found Yukiko-chan would've won.
No way, I think Eri-chan would've won.
Hey, did those ballots have a gold seal?
Y-Yes.
It's the Teitan High School sea
Well then, Dad had one in his uniform pocket.
It dropped out once when I was sorting his old clothes.
I see. That piece of paper was the Miss Teitan ballot.
Whose!? Whose name was written on it?!
Eri, or me? Which was it?
But it seemed like dad had sent it to the laundromat.
So the paper was all torn up.
Is that the truth? Come out with the truth!
It's all right, Ran-chan. You don't have to worry about your mother's feelings.
No, it's the truth.
Geez, why don't you just go ask him?
Hi-His hands...
The master has his hands raised
Hey, what's the meaning of this?
Did someone go into the room with a gun--
That can't be.
Earlier when I took coffee to him and came back,
I made sure the door was locked with the key.
No way!
He was shot.
He was shot
Where is the key to that room?
I-It's in my room.
Go get it right now!
Then, I'll go call the police...
And an ambulance as we
Please hurry with the phone calls.
D-Did something happen?
Hey, Mikio-san!
Are you alright? Mikio-san?!
This is bad.
But did Mikio-san really collapse?
After he raised his hands.
A gun! A gun shot!
Damn!
Ran, please!
Yeah!
"Please?"
I brought the key.
M-Master!
Master!
This is the worst outcome.
Yeah.
We were all fooled.
So you mean...
Even though there was a gun supposedly aimed at him.
Why would he do that?
But, what a shame. One can't fool the detective's eyes!
Hey-!
Next Conan!
The Similar Princesses! Part 2!
Next Conan's hint!
Bookmark.