Friendship, love, and mystery!
We are able to give it all we've got because we have those promises.
The Princess and Queen are two mothers.
All the keys are on Uncle!
Seeing the one and only truth,
The appearance of a child, but the intelligence of an adult.
That name is: Detective Conan!
To find the person who's targeting Fujieda Mikio-san, Uncle will be paid ten million.
He said it would be a simple case, but...
Without solving the case he spent some of the money on a celebration.
Now he's in debt by 8 million. After being seriously shocked, he's sleeping at home...
Instead of Uncle, Ran's mom went to meet the client.
There, she encountered my mom.
And then that night...
Fujieda Mikio-san was murdered in a locked room.
Eh? Isn't this Eri-san?
AndYukiko-san, too!
What are the two of you doing here?
Ah, actually...
I came here as a representative for the job that my husband accepted.
The client wanted my husband to find out who wanted to kill the master of this house, Fujieda Mikio-san.
But why did he say that the one after his life is in this house?
Because under the pillow in Mikio-san's room...
"Watch your back."
And, "Take it easy." Both on memo paper.
And one bullet was there.
The only one who could do that is someone within the household.
Th-That's true.
The time of the crime was...
That's right! I think it was about 8 PM.
Yes.
At the time, everyone was watching what was happening in the surveillance room.
I see.
And then, suddenly, Mikio-san stood up with his hands raised.
He was hit and collapsed.
We rushed there, but...
We heard two gunshots coming from the room.
We broke down the door and when we went in...
That was the situation.
Inspector Megure!
We found the gun.
Oh, is that so?
The gun is a Compact Colt 45.
Three cartridge cases were dropped.
They match the three bullet wounds on the corpse.
It seems the criminal shot the victim from outside the window, and ran away.
So in other words, it could have been a stranger.
But, what's this?
A towel with a burn trace.
That's probably...
Probably used to avoid getting the gunpowder on him.
It could also be used for silencing the sound of the shot.
Hey!
Chiba-kun, go and check the gun's firing trajectory for now!
Ah, yes!
Takagi-kun, check around to see if anyone saw a suspicious character around here.
Yes ma'am.
W-Wait a moment!
Ah, yes, yes!
I would like you to check and see if the bullet hidden under the pillow is the same with the one that was used to shoot the victim.
Alright. Inspector, bring the inspection team into the living room with me.
After checking everyone for gunpowder traces, take their statements.
Hey! Eri-san!
Come on, Eri's desperate.
But...
You see, there's a 10 million yen bet on this.
Hey! To-Toilet!
It's leaking out!
TOILET!
So one by one, please tell the inspector.
During the 3 minutes from when Mikio was shot in the audio room until we found his corpse,
Where were you and what were you doing.
I went to my room to get the key.
Then I went to the audio room.
I went to my own room to call the police and an ambulance,
After that I stayed locked up in my room.
Oh!? Even though you knew that your husband was shot?
But the person with the gun could've still been wandering around the house!
That could be true.
And I saw Mikio-san get shot along with the butler and the others.
If I'm being suspected shouldn't I have left the room before he was shot just like Shigeru-san did?
Is it so?
Yes. I wanted to go back to my room to write my manuscript.
But after that...
I went to the audio room with Eri-san and the others.
Because we heard a gunshot twice in front of the room.
I couldn't have done that.
So, when you went into the room...
Did you hear any suspicious sounds?
No.
The volume of the classical music was very high.
Ah, Inspector-san, is it okay for me to sit down?
Sure. I don't mind.
The butler and the maids, please take a seat.
Thanks anyway. I feel more comfortable standing up.
Inspector Megure, I captured this suspicious man in the garden.
What?
Hey, come here!
Oh! This man is gardener of this house, Doi-san.
Gardener?
He's been like this since the beginning.
No matter what you ask him, he stays silent.
Doi-san was in the garden when Mikio-san was shot in the audio room at 8 PM.
He was on the surveillance camera the whole time.
When the case happened, he was the only one who wasn't here.
It's better to see than hear 100 times.
Would you like to watch it?
The surveillance video.
I see.
He was in the yard when the shots were fired.
Oh, but after that you don't see him.
But it recorded the light.
Because the light kept moving,
So he seems to be there.
But if only every room had a surveillance camera,
Who, where and what they're doing would all be clear after watching.
But according to the video, we know it wasn't the doing of a stranger,
So there's a high possibility that it's an inside job.
Because there are so many surveillance cameras,
But not a single one recorded someone suspicious...
So if you think about it, this person must be familiar with the layout of the cameras.
T-That could be.
The only suspects left are the 4 maids.
But they were with all of us since the beginning.
Let's see if they would know of any motives.
Hey! Conan-kun, you're doing good today.
You usually disappear on me.
It's because those two have said most of what I wanted to, so there's nothing for me to do.
But this case is very weird.
The butler and Motoka-san,
Were with us watching the monitors when the first gunshot was fired.
But when the second and third shots occurred, they have no alibis.
All you could see after the first shot was the light, and not Doi-san.
Shigeru-san, who doesn't have an alibi when the first shot occurred,
Was with us when the second one occurred.
That means...
If either the surveillance camera's video...
Or the second and third gunshots were the trick,
All of their alibis should crumble.
There also two doubtful points.
Why was there a pause for three minutes between the first and the second gunshot?
In the book that he was reading before his death, there's a cord used as the bookmark.
Even though there was a gun supposedly aimed at him.
Why would he do that?
Eh? The one who hates the master the most?
Among those four people?
Yes.
That would be the butler, Ueki-san.
Since master sent him to the attic which was full of dust, it has caused his asthma to act up.
But if I was in Shigeru-sama's position, I would be mad too.
Ever since the master got the inheritance...
This is the home Shigeru-san has lived in ever since he was young.
Yet he still charges him rent!
It's seems like Motoka-sama doesn't hate the master, but...
We all know the marriage was 'cause of the house property.
Maybe if the master was to die,
The one who would be the happiest would be Motoka-sama.
Yes, yes.
That gardener, Doi-san, is always glaring at the young mistress.
Of course
She's been talking to the master about turning the garden into a swimming pool.
What're you doing there?
So-Sorry.
That's the garden which the late madame loved the most before her death.
Ah! But...
That's enough, come on back.
Yeah.
Can it be that Doi-san's hometown is in Kouchi?
I lived in Takajou city.
Takajou city, eh?! What a coincidence!
'm from Kami city!
Ah, Kami city?
When I was a child I always went swimming in the Kagami river!
Really! The Kagami is really a very clear river.
Even Sakamoto Ryouma went swimming there.
To-Tosa accent!
Yukiko, you were born in Kouchi?
No! But when she was an actress...
She played a role that spoke with a Tosa accent. She learned it at that time.
When it comes to stuff like that she's a genius.
At least that's what Shinichi-niichan said.
So, did that yield anything?
Yeah. He said some very interesting things!
He heard the gunshot several seconds after the sound of the glass breaking.
What do you mean?
Usually the gunshot and the glass smashing should happen at the same time, right?
Who knows! Maybe he broke the glass with the gun, then shot.
But that bothers me.
Then the gunshot should sound just after the sound of breaking glass, right?
But he doesn't remember how many gunshots he heard.
He thought some bad kids nearby were setting off fireworks as a prank.
So he didn't mind it much.
Could it be that Yuusaku's hint has something to do with this?
What? Did you contact your husband?
Yeah, I called him just now.
I explained the case to him,
Yuusaku told me as he was laughing
"Signpost for the wrong road."
He wanted me to pass it on like that.
Pass it on to whom?
Huh, urn... Of course to Eri-chan!
Ah, really?
I should be grateful, right?
No!
I also think so.
Hey, Inspector.
Isn't the investigation done?
We couldn't have committed this crime.
Inspector!
We've spoken to the neighbors nearby.
Nobody has seen a suspicious character.
I see.
And we haven't confirmed the gun trajectory yet.
But the bullets which were used to kill the victim...
And that one which was used to threaten him are from the same gun.
But there's one thing that's very strange.
One of the three bullets which were taken out of the corpse...
For some reason, the lines are more shallow.
What do you mean?
So that's what it is.
It's not "eh."
Your expression's tells me that you've figured it out.
It doesn't matter, either way, I figured it out.
So tell me, Shin-chan!
You won't be appearing on stage as the Night Baroness again, will you?
It'll be alright. It'll be alright.
I'll settle it cool tonight.
Hey! It's already 11 PM!
Can we continue tomorrow?
Ah, no, we're still investigating.
Investigating what?
Hasn't it been over for a while now?
Don't fool me!
That's right.
We're all being fooled by the criminal.
It seemed that Mikio-san...
Was being threatened with a gun from outside the window, then he was shot.
But, what a sham
One can't fool the detective's eyes!
This Night Baroness's private eye.
Hey hey hey, where did you get so many lights?
Then could it be, Yukiko...
You know who the criminal is?
Yeah. It's all clear now.
So what trick did the criminal use?
Could it be the surveillance cameras?
We were being tricked long before that.
The criminal misled us with those two memos and that one bullet.
So we certainly thought he would use a gun, a signpost that led us down the wrong road.
But, wasn't Mikio-san really shot?
Didn't you notice it, Inspector Megure?
In the book that Mikio-san was reading before his death...
There's still the cord which he used as a bookmark!
N-Now that you mention it.
Usually you put the cord in at the page where you stop reading.
Someone who's being threatened with a gun wouldn't do that.
T-That's right.
If you wanted a break from reading a book, what would you do?
Well... Turn my head, or move my shoulders...
Then I'd stretch!
Yes. Mikio-san just stood up and stretched.
That's foolish.
Then Mikio-chan collapsed! Are you saying he collapsed because of stretching?
Not because of stretching, but there was a problem when he stood up.
It's happened to you before, when you suddenly stand up,
You begin to feel like you're going to lose consciousness.
But how could he calculate the timing so precisely?!
There's a drug that would make it easy.
The medical name is... Isopu...
Isopuro... Isopu...
Isoproterenol.
The drug is for patients who faints or gets dizzy often.
It makes it easier for them to faint to find out why it happens.
I see, he used this medicine to induce fainting.
And planned for when he raised his hands and fell down.
Am I right?
Yes, at that time he wasn't shot yet.
But the criminal didn't think that was enough.
He completely misled us to a wrong road with those words.
"Master has his hands raised!
So you mean...
We were all fooled.
Yeah. Isn't that right, the butler, Ueki Shouhachi-san?
If it's Ueki-san then he could've put the poison in his coffee before he drank it.
And he also knows that he usually stretches after reading.
This medicine is usually used for people who have asthma.
So he did this to create an alibi for himself.
He pretended to go get the key to the audio room.
He went around to the room from the outside...
And shot at the dizzy Mikio-san three times and killed him.
But you only hear d the sound of gunshot in front of the room twice, right?
Ah, just now Yukiko-san asked Doi-san,
He said he heard the sound of the gunshot several seconds after the glass was smashed.
Furthermore the classical music was playing very loudly.
You know what happened now, don't you?
Ri-Right!
It's a silencer!
He shot the first time with a silencer.
So you only heard the sound of the glass breaking.
And why the lines on the bullet were shallow was 'cause of the silencer.
So the reason we didn't have a gunpowder reaction was...
Because of the towel.
Anyway, let's find the silencer.
That won't be necessary.
Because the butler still has it hidden on him.
Maybe it's in his socks.
What?
Excuse me. Inspector!
It's here! The silencer!
He didn't want to take a seat, did he? So I found that.
If he doesn't sit down, his socks won't be exposed. He did this to cover something in his sock.
Wa-Wait a moment! Doesn't this burn hurt?
I can handle something of this level.
As long as I could protect the late madame's garden.
Garden?
Yes! This house's garden.
The young madame had treasured and maintained the garden since she was very young.
I feel that the young madame is still living somewhere in this garden.
To leave it to that master who has nothing to do with it...
I couldn't forgive
What?! So you're just the criminal?
I thought my enemy was this brother, Shigeru-san!
In this case, I'll get even less of the heritage.
After all the hard work I went through, hiring a detective.
It's a big failure.
Eh? About the distribution of the heritage...
If Mikio-san has no parents or sibling
His wife will inherit all of it.
His brother-in-lav/ shouldn't have any.
Really?
Oh, Motoka made a mistake.
But that's if Mikio-san didn't make a will.
Huh?!
Anyway, please pay 10 million yen for seeking out the criminal.
Ah? Why? Wasn't Mikio-chan murdered?
Look! I didn't promise you that I'd protect his life in the contract, did I?
Your signature and seal are both here!
Oh, okay! As long as I get Mikio-chan's heritage...
I pay you 10 million yen.
By the way, before the inheritance is confirmed...
The property under Mikio-san's name will be frozen.
'You can only pay me with your own assets.
Ah? It can't be!
If you refuse, we'll sue you and confiscate your property.
I'm counting on you!
Oh my! Oh my!
After that...
Mikio-san's will was read.
To those who can't protect my life...
I won't give a single yen!
I would rather contribute it to our nation.
That's how the passage was written.
Then the next day...
Here you go, dear. This is 1 million, 943 thousand yen after deducting your debt.
You should thank me!
Eh? Do you smell some strange scent?
Do you have a pet?
That's cause this morning, a client was here with her dog.
Really Yukiko-chan, it's been a long time!
Ah, yes. I have something to ask you, Kogorou-kun!
Ah, Eri-chan, ask him!
No! Yukiko-chan said she wanted to ask you.
They want to know something about the Miss Teitan High School competition.
Uncle, which one did you vote for?
Ah, that one from 20 years ago?
Well, it's probably Eri-chan.
These two were lovey-dovey at the time.
It must be Yukiko-chan!
She was unbelievably cute at the time.
If I remember, I voted for Eri.
Dear!
At that time I didn't understand it at all.
I thought that 'miss' meant mistake!
So I wrote that clumsy woman's name on it.
What?
So after you know the meaning of miss, who will you vote for?
Of course I'll vote for my very pretty, lovely Yukiko!
Ah! No! Although Eri likes reading books, she's still so popular!
Ah, right, right, the payment for helping you this time.
Yukiko and I will take 10 percent, or 1 million.
So I'll pay the debt for the bar, the snacks, and the Poirot coffee shop downstairs.
My allowance, and the cost of living for next month.
And the laundry charge for the pants.
Here, you're change.
Hey, hey!
Only 4,382 yen was left?
So Yukiko, let's go eat some delicious stuff!
Yeah, let's go, let's go.
Hey!
So which one did win the Miss Teitan contest?
Exactly.
That car had been following our car for a long time.
That's right.
That's what I thought too. So I left just before the light turned red.
I wonder who it was.
Next Conan!
Secret of the Touto Film Developer Place. Part 1!
Together with Hanga-san.
Yeah, yeah.
Messy room.
This is bad Conan! Summer vacation is almost over.
Second semester has already started.