Friendship! Romance! Mystery!
We try our best because we've made those promises!
The Yaiba movie we've been waiting and waiting for.
A surprising incident occurs before the showing!
Perceiving the one and only truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
SECRET OF THE TOHTO FILM DEVELOPMENT STUDIO
(PART ONE)
2,958 CCs...
220 Horsepower.
6 cylinders, 24 valves...
And a DOHC engine...
Hey, hey...
Weren't there any other rental cars available?
What's wrong?
This type of car suits me better anyway.
Even so, aren't you speeding a bit too much?
Don't worry.
I'll be sure to watch out for speed traps.
Idiot!
I'm telling you to watch your speedometer, not for the police!
Um...
Can I ask you something?
Where are we going now?
-Come on and tell us already.
OK? Please?
It's a place where everyone will be extremely happy!
She's being mean...
Conan-kun's mom!
I already told you she wasn't my mother, but some old woman I'm related to!
I mean, young lady...
Hello?
How could she pass as a young lady...
Karata-san!
Because of a little unexpected hiccup in the timing, Number-0 might take some more time?
In any case, we're heading there now.
Thanks for the help!
I wonder what that could be?
Number-0.
Could it be the number of a robot or something?
Hey, can you tell us?
Se-cr-et.
Actually, we're going to see a preview screening of Kamen Yaiba: The Movie 2, aren't we?
Really!?
Awesome!
I wanna see, I wanna see!
K... Kamen Yaiba?
But...
How did you know?
That we're going to a Yaiba preview screening...
The timing you mentioned concerns the color correction for a movie...
And the "Number-0" you mentioned refers to a recently completed film.
Both are industry terms that only people in the film or drama production profession would use.
And, if it were to be a movie that everyone would enjoy, then...
It would have to be Kamen Yaiba: The Movie 2.
The reason we get to watch the Number-0 is because...
The premiere date is approaching soon, and they want to finalize the Number-0 version in a preview screening.
As expected!
Hey, the traffic light turned green a while ago!
No way!
Oh no, it's changing to yellow!
I'm sorry...
I lost focus.
Hey!
Would you give it a rest?
There are kids in here!
OK, OK.
Whoa...
This feels like a roller coaster...
Hey!
She is so much fun...
Conan-kun's mom!
Didn't I say...
She wasn't?
So this is the Tohto film development studio?
There's a lot of history here.
It's come all this way coupled with the development of Japanese film.
Well, let's go in.
Everyone, be polite inside, all right?
Yes!
Oh, Yukiko-chan!
You look as beautiful as ever.
Why, of course!
You haven't changed a bit either, Karata-san.
Oh, that's right.
This is the one who is letting you all preview the new Yaiba movie, Karata-san.
Nice to meet you!
His job is that of a timing man (color timing).
He always made the colors of the movies I was in look amazing!
Karata Takayoshi (46)
Timing Man
That means...
You were an actress?
That's right!
I was one of your mother's or father's idols.
Really?
I see now.
Your deduction skills came from your father.
And your confidence for showing off and acting while using the voice changing bow-tie...
As well as the reckless behavior you exhibit when you hear the word "cut"...
That all must be inherited from your mother.
Well, excuse me.
When is the Number-0 preview?
Actually, it looks like it's gonna take even more time...
I think 1'1 probably be able to get it done by 7:00 tonight somehow...
I'm sorry, but could you tour the studio or something and wait for me until then?
Hojima-kun and Negami-san.
Sorry, but could you guys show Yukiko-chan and these children around the studio?
Hojima Akira (28)
Printing
Negami Yoshihiko (42)
Film Man
Sure.
No problem.
This is the screening room where you all will see the Kamen Yaiba movie later.
It's just like a movie theater!
I can't wait to watch it.
This is the darkroom.
It's used to check that none of the film has been damaged before it's placed into the projector.
And this is the developing machine for the 35mm positive film.
Well?
Aren't all these machines interesting?
It's almost like a research laboratory.
What's this sound?
This signal indicates the darkroom is being entered, so we know not to open the two doors unnecessarily.
This is because while the film is being developed, even a little bit of light getting in will ruin it.
After the film has been checked...
Negami-san here is responsible for developing the negatives with the negative developing machine.
And, as the printer, it's my job to print them all out into positives.
And after we edit the film and add in the sound, the one that adjusts the colors...
That's the job of our timing man, Karata-san.
Why are you the only one who doesn't have "man" in his title?
Now that you mention it, we don't say "printing man".
Yeah, guess not.
Could it be be that you're the weak one?
Weak?
It's not like we're transforming heroes.
Oh, it's already 6:40.
I guess it's time we went over to the screening room.
You're right.
It seems it's still going to be some time before the screening.
But Karata-san said it would be ready by 7:00...
Karata-san just said it will now take until at least 11:00 PM at the earliest.
Furumura Norihiro (39)
It's going to be that late?
Well, they said I couldn't do anything else and had me go, so not my fault.
You look sleepy.
Mah-jong again?
Maybe.
But, this is bad...
What's wrong?
If it's at 11:00, I won't be able to make my flight...
And I can't just leave the kids here that late, either...
Then, how about the kids come over to my place first?
My apartment is nearby.
They can sleep there until it's time for the screening, and I can take them home in my car afterwards.
Well...
If you would?
But, are you really going to put these kids in your disgustingly dirty room?
That's mean, it's just a little messy.
It's not dirty!
Well, if it's all right with the kids?
Hey, let's stay, Conan-kun!
Tomorrow is Sunday, anyway!
That's right!
And we can go back to school and brag to the others!
Well, Conan?
Well...
Call home and tell them you'll be coming home late.
Yes!
Well then, with that taken care of, why don't we hurry and finish up so we can get a quick nap in ourselves?
Sounds good.
We can do it in preparation for our celebratory "tetsuman".
What's "tetsuman"?
Is he the partner of Film Man?
It's our all-night mah-jong.
Shin-chan...
What is it?
Jeez, "what is it"?
You seem popular with the girls.
You mean Ayumi-chan?
There's one more...
Haibara-san.
She's stared at your face ten times today.
She's probably just observing the growth process of her drug's test subject.
Silly, the only reason girls stare at boys,
aside from when they have something on their faces,
s because they like them.
Haibara?
No way...
By the way, you noticed it as well, didn't you?
That strange car on the way here.
Oh, so Shin-chan noticed it, too.
Of course.
We were stopped at the light until it turned yellow...
But the car behind us didn't even honk their horn.
It was likely so as to not garner our attention.
In other words...
They were tailing us.
In fact, that car had been following us for quite some time before that.
That's right.
That's what I thought too, so that's why I waited until just before the light was going to turn red to go.
Who could it be?
That's true...
If that car's target was me, or...
Even Kaibara...
The chance that it was them who were following us is high.
The ones who shrank my body...
Those men in black!
That's true...
If that car's target was me, or...
Even Kaibara...
The chance that it was them who were following us is high.
The ones who shrank my body...
Those men in black!
No...
There's another possibility.
The people in that car may have been...
Some of my die-hard fans!
They must have been trying to follow me home to get an autograph!
Oh, how adorable!
If only it were like that...
At any rate...
Protect them with all you've got.
You're the only one I can depend on.
Yeah...
I know that.
Well, everyone, seeya!
Enjoy the movie and get home safe!
Yes!
Thank you very much!
Oh, that's right...
Come here for a sec.
What is it?
The girl who keeps staring at you...
Make sure to stay with her until the end.
I know.
So annoying...
You're going to be late for your plane.
Right, right!
Bye, Shin-chan!
Bye, everyone!
I'll see you later!
This is...
This is even messier than I imagined.
You really should clean up properly.
Then...
Why don't we clean up before sleeping?
No, no! Don't touch anything!
Why?
Because then I won't know where anything is.
Is that so...
Is that really true?
It's the same everywhere.
Well, we're going to sleep on the sofas, so you kids can sleep on my bed.
If you line up on the bed sideways...
It can fit five kids, can't it?
It's a big mess in here, too.
Really...
It's just like this because I've been so busy lately.
Good work today!
Let's do our best during tonight's "tetsuman"
What's he doing?
I'll provide the results later!
It seems like he's really gotten into recording video diaries lately.
Anyway, I still have some work to finish, so I'm going to head back.
What should I do?
I'm too excited to sleep!
Hey, Mitsuhiko...
No, not yet...
If I remember correctly, it was The Counter Attack of Baron Potato, right?
No...
The subtitle from the preview was...
It was...
The subtitle was...
Oh, come on!
It's The Requiem of the Potato Queen!
Can't you at least remember that much?!
They fell asleep...
It can't be helped.
They're kids...
Unlike us.
Say, Haibara...
There's...
There's something I want to ask you.
Is there something on my face?
What was with that sound?
Hey, Furumura-san!
Did something happen, Furumura-san?
Furumura-san...
Conan...
What's going on out here?
Is it time?
Furumura-san!
In that pitch darkness...
How did they do it?
To navigate through such a messy room in pitch darkness without making a sound so quickly...
It seems impossible.
The murderer didn't make any sound at all.
A silent crime...
I see...
That's why they did that in such a panic.
That person is the culprit!
SECRET OF THE TOHTO FILM DEVELOPMENT STUDIO
(PART TWO)
Fluorescent Paint
There are lots of different people on a movie's staff!
Suwa-san, Yoshioka-san, Haibara...
Who?