Friendship! Romance! Mystery!
We try our best because we've made those promises!
A silent murder in the pitch darkness.
Clean deductions at a messy crime scene.
Perceiving the one and only truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
In order to attend a preview screening of Kamen Yaiba: The Movie 2...
We came to the Tohto film development studio with my mother.
However, the screening time was pushed back, meaning we had to come back later that night.
After my mom left early to return to America...
We went to stay at Hojima Akira-san's house as we waited.
SECRET OF THE TOHTO FILM DEVELOPMENT STUDIO
(PART TWO)
The murder victim has been identified as Furumura Norihiro-san, age thirty-nine.
It seems e was employed at the Tohto film development studio just opposite this apartment building.
He was stabbed through the heart with a kitchen knife, huh?
I assume they covered him with a blanket so as to prevent the blood from splattering.
Ah, no...
He had actually come over here to nap for a while.
Hojima Akira (28)
We had originally planned to play some all-night mah-jong to celebrate completing the film.
Film?
The test screening for it was pushed back to 11:00 PM, so we all decided to rest for a bit.
Those kids, too.
I see.
And which room were you guys sleeping in?
That room there.
The five of us were sleeping on the bed sideways.
Then, all of a sudden, we heard this "waaaaa" sound!
And this is what awaited us after opening the door.
I see...
But, it's strange.
What is?
The murderer didn't make any sound.
None at all.
I mean, after all, you guys were asleep...
I mean after they stabbed Furumura-san.
Normally, while the culprit was making their getaway, there should have been some noise.
The culprit must have come and gone very stealthily, then.
Well, that's true...
To navigate through such a messy room without making a sound so quickly...
It seems impossible.
If that's the case, the culprit must have been the one sleeping on the sofa next to the victim...
It had to be Hojima-san.
No way!
The door did show no signs of a forced entry...
Just a minute here!
I'm not the only one that has a key to this apartment.
Our work colleagues that we often play mah-jong with, Karata-san and Negami-san, do too.
F-Furumura is?
Who would do that!
As for that, we hope to clear it up after speaking with the two of you.
At 10:55 PM, the time of the crime, where were you and what were you doing?
Karata Takayoshi (46)
Timing Man
I had already finished my timing work by then.
So I left the remaining work to the other employees and went to sleep in the resting room.
T-Timing?
It refers to correcting the colors on the film.
Is there anyone who can verify that?
Well, there were a few others in the rest area at that time, but they were all asleep.
And? How about you?
Negami Yoshihiko (42)
Film Man
I was alone in the darkroom checking the film at that time.
That means neither of you have an alibi then?
So? Why do you have spare keys?
We have them so we can play mah-jong immediately after work.
It's to allow whoever finishes their work first to come here and set up beforehand.
But, it may not just be we two who also have keys to this apartment.
He has other mah-jong friends as well.
But the only ones I've ever given keys to were you two and Furumura-san here.
Well, if they came here frequently, they would know where things were placed.
I guess that means they could get in and out quietly, even in the dark.
But...
Conan-kun?
Just look at how it's really pitch dark in this room.
Hey, stop that! You shouldn't be disturbing the police like that.
Still, Conan-kun definitely does have a point.
That's right.
If it was that dark, no matter how familiar you were, you'd definitely collide with something.
The third button on the victim's shirt has been torn off.
It seems there must have been a struggle with his assailant before he was stabbed.
But his shirt sure is dirty...
Even the collar is turning black.
Furumura-san didn't like bathing, so he only took a bath once a week at most.
Now that you mention it, he was wearing that same shirt when we four were playing together, three days ago.
I guess he hadn't changed since then.
In any case, I couldn't have done it!
It's impossible for me to struggle with him in pitch darkness, rip off a button, and then stab him!
But, if we assume you were the only one awake then...
You could have used a pocket flashlight or something to find and approach him, even in the dark.
And on top of that, the kids said they didn't hear the criminal flee.
Or, could it be that you heard the culprit?
No... I was woken up by Mr Furumura's scream and didn't hear anything else.
W-What?
Inspector, there's a video camera on the floor.
Why is there a video camera here?
Oh, Furumura kept a video diary and updated it every day.
Has it been on the whole time?
Alright, get this hooked up to the TV right away and play it.
It may have recorded some evidence of the crime.
Good work today!
Let's do our best during tonight's "tetsuman"!
I'll provide the results later!
The camera was turned off then.
It's been switched back on!
But it's pitch black...
I-Inspector!
Y-Yeah...
Hey, Furumura-san!
Is everything all right?
Furumura-san!
That's my voice!
That "gara" sound was me opening the bedroom door.
Right then, this little boy turned on the lights.
But...
Why was the video camera switched on then?
It may have fallen to the floor during his struggle with the culprit and switched on then.
Our main problem remains the noise.
The victim's scream and Conan-kun opening the door...
And even Ayumi-kun crying out, but, Hojima-san...
There's nothing except your voice.
Which means, just as we expected...
Stop joking around!
If I was going to do something like that, I wouldn't have invited kids to stay with me!
Not to mention, there's no reason why I would want to kill Furumura-san!
Don't you have one?
Didn't you resent him for ruining that film you were fond of?
Oh, The Tale of the Mother and the Obedient Son?
That's true for you, too, Negami-san!
And you, Karata-san—you were angry as well!
Well, I guess you're right...
What's all of this about?
What's this about ruining a movie?
Yeah...
While checking the film, Furumura-san didn't notice damage to the roll and ended up loading it anyway...
Which caused it to tear completely.
This turned out to be a huge loss for us.
The refilming of the lost scene had to be financed by us personally.
Well, film checking is done in the darkroom by touch, which means you have to be very careful.
Someone who plays mah-jong from night to morning like he did would obviously have trouble with it.
But the one who checks the film...
Negami-san, isn't that you?
Yeah, but Furumura was also a film man in the past.
After that incident, he was switched over to sales.
But why would that make the three of them hate him?
Could that have led to cuts into their bonuses?
The Tale of the Mother and the Obedient Son series was one of our proudest achievements.
Our anger should come as no surprise, considering he completely ruined the final installment.
It's always seemed that Furumura-san was the only one who didn't take pride in it.
But, he didn't hate the series enough to ruin it.
Not to mention that he's one of our mah-jong companions.
Actually, we had almost forgotten the entire thing.
A silent crime...
Getting from the entrance to this door wouldn't be difficult, considering there are no obstacles.
The problem is this living room.
To flee this room so quickly in pitch darkness without making noise—it's impossible.
Which would mean the criminal must be the one who was in the room the entire time: Hojima-san?
And the video camera, too!
I see—No wonder he did that in such a panic.
If this proves true, it explains why he wasn't heard on the video tape...
It seems the culprit is that person...
The one who committed this crime in the dark is that person...
But I don't have enough evidence...
What should I do?
What's wrong, Ai-chan?
You look scared.
Nothing.
It's nothing at all.
She said it's nothing.
Really?
Could it be...
At any rate, the information we have now...
Furumura-san was stabbed while sleeping on the sofa at 11:00 PM by an unknown person.
If the culprit had tried to flee quickly after stabbing him...
They would have surely hit something and made some sort of noise.
Despite this, the children sleeping in the next room heard nothing.
In addition, the tape from the video camera that was likely switched on after hitting the floor during the struggle...
Failed to record any such noise as well.
In other words, the culprit must be the one sleeping on the sofa next to Furumura-san: Hojima-san.
It could be no one else.
Hey, wait...
That's correct.
Agasa-san!
P-Professor!
I received a call from Conan-kun requesting I pick up the children.
And I heard about this case in the process.
No matter how you consider it, there's only one possible solution.
First: Hojima-san must have been the perpetrator.
This is because most people are unable to traverse freely in the dark without hitting things and making noise.
But, of course, if it were a ninja or ghost, this would be a different story!
Agasa-san, that is your line of reasoning as well?
Still, there's something that bothers me.
You know, the third button on Furumura-san's shirt that was torn off in the struggle.
You haven't found it yet, right?
I guess we haven't...
This missing button bothers me.
Buttons don't just grow wings and fly away.
It's possible that it dropped into this messy room somewhere...
Or that the culprit is holding it.
This means that when you take Hojima-san to the station, you need to do a full-body check.
That's right.
Well then, Hojima-san, please come with us.
I'll come.
But I'm really not the culprit...
Then, well also need you two, Negami-san and Karata-san, to come along as well.
Was that how you wanted?
Yeah. You were perfect.
Well, let's go along to the police station and listen in.
You guys slept enough to stay up, right?
Hey, Haibara! Let's go.
But I really wanted to see the new Yaiba...
Me too...
We can all go watch it when it hits theaters, can't we?
W-What?
So, it really was you...
Negami-san.
Why?
It was the sound.
The sound.
The sound?
But, those kids didn't hear me make any noise...
And there wasn't any on the video tape either!
That's right We didn't hear any suspicious sounds on the tape...
And that's the problem.
The video camera failed to record even a single suspicious noise.
Since no sound was recorded...
The culprit likely deliberately pressed the button on the camera and proceeded to place it on the floor.
Perhaps this is because the culprit was confident in his ability to navigate through the room in darkness.
This, of course, relates to your job as a film man.
You said it yourself, didn't you?
While working in the dark, you must rely on your sense of touch to check the film.
Even if you're accustomed to working in a darkroom, it's still impossible to do it all in complete darkness.
Which would mean you use special markings to indicate locations in there.
And, as I expected, I found such markings in this room when I entered.
The corners of the objects in this messy room...
Are all marked with black tape.
I believe that all of this black tape was used only to conceal the fluorescent tape underneath.
See, if you tear off a bit of the black tape, you can see the fluorescent tape underneath.
These are used in darkrooms for light, as any actual light exposed to the film could render it useless.
As such, even if the lights are turned off, the average person wouldn't notice the tape immediately.
But, as their eyes slowly adjust, the tape will become more and more obvious.
By preparing these markings and remembering the condition of the room, you could rely on their light...
To make your way over without hitting anything or making any noise.
The reason you were in such a panic this time was because we changed the layout of the room, right?
That's also why you hurried over to the light switch after Conan-kun turned it on.
You didn't want their eyes to adjust and see them.
Now that you mention it, there's also black tape on the video camera.
But, even if he knew the position of the camera...
He couldn't have killed him without knowing the position of his heart.
If he had missed the heart, the victim may have survived.
The button.
He likely coated the third button on Furumura-san's shirt with fluorescent paint as well.
That's how he was able to locate the exact position of the victim's heart.
In other words...
After using his spare key to gain entry...
He would have no trouble stabbing the victim in the heart, even in the dark.
He probably put the fluorescent paint on the button three days ago...
Which was the morning after Furumura-san passed out from staying up so late.
He was well-aware that the shirt wouldn't be washed or changed that week as well.
If the button you used for the crime had been discovered by the police, your method would have been noticed...
And that's precisely why you fell for my mentioning that it was strange the third button was missing.
You removed the fluorescent paint from it and tried to return it here.
After hearing Agasa-san's reasoning, we took your statement and had you wait in that interrogation room.
Who'd have thought it'd turn out this way.
But he sure did cover up well, huh?
Hojima-san and Furumura-san, who used to be a film man himself, both failed to notice the tape.
You think you've seen through it all?
The one who put the fluorescent tape in here was Furumura himself.
He put the tape on the video camera so he could reach for it quickly, even in the dark.
He put the rest of the tape around Hojima's apartment here so he could get to the toilet easily at night.
I didn't tell the others about any of this, but...
I could never forgive him.
That fool's mistake ruined the most pivotal part of our greatest film!
But couldn't you just re-film that scene?
That wasn't possible.
It couldn't be perfect.
The scene that needed to be re-filmed was intended to include the protagonist's younger brother.
But... The actor died in an accident before it could be filmed again.
We couldn't do anything about it, so we just had to omit that character from the scene.
There's already no way for the film to be done a second time, no way for it to be truly completed.
It was all his fault!
It was all his...
Professor, thanks for the help.
Hey, wait...
Well, head back to the car.
It's a bit far, but it'll be good for your health to come on foot.
Kudou-kun!
It's fine.
That cigarette—it's the same as when they didn't sound the horn at the stop light.
When we were at the stop light, they didn't sound their horn in order to remain unnoticed.
It's the same for when they were watching us at the apartment just then.
To remain unseen, they didn't smoke in our line of sight.
If they had, we would've seen the light and discovered someone was monitoring us.
Well, that's general practice, even for when the police are tailing people.
But just then, they were smoking openly, and we could see the cigarette.
That means they must have lost us.
Given that they're still roaming around looking, they still haven't been able to locate us.
Well, I did have Detective Takagi administer a blood-alcohol test and question them for a bit.
They were held up until now, so it's no surprise they've lost us.
Could they have been...
Who knows?
We can at least be sure they aren't just fans of my mother.
Their target...
Must have been one of us...
I see.
You lost them?
No matter, we still have other leads.
Continue.
But...
The resemblance is striking.
St-Strangled?
I'm sorry about Haibara, but she's going to have to hang on until then for me.
Until we at least know if their mark is me or Haibara...
We can't make a move.
It's all right I'll go solve it now.
THE 4 PORSCHES
(PART ONE)
Next Conan's Hint
Reel
Next time there's a new development!
Ooh, there's a red Porsche, a white one, a green one.
As for a black one...