Friendship! Romance! Mystery!
We try our best because we've made those promises!
An ordinary train station with an unusual case.
A mere piece of paper's distance separates good and evil!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Geez.
It's because you're always drinking juice that you have to go to the restroom so often.
But it was really good, wasn't it, Uncle?
If only Ran-neechan could've come...
It couldn't be helped since she had some club activity suddenly come up.
By the way, how about this?
Let's get some good ramen before going back!
More food?
Well, I couldn't enjoy the French cuisine because my back was sore from the seats.
So, let's take a detour!
Next stop is Nishi-Sumida.
Nishi-Sumida.
HIDDEN CIRCUMSTANCES OF THE FALLING INCIDENT
The train is now approaching the station.
Ramen!
Let's go, Conan.
I'll order the salty flavor.
How about you?
Hey, hey, are you really going, Uncle?
You bastard!
Geez, can't they just get along?
Knock it off, stop the fighting!
Didn't you hear me?
I said knock it off!
Oh, Inspector Gotou.
We've been waiting for you.
Something wrong?
Mouri?
You're Mouri-san, right?
The famous detective?
Is that true?
You got it...
I'm Gotou from the Nishi-Sumida Police Station.
I heard about you a long time ago.
But I never thought I'd run into you here!
Such a joy!
It just so happens that he witnessed the fight that led to this incident.
Yeah, I suppose that's the case...
Oh, that's great then!
It'll be a pleasure to have Mouri-san working on this case!
Ah, no, the pleasure's mine.
Just let me, Mouri Kogoro, take care of this case.
Hey, hey...
So, we know the victim's identity?
Yes, sir.
Furuta Keisuke-san, age 41.
He works at a nearby company.
He usually takes this express train to work, and was likely on his way home.
The cause of death is a fracture to his skull due to the impact.
The one who got into a fight with him was Sugimoto Hideki-san, age 27.
Sugimoto Hideki (27)
A company employee from the city.
I'm Gotou from Nishi-Sumida.
I have a few questions to ask you.
It's too loud here.
If that's the case, please feel free to use our employee break room.
Moriya-kun...
Yes, right this way.
Thanks for the help.
What's with this wound?
I was on my way home today after treating a customer to dinner.
I got up to use the restroom, and left my bag on the rack while I was in there.
I stayed in there a while due to an upset stomach, and when I returned my bag was missing.
Oh, and then?
Then, when we reached the station...
I saw that guy leaving with my bag.
Hold it!
What are you doing with my bag?
Who are you?
Furuta Keisuke (42)
Company Employee
What are you talking about?
But he refused to return it.
And that's what you two fought over?
Yes...
Then, when I tried to take my bag back...
The strap broke...
And unfortunately, they hadn't yet put the safety fence around the construction site.
Then, you'd never met Furuta-san before, right?
Right.
I hadn't.
What do you think, Mouri-san?
It's truly a shame.
If Furuta-san had never taken Sugimoto-san's bag in the first place...
None of this would've happened.
Uhm...
Did Furuta-san really take that bag?
What do you mean?
Could he have mistaken it for lost luggage?
Lost luggage?
Yes.
He's brought lost items to us before.
It's rare to find kind people like him nowadays, and everyone here speaks highly of him...
I really don't think he's the kind of person who would do this.
Is that true?
Mouri-san?
If what you've said is true...
Then the victim may have already tried to determine the identity of the owner.
Oh, go confirm this with the passengers.
Right, understood.
Inspector...
Now, now, please hold on, Sugimoto-san.
We have to wait for testimony from witnesses first.
It's just as the station worker said.
Apparently, Furuta-san attempted to find the bag's owner before getting out.
Are you sure?
There are passengers who remember you.
According to them, Furuta-san had gotten on the train after Sugimoto-san went to the restroom.
In other words, Sugimoto-san left his bag on the rack and went to the restroom.
Afterwards, Furuta-san got on the train and took the bag thinking that someone had forgotten it.
However, Sugimoto-san didn't know this, and thought that his bag had been stolen.
You then found Furuta-san among the other passengers with your bag, and tried to take it back.
From Furuta-san's point of view, after confirming that the owner was not around...
It wouldn't be feasible to believe that someone suddenly appeared to claim it.
Instead, with his strong sense of righteousness...
He got into a struggle while attempting to protect the bag.
And ended up dying in an unfortunate accident, right?
Noway...
And what about you, Sugimoto-san?
Was it really necessary to get in a fight over such a thing?
I was reckless...
He intended to take it to the lost & found out of kindness.
But ended up dying in such a resentful way.
In any case, you can have this back.
It's gone!
What seems to be the problem?
The receipt is gone.
Receipt?
The receipt from when I treated that customer to dinner.
It was with the rest of the money in here...
But now it's all gone.
Are you sure they aren't in your pocket?
No, I clearly remember putting it in my wallet.
Not good...
Maybe they fell on the station floor during the fight?
Saitou-kun.
I'll go check.
How'd it go?
Well...
It seems that it did not fall out.
Also, Inspector...
I've retrieved Furuta-san's belongings.
A multi-course dinner in Sasayama?
Inspector, may I see that for a moment?
Ah, here you go.
Excuse me for a moment.
I knew it!
This is my missing receipt!
See, "Sugimoto Hideki-sama."
And the amount charged is the same, 25,000 yen.
But why was it in Furuta-san's pocket?
Uhm, actually...
It only happened once, but...
There was an incident wherein money was missing from an item Furuta-san turned in.
What was that?
Furuta-san was also suspected at that time, but...
A thief usually wouldn't turn in the rest of the items.
I see, so that's what happened.
Furuta-san could have stolen the money while pretending to just turn the bag in.
It's a common form of theft.
Form of theft?
That's why he refused to return the bag.
It would expose his crime if he had.
Is that so?
But to think it ended like that for Furuta-san...
I don't believe it.
Sugimoto-san...
Yes?
Just in case, please check to see if anything else is missing.
It's fine.
Is that so?
Then, for the time being...
Would you mind filling this out?
Sure.
Uhm, can I borrow a pen?
Oh, my apologies, I forgot about that.
Ah, excuse me.
You bastard!
As I thought...
I see, so that's how it happened.
I've figured it out...
The true secret behind this accident!
Geez, what's so important that it can't wait?
Where'd that brat Conan go?
After calling me all the way over here...
Leave it to me, Uncle.
All right, we're all good.
Inspector Gotou.
What is it?
Mouri-san wants all of us to come to the boarding area.
Boarding area?
What's going on, Mouri-san?
This pose...
That's the renowned Sleeping Kogoro!
But, Inspector!
Ah, Mouri-san...
This case was just an accident due to a luggage misunderstanding.
That's incorrect, Inspector Gotou.
What do you mean by that?
I'll explain it to you now.
First, let us first review Sugimoto-san's testimony again.
If I recall, after Sugimoto-san returned from the restroom, he noticed his bag was missing...
And then he saw Furuta-san with it in the station, so he quickly left the train.
Is that correct?
Yes, there's no mistake.
However, when we saw it happen, Sugimoto-san jumped out from behind the vending machine.
Is there something wrong with that?
Don't you find it odd?
Why would he be there if he had just come off of the train?
I guess he came from the complete opposite direction.
Construction Area
Construction Materials
Furuta
1st Car
Vending Machine
Sugi-moto
Platform
I see!
Now that I think about it...
It doesn't make any sense to appear from here.
But why would Sugimoto-san do that?
He was waiting...
For Furuta-san to steal the money.
What was that?
No way, you just made that up!
Sugimoto-san most likely figured that Furuta-san would steal the money while pretending to turn in the lost bag.
That's why he purposely put his receipt in his wallet.
If the receipt is found on Furuta-san, it would expose his thievery and make taking the bag back easy.
Stop pushing your claims!
Then...
Right.
To allow Furuta-san to steal the money...
Sugimoto-san purposely left the bag on the rack when he went to the restroom.
But there were other passengers there.
How would Furuta-san know it was a lost bag?
It was the cell phone.
Cell phone?
Didn't you notice?
The cell phone was in the bag.
The cell phone he took out probably had an unanswered call.
Just before the train pulled into the station, Sugimoto-san called that cell phone with another one from the restroom.
And no one ended up answering the phone.
Therefore it seemed to be a lost bag.
I see.
As expected of Sleeping Kogoro.
Furuta-san went and hid behind the construction zone.
And after watching him steal the money out of the bag from the vending machine, Sugimoto-san...
Confronted Furuta-san and pushed him into the construction zone.
He was then knocked to the ground.
Of course, he had laid the warning sign face down on the ground.
He had also cut the rope.
Then all he had to do was take the bag from the fallen victim.
If Furuta-san didn't want the bag to be taken, he'd reach for the straps, which had already been weakened.
After losing his balance, Furuta-san would fall off the edge.
Excuse me, but I need to check the straps of your bag.
Inspector!
That's right.
This case wasn't an accident.
It was a premeditated murder disguised as an accidental death.
What is this?
This is all just conjecture.
Don't you see?
That guy was hanging onto my bag with all of his strength.
Forcing him to fall while we were arguing...
How could I possibly do something like that?
You could easily manage it...
By using the ballpoint pen in the pocket of your coat.
Ballpoint pen?
While fighting behind the construction area...
You stabbed Furuta-san with that ballpoint pen.
And then, you pushed him backward as he was getting up.
They're still there, you know.
The marks you made on Furuta-san's right hand with your ballpoint pen.
What do you say to that?
Sugimoto-san?
Sugimoto-san...
I couldn't forgive that guy!
Because he took...
My girlfriend's life!
Half a year ago...
When she was crossing the street...
He was speeding and ran her over!
We had decided to get married soon...
Since there were no other witnesses...
They believed his testimony that she suddenly jumped into the street.
That bastard escaped punishment!
How...
How could he...
So you wanted to kill Furuta-san...
And decided to set up this trap?
That guy...
It's all his fault!
How was I supposed to forgive that!?
All right, it's ready to eat!
Geez, Dad...
Even if the ramen place was closed, you didn't have to buy cup ramen to eat.
Right, Conan-kun?
It's not a big deal.
I really like this!
Delicious!
I'll have another!
You're gonna get fat.
Well, for Uncle, this kind of food suits him better than that French cuisine.