Friendship! Romance! Mystery!
We try our best because we've made those promises!
They all have the same car - 4 Porsches!
This case turns out to be more than I expected!
Perceiving the one and only truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
THE FOUR PORSCHES
(PART ONE)
She's had a fever ever since we got back yesterday.
Hey, are you all right?
It's only a cold.
There's no reason to bother visiting me.
Given how much has been going on lately...
She must just be exhausted.
More importantly...
Are you sure you're all right?
Remember, those two who were tailing us the other day...
They could have followed you and found this house and the professor.
There's no need to worry.
No one followed me and no one's watching this place.
You really should see a doctor...
Since today is Sunday...
We can't go to most of the hospitals in the area.
I know!
Why not ask Dr. Araide?
No, I called a moment ago but he wasn't there.
Since that earlier case is going to trial soon, he must be busy.
You know, there's a clinic at the Tohto Department Store in Haido City.
We could try going there.
I think their day off is on Thursdays.
I guess, if I have no other choice...
It's best to get these cleared up early.
Colds often lead to all kinds of other illnesses, don't they?
We can't see a doctor immediately?
That's right.
There are so many patients today.
You're looking at around a two hour wait.
There's nothing we can do.
First of all, go ahead and get the appointment, Professor.
Ah, excuse me, can I schedule now?
Yes.
Now, until we get to see the doctor...
We could waste time at the department store.
Yes, thank you very much.
You know...
I'm starting to get a little hungry.
There's a shop in the restaurant row there that's really popular for its egg porridge.
If Ai-kun had some of that...
It might make her feel better, right?
All right, Professor.
All right, all right.
All right, all right, all right.
Stop!
All right, we're here, Ai-kun.
Here, hold on.
You must be a bit disoriented, right?
Don't patronize me.
Just move out of the way.
I can...
Get out of a car on my own.
Porsche...
356A...
Gin's car...
Hey!
Haibara!
Hey, Haibara...
While it's true that's the same type of Porsche that Gin drives...
His is black, and this one is green.
The colors aren't the same.
Not to mention...
Since there are three Porsches parked near each other...
A group of Porsche enthusiasts are probably just having lunch together at this department store.
Another Porsche.
This one's a 911...
All right, that's good.
Banba-san!
Damn it...
Out of bounds again?
Banba Yukiya (41)
That's him, all right.
This happens every time.
Well, like usual, let's just go shopping until he sobers up.
Wait, my purse is in my car.
Me too.
Hey, Uncle...
Do the four Porsches parked here belong to you all?
Yeah.
The older green one here is Hotei-san's...
Hotei Eiji (39)
Porsche 356A.
The newer type there on the right is Taiyama-san's Porsche Boxster.
Taiyama Kaoru (34)
And this is my baby:
A Porsche 911.
And this red one over here is...
A Porsche 928 that belongs to Banba-san, who's asleep in my car.
But why did all four of you take your car?
Oh, that's because...
As well as being Porsche enthusiasts...
We're all golfing buddies.
When the four of us play golf...
We meet here and go together in Kureko-san's car.
It's more fun when we all pile into one car.
And we only have to pay the road toll for one car.
The parking fee at this department store isn't that bad, and it's free if we buy something.
And since he always starts chugging down beers about half way through...
By the time we're done, a certain someone is completely drunk...
So there's nothing we can do but go shopping until he sobers up.
Well, the parking lot gets so crowded on Sundays.
It's hard to find an open space, so we have to make a space of our own.
We should get moving.
See you.
Make a space?
I don't know many people who have the courage to park between two Porsches, do you?
Oh, I see!
Well, Ai-kun, we should get going too.
Haibara?
I'll pass.
I'm not feeling well.
I'm going to wait in the car until the appointment.
Hey, Ai-kun...
It's no wonder.
Having been followed by those people whose intentions we don't know...
It's natural to be apprehensive.
Then, you mean...
The people trailing you were with those guys in black?
It's possible, but there's still no proof.
While I don't know if their mark was me or Haibara...
I can't make a move.
There was a robbery in the Tokyo metropolitan area last night before dawn.
The criminal is still at large...
Acting on information from an eye witness, the police...
Let's see, it should be on the 10th floor.
But I don't feel right...
Leaving Ai-kun behind.
It can't be helped.
Kyoto-style ramen...
This one has western-style food...
That's an Italian place...
And Chinese...
A lot of options, huh?
What's this?
Such a long line...
Tarugatei?
Oh, this is it!
Hey, hey...
Be serious!
There are way too many people in line.
Professor!
It's that famed egg porridge.
We'll use up all of our free time just waiting...
Damn, looks like I forgot my phone in the car.
Wait just a minute.
I'm going to go get it and come right back.
They're the ones from the parking garage...
Hey!
Cool kid!
It's been a long time, hasn't it?
J-Jo...
Jodie-sensei?
Oh, and Ran-kun and Sonoko-kun too!
Hello!
But why?
Why are you here?
We're here to try the Tarugatei egg porridge.
Problem?
There's no problem...
That's just like Sonoko all right...
We've heard how good this place is, so we invited Jodie-sensei along.
Yes!
Japanese food is healthy and very, very good!
I see!
Speaking of which, what are you doing here, Conan-kun?
You said you went to visit Ai-chan today because she was had a cold.
No...
Ai-chan?
See, Ai-kun was actually...
Going to come here.
We were thinking about bringing her here to try the egg porridge, but...
Since it was impossible with her bad cold...
We didn't invite her.
Right, Professor?
That, that's it!
For those watching Wild Sunday at home, please look at this!
It's amazing isn't it, this huge line?
We're standing right outside of a restaurant here in the Tohto Department Store, where inside...
See it's so popular that even a TV crew is here; that made us want to try it too.
Isn't that Katou Tomomi from Gourmet Corner?
It is!
Hey, hey... Listen to people when they talk.
Now, let's proceed with some interviews.
The serial arsonist has yet to be apprehended.
Police headquarters has urged the nearby residents to remember to be cautious.
What I'm saying is that everyone was stupid!
Thanks a lot.
Let's hear one last tune...
"Kimi to Yakusoku Shita Yasashii Ano Basho Made."
And so...
Let's go ahead and talk with someone else.
Boy, can I bother you for a moment?
Boy, have you come to this department store especially for the egg porridge too?
Yeah...
But since so many people are in line, I might give up.
Oh, is that so?
I bet you've come to try the Tarugatei egg porridge as well, haven't you?
That's it, we're gonna go.
OK, Professor...
Let's go!
Hurry!
Hey!
Wait!
Conan-kun!
The line is moving fast!
You can eat soon!
Forget about him, Ran.
But...
That brat doesn't have any taste anyway.
Hey!
Why, all...
Of a sudden?
Hey!
Shinichi!
That guy there...
He came back.
The professor and Kudou-kun?
Why?
Why does he have such a scared look on his face?
Shinichi!
Banba-san!
What's wrong?
Shinichi!
It's no use.
He's been strangled.
Hello? Is this the police?
I'm here in the underground parking garage of the Tohto Department Store in the Haido District!
At any rate, I'll stay here.
Professor, you get in the car and get Haibara out of here.
Why?
Because my image was just broadcast by a television camera a moment ago.
If those guys who were following us the other day were watching...
And if they're really with those men in black...
They'll inevitably come here, right?
Don't worry, that was just a lunch-time talk TV show.
The viewership couldn't be more than 10%.
If it was a live broadcast aired during golden time...
They might see it...
Fool!
There are around 40 million TV viewers in the Kanto area.
Even a 1% rating would come out to 400,000 viewers.
10% gives us 4 million people...
There's no guarantee that those guys aren't among them.
I guess...
Now, if you understand, hurry and get Haibara out of here.
If you look around the city, you should be able to find a hospital that's open on a Sunday.
Haibara's not well.
She's just been acting strong for us until now.
It's always raining...
Hey, there are patrol cars stopping in front of this department store!
I guess something happened.
I bet it's because of that four-eyed kid again.
He's always getting involved in cases somehow.
No way!
Seeing is believing.
"Seeing is believing."
Let's go have a look.
Hey, why can't we get out?
We were just contacted by the police.
There's been a serious incident in this parking garage, and no one can leave until they get here.
That's what they said.
Until they catch the criminal, we're stuck.
Shinichi?
We have no choice.
Find an empty space and wait there quietly.
But what if those guys show up?
Don't worry, I'll solve this quickly.
Don't make any moves until then.
Hey!
Shinichi?
Shinichi!
It's all right.
I'll solve this in no time.
Brown hair...
How did the culprit strangle Banba-san?
And how did they get the murder weapon back?
He has to get Haibara out of here now!
They're gone?
The professor and Haibara!
THE FOUR PORSCHES
(PART TWO)
Power Window
Next Conan's Hint
Repeat-after me:
"Power window"!
Power window!
Yeah!