Friendship! Romance! Mystery!
We try our best because we've made those promises!
Haibara has become involved in the Porsche case.
Jodie, Araide, and Vermouth.
Perceiving the one and only truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
The 4 Porsches
(Part Two)
The murder victim is Banba Yukiya-san, age 41.
Cause of death is suffocation.
Since the marking left from behind is a thin one...
The weapon of choice was likely a string of some sort.
Banba Yukiya (41)
It seems he was strangled with quite a bit of force.
And? Who found the body?
It was this gentleman.
He apparently golfed with the victim...
And found the body upon returning from shopping here.
Who are those two behind you?
Yes, sir.
They're golfing companions of ours as well.
And, they're Porsche enthusiasts.
Conan-kun?
You all are Porsche enthusiasts, right?
How did you know?
When the professor and I came to this department store...
We saw this guy and his friends parking their car...
And talked to them briefly.
And, where is Agasa-san?
He's probably still inside shopping.
Then, Conan-kun...
Can you give us the details from that time?
At around 1:00 PM...
Those four pulled up in that man's white Porsche...
And only these three got out.
He said they were going shopping in the department store while they waited for their friend to sober up.
I think everyone was going to return home in their own cars.
Then, these four Porsches belong to you all?
Yeah.
Inspector Megure!
A moment?
What have you found?
Yes, sir.
Thanks.
It seems that our suspects are the three of you.
The estimated time of death puts his passing at 1:00 PM.
That's just after you all entered this parking garage.
In other words, the probability that one of you...
Strangled Banba-san when you got out is extremely high.
That is, unless you feel you forgot to lock the car door?
No, I did lock them as usual...
But when we got out, he was still alive.
Hotei-san, Taiyama-san—is this true?
He even said something his drunken state.
"Out of bounds again" or something like that.
Moreover, the three of us got out at the same time.
None of us had the time to strangle him.
Well, let's get the questioning out of the way first.
Please give us your name...
The nature of your relationship with the victim...
The order in which you left the car...
And exactly which one of these vehicles belongs to you.
I was the first to get out.
Kureko Yoshihito (45)
My name is Kureko Yoshihito.
I became acquainted with Banba-san at a Porsche Debut Exhibition.
This is my Porsche 911.
The four of us came here after golfing, considering we always ride together.
The rest is as the boy said.
Since we wanted to fill time until Banba-san sobered up...
We decided to go shopping in the department store.
I later realized I left my cellphone in the car.
But he was already like this when I got back.
Then, I guess that means you didn't see the one who strangled him?
Oh, no—the time I came back was at least an hour later.
What's this?
There was a box in the glove-box.
It's a music box!
The tracking needle was broken, so I decided to get it fixed, but I keep forgetting about it.
It still works...
So you could technically strangle someone with it.
I was the second to get out—Hotei Eiji.
Hotei Eiji (39)
Banba and I were friends since the days when we'd race down the mountain roads together.
It's been a long time since then.
I've taken an interest in classic cars as of late.
So, I bought this Porsche 356A that was first issued 50 years ago.
Excuse me, if you will.
There are some things in the back seat.
That's a fishing pole.
I like to fish as well.
This is an automatic reel, isn't it?
This could be used to remotely strangle someone.
Don't say that!
It was in the bag, wasn't it?
I haven't touched it in the time since Kureko-san called me down here.
Taiyama Kaoru (34)
My name is Taiyama Kaoru.
I was the last to get out, but...
Could a woman like me actually have the strength necessary to strangle a man?
Really, I only have enough for driving a golf ball.
And?
What was your relationship to Banba-san?
Nothing really.
We became acquainted after talking to each other about Porsches in the golf course parking lot.
We began hanging out after that.
I bought this Porsche Boxster shortly after it went on sale, and Banba-san happened to like it.
I see something in your car.
There, in the passenger's seat.
It's a gift for my nephew.
It's a Porsche model car.
But, come on.
This couldn't strangle someone to death, could it?
Besides, after we got out to go shopping...
I didn't go near Banba-san until Kureko-san called for us.
I haven't touched anything since then!
Hey, did you look up here?
A security camera?
I see!
You can know if they're lying immediately if you look.
All right, let's get to the security room.
Yes, sir. Will the rest of you please come with us?
I guess we have no choice.
I thought I told you not to move!
But...
Ai-kun's condition...
We need to hurry and get her to a doctor.
I guess we have no other choice.
I'll ask Detective Takagi to get his patrol car and get you out of here quietly.
But those guys might ambush us outside...
Hi!
Who are "those guys"?
Conan-kun, you really are involved in this case, aren't you?
But, why did you all come down here?
The police shouldn't be letting anyone back here that isn't with them...
We told them we were coming in to get you and they let us in.
Right, Ran?
Huh?
Ai-chan is here, too.
Oh yeah, Sonoko-neechan is a great detective, isn't she?
I was just about to go to the security room to see the security footage.
Will you come with me?
Come on, let's go...
Come on, Sonoko-neechan!
Hey, sensei, you too.
Come along, Jodie-sensei!
Wait, Conan-kun.
Reddish...
Brown hair...
What's going on here?
Taiyama-san, Hotei-san.
Both of you went back to your own cars after getting out of his.
I went back for my purse.
That's because Kureko-san also pays for our golfing sessions.
The three of you then went shopping inside here.
And until Kureko-san came back to get his cellphone about an hour later...
None of you approached the car—correct?
Isn't that what we told you?
It's impossible for us to have done it.
If they had all been involved...
It's very unlikely he would have called the police.
Moreover, none of them did anything suspicious when they left the car...
There weren't any suspicious movements.
I don't get it...
How the culprit strangled Banba-san...
And how they retrieved the weapon.
Damn it, I have to hurry...
To get Haibara out of here...
I have to solve this now!
Inspector Megure!
We've just finished developing the pictures of the three cars.
Thanks, bring them over.
Yes, sir.
This is it!
Sonoko, do you have it?
The three of them could have strangled him together before getting out...
Perhaps...
Say...
Why don't we go back and look at the car again?
You might end up finding something.
Inspector...
That's true.
We should be 100% sure.
Let's go have another look.
The little red riding hood from the bus jacking...
And the girl in the Beetle...
Maybe...
Even though Shin'ichi said not to move...
If Ai-kun doesn't get some help soon...
I have no choice.
I have to call Araide-sensei again.
Yes, this is Araide.
Is this Araide-sensei?
This sounds like Agasa-san, I believe?
I'm lucky!
When Conan-kun called earlier, it seems you weren't in...
Conan-kun did?
That's strange.
I was in all day today.
At any rate, did you need something?
I see...
The investigation is preventing you from leaving, huh?
Yeah, mostly...
Well, let's see what we can do.
After seeing the scene again...
Have you noticed anything?
No, not especially...
Then, why not let Sonoko-neechan look through everyone's cars?
Me?
Considering how good of a detective she is, she might find something!
First would be Taiyama-san's car.
Can we have the key?
Here, Sonoko-neechan.
Aside from it being so expensive...
There doesn't seem to be anything strange about it.
Is she...
Could it be, Sonoko...
You mean, you've got it?
Yeah, I finally know...
How Banba-san, who was sitting in the front, was strangled...
And exactly who was responsible.
Really?
Once again, why is it that someone has to seem asleep, like Mouri-kun, to solve a case anymore?
But you really know, just by sitting in the car?
It wasn't by sitting—it was by touch.
By touch?
Look, isn't there a hole in the glass here?
I felt it when I happened to touch it.
The criminal is...
the owner of this Porsche Boxster,
Taiyama-san.
You're the one responsible, right?
Hey, hey...
Are you serious?
Taiyama-san did?
Well, Detective Takagi...
Get into the driver's seat of the Porsche 911, next to Banba-san's body, and pretend you're the victim.
Understood.
Conan-kun, proceed with what I instructed earlier.
Oh, you mean about getting the fishing line?
But can this really kill someone?
Just do what I told you earlier.
It will all come to light soon enough.
Yes!
The first request was to get Detective Takagi...
And put the line around his neck.
Next was to wrap it around the head-rest...
Get out of the car with the line...
And close the door.
And then I was supposed to take both ends of the line...
Take it under the middle Porsche...
And then over to Taiyama-san's car.
Then all I have to do is put the line in the gap on top of the window...
And then get in the car.
But wait...
Banba-san was strangled with quite a bit of force, and it was from behind.
Maybe you were trying to say she secretly got him from behind...
But she's still just a woman.
Right—which is why Taiyama-san used...
This power window.
Taiyama-san most likely...
Put the line around his neck as he slept.
She then used the excuse that she forgot her purse to get to her car.
She lowered the window...
And tied the ends of the line around the gear lever.
Next, by pressing the switch to activate the window...
The power from the window takes over.
This alone is enough to strangle the victim.
Hey, Sonoko-san...
Not to mention that the darkness of this parking garage makes the line invisible.
When you put the key in the car...
The engine would trigger the power window...
And drown out any loud noises.
But how is it you retrieve the line?
It's quite simple...
So long as you use this model car.
All that's required is you tying the line to the rear wheels of the car...
And setting it outside of the box.
After he's strangled, the line breaks...
And the model car will keep going...
Until it has completely reeled in the line.
While it's true that it will retrieve the line...
I remember that when I checked...
There wasn't a noise like that at the time.
Oh, you don't know?
The battery of these model cars only last for ten minutes.
It had already died out by the time you got here.
Would you like to check the model car?
I'm sure you'll be able to find the string.
While it's true that Hotei-san's fishing reel could do it as well...
The reason he isn't the culprit is the...
Power window.
Between the three of us...
Only my Boxster has it, right?
I had thought it was a clever plan.
But you're just too creative a detective for me.
You mean, it was you?
But why?
"Why"?
He must be thinking about this on the other side as well.
"Why did you kill me?"
Have you heard that story?
His story about running against the yellow Ferrari.
I actually heard him mention it after golfing once.
But, he only saw it happen...
That was a lie.
He was the one responsible for it.
He planned to spray cold water at the people in the Ferrari.
The driver that day was my younger brother.
During the battle, it was our Ferrari that veered over the edge.
I was saved when someone passed by and saw me by chance three hours later, but...
It was already too late for my brother.
Even though I couldn't remember the numbers on his license plate...
I could never forget his face...
Or his red Porsche 928...
And of course that golf bag in the passenger seat.
I decided to buy a Porsche of my own...
And began searching for that man at local golf courses.
I became acquainted with him to exact my revenge.
But, why didn't you just tell this to the police?
It wouldn't have mattered.
My brother was also at fault for driving that way.
The reason I initially sought him out wasn't for revenge.
At that time...
If he had called for an ambulance immediately...
My brother might have made it.
I really wanted to just ask why he didn't.
If he had said it was because he was scared, or afraid of being caught...
I would have forgiven him, even if I regretted it.
But after hearing him mention it that way after golfing...
I settled for revenge.
What you guys drive fast shouldn't be your cars.
Just stick to driving golf balls.
All right, with the case out of the way...
It's time to call the professor so we can get Haibara out of here.
Hurry!
Hurry up!
Oh, Ran—where's Jodie-sensei?
She left.
She suddenly remembered something urgent.
What?
Ah, Conan-kun!
They're gone?
The professor and Haibara are!
Could it be...
Could it be—?
Oh, I was waiting.
What's this "waiting" stuff?
Why did you go home?
I told you not to!
Don't talk so loud.
Araide-sensei is here with us.
Araide-sensei?
He's actually there?
Yeah, he's looking after Ai-kun now.
Even though you said he wasn't in, he was when I called.
When the case was preventing us from getting out, he said...
"Professor, since you know the police, if you claim the girl you had with you suddenly fell ill...
"They should let you leave."
We couldn't go in one of the patrol cars, since they were tied up at the department store...
But she was luckily outside and willing to take us.
Hey...
Don't tell me that "she" is...
Hi!
I've cut up some fruits.
They're rich in Vitamin C, which is great for colds!
She finally ended up falling asleep.
Oh...
Sorry.
That's Jodie-sensei.
She brought us back here.
Her car was fortunately parked in an outside lot, so she was able to help us.
Well, it seems Ai-kun only has a cold.
It's nothing to worry about.
Seven...
Eight...
Nine...
Ten...
Ready or not—
It's set...
Here I come—
After you.
I see you—
You've been found...
Professor!
Hidden Bathroom Secret
(Part One)
Haibara's older sister, Miyano Akemi
Next Conan's Hint
The next broadcast is on a culture day!
Reading!
Television!
Movies!
Mystery!
Put them all together and you get me.