Friendship! Romance! Mystery!
We try our best because we've made those promises!
Haibara's sister, Miyano Akemi-
Has hidden the Organization's secret somewhere!
Perceiving the one and only truth,
The appearance of a child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
HIDDEN BATHROOM SECRET
(PART ONE)
Medicine?
All I can remember...
The professor was carrying me...
After that, I think...
I think...
How silly.
If I had really been discovered, I wouldn't have been able to have that dream.
The professor even dozed off over there...
Professor!
Yo, Haibara.
You awake?
Tomato juice...
You should tell the professor...
To stop drinking canned juice while surfing the net.
He's always falling asleep there and spilling it everywhere.
Aside from that, why are you...
I had an ominous premonition, so I decided to check on you.
I said I was coming over to nurse you.
Well, I guess I may have been thinking too much.
Don't worry—it's OK to get back to sleep.
Sorry for the wait.
The egg porridge is ready!
It isn't as good as Tarugatei's, though.
Is she asleep?
That's strange.
She was awake a moment ago.
Well, I'll just leave it here.
Remember to ask Ai-chan what she thinks of it after giving it a try.
Well, I promised to meet up with Sonoko, so...
Go out the same way you came in.
The back door in the basement, right?
You should hurry and fix your front door, Professor.
See you, Conan-kun.
Thank you, Ran-neechan.
Jeez...
You may be an expert at pretending to cry...
But you're terrible at feigning sleep.
What's with you?
She made a trip here just to make porridge for you.
Trying to act big?
Not really.
I didn't ask her to come.
It's not that I don't realize you aren't used to the caring type like Ran, but...
She went through to the trouble of making it.
Eat it before it gets cold.
You still don't get...
I don't want you to know anything either.
But thank goodness it's the weekend.
Yeah, with those suspicious people watching over us...
It's a really bad idea to let Haibara go out.
Ai-kun seems to be doing much better.
After the weekend is over...
Maybe we can take Ai-kun to meet Professor Miyano's friend.
Hey...
What's that about?
Oh, I didn't tell you?
When I asked the other professors I know about Professor Miyano...
I found a designer that was his primary and secondary school classmate, as well as his childhood friend.
It seems that during the professor's younger days, his friend oversaw the books he self-published.
Even though the books didn't sell well, the design was very original.
Among his fellow scientists, it was well received.
If we meet with that person...
Whether it be on the case of the men in black...
Or about Ai-kun's parents...
We could at least learn a little more.
Hey, hey...
She doesn't seem any better at all.
We really shouldn't be going today.
We can't tell whether or not those guys are lying in wait somewhere.
Isn't it the one who really wants to go, you?
Well, that's only because I think we may find out more about the men in black...
Which makes it worth the visit.
In that case, don't beat around the bush.
Well, there's nothing to worry about, Shinichi.
We're doing all right, as you can see.
Those guys haven't discovered anything yet.
Yeah.
I suppose.
I was indeed a childhood friend of that professor you mentioned, Miyano Atsushi.
Unfortunately, I haven't seen him for 30 years.
The last time I saw him was...
Dejima Souhei (54)
President of Design Office
When I borrowed this house that he had inherited from his parents.
In other words...
This house originally belonged to Professor Miyano.
Yeah.
I told him I intended to start a design firm...
And he said that since his house was going to be empty, I could borrow it for the time being.
It's been 30 years since then.
This house is where my father was raised...
And where did Professor Miyano stay after that?
Well, he had found a sponsor to support a theory of his, and said he would be moving to a large research facility.
But I don't know where it is.
It must be them.
Probably.
And, after that, Professor Miyano never contacted you again?
Yeah.
He only sent a postcard stating he had gotten married.
Oh, there was one time when that person came around when you weren't here.
Remember?
Zaitsu Ukihiko (41)
Designer
During that time, President...
Didn't you go out when you had a mental block on new design ideas, and not come back for some time?
He came around one of those times.
He brought his beautiful foreign wife...
And his adorable four or five year old daughter.
It seemed he had something important to discuss with you...
And, in the end, stayed for an entire day before leaving.
He said the president might come back soon.
Didn't I tell you?
I never heard about this!
I think his wife's name was Elena, and their daughter was named Akemi-chan.
Sis...
Strange father and daughter, huh?
Yeah.
Imai Tetsuo (52)
Designer
Especially when he couldn't do anything about his daughter's mischief.
That child hid all of our work tools.
She then watched us in glee as we panicked.
His wife stayed put and never said a word to us, which made me wonder if she even knew the language.
I later Overheard her speaking Japanese to her daughter.
The father kept on looking outside the window...
Oh yeah, at that time...
There was a car stationed outside this house.
Yeah, it was black with smoked windows, right?
Surveillance...
Hey, hey, exactly when did this happen?
It was right after we had completed renovating this old house into the office...
So it must have been about 20 years ago.
At that time, did Professor Miyano leave any messages?
Nothing in particular.
By the way, what is your relation to Miyano-kun?
Oh, well, we're both professors...
This old man is finally getting married and wanted to invite his old friend to the wedding.
But, we didn't have his address...
So we came to ask if you knew.
Right?
Yeah.
I'll be heading out to buy lunch soon.
Then, bring me a hamburger along with the usual.
Natsuhori Isamu (35)
Designer
The usual teriyaki fish, with medium fries and corn soup on top, right?
Anything else?
Well, I'll have the same as the president.
I want an apple pie and a large cola to go with that.
Jeez...
It's because you drink so much that you keep having to go to the bathroom.
Sorry for acting like a kid.
Oh, Imai-kun...
Please make some coffee—and for our guests, too.
Well, that's about it—I don't know Miyano-kun's address either.
Well, if you'll excuse me, I still have work to do, so after the coffee...
Ah, yes.
Speaking of Akemi-chan, she came over once as well.
Oh, didn't I mention that?
It was that cute girl who borrowed our bathroom.
When she said, "It's been a while" to us...
It came as quite a shock.
Was she actually Miyano-kun's daughter?
Oh, you didn't know?
Didn't I just say I haven't heard of this?
Sorry.
And after that, did she only come to use the bathroom?
Yeah...
But she said something very strange.
She said it was embarrassing to borrow the bathroom, and told me not to tell anyone.
As for who she wanted to keep it a secret from...
Hey, hold on!
There you go.
Both of you?
There's no doubt about it.
My sister must have hidden something here.
Somewhere in this bathroom.
But, to hide something in such a small place...
It's possible that someone has already found it.
Yeah, the chances of that are high, but...
Maybe...
There's something here we can find.
Something that would constitute as a lead to those men in black...
Hurry.
Hurry and get out!
Let's look again later.
There we go.
Do you kids want some as well?
No, we're fine.
Say, after that girl came, did anything strange happen?
Yeah.
Someone broke in here.
Twice, even.
A break-in?
But nothing was taken.
Is it all right? Your stomach...
Yeah, I think it's better.
Instead of that, the problem was...
After the girl came...
I don't know why, but strange things began to happen.
Strange things?
President!
Death by poisoning, huh?
Yeah.
The deceased is Dejima Souhei-san, age 54.
He is this design firm's president.
It seems that while eating his lunch, a hamburger, with the others...
He suddenly felt pain and collapsed.
And, who bought the hamburger?
I did.
In that case, you had the best opportunity to put in the poison.
Please hold on a second!
The president took that burger himself.
You see, I bought the same burger
for everyone—the teriyaki burger.
I wouldn't know which one he would take.
How could I have done it?
Is that true?
Or could it be that the poison was smeared on the tools that the President Dejima usually used?
Where is the president's station?
Over here.
And the seat next to his?
It's Imai-san's.
Then, the person who could most conveniently poison the president...
While it could have been me...
The president ate cookies before the burger.
Look, next to the coffee cup, you can see the empty packages for the cookies is still there.
I brought those in from the kitchen.
He asked me to bring them along, since I was bringing coffee in for everyone.
I see.
That means that if the poison had been on his tools...
He would have died while eating the cookies instead.
What medicine is this?
It's a laxative.
The president took them often due to his hemorrhoid problem.
But he may have taken too much, and hurt his stomach.
That's happened a lot recently.
Come to think of it, the same thing happened before he ate the hamburger.
He rushed to the bathroom with a stomach ache.
The bathroom?
Did anyone go to the bathroom before the president?
Uhm...
I did, before I went to buy lunch.
I went in after that, and then Zaitsu-kun went.
Afterward, the president went to the bathroom...
And ate the hamburger when he came out, correct?
Ah, yes.
In other words...
If you had smeared poison inside the bathroom...
Give me a break!
While I did go to the bathroom before the president...
I wasn't the last one to go in before him.
See, between the president and I going...
Those two kids went as well.
Conan-kun?
With Ai-chan and Professor Agasa?
Ah, well...
We came to ask Dejima-san about something and then all of this happened by chance.
But you guys seem to frequently find yourselves in these situations...
You're becoming more and more like Mouri-kun.
So, which of you went in first?
We went together.
Both of you went in together?
Ah, that's because...
I dropped a coin over there...
And I thought that it might have rolled into the bathroom under the doorway.
So both of us went in to look, right?
What my sister stole and hid from the organization...
In that case, where is the poison, exactly?
Then, why don't we check all of the places from his workstation to the bathroom?
From the workstation...
To the bathroom?
The president went to the bathroom after eating the cookies...
And, after coming back, collapsed after eating the hamburger, right?
That means the poison could have been left somewhere.
From the time the president collapsed to the time Inspector Megure came...
No one left this workroom.
No one threw or wiped anything away, either.
Is that so? At any rate, let's investigate.
Yeah, and order a body search.
What?
There are no signs of the poison anywhere?
Yeah—the bathroom, the corridor, nor the workroom.
Nothing at the spots the victim could have touched.
But oddly, there was a positive reaction on the right side of the victim's pants and the empty hole in his belt.
And also on the fingertips of his left hand, as well as the handkerchief.
It can also be found on the hamburger's packaging.
But, only trace amounts were found on those places—likely from when he touched them.
Then, why was the poison only on his left hand?
I see! It's the coffee cup's handle!
If you smear poison on that...
He would use his right hand for the cookie and his left for the cup, meaning he'd touch the poison.
If so, after he went to the bathroom...
He would have used his right hand to open and close the door.
But since no poison was left in the bathroom...
That means the culprit is...
The one who brought the coffee here.
Imai-san—that would be you.
Ah, no, Inspector!
Of course, we also inspected the coffee cup handle and the cookie packaging, but...
No poison was found.
Oh, really?
And the flush handle of the toilet is on the left side.
If there was poison on his left hand before he went to toilet...
It should have been left on the left side of his pants when he pulled them up.
Then, why was the poison found on the right side of his pants?
Hey, did the president have any habits?
Like being left-handed, for instance.
If you mean something characteristic...
He's a hygiene freak and a coffee addict, I guess.
A hygiene freak and caffeine addict?
When he sat at his desk, he would first use a wet tissue to wipe his hands clean.
It took me ten years to learn how to make the coffee to his liking.
And also, did you notice any suspicious people keeping watch over this place?
Other than the two break-ins, nothing else happened.
Break-ins?
Yeah, the window lock was forced open.
Ai-kun, could it be that the culprit this time is...
Yes.
To eliminate the target without leaving any evidence...
As though to hide their tracks in the mist.
It's akin to their usual methods.
The break-ins that occurred after my sister visited...
It was most likely them.
Yeah.
They came to check if she hid anything here or not.
Don't! This isn't something you need to know!
If you probe any deeper, you will... Really...
HIDDEN BATHROOM SECRET
(PART TWO)
Toilet Fixtures
The next episode will bring Haibara an intense message.
What do you mean by "intense"?
To the point of making you cry.