Friendship! Romance! Mystery!
We try our best because we've made those promises!
The real culprit and the secret tape...
As well as the message that shocks Haibara!
Perceiving the one and only truth,
The appearance of a child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
HIDDEN BATHROOM SECRET
(PART TWO)
The break-ins that occurred after my sister visited...
It was most likely them.
Yeah.
They came to check if she hid anything here or not.
There are also signs that listening devices were planted in the bathroom.
They likely decided to install the bugs after not finding anything originally.
This way, they were able to listen to the employees to find out whether anything had been hidden.
They broke in a second time just to retrieve the bugs—that's the most likely scenario, anyway.
But, don't you think it's unrelated to this murder case?
After all, President Dejima was only your father's friend, who was once with the Organization.
It's been thirty years, you know.
The target was me.
What if they killed my father's friend...
In order to put pressure on me?
Don't be silly.
Why would they do something like that?
I felt it.
At that department store in Haido City, on that day...
As I was losing consciousness...
I could feel the cold gaze of contempt on me...
What'd you say?
Why did you come here then?
If you knew it would be dangerous, then why?
Because I want to know.
Am I not allowed?
I want to know whether my parents...
Were really like the Organization claimed.
Especially after meeting your cheerful mother.
But, the rumors about my father, the mad scientist, seem to be true...
And my mother seemed silent and gloomy.
It's hard to figure exactly what she was thinking, isn't it?
Stupid...
Those are just rumors.
Don't jump to conclusions.
Do you know what they called my mother in the Organization?
Hell Angel.
The angel from Hell.
But, since this isn't interesting any longer...
That's one less burden.
All right, we're done with my troubles.
Don't interfere with the case anymore.
How about we leave this place now?
But, even if we do leave...
There's no actual way to escape.
But, if we don't find what your sister hid in the bathroom...
Oh, from Kudo-kun's deduction about the listening devices just then...
Didn't he say that, with the aid of the bugs, they could listen in and find out where it's hidden.
During the second break-in, they came to get it, and took it away with the bugs, right?
So, the reason for staying here is actually...
Then, you mean that nothing was taken during the break-ins?
Yeah.
Natsuhori Isamu (35)
Designer
But the president thought that one of his designs was stolen.
Imai Tetsuo (52)
Designer
He said someone could have secretly taken a picture of that design.
The president was always hung up on those sorts of things.
Whenever he saw a design similar to his own, he would fly into an uncontrollable rage.
He also got pretty angry this morning.
This morning?
Zaitsu Ukihiko (41)
Designer
Yeah, he went to tell off another design firm.
"As I thought, you stole my designs!"
You were also the ones who broke into our office!" Like that.
Could it be...
Yeah.
It's possible that, when he went to the rival design firm, he was poisoned somehow...
But the president got angry with good reason.
If news of designs being stolen ended up spreading...
Everyone would get tired of it and throw them away.
Speaking of that break-in, some strange things happened afterwards.
Strange things?
Something I had lost a long time ago, my ball point pen, suddenly reappeared.
Right, right.
Together with the ruler I always used.
I thought they were stolen, but you're saying they reappeared?
Yeah, accidentally found it in the slipper cupboard near the door.
But didn't this happen before the break-ins?
Is that so?
The stranger thing is after that, the president...
Ah...
In that case, it started from that time, I guess.
"Save water, save water!" he said.
He kept emphasizing it from then on.
To the point that he prohibited us from taking showers here at work.
He was never one to be concerned with such matters in the past.
I see!
That's how it was...
Then, can you please give us a tour of this design office?
Sure.
Something isn't right.
This was not done by those men in black.
The culprit was most likely...
Him.
He killed President Dejima in the bathroom with an ingenious trick.
And, with the treasure right in front of him, he couldn't possibly go back empty-handed.
Then...
Yeah.
It should still be there.
In that bathroom...
Whatever your sister hid away, it should be there.
Inspector, at any rate, let's have a look at that other design firm.
Right.
President Dejima may have gotten the poison on his and unknowingly while over there.
No—That's impossible.
Ah, well...
When he returned here, he would have come into contact with something, right?
Like a door knob or the back of a chair, for instance.
But, the places that came up positive for poison were limited to...
His left hand, the right side of his pants, the hole in his belt...
As well as his handkerchief...
And then the packaging for the burger that he was eating before he died.
But, since only trace amounts of poison were found there...
He must have come in contact with the poison before touching those places.
You should understand by now.
Exactly when did the president come into contact with the poison?
Think: Where would you need to undo your belt, pull down your pants...
And also use your handkerchief?
Could it be...
In the bathroom?
That's right In the toilet, President Dejima was...
Killed after being trapped into touching the poison.
And the one responsible was one of the three employees here.
But Agasa-san...
We didn't find any poison in the bathroom.
It's natural that you couldn't.
That's because what had poison on it has already been removed from the bathroom...
By President Dejima himself.
What?
It was brought out?
Oh, you know it, right?
Something that has to be discarded after it's used.
Unless you mean the freshener...
f he changed the towel, there should be a cleaner one hanging there.
Other than that would be the toilet paper...
get it!
The empty toilet paper roll!
It's the empty toilet paper roll!
If you smear poison on it beforehand...
After you've finished with it and replace it...
To throw it away, you have to bring it out of the bathroom.
But, if that's the case...
Wouldn't the new toilet paper roll have poison on it as well?
You would normally use it after replacing it, right?
So the part of the new roll with poison on it...
Was torn away and, after being used, was flushed away.
I see...
Do you not see now?
As such, President Dejima's actions in the bathroom were likely as follows...
He first noticed that the toilet paper had run out.
He used his right hand to take off the poisoned empty roll and put it on the floor.
He then took a new roll of toilet paper and replaced it on the holder.
After finishing, he used his right hand with poison on it to pull up his pants and fix his belt.
Then, he used his left hand to pull the lever on the left side to flush.
And after washing his hands...
He used the handkerchief to dry up, and unknowingly wipe away the poison...
Before he brought the empty roll out of the bathroom.
This way, there would be no poison left in the bathroom.
But, on the body, wasn't poison found on the left hand?
Since he wasn't left-handed...
Why did he get poison on his left hand when he took the empty roll?
Come on, Inspector.
He had to use his right hand to open the door, so he used his left to hold the roll.
I see.
You're saying that, after throwing the empty roll away in the trash...
When he used his left hand with the poison on it to hold the hamburger, he would be poisoned.
Well, why don't we give it a try?
By actually going into the bathroom.
Wait, Agasa-san!
The most important question hasn't been answered!
Who among these three employees is responsible for the trick?
The most suspicious person should be you, the one who went in before the president.
Wait, isn't it strange?
While it's true that you could poison him that way...
The president only went in because of a stomach ache.
During the time that he was using the toilet paper, if no one went to buy the hamburger...
The murder wouldn't be possible.
And it was the president himself who requested a hamburger, right?
Too much of this is circumstantial...
That means the culprit must have rehearsed this a number of times.
President Dejima would have never dreamed...
That the coffee Imai-san made for him daily...
Had laxatives in it!
Laxatives?
Then...
Imai-san did...
He gradually increased the dosage to get him accustomed to the taste.
Afterwards, he just had to gauge the dosage and timing taken to get to the bathroom.
Then, the reason the president had been having stomach problems recently was...
Yeah, that's right.
And on the day the president decided to eat the burger...
He decided to carry out the murder.
The reason Imai-san brought the cookies together with the coffee...
Was to make him go to the bathroom quickly.
When someone eats something, starting from the transverse colon to the sigmoid colon...
There will be peristalsis.
It also means that when something enters the stomach...
They will easily get the urge to go to the bathroom.
For President Dejima, who uses laxatives regularly because of his hemorrhoids...
Even if the autopsy revealed laxatives were in his stomach, it wouldn't draw any attention.
And even if laxatives were found in the coffee...
We wouldn't find it suspicious due to his habits, right?
Then Imai-san placed the poison when he went into the toilet...
Hey, hey...
Didn't I go in before the president?
If I didn't go in to just urinate, wouldn't I have died?
You always use your left hand to hold your drink...
And if the restroom was close, then it fits that he would be going for #1.
If that wasn't the case, he could plan on passing you a wet tissue.
Then, he would just ask you to wipe your hands.
How did he know what I went in for?
It wasn't like he peeped into the bathroom.
From the bathroom's water sounds.
Water sounds?
Didn't President Dejima keep reminding you all to save water?
You wouldn't use full-flush if you went in just for that, would you?
Of course, the ones who went in after you and were chased out by the president...
Conan-kun and Ai-kun, wouldn't have had time to touch the empty roll.
All right, now we have to find the empty toilet paper roll President Dojima threw away somewhere.
Wait.
We usually throw it here.
Look, there it is.
Inspector...
All right, analyze this!
If there's poison on this, it should also be...
On the bag with the empty toilet roll...
And maybe the bottle used to house the poison.
In the triangular corner of the sink drain...
If it were me, after planting the poison in the bathroom...
I would hide it there while making the coffee in the kitchen.
It's dirty and has an unpleasant smell.
No one would dare touch it.
Even if I couldn't get rid of it without drawing attention...
Someone would definitely do it for me on accident.
And, unlike a trash can, it's easy to take it back and change the hiding place.
Inspector, in the triangular corner of sink drain...
We found a plastic bag that looks suspicious.
Oh, I see.
If we find fingerprints or traces of poison on and in this bag...
They should be there.
In order not miss a chance to kill him...
I always took it around with me.
The thought of murder came to me about twenty years ago.
Twenty years ago?
Yeah.
It was before you started here.
Remember, you may have heard that I left and went independent, but ended up back here?
It was then.
Come to think of it, I've heard the president mention that.
You went independent, but didn't have an eye for art and came back.
No eye for art, huh?
Is that what he said?
It's because the president colluded with the publishing companies.
He said not to give "that traitor" any work.
Really?
Yeah.
I heard it from my friends in the publishing company.
I was furious even back then, but there was nothing I could do.
I was in the kitchen then, thinking of how to do it...
I was planning how I would kill the president when he got back.
And then...
Akemi-chan came along with her parents and stood behind me.
"What's wrong? You look scared."
"Are you looking for something? Or maybe...
"Could you be hiding something?"
"Don't hide it in the triangular corner."
"Somebody might throw it away."
She said it with such a concerned face.
"Uncle is just a little tired," I told her.
She just smiled.
And, after that, Akemi-chan began to hide all of our work tools.
But, when I saw her innocent and smiling face...
Somehow, lost the desire to kill.
Then, why did you—now?
It was that time, when I discussed going independent with the president again.
He replied, "Your sense just isn't there anymore."
"If this were twenty years ago, it'd be a different story."
After I saw her for the first time in such a long time...
I tried not to let the president's harsh words bother me.
By "her"...
You mean the one who came to borrow the bathroom then, Akemi-chan?
Yeah, I was looking forward to it...
Her radiant smile.
I'll come again next week.
I'll bring my sister, too.
But, she never came.
I had thought her smile would be enough to quell my urge to kill him.
I guess I was just optimistic.
And so?
You found it, didn't you?
When you went in with the professor...
You found what my sister hid away.
Yeah.
Ever since your sister borrowed the bathroom...
President Dejima suddenly started stressing that they save water...
That's when I got it.
I thought that maybe something had been fixed onto the floating ball in the toilet's water tank...
Which caused the water to keep running.
I opened the tank to take a look at the back of the floating ball...
And found that a plastic bag had been taped to the bottom of it.
There were also traces of even older tape there.
Most likely, twenty years ago, your sister took Imai-san seriously when he said he was tired.
In order to let them get some rest, she decided to hide their pens and rulers.
And twenty years later...
When she came back, she decided to switch what she had taken before with what she had brought along.
Cassette tapes numbered one through twenty, sealed in a plastic bag.
Cassette tapes?
Yeah—there should be leads to those men in black on them.
Vital information that had to be well-hidden from their eyes.
Wait!
Don't tell me you're listening right now!?
Yeah, I've listened from eleven to fifteen, but...
There isn't anything at the beginning, so I haven't heard anything yet.
Don't! This isn't something you need to know!
If you probe any deeper, you will... Really...
Forgive me, Haibara.
This tape is something I shouldn't have heard.
It's a voice for you.
Listen.
For the 11-year-old Shiho...
Happy Birthday.
Mom...
Have you found someone that you like?
Mom's first love was...
Most likely, she felt that her own death was imminent, and asked Haibara's sister...
To pass along a message to her daughter...
Via these cassette tapes.
With her sister being watched so closely, she couldn't pass it right to Haibara, so...
She remembered her pranks in the past...
And decided to put it in the design firm's bathroom, in hopes of passing them along discreetly.
I'm happy for you, Haibara.
Mom...
Your mother was a real angel.
Sorry to have kept you waiting.
Well, I won't be requiring your help just yet, but...
Once they're in your sights, take them out with one shot...
Calvados.
Just when we thought we found the wedding ring, it's a kidnapping?
That old lady?
Where is that old lady right now?
Wedding Ring
Next time is a one-hour special!
Those who've been to Huis ten Bosch should take note.
A special gift.