Friendship! Romance! Mystery!
We try our best because we've made those promises!
Today, we have a 1-hour special!
A theme park sounds the bells of a case!
Perceiving the one and only truth,
The appearance of a child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
A wedding at Huis ten Bosch, huh?
Isn't that romantic?
I've always wanted to go to Huis Ten Bosch.
But, Sonoko...
Is it really OK for you to have invited us as well?
Won't we be troublesome?
No way—if I went alone, it'd be boring.
Not to mention, if something happens, you'll be there to help out, right?
"Something happens"?
Actually, there seem to have been a lot of problems prior to the wedding.
But, Shinya and I have been friends ever since I could walk...
Back then, everyone was saying that we should get married some day.
Even though that has nothing to do with the wedding...
I just hope he's happy.
I never knew you could be so kind, Sonoko.
Would anyone like something to drink?
Conan-kun, would you like something?
Excuse me!
What should I get?
Let's see...
May I have an oolong tea, please?
I'm terribly sorry, but this is the last can of oolong tea.
You can have it then, boy.
No...
You asked for it first, mister.
Really?
In that case, my apologies in advance.
Thank you very much.
Could I get a paper cup?
Here, little boy.
Thank you.
Sorry for being such an inconvenience!
It's nothing.
Thank you very much.
Coffee!
Takahashi Junichi (27)
Otaru Glass Artisan
Siblings on a vacation, huh?
You get along well.
No, we're not siblings...
But, why is it every time Ran goes out...
This four-eyed brat insists on coming along?
Sonoko-neechan...
It can't be helped.
Without me around, no one would cook for Conan-kun.
Hey, hey, Sonoko...
Geez, what else do you want?
I think I should be a little more honest today.
THE BRIDE OF HUIS TEN BOSCH
From the Shinkansen...
Oh, what a coincidence.
Are you all going to Huis ten Bosch as well?
Yes.
Are you going sightseeing by yourself?
Yeah...
But there's no need to look at me with such pity in your eyes.
In that case, how about we come along with you?
That'd be great!
To be able to go with such cute girls...
I'm warning you—her escorting fee is pretty high!
Joking, joking!
You scared me!
Uhm, how much longer does she plan to keep this up?
So this is Huis ten Bosh!
It's so great!
That's true.
his doesn't even look like it's in Japan.
Sonoko-san!
There you are.
Shinya-san...
It's been so long!
Thank you, for coming to my wedding.
It's nothing—I just happened to be taking a tour of the place is all.
This is my friend, Ran, and Conan-kun.
I'm Mouri Ran, nice to meet you.
Hello.
Katori Akane (26)
Bride
Ooga Shinya (24)
Groom
I'm Ooga Shinya.
This is my fiancee, Akane-san.
I'm Katori Akane—very pleased to meet you.
You're really pretty, you know!
Well, I guess I'll be going then.
Thanks a lot for coming with us.
That gentleman is?
That's Takahashi-san, who we met on the Shinkansen.
Hey, hey, we should get over there as soon as possible!
Look! Windmills!
And there's a bridge!
Look, look! Swans!
They're so graceful!
It feels like we're actually in the Netherlands.
I'd love to go there...
Now you see why we picked this place for our wedding.
Sonoko-san, when you get married, will you hold your wedding here at Huis ten Bosch as well?
I'm still a high school student!
But, already have somewhere in mind for that special someone.
Since when did that happen?
Europa Hotel
Father, this is Sonoko-san and her companions.
Ooga Tatsuya (55)
Ooga Financial Group Head
Shioya's Father
Ooga Masayo (52)
Shinya's Mother
So this is the young missis!
I must thank you for traveling so far for our son.
You've really grown...
I'm sure you must be tired, Sonoko-chan.
Not at all, Miss.
My youth prevents me from tiring so easily!
This is my good friend, Ran, and Conan-kun.
We're very humbled by your invitation.
Thank you very much.
Ooga Mika (29)
Shinya's Sister
It's fine.
The guests may be small in number, but that doesn't lead to a lonely wedding.
I'm told the bride's side of the family won't even be attending.
Now, now, Mika-san, not in front of the guests.
Ooga Tae (78)
Shinya's Grandmother
Young lady, I trust President Suzuki is doing well?
Yes, he's always playing golf.
You look as spirited as ever, Tae-obaasama.
Thank you.
Even now, I have yet to find an heir to the Ooga Financial Group that will cause me no worry.
That's what gives me the energy to work as hard as ever.
Hey, hey...
Carillon Symphonica
Hey, Ran, how would Makoto-san like these?
They're all right.
Does Shinichi already have one like this?
Geez...
Conan-kun, we're going!
All right!
Stad House
Have you just finished looking through the ornamental glass museum?
No, I just got here myself.
Sonoko, it's Tae-obaasan and Mika-san.
The old mistress is interested in antique glasswork.
Conan-kun...
Take a look at this.
It says it's from the 17th century.
Did glass even exist that long ago?
In Ancient Egypt, glass was manufactured as early as 3000 BC.
It was that early, huh?
Experts claim that glass-blowing began during the Roman Empire.
That includes glass windows as well.
I see.
You seem to be quite knowledgeable.
Oh, I work with glass in Otaru, a town in Hokkaido.
I requested time off from work in order to come see the glass utensils here in Nagasaki.
Is that so?
In fact, I'm also an admirer of glass — hence why I have a studio in the middle of this theme park.
How about this?
Why don't you join us for dinner tonight?
In the meantime, you can tell us about your making glass in Otaru.
If it's possible, it'd be my pleasure.
I'm Takahashi.
Dom Tower
So high...
All of those buildings look like toys from up here, don't they?
The scenery isn't bad either.
Aren't you scared?
Back then, I loved high places.
Look, seeing all those people down there bustling like ants...
Isn't it a wonderful feeling?
This is Takahashi-san, a glass artisan from Otaru.
I invited him along in order to ask him about glassmaking.
I'm Takahashi.
I'm Ooga.
Tomorrow is my son Shinya's wedding, which is why our entire family has gathered here tonight.
Mochida Hideo (53)
Ooga Bank Vice President
Shinya's Uncle
But I never thought it'd be Shinya-kun that would end up marrying first.
Mika-san, seems he got around to it before you.
That's only because I do not settle for less.
That's right, Takahashi-san...
Please join us for tomorrow's wedding.
But, I...
We'd love to have you.
In time, Shinya-kun will become the heir of the Ooga Financial Group.
As such, attending the wedding isn't going to do you any harm.
How can I?
I'm simply a glass worker...
Understood.
I cannot refuse such an invitation.
Thank you very much.
Akane-san...
Please wear this at the wedding tomorrow?
For generations, this ring has been worn by the wife of the Ooga's first-born son.
During the Meiji era, the first generation of the then-merchant Ooga family...
Brought this ring back from their first trip to Europe.
Thank you very much.
Thank you, Mother.
Aren't you rushing things a bit?
But, Mother, I wore this ring at my wedding as well...
After you passed it along to me.
That's because everyone thought of you as the perfect wife for Tatsuya.
You can always wait for the rest of the Ooga family to accept her before putting the ring on her.
Then, are you all saying Akane-san...
Still isn't acceptable as my wife?
Well, there won't be a problem with putting the ring on her finger at the wedding.
Looks like we really got invited to a high-class wedding...
How can this happen?
No wonder the wedding has to be held on the second day.
What's going on, Sonoko?
Didn't I already tell you?
Before the day of a wedding, the bickering never stops.
Say, Sonoko...
Why is the old lady so hard on Akane-san?
Because Shinya-san said that if he wasn't allowed to marry Akane-san...
He would leave and never return.
That's the only reason his family agreed to the wedding.
But Akane-san is such a nice person...
The family of a financial group has all sorts of problems.
Is it because a poor girl's marrying into this?
That, and since she is older than him by two years, which displeased the old lady.
No way!
I guess it can't be helped, though.
Hey, hey!
The fireworks show is starting.
Ran-neechan...
I'm going over there to get a better look.
Be careful, all right?
My, my...
At times like this, it's inconvenient to be small.
That's...
Akane-san and Takahashi-san...
Huis ten Bosch Palace
Akane-san...
You look beautiful!
Really, you look amazing!
Akane-san, after the wedding, be sure to toss me the bouquet!
Pretty please?
Hey, hey...
I'm not sure if I can toss it well enough, but...
I'll try.
There's only an hour before the wedding now.
My, so pretty!
Say, Shinya-san, tell me!
How's it feel looking at your bride?
Really... lovely.
Getting hot, getting hot...
Sonoko!
Shinya...
Gazing at the bride with your mouth open is embarrassing.
Wait in the lounge until the ceremony.
Akane-san...
I've come to act as the bride's father.
Thank you very much.
Huh?
Uncle stepped on the power, that's why.
Really?
Ah, this?
Sorry, sorry.
This picture...
Is it of Akane-san's parents?
Grandma...
It's fine, just a heart palpitation...
I should be fine with a little rest.
All right.
Just hang onto me.
You should rest in your room before the ceremony.
Tae-obaasama should be all right, shouldn't she?
If it's nothing serious, I guess so.
I'm fine now.
Huh?
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
Akane-san...
The ring...
Do you have it?
The ring is gone!
It's true!
That ring... I-It's missing!
What's this?
It's a picture of Akane-san.
This was...
A picture taken by Shinya-san in June when we came here to arrange the wedding.
What does it mean?
No idea.
If I cannot find that ring...
I...
Will never be forgiven...
No matter how much I apologize.
Akane-san, what're you saying?
That's just a silly ring!
At any rate, let's find that ring!
What now?
That ruby ring went missing!?
That—is it true?
Cancel it.
Cancel this wedding.
Without the ring, we'll go without a wedding.
Even now, you're still...
Now, now, now, mother...
Take a look around, Masayo-san.
Ever since this wedding was brought up, we've had nothing but misfortune.
All of it's the fault of that girl.
Now, even our treasured family heirloom, that ruby ring, is missing.
This is not Akane's fault!
And, what is she doing now?
Akane-san, I mean.
She said she wanted to be alone.
I saw her in the lounge.
Is that so?
She must have been hit hard by all this.
Everyone, the wedding is about to commence.
Has something happened?
The ruby ring has gone missing.
The one our ancestors brought back from Europe?
That ruby ring?
Until my sister came in with the others...
I'm certain it was still there.
Hold it, Shinya...
That's a strange choice of words.
Could you be implying that one of us took it?
When Sonoko-san and her friends came inside...
The ring—it was still there.
What that means is...
It had to be someone who came in afterward.
Where's that glass worker from Otaru, Takahashi?
After the ring went missing...
All that remained was this photo.
Shinya-san should be the one who took this photo.
And the only ones who could get their hands on it...
Are the members of the Ooga family, no?
That's not necessarily the case.
z Akane-san has that picture too, you know.
It's also possible that she took the ring herself...
Just so she could bring more misfortune to the Ooga family.
How can that be!?
I see how it is.
Being held under suspicion isn't comfortable for us either.
In that case, take a good look at each of our rooms.
But...
Should the ring not be found, the wedding will be canceled.
Any questions?
It's still missing, huh?
A ring that small could be anywhere.
Right, Ran?
What's wrong, Ran?
I'm worried about Akane-san and think I should go see how she's doing.
Ran...
Say, what did the old lady mean by "misfortune?
Ah, that?
She was almost killed recently.
It's happened twice now.
Madam, the brakes won't work!
Madam!
The second was on a sunny morning...
It happened while we were walking...
Well, she was saved at the last minute, but...
The missing ring today marks the third occurrence.
Grandma Tae can't take it anymore.
Akane-san, it's Ran.
Akane-san...
That's strange...
It had to be someone who came in and took it.
Sonoko!
Ran-neechan...
Akane-san's not in the lounge!
Her wedding dress was left there...
And now I can't find her anywhere!
Could what Mika-san said have been true?
That Akane-san...
Really took the ring herself.
Akane-san is absolutely not that kind of person!
At any rate, let's find her first!
But, what about the ring?
Without it, there won't be a wedding...
I've been thinking there was something strange about the hydrangea in the photo the whole time...
In flower language, they're "frivolous."
I bet there's some place that's connected with hydrangeas.
Shinya-san, what's going to happen to the wedding?
About that...
Akane-san is missing.
What?
The bride is?
Yes...
We'll split up and look for her right now.
I'll help as well.
I am very grateful.
I'll look for the ring.
Hydrangea...
Where should we start looking?
Akane-san!
Hydrangea...
Frivolous...
Music box...
Siebold...
Hold on a second...
I've heard of him before.
Siebold was the one who brought Japanese plants to Europe.
And I think one of them was...
The hydrangea.
The scientific name for one of the hydrangea was "Hydrangea otakusa."
Siebold named it after his nickname for his Japanese wife, Otaki-san.
So that's what it was, huh?
Hold on...
The meaning of Akane-san's photo...
Could it be...
Otakusa...
Otaki-san...
Taki...
Got it!
Geez...
Although, I'm not sure who hid it here...
I see!
The sculptures in this fountain are of Aphrodite and Psyche!
Ran-neechan!
Conan-kun!
I found the ring!
Really?
What's wrong?
Actually...
This is...
One of Akane-san's high heels!
Women don't walk in high heels without wearing both, right?
That means she must have been kidnapped...
Finding the ring was easy...
But a kidnapping?
There's only one here.
It likely fell to the bottom of the windmill.
That's...
What on earth happened?
That's what I'm trying to determine.
Whether Akane-san was violently taken away by someone or not.
Are you implying she was kidnapped!?
Don't be ridiculous.
She must have run away from here ages ago.
I already checked the Huis ten Bosch gates, and it doesn't seem anyone like her left.
According to Akane-san...
A while ago, one of her parents planned an arranged marriage for her.
I wonder if she's still talking to that man.
For all we know, she may have come here just to make a fool out of Shinya.
That's ridiculous!
I would know her the best!
It's just as Grandma said.
Shinya-san, you have absolutely no idea what's going on.
You don't even know who all she dated in the past, do you?
Wrong!
The man she was arranged to marry was a disciple of Akane-san's father.
That's something that happened ten years ago!
After he resigned and left ten years back, he was never heard from again.
Not even once!
( All right, let's stop talking about this for a moment.
We may have mentioned it to everyone, but ultimately, there may be no wedding at all.
If word about the outcome of this wedding does get out...
The reputation of the Ooga Group will be tarnished.
Maybe we'll have no choice but to rethink Shinya-kun's promotion.
Dear...
Thin hair...
About this length.
And she might be wearing a pink one-piece dress...
Could it be that one person?
Have you seen her before?,
Yeah, she went into the windmill house alone.
When was this, may I ask?
It was just after I came back from my lunch break...
So around 1:00.
Around 1:00...
If this is a kidnapping as you say...
Then you're implying that the culprit is among us.
Although we can't say so with certainty...
It's highly likely.
How dare you!
Do you even know what you' e saying?
My, it's all right, Mochida.
And, why have we all been gathered here?
Someone saw Akane-san at 1:00 this afternoon.
An employee here that sells maps watched her enter the windmill.
As such, would all of you please tell us where you were at 1:00?
Are you trying to check our alibis?
I was here sorting the checkbooks.
My wife and I stayed here.
At 1:00, I was in the Friesland sector of the park horseback riding.
Since the marriage was on its way to being called off...
I went to the main hall to drink some beer.
And you, Takahashi-san?
At 1:00?
I went back to the ornamental glass museum to look at the glasswork on display.
Just as I thought.
Can I see?
Sure, here you are.
If you want any of the pictures...
I can get a print-out for you at the front desk.
Got it!
Thank you.
Uncle Mochida, can I ask you something?
What is it?
Is there anything worth noting about Akane-san's family?
Her father is famous in Nagasaki for the glasswork store he owned.
He died ten years ago.
Anything else?
People say he committed suicide after being unable to pay back the loan he owed Ooga Bank.
Suicide?
Now, our elder madam owns that glass shop.
Since he had offered its mortgage to the bank as a collateral guarantee, she could get it.
Because she wanted his shop so badly, she reduced the repayment window for his loan and took it over.
Many people criticized her for it, but they were wrong.
We were only doing honest business.
Let's see...
Yes, I've seen this man before.
He was sitting and drinking beer alone over there.
It was about an hour ago.
Yeah, I remember this woman.
She seemed to really take to this place and even went up to the second floor.
Is that so?
Thank you very much.
Not here...
Gotta go a little further back.
Here it is—the place where the minute hand's pointing...
Right now, it's 3:05...
This means that, when he took the picture, it wasn't 1:00 but instead 2:05!
Since the face of the clock isn't numbered...
People would mistake the time as 1:00 just by the angle of the hands!
Assuming that person kidnapped Akane-san at the windmill around 1:00...
And didn't come here until 2:05...
Akane-san shouldn't be too far from here.
She's probably being held somewhere between the windmill house and the flower clock.
I have to find her as soon as possible.
So, you say you prefer high places, huh?
That's right.
Oh, are we going to go on that?
Yes.
Damn it...
Where is she?
Why does the melody sound so strange?
I got it!
The bells aren't chiming!
You don't want to get on?
Not at all!
I'm afraid of heights.
Just thinking about it gives me goosebumps.
You go on ahead.
And yet you're so young.
Akane-san!
Takahashi-san put Tae-obaasama...
Conan-kun?
That old lady!
Where is Tae-obaasan right now!?
She just...
Let's see...
She got on a hot air balloon with Takahashi-san just then.
Yeah, that's it.
That hot air balloon.
It looks like it's turning into a bird!
That's...
What's that?
A bomb!
There he is!
Almost too late!
What's that?
Don't touch that!
That device is set to detonate a bomb on the hot air balloon!
Just don't touch it!
What'd you say!?
It seems that both of you...
Ended up saving me from danger.
Thank goodness, Granny.
Akane-san...
Thank goodness you're safe.
Shinya-san, I'm sorry.
Takahashi-san, he...
Takahashi-san?
Akane-san, do you know him from somewhere?
What's going on here?
Why on earth was Grandma put in such a dangerous situation?
Sonoko...
Sonoko!
Allow me to explain everything.
Sonoko...
This series of events...
Was originally orchestrated by two apathetic individuals, but because it all happened at once, by chance...
It seemed like the work of a single perpetrator.
The first of which...
Tae-obaasama.
It was you.
Isn't that right?
The person who first opposed the wedding between Shinya-san and Akane-san was you.
Grandma!
It's fine, just a heart palpitation...
I should be fine with a little rest.
Isn't that right...
Mika-san?
What's going on?
Conan-kun, give it to them.
Yes!
Akane-san...
You found it!
This...
Thank you!
Conan-kun?
Where did you find it?
There's a fountain in Central Square, right?
It was found around there.
If the ring had been hidden nearby, someone may have come across it during our search.
Tae-obaasama told you that.
Isn't that why you hid it at the fountain?
Mika-san.
It's as you say...
Then...
What could the picture of the hydrangea flowers possibly mean?
I was deceived by the picture as well.
At first, because it said "frivolous" in flower language...
I thought the picture was attempting to relay that Akane-san had been unfaithful.
But, that picture—it has another meaning.
Another meaning?
The water in that fountain...
Flows like a waterfall, doesn't it?
Yeah.
One of the more minor hydrangea flowers was named "Hydrangea otakusa."
This name was assigned by Siebold.
"Otakusa" was his nickname for his wife, Otaki-san.
Otakusa, Otaki-san, "Taki" (waterfall), see?
So that's it!
You already knew, didn't you?
Yeah.
While the picture at first seemed to be telling us something was wrong with Akane-san...
It was really just telling us the secret location of the ring.
Now you understand, right?
That the culprits responsible for hiding the ring are...
Grandma and Mika-san.
But, Akane-san's kidnapping...
That was a total coincidence.
Akane-san felt responsible for losing the ring...
And thought about running away from her wedding to Shinya-san.
She left on her own from there.
Would you tell us what happened next...
Akane-san?
After I left the room...
I happened to see Takahashi-san...
And decided to quietly follow him...
Takahashi-san!
What are you...
I intend to teach that old woman a lesson.
Miss, have you forgotten?
That old bitch...
She's the reason your father's dead!
Furthermore, the person who stole your ring is the one named "Mika."
It can't be...
Of course, it was the old woman that masterminded it.
Miss...
Please follow me.
Afterward...
Before I was rescued by Conan-kun...
I was being held in the Carillon Symphonica.
Then, that person is...
Right, the person who mentioned Grandma earlier is Akane-san's previous fiancé.
I'm sorry for hiding it from you all this time...
Yesterday, when I saw Takahashi-san with Sonoko-san at the station...
I was really shocked.
It'd been ten years already.
Akane-san, you met with Takahashi-san last night, right?
When I asked him why he came here...
He said that his reason for coming was just to see the wedding.
But...
I wasn't sure if that was the only reason.
Takahashi-san, open your eyes and witness what's happening.
How long do you plan on laying there?
How did you know?
I thought it was strange from the beginning.
Because even though you claimed you were from Otaru...
When you saw Akane-san's wedding dress...
You were speaking the Nagasaki dialect.
"My, so pretty."
The one who sabotaged the brakes in Grandma's car...
And the one who pushed the rock from above...
Was you, right?
Yeah, that's right.
Because my master...
Akane's father, was...
Driven to death by this old woman!
Master, because of Ooga Bank's sudden demand for the loan repayment...
Felt he had nowhere else to go, and committed suicide!
That painful expression on my master's face...
I'll never forget it!
Master!
How could you be so down on yourself!?
Leaving Akane-san behind like this...
All because some old woman wanted to use his glass factory to indulge in some hobby of hers!
Prior to that incident, orders from several major clients had been decreasing significantly.
When Master and I went to ask one of our wholesalers...
He admitted he had no choice, saying that Ooga Bank had pressured him to reduce his orders.
It wasn't like that!
Father...
Mother loved Katori-san's glasswork...
So of course she hoped he would continue.
It got to a point where she wanted to help him run his business.
But, Katori-san's pride as an artisan would never allow it.
'When it comes to my glass, I will only sell to those who appreciate its worth."
On that principle, the only glass products he produced were elaborate ornaments.
Of course, the prices were extremely high...
But they were high-quality pieces of art.
The operation costs weren't profitable.
Not to mention that his debts had continued to build.
In the end...
We gave him an extra day to pay us back...
And then two days became a week, and one week became two.
We were only a small bank.
We couldn't drag it on for...
That's a lie!
I'm not lying!
I'm not lying, Takahashi-kun...
You're lying!
Master was never that weak of a person!
He always woke up early, to pour blood, sweat, and tears into his work from dawn until dusk...
His hands would teach a novice like me to...
The reason Grandma opposed the marriage to Akane-san...
Was because of the rash decision she'd made in the past that indirectly caused her father's death.
That's why she couldn't bring herself to face Akane-san.
And because of this, Akane-san came to know Takahashi-san planned to avenge her father.
So she had to be locked away.
I know what he has done is unforgivable...
But, please, could you forgive Takahashi-san?
Miss...
Grandma...
I'm begging you as well.
Grandma!
President!
I know you were to play the bride's father, Mochida...
But, despite being young, how about we let Takahashi-san do it instead?
Of course!
I approve!
Grandma!
Then...
Are you allowing them to get married?
Now that the ring's here, I couldn't disapprove even if I wanted, could I?
That's wonderful!
Grandma intended to do this from the beginning, didn't she?
Once the ring was found, the two people could marry one another.
How did you know?
The sculptures on that fountain are of Aphrodite and Psyche.
Aphrodite was jealous of her own son, Cupid, for falling in love with Psyche...
So she set up a series of trials to test Psyche.
But, in the end, Psyche passed every test, and earned Aphrodite's approval.
The fountain depicts that final scene.
Grandma had her hide the ring there...
Only because she had heard of the Greek myth.
Using the picture of the hydrangea, she tried to hint at the connection between Siebold and "taki."
Isn't that right, Grandma?
It's those horizontally-written foreign symbols—who knows what they say?
Grandma, really...
Just blame everything on me, will you?
I do.
Do you vow to love one another?
It should've been me getting ready to marry Makoto-san!
Sonoko...
Ran got it!
Fate just isn't on my side.