Friendship! Romance! Mystery!
We try our best because we've made those promises!
In the bright convenience store we're known to frequent...
Something happens in one of its dark corners!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Yes, this is the Mouri...
Oh, Conan-kun.
Where'd you go? It's already so late...
You're staying at Professor Agasa's house tonight?
Yeah.
After hearing that I caused Haibara's cold to worsen...
I decided to stay over and help nurse her until she's better.
That's all right, but...
What about a change of clothes, and your school things?
That won't be a problem.
I brought everything with me.
Not to mention that we'll be on winter break soon.
Do you mind, Ran-neechan?
Take good care of her.
Thank you, Ran-neechan.
Bye.
There's no need for you to stay here as well, Shinichi.
Isn't it just caring for Ai-kun?
I'll be fine by myself.
It's not that.
It just seems that, as of late...
There have been more and more suspicious people around us.
I had a premonition that has me thinking something's going to happen here...
THE CONVENIENCE STORE TRAP
(PART ONE)
Who are you ?
Jodie-sensei!
You look really tired.
Are you all right?
Oh, yes.
Well, I can imagine the headache you're getting from these naughty Japanese kids.
Don't fret over it alone.
No, no!
Everyone is a good student.
To think I have to say "goodbye" to them so soon...
I cannot help but feel very, very sad.
Jodie-sensei is resigning?
It can't be!
Due to some extenuating family problems back home...
She will be officially leaving for America at the end of this month.
What could they be?
Those family problems.
No idea...
Even though it has only been for a short while...
To be able to learn together with all of you, it made me very, very happy.
And while I'm sure there will be some difficulties in your future...
I am confident that you all will be able to overcome them.
Good luck.
Give it your all.
S-Sensei...
Hey, Jodie-sensei!
You can tell us now, right?
Tell you about what?
The reason that you're resigning.
Exactly what are these "family problems"?
Oh, that was a lie!
Actually...
I have looked all over...
For a very, very important treasure map.
And I finally found it...
Or so I think!
A treasure map?
Surely, she doesn't mean her first love?
But, if that were the case, she wouldn't say it was a map - she'd just say she found the treasure...
Ah, wait, Sensei!
We can't get it with just that...
No, no - secret!
I can't tell you.
A secret makes a woman, woman!
OK...
But, it's a real pity...
I wanted him to take Sensei's classes as well.
Him?
Oh, you mean Shin-ichi?
Let him be.
The type of guy that buries himself in solving cases while leaving his wife alone...
Would never be able to appreciate the merits of Jodie-sensei's lessons!
And exactly how long is he planning to take solving this one case?
He should just give up and come back already.
No, that's just impossible.
He's not the type to give up half-way.
Because...
He wants to look good.
That's what I really, really, really like about him!
I love it!
That's enough!
All I said was that he's a stubborn person who likes to look good!
And even if he doesn't come back, I'll...
Speaking of not coming back...
Is Cool Kid back?
The little one with the glasses?
As of late, he's there no matter when I call Doctor Agasa's house.
What? He ran away from home?
He doesn't know what's good for him - next time I see that little...
It's not like that. He's nursing Ai-chan.
He said that, since it was his fault her cold worsened...
He won't be back until she recovers.
He even took a change of clothes.
I guess that little brat has good points, too...
Forgive me for that.
I know!
Why don't we have a party at Sensei's apartment right now?
So sudden...
Party?
It'll be a farewell party for Jodie-sensei.
Let's get some snacks and juice from the convenience store.
That's a great idea!
How about it, Sensei?
Then, let's go to the convenience store in front of the station.
The one where Aya-chan is working part-time, right?
Was there such a student?
She was our middle school classmate.
She's a really cheerful girl - you'll definitely like her.
Thank you for your patronage.
Welcome!
Excuse me.
Is there a girl by the name of Nanakawa Aya working here, by any chance?
Yeah...
She s back there with the store manager.
How many times do I have to tell you so that you'll understand?
Jeez...
We don't have enough manpower for peak hours as it is.
I don't have any choice but to hire someone new to replace you.
How could you...
What happened, Aya?
Ran...
Aya?
What happened, Aya?
And who are you all?
Just friends.
Fri-en-ds!
I am a high school teacher.
Has something happened?
It's really nothing much.
It's just that the money in the register and the stock in the inventory aren't lining up.
And it only happens to be a problem on Aya-kun's shift when she closes the store.
That's mean!
How could you accuse Aya of being at fault based solely on that?
It could just be one of the customers shoplifting.
After all, Aya's told us that there are usually a lot of customers in the morning and at night.
It must be then!
Yeah.
That's what I thought as well.
That's exactly why, when I refurbished the store...
I installed four separate security cameras.
And, despite never taking my eyes off them...
No such customer ever showed.
Then, it has to be a thief.
I thought of that, too.
That's why I parked my car in front of the store last night and kept watch the whole time.
But the only one who came out was...
Aya-kun, when she closed the shutter after cleaning up.
From that moment until it was time to open the store, no one came.
And, after I opened the store and checked the inventory, I found it was off once again.
The only possibility is that Aya-kun is taking them.
I didn't take them!
By the way...
What types of merchandise were taken?
There were a lot.
Game software, DVDs, CDs...
Bento boxes, onigiri, mineral water, Oolong tea, cola...
As well as a lot of chocolate, sweets, and snacks.
It's easy to picture a group of young people together...
Playing games while listening to music or watching DVDs, and enjoying themselves to their hearts' content.
I guess so.
But, supposing the culprit really is Aya...
Wouldn't she be captured on the security cameras?
The security cameras automatically stop recording after closing hours.
The electricity bill isn't a small one.
Then, the reason the light here is unlit...
Yeah, it's to save electricity and make up for losses.
The only ones who come back here to borrow this bathroom are our regulars...
So it's all right if it's a little dark.
Hey, Aya...
Did you notice any suspicious customers?
I wouldn't say they're "suspicious," but...
Some of the customers did catch my attention.
Three of them.
Are there any clues?
What sort of people are they?
All three of them come to borrow the bathroom often.
Please, give us the details.
One of them looks like a university student.
He comes by occasionally to read the game magazines until closing time.
A game maniac, huh?
But that person has never bought a game at our store before.
All he buys are cup noodles and instant food.
He's also a really selfish person, always cutting to the front of the checkout line.
The second one looks like a salaryman.
He's rather timid and especially polite.
Especially polite?
His head is always bowed.
When the aforementioned university student cuts in line...
He just lets him pay first, without getting angry.
Even when going to the bathroom, he will say, "I'm not in a hurry, you can go first."
The things he buys are toothbrush sets, dry batteries, shavers, and towels.
Those are all things you would take on a trip, right?
The third person is a stubborn and thrifty old lady.
Ah, I know that old lady too.
She always bargains with me over the bento boxes that have nearly expired.
She's always insisting that we should learn from the other stores' prices.
But that old lady's not a bad person...
I see her switching off lights that aren't in use.
She even mentioned that adjusting the store to a certain temperature would save on the electricity bills.
Well, usually, after talking with me for a while, she'll end up leaving without buying anything.
That means all three are suspicious.
Why?
Because...
That game maniac student may want to buy the games he's reading strategies for, but can't afford them.
The salaryman may like to travel and prefer to take snacks along.
The old lady may not have bothered to buy anything, but surely there's some bento she wants to eat.
All three of them are possible culprits.
I think it's best to suspect Aya-kun before moving on to our customers.
Didn't I tell you?
Aya is not the kind of person who would do something like this!
Then, explain it to me!
Why it is that, right after I scolded Aya-kun in this very spot just last month, the inventory stopped disappearing?
Is that true?
Yeah.
Nothing appeared to have been missing this month.
I actually intended to end surveillance after closing the store last night.
And just as I thought Aya-kun had reflected on her misdeeds...
When I came to the store this morning...
Quite a bit of the merchandise was missing yet again.
It seems her urge to steal could not be suppressed any longer.
Now...
Hurry and apologize, and I'll forgive you this time.
Otherwise, you're fired.
Hey, Ran...
This situation doesn't look good.
Yeah...
That's right!
Why don't we discuss it with Shinichi-kun?
If it's him, he'll be able to solve this mystery in no time...
But, I...
I don't know Shinichi's phone number...
The number doesn't show whenever he calls.
Sonoko, what about you?
Any brainwaves?
I wouldn't be saying this if I had...
Then, how about we try Conan-kun?
Doesn't that kid often notice interesting things?
Right...
Even though, it's a bit embarrassing...
To resort to asking that bespectacled brat.
Let's see, Conan-kun's at the professor's house, so...
Jodie-sensei!
Relying on someone else without exerting any effort of your own...
It's just not right.
There are only a few of us here.
Let's think of something to help her.
But...
I honestly didn't take anything!
Are you still saying that?
Because the one you rely on most can disappear, at any time.
All right, hurry up and confess!
You are the culprit, right?
This is a misunderstanding, Manager.
I really didn't take any merchandise from the store!
If Conan-kun were here, he'd definitely notice something...
Can we really not make the call, Sensei?
No, no!
Cool Kid is busy caring for Ai-chan right now.
We mustn't disturb him, right?
Even if that's true...
But, if this goes on, Aya will...
It'll be fine!
We don't need to ask for that brat's help.
Allow the Deduction Queen, Sonoko-sama, to solve it for you in the blink of an eye!
Ah, really?
Let's begin with an overview of the facts.
Why is it the money in the register and the inventory of the store don't match up?
And, in the end, for some unknown reason...
The amount is always short whenever Aya is in charge of cleaning and closing the store.
Naturally, the manager has suspected Aya of taking them.
But our middle-school classmate, Aya, is a good girl...
As such, we're investigating in order to name someone else as the culprit.
No problems so far, I hope?
There are three customers that Aya found suspicious, right?
One is a game maniac...
He looks like he's in university.
Another is a rather timid but very polite man that appears to be a salaryman.
And the last one is...
A stubborn old lady.
Let's see...
What the three of them often buy here are...
The game maniac only buys cup noodles and instant food...
The salaryman buys toothbrush sets, dry batteries, shavers, and towels as if he were going on a trip.
And for the old lady - nothing.
She only talks with the others in the store, without buying anything.
Those three all seem suspicious but also not suspicious at the same time...
Hey, could it be a shoplifter or a genuine thief?
Didn't I already say that was impossible?
The manager already installed security cameras, didn't he?
A thief would have "no chance."
It's impossible.
The problem is that, in the past, after the manager suspected and scolded her...
The inventory stopped disappearing.
But, one month later - yesterday...
It was once again her turn to mind the store, and again a lot of the inventory disappeared.
Come to think of it, Aya...
Does love snacks and juice, right?
She's also quite keen on games...
Hey!
Weren't we trying to prove that Aya is innocent?
I know...
Think hard...
At this point, if it was Shinichi...
If it was Shinichi...
The clues are what differ from the expected.
Whenever there's a case, there's always something that differs from the norm.
First of all, you have to find those points through careful observation.
Even though it may seem like something anyone could manage...
And even if it's something trivial that occurs routinely...
It's relevant so long as it's unusual.
Nothing is more essential than those small changes in the norm.
Something that differs from the expected...
That's right, things only disappear on days when Aya is on closing duty...
Do you do anything special on the days you're on closing duty, Aya?
Nothing really...
I just clean the store.
Manager, did you notice anything?
No, nothing in particular...
It could be something trivial - anything will do!
Uhm...
Even though it's nothing big...
What is it?
The store is especially clean only on the days Aya-chan is on closing duty.
Look.
She neatly arranges the boxes that arrive before the store closes.
The other store assistants and I...
Always leave the arrangement of the boxes to the one who comes in the next morning, and head home.
You do the same as well, don't you, Manager?
You were planning to atone for your misdeeds, weren't you?
I won't be taken in by that.
That's not...
It's the same for the bento boxes, isn't it?
The ones that go missing are those near their expiration dates.
You thought it wouldn't matter since they would be thrown away soon anyway, right?
But a thief's a thief.
What do you say we let the police look into this?
Wait!
You're getting the police!?
Oh, are you saying...
That the lot of you can find them for me?
The real culprit.
Shi-
Shinichi...
Shinichi!
Ran?
My imagination?
Oh, Shinichi!
Where'd you go?
Ah, had something to do.
Where's Haibara?
I don't see her around.
Ai-kun is still holed up in her room.
Hey, hey...
She still hasn't recovered from her cold, has she?
It's all right.
I switched the heater on for her.
And, I think it's better to leave her alone...
She's probably listening to those tapes again.
Shiho, what you're doing now...
Mom will approve of whatever you choose.
I'll be rooting for you, so you have to do your best!
Well, until next time, on your 19th birthday!
Bye, bye...
See you...
Ah, and...
Welcome!
Excuse me!
Toilet!
Toilet! Toilet!
Toilet! Toilet! Toilet!
The line has grown pretty long.
Wow...
There are more and more people coming.
Yeah, seems so.
Even the bathroom line is crowded.
Come to think of it, Aya mentioned it before...
Those three suspicious customers borrowed the bathroom often as well.
At any rate, this can wait until after we've served these customers.
Until then, head up the cash register.
Yes...
If you're not buying anything, could you get out?
But...
You're a hindrance to my business.
Now...
Yes, yes, yes.
Wait...
If this goes on...
Aya will...
Aya-chan!
Ran, what should we do?
Shinichi...
What exactly should we do?
Shinichi!
When you have eliminated the impossible, whatever remains, however improbable...
Must be the truth.
Everyone, hurry!
Run!
I don't mind sharing my deduction, but...
If I'm wrong...
Or if it isn't completely accurate...
If you think your deduction's correct...
Go try it out.
"Try it out"?
THE CONVENIENCE STORE TRAP
(PART TWO)
Convenience Store Bathroom
Next time is the last Conan episode of the year.
Following that will be a special!
Please look forward to Conan's return on January 5th!