Friendship! Romance! Mystery!
We try our best because we've made those promises!
The strange case Ran encountered at the convenience store...
An outstanding deduction to save her friend!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
THE CONVENIENCE STORE TRAP
(PART TWO)
Who are you ?
Sensei!
Jodie-sensei!
Are you all right, Sensei?
Did you think of something?
You seem to be deep in thought...
No idea.
Nothing at all.
What happened?
Ah, it's just that this is the first time we've seen your face without glasses.
Right?
The first time?
But, those glasses...
They look really old.
Oh, yes.
This is something that's very precious to me...
The only trace left in this world of a very, very important person.
That's why I wear them.
A very important person?
Maybe a remembrance of an ex-boyfriend or something?
Aside from that...
Have you all understood this case yet?
Not at all...
It stopped-
The delivery truck?
Come to think of it...
That store assistant said it before, right?
Remember, on the days Aya is on closing duty...
She neatly arranges the boxes that arrive before leaving.
That's right, they did mention something like that...
So, how is that connected to the case?
About that...
How is it connected...
Jeez...
You got my hopes up.
But...
Right...
We brought the goods you ordered.
That was fast.
Well, I'll leave them in the passageway in front of the bathroom as usual.
Ah, wait...
There are still customers waiting to use the bathroom, so it's not a good time...
Really?
Then, we'll bring them around again later.
We still have deliveries to a few other places.
We'll drop by again after we hit those.
I apologize.
The items can't be left outside of it.
If the goods are left there, the customers can't get out...
All right, we'll be back later.
Sorry about that.
Thank you.
On the days Aya's on closing duty, she arranges the boxes in the bathroom passageway...
Hey, what was it?
That famous line by Holmes...
Shinichi often recites it with an arrogant expression on his face.
If the impossible is something, and something...
When you have eliminated the impossible...
When you have eliminated the impossible,
whatever remains,
however improbable,
must be the truth.
When you have eliminated the impossible, whatever remains, however improbable...
Must be the truth.
When you have eliminated the impossible,
whatever remains, however improbable,
must be the truth.
Was that the line?
What? What?
Could it be that Ran just got something?
Jeez...
Don't be giving me false hope.
I've got it...
I think I have it, but...
Yikes!
It's already past 9:00 PM.
I have to call my mom.
The store's also cleared out a bit.
Aya-kun...
Manager...
Well, isn't it about time you confessed?
But I really didn't do anything...
It looks like I'll have to leave this to the police, huh?
That's...
I don't mind sharing my deduction, but...
If I'm wrong...
Or if it isn't completely accurate...
I'll be inviting even more trouble for Aya...
If it were him in this situation...
"Cannot display"...
Hello?
Hey, Ran.
How are you?
Shi-
Shi- Shinichi...
Sorry, Ran.
It's not a big deal, but...
There's something I'd like to ask you.
Shinichi...
Shinichi!
What?
Is that Shinichi-kun calling?
Hey, what happened?
Uhm, see...
My friend's in a pinch right now...
You know her too, Shinichi - it's Aya-chan from middle school.
Yeah. Nanakawa, right?
At the convenience store where she's working part-time, the inventory keeps disappearing.
And it's only on the days Aya's on cleaning and closing duty.
The manager is suspecting her of taking it all...
He threatened to call the police if she didn't confess.
The security cameras didn't record anyone shoplifting...
Items were still disappearing even while the manager was keeping watch out front after closing time.
That's why the manager thinks Aya is the culprit...
Say, what sort of items disappeared?
Game software, CDs, DVDs, beverages, bento boxes, sweets, and snacks.
Oh, and, Aya said that, among the customers, three of them are suspicious.
What types of people are those three?
The first one reads game magazines in the store right until closing time.
He looks like a university student...
And all that he buys are cup noodles and instant food.
Second is someone who often lets people ahead of him in line - a timid but especially polite salaryman.
What he buys are things like toothbrush sets, shavers, dry batteries, and towels.
The last one is a stubborn old lady that likes to bargain over bento boxes that have nearly expired.
It seems she never buys anything from this store.
And then?
The common link between those three is that they all often borrow the bathroom.
And, one month ago, after Aya was scolded by the manager outside the bathroom...
The items stopped disappearing.
But last night, just one month later - again on Aya's day - they disappeared once more.
I see.
So it isn't unreasonable to suspect Nanakawa.
Hey, don't make it sound as though, you're speaking of a stranger!
Well, there should be something else, right?
Something Nanakawa does while on cleaning duty that the other store assistants fail to do.
The other assistants leave the boxes that arrive before closing in the bathroom passageway, and head home...
But Aya always arranges them properly before closing the store.
Actually, if the security cameras were still working at that time...
We could prove Aya's innocence.
Unfortunately, the manager only has it record during operating hours.
Say...
Would the stolen bento boxes happen to be...
Just the ones that have nearly expired?
How'd you know?
Just as I thought.
The culprit is likely not a very bad person.
What? You know who the culprit is?
Yeah.
The culprit is most likely...
Wait a minute, Shinichi!
I also tried to reason it out on my own...
Don't laugh, and listen, please?
Sure...
Ran...
Let me hear it.
Your deduction.
That is my deduction.
I considered a lot of things, but...
If it's not a shoplifter, nor an actual thief, nor Aya...
Even if it's unbelievable, this is all there is...
How is it? Am I right?
Hey, didn't I ask you not to laugh?
Sorry.
I'm not laughing at your deduction.
It's just that, even though you managed to deduce that much, I can only imagine your troubled face.
I just find it really funny.
Then, you mean, my deduction's right?
Well, who knows?
What's that about?
Stop keeping me in suspense and tell me!
Unlike a certain someone, I'm not a famous detective who's always brimming with confidence.
Idiot.
Even detectives are normal humans.
They aren't almighty gods.
As a detective presenting his deductions...
There are times when he feels uneasy about it as well.
He worries if maybe he overlooked something, and whether there are any other possibilities that remain.
That's why, when one's deduction hits the bull's-eye, it's the greatest feeling in the world.
I was only wondering if I should rob you of that sense of achievement.
Shinichi...
Your husband - he's always saying profound things, as always.
If you think your deduction's correct...
Go try it out.
"Try it out"?
It should be all right, Ran.
There's a simple method you can use to unmask the culprit in front of everyone.
Unmask the culprit?
If you were the culprit, Ran...
What circumstances would make it most difficult for you?
If I were the culprit?
Ran...
Mouri-san?
Excuse me.
I'd like to borrow the bathroom.
Sure.
Ran...
Where's Ran?
The bathroom...
The bathroom?
Fire!
Everybody, hurry! Run!
You'll be burned alive if you don't hurry!
Hey!
Stop this now, I tell you, or it'll affect my business!
Hey, you!
Exactly what were you intending to...
It can't be...
Why?
Who is he?
What's going on?
As expected, it was you...
The especially polite salaryman customer.
Don't tell me, this man...
Yeah, that's right.
The one who stole from the store at night...
And gave Aya such a hard time-the culprit is...
This person!
I kept watch over the front of the store all last night...
But I didn't see this person sneaking in.
Of course you didn't see him.
Because this person...
Has been living in the ceiling of this store's bathroom!
That's unbelievable...
It may be unbelievable, but...
This is the truth!
See, after Aya closed the store...
He would come out of the bathroom ceiling and go into the store itself.
He would then take the beverages and food needed to sustain himself.
But...
Aya-kun is only on closing duty two, three days a week - if he did that every day...
If he takes a certain amount at a time...
He'll have enough to last him two or three days.
But why did he steal the game software and CDs?
Maybe, he secretly exits the store occasionally...
And sells them for haircuts and baths.
If he didn't, his hair would grow long and he'd get more and more dirty with time...
To the point he'd never be able to come down from the ceiling again.
But wait, is it really possible to come and go from the bathroom without an employee or customer noticing?
If he suddenly came out of the bathroom...
Or went in and never came out...
Everyone would get suspicious immediately.
That's fine...
For an excessively polite and cautious person.
See, if he let people take their turn in the bathroom before him...
And kept going until he was last in line...
No one would see him enter the bathroom...
And it wouldn't matter if he never came out.
Oh, I see.
If he can get into the bathroom just before it gets crowded...
And get back into the store during the more bustling times...
He could mingle with the other customers and avoid suspicion.
If he lives in the ceiling...
e would know the times that the bathroom is at its busiest.
Given that the store would obvious y be busy when the bathroom is...
Not even the store assistants would remember who entered and left here.
What about the toothbrush set, shavers, dry batteries, and towels that he buys?
The batteries are...
For the flashlight he uses when searching for items in the dark.
The others are simply daily necessities.
There's a mirror and soap in the bathroom already.
Manager!
It's just as that girl said...
One of the panels in the ceiling has been dislodged.
What'd you say!?
Then, he really was hiding in the ceiling.
It's full of garbage, Manager...
This is bad!
What exactly is this about?
And why is it that it's only when Aya-kun's on closing duty that...
That's because Aya is very conscientious with her work.
It's the boxes of goods placed in the passageway here.
All of the other assistants leave them lying around, which prevented him from getting through, but...
Aya arranges them neatly on both sides.
That's how the culprit could come out of the bathroom in the middle of the night.
But Ran, he only has to shift the boxes in order to get through.
You think so too?
I thought that part was hard to justify as well.
Wait...
While it's true he could just shift the boxes to get through...
If the store assistants noticed the boxes had been moved...
They would begin to suspect someone had come through the passageway...
And turn their suspicions on the bathroom.
That guy was just afraid they'd discover his hiding place.
Due to this psychological effect, he didn't pass through.
That's how it is.
That's right.
I see...
But I still don't understand...
Why did you stop stealing for an entire month?
Well, you may have relied on selling those games and CDs to get by, but...
f you hadn't stopped at that time, my suspicion of Aya-kun would've grown even deeper.
That's because...
This man isn't really a bad person!
He likely heard from the ceiling that Aya was being scolded due to his actions...
And decided to stop.
I see - so that's what happened.
He decided to steal the bento boxes that were about to expire...
In order to minimize losses to the store.
But...
A thief is a thief!
To have put Aya through all this...
Ran! Wait!
Causing Aya so much anguish...
I... I will never forgive you!
My most sincere apologies!
I was laid off by my last employer three months ago...
And chased out of my apartment!
Starving, I staggered into this store...
But, I didn't have enough money to buy anything.
Just as I was spacing out in the bathroom, the lights suddenly cut out.
I tried to get out, but couldn't since the door was locked.
And then, just as my eyes adjusted to the darkness...
I saw this mountain of food!
And so, you stole from my store.
Yes...
I thought that, with this much, a little wouldn't matter...
This isn't a joke!
Do you have any idea how much we have to sell in order to earn all of that back!?
I'm sorry...
At any rate, you'll be paying back every bit of it.
But even if I wanted to, I don't have any at all to give you...
I'll have you work here.
But, of course, you won't get any pay at the onset.
You're hiring me?
Even after all of this trouble I've given you...
I started this store from scratch as well, so it's not that I don't understand how you feel.
Manager...
Thank you very much.
Just be sure to work hard!
Yes!
Uhm, sorry to spoil the moment, but...
Could you please give a proper apology to Aya?
Both of you!
Forgive me.
I'm sorry.
Really...
I'm sorry!
That's great, Aya.
Thank goodness, thank goodness.
Thank you, Ran, Sonoko!
This is nothing.
You just have to leave it to Sonoko-sama!
Hey, Lady Detective!
Sorry, Shinichi.
What did you want to talk about?
Well, it's not a big deal, but...
Have you been to my house recently?
I haven't. Why?
Nothing.
It's fine, then.
Well, see you.
Wait, Shinichi!
It isn't Ran, huh?
That's how it is - I'll be staying over at Sensei's house tonight.
Have dinner downstairs at Poirot, all right, Dad?
See you.
Jeez...
It was supposed to be Sensei's farewell party...
But she's drunk and asleep.
She's probably at ease now, since she gets to finally return home after so long.
Huh? Where are you going?
Just the bathroom.
Once again...
I was saved by him once again.
It's mortifying.
What?
A photograph?
Why?