Partner, there's something different about tonight.
Yeah...
It's a two and a half hour special episode.
Ta-da!
Hi!
Happy New Year!
All of us at Detective Conan will keep doing our best!
So the TV show, the movies, and Shounen Sunday...
And me, Suzuki Sonoko-chan...
Then, me too, Mouri Ran...
Hey, hey, what're you guys doing?
Cheer us on!
We just missed it!
An eerie atmosphere, two mysterious people...
The net closes in on Conan and Haibara.
There's no looking back when your life's in danger.
A breathtaking two and a half hours is about to begin!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
There's a dream I keep having lately, one where you suddenly leave
Saying nothing to me as I hang my head...
You have your hands gripped into fists inside your pockets
Like flowers, who compete with their colors...
Melancholic rain just makes you glow even brighter
Until we reach that tender place that I once promised you
We just keep on running, even now
Until we reach the season when your colors glow brightly
Days when we don't meet just make our love stronger, and one day...
Until we reach that tender place that I once promised you
Adding an exit to the path we're on just turns it into a maze
And even if we have to follow unmarked roads...
Our faith in each other will guide us, until we reach that tender place...
An out-of-season Halloween party?
What month do they think it is?
Isn't Halloween on October 31st?
That's why it says so, right?
That it's "out-of-season".
And?
What's it say in the invitation?
Well, in the letter...
"To incompetent detective Mouri Kogoro...
"On the night of the coming full moon, you are invited...
"For an evening aboard a blood-soaked party boat.
"Of course, regardless as to whether you are present or absent...
"The sad lamb who heads to the slaughter will seal its own fate...
"And the sinners shall revel in its death throes."
So it's a challenge to the Great Detective Mouri Kogoro, is it?
Who on earth sent such a thing?
I wonder if it's a foreigner?
There's alphabet writing here.
V-E-R-M-O-U-T-H...
Vermouth?
Sorry, Ran-kun, I've never heard of a name like that.
I see...
I was just wondering who could've sent this letter.
And?
Is Mouri-kun going?
To this party.
It's tomorrow, isn't it?
They say a true Tokyoite can't just turn down a fight.
Dad's having Sonoko do his makeup, and...
He's trying to decide what to go as.
Makeup?
It was written on the invitation.
Because it's a "Halloween Party",
attendees are to come as monsters...
And arrive in formal suits and dresses.
Of course, their guests, too.
By "guest", I take it you're going too, Ran-kun?
Do I seem like I'd want to attend a monster party!?
Oh, I suppose not.
Oh, one more thing...
I have a favor to ask you, Professor...
What is it?
If one came to my dad here...
Then, maybe...
One was sent to his place too?
You mean Shinichi-kun's place?
So, could you check his mailbox for me?
If I don't send a text about his invite, he'll grumble about having missed it.
If anything came, I'll call and let you know.
But, I don't think anything did...
Also, can you keep this a secret from Conan-kun?
If he finds out, I'm worried he'll get involved in something dangerous...
And...
And, what?
Tell him school's starting back up soon, so he should come back to our place.
And that he shouldn't be going off all by himself like that.
Got it.
I'll tell him.
Bye, then.
How's this look?
Suzuki Sonoko's magnum opus!
I dunno, I feel like it's missing something...
What're you talking about?
When it comes to this, less is more!
If you overdo it on your makeup and ruin it, you'll end up looking terrible.
I guess, but...
I like it!
It looks perfect on you, Dad!
It definitely has your style written all over it.
Think so?
And?
Do you know what you're going as yet, Sonoko?
But of course!
With a cute super-miniskirt, I'll
make all the monsters fall for me!
Make monsters fall for you, huh?
Because!
There's gotta be at least one super
hot guy among the monsters, right?
As if such a guy'd be found there...
What's that?
I'm sure the reason you're going is so
you can find some sexy vampire woman.
Well?
Aren't you going?
To that ghost ship.
Yeah.
It's the sender's name that bothers me.
Do you have any leads?
No.
But I think Haibara might.
Vermouth is the name of an
alcohol like Gin and Vodka.
Dunno.
Haven't heard of it.
I'm not exactly familiar with alcoholic drinks...
It's a liquor originally from Italy.
The way I said Vermouth is
the English pronunciation.
Here in Japan, we use its German name...
Wermut...
Isn't it?
I thought so.
I'll take your expression to mean you've heard that name before.
It's the codename of one of those guys in black.
Then, that invitation...
Yeah.
It's a personal invitation from
their colleague Vermouth-san.
Well, I'm not sure if they've set a trap or have just gotten impatient, but...
This is a good opportunity.
Don't do it.
Don't go, it's a trap!
If you go, they'll kill—
Yeah...
You may be right.
Then...
Then, why!?
Hey, Shinichi...
Isn't that going a bit far?
I'm sorry, Haibara.
At this rate...
We'll never get a step closer.
But, if you leave Ai-kun here like this...
Look at this, Professor.
The name on the invitation that came to my house.
The envelope and the invitation are both addressed to Kudo Shinichi, but...
The letter that came with it...
"Dear Edogawa Conan"!?
Hey, Shinichi, that means...
Yeah.
They know.
That my true identity is...
The one whose body was shrunken with APOPTOXIN 4869, Kudo Shinichi.
And likely also...
That Haibara is a former member of their Organization, Sherry...
But, isn't this strange?
If they know so much, why don't
they just come here and kill you?
Who knows?
I don't know the reason, but...
If I'm not mistaken...
I might have a hunch.
Hey, don't tell me you caught Ai-kun's cold?
I'll be fine.
What is it?
A phone call?
An e-mail...
All right...
That just leaves the matter of...
A Halloween party, you said?
Yeah.
Starts at that harbor, 7:00, tomorrow night.
But, Partner...
What business would I have at a party like that?
Because Vermouth's going to make an appearance.
Our orders are to sniff out her true intentions.
The orders aside, I've had about
enough of her secrets and lies.
I haven't gotten the boss's
permission, but I don't care.
If she's up to something,
I won't show her any mercy.
I don't care who she is.
Even if she is that person 's favorite.
That's strange.
That's definitely strange.
Compared to when I came to check the mail...
The water, gas and electricity
meters have all gone up slightly.
There's someone in here...
What better vantage point for conducting surveillance on Haibara and myself?
I could take one or two of them...
But, what if there are three or more?
Stay calm.
Judging by what I saw on the meters...
There's no more than one or two here.
And...
What an amazing full moon...
Really...
Great match for a spooky Halloween party, right?
All right!
I'm getting hyped now!
Really gets my blood stirring!
Hey, Uncle...
It's werewolves whose blood is
stirred by the full moon, isn't it?
But you're D-R-A-C-U-L-A.
Shut up.
I was talking about my "great detective" blood.
Excuse me?
Are you also going to take part in that off-season Halloween party?
You got it!
But I feel a little silly going to a costume party, you know?
Well, to tell you the truth...
I'm going too.
But, will Ai-kun be all right if we leave her in there?
Yeah.
I turned the heat on, and of course left plenty of food and water.
Come on already, show me the new game you made.
You wanna try it?
Some of the things in the drawer seem like they've been moved.
You were looking for it, weren't you?
You want to take them on all by yourself.
Wow, they're all here!
A werewolf...
A Frankenstein...
A mummy...
There's even a Chinese vampire!
So many monsters!
Really!
I'm so excited!
But, is it all right?
For a daughter of the Suzuki
family to be seen with this crowd.
It's fine, it's fine.
Unlike Ran, I actually kind of like parties like this.
Incidentally, young lady...
Just what kind of monster are you, anyway?
How rude!
I'm a witch, a witch!
I have a broom, don't I?
What's with that guy?
Hey, Uncle...
Look, I think he's telling us to move up in line.
Geez...
If that's all, why didn't he just say so?
He was just getting in character for the monster he's playing.
My, my, you certainly make a lovely witch!
Thank you.
But I'm...
Not a witch.
Medusa!
Careful, I'll turn you to stone.
Next guests!
Your invitation, please?
Coming!
Here we have...
The great detective, Mouri Kogoro-sama, yes?
You recognized me?
Well, now...
Your name's written on the invitation, isn't it?
If you would sign here?
Sure.
Mouri Kogoro...
By the way...
There aren't gonna be any real murders or anything, right?
It came with the invitation you sent.
This letter, saying they'd commit a crime here.
It is true that we sent the invitation, but...
The letter and envelope aren't from us.
Is that so?
It's true there's going to be a
murder mystery game, though.
Maybe the producer slipped that in there to entice Mouri-san to come?
Producer?
No, it's nothing.
Please enjoy the Cursed Masquerade.
Come on, Uncle!
Hurry up!
Hey, hold on!
Next guest, please?
Your invitation?
You wouldn't happen to be...
That high-school detective...
Thanks.
They really invited quite a few people...
No kidding.
It's finally getting started.
Yeah.
To my fellow dread monsters, who haunt the realms of the undying...
Welcome to my ghost ship: the Sea Phantom.
I am the captain of this accursed vessel, Captain Gold.
Only one hour remains until the banquet.
First, you must find the companions that are also bound to your fate...
Seven comrades with whom you share the same seal!
The same seal?
A tarot card.
You got one when you boarded, didn't you?
Most likely, they're putting those with the same cards on one team for some sort of game?
It has XV written on it...
A "Goat" card?
Then we're the "Goat" team?
That's not a goat.
XV is the Roman numeral for 15.
That card is THE DEVIL —it's the devil's card.
Is that so...
And the reason for splitting us up
isn't just for the sake of the game.
This party also serves as a movie audition.
Audition?
Haven't you heard of it?
Every summer, they produce a new
"The Voyages of Captain Ghost" movie.
Yeah.
Isn't that the one where people who've done bad things...
Get visited by a ghost ship crawling with all sorts of monsters?
Then, if I do well, I can be in the movie too!?
Right.
This year's party will be the fourth.
I believe some of the movie staff is secretly among the guests...
In order to keep an eye out for anyone with acting talent.
I see.
They can divide different people who've come as the same monster, in order to judge them more easily.
And that's why everyone is
trying to make an impression.
The werewolves howl at the moon.
The Frankenstein's monsters
pantomime moving like a robot.
The mummy says nothing, and keeps his silence.
Well, even if they do get cast, it'll
likely be a non-speaking minor role.
Why spend the money on
elaborate makeup for extras...
If you can get a horror fan that's willing to dress themselves up for free?
Not to mention, using the ghost ship from the movies for the event makes for a great publicity stunt.
Now, my fellow monsters, it is
time to launch from the harbor!
The hour has come for us to cross the seven
seas and show the foolish mortals our wrath!
Is this ship...
Going to sail?
Anyone got a DEATH card?
HERMIT?
Who has a HERMIT card?
Kudo Shinichi?
That high-school student detective is on this ship?
That's right!
But, I heard he got mixed up in
some sort of case and was killed...
No way, no way!
That's obviously a hoax.
Then?
What's he disguised as?
He had bandages, so I guess a mummy?
A mummy detective?
How cool!
All right...
Looks like all seven of us are here.
These are all ones I saw earlier...
That means our team is...
Miss Medusa here.
Mr. Werewolf, Mr. Frankenstein, Mr. Mummy...
And, let's see here...
How about "Mr. Mummy #2"—will that do?
What?
Shake your hand?
I see.
You're the Invisible Man, huh?
Well, I wonder what they're going to have us do.
I think it was supposed to be a whodunit game.
Well?
What do you think of my new game?
Not bad, right?
Yeah, it's great!
Right, right?
Hello, Agasa residence.
Sorry to call so late.
This is Araide.
Is the professor—?
He's not here.
I think he went somewhere with Edogawa-kun.
Huh?
But, I thought I just heard their voices...
Oh, this?
It's a tape recording.
I'm not sure what kind of stunt they were trying to pull, but...
It's been running for a while now.
Anyway, what did you want?
Actually, I wanted to talk to you.
You were saying your cold hasn't
improved for a while, weren't you?
I thought we could have it checked out
at a fully equipped hospital just in case.
I asked a specialist I know at a nearby hospital for an appointment, but...
Due to an upcoming business trip, his only opening is this evening.
So...
My apologies for being so last minute, but...
Would it be all right to take you there now?
I'll let the professor know you're with me.
But, if it's too much trouble, no problem.
That's fine.
I'm kind of annoyed at being left behind.
I don't have much to do here by myself anyway.
Great.
Well, in that case, I guess I'll come
by to pick you up in about an hour?
Can you be ready to go by then?
Got it.
See you then.
Finally, we got all seven!
Bunch of slowpokes.
Hey, Uncle...
I don't see our Werewolf, Frankenstein, or Mummy anywhere around here...
What?
Did they all go to the bathroom?
Guess so.
Shall we go look for them?
It seems the banquet is to begin soon.
Sure...
Here we go.
There he is.
Mr. Frankenstein!
Been looking all over for you!
But, man, what a bathroom this is!
Dark, full of spider webs, and
complete with broken mirrors, too.
Not to mention that they're unisex.
With us all being monsters, I suppose
there's no need for distinguishing genders.
It won't come off...
The blood on my hands won't come off...
I wash and wash, but it's still there...
Hey, hey...
You're not even gonna break character in the bathroom?
Excuse me...
Are Mr. Werewolf and Mr. Mummy in here?
They don't seem to be here.
What was that about?
Hey, chief—how's it hangin'?
Bartender!
I'll have what he's having.
A "Silver Bullet" for you in that case?
I'll take a "White Lady", please.
Coming right up.
You seem a little down.
Everything all right?
Hey!
The hell?
He looking for someone?
But, where could he have gotten off to?
That Mummy...
How should I know?
Geez.
These guys don't seem to have a lot of team spirit.
It's almost been an hour, I think.
What?
The banquet's starting.
Monsters, heed my call!
I come with splendid news!
The first course for tonight's banquet has been found:
At this hellish party, there is someone with neither a hideous appearance nor magical powers...
That's right—there is a human among us!
Now, work alongside your comrades to locate this foolish mortal among us...
We shall devour their flesh, tear out their
innards, and drink every last drop of their blood!
All right!
If we must find the culprit, then it's time for the great Mouri Kogoro to shine!
But not all seven of us are here.
Who cares?
It's not like they'll mind if I figure it out for all of us.
I hold the clue to identifying him in my hand.
If you want the treasure, come to the deck, my detectives—
All right!
What the...
What happened?
Sorry, a construction truck dropped some of its cargo onto the road.
We're working to clear the way.
Could you wait just a moment?
Actually, I'm in a bit of a hurry.
I'll take a detour.
My apologies.
My apologies...
Thank you for your patience.
You can go on through now.
Thank you.
Bye.
Drive safely.
The car just came through.
What's that?
It's...
Captain Ghost...
Well, this is certainly an elaborate production.
This is...
Real blood.
What!?
Quickly!
Someone get him down from there, quickly!
Coming, coming.
Hi!
Oh, sorry!
I am sorry to have startled you.
I am an English teacher from Teitan High School helping Dr. Araide.
On his way here, his car broke down.
As a result, I came over to pick you up in his place.
If it's OK, could you take off this chain lock, please?
I'm running pretty late.
Jodie-sensei?
His heart's been pierced by a crossbow bolt.
What's more...
There's a THE DEVIL card pinned to him.
Perhaps the killer was saying THE DEVIL had claimed him.
Claim or not, I'm sure he's crossing the River Styx right about now.
Death was more or less instantaneous.
Looks like it.
I'm sure the crossbow itself is
somewhere in this deep blue sea.
There's no chance of recovering it.
Well, then...
Is there a camera anywhere on this ship?
I'd like to photograph the crime scene, so...
We have some digital cameras we use to film some of the events here, but...
If it's going to be admissible as evidence, I'd prefer to use film.
Uncle, I have a disposable camera, if that'll do.
Here.
Well, better than nothing.
Now, to have a look at the deceased.
I've seen this face somewhere before...
Isn't he that movie producer
who shows up on TV a lot?
If I recall correctly, his name is Fukuura Senzou.
Before the Captain Ghost series...
He produced "The Thirteenth Unlucky Day".
I think that was the movie that made him famous.
Then, don't tell me he starred in his own movies as the ghost captain?
Oh, no, an actual actor plays the ghost captain in the movies.
But since Fukuura-san liked the character so much, he plays the role during these annual parties.
We'd put a spotlight on the crow's nest and he'd give a hint, as well.
That riddle about a human
hiding among the monsters?
There's a microphone attached to his skull mask.
It seems like he could talk directly
into the speaker system from there.
And?
What's the riddle's solution?
Actually, he came up with the riddles and hints himself, so we don't actually know.
I heard that the group that solved the puzzle first would get tickets to a preview screening...
At any rate, we can rest assured that the murderer is among you staff members.
First of all, Fukuura-san cried out as he was announcing the riddle to us all.
Most likely, this is when he
was shot with the crossbow.
However, at that time, all of us guests
were below deck in the reception hall.
That makes it impossible for one of us to
have shot Fukuura-san at the top of the mast.
The only possibility is for it to
be someone above deck...
Someone with the staff that was busy preparing the lighting, sounds, and atmosphere.
And secondly, this THE DEVIL card!
Most likely, to make it seem one of the guests was guilty of the crime, one of you printed extra cards.
Oh, no.
The cards were prepared by Fukuura-san alone, so we couldn't have known to make a copy.
Last year, it was playing cards, for instance.
Besides, there were several
guests who came onto the deck...
Saying they wanted a view of the ocean.
It was dark, so I didn't really see which guests.
Is that so?
I see.
In other words, it's likely the killer is among us seven who received THE DEVIL cards.
Do not worry.
The doctor we are going to see is very, very good.
He will cure your cold right away.
You will feel much better!
By the way, how long until this ship docks at the port?
About an hour, I think.
I see.
Then, let's return to the cabin and investigate the case until then...
Mr. Sleeping Vampire.
Yeah...
What's up, Uncle?
Looks like we'll be a while, so I was gonna tell Ran.
She's not picking up.
Maybe she's in the bath?
Now then...
If I could see everyone's THE DEVIL card?
Huh...
Huh?
What's wrong, Mr. Mummy?
Could I have dropped it somewhere?
So you deliberately put it on the arrow to deflect suspicion?
Must be reverse psychology—what criminal would be so foolish as to put his own card on the arrow?
Of course, you had no idea that
Fukuura-san only made seven of each card.
But, I actually did know that!
Why would you know that?
Because, I had to know, in order to scout guests with makeup talent...
Fukuura-san assigned me.
I'm with the movie staff!
You're movie staff?
So, why would I kill him?
Are you the only staff member
hiding out among the guests?
No...
Most of the other mummies are too.
When we found guests showcasing
really convincing characterizations...
We were to report them to Fukuura-san.
The one who did our makeup
was Fukuura-san himself, right?
Yeah.
He gave us most of our instructions while he was doing our makeup.
Instructions?
What kind of instructions?
Like "order a specific drink", or...
I was told to order dishes with chicken in them.
He had me wear this red wig.
Anyway, these instructions were all separate, and...
We were told not to discuss them during the contest.
What the hell?
How would I know?
Fukuura-san is the one who came up with it.
But, you know...
While we were awaiting that riddle, you were nowhere to be found.
I went to the bathroom!
These two were with me.
Right?
We did go down together, but...
See?
But...
I never saw you leave.
What're you saying!?
I passed behind you on my way out!
What's wrong with you!?
You must not have noticed...
Someone smashed the mirrors!
Those weren't smashed as part of the horror themed atmosphere?
No...
They weren't broken when the ship left the harbor.
Is that true?
He's right.
We were all helping decorate the ship, but...
There wasn't anything on
there about breaking mirrors.
Then, where were you when Fukuura-san was about to give out the hint?
I was there!
Right next to the werewolf!
Right?
You did see me, right?
Well, I don't really remember.
Come on!
I really wanted to land the part in the movie...
So I was focusing on standing out from the crowd.
With this.
Now that you mention it, I did hear that howling...
So it sounds like no one saw you after that.
In other words, there are some gaps in your alibi.
No way...
I'm being set up!
Someone's plotting to make me take the fall for this!
A cornered criminal will say
anything to deflect suspicion.
At any rate...
The one with no alibi who happens to be lacking their card...
Mr. Mummy...
Isn't it you?
Isn't it you who did this?
I'm afraid you're off the mark, Detective Mouri.
What!?
The truth of this matter is still shrouded in darkness.
The voice is coming from the captain's microphone!
Who has the nerve to contradict me?
Out of my way!
Who's there!?
Where are you!?
A pity you got it wrong.
You even drank the key to solving this case.
Bastard!
The hell are you!?
You'll be in trouble if you're screwing with us!
You don't remember?
It's me, Detective Mouri.
The Invisible Man...
I'm here to deduce who killed Captain Gold, the chairman of this party...
The movie producer, Fukuura Senzou-san...
And...
Reveal precisely how they did so.
Now...
Shall we begin?
That voice!
That tone...
It can't be...
All in the pale moonlight...
Illuminating this dark night.
You're...
That detective...
Brat!
Kudo...
Shinichi!
No way!
What're you doing here!?
"Kudo"?
That famous high-school detective?
He's not dead after all!
This...
It can't be...
Since before, he...
Here!
I take it you have no objections?
Give me the film already!
Partner...
I thought Gin took care of him with that poison.
So what in the world is going on?
Hey...
Can I ask you for a favor?
Detective brat, it's been a while.
Sorry to steal the show from you, but this case is already closed.
The killer who aimed at Fukuura-san right on the mast where you're standing...
After leaving the party for the dark upper deck, put his THE DEVIL card on a crossbow and fired...
Can only be one person:
The one who has no alibi...
And is lacking their THE DEVIL card: the Mummy—it can be no one else!
Exactly what part of my deduction is "off the mark"?
Hey!
Go ahead, explain yourself!
Oh, excuse me.
I have a bit of a cold, so my voice is going.
A cold?
Where were we?
His alibi and card, right?
The culprit probably lifted it from Mr. Mummy to make him appear guilty.
"The culprit lifted it"?
Well, if the Mummy's not the killer, that's what you'd have to say.
Since the cards were specially made to be one per person.
Right.
And whether or not the killer knew this...
They stole it from the Mummy in that bathroom.
In the bathroom?
Hey, is he right, Mummy?
Dunno...
He says he doesn't know.
Doesn't seem likely, then!
Well, that's not surprising...
Considering the killer snuck into the stall next to his, and sprayed a sedative under the divider.
The Mummy passed out from inhaling the sedative...
And then the killer jumped over the divider, taking the card.
Hey, hey...
Where's the proof of that?
I don't have any.
That's just one of the ways he could have done it.
The drug and the syringe are probably at the bottom of the ocean by now.
What's all this now?
Don't tell me you don't actually know who did it, then?
On the contrary, there's only one person
who could have done it, Detective Mouri.
What?
The one who killed Fukuura-san...
And tried to pin the blame on the Mummy...
Could be only one person.
It was you...
Mr. Werewolf!
What now!?
The werewolf?
You sure that cold isn't dulling your wits?
We saw the Werewolf in the bathroom...
And he was with us while Fukuura-san was talking.
On the other hand, no one saw the Mummy!
What are you talking about!?
You saw me leave the bathroom yourself, didn't you!?
Are you saying my memory's bad?
Also, I was right there when he was giving
the hint over the speaker, right next to you!
Hey, hey!
Don't tell me that you were really the Invisible Man and not the Mummy or something!
The Frankenstein has the key to solving this particular quandary.
He does?
Could you tell us, then?
Why you were in character by that sink, and what you saw that surprised you?
Most of us horror fans know about this party...
Where there are talent scouts from the movie staff among the guests that are looking to cast people.
So I figured out this man was one of them...
And followed him to the
bathroom to try to impress him.
I did an acting routine the
whole time he was in there...
But the person who came out of his stall was...
The werewolf!?
The mummy is the werewolf!?
Hey, hey!
Then, that means...
Exactly.
There was one more thing the killer placed on the Mummy besides the blame...
The mask he was wearing!
The reason the bathroom mirrors were broken was to keep him in the dark about this fact.
But even without mirrors, wouldn't he notice anyway if someone put a mask on him?
First of all, his face is covered in bandages.
If it should be put on him while he's unconscious, he might not notice.
The mask would cover his differently colored tie.
Otherwise, their suits and white gloves are basically identical.
No one else would notice the change.
But, him just so happening to be next to someone with a THE DEVIL card...
Who was playing a role where he wouldn't speak...
Isn't it too much?
The matching card was a coincidence, but that's it.
He was waiting for anyone.
Anyone who was playing a monster that
doesn't speak, of which there are many here.
He might've gotten the idea to use the card when he saw it was the same as his own.
That way, the one without a card would be suspected.
Thus, we would be thrown off the scent of the real killer.
But, when Sonoko-kun called out...
The werewolf ran right out of the stall.
If he was unconscious, why
did the timing work so well?
Before he did, didn't you hear something?
I see!
The howl of the wolf!
The howl was pre-recorded, and activated by a remote.
He just had to press the switch from inside the next stall over.
The Mummy would then wake up from the loud noise.
Yeah.
Most likely, the speaker was
attached to the back of the mask.
The killer also put a transmitter on it...
So that they could react quickly to any conversation around the Mummy.
And whenever someone tried to talk with the Mummy, he'd press the switch...
And make him think the Werewolf was nearby.
I see.
He did seem like an odd werewolf,
howling and looking around all the time.
This way, he could make it seem that the Werewolf was still at the party and give himself an alibi.
He went to the top of the deck, and used a crossbow to shoot Fukuura-san, who was in the crow's nest.
Then, he followed the howling speaker to find the Mummy among the guests and recover his mask.
He was then free to blend back into the crowd.
Well, did I leave anything out?
Mr. Werewolf.
Does that sound right?
I dunno what kind of high-school
detective you're supposed to be, but...
That's quite a story you made up there!
I put this mask on the Mummy?
Where's the proof?
Do you have any proof that I did it!?
I do have some things that point to you being the murderer.
There are two right here.
This is the first.
This was the hint he was going to say would help find the human among the monsters.
A chicken?
Hey, hey, where'd that come from?
Its leg was tied to the mast up here.
Most likely, Fukuura-san was going to do this while the spotlight was on him.
Hanging it upside-down?
Upside-down?
Maybe he wanted us to say it backwards?
Kenchic...
Kenchic?
How the hell is that a hint!?
Kenchic, kenchick...
I see.
A male chicken is a "cock".
At its bottom is a "tail".
Long ago, they used to mix alcoholic drinks with a rooster's tail...
Which served as the origin of the word "cocktail".
So "cocktail" was the hint?
Detective Mouri...
You drank it yourself, didn't you?
That cocktail.
But I just had beer, I didn't—
That's right, I was looking for the werewolf when...
Hey, chief—how's it hangin'?
Bartender!
I'll have what he's having.
I did drink it.
I think it was a...
It was called a "Silver Bullet", that cocktail!
My instructions from Fukuura-san were to order it at the bar!
So the person we saw run from the bathroom was actually...
It was because you hadn't followed
instructions and ordered the cocktail yet!
Yes...
That's a coincidence!
I ordered that as well.
No, you didn't!
That was the Mummy you put your mask on!
It's just like Shinichi-kun said!
I don't know who you think you are, brat.
I'm the only werewolf here!
So, Mr. Werewolf...
Did you really drink that cocktail?
You, hoping to get noticed by the casting
directors by acting the part of the werewolf?
Yeah, I sure did!
What of it?
Why wouldn't a werewolf drink alcohol?
Really, a Silver Bullet?
Yes, I already told you!
A Silver Bulle—
Hey, could it be...
A Silver Bullet?
But isn't a silver bullet...
Yeah...
A werewolf wouldn't...
Right.
The name of the cocktail is "Silver Bullet".
Literally a bullet made from elemental silver.
And in the movies, that's always the one weapon that can kill a werewolf.
Every horror fan knows that.
And the cocktail that shares its name is...
A ward against evil as well.
Perhaps by giving that as the hint...
He wanted the guests to go to the bar...
And ask the bartender who had ordered what drink.
And then reveal that the Mummy who had
the Silver Bullet was the human in disguise.
Because what self-respecting monster would order a cocktail like that?
Right?
Mr. Werewolf.
Well, the bartender, who wasn't in on the clue...
Unwittingly served the cocktail to Detective Mouri as well.
Since it was Fukuura-san who did the Mummy's makeup, most likely...
Under his bandages, there's a mark confirming him as the answer.
Pardon me.
There it is!
It says "human" right there.
And?
You said you had two pieces of evidence.
Affixing a card to a crossbow bolt and hitting
someone with it from that distance is impossible.
Of course, that's especially so with such uncertain footing like this rope ladder.
To hit the victim, the killer would've had to fire from close range.
There are still traces that the werewolf was standing here.
What?
He stepped on it after he broke the mirrors.
Fragments of broken mirror should still be stuck to the soles of his shoes.
I'm sure forensic testing will
confirm that they're a match.
Now, Mr. Werewolf...
If you would please show us...
The soles of your shoes.
And then, please explain why you climbed all the way up here.
I'll just take a look, Mr. Werewolf...
Please, your foot.
It wasn't me!
It's not me!
I never wanted to do it!
It's that devil's fault!
It's all the fault of that fiend!
That fiend named Vermouth!
Jodie-sensei!
Oh!
Araide-sensei, what is wrong?
That's what I should be saying!
Where are you taking her?
No, no!
We are just going for a drive.
Unlike you, I have a lot of free time, you see.
Free time?
Dr. Araide...
You have a court appearance for that murder case soon, right?
You will have to testify for it.
That the housekeeper, Yasumoto Hikaru-san, pulled the trigger...
And you hid the fact that she killed your father.
Hikaru-san pulled the trigger?
It is no use pretending.
I secretly asked Detective Mouri for the truth.
What are you talking about?
The killer in that case was my stepmother!
Beyond that, he was electrocuted...
He wasn't shot at all!
"Vermouth"?
So you're saying this "Vermouth" told you to kill Fukuura-san?
Well!?
No...
It's true that I did hate Fukuura-san.
He abruptly canceled the "Unlucky Days"
series of movies that I was obsessed with...
And started the stupid kid-friendly
"Captain Ghost" franchise in its place.
I vented my hatred for him on a certain internet forum.
There, I mentioned I wanted revenge.
That was when this "Vermouth" contacted me.
They told me how to kill him and supplied me the murder weapon.
And you agreed to kill him just over that!?
This is a person's life we're talking about!
Of course I refused at first!
But then...
I started receiving surveillance photos of my family...
Along with tapped and recorded phone calls.
There were documents detailing everything we did every day!
A big cardboard box full of the stuff!
I was told that if I refused or went to the police, someone in my family would end up killed!
He was electrocuted and not shot?
What's so funny?
Oh, sorry!
The trigger I meant was the circuit breaker.
The one who laid the trap for him to die was the criminal...
But the one who unwittingly pulled the trigger was the housekeeper, Yasumoto Hikaru-san.
In order to spare her the anguish, the police report was revised to omit out that part.
It was rewritten so that some
other method triggered the trap.
Well, it's not surprising you didn't know.
Because that detail wasn't in the report that you stole from the Tokyo police.
That police report you stole to keep up your disguise as Dr. Araide...
For his court appearance.
Am I wrong?
Who in the world—
"A secret makes a woman woman."
Do you remember?
Those were the last words you spoke to me.
Words I never forgot.
I've held onto them all these years.
A mantra to avenge my father.
Isn't it so?
Chris Vineyard!
Or, do you prefer...
Vermouth?
Who are you?
It's a big secret.
I can't tell you.
A secret makes a woman woman.
My papa's glasses...
I'm sorry.
What happened to Papa?
Is he asleep already?
He'd promised me a bedtime story...
Then, could you stay by Papa's side until he wakes up?
And then you set fire to my house, and turned everything in it to ash.
Including the records my father had collected in his secret FBI investigation of you and your associates.
But I survived.
I remembered that my father liked orange
juice after waking up and that we'd run out.
My mother wasn't feeling well and had been lying down all day...
So I left for a nearby store by myself.
So, you were the girl in that house?
I've long looked for you.
Because the only remains found in that
charred house were those of your parents.
That was thanks to my father's colleagues.
They applied for the Witness
Protection Program on my behalf.
You mean that ridiculous program that gives new identities to witnesses whose lives are in danger?
That must've been so hard, huh?
Leaving behind your name and home to become an entirely different person.
And so?
You courageously followed in your father's
footsteps and chased me all over the world?
The FBI's...
Special Agent Jodie Starling?
I expected no less from the "Witch of a Thousand Faces"—Vermouth.
With your ability to disguise yourself, you can infiltrate any organization for intel.
I'm more impressed with you, seeing through my disguise as Dr. Araide.
I knew.
Despite not having any serious illness, you visited his clinic incognito with no disguise as the actress Chris.
When I saw that, I knew you were going to kill him and assume his identity.
Then, could that mean...
When I saw his family's car break through a guardrail and plunge into the ocean...
That was your doing?
Right.
I faked their deaths before you could kill them.
That way, as long as the car remained at the bottom of the sea, and no one had known he was dead...
You'd have an easier time masquerading as him.
Of course, the passengers in the car were played by expert diver colleagues of mine.
The real Dr. Araide is living safely somewhere far away from here.
Then, you assumed his place at the
Araide Clinic, just as we had predicted.
Uncovering what you were after was a simple matter of covertly breaking into the clinic.
A dart had pierced the photo of a
brown-haired woman of around twenty.
It was clear that you intended to find her and finish her off.
Now, some questions from me.
Questions about the woman you were attempting to lure out and kill, and about this girl resembling her.
She will be going into Witness Protection, of course.
Is she really the girl in that picture?
I have more.
The meaning of the words on the two pictures below hers.
"Cool Guy" and "Angel".
That boy certainly has a sharp mind, but...
He's not a "guy" but a "kid".
Right...
The one named Conan, that boy.
Why was it you didn't make your move until he was safely apart from this girl?
And on that hijacked bus...
Please stop!
Can't you see he's just a boy!?
You put your life on the line to protect him.
Tell me: Why did you do it?
If not for them, this wouldn't have happened!
So...
Please catch Vermouth!
And?
Vermouth is the name of an alcohol—it's obviously fake.
Do you know his real identity?
And you haven't seen him, either?
But, what about the address on the
invitation sent to bring you here?
Don't tell me...
You already threw it away?
Not like their real address would've been on it.
At any rate...
We'll have to tie you up somewhere until the ship reaches harbor.
Looks like another case closed!
Now...
Answer me.
Fine.
I'll give you your answer.
You see...
Don't move!
My, my...
What a dangerous toy you have there.
Did you get the proper permits from the Japanese police, I wonder?
I'll have the joint police operation
authorized after I have you in custody.
Naturally, I'm prepared to
accept any official reprimands.
But before that, there was
something I had to ask you about.
Oh?
What might that be?
Why don't you...
Why don't you seem to age?
When I set eyes on you...
In front of your mother's
casket, you said these words:
A secret makes a woman woman.
Hearing those words again made my heart race.
When you killed my father and made it look like a suicide...
You picked up his glasses after they'd landed in a strange way.
They lifted fingerprints from the
lenses and matched them to you.
But there was still a problem:
You were too young to be a suspect in a twenty-year-old cold case.
I didn't think it possible, but I compared the fingerprints to another person, and...
The result sent chills down my spine.
You and your mother Sharon Vineyard are actually one and the same!
And now, I finally have...
The final piece of the puzzle I need...
The witness who can give
me the key to arresting you.
You guys!
Come out and hold this woman!
After I secure extradition from the Japanese police, you'll be telling me everything.
All of it.
But, even if you remain silent,
I'm sure this girl won't.
Thank you, Calvados.
Not just yet.
There's something I want to ask this woman first.
How...
I know you think you've lured me into
a trap with your colleagues here, but...
I came here two hours ago, disguised as you.
And in your voice I said...
"This is it tonight!"
"Come back tomorrow!"
You didn't realize?
As for the case reports I stole concerning
Detective Mouri, there was another purpose.
I took all of them in order to not call
attention to the one I was interested in.
And the reason I returned them to the police was...
To give the impression that the reason I was in Japan involved the Mouri Detective Agency.
All in order to get you to stake out that detective agency.
Along with your FBI buddies.
Thanks to that, I know how many of you there are, where you're staying, and your contact information.
As well as the fact that you were setting up a trap for me here.
Then, you knew we broke into your room?
Yes, I only pretended I didn't.
I thought that by letting you see the
photo, you might find the girl for me.
But I have to say, you've
surprised me twice this evening.
First, that you were the girl from that night.
And second, you knowing the
secret behind the Dr. Araide case.
Who'd you pry that from?
No one in their right mind would leak it.
I didn't pry it from anyone...
I was told...
This girl said that if I could use it to reveal your true identity, she would trust me...
Oh?
She did, huh?
Well, take your time telling your story to the police.
But to catch the criminal so quickly...
That's Kudo Shinichi for ya.
Well done!
It's nothing, really.
It's just because the killer and I used the same trick.
What's that supposed to mean?
The same trick as that werewolf...
Now, this is where our twenty-year reunion ends.
It's time to say goodbye.
Hey, smile.
You'll get to meet your daddy in heaven.
You used the same trick as the werewolf?
The killer put his wolf mask on
top of the Mummy's, didn't he?
But you were just wearing bandages!
So what do you mean by that!?
You...
It can't be...
Yeah.
Like I said.
This...
Is what I mean!
You're—
Hattori Heiji!
Cool Kid...
Edogawa Conan...
A detective!
You weren't Shinichi-kun...
Hattori Heiji...
In disguise!?
You were disguised!?
But he looked and sounded like Shinichi-kun!
Of course.
I personally spent six hours crafting that disguise.
Naturally his voice was similar, because...
Heiji-kun would whisper his deductions into the microphone on his collar...
And Shin-chan would hear it and repeat it aloud.
It would then be emitted from the speaker on Heiji-kun's necktie.
It was a perfect collaboration with Professor Agasa!
We're all clear here, Kudo.
Take 'em down over there.
I don't think so.
Your body is blocking mine from the rifle's line of fire.
Now...
Once Jodie-sensei's inside, get in the car.
Let's take a ride to the police station.
Jodie-sensei!
Quick!
Into the car!
Jodie-sensei...
Can you make it?
Yeah...
It can't be...
Kudo Shinichi?
Remember, that brat you killed with the Organization's drug.
Sorry, Vodka.
The names and faces of those I've erased...
I make it a point to forget them.
And?
Are you saying this dead brat came back from the grave?
No...
Things have just gotten a bit strange...
Regardless...
Why the hell are you going around dressed up as Kudo Shinichi!?
Sorry 'bout that, Pops!
I was thinkin' he hasn't made
an appearance in a while, so...
I just figured if I solved a case as him,
I could taunt him into showin' up, but...
Who knows?
Maybe he really is dead, like the rumors say?
Geez!
You Osakan brat!
This is the second time you've done this!
If Ran were here...
She'd beat you to a pulp!
Hey, cut me some slack!
What choice'd I have?
Kudo sent a text askin' me to.
He said they were onto him, and it looked like they were about to make their move.
To strike first, he said he needed me to assume his identity and board this ship.
But, it's pretty scary...
When Kudo went to his house, his ma was there.
She said she was worried about him, and had been campin' out in his house to keep an eye on him.
Hey, hey...
Who woulda thought she was this good at disguises?
She'd give Arsène Lupin a run for his money.
Thanks to her, I was able to
investigate as the Invisible Man.
What worries me is the girl they left sleepin' and locked up in old Agasa's basement...
Kudo said that as long as she didn't hide the spare pair of the trackin' glasses, it'd be all right, but...
If I were her...
And Kudo was gonna go as her to face
down that dangerous bunch all on his own...
I wouldn't be able to just sit there and let him.
I'd force the door open...
Do somethin'...
No matter what.
No matter what, Kudo.
I'd go find you.
Haibara...
You...
Haibara!
Shit!
Stay back!
Stay away!
Turn around!
You fool!
No, Kudo-kun...
This is my fight.
It never should've involved you.
So...
Don't die!
You can't die!
The spare pair of tracking glasses...
I knew you'd kept them!
Kudo-kun...
Get away from here, Haibara!
Hurry!
What're you waiting for!?
Get away, Haibara!
Get out of here, hurry!
Move it!
Good night, baby.
And...
Welcome...
Sherry!
The only reason I can think of for Vermouth to want to kill Haibara but keep her distance from me is...
That she's actually the actress Chris Vineyard, and...
Moreover, she and Sharon Vineyard are the same person.
She likely used disguises to switch between the two identities.
Being a friend of yours, she probably recognized
a child version of me she'd seen in photo albums.
It would have been simple for her to see through my secret identity.
I also understand why she's trying to
avoid getting me involved in this case.
It's all right.
I'll be sure to come back in one piece, so don't worry about me.
Is that really true...
Sharon?
Foolish woman.
Ruining this kid's cute little plan and...
Coming all the way here to die.
I didn't come here just to die.
I came to end it once and for all.
Even if you were caught, so long as I'm alive...
You people will never stop looking for me.
In exchange, promise me something.
That you won't harm anyone other than me.
Can you give me your word?
Fine.
I'll spare everyone aside from this FBI woman.
But you first, Sherry.
If you must blame anyone in all of this, blame
your parents for starting their foolish research.
Cool Kid...
It can't be...
How!?
Wait, Calvados!
Impossible...
Did she see them?
Wait, Calvados!
Wait!
Didn't I tell you to wait!?
Now, move away from that brown-haired girl.
Hurry, if you don't want to die!
No, don't move!
Now!
Out of the way!
Stop!
I called the police, so just hang in there a little longer, please!
Sis...
Silver hair?
If you must blame someone...
Blame God for putting you in this position.
What are you doing!?
Hurry and grab my hand!
Hurry, the rain's making my hand...
Why'd you save me?
Why'd you do it?
Is a reason necessary?
I can't say what brings a person to kill another, but...
For a person to save another...
One doesn't really need a logical reason, do they?
Move!
What are you doing?
Hurry and grab my hand!
Move it, Angel!
What!?
The rifle's line of fire can't reach me...
When did you...
Drop the gun.
Drop the damn gun!
Or the next one goes through your head!
A pump...
Shotgun?
OK, Calvados...
You can flank her.
Damn...
He has me...
Now, Calvados...
Use your beloved shotgun and waste this little FBI kitten.
Oh?
That guy...
His name's "Calvados", huh?
A rifle, shotgun, and three handguns.
I figured he was an arms dealer or something.
Akai Shuuichi...
Shuu!
I'm afraid with both legs broken, he might have to be on disability for a while.
Well...
Calvados is an apple brandy.
A fitting partner for a rotten apple like you.
Rotten Apple?
Our little codename for you.
Star actress Sharon was known in the
limelight as the stage's "Golden Apple".
You're just as beautiful as you were then, but...
Underneath, you're just rotten to the core.
A true rotten apple.
Don't...
Shuu!
Not to worry.
She's wearing a layer of bulletproof clothing.
I can tell by her movements.
Might have a few broken ribs, though.
Look where the buckshot has scratched the skin.
This is really her true face, undisguised.
I can't get a clear shot with the kids there!
Cool Kid...
Using the mirror to aim and hitting
the gas tank in her condition...
She's good.
Shuu...
Don't stand there impressed!
You let her take a hostage and get away!
I'm not the one who left the keys in her car.
Well, excuse me...
Well, with her friend, at least
we won't leave empty handed.
Oh, come on...
He had yet another gun?
He didn't want to be taken alive?
And...
There's the Japanese police.
This girl must've called them...
Even if she couldn't hear our conversation from the trunk, she heard the gunshots and got out.
She must have seen the photos
at my house and got suspicious...
Causing her to sneak into my car to investigate me.
The sound of gunshots drew her out to protect the brown-haired girl staring down the barrel of a gun.
She thought the shots she heard hit the girl, and now they're both unconscious...
Geez...
I don't know whether to call her brave or reckless.
Then, I'll leave the rest to you.
Tell them you're an FBI agent on vacation in Japan who managed to stumble upon a child abduction case.
With that woman having fled the scene, it's not like the police would believe the truth.
In the end, we didn't hook the big one.
And, in any case...
The time isn't yet right for that brown-haired girl to see me.
OK, Boss...
Now, to deal with the kid...
This boy, who thinks he can do anything...
Electrodes and a heart rate monitor?
With a microphone and a transmitter!
Could it have picked up the
sound of the phone before!?
I wouldn't do that.
It'll think my heart has stopped, and transmit your boss's phone number to my colleagues.
It's the obligation of a phone company to protect the privacy of its customers, but...
With the proper warrants, they'll be able to access everything they need.
And if it's a land line instead of a mobile phone, they'll narrow it to an address and everything.
In other words...
By analyzing the tones recorded from that phone call...
We'll find your boss's name and location.
That's even if you kill me.
Well...
I knew that if you caught the traitor Sherry you had so frantically been searching for...
You'd no doubt end up contacting your superiors.
When it looked like Jodie-sensei was about to be killed...
I had no choice but to change my plan.
Your move—what'll you do?
My colleagues are waiting at a
safe distance for the transmission.
If you don't want it transmitted...
Take me to your boss.
Let's settle this, Vermouth!
I'm sick of playing hide-and-seek with you people.
Fine.
You win.
I'll give up on Sherry.
It's just sleeping gas.
Fool...
The gas will also knock you...
Yeah, it's a gamble.
If you wake up first...
You can call the police and arrest me.
I'll then lead you to my boss's hideout.
But if I'm the first one to awaken...
You already know, don't you?
This is bad!
I have to wake him up quick...
Or Shinichi will...
Shinichi!
You were beaten by Akai Shuuichi?
Yeah.
I ran into him and he broke three of my ribs.
The one you tried to lure to his death a year
ago with your serial killer cover in New York?
That FBI dog, you mean?
I thought he might let his guard down if he thought I was just some random criminal.
In retrospect, I should have been willing to die to take him down with me back then.
The boss—that person...
Fears the one who will become our silver bullet...
Is that man.
A silver bullet that can take us down in one shot...
Doesn't exist.
Anyway, I'm in a phone booth off the Number 20 line.
Can you pick me up?
I'm sure the feelings I've had since that day
I ran into a bit of trouble, and can't move...
Before that...
I have something to ask.
A brat named Kudo Shinichi...
Heard of him?
will reach you, even when we're apart
No, can't say I have.
Why'd you save me?
Is a reason necessary?
I entrust this wish to the passing seasons
For a person to save another...
One doesn't really need a logical reason, do they?
That's right...
Love is always a red song
That boy who got through to me...
He may be the one.
It's painful...
I shed a single tear
The one I've been waiting for all this time...
The silver bullet.