Friendship! Romance! Mystery!
We try our best because we've made those promises!
We start the year with the Detective Boys!
It's Genta's butt and not a monkey's!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Hey, are you serious?
About you and Haibara nearly being kidnapped?
Yeah.
Well, we somehow got away unscathed.
It's just that the criminal happened to escape.
But, it's really great...
That both of you recovered from your colds and can make it to school.
I was really worried, you know...
Thank you.
It's all right now.
We actually wanted to visit you, but...
Conan warned us that the cold would spread and told us not to come.
Right?
Yeah.
Is that so?
We had a lot of time to visit before school started...
That's right.
I'm feeling hungry now that I'm relieved...
Not again.
Say...
Is it really all right?
For me, to come out?
Yeah, probably.
For now.
"Probably"?
I already removed all of the listening devices that were installed in the professor's house.
Actually, I hung around here alone last night...
As you.
I asked my mom to help me disguise like you once again.
Shin-chan, you look great!
Well?
Oh, really?
Again, you went off on your own and did something dangerous...
At least for the time being, there's no sign of any suspicious people following or watching us.
Well, even though we can't let our guard down...
It's not our style to be scared and hide at home forever.
For now, I think we should place faith in those words...
I lost.
I'll give up on Sherry.
Those words?
And you've recovered from your cold, haven't you?
Isn't it because the pressure from those guys is gone?
Find the Buttock's Mark
(Part One)
An FBI agen—
Sonoko!
Really?!
Sonoko, geez...
But, Sensei is...
Seriously?
Sonoko!
This is a hospital! Keep it quiet!
I'm sorry.
Do not worry about it.
But, why did you become an English teacher in Japan?
Could it be an undercover operation?
Sonoko...
No, no!
It's not?
I carelessly let a criminal I've followed for a long time escape during an investigation.
I decided to take a short holiday...
And so I came to Japan.
I really, really love the games in Japan!
Games?
The reason I became an English teacher is...
I have always wanted to be one.
But, my holiday has come to an end.
Once my stomach injury heals...
I must go back to America.
Then, the treasure map Sensei mentioned looking all over for is...
They have gotten some clues on the criminal.
So, my superior contacted me and told me to come back.
He said it was a chance for me to redeem myself.
I see...
Before returning, I thought of saying farewell to Cool Kid.
When I went to the professor's house...
I saw Cool Kid and Ai-chan...
Being shoved into a car and taken away by some suspicious people...
And gave chase.
And when I cornered them...
They suddenly fired a shot at me.
Naturally, I returned fire.
Of course, the gun was one I snatched from the suspicious people.
But, thank goodness...
That Mouri-san had been hiding in my car trunk...
And protected Ai-chan for me.
At that time, I...
Having been shot in the stomach...
Was unable to move.
The criminals gave up on the kidnapping...
And were going to kill the children and escape.
Did that really happen?
Yeah.
I discovered pictures of Shin'ichi and Conan-kun hidden behind her bathroom mirror, so...
I went to Jodie-sensei's apartment to ask her about it.
But Sensei was out, and just as I was about to head home, I saw her car parked in front of her apartment.
Since the trunk was unlocked, I just spontaneously...
"Spontaneously"?
You...
But, I'm glad...
Sensei isn't a bad person.
I thought for sure Sensei got caught up in one of Shin'ichi's cases...
And the culprit coerced her into taking pictures of him in order to find his weaknesses.
That's when I thought of confronting the criminal directly and finishing him off!
Hang on, Ran.
Are you being serious?
Exactly what were you thinking? Jeez...
Oh!
Those pictures are of all the close friends I've made in Japan.
Actually, I initially had them stuck up on a board in my living room, but...
When my Japanese friends came over, they all looked strangely at them.
That's why I moved them there.
I see!
Americans often display pictures on their office desks, don't they?
Like of family members.
Since people in Japan generally don't take to that habit...
It's no wonder they find it strange.
Come to think of it, when I went to the dressing rooms backstage at that New York opera house...
I saw a lot of pictures on the actress's mirrors, too.
You mean the trip where you and Shin'ichi-kun were attacked by that phantom killer?
Speaking of phantom killers...
I've heard recently that there is one around here.
Please be careful.
Yes.
It looks like someone's here.
Well, we'll be going now.
Hurry and get well soon, Sensei.
Thanks, both of you!
See you.
How is it?
Your condition.
Yeah, I'm fine.
It seems it narrowly missed my vital organs.
Speaking of which, have the Japanese police approved that statement?
Yeah.
Upon hearing the sirens, one of the kidnappers seized the boy as a hostage and fled.
After leaving the car and the boy in the forest, they vanished.
Also, the other one—whose leg had been injured—committed suicide with his own gun.
Regrettably...
Due to darkness around them...
Neither you nor the children were able to see them clearly.
Of course, we coordinated our statements with the children beforehand.
Well, given that we failed to apprehend them and there's no clear motive...
I don't want to complicate matters by announcing that the culprit is that actress, Chris Vineyard.
Since we failed to seek permission from the Japanese police...
We're partly in the wrong ourselves for sending you undercover at all.
The issue we have is the girl known as "Sherry."
Will she accept...
Our request?
Well, with the FBI on the move...
Those guys wouldn't dare do something reckless now.
Oh, come to think of it...
The professor said Jodie-sensei called for you this morning.
What was it about?
Did she want to confirm our statements?
Yeah.
That was more-or-less it.
I'll be frank...
We'd like you to join the Witness Protection Program.
The woman from that time, Chris Vineyard...
Right...
That one known as "Vermouth," is out to silence you by killing you.
In other words, you possess information that's very unfavorable in regards to her.
Regarding the Witness Protection Program...
You may know about it from movies or some books, but...
Your name, personal history, and address...
Everything will be changed to someone else.
It will free you from this life of constantly being on the run from those that are after you.
In the future, you'll have enough income and welfare benefits...
To be assured of a comfortable life.
Of course, it is all up to you whether to accept it.
Once you accept it...
You will no longer be able to meet with nor even call your family and friends ever again.
If you fear that woman's vengeance...
And do not wish to involve your friends...
I await your positive reply.
What's wrong, Haibara?
Did you catch another cold?
Not that.
I just haven't been walking outside for a long while.
I feel a little tired is all.
Well, my house is this way.
Until tomorrow!
See you in school!
Yeah!
Ouch...
He's the phantom killer!
Someone, capture him!
Ayumi-chan's voice?
What happened?
Ayumi-chan!
Ayumi-chan?
I see.
Then, you don't remember what that person looked like?
Because it's a rainy day...
And he was wearing a raincoat...
And a hat...
I was really scared and couldn't see what he looked like.
The lady whose arm was slashed also said she didn't see his face.
Based on the modus operandi...
It's likely the same culprit from the last three cases, but...
His clothing is different from before.
I heard him say "Oh—"!
It's definitely a man!
But, with only his yelling voice to go by...
At any rate, let's go conduct a physical investigation at the crime scene now.
Maybe you'll recall something?
This is the place...
The place where I bumped into the phantom killer.
And we ran over when we heard Ayumi-chan's screaming.
So, it was because of Mitsuhiko-kun and the others that the culprit ran away?
That's not it.
He already ran away before that.
Really?
Before running off, he rushed toward me and gave me a huge shock...
"Rushed toward you"?
Later, I heard another "Clink!" sound...
I think he must have picked up something.
Could he have dropped some change?
Or his glasses, or his house keys, or something?
It could also be necklaces, bracelets, and the like...
Do you know what the culprit picked up?
But, I think it has something to do with the number 5.
The number 5?
Because on the palm of my right hand...
A mark shaped like the number 5 was left behind.
Later, I looked all over the sidewalk, but...
I couldn't find anything that had been dropped.
Can you draw the mark?
I can.
It was...
Shaped like this.
It doesn't look like a 50 or a 500-yen coin, huh?
It could also be the letter S from the alphabet.
Well, at any rate...
Let's find a match for this mark.
It could be a game coin from some pachinko parlor.
Over there!
Bastard!
Excuse me!
Like I'd let you get away!
Damn it!
There are too many onlookers!
Over there!
The man wearing a raincoat!
Found him!
He's the phantom killer!
Wait!
That man is—
Takagi-kun.
It really is Detective Takagi.
That was mean...
Say, Takagi-kun...
Did a man wearing a raincoat run past here?
There are people like that everywhere...
It was just raining a bit ago.
But it was daring of him...
To return to where the police are conducting an on-scene investigation while wearing the raincoat.
Yeah.
The culprit probably figured that no one would expect him to return to the scene in the same clothes.
Could he have thought Ayumi saw his face and wanted to come back to deal with her?
It's not that.
He came back because he was confident no one saw his face.
But for what reason?
No idea.
Perhaps he left something behind at the scene he shouldn't have?
Or could it have been to confirm something?
Damn...
I just realized I got splashed.
At any rate, it's important to first find out about this mark that Ayumi-chan drew...
Hey!
Genta-kun!
On Genta-kun's butt...
Did my pants tear?
No!
The mark of the phantom killer is on it.
Are you serious?
That means you came into contact with the culprit somewhere, doesn't it?
Hey, hurry and remember, Genta-kun!
Where was it, exactly?
Come on! Please answer, Genta-kun!
Where did you get it?
Exactly where was it you got the phantom killer's mark on your butt?!
But is this really the phantom killer's mark?
Yeah.
It's identical to the mark left by whatever the culprit dropped.
I just happened to put my hand on it...
The culprit then panicked and snatched it back up before running away.
Afterwards, that very same mark was left on my palm.
In other words, Kojima-kun has come into contact with the culprit or his belongings somewhere...
Possibly in the crowd of onlookers just now, where the culprit—wearing a raincoat—ran away in a fluster...
When Kojima-kun gave chase.
But even if you say that...
Tripping over someone's bag in such a huge crowd...
Or stumbling and colliding with their bicycle...
Doesn't mean that person is the criminal!
Not to mention...
No, nothing...
It's possible that mark from a bag or bicycle...
Is the same as the mark on something the culprit owns.
That means it could be a name-brand product.
Anyway, let's head back to the crime scene and ask the people around.
The person with the bag or the one with the bicycle may still be there.
Sato-san?
Hey, Conan-kun, let's go.
Yeah...
This is strange...
This mark on Genta's butt...
I've seen it before...
Ah, over there!
I tripped over that man's bag just then!
But, there isn't a corresponding mark on it...
And this bag isn't dirty at all.
It doesn't seem to be the one, does it?
The mark on Genta is covered with mud, so...
Speaking of being covered in mud, isn't the bicycle more suspicious?
Where is that bicycle?
Let's see...
It's that person!
That lady!
While the bicycle is indeed covered in mud...
That mark doesn't appear to be on it.
Where exactly could you have gotten this mark that looks like a 5 or an S?
It's neither 5 nor S.
The marks on Ayumi-chan's hand and Genta's butt are most likely mirror images of the actual shape.
In other words, the actual shape should be the reverse of 5 or S.
Oh, I see...
Something more is the size of the mark.
Something that could leave such a large mark on Ayumi-chan's palm...
It should be possible to figure that out.
No...
The one in my hand was much smaller.
On this part of my right hand, about the size of a 1-yen coin.
In that case...
The two marks are of the same design but found on different objects?
If it's something that small...
Is it an accessory of the same brand?
Mirror image...
Accessory...
This mark on her cuff is...
Could it be...
Sato-san!
This is it!
This is the mark!
The car's...
Yeah.
That mark came from letting the car go unwashed after driving a muddy road.
That's right, Genta-kun was sitting on the bonnet of Detective Sato's car earlier.
Why didn't you tell us immediately?
Actually, I thought about it at the beginning, but...
I kept quiet about it.
Because I never...
Never thought...
I never thought Detective Sato would turn out to be the phantom killer!
I'm not...
The culprit must have the same make of car as I do.
Then, the mark left on my palm is...
It belongs to the key of this make of car.
The car's master key has a cover with the mark etched on it.
Look!
It's true!
As proof, look at Ayumi-chan's cuff.
Isn't there a sawtooth pattern on it?
It's true.
This is probably the mud from the key...
That was left on her cuff after she pressed on it.
No, this isn't mud.
Its color changed to black...
This is—Blood...
Don't tell me...
That a possible reason the culprit returned to the scene was...
Yeah.
It was likely to check if Ayumi had seen the mark.
He should've realized it as well.
When he sees my car, he'll know it's only a matter of time before he's exposed.
Then, the culprit will escape if we don't act fast!
Takagi-kun!
Contact Inspector Megure immediately!
Have him cordon off this area!
Check all cars with the same mark that are leaving this area!
Yes!
Also, include everyone in the area who owns a car sporting the same mark.
For someone who'd risk being recognized by coming back to confirm if his car make had been identified...
There's a high possibility that he's in a nearby car park or garage.
Understood!
But...
If there are a lot of that kind of car around here...
Would it not be difficult to find them all?
No, there shouldn't be too many.
The make of car that has this logo on both the vehicle and the key...
Went out of production seven, eight years ago.
It's a relatively old model.
And, it was raining at the time of the crime.
The car should be wet.
There shouldn't be too many around with no alibi that also happened to lose their car's master key.
Why does the culprit not have the car's master key?
Could he have dropped it at that time?
The key-shaped blood stain on Ayumi-chan's sleeve...
That's the evidence the culprit held the key in his bloodstained hands while escaping.
In other words...
The key that will respond to a blood test...
Will never be shown to the police.
What is this about, Takagi-kun?
Weren't you full of confidence that this method would uncover the culprit?
Idiot...
We're not investigating the key.
Everyone connected to you may be the victim of the culprit's vengeance.
As I thought, I should go over to take a look.
Hey, open up!
Bye-bye.
Find the Buttock's Mark
(Part Two)
Key Cylinder
Next Conan's Hint
Next time is...
Genta-kun's butt!
Stop it!
Genta-kun's butt! Genta-kun's butt!