One rainy day, on the way home from school...
Ayumi-chan collided with an escaping phantom killer.
Even though she couldn't see his face...
She had a mark on her hand that resembled the number 5 from something the culprit owned.
And then...
We found the same mark on Genta's butt.
Could it be...
This is it!
This is the mark!
The key-shaped blood stain on Ayumi-chan's sleeve...
That's the evidence the culprit held the key in his bloodstained hands while escaping.
In other words...
The key that will respond to a blood test...
Will never be shown to the police.
FIND THE BUTTOCK'S MARK
(PART TWO)
Only three?
Really, Inspector Megure?
Apparently, one was detained at a checkpoint and the other two were found cruising nearby.
The car owners are all residents of the area without alibis...
And they all claim to have lost their master keys.
At any rate...
I've had the three of them drive their cars over to your location.
You've gotten a look at this phantom killer before, haven't you?
I'll leave the identification to you.
Understood.
The three suspects are on their way here now.
That's as good as knowing who the culprit is!
Ayumi-chan heard the culprit yelling before.
When that guy sees Ayumi, he might just turn pale from fright!
That's right!
Ayumi will do her IJest!
I object.
If the culprit truly is among those three...
And you do meet him directly...
If that results in his arrest, it'll be fine, but...
If he is acquitted due to a lack of evidence, what will your plan be then?
The culprit will bear a grudge for placing him in this predicament...
And target you.
It's possible he'll exact his revenge on you someday.
All the more so with an indiscriminate phantom killer, don't you think?
You're thinking too much, Haibara-san.
That's why I say you shouldn't get involved so recklessly without substantial evidence.
But, I was the nearest and the only person to see the culprit...
If you have the three of them wear raincoats...
I may be able to identify the culprit.
In that case, you can also identify him from photographs, right?
For his voice, listening to a tape recording will do.
In any case...
Don't come into direct contact with the culprit so he doesn't get a stronger impression of you.
Indeed, as Haibara said, it is too risky to confront the culprit directly.
Even so, it wasn't easy to narrow it down to just three, so it'd be bad to release them with few questions.
Moreover, there may be more victims.
Shall we take the middle road and try looking at them secretly?
All right.
Over here.
Stop!
Now, step out of your cars one at a time...
State your name and occupation...
And tell me, from the time of the crime, around 2:00 PM...
Just what you were doing.
Starting from you, on the furthest left.
Jeez...
They said it was to help with an investigation...
Yet we're being treated like criminals.
Enomoto Hiroshi (21)
Part-Time Sushi Shop Employee.
I'm Enomoto Hiroshi...
A university student working part-time at a sushi shop in the 3rd District.
You bought this working part-time?
This car?
No, this was bought with my parents money.
There a problem with that?
I see now.
It isn't possible for them to see us through the smoked glass.
And?
Do you remember hearing that man's voice?
It seems familiar, and yet doesn't...
I'm off duty today.
After getting scolded by my parents last night, I was feeling annoyed.
Just when I decided to go to the mountains to relax...
I was held up by your investigation.
"Relax in the mountains?
Well...
That place's nice scenery makes it great for relaxing.
That explains the dents and mud on the body of your car.
Then, next is you in the middle.
Yes!
Don't dent my car!
I'm sorry...
I'm not very good at driving...
But I'm good at repairs.
Then, your occupation is...
Fukuchi Naokazu (36)
Car Mechanic.
Yes...
I'm a mechanic at a car repair shop, Fukuchi Naokazu.
The shop is closed today, but...
Something's wrong with my beloved car, so I've been trying to repair it at work since morning.
But, according to the report, you cruised around downtown for quite some time...
In order to check whether the car had been fully repaired...
I was just taking a few turns around the shopping district.
Something wrong with that?
Oh, no...
Next.
My name is Degawa Toshiaki.
Degawa Toshiaki (43)
Lock Shop Owner.
I own a lock shop in the 1st District.
And still, I lost the master key to my car.
The blunder of my life, indeed.
But your car, unlike the other two, is clean and sparkling.
Oh, I wash it every time I go out.
This car is the only thing I live for, after all.
And, where did you go this afternoon?
There was a call out for helping open the door for someone who'd lost her house keys.
The woman was really bad at giving directions, so I circled around for ages looking for the address.
But, in the end, I didn't manage to meet up her.
She called again to say her boyfriend had brought the spare, so she was fine now.
Hey, did you notice anything?
Nothing at all.
And none of them yelled either.
The three of them are of similar height and build.
Hey, you over there!
Why are you sneaking about?
Ah, well...
Detective Takagi!
I have a favor to ask...
What is it?
About that, a little...
As I thought, I should go over to take a look.
If I'm right beside them, I may be able to recognize the culprit.
Don't.
Didn't I already say?
If the culprit isn't convicted...
There's the possibility that it could become dangerous.
But...
It's not only you.
Everyone connected to you may fall victim to the culprit's vengeance.
I understand your feelings of wanting to bring the bad guy to justice, but do bear with it.
It also requires courage to hide oneself.
Right...
This is the correct choice.
For your own sake...
And for others.
Just like that, all right?
Ask the forensics team to bring a flathead screwdriver?
That should make it clear.
Clear that the one who tried to cover his crime with petty tricks...
Is not only a liar, but also the phantom killer.
Right...
It's that one.
Well, for the time being...
The three of you will have to leave your cars in police custody.
There are more investigations to carry out.
Hey, hey!
You must be kidding!
We're here to assist the Beika police with an investigation!
Why do we gotta turn over our cars?
And, I hope you can give us an explanation as to...
Why we got called all the way out here to be treated as suspects in the phantom killer case...
If it's solely because we lack alibis for the time of the crime...
There should be a ton of other suspects apart from us three.
First of all, it's your cars.
All of them are of the same make, no?
Yeah.
Moreover, all three of you stated that you had lost your master keys.
While escaping, the culprit dropped the master key with the unique emblem of this make of car on it.
In addition...
We were tipped off that the culprit took the key into his then bloodstained hands.
We also learned that the culprit returned to the scene to check if his identity had been exposed.
Once we pieced this together and began investigating, we assumed he'd be aware of the suspicion...
And we also determined that it's highly likely that the culprit is a resident of this neighborhood.
This is all according to information obtained from an eyewitness.
In other words...
The one with this make of car...
With no alibi...
And is a resident of this neighborhood...
Who cannot produce their bloodstained master key to the police...
Among you three, that one is the culprit.
But, I really lost my key...
Well, regarding that, the truth will be revealed with only a simple check...
By the forensics team.
A "check"?
What the-
It's only a Luminol reaction test.
Now, Detective Takagi...
Please start.
Yeah.
Well then...
Please proceed as we discussed on the phone.
Understood.
Let's start from Enomoto-san on the furthest left.
Hey, hey!
You're not thinking of looking for the master key by rummaging around my car, are you?
That's too much, even for the police...
We won't be inspecting the interior of the car.
Say, Conan-kun...
Exactly what are you investigating?
If I were the culprit...
I would have thrown away the bloodstained key.
Idiot...
We're not investigating the key.
We're looking to see if, when the culprit escaped from the scene via their car...
They inserted the key itself into the driver's side door.
I see!
It should have been stained with blood as well, right?
But...
If there was only a little stain...
Will it really still show up.
Absolutely.
Luminol is very sensitive to it and will react to even the slightest presence of blood.
Right, the culprit may try to hide this...
And might have lied or done something on the sly.
Lied? On the sly?
Try and reca.
What did the three of them each say they were doing during the time of the crime?
Let me see...
Enomoto-san said he was going to the mountains for a drive...
Fukuchi-san said he wanted to test his car repairs and cruised around the shopping area...
Degawa-san said he was looking for the house of a client who'd lost her keys...
And ended up going around in circles downtown.
How did these people lie?
Well, take a look.
Degawa-san, who treats his car as though it were his life, has his clean and sparkling...
Fukuchi-san, who is bad at driving, parked his car extremely close to the one next to his...
And Enomoto-san, who likes driving, has a car covered with numerous dents and a lot of mud.
Get it yet?
Not at all.
Well, if Genta wanted to practice biking, what would you do?
Of course I would practice it when Mom's around.
Probably on a road people hardly use.
It'd be dangerous to run into someone.
Ah, I see!
Fukuchi-san is lying!
If he's bad at driving...
He wouldn't have driven downtown where there are lots of people!
Moreover, at the time of the crime, it was raining and visibility was poor.
Test driving the car repairs under those conditions would be the worst course of action.
Furthermore, Fukuchi-san managed to align his car neatly with the one opposite his.
This is proof of his superb driving skills.
If he were so poor at driving, it'd have been at least slightly slanted.
In that case, could it be that the culprit is the lying Fukuchi-san?
Yeah.
He parked exceptionally close in order to make it difficult to investigate the keyhole.
But this will be his last-ditch struggle.
Look.
If you move the adjacent car slightly...
The keyhole on the driver's side door is accessible.
And when you conduct a Luminol test on the keyhole, you'll find...
The bluish-purple fluorescent reaction that occurs from the interaction of Luminol and blood.
That's odd...
There's no reaction.
No way!
Really?
Wait...
What's going on, Takagi-kun?
Weren't you full of confidence that this method would uncover the culprit?
Well, it should have worked, but...
Hey, Mister...
May I borrow a flathead screwdriver?
A flathead screwdriver?
Here.
Thank you.
Well?
Are you satisfied now?
Since there weren't positive reactions from any of our cars...
Can you let us go now?
It's obvious none of us is the phantom killer.
Now, now - please calm down.
What happened, Conan-kun?
It's different from what you-
Where's Conan-kun?
He just went over to where you were.
In order to borrow a flathead screwdriver from one of the forensics people.
When you press down on this keyhole, it moves...
Why is that so?
Hey, little boy!
The key cylinder was lined with vinyl tape!
I see now.
He predicted it would be investigated by the police...
So he installed another car's key cylinder temporarily.
Then...
The real reason he parked so close to the car beside his...
He wanted to hide this.
If you don't open the door and remove the outer cover like this...
It's impossible to evaluate the internal part of the key cylinder.
Then, could it be...
Conan-kun predicted this at the start...
Ah, no...
This really is this car's key cylinder!
Because I carelessly broke it while installing it...
I decided to just secure it like this before buying a new one!
Then, can we have a look?
At the car keys.
And also the key number engraved on the key.
As a car mechanic, you should know about it.
There's a number engraved on the key cylinder on the driver's side.
Once we compare that with what's on the key, we can tell if it's the original set or not.
Additionally...
We could also use some Luminol reagent on the ignition keyhole near the steering wheel.
It will definitely react positively for blood.
The lock for the engine is very secure...
And isn't something that can be changed in such a short timeframe.
I understand.
I will have to show you the key number...
About that, I remember the key was in the glove box...
Hey, open up!
When asked about his motive later, the guy said...
He wanted to commit a noteworthy crime to garner the world's attention.
As well as to spice up the mundanity of everyday life.
However, since in this series of phantom killer cases, there were no fatalities...
That doesn't redeem him at all.
At any rate...
The crimes committed by this dumb, attention-seeking criminal...
Generated only a small disturbance for the police around Beika...
And ended on a quiet note.
But, thank goodness!
The culprit was captured!
Now Ayumi-chan doesn't have to worry about being targeted.
It'd be OK, even if I was targeted.
Because Conan-kun would protect me.
Hey, hey...
Of course...
I can depend on Mitsuhiko-kun, Genta-kun, and Ai-chan too.
I'd be fine!
Yeah...
Sorry.
I need to attend to something.
Bye-bye.
Bye-bye!
See you later!
Oh, I'm so glad...
That you've come to visit me.
If I give it any more time...
I might change my mind again.
Then, you've already decided whether you want to accept the Witness Protection Program offer?
Yes.
Of course.
Of course...
I refuse.
Indeed, it may be safer to become someone else by changing my name and address, but...
In the end, it will all repeat again.
To stay in hiding and to live in fear...
If my identity seems exposed, I have to become someone else yet again.
There's no end in sight.
Moreover...
There's no proof that I should completely trust in the FBI.
And...
I understand your feelings of wanting to bring the bad guy to justice, but...
It also requires courage to hide oneself.
But...
But I...
I don't want to run away!
If I keep on running away, I can't win!
It's because I don't want to run away...
As I expected...
You're not going to object?
Yeah.
As an FBI agent, I'm entirely against it, of course.
But...
As a girl who was once on the run for her life...
I hope that you can treasure those feelings right now.
Do your best.
See you.
Geez...
Itis as though I was looking at the younger you.
The you who kept refusing to join the Witness Protection Program...
And instead insisted on joining the FBI as a condition for accepting.
That's different, James.
That which I lacked at that time...
It seems she already has it.
Right...
While it's extremely hazardous and is something that could become a disaster...
It's stil really heartwarming and conceals great courage.
There's this feeling of nostalgia...
This is what they call "Nosutara Jiji, huh?
Beware of fire hazards!
Huh?
Where's Ayumi?
Wait, don't leave me behind!
Could it be...
A WORLDLY INHERITANCE
(PART ONE)
NEXT CONAN
S HINT