This place sure has character!
It feels like it's from a long time ago!
That "nostalajiji" thing, right?
Come on, Genta-kun.
It's called "nostalgia.
When did that change?
How old are you guys again?
At the very least, it's a village that fits the image of one that's soon to be registered as a World Heritage site.
Yeah, but it seems it's become popular and gotten more tourism recently for a differentreason. >
What's that, Conan-kun?
A different reason?
That would be...
Thiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiissssssssss!
Geez, everyone's making fun of me...
So the other reason is because of ghosts?
About half a year ago...
A number of people came out and said they saw the ghost of a child, leading to the spread of the rumor.
As a token of appreciation for solving a case, we got the rare opportunity to go on this tour...
Try to taste the ancientness of Japan!
I guess there's no helping it...
I'm gonna go taste the beer!
Welcome!
This again.
LOVE, GHOSTS, AND WORLD HERITAGE
(TPJ li)
(PART ONE)
It gets more and more amazing!
It's almost as if we've gone back in time!
We're staying here tonight?
Minshuku are old-style Japanese lodgings, similar to bed-and-breakfasts.
It's a World Heritage site and minshuku at the same time!
It's really just like Old Japan!
It's divided into three levels, isn't it?
It looks like there are more rooms than you'd think from outside.
I wonder if that means it belonged to a large family long ago...
This is...
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
This foundation stone and the soil around it are new...
Considering that this sort of house must have been built a hundred years ago...
Oh, is this the place?
I guess these people are staying here together with us.
Good day!
Nice to meet you!
A minshuku with a steeply sloped roof!
Fumiko's so excited!
Yeah, Kanako too!
What a dirty old place.
Kawaji Kensaku (37)
Tourist.
I sure hope there's a bath.
But as far as air conditioning...
I guess that's too much to ask for!
What a creep!
Fumiko, he'll hear you!
Did you say ladies say something?
Will you stop it?
Grow up!
You're being a bother to others!
What'd you say?
I'm being a bother?
Don't leave anything out, you bastards...
You're the one being shameful.
Shameful, you say?
Bastard, who the hell're you?
Not "bastard."
My name is Mouri Kogorou.
Mouri?
Is that the...
Great Detective, Sleeping Kogorou...
I am called that...
Well, not by choice.
Did you hearthat?
Not by choice," he said.
I heard nothing.
ioiuosa/v\v.
Fumiko's so excited!
You're a celebrity, Mouri-san!
Now, now, that's enough!
With you young ladies shaking me about, my beer's going to spill!
My name is Sakaki Shoukichi.
It's an honor to meet you, Mouri-san.
I am Kuwashima Kazuaki.
Nice to meet you!
Pleasure to meet all of you!
That's not interesting at all.
Uhm, sir...
What is it?
Nagakura Iwao (50) Master of the Minshuku.
Sir, your lodging is at Ishioka-san's place, one house down.
Should've said that in the first place!
This pork nabe is delicious!
The iwana is also yummy!
Yum, yum!
The miso soup smells wonderful!
It warms the soul, doesn't it?
All righ't!
In the wintertime, it's got to be hot sake!
Here you go.
Sorry to trouble you.
Don't mess with me!
Publishing this kind of thing...
We don't need that here!
Dear!
You're being rude to our guests!
I apologize.
We've been having a few problems lately...
I wonder what's wrong.
It's this, Ran-neechan.
This article.
What does this magazine have to do with it?
"World Heritage, and Ghost Infestation"?
"Local Residents Disturbed by Preposterous Goings-On"...
Ghosts, how outrageous!
It's a bother to us!
Yes, sir...
Isn't that right?
If you're going to talk about World Heritage, it should be about the assets of humanity that the world is proud of!
It must be a real headache for you!
People who come to see that sort of frivolous thing are just far too rude!
Here.
It must be tough—here, drink up!
No, as the master of this minshuku, I should be the one serving you all...
As expected of Mouri-san!
You're absolutely right!
Here, a refill.
Oh, thanks.
Drown your sorrows!
Drink up!
Hey, hey... It's started.
Well, we'll be going then.
Excuse us.
Goodnight!
Nice meeting you!
All right, let's drink, let's drink!
It was delicious!
Conan-kun, we should turn in as well.
Yeah.
What should we do?
You think we'll be able to?
Probably!
We have to determine whether or not the ghosts are real!
All right!
Of course!
That's why we came, after all!
Right, Conan-kun?
Sounds like fun!
Have a good time.
I'll pass, and be reading in the room.
Haibara!
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
Nothing in particular.
Oh yeah, we're going to go out and stroll around for a bit!
At this time?
It's not that late yet.
And plus, it's also one of the specialties of this place!
Beware of fire!
Scary, but pretty!
It wouldn't be strange even if that did show up!
They do this every night, huh?
Everyone takes shifts and they go around like this...
Yeah.
Fire is the main enemy of these sort of houses with thatched roofs.
There's no choice but to have everyone look out after each other.
Having everyone in the village take responsibility and cooperate...
It's better than just hoping for the best, right?
Nothing out of the ordinary!
Thank you very much.
Beware of fire!
Who's there?
Hey, who are you?
Beware of fire...
Huh, where'd Ayumi go?
She was just with us...
Ayumi-chan!
Geez, I guess we gotta... Ayumi-chan!
Ayumi! Ayumi-chan!
She was with us until around here, right?
I wonder if she just got hungry and went back alone...
Geez, she's not you, Genta-kun!
You think so?
Over there...
Is she there?
It's Ayumi-chan's scarf!
There's no doubt about it!
What's your name?
Who are you?
Wait, don't leave me behind...
Wait!
Ayumi-chan?
Sorry, even though we were with her...
Anyway, we came back because we thought it'd be better if we got a large group to search for her...
I understand.
Let's all split up and search for her!
Dad!
Geez... Come on, Dad...
Excuse my husband for not being able to stop when he's had enough alcohol...
I'll let the people of the village know, and have them help search!
Sorry for the trouble, thank you!
I'll help as well.
What's wrong?
Something happen?
I can help, you know.
No thanks, it's fine!
I don't stink, you know!
Ayumi-chan!
Ayumi!
Found her!
At the roots of the Japanese cedar tree at the Water God shrine!
Ayumi-chan!
Hang in there, Ayumi-chan!
Huh, Conan-kun...
Ayumi!
Are you all right?
Huh, everyone...
Does it hurt anywhere?
It doesn't look like you're injured, but...
I'm completely all right...
Can you talk for a bit?
Just what happened?
Well...
You met a girl?
Yeah...
About ten years old, with bobbed hair...
And a red skirt.
That's ridiculous.
That can't be...
Nagakura-san...
She must have come to visit with Eiji...
Mami-chan, that is.
Mami-chan?
Is that child called Mami-chan?
That's right.
Mami-chan was a childhood friend of the late Eiji...
They were only a year apart, and very close...
IM Dt00
She believed in Eiji's innocence, and came to visit!
Mami-chan did...
Innocence?
Geta hold of yourself!
Little Miss, you were mistaken.
That is definite!
Why is that?
I'm sure I saw her!
Do you not trust her, Mister?
Ayumi-chan isn't a child that tells lies!
Everybody, calm down...
Why are you so convinced that she's mistaken...
Mister?
It's obvious.
Both of them...
Eiji last month...
And that child has been dead for ten years already!
She passed away ten years ago?
It's as we thought...
Ghost!
Geez...
Sorry, I just thought I'd join in on the story...
As we thought...
Scary...
It's all right, Keiko.
What's all this uproar about?
Geez, Dad, what are you doing at a time like this?
You all...
Did someone put you up to this?
Dear!
I see!
Must have been that lot...
"That lot"?
I'm not being taken in by that!
I won't do as you wish!
Never!
Moreover, Eiji...
That person is no son of mine!
I'll have you remember that!
You... Eiji would be so sad—
You, shut up!
Please calm down, sir...
You can just let it go...
That's right, don't be so angry—let's all just have a drink...
Just leave me alone!
It certainly seems that there's something here, in this village.
And not just a ghost.
Yeah.
It seems like it's worth investigating, doesn't it?
Right?
You were a ghost?
Mami-chan...
Otozawa-san, is it...
This is the house where Mami-chan's family lived until ten years ago.
I hear she was an only child.
Hey, Ayumi-chan!
It seems that Mami-chan died of illness...
And right after that, they say her mom and dad moved somewhere.
There aren't any photographs or anything left here...
I guess since it was ten years ago, there wouldn't be.
If there were some photographs, you could determine whether what Yoshida-san saw was real or not, right?
That's exactly it!
As expected of Haibara-san!
"Real or not"?
Are you talking about the ghost?
Hey, hey, don't tell me even you're...
You don't believe it, Conan-kun?
Look here!
As a detective, I use logic and reasoning to determine things!
As far as ghosts...
I never said anything like that!
You don't believe Yoshida-san...
That's what we're hearing from the two of you.
No, I...
Ayumi-chan!
I'll remember this, Conan!
Geez...
What's left is the person named "Eiji".
Yeah.
He committed suicide?
Nagakura Eiji?
Yeah, no doubt about it.
Like you asked...
I researched whether or not the name "Nagakura Eiji" appeared in the newspapers with connection to any crime...
Jewel Thief Suicide —
Nagakura Eiji (20)
And there it was.
Homicide in Shoujin-Town
Due to death of suspect, half year case concluded
Let me see...
The incident occurred exactly half a year ago...
The town of Shoujin is right next to the Onizawa area, where you all are now.
He probably felt he'd be found out by the police from the fingerprints left at the scene...
And had no other means of escape.
Nagakura Eiji was a jewel thief who committed suicide.
However, his mother believes in her son's innocence.
We can understand why the people of the village weren't forthcoming about it.
Conan-kun...
I'm not lying, so...
Since I really saw her...
And I really want you, Conan-kun,to believe me...
That is...
You want us to investigate it, right?
Yeah!
Let's do it then!
If doing so will satisfy you.
Haibara, you...
Edogawa-kun.
Yes, ma'am.
Even so, this is really a creepy place, isn't it?
I met Mami-chan at the place I pointed out earlier, and as if she were inviting me, we came to this Water God shrine.
And then, what happened?
Ayumi?
She disappeared.
Disappeared?
Just like that, she disappeared.
After that, I never met her again.
Sometime while I was calling for Mami-chan...
I guess I got tired and fell asleep at the root of this Japanese cedar tree.
Where did she disappear, exactly?
The fog was thick...
It was around the side of that Water God shrine.
It's still new, isn't it?
If I remember correctly, Tamai is one of the minshuku on the main street.
So that's what it was!
This yukata rode, fluttering, on the wind...
And that's what Ayumi mistook for...
What are you saying, Genta-kun?
There's no way laundry could have flown all the way here!
I didn't mistake it!
I definitely saw Mami-chan!
I believe you, Ayumi-chan.
It was just a coincidence!
A coincidence!
Hey, hey—it was you guys in the first place that...
That person, from yesterday...
Just what is he doing?
Beware of fire!
A person's footsteps...
It came!
They really do exist...
Ghosts lacking feet is a common Asian belief.
But ghosts don't have feet, Genta-kun!
Oh, that's right.
Then...
You guys, stay here.
We're coming too!
Then be quiet!
You...
There's nothing out of the ordinary here.
It must be the topmost floor.
Bastard!
What were you
doing?
Nagakura-san!
Call an ambulance!
The police too!
Got it!
We understand!
Ran-neechan!
Over there...
Mami-chan...
You really existed...
Where are you going!?
Could it be...
The ghost attacked Nagakura-san>?