Dear!
Please hang in there!
Don't let go!
Ma'am, please calm down.
Wait, hold on!
This is...
These aren't marks of having been hit or having been grazed...
What the hell is it?
Here, don't get in the way, little one.
Sorry.
Gifu Fire & Disaster Management Agency.
He's unconscious, and in serious condition, huh...
Well, even if they try for it at the hospital, getting a statement will be hard...
Even so, it almost looked as if he just passed out...
Having drunktoo much, sound asleep...
Oh, excuse me.
Sakaki Shoukichi (52)
Mouri-san solves cases while he's asleep, doesn't he?
Ah, well...
Mouri?
You're the Sleeping Kogoro, Mouri Kogoro-san, aren't you?
The detective!
The Great Detective, yes.
Excuse me!
I have already obtained permission from the higher ups.
Please, by all means, help us with our investigation!
From the higher ups...
Well, well...
LOVE, GHOSTS, AND WORLD HERITAGE
(PART TWO)
Even though the village is going to be registered as a World Heritage site soon...
For an incident like this to happen...
Actually, I was also born in this village.
I'd like to resolve this case as soon as possible.
Please, Mouri-san!
Understood!
To be asked such a thing so passionately...
Please allow myself, Mouri Kogoro, to offer my utmost assistance.
Thank you very much!
You can count on me!
Then, getting right to the point, Mouri-san...
The culprit is?
It wouldn't be the ghost, would it?
What're you talking about?
Of course not!
No, was just talking to myself.
Then, that means, as we thought...
Yeah, that's right.
It was that person!
ButConan-kun saw her too, right?
Mami-chan.
No, it was just something that looked like it.
Are you going to say it was laundry again?
But, thanks to Ayumi-chan mistakenly seeing her, we know what direction the culprit fled.
If it was this direction, then it's a dead end.
It seems that it wouldn't be possible to leave the village.
Then that means...
That the culprit has not yet left this village!
And what's more, at this late hour...
It's unthinkable that they purposely entered this village from outside.
Including the tourists, the culprit must be someone inside this Onizawa area!
You all—who...
Please pay them no mind.
What they've said, even an amateur could have figured out.
That's right.
Don't get in the way, you guys.
Rather, there is something much more serious that we should observe.
And, that is.
The culprit, while sightseeing during the day, tied and hid a rope there in advance.
Then, at night, they used it to sneak in from the outside.
Which would mean...
The culprit is someone other than those staying in the Nagakura home where Mouri-san's party is staying...
In other words, someone that is lodging elsewhere.
Is that correct?
As expected of Mouri-san!
What a splendid job you've done!
Oh, it was nothing!
Well, if that's the case...
Anyway, the question is...
What was the culprit doing there?
We should look there!
Genta-kun, please don't push!
Hurry, hurry!
We still have to go up one more floor!
Wasn't he just an ordinary burglar?
Butthen, just what would he have been trying to steal from here?
I guess I really did see it wrong...
Even though Conan-kun was there, he also felt that way...
But...
It wasn't that they were necessarily trying to steal anything...
MBiog's to mtelfeg
were searching for something.
Just what was it?
Nothing in particular.
I was just thinking that from here, you can clearly see where Nagakura-san was attacked.
If we can see it clearly from here, then that means the opposite is also true, right?
Is that how it was!?
What'd you say?
Conan-kun, did something happen?
Hey, hold on, kid!
As I thought...
There's no mistaking it.
What's with this?
Don't touch!
You'll get poisoned!
It's a lacquer tree, isn't it?
If I remember correctly, Nagakura-san's hands were...
Yeah.
That means, Nagakura-san passed here yesterday.
What the heck is that?
That's the creepy guy from the day before yesterday...
Could it bethat person attacked Nagakura-san?
Even so...
Why are the people of the village arguing?
As for that, I know why.
Before I came here, I read it in a magazine...
It seems that originally, there was opposition to this village being registered as a World Heritage site.
A group against it said there was no need for higher levels of tourism...
And a group for it, saying they wanted to have the world know about the village's existence.
Nagakura-san was the representative forthat pro-registration group.
I see.
So what Nagakura-san said then...
You all...
Did someone put you up to this?
Dear!
I see!
M ust have been that lot...
So "that lot" must have been in reference to the opposition group!
Please calm down, everyone!
Please leave this matter to the police, and return to your homes!
How is this possible?
We have things to say about the village!
He's getting away!
An investigator?
It seems he was sent here from the World Heritage site registration committee or something...
I've heard of that before.
Their job is to impartially investigate whether a site is worthy of being registered or not...
All while hiding their identity.
I see.
But in that person's case, it seems that wasn't all he was doing...
You went around to each municipality and collected bribes from them under the guise of heavy travel expenses.
Isn't that right, Kawaji-san?
What is that about?
Kawaji Kensaku (37)
Tourist
Don't play dumb!
We've even received reports of damage!
The evidence is piling up!
You also requested a commission from Nagakura-san, but it went sour, so you...
That's what happened, right?
Don't make jokes!
I did ask for money.
And it's also true that I was refused.
That's why I gave up, and, having decided to leave today, went to bed early.
I never set one foot outside!
That you would give up so easily...
Who would believe that?
I decided for myself to give up!
Because I knew from many years of experience that if I kept pressing, I wouldn't be able to get any more money!
Look at this!
This is...
It's Nagakura-san's patrol log.
According to the route for that day, up until the 9th house, all the seals were stamped.
Where Nagakura-san was discovered, and where the crime occured, was on the way to the 9th house.
Right next to Ishioka-san's house, where you were staying!
I don't know anything about that!
Besides, I wasn't the one who decided that I'd be lodging at that house!
Was there anyone who saw you sleeping?
It was a single room, so there wasn't anyone...
But it wasn't me!
I wouldn't do something as ridiculous as stabbing anyone!
In the end, Kawaji Kensaku...
Was taken to the station as a person of interest in the blackmailing an attempted murder cases.
But, as far as being a suspect in the attempted murder, it was too early to tell.
As far as being suspected of breaking into the Nagakura residence, they were willing to let it slide.
It seemed as if the case was resolved, but...
Thank you very much!
Thanks to you, we were able to arrest the suspect, Kawaji!
How about it, then?
Let's have a drink!
Geez...
Is what I'd like to say, but I do have to continue with the investigation.
That's true, that's true.
It's been a string of misfortunes for Nagakura-san's family, hasn't it?
It's good that we were able to resolve it quickly.
A string of misfortunes?
You're talking about his son, Nagakura Eiji, right?
It seems like it was quite an ordeal.
Jewel Thief Suicide.
Robbery-Murder Case in Shoujin-Town.
Due to death of suspect, half year case concluded!
That must be it...
She believed in Eiji's innocence, and came to visit!
Mami-chan, that is...
Moreover, Eiji...
That person is no son of mine!
I'll have you remember that!
Well, anyway...
After that happened, ten days ago...
As a new starting point, they re-thatched the thirty-year-old roof, and...
They moved the house to its present location.
They moved it?
What'd you say?
They moved such a big house?
So that's why the foundation stones were new!
But that wasn't the only thing we were surprised to find out.
What was that!?
Until about half a month ago, the Nagakura home stood here?
That's right.
It seems that they moved it from here to its present location.
They switched it out completely with the Otozawa home that originally stood there.
Why did they do such a thing?
He said something about starting over...
Rather, that place is the best place in the village as far as appearances go.
As the representative of the Pro-Registration group, he coerced others in order to get his way.
It seems that some people were saying that.
Even so...
It sure looks similar.
It sure does.
Could you mean...
Similar to Nagakura-san's house?
If it was nighttime, it wouldn't be strange to mistake one house for the other.
Did the culprit's motive have nothing at all to do with the whole World Heritage registration business?
That is to say, one house was simply mistook for another...
And on top of that...
Conan!
What's wrong, all of a sudden?
Conan-kun!
Geez, don't run!
Just as we thought.
The inside is exactly the same as well.
If I remember correctly, at Nagakura-san's house, that person was searching around here...
Found it!
What'd you find?
Awesome!
Amazing!
Pretty.
They're so beautiful!
This...
Yeah, probably.
Hello?
Oh, Shin'ichi.
What's this?
The jewels that were stolen in that robbery incident?
What happened to them, you ask?
It seems that they haven't been found yet.
The investigators concluded that they must have been dumped somewhere.
Speaking of "haven't been found"...
The shop's jewel appraiser that was taken hostage during that conflict is still missing.
It's thought that he was murdered after having served his purposes, but...
Ah, no... That was...
Nothing, it was just me.
Is it all right, Conan?
That stuff...
We really should have taken it to the police...
Shh, you're loud.
Well, well...
Mouri-san, here you go.
As I thought, that person is the true culprit.
They'll probably show up there tonight!
This is it!
You did come after all...
Mister.
We've been waiting for you.
You can't run away this time!
What are you talking about?
I just couldn't sleep so I took a stroll...
I got lost, and well, it looks so much like that house...
If that's the case, I wonder what those jewels are?
Might they have been stolen from that jewelry shop a month ago?
What are you talking about?
There's no use playing dumb.
Because you're the person who murdered Nagakura Eiji and made it look like a suicide...
The jewel robbery's principal offender.
Eiji-san...
He had a lot of debt, it seems.
So you forced him to stand watch or something along those lines...
And the jewel robbery and the murder of the guard, both were crimes only you committed, right?
I don't know...
I have no idea what you're talking about.
Then, while on the run from the police...
You visited this Onizawa Village under Eiji-san's advice and hid the stolen jewels in the vacant former Otozawa home.
Never imagining that, half a month later, the entire house could have been moved.
After that, in order to pin all the crimes on Eiji-san, you murdered him and made it look like a suicide.
Then, pretending you were a tourist, you returned to this village...
Intending to retake possession of the hidden jewels!
What you're holding in your left hand are those very jewels!
That night, while Nagakura-san was away doing his rounds...
You were discovered searching for the jewels, and escaped out the window.
Basically, you didn't sneak in from the outside.
You were already there from the start.
But unfortunately for you, Nagakura-san saw you while making his rounds.
And when he hurriedly rushed back to his own house...
That was the reason the order of the hanko stamps on Nagakura-san's patrol log was odd.
I'm just an old man—an ordinary traveler.
As far as these, I just happened to come upon them...
We already know that you're not just an old man nor an ordinary traveler.
Because we've taken notice of the area around your right eye.
Those are marks from a loupe.
The appraiser that was taken hostage and thought to have been murdered, the one that remains unaccounted for...
Sakaki-san—that would be you, would it not?
Certainly.
But, after the culprit committed suicide, I was scared and remained in hiding...
I just now finally gathered up the courage to come here and try to return the jewels.
What if I were to say that, my little friends?
Then you would admit to searching for the jewels on the third floor of Nagakura-san's house last night, right?
Well, I wonder...
Then, how about escaping through the window and injuring Nagakura-san?
That's right, I was sound asleep from the sake.
So it couldn't have been me at all.
If that's so, when and where did you contract lacquer poisoning?
When you were drinking sake, neither your nor Nagakura-san's hands were poisoned.
If we ask the people you were eating with, we'll know for sure.
But that is definite proof that the two of you were in the same place at the same time.
Nagakura-san!
Call an ambulance!
There is no other place in the village with lacquer trees.
It's settled, then, isn't it?
You...
Who the hell are you all!?
Edogawa Conan, a detective.
And we are the Detective Boys!
Don't mess with me! Move!
I won't be caught by you all!
Give Eiji back!
Give him back!
Get away... Get away!
All right, now!
Ow-ow-ow...
Great job, Ayumi-chan!
That was definitely a true-to-life performance!
Enough to win an Academy Award!
Performance?
I just stood there silently.
Butthen...
Just now...
It's the fog, just fog!
Look closely!
Fog?
A Brocken specter, right?
It's something that is often seen from airplanes and mountain summits.
Really?
Then that must have been the same too, right?
That's right!
In this world, there's nothing that cannot be explained by logic and reasoning!
Mouri-saaan!
Thank you for the telephone call yesterday!
Telephone?
Thanks to that, we were able to head off his escape...
As expected of Mouri-san!
I am the humble Mashino Tamekichi.
You have my admiration!
Admiration?
For real?
That's—of course it's for real!
Of course it's for real!
Even for a little bit, I wanted to meet you...
Even as a ghost...
Mami-chan.
Ayumi-chan, hurry!
We're going!
Coming!
Wait for me!
The two houses that switched places were returned to their original locations.
Nagakura-san, having recovered from his injury...
Understood it to be the ghost of his son's childhood friend that helped bring the truth of his death to light.
Though of course, being a detective who uses logic and reasoning, I don't believe it.