Friendship! Romance! Mystery!
We try our best because we've made those promises!
Below the office stands the Poirot coffee shop.
A forgotten mobile phone rings up a case!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
My name is Mouri Kogoro.
My business is to fight against the shadow of society called crime.
Conan-kun, it's time to eat breakfast.
Conan-kun?
Welcome!
Two orders of breakfast.
Even though my daily defective work mostly involves extramarital affairs and searching for people...
Once in a while, I will be involved in nasty and bloody cases.
Every day, the newspaper reports on tragic cases brought on by revenge, money, or relationship problems.
It really is a sick world.
Whenever I feel tired from my detective work, I come here.
Your coffee is served.
That's right.
It's this hot cup of coffee that temporarily relieves my heart of its weariness.
HOT, HOT, HOT!!!
What's this guy think he's doing?
The Forgotten Cell Phone
(Part One)
Isn't this a rare sight?
Seeing you here this early in the morning.
Are you meeting a client here, by chance?
No, no.
Ran went to Karate training camp yesterday, so I'm here to have a late breakfast.
Besides, today is Sunday.
Occasionally, I'll separate myself from the endless cases and let my body and heart rest a little.
Neighbors, good morning.
My name is Baishou, Baishou Shuuhei.
For the sake of everyone, I will devote myself completely to work.
With your vote, please join me in making this a peaceful city.
It's work.
Hello, this is Mouri Kogoro's Detective Agen—
Get up, Hiroshi-kun.
It's already 8:30.
If you don't wake up for Yuka, Yuka will be sad!
Here's a kiss for you.
The one who needs to wake up is you!
Get the number right, then dial!
Damn, damn, damn.
Excuse me, but...
Are you free?
That he is.
He hasn't gotten any work all week.
Actually...
But, asking a famous detective about this kind of thing isn't appropriate.
Azusa-chan, have you encountered some trouble?
Actually, two days ago...
I found a weird item here in the restaurant.
I would like you to find the customer that lost it.
Finding people again.
What was that weird item?
It's this.
A cell phone?
It looks like an ordinary cell phone.
The outside design is indeed rather rare, but it doesn't seem to have any suspicious parts.
If the person who lost the cell phone really wanted to find it, he would have called.
A person did call.
Three times.
Three times?
Yes.
When I picked it up the first time, that person said...
"Oh, sorry, wrong number."
Wrong number?
What about the second time?
The second time went like this:
"Huh, did you hear anything ring just now?"
It seemed like there was another person with him.
When I tried to speak, he hung up again.
It must be that that person is planning on finding the cell phone based on the ring tone.
But since he went to the wrong place and the ring tone didn't go off, he thought he dialed the wrong number.
But the person who called doesn't seem like the owner of the cell phone.
Why's that?
Because when the third call came...
The person's tone suddenly changed.
Hey, you're his woman, right?
Give that guy the phone!
And he was yelling, "Otherwise, I'll kill you."
K—
Kill you?
And then?
Azusa-neechan...
What did you say to him?
That's...
You explained the situation to him, right?
I was so scared that I turned the phone off.
I see.
Let me take a look at the cell phone.
I told my boss all about it the next day, but ended up being scolded.
From then on, I kept the cell phone on, but no one called for the entire day.
As expected, it's not strange at all that no one called.
Why's that?
Because this cell phone won't connect.
Listen, even while dialing, it gets a busy tone.
Indeed.
I see!
The owner of this cell phone couldn't pay his cell phone bill, so his phone's service was disabled.
In other words, the dangerous-sounding man who called was a debt collector!
Under the impression that the man was living alone, he hung up when a woman picked up...
Thinking he had called the wrong number.
As such, he rechecked the phone number, and when he called for the third time, he was livid.
Then...
What about the second time when he asked if there was anything ringing?
That's probably because when he called in front of his apartment...
He didn't hear the ring sound, so he thought it was strange.
Say...
Do you still remember the customer that left this cell phone behind?
Yeah.
He came in after noon.
He wore glasses, had a side part, and was a little chubby.
He kept playing with his colorful cell phone, so I remember him clearly.
When the first call came, it was about an hour after he left.
The second call came not long after the first one.
The third one came about 30 minutes after that.
The incoming calls are shown as unknown numbers and the call-out and call-in records are blank as well.
For the contact list, there are a lot of names and numbers in there.
Then, did you try calling one of those numbers?
I tried calling before, but it seems like they were all fake numbers.
And the names seem to be fake as well.
Indeed, all the names have only their given names written in Katakana—that is strange.
Let's see the numbers.
1027?
I see, this really is strange.
Numbers that start with 1 don't exist, and they're 10 digit numbers too.
What's this black dot after the name?
That black dot appears after some names but also doesn't appear after others.
It's true.
The dot is there after some names and isn't there after others.
Are these numbers supposed to be some code?
This is really annoying!
Damn it!
Hey...
Where was this cell phone found?
Let's see...
It was here.
Underneath the seat right next to where Mouri-san is sitting.
It probably fell on the floor when he was putting it into his pocket.
And because he didn't notice it, he accidentally kicked it underneath the seat.
When the first call came, I found it quickly because of the ringing.
The antenna was pulled out as well.
When you found it, was the cell phone by any chance folded?
Yes, and that's why I think it was dropped when he was putting it into his pocket.
But isn't that strange?
What's strange?
Because if the cell phone was folded and he was putting it into his pocket, shouldn't the antenna be pushed in as well?
I see!
If the antenna is broken, that wouldn't be good.
The fact that he didn't push the antenna in shows that he's a careless guy.
It also might be that he purposely wanted someone to hear the call and find the cell phone, so he hid it there.
Or something like that.
Right, Uncle?
I was just about to say the same thing.
But why would he want to do that?
We still can't tell who the owner is after all, can we?
Oh, I have a way to find out.
How?
Azusa-chan...
On every cell phone, there is a sticker with the serial number on it.
If we ask the manufacturer about this number, we can find out from which shop the cell phone was sold.
And if we go to the shop, we can find out the name of the person who bought the cell phone.
Amazing!
First, let's take off the back cover...
And then remove the batteries...
It's not there.
The sticker...
Has been taken off.
How can this be?
Hey, can you tell us more details about that customer?
More details?
It doesn't matter if they seem trivial, just whatever details you can think of.
Let's see.
Now that you mention it...
That customer...
Ordered yakisoba, carbonara, a fruit parfait, tomato juice, and a Caesar salad...
Which came to exactly three thousand yen!
Exactly three thousand yen?
Had he not ordered these five specific dishes...
The total wouldn't have been three thousand yen.
I was emotionally touched by this fact for a while.
Conan-kun said any details were fine, so I thought I'd mention it...
But five dishes for lunch, he really can eat.
Yeah, yeah!
He looked like he was in the middle of work and still ate so much.
In the middle of work?
Yes, because he asked me for the receipt.
Receipt?
Who was it made out to, then?
Of course, it was "Ue-sama".
"Ue-sama" is a polite means of referring to a guest without asking their name.
Figures.
Thank you very much.
Your vote today is greatly appreciated.
From now on, I will work even harder for everyone's sake.
But...
If it was just him and he asked for the receipt, then there's only a low probability he's a normal company employee.
Then, just who is he?
He's probably on a business trip or may be a small business owner.
Or he might just be someone with a habit of asking for receipts.
In that case...
He may be a private eye or investigative reporter.
Police officers usually ask for receipts too.
Then, beat officers will also ask for a receipt every time after they finish eating?
No, no...
Welco—
That's just for police detectives.
Sorry to bother you.
Not at all.
For example, when looking for information, following someone or investigating...
The detectives need to provide receipts for traveling and food expenses, but...
Uniformed officers like us never do.
You're that person always with Takagi.
Yumi-san, why are you here?
Of course, it's to tell the famous detective who still hasn't paid his ticket to pay up.
I was planning to pay for it today...
Today is Sunday.
I was joking.
I'm actually looking for information about a certain man...
But the only available clue is this.
Three thousand yen!
Is this person someone who wears glasses, has a side part, and is a little chubby?!
Yes.
Do you know where he is?
I do.
That's great!
I can finally return this to him.
Return it?
That person left his cell phone here.
There were strange calls too—it was really troublesome.
But, it'll be impossible to return it to him.
That person died the day before yesterday.
Died?
No way...
Don't tell me he was murdered.
Wrong.
He was hit by a truck at an intersection in the 3rd District.
A traffic accident?
I remember now.
It was in the news.
Yes.
The accident happened two days ago at around 2:00 PM.
He was rushed to the hospital, but it was too late.
He died that night.
He also had no identification on him, so we're investigating who he was.
Wait a second...
Could this be a hit and run case?
No.
The truck driver didn't run away and wasn't under the influence of alcohol.
According to the eyewitness, that person suddenly left the sidewalk and ran into the street, getting hit as a result.
That means this isn't a case of murder, either.
Then, don't tell me it's a suicide case?
That doesn't seem to be the case either.
That person, right before the accident happened, asked for directions at a convenience store.
We were told he was in a hurry and asked for a store named "Poirot".
If he planned to commit suicide...
There'd be no reason to ask for directions to a store that was two kilometers away, right?
That's true.
But I guess we at least figured out why he hurriedly ran into the street.
It seems he ran across the street in order to come here to retrieve his cell phone, and was hit by the truck.
No, that's not it.
Dead people can't talk.
We're back to the beginning.
That cell phone was hidden here after being folded, with the antenna pointing outward.
It's as if it were there so someone could hear it ring and discover it.
Furthermore, there are those weird numbers and names in the contact list.
What was it?
Exactly what had that man intended to do here?
But, the accident occurred two days ago.
How come you guys didn't come here to investigate earlier?
That couldn't be helped.
That man didn't have any identification with him.
That's right...
Instead, he carried a lot of receipts.
He meticulously collected them, didn't he?
Haido, Bizen, Kenbashi...
He's been all over the city.
That's right.
We investigated all the stores he visited in accordance with the dates.
It took us a day to get here.
Even though some people remembered him, no one knows who he is or where he lived.
Then, it's possible that he was trying to hide from those loan sharks.
Loan sharks?
Yes.
A dangerous-sounding man called the cell phone that had been left behind...
Yelling, "If you don't get him on the phone, I'll kill you."
Is that true?
Yes...
The calls came about an hour after the customer left.
In any case, I suggest you steer your investigation along the lines of usury.
If he borrowed money, then he would have left his name and address at the lender's place.
What is it?
You can find out without doing all that.
Because that scary person who called should know the number of this cell phone.
If I were that scary person and found out that this cell phone wouldn't connect...
I'd call the telephone company and ask for the owner's name and address.
And then?
So if you call the telephone company and ask if that scary person has called, then you would know.
Stupid!
If you're not the police...
Why would the telephone company give the owner's name and address out to some random person?
Do you understand, Conan-kun?
But, sometimes there are people who unthinkingly call the telephone company when they're in a state of panic...
Once, I got lost on the way to a friend's house.
I tried calling their cell phone but it had been turned off.
Without fully considering it, I called the telephone company asking for their address.
I asked if they could tell me the address based on their cell phone number.
That's right.
Do people do that?
And then?
Did they find it for you?
In the end, they didn't tell me.
So I asked one of the officers at the police box for help in locating the address based on their name.
Certainly, if that dangerous-sounding man was in a panic to find the owner of the cell phone...
He may have at least tried calling the telephone company.
Numata-san, you get the number for the telephone company too.
Yes.
Anyway, let's split up and ask around to see if anyone has called.
How nice, being a police officer who can ask for any information.
I guess, though the procedure takes some time.
If we know his number, then we'll know his name and address.
That's right.
If I had kept that mail address, I would have been able to find my way there...
To the residence of the boss that woman devoted herself to, the boss in charge of the organization...
Yes, from the day before yesterday.
Yes.
That's right.
Yes, yes, I understand.
Please do.
How did it go?
Don't know yet.
Have to wait for them to confirm it and call back.
Until then, we'll search elsewhere.
Azusa-chan, why don't you give the customer at table one more coffee?
Yes.
Sorry for the trouble.
No problem.
Study hard!
I will.
Yes, any calls requesting name, address, or phone number...
How about a refill?
Thank you.
Yes, two days ago.
Yes, yes...
Here you go, on the house.
Thank you!
I'll just leave it here.
Apologies, thank you very much.
Here.
Orange juice for Conan-kun.
Thank you, Azusa-neechan.
Sorry, it's Sunday and I got you guys involved in such a strange case...
Say...
Can you show me that forgotten cell phone one more time?
Yeah.
Here you go.
Thank you.
It's so strange.
In this cell phone, the clues are...
The 10 digit numbers that begin with 1, and the black dot after the names.
What do these mean?
Thank you very much everyone.
This is Baishou Shuuhei!
To thank everyone for their support, I will work even harder.
Thank you very much, thank you very much!
Yes?
Hello?
Yes.
That's right.
Yes, yes...
Did we find it?
A clue that links to that man?