The Forgotten Cell Phone
(Part Two)
Thank you for coming!
Yes.
Is that so?
I understand.
Yes, thank you very much.
Well?
From the day before yesterday to yesterday, there were three calls in total.
Three calls?
What did they say?
The first person was on his way to a job interview, but...
He left the paper with the address at home.
He wanted to get the address by any means necessary...
Since he probably wouldn't get the job if the interviewer found this out.
The second person got a phone call from their daughter, who had run away from home.
They wanted to know where the call had been made from.
The third person said he met a friendly person while traveling...
Who accidentally left his cell phone in the caller's bag.
He wanted to know this person's name and address so he could return it to him.
That's the one!
That's the only one where a cell phone is mentioned.
I agree.
And also, that last person is the only one who also wanted to get the person's home phone number.
And, what was the number?
They refused to help him, so there wasn't any record.
Furthermore, none of those three made the calls from their houses.
They made them outside, so we have no way to tell who or where they are.
Outside?
One person called from a train platform at Beika Station in the evening two nights ago.
One person called from a sports shop called "Apollo" yesterday at noon.
The other person called from a restaurant named "Columbo" last evening.
But, they forgot which of these was which, so we don't know when or where the one we need was.
That's right.
They also said the person who asked for the phone number suddenly hung up on them.
Suddenly?
Yeah, there was some noise over the phone at that time.
A noise that almost blocked out the conversation.
A really loud noise.
But it was only for a short moment so they couldn't really discern what kind of noise it was.
It looks like we have no choice but to call those places and ask...
We'll have to get in contact with the places those three people called from.
I passed the exams!
That's great!
It was all thanks to you.
Now we can all relax.
Here's your change.
Here goes the first call.
Yeah.
The Tohto Loop Line train will be arriving shortly.
The public phone on the platform?
If you want to ask about the night before yesterday...
There were many people using the phone.
I see, guess it can't be helped...
Hey, could it be that person?
The person who was hesitating about whether or not to make a phone call.
Now that you mention it, there was a person like that.
He was wearing a long coat and had a face like that of a dangerous person.
He's been coming to the station quite frequently lately.
When that person was on the phone, was there a loud noise nearby?
A loud noise?
Yeah.
That happens all the time!
This is a train station after all.
Listen...
The train headed toward Kenbashi will arrive at Platform Number 2.
Boarding passengers should stand behind the white line.
I see.
The announcements at the station.
Hello?
Seems like it's hard to communicate.
So you heard that?
This is the loud noise.
Thank you.
We understand now.
Besides that, do you have any other clues about the dangerous man wearing a long coat?
That person will probably appear again tonight.
I've been seeing him at the station a lot lately.
Please give us a call if you see him.
Sure, I'll do that.
Thank you for your cooperation.
There was, there was.
A man with a crew-cut came here yesterday around noon asking to borrow the phone.
Apparently, his cell phone's battery died and he didn't have any change on him.
So he came here to borrow the phone.
What, a loud noise?
That's right.
A noise so loud that he was forced to hang up the phone.
Was there a noise like that?
Oh, that noise must be the nearby construction work.
Construction work started about a week ago in front of the bank across the street.
See, here's that noise again.
The noise is constantly off and on from noon onwards.
Construction noise, huh?
Yesterday evening...
That's probably one of our regular customers.
A male customer who's always wearing sunglasses and doesn't talk much.
He happened to forget his cell phone, and needed to use the pay phone in our restaurant.
I had to make change for him, so I remember it well.
A loud noise?
Yes.
Did you hear a noise that was so loud it could've prevented the conversation from continuing?
Not sure, this street is famous for its serenity.
Good afternoon, residents of this city.
I am Baishou Shuuhei—please give me your support and you vote.
Together, let's transform this city into a quiet neighborhood.
Did you hear that?
That loud noise persists throughout the day.
It seems we're right on that campaign car's course.
A campaign car, huh...
When will that regular customer come again?
He comes everyday.
When he shows up again, I'll give you guys a call.
Thank you.
I will await your call.
Each of those three are suspicious, aren't they?
All three phone calls meet all the requirements, huh?
This is...
Ah-le-le!
What's this?
This cell phone is so strange.
Uncle, look at this.
Brat...
Don't tell me you broke that cell phone or something.
It's not that.
Most of the four numbers in the beginning of these phone numbers are similar.
1028...
1025...
These numbers are indeed near each other.
They're probably neighbors.
You idiot!
Didn't I tell you before that 10-digit phone numbers beginning with the number 1 don't exist?
This has got to be because the chubby owner of this cell phone...
Assigned ascending numbers to each person he met during his work.
Hey, which one is the smallest number?
It should be this one.
It's over 1000, so he must've known a lot of people.
Yeah.
He might be a door-to-door salesman, and probably just assigned all of these numbers to his clients.
Then, what's the meaning behind these four numbers?
And this, what does this black dot represent?
Some have black dots and some don't.
He probably marked potential customers when he went to visit them.
The numbers at the end like 150 and 600 most likely represent the quantity of goods he sold...
But isn't this too strange?
See, the first four numbers at the beginning are never less than 1022.
If you look closely, two people have the numbers 1031.
One...
Two...
It's true.
And this...
If there's 1101, then why isn't there any number from 1032 to 1100?
If it's in numerical order...
Then why does it jump from 1031 to 1101?
Uhm, could it be this?
It'd be a calendar, wouldn't it?
Calendar?
1031 is October 31st.
1101 is November 1st or something like that.
I see.
Thinking about it that way makes sense.
Hold on...
If these numbers represent the end of October to the beginning of November of last year...
That period of time was during the Tohto Diet elections!
Yes...
Furthermore...
The neighborhood association's baseball tournament...
And preparations for the Autumn Festival were also during that time, so it was a busy time.
Well, we can be sure that this man wasn't a resident of this neighborhood, at least.
Hey, what's with that tangent?
Sorry.
It's fine.
If the four numbers at the beginning represent dates...
Then the numbers behind them might be the time he went to visit his clients.
150 is 1:50, and 600 is exactly 6:00.
Then why are the surnames in kanji and the given names in katakana?
It's because the surname can be found on the home's nameplate...
Whereas the given names can only be discovered while talking.
That person is probably one of the clients who was angered by the products this cell phone owner sold.
Who?
The person who called from a blocked number and yelled, "Give that guy the phone."
That same one that also called the phone company and asked for this person's name and address.
That dangerous person.
Once we know who that person is and where they are, we can ask them for the number to this cell phone...
And learn the chubby man's identity.
Damn it, if only that guy were still alive, this wouldn't have been so much of a headache.
Hey...
Is that how it really is?
It's suspicious, after all.
The place where the cell phone was dropped.
The antenna of the cell phone was sticking out while the cell phone was nicely folded and placed under the sofa.
You're right, that is strange.
It's as if they wanted someone to find it when they heard the cell phone ringing.
Regarding the ring tone, the second phone call from that dangerous person said...
"Did you hear anything ring just now?"
Could it be that chubby man specifically asked the dangerous man to call the phone...
In order to secretly give the cell phone over to him?
Nonsense.
If that were the case, why didn't he just meet up with the dangerous man here?
If dropped, it would be discovered by an employee, and then he'd have no way of secretly giving it to him.
Uncle is right.
Of course.
If he had wanted to give the phone to someone in secret, he wouldn't have deliberately made an effort to retrieve it.
It's not like he mixed up the location or anything, after all.
Mixed up?
I mix things up all the time, so...
Now that you mention it, at the convenience store, that chubby man...
I see.
He was asking for directions.
If he's not familiar with this area, he could easily mistake one place for another.
So the suspicious place is...
Apollo!
Is it the sports shop that has a name similar to our Poirot restaurant?
I see.
But, Azusa-chan...
No matter how similar the names are, it's hard to mistake a sports shop for a restaurant.
You're right.
Hey, Azusa-neechan...
Why is this shop called Poirot?
You've heard of Hercule Poirot from the detective stories, right?
Our shop owner loves mystery novels, so he got it from that.
Conan-kun, you know Poirot, right?
He's that slightly plump man...
I've seen him on TV.
He often remarks, "You know, my wife says..."
The police detective who wears a wrinkled coat, right?
No, no.
That guy isn't Poirot, he's Columbo.
Could he have mistaken the mystery novels' protagonists?
Furthermore, that Columbo restaurant and ours are both in the 5th district.
If that chubby customer only remembered it was a shop in Beika's 5th District named after a detective series...
It'd be an easy mistake to make.
Let's go.
Where to?
Isn't it obvious?
The other famous detective's shop...
Wait up!
Hey, I'm going too!
Me too.
The identity of that chubby man...
Will soon be revealed!
The customer that often wears sunglasses that I mentioned earlier hasn't arrived yet.
Really?
Then, do you mind if we wait here?
No problem.
Are you going to be all right, Azusa-chan?
You just rushed out of the shop.
Yes, since the shop owner is there.
I just need to return by evening when it gets busy.
I wouldn't be able to concentrate while thinking about this anyway.
Say, Mister...
Did that customer ever ask you anything?
Whenever he comes, he always asks...
If I've come across a lost cell phone.
It's as I thought.
Looks like this is the right place.
Yeah.
Oh, he's here.
Welcome!
That's him.
But is something the matter with that customer?
Nothing much.
I'm going to talk to him.
I'll know if he's the person who called after hearing his voice.
No, I should go.
This is when you let a man handle things.
Huh?
What's wrong, Detective?
Aren't you going to talk to him?
Before we talk to him...
You should hear my deductions.
First, the strange names written in katakana in this cell phone's contact list.
Although they look like names of people, they're actually abbreviated names of certain organizations.
Certain organizations?
Please let me see that for a second.
What's the meaning of this?
In this cell phone's contact list, there are many strange names that don't seem like family names, right?
Do you mean "Kenbashi Shou"-san and "Daitoma Cho"-san?
I see.
If they're the names of places, I've heard of them, but...
I've never heard of anyone with surnames like those.
Right.
Those names likely belong to organizations based in those areas.
For example, "Kenbashi Shou" represents the Kenbashi Shopping District...
And "Daitoma Cho" represents the Daitoma Neighborhood Association.
If we read it that way, it all makes sense.
"Aida Ken" is Aida Construction.
"Ishizawa Seisaku" is Ishizawa Manufacturing.
Furthermore, there are 10-digit numbers recorded along with each of those names.
The first four digits represent dates.
The numbers after represent the amount of money.
The black dots beside the names represent "black figures".
In short, revenue.
Those without black dots are the opposite: Expenses.
Taking into account the dates were concentrated around the time of last year's election...
There's only one conclusion that can be drawn!
Don't tell me...
They're secret campaign financing records?
Exactly.
Even though we don't know how that chubby man came into the possession of these records...
The fact remains that he had intended to use this to blackmail someone.
The reason he entered the records into the cell phone...
Was in order to show the other party proof that he indeed possessed them.
Then, that person is...
He's probably someone hired by the one whose campaign car is making the rounds on the streets in this area...
Diet Member Baishou.
All for the purpose of getting the secret records back.
The reason he suddenly hung up while on the phone with the telephone company...
Was because he heard the sounds from Diet Member Baishou's campaign van.
While searching for the guy with the secret records...
He thought it would have been bad if it was found out that he was connected with Diet Member Baishou.
And so he instantly hung up.
Also, the man with the sunglasses was the one who chose this restaurant as the location for the transaction...
Because he was a regular customer here.
He had originally planned to call the cell phone from here and take it without anyone noticing...
But the chubby man mixed up the location.
But why didn't that chubby man contact us once he realized that he was at the wrong restaurant?
It's probably because, by the time he realized that...
It was already past the time they'd arranged to do the exchange.
The original plan was to have the shop owner find the phone after it started ringing...
And then have the man in sunglasses claim it was his.
Even though he mistook the place, he could easily get it back at Poirot by calling his cell phone.
However, if he did that, there was a chance the man in sunglasses could've picked up and ascertained his voice.
That chubby man had probably used fax and text messages to communicate regarding the transaction...
In order to prevent his face or voice from being noticed and exposing his identity.
That's also why he had the line killed and removed the production sticker from the cell phone.
So the reason that chubby man rushed back to Poirot was...
Was to make sure whether or not the man in sunglasses had taken the phone or not.
If it had been handed over to the police as a lost item, his plan to get money would have been destroyed.
But if that's the case...
Then no matter how much we question that man in sunglasses, he won't say anything.
Don't worry, there's still a way.
Right, Conan?
Let's go, Azusa-neechan.
Hurry up!
Conan-kun?
Say, Miss, I wonder who lost that cell phone?
If no one wants it, can you give it to me?
This is my first time seeing a cell phone with such a strange case.
Ah-le-le!
There are so many strange names and numbers.
Conan-kun...
Hey, brat!
I mean, little boy...
That's actually my cell phone.
Oh, really?
Show me some proof, then.
Proof?
Yep.
If this really does belong to you, you should know the number of this cell phone, right?
I can test to see if the number goes through...
So tell me the number.
Just hurry up and give me the phone.
It's a police woman.
Maybe I should give it to her...
Wait...
I understand.
I'll tell you the number.
And so, we finally obtained the chubby man's phone number.
Using that number, the police managed to locate his apartment.
It seems that man was likely an investigative reporter.
Buried under heaps of receipts, a copy of the secret records was found.
And on it, the names, dates, and the
amounts of money were clearly written.
It was more than enough evidence.
As such, in the middle of his campaign, Diet Member Baishou...
And those who received money from him, were all arrested one after another.
Welcome!
I am Mouri Kogoro.
A cup of hot coffee.
I am but a humble detective engaged in the battle against the shadow of society known as crime.
No, allow me to correct that...
I am Mouri Kogoro...
A famous detective.
Welcome!
Thank you so much for yesterday.
If anything else comes up, feel free to come to me.
Yes!
Right.
There's no case I cannot solve.
For example, that student...
After successfully getting into college, he has no need to come here to study anymore, yet he still comes.
There's no doubt that he has a crush...
A case!
Yes, this is famous detective—
Hello, Dad?
It's me.
What is it?
It looks like today's club activities are going to run a bit late, so could you do some shopping for me?
Yeah, I don't mind.
Let's see... potatoes...
Potatoes...
Carrots... onions... pork... and apples.
Could it be that we're eating curry tonight?
That's correct!
As expected of a famous detective!
All right, got it!
This is a big case.
I'll get to the scene right away!
HOT!
Dad, what's wrong?
Coffee... coffee... hot!
Nothing to do as usual, right, Uncle?