Friendship! Romance! Mystery!
We try our best because we've made those promises!
Having a determined heart to catch a big fish...
An unexpected case gets in the way!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Wow, it's so big!
Such a beautiful lake...
This lake, Okutani...
It's known as the perfect place for bass fishing.
If you're lucky, you could even catch one that's over 5 kilograms.
Five kilograms?
All right!
I can eat all I want!
Let's do it!
Genta-kun, I think you took it the wrong way.
What did I get wrong?
Isn't it a contest?
To see who can eat the most?
Ran and I were invited to a fishing tournament that was being sponsored by Sonoko's father's company.
And, after Genta and the others heard about it...
They all wanted to come along...
So here we are.
THE FISHING TOURNAMENT TRAGEDY
(PART ONE)
OKUTANIKO
Ah, they're here!
Sonoko!
Good morning.
Good morning!
Thank you for letting us come!
Well, well...
Everyone has good manners today?
All right, do your best today, little ones!
Who are you calling "little one?"
And the glasses kid is here too, huh?
Sorry I'm such a burden.
Mizui-san!
Sonoko-san!
What is it?
These kids also want to join the fishing contest...
Could you sign them up?
Of course, right away.
Well then, I'll need you guys to write down your names and contact info right here, if you would.
This is Mizui-san, one of our employees.
And this is my good friend Mouri Ran.
Pleased to meet you.
Mizui Junichi (27)
Tournament Committee Member
I'm Mizui Junichi...
Pleased to meet you too.
Let's see...
I think I'll use this one!
Then I'll use this one!
What about you, Conan-kun?
This one.
That one!?
It looks disgusting, like a caterpillar!
But look, Ayumi-chan...
This kind of soft bait is perfect for fishing here.
It says so on the magazine.
That's so interesting!
Look, this one's just like a frog!
I didn't know they had this kind of bait.
Seriously, it does look just like a frog.
Oh, are you guys participating too?
Yeah, and we'll win for sure!
Really?
Ayukawa Saori (27)
Tournament Participant
Then it looks like I've got some tough competition.
You're participating too, then?
Of course—I'm registered and everything.
How about a handshake?
The champion fishing with kids—what a nice picture.
Funaki Toshihiko (35)
Freelance Writer
Well, good luck to you guys.
Right, we'll do our best!
We touched her hand...
I'm not going to shower tonight.
Hey there, you kids...
The competition is about to start!
So, what did you guys talk about with that girl?
We had a handshake...
She grabbed my hand so firmly...
Ayukawa-san and you guys?
Yep, firmly...
Man, she sure was pretty...
Do you know her?
She was last year's winner.
Wow, that's really impressive.
And the one who's approaching her is...
Another favorite to win the competition, Masubuchi Takuya-san.
Masubuchi Takuya (29)
Tournament Participant
He was the champion two years ago.
It is currently 10:00 A.M.
Starting right now...
It's the first day of the Suzuki Cup Lake Okutani Fishing Tournament!
All contestants must bring a catch of five bass...
To the tournament center by 4:00 this afternoon.
All right, time to get our game on!
Let's go!
Yeah!
Looks like we would've been better off using a boat...
Bass usually hide underneath broken tree branches and trunks in the water.
All right, this spot will do.
Are you sure this place is good, Conan?
Look, she's fishing here too.
See, even the defending champion chose this place.
All right, Genta—let's get started.
No problem, leave it to me!
It's networking...
Can't catch a thing...
Using a boat still seems better.
How's it going, little ones?
Caught anything?
Absolutely nothing...
It's not going well.
I'm Funaki, gathering material for the Bass Magazine...
I'm talking about bass—don't get it confused with "bus".
We're aware of trivial things like that, all right?
The magazine will focus on this tournament in next month's issue...
So I'm interviewing and gathering data.
Oh yeah, how about a picture?
Everyone get together.
Here goes—say "cheese"!
Rice field!
Ayukawa-san seems to be doing pretty well.
Better get a shot of her...
Hey, if our location isn't then problem, then it probably has something to do with our bait.
That's gotta be it...
I don't think this is a good idea.
We're only gonna go see what bait she's using.
Just stay here, Ayumi.
Still...
Whoa, so many different kinds...
It's this one—this has to be it!
You think we can make a catch with this one?
Of course we can!
That one won't do, you know.
Here, try this one out.
This big one has a special scent...
It should bring a catch for sure.
Thank you so much!
It's pulling!
Something's pulling!
With great strength!
Don't panic, Mitsuhiko!
Calmly and carefully reel in the line!
You've got it, see?
That's it!
Keep going, just like that!
It's too heavy!
I'm losing my grip!
Just a little more—keep reeling it in!
It's a black one!
Come on, you got it!
This is...
This is it?
Ouch!
Are you all right?
Let me take a look.
It's no big deal.
I'll clean the wound for you.
I have band-aids.
We'll disinfect it in a moment.
All right...
Conan-kun, it's late...
We were getting worried.
You guys had better hurry and get them counted!
What's wrong?
Not feeling well?
Is it because you guys don't even have anything to be counted?
Not even one!?
All four of you!?
So four times zero is still zero?
Sonoko, that's enough!
Yeah, but...
It's time to announce today's results from the competition.
Currently in the first place, with a catch weight of 13.524 kilograms, is Ayukawa Saori-san!
She's really good!
We had the right place and the right bait, and then...
It's probably just luck.
Tomorrow, we'll make our comeback with a change of luck!
Do you guys actually think it's that easy?
What the hell are you talking about?
Please don't say something like that!
There's no reason for you to get this angry...
I'm going first.
It's big, isn't it?
It was caught by a friend of mine.
February 24 2001
Fisherman
Kanie Kensuke
Is that guy's name Kanie-san?
Yeah, Kanie Kensuke.
Used to be quite famous.
How can we catch fish that big?
You'd have to start learning to fish at a young age.
If you start right now...
You'll definitely turn into a great fisherman when you grow up.
Really?
I wish I could start right now...
Say, Saori-san...
What made you want to start fishing in the first place?
Since my father fished often...
He would always take me to a lake or river when I was young.
Because of that, I hadn't even been to an amusement park or zoo before high school.
Really?
That's so sad...
There you are, Ayukawa-san!
How'd you like to grab a drink together...
To celebrate your victory?
No thanks...
What's wrong...
Don't want to have a drink with me?
Is it really appropriate for you to refuse like this?
Relax, I'm just kidding!
Honestly, I wanted to seek your advice on a particular topic...
The other reason I came here was to solve the case about the express train.
You must know all about everything that happens around here, correct?
Well, I wouldn't exactly go that far...
I know you'll help me—tell me you will, please...
Please, Saori-san...
Very well.
You'll be such a big help!
Thank you so much!
Is he writing about the express train?
I've read an article by him before.
He's a freelance writer.
He's written for many different magazines.
I see...
Hey, Conan, how about we fish on a boat today?
In this season...
The bass tend to stay in shaded water near the shore to search for food.
Forget your reasoning—we didn't even catch anything yesterday.
That's why, today...
Boat it is...
It's the only way to win!
I'm still going to fish on the shore.
I'm going for a different location today.
Guess we'll split up here, then.
What to do...
Ayukawa-san!
Good morning.
Where are you going fishing today, Ayukawa-san?
I'm going to Kutani River today.
Can I come with you?
Well, it may not be such a good idea, since it's kind of dangerous there...
Is that so...
I'm sorry, Ayumi-chan...
Well, good luck, everyone!
Kutani River, huh?
Let's go over there too, Mitsuhiko.
We'll have to get there by boat.
Well, good luck, everyone.
Let's get going, Ayumi-chan.
Look, it's Ayukawa-san!
Where?
I see her!
Ayukawa-san!
Maybe I should've taken the boat...
Look, it's the express train!
Hey!
What's wrong?
Did we hit something?
I thought I heard something...
What's this?
It's probably some kind of fishing tool.
But I've never seen one like this before...
That's the other favorite for first place, Masubuchi-san, right?
He'll probably make a lot of catches here, then.
Does it really matter how talented he is?
Hey, it's already the second day...
Conan-kun and the others will probably catch a bunch today.
Is that so?
It's just a little further upstream, right?
What's wrong?
Hey, look over there.
What's he doing?
He probably gave up and started resting...
Because he couldn't catch anything.
That can't be...
What's wrong, Ran-neechan?
Conan-kun...
Somebody collapsed over there!
Ayumi-chan, don't move.
I got it!
Funaki-san!
Petroleum...
There should be bloodstains left behind if he hit his head before accidentally falling...
So search carefully and thoroughly!
And what of the time of death?
The body's still warm...
So the time of death is most likely between 15 to 30 minutes ago.
That guy looks scary...
And the ones who discovered the body are...
You guys are...
With the Smoky Kogorou...
It's Sleeping Kogorou.
Sorry for the trouble from before, Inspector Yokomizo.
And you are?
Second-year Teitan High School student Suzuki Sonoko...
Representative sponsor of this fishing tournament.
I guess that makes you the rich daughter of that flashy sponsoring company...
Now then, please describe how you discovered the victim, in detail.
Sonoko and I were on our way to the tournament headquarters.
We wanted to see how Conan-kun and the kids were doing, but...
We happened to find Funaki-san lying here on the ground instead.
So the victim's name is Funaki...
Yeah...
He's a freelance magazine writer.
He said he wanted to write a special article for this month's issue of the magazine "Bass."
Where were you at that time?
About 30 meters upstream from here...
I was fishing with Ayumi-chan.
While you were there...
Did you happen to hear anything like a scream from the victim?
Nothing like that...
Inspector, a moment.
Did you find it?
About that...
We searched very thoroughly, but...
We couldn't find anything that might have hit the victim's head.
What?
Absolutely nothing?
So you were around Otaki Rock from 10:00 to 10:30 AM...
Can anyone confirm that?
I was with him.
We were fishing there all morning.
Hey, where is this place?
Right around here.
All right, you two are free to go.
What a scary-looking guy!
Funaki-san's body was discovered within 30 minutes of his death...
And it takes about 20 minutes to walk from the headquarters to the body's location...
Moreover, if you didn't have a boat...
The only way to cross the river would be the road on the dam.
It takes at least five minutes to cross that...
So people on the other side of the dam...
And those closest to the inner lake...
Can be eliminated as suspects.
It's Ayukawa Saori-san, right?
Yes, that's right.
What's wrong...
Don't want to have a drink with me?
Is it really appropriate for you to refuse like this?
Where were you between 10:00 and 10:30 this morning?
Please, explain.
All right...
I was up towards one of the streams that flows into Kutani River.
Can anyone else attest to that?
We saw her!
Even though we were on our boat...
We clearly saw her passing by on the shore of Kutani River.
It's true...
She even waved "bye-bye" to us.
There's no mistaking it!
Fair enough.
You're free to go.
Please excuse me.
Looks like we're next!
Don't worry about it.
Don't you need our alibis?
Just don't get in the way, kids...
That gave me a scare.
That was the guy who took a picture of us, right?
That place is probably cursed.
Cursed?
What you mean by that, Mizui-san?
Actually, someone else also died there about half a year ago.
Because there was no one else around at the time...
The case was concluded as an accident.
Who was the victim?
It was Kanie-san.
He was close to Ayukawa-san and Masubuchi-san.
Kanie...
Kanie Kensuke.
Used to be quite famous.
Then, he was also a favorite to become champion, right?
Yeah, and just like Masubuchi-san, he learned fishing from Ayukawa-san's father.
Ayukawa-san's father?
He already passed away, but...
He was one of the creators of fishing tournaments in Japan.
He even formed clubs, and taught people to fish for bass.
Someone else died there half a year ago...
This can't be a coincidence.
Most likely, the culprit is one of those two.