Friendship! Romance! Mystery!
We try our best because we've made those promises!
Having a determined heart to catch a big fish...
An unexpected case gets in the way!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Wow, it's so big!
Such a beautiful lake...
This lake, Okutani...
It's known as the perfect place for bass fishing.
If you're lucky, you could even catch one that's over 5 kilograms.
Five kilograms?
All right!
I can eat all I want!
Let's do it!
Genta-kun, I think you took it the wrong way.
What did I get wrong?
Isn't it a contest?
To see who can eat the most?
Ran and I were invited to a fishing tournament that was being sponsored by Sonoko's father's company.
And, after Genta and the others heard about it...
They all wanted to come along...
So here we are.
THE FISHING TOURNAMENT TRAGEDY
(PART ONE)
OKUTANIKO
Ah, they're here!
Sonoko!
Good morning.
Good morning!
Thank you for letting us come!
Well, well...
Everyone has good manners today?
All right, do your best today, little ones!
Who are you calling "little one?"
And the glasses kid is here too, huh?
Sorry I'm such a burden.
Mizui-san!
Sonoko-san!
What is it?
These kids also want to join the fishing contest...
Could you sign them up?
Of course, right away.
Well then, I'll need you guys to write down your names and contact info right here, if you would.
This is Mizui-san, one of our employees.
And this is my good friend Mouri Ran.
Pleased to meet you.
Mizui Junichi (27)
Tournament Committee Member
I'm Mizui Junichi...
Pleased to meet you too.
Let's see...
I think I'll use this one!
Then I'll use this one!
What about you, Conan-kun?
This one.
That one!?
It looks disgusting, like a caterpillar!
But look, Ayumi-chan...
This kind of soft bait is perfect for fishing here.
It says so on the magazine.
That's so interesting!
Look, this one's just like a frog!
I didn't know they had this kind of bait.
Seriously, it does look just like a frog.
Oh, are you guys participating too?
Yeah, and we'll win for sure!
Really?
Ayukawa Saori (27)
Tournament Participant
Then it looks like I've got some tough competition.
You're participating too, then?
Of course—I'm registered and everything.
How about a handshake?
The champion fishing with kids—what a nice picture.
Funaki Toshihiko (35)
Freelance Writer
Well, good luck to you guys.
Right, we'll do our best!
We touched her hand...
I'm not going to shower tonight.
Hey there, you kids...
The competition is about to start!
So, what did you guys talk about with that girl?
We had a handshake...
She grabbed my hand so firmly...
Ayukawa-san and you guys?
Yep, firmly...
Man, she sure was pretty...
Do you know her?
She was last year's winner.
Wow, that's really impressive.
And the one who's approaching her is...
Another favorite to win the competition, Masubuchi Takuya-san.
Masubuchi Takuya (29)
Tournament Participant
He was the champion two years ago.
It is currently 10:00 A.M.
Starting right now...
It's the first day of the Suzuki Cup Lake Okutani Fishing Tournament!
All contestants must bring a catch of five bass...
To the tournament center by 4:00 this afternoon.
All right, time to get our game on!
Let's go!
Yeah!
Looks like we would've been better off using a boat...
Bass usually hide underneath broken tree branches and trunks in the water.
All right, this spot will do.
Are you sure this place is good, Conan?
Look, she's fishing here too.
See, even the defending champion chose this place.
All right, Genta—let's get started.
No problem, leave it to me!
It's networking...
Can't catch a thing...
Using a boat still seems better.
How's it going, little ones?
Caught anything?
Absolutely nothing...
It's not going well.
I'm Funaki, gathering material for the Bass Magazine...
I'm talking about bass—don't get it confused with "bus".
We're aware of trivial things like that, all right?
The magazine will focus on this tournament in next month's issue...
So I'm interviewing and gathering data.
Oh yeah, how about a picture?
Everyone get together.
Here goes—say "cheese"!
Rice field!
Ayukawa-san seems to be doing pretty well.
Better get a shot of her...
Hey, if our location isn't then problem, then it probably has something to do with our bait.
That's gotta be it...
I don't think this is a good idea.
We're only gonna go see what bait she's using.
Just stay here, Ayumi.
Still...
Whoa, so many different kinds...
It's this one—this has to be it!
You think we can make a catch with this one?
Of course we can!
That one won't do, you know.
Here, try this one out.
This big one has a special scent...
It should bring a catch for sure.
Thank you so much!
It's pulling!
Something's pulling!
With great strength!
Don't panic, Mitsuhiko!
Calmly and carefully reel in the line!
You've got it, see?
That's it!
Keep going, just like that!
It's too heavy!
I'm losing my grip!
Just a little more—keep reeling it in!
It's a black one!
Come on, you got it!
This is...
This is it?
Ouch!
Are you all right?
Let me take a look.
It's no big deal.
I'll clean the wound for you.
I have band-aids.
We'll disinfect it in a moment.
All right...
Conan-kun, it's late...
We were getting worried.
You guys had better hurry and get them counted!
What's wrong?
Not feeling well?
Is it because you guys don't even have anything to be counted?
Not even one!?
All four of you!?
So four times zero is still zero?
Sonoko, that's enough!
Yeah, but...
It's time to announce today's results from the competition.
Currently in the first place, with a catch weight of 13.524 kilograms, is Ayukawa Saori-san!
She's really good!
We had the right place and the right bait, and then...
It's probably just luck.
Tomorrow, we'll make our comeback with a change of luck!
Do you guys actually think it's that easy?
What the hell are you talking about?
Please don't say something like that!
There's no reason for you to get this angry...
I'm going first.
It's big, isn't it?
It was caught by a friend of mine.
February 24 2001
Fisherman
Kanie Kensuke
Is that guy's name Kanie-san?
Yeah, Kanie Kensuke.
Used to be quite famous.
How can we catch fish that big?
You'd have to start learning to fish at a young age.
If you start right now...
You'll definitely turn into a great fisherman when you grow up.
Really?
I wish I could start right now...
Say, Saori-san...
What made you want to start fishing in the first place?
Since my father fished often...
He would always take me to a lake or river when I was young.
Because of that, I hadn't even been to an amusement park or zoo before high school.
Really?
That's so sad...
There you are, Ayukawa-san!
How'd you like to grab a drink together...
To celebrate your victory?
No thanks...
What's wrong...
Don't want to have a drink with me?
Is it really appropriate for you to refuse like this?
Relax, I'm just kidding!
Honestly, I wanted to seek your advice on a particular topic...
The other reason I came here was to solve the case about the express train.
You must know all about everything that happens around here, correct?
Well, I wouldn't exactly go that far...
I know you'll help me—tell me you will, please...
Please, Saori-san...
Very well.
You'll be such a big help!
Thank you so much!
Is he writing about the express train?
I've read an article by him before.
He's a freelance writer.
He's written for many different magazines.
I see...
Hey, Conan, how about we fish on a boat today?
In this season...
The bass tend to stay in shaded water near the shore to search for food.
Forget your reasoning—we didn't even catch anything yesterday.
That's why, today...
Boat it is...
It's the only way to win!
I'm still going to fish on the shore.
I'm going for a different location today.
Guess we'll split up here, then.
What to do...
Ayukawa-san!
Good morning.
Where are you going fishing today, Ayukawa-san?
I'm going to Kutani River today.
Can I come with you?
Well, it may not be such a good idea, since it's kind of dangerous there...
Is that so...
I'm sorry, Ayumi-chan...
Well, good luck, everyone!
Kutani River, huh?
Let's go over there too, Mitsuhiko.
We'll have to get there by boat.
Well, good luck, everyone.
Let's get going, Ayumi-chan.
Look, it's Ayukawa-san!
Where?
I see her!
Ayukawa-san!
Maybe I should've taken the boat...
Look, it's the express train!
Hey!
What's wrong?
Did we hit something?
I thought I heard something...
What's this?
It's probably some kind of fishing tool.
But I've never seen one like this before...
That's the other favorite for first place, Masubuchi-san, right?
He'll probably make a lot of catches here, then.
Does it really matter how talented he is?
Hey, it's already the second day...
Conan-kun and the others will probably catch a bunch today.
Is that so?
It's just a little further upstream, right?
What's wrong?
Hey, look over there.
What's he doing?
He probably gave up and started resting...
Because he couldn't catch anything.
That can't be...
What's wrong, Ran-neechan?
Conan-kun...
Somebody collapsed over there!
Ayumi-chan, don't move.
I got it!
Funaki-san!
Petroleum...
There should be bloodstains left behind if he hit his head before accidentally falling...
So search carefully and thoroughly!
And what of the time of death?
The body's still warm...
So the time of death is most likely between 15 to 30 minutes ago.
That guy looks scary...
And the ones who discovered the body are...
You guys are...
With the Smoky Kogorou...
It's Sleeping Kogorou.
Sorry for the trouble from before, Inspector Yokomizo.
And you are?
Second-year Teitan High School student Suzuki Sonoko...
Representative sponsor of this fishing tournament.
I guess that makes you the rich daughter of that flashy sponsoring company...
Now then, please describe how you discovered the victim, in detail.
Sonoko and I were on our way to the tournament headquarters.
We wanted to see how Conan-kun and the kids were doing, but...
We happened to find Funaki-san lying here on the ground instead.
So the victim's name is Funaki...
Yeah...
He's a freelance magazine writer.
He said he wanted to write a special article for this month's issue of the magazine "Bass."
Where were you at that time?
About 30 meters upstream from here...
' ' ' I
I was fishing with Ayumi-chan.
While you were there...
Did you happen to hear anything like a scream from the victim?
Nothing like that...
Inspector, a moment.
Did you find it?
About that...
We searched very thoroughly, but...
We couldn't find anything that might have hit the victim's head.
What?
Absolutely nothing?
So you were around Otaki Rock from 10:00 to 10:30 AM...
Can anyone confirm that?
I was with him.
We were fishing there all morning.
Hey, where is this place?
Right around here.
All right, you two are free to go.
What a scary-looking guy!
Funaki-san's body was discovered within 30 minutes of his death...
And it takes about 20 minutes to walk from the headquarters to the body's location...
Moreover, if you didn't have a boat...
The only way to cross the river would be the road on the dam.
It takes at least five minutes to cross that...
So people on the other side of the dam...
And those closest to the inner lake...
Can be eliminated as suspects.
It's Ayukawa Saori-san, right?
Yes, that's right.
What's wrong...
Don't want to have a drink with me?
Is it really appropriate for you to refuse like this?
Where were you between 10:00 and 10:30 this morning?
Please, explain.
All right...
I was up towards one of the streams that flows into Kutani River.
Can anyone else attest to that?
We saw her!
Even though we were on our boat...
We clearly saw her passing by on the shore of Kutani River.
It's true...
She even waved "bye-bye" to us.
There's no mistaking it!
Fair enough.
You're free to go.
Please excuse me.
Looks like we're next!
Don't worry about it.
Don't you need our alibis?
Just don't get in the way, kids...
That gave me a scare.
That was the guy who took a picture of us, right?
That place is probably cursed.
Cursed?
What you mean by that, Mizui-san?
Actually, someone else also died there about half a year ago.
Because there was no one else around at the time...
The case was concluded as an accident.
Who was the victim?
It was Kanie-san.
He was close to Ayukawa-san and Masubuchi-san.
Kanie...
Kanie Kensuke.
Used to be quite famous.
Then, he was also a favorite to become champion, right?
Yeah, and just like Masubuchi-san, he learned fishing from Ayukawa-san's father.
Ayukawa-san's father?
He already passed away, but...
He was one of the creators of fishing tournaments in Japan.
He even formed clubs, and taught people to fish for bass.
Someone else died there half a year ago...
This can't be a coincidence.
Most likely, the culprit is one of those two.
THE FISHING TOURNAMENT TRAGEDY (PART TWO)
First, Masubuchi-san...
Please tell us your whereabouts between 10:00 and 10:30 AM yesterday.
10:00 to 10:30, huh?
I was below the metal bridge at the time.
Which side of the metal bridge were you under?
The side with the rail tracks.
By the tracks?
Yeah, that's right.
The location of Funaki's death is...
In the grass, 100 meters upstream from the bridge.
I figured as much...
I was surprised to see so many police officers around there.
I believe that the route to that area will pass by your backside...
Did you see anyone suspicious passing by?
No, I didn't...
I was concentrating on my fishing.
Is there anyone who can prove that you didn't leave the area below the bridge?
There isn't.
No solid alibi...
Masubuchi-san was nearby...
Uhm...
What is it?
Is that all?
Yeah, there's nothing else for now.
No sign that the victim called for help...
And no trace of the weapon used.
Conan, does this mean we can't fish anymore?
It won't end this way.
You guys can still go fishing if you want to...
Understood.
Inspector, all the people on the lake were using rented boats...
And all of their alibis have just been confirmed.
It seems that there was never any boat near the crime scene.
So the culprit didn't use a boat?
If that's the case...
Then the culprit's probably among the people who walked around the lake.
Inspector, we went to the hotel where the victim stayed last night...
And one guest was able to give us a valuable statement.
What is it?
Right.
Apparently, the victim had some sort of dispute with a man named Masubuchi.
Is that so?
All right...
Well?
You seemed to have some sort of conflict with Funaki-san.
Hey, brats!
Why are you trying to eavesdrop here!?
We're just fishing here!
Yeah, we figure that we can catch some pretty big fish...
If we're at the location selected by the front-runner, Masubuchi-san.
That's right, as big as a whale!
But we wouldn't be able to transport a fish that big!
You guys...
Catching something like that would be perfect for showing off at school.
We can show off!
Geez, such big talk from such little kids...
Well, how about it, Masubuchi-san?
Staying silent will only make your situation worse, you know...
Because many people witnessed your argument with Funaki-san.
Funaki-san.
Funaki-san?
I only raised my voice because...
He said something odd.
Something odd?
That's...
What is it?
He asked, "You like Ayukawa-san, don't you?"
"If so, how about I take a picture of you with her?"
So I got mad.
Is that the whole story?
Yeah, and he said that she wouldn't be able to refuse if he told her to do it.
Funaki-san said that Ayukawa-san wouldn't be able to refuse if he told her to do it...
Come to think of it, last night...
Ayukawa-san agreed to his request despite appearing unwilling...
Someone died here half a year ago as well...
Conan, why did we have to come here?
The police found nothing, so...
I don't think we can find any clues here.
Let's go back.
Mitsuhiko has a point...
There's no murder weapon here...
And we didn't even hear a cry for help from Funaki-san...
Express train...
The smell of petroleum...
The stain on his vest...
That's it!
Genta, Mitsuhiko—follow this track!
But why?
Funaki-san wasn't killed here!
He should've been killed somewhere along this track.
Where are we going? I don't see anything.
We're almost at Okutani Station.
There has to be something...
Getting hungry...
Doesn't that belong to Funaki-san?
This is the actual crime scene...
But how did the culprit do it?
Did anyone come up to this bridge from 10:00 to 10:30 this morning?
Was there a photographer?
Oh yeah, he came at about 9:50 AM from the around the dam...
And then left using the stairs that you guys just walked up.
Did anybody else come here afterwards?
Nobody else came after the scene caused by the arrival of all the police.
Is that so...
Well, Ayukawa-san came early in the morning...
And then left through those stairs.
Ayukawa-san did?
Yeah, at around 7:30...
She returned after about 10 minutes.
So it was Ayukawa-san after all...
But how did she do it?
Hey...
We almost forgot that we have to return the boat.
Genta, you said that you saw Ayukawa-san walking upstream this morning, but...
Which side of the shore was it?
Let's see...
It was left from where we looked up...
So it should be this side.
If she came back this way...
And threw a rock on Funaki-san from above...
Then she had to have crossed the bridge...
But the guard said that nobody crossed it.
Besides, if he was murdered here, how did the body end up all the way over there?
How did she carry it over?
If he drifted naturally down the lake in that direction...
And then crawled up onto shore after regaining consciousness...
No, Funaki-san's body wasn't wet, and there was no boat involved.
Discovering the body over there simply feels unusual...
But there's no doubt that this is the crime scene.
Conan-kun...
We'll be charged extra if we don't go return the boat now.
How did the culprit do it?
Conan-kun, the boat...
Yeah, I got it...
Are you two getting on too?
I guess so.
All right.
Genta-kun, let's get rid of this.
What is that?
We found it earlier.
Where?
Around where Kutani River merges with the main river path.
Wait, that handkerchief...
What is it?
That handkerchief... It belongs to Ayukawa-san!
I understand!
And the winner, with a total catch of 30.5 kilograms of bass, is Masubuchi Takuya-san!
The sponsor's representative, Suzuki Sonoko-san will present the award.
Let's all give a round of applause!
A few words?
I chose the right location this time, and I got lucky.
I'll put even more effort in the next tournament!
I know you're the culprit—I'll find proof...
In second place, with a total catch of 22.68 kilograms, is...
Ayukawa Saori-san!
Please share a few words!
I aimed for two wins in a row, but...
Unfortunately, I lost to Masubuchi-san.
Next year, I'll be the one taking home the big trophy!
Let's give them another big round of applause!
Well then, that concludes the 17th Suzuki Cup Lake Okutani Fishing Tournament!
Thank you all for attending!
Hey, doesn't that look a lot like Sleeping Kogorou!?
What?
Ayukawa-san, just a minute.
I'd like for you to speak a little more...
About your motive for murdering Funaki-san.
What was that!?
What? It was Ayukawa-san?
Why did something like this happen...
In this tournament sponsored by father's company?
Well, would you care to explain?
What are you saying!?
At the time of the crime...
Saori-san was at Kutani River, on the opposite side of the lake!
That doesn't matter...
Because Funaki-san was not killed where he was found.
How is that possible?
Conan-kun, show it to everyone.
This camera was found by the rail track along the Kutani River.
It belongs to Funaki-san.
I remember it from when he took pictures of us yesterday.
What?
The victim's camera was by the shore of Kutani River...
But why was it there?
The precise location is below the Kutani Bridge...
And these are the pictures developed from the film in the camera.
Yes, sir.
There is a picture of the express train among them, right?
The only place to take a picture of that...
Is the little piece of flatland underneath the Kutani Bridge where the frame and the cliff connect.
I asked the people working for the railroad magazine...
And they agreed that that place is the best location to take a good picture of the train.
Ayukawa-san, you were invited to have a drink with Funaki-san last night, were you not?
During that time, you heard that he wanted to photograph the express train for the magazine...
So you informed him of that place.
But...
Funaki-san was found 3 kilometers away, on the other side of the bridge.
Didn't I already tell you that that's irrelevant?
Inspector Yokomizo...
Did you notice the stain on Funaki-san's vest?
Well...
I suppose the forensics report did mention that.
I believe it was petroleum and coal dust.
They were from the smoke expelled by the passing express train.
Smoke?
Funaki-san had been on top of the express train...
From underneath the Kutani Bridge to the location his body was discovered.
On top of it!?
While waiting for the best opportunity for a good shot of the train...
Funaki-san was struck on the head by a falling rock...
And fell over the cliff onto the top of the train.
After that, he stayed up there and passed the bridge...
Fell off when the train made a sharp turn...
And landed where we found him.
But isn't all that a little too much of a coincidence?
It's not a coincidence.
A train leaves the Okutani Station every morning at 10:50.
In order to make sure that he fell onto the train...
Ayukawa-san needed perfect timing to kill Funaki-san.
Then...
Was the location that the body fell to also a part of her calculations?
Most likely.
No way...
No matter how careless Funaki-san was...
It couldn't have been that easy for Saori-san to kill him.
Besides...
If it's something like a rock that's thrown down from the bridge...
The guard at the end of the bridge should've seen it.
I have confirmed with the guard...
That nobody crossed the bridge between 10:00 and 10:30.
If that's the case, then Saori-san couldn't possibly have committed the crime.
You've been made to think that way...
But Saori-san is indeed the culprit.
This is a very meticulously planned-out and executed crime.
That's impossible!
Saori-san was at Kutani River, on the other side of the bridge.
Weren't you, Saori-san?
That's true...
But what the guard said...
Was that Ayukawa-san walked down the nearby stairs at 7:30 AM.
Even so, I don't think her going there at that time has anything to do with the crime...
Conan-kun.
Coming!
Isn't this just a wooden board?
Genta-kun and Mitsuhiko-kun found this while on their boat...
At the location where the Kutani River merges into the main one.
Ayukawa-san used this board there.
How did she use it?
At around 7:30 in the morning...
Ayukawa-san tied the board directly above where Funaki-san stood...
With half of it dangling in the air, just on the verge of falling over...
And placed a rock on top of it.
At 10:07, from the other side of the bridge...
Ayukawa-san aimed her fishing hook above Funaki-san, who was taking photos of the train...
That's just what you imagined...
Do you have any actual proof that this happened?
Masubuchi-san, didn't you find it odd that Ayukawa-san would go to Kutani River?
It's not a very good fishing spot, is it?
Now, why would she be there if her goal was to win first place?
Also, the handkerchief tied to the board belongs to her, too.
Anyone could have the same kind of handkerchief!
Please go analyze that handkerchief...
It should react to luminol.
But I don't see any bloodstains on it...
Ayukawa-san, didn't you use this handkerchief when Ayumi-chan hurt herself yesterday?
If that's the case, some of her blood has to be on it.
Of course, you won't be able to see it now...
But, Ayukawa-san...
After drying once...
Blood will react to luminol no matter how much you wash it.
Just how long after helping Ayumi-chan did you wash it?
Ayukawa-san?...
Why did you murder Funaki-san?
For half a year, that guy's been blackmailing me...
Saori-san...
Half a year ago...
A person named Kanie-san also wound up like Funaki-san...
And was discovered at the same location.
Funaki-san's blackmail probably has something to do with that incident, right?
I never intended to kill Kanie-san...
You mean that you killed this man named Kanie too?
We were walking along Kutani River...
I'm just not ready for marriage yet...
You're in love with Masubuchi after all, aren't you...
How about it? At least give me a clear answer!
Saori-san...
So Funaki-san happened to witness that incident...
And then threatened you...
Isn't that it?
I won't mention anything to the police...
In exchange, you help me financially. I'm in a pinch and could use 2 million yen.
How about it?
The newest camera on the market costs over a million yen...
Know what I mean?
On three different occasions...
I actually gave him more than 7 million yen.
And then, about half a month ago...
I heard about how you got sponsored by Pacific Sports, with a contract and everything...
How much are you raking in?
That's none of your business.
Whatever you say...
Think you can toss me 10 million yen?
If not, you know what would happen, right?
After that, when he mentioned that he wanted to photograph that express train...
I thought he would definitely go to that spot below the bridge if I told him about it.
All you had to do was get the timing right...
And the train would just carry the body away...
Exactly how it happened with Kanie-san.
That was your plan, right?
When I thought about the possibility of being blackmailed for the rest of my life...
It would make my sight turn completely black...
It seems I've ruined your whole tournament...
I truly am sorry.
Compared to me, isn't the tournament more important to people like you?
Father...
I'm sorry.
Ayukawa Saori-san, we'll have to discuss the case in further detail...
Please come with us to the station.
Right...
Saori-san!
No matter how long it takes, I'll be waiting for you...
Saori-san...
They really were amazing, weren't they?
Sonoko-neechan's deductions.
They sure were!
Seriously, when did you go investigate all of that?
Well, uhm, little by little...
It's a piece of cake for me!
I don't remember anything about doing something that great...
What's this "little by little" stuff about...
That's right, what about you guys?
Catch any fish?
Well, that...
Making a big catch is way harder than solving a case...