Friendship! Romance! Mystery!
We try our best because we've made those promises!
The point is in the fishing and trolley.
We reveal the truth that goes against common sense!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Invited by Sokoko,
we all come to a bass fishing contest held at Lake Okutani.
There, we meet the candidates for championship
Ayukawa Saori (27)
Tournament Participant
Masubuchi Takuya (29)
Mr. Takuya Masubuchi,
as well as freelance writer Mr. Toshihiko Funaki.
Funaki Toshihiko (35)
Freelance Writer
The competition for the 1st day ends.
It's a bit of a concern that
that night, Mr. Funaki and Mr. Masubuchi get into an argument,
and sure enough, the following day,
very near the place we were fishing,
Mr. Funaki is found dead from a strong impact to his head.
I wonder if that place is cursed...
Cursed?!
Mr. Minai, what do you mean?
The thing is somebody died there 6 months ago too.
Who is the person that died?
A person called Mr. Kanie,
who was also good friends with Ms. Ayukawa and Mr. Masubuchi.
A person died there half a year ago.
This is no coincidence.
The murderer is probably one of the two!
THE FISHING TOURNAMENT TRAGEDY
(PART TWO)
First, Masubuchi-san...
Please tell us your whereabouts between 10:00 and 10:30 AM yesterday.
10:00 to 10:30, huh?
I was below the metal bridge at the time.
Which side of the metal bridge were you under?
The side with the rail tracks.
By the tracks?
Yeah, that's right.
The location of Funaki's death is...
In the grass, 100 meters upstream from the bridge.
I figured as much...
I was surprised to see so many police officers around there.
I believe that the route to that area will pass by your backside...
Did you see anyone suspicious passing by?
No, I didn't...
I was concentrating on my fishing.
Is there anyone who can prove that you didn't leave the area below the bridge?
There isn't.
No solid alibi...
Masubuchi-san was nearby...
Uhm...
What is it?
Is that all?
Yeah, there's nothing else for now.
No sign that the victim called for help...
And no trace of the weapon used.
Conan, does this mean we can't fish anymore?
It won't end this way.
You guys can still go fishing if you want to...
Understood.
Inspector, all the people on the lake were using rented boats...
And all of their alibis have just been confirmed.
It seems that there was never any boat near the crime scene.
So the culprit didn't use a boat?
If that's the case...
Then the culprit's probably among the people who walked around the lake.
Inspector, we went to the hotel where the victim stayed last night...
And one guest was able to give us a valuable statement.
What is it?
Right.
Apparently, the victim had some sort of dispute with a man named Masubuchi.
Is that so?
All right...
Well?
You seemed to have some sort of conflict with Funaki-san.
Hey, brats!
Why are you trying to eavesdrop here!?
We're just fishing here!
Yeah, we figure that we can catch some pretty big fish...
If we're at the location selected by the front-runner, Masubuchi-san.
That's right, as big as a whale!
But we wouldn't be able to transport a fish that big!
You guys...
Catching something like that would be perfect for showing off at school.
We can show off!
Geez, such big talk from such little kids...
Well, how about it, Masubuchi-san?
Staying silent will only make your situation worse, you know...
Because many people witnessed your argument with Funaki-san.
Funaki-san.
Funaki-san?
I only raised my voice because...
He said something odd.
Something odd?
That's...
What is it?
He asked, "You like Ayukawa-san, don't you?"
"If so, how about I take a picture of you with her?"
So I got mad.
Is that the whole story?
Yeah, and he said that she wouldn't be able to refuse if he told her to do it.
Funaki-san said that Ayukawa-san wouldn't be able to refuse if he told her to do it...
Come to think of it, last night...
Ayukawa-san agreed to his request despite appearing unwilling...
Someone died here half a year ago as well...
Conan, why did we have to come here?
The police found nothing, so...
I don't think we can find any clues here.
Let's go back.
Mitsuhiko has a point...
There's no murder weapon here...
And we didn't even hear a cry for help from Funaki-san...
Express train...
The smell of petroleum...
The stain on his vest...
That's it!
Genta, Mitsuhiko—follow this track!
But why?
Funaki-san wasn't killed here!
He should've been killed somewhere along this track.
Where are we going? I don't see anything.
We're almost at Okutani Station.
There has to be something...
Getting hungry...
Doesn't that belong to Funaki-san?
This is the actual crime scene...
But how did the culprit do it?
Did anyone come up to this bridge from 10:00 to 10:30 this morning?
Was there a photographer?
Oh yeah, he came at about 9:50 AM from the around the dam...
And then left using the stairs that you guys just walked up.
Did anybody else come here afterwards?
Nobody else came after the scene caused by the arrival of all the police.
Is that so...
Well, Ayukawa-san came early in the morning...
And then left through those stairs.
Ayukawa-san did?
Yeah, at around 7:30...
She returned after about 10 minutes.
So it was Ayukawa-san after all...
But how did she do it?
Hey...
We almost forgot that we have to return the boat.
Genta, you said that you saw Ayukawa-san walking upstream this morning, but...
Which side of the shore was it?
Let's see...
It was left from where we looked up...
So it should be this side.
If she came back this way...
And threw a rock on Funaki-san from above...
Then she had to have crossed the bridge...
But the guard said that nobody crossed it.
Besides, if he was murdered here, how did the body end up all the way over there?
How did she carry it over?
If he drifted naturally down the lake in that direction...
And then crawled up onto shore after regaining consciousness...
No, Funaki-san's body wasn't wet, and there was no boat involved.
Discovering the body over there simply feels unusual...
But there's no doubt that this is the crime scene.
Conan-kun...
We'll be charged extra if we don't go return the boat now.
How did the culprit do it?
Conan-kun, the boat...
Yeah, I got it...
Are you two getting on too?
I guess so.
All right.
Genta-kun, let's get rid of this.
What is that?
We found it earlier.
Where?
Around where Kutani River merges with the main river path.
Wait, that handkerchief...
What is it?
That handkerchief... It belongs to Ayukawa-san!
I understand!
And the winner, with a total catch of 30.5 kilograms of bass, is Masubuchi Takuya-san!
The sponsor's representative, Suzuki Sonoko-san will present the award.
Let's all give a round of applause!
A few words?
I chose the right location this time, and I got lucky.
I'll put even more effort in the next tournament!
I know you're the culprit—I'll find proof...
In second place, with a total catch of 22.68 kilograms, is...
Ayukawa Saori-san!
Please share a few words!
I aimed for two wins in a row, but...
Unfortunately, I lost to Masubuchi-san.
Next year, I'll be the one taking home the big trophy!
Let's give them another big round of applause!
Well then, that concludes the 17th Suzuki Cup Lake Okutani Fishing Tournament!
Thank you all for attending!
Hey, doesn't that look a lot like Sleeping Kogoro!?
What?
Ayukawa-san, just a minute.
I'd like for you to speak a little more...
About your motive for murdering Funaki-san.
What was that!?
What? It was Ayukawa-san?
Why did something like this happen...
In this tournament sponsored by father's company?
Well, would you care to explain?
What are you saying!?
At the time of the crime...
Saori-san was at Kutani River, on the opposite side of the lake!
That doesn't matter...
Because Funaki-san was not killed where he was found.
How is that possible?
Conan-kun, show it to everyone.
This camera was found by the rail track along the Kutani River.
It belongs to Funaki-san.
I remember it from when he took pictures of us yesterday.
What?
The victim's camera was by the shore of Kutani River...
But why was it there?
The precise location is below the Kutani Bridge...
And these are the pictures developed from the film in the camera.
Yes, sir.
There is a picture of the express train among them, right?
The only place to take a picture of that...
Is the little piece of flatland underneath the Kutani Bridge where the frame and the cliff connect.
I asked the people working for the railroad magazine...
And they agreed that that place is the best location to take a good picture of the train.
Ayukawa-san, you were invited to have a drink with Funaki-san last night, were you not?
During that time, you heard that he wanted to photograph the express train for the magazine...
So you informed him of that place.
But...
Funaki-san was found 3 kilometers away, on the other side of the bridge.
Didn't I already tell you that that's irrelevant?
Inspector Yokomizo...
Did you notice the stain on Funaki-san's vest?
Well...
I suppose the forensics report did mention that.
I believe it was petroleum and coal dust.
They were from the smoke expelled by the passing express train.
Smoke?
Funaki-san had been on top of the express train...
From underneath the Kutani Bridge to the location his body was discovered.
On top of it!?
While waiting for the best opportunity for a good shot of the train...
Funaki-san was struck on the head by a falling rock...
And fell over the cliff onto the top of the train.
After that, he stayed up there and passed the bridge...
Fell off when the train made a sharp turn...
And landed where we found him.
But isn't all that a little too much of a coincidence?
It's not a coincidence.
A train leaves the Okutani Station every morning at 10:50.
In order to make sure that he fell onto the train...
Ayukawa-san needed perfect timing to kill Funaki-san.
Then...
Was the location that the body fell to also a part of her calculations?
Most likely.
No way...
No matter how careless Funaki-san was...
It couldn't have been that easy for Saori-san to kill him.
Besides...
If it's something like a rock that's thrown down from the bridge...
The guard at the end of the bridge should've seen it.
I have confirmed with the guard...
That nobody crossed the bridge between 10:00 and 10:30.
If that's the case, then Saori-san couldn't possibly have committed the crime.
You've been made to think that way...
But Saori-san is indeed the culprit.
This is a very meticulously planned-out and executed crime.
That's impossible!
Saori-san was at Kutani River, on the other side of the bridge.
Weren't you, Saori-san?
That's true...
But what the guard said...
Was that Ayukawa-san walked down the nearby stairs at 7:30 AM.
Even so, I don't think her going there at that time has anything to do with the crime...
Conan-kun.
Coming!
Isn't this just a wooden board?
Genta-kun and Mitsuhiko-kun found this while on their boat...
At the location where the Kutani River merges into the main one.
Ayukawa-san used this board there.
How did she use it?
At around 7:30 in the morning...
Ayukawa-san tied the board directly above where Funaki-san stood...
With half of it dangling in the air, just on the verge of falling over...
And placed a rock on top of it.
At 10:07, from the other side of the bridge...
Ayukawa-san aimed her fishing hook above Funaki-san, who was taking photos of the train...
That's just what you imagined...
Do you have any actual proof that this happened?
Masubuchi-san, didn't you find it odd that Ayukawa-san would go to Kutani River?
It's not a very good fishing spot, is it?
Now, why would she be there if her goal was to win first place?
Also, the handkerchief tied to the board belongs to her, too.
Anyone could have the same kind of handkerchief!
Please go analyze that handkerchief...
It should react to luminol.
But I don't see any bloodstains on it...
Ayukawa-san, didn't you use this handkerchief when Ayumi-chan hurt herself yesterday?
If that's the case, some of her blood has to be on it.
Of course, you won't be able to see it now...
But, Ayukawa-san...
After drying once...
Blood will react to luminol no matter how much you wash it.
Just how long after helping Ayumi-chan did you wash it?
Ayukawa-san?...
Why did you murder Funaki-san?
For half a year, that guy's been blackmailing me...
Saori-san...
Half a year ago...
A person named Kanie-san also wound up like Funaki-san...
And was discovered at the same location.
Funaki-san's blackmail probably has something to do with that incident, right?
I never intended to kill Kanie-san...
You mean that you killed this man named Kanie too?
We were walking along Kutani River...
I'm just not ready for marriage yet...
You're in love with Masubuchi after all, aren't you...
How about it? At least give me a clear answer!
Saori-san...
So Funaki-san happened to witness that incident...
And then threatened you...
Isn't that it?
I won't mention anything to the police...
In exchange, you help me financially. I'm in a pinch and could use 2 million yen.
How about it?
The newest camera on the market costs over a million yen...
Know what I mean?
On three different occasions...
I actually gave him more than 7 million yen.
And then, about half a month ago...
I heard about how you got sponsored by Pacific Sports, with a contract and everything...
How much are you raking in?
That's none of your business.
Whatever you say...
Think you can toss me 10 million yen?
If not, you know what would happen, right?
After that, when he mentioned that he wanted to photograph that express train...
I thought he would definitely go to that spot below the bridge if I told him about it.
All you had to do was get the timing right...
And the train would just carry the body away...
Exactly how it happened with Kanie-san.
That was your plan, right?
When I thought about the possibility of being blackmailed for the rest of my life...
It would make my sight turn completely black...
It seems I've ruined your whole tournament...
I truly am sorry.
Compared to me, isn't the tournament more important to people like you?
Father...
I'm sorry.
Ayukawa Saori-san, we'll have to discuss the case in further detail...
Please come with us to the station.
Right...
Saori-san!
No matter how long it takes, I'll be waiting for you...
Saori-san...
They really were amazing, weren't they?
Sonoko-neechan's deductions.
They sure were!
Seriously, when did you go investigate all of that?
Well, uhm, little by little...
It's a piece of cake for me!
I don't remember anything about doing something that great...
What's this "little by little" stuff about...
That's right, what about you guys?
Catch any fish?
Well, that...
Making a big catch is way harder than solving a case...