Friendship! Romance! Mystery!
We try our best because we've made those promises!
The client is a famous child actor!
Searching for his mother, we plunge into a hot springs!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
With the body of a child and the brain of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
If I become his wife. Kanichi-san, what will you do?
Well then you're finally going to get married, aren't you?
You would never listen to anything I said.
Dad!
No, stay back!
As long as the moon of this night looks down on me. I'll forget... I'll forget about you!
Hey, Dad! Can you hear me?
And whenever the moon is clouded, wherever
Kanichi-san is, he'll curse you and weep about this night.
This is Youko-chan's big scene.
Kanichi-san...
will never forget about you.
Note: Konjiki Yasha (Golden Demon) is a serial story written by Ozaki Kouyou from 1897 to 1903, telling the story of Kanichi and O-Miya, whose romance falters when she marries a rich man and he becomes a vicious moneylender.
Isn't this the scene from "Golden Demon" with Kanichi and O-Miya on the beach at Atami?
How many times have you watched this video?
Huh!? Hey, Ran!
This is more important.
You'd better explain to me clearly why you turned down Mom's invitation to have dinner.
Ah, it's just that day wasn't very convenient.
What was so inconvenient?
What's the big deal? It's not like she's died or anything.
We can see her anytime.
That reminds me, the author of "Golden Demon", Ozaki Kouyou, died while serializing it and it was left unfinished.
And so these two lost the means to attain happiness for all eternity.
But in our case, I won't let it go unfinished.
Definitely.
You wouldn't be...
Still trying to put me and Eri back together, would you?
Of course I am!
Don't you think any child would want both their parents to get along with one another?
That's just nonsense.
There are some people who don't even want to see their parent's faces.
Kinukawa Kazuki (7)
Talent
And I'm one of them.
What's with this kid?
Heh?
Where have I seen his face before?
Could it be, little boy,
That you're Kinukawa Kazuki-kun, the famous child actor from those TV dramas and movies?
Uh, well yeah.
Wow, you're even cuter than you look on TV.
What's a famous star want in a detective agency?
I want you to look for someone.
Whoever sent these postcards to me.
Some woman named Atsuko.
A SMALL CLIENT
(PART ONE)
True enough, the sender wrote only her name without her address.
Wait, aren't these fan letters?
They include a lot of comments about the dramas and movies that Kazuki-kun was in.
It looks like she's a really big fan.
Because from the spring two years ago through the winter last year she sent one every month.
But every one of these is covered in stains and all worn-out.
If they're fan letters, you should treat them seriously.
How could I help it? They creep me out so I just left them lying around.
Creep you out?
Those aren't fan letters.
Because those postcards are from my mother.
Your mother?
Yeah.
Six years ago, when I was one year old, that stupid woman abandoned me in front of a church like I was garbage.
I see. That's why you said you didn't want to see your parents.
But since you want me to search for her, I suppose you must still really want to see your mother.
Don't misunderstand me.
I only want to see her so I can tell her one thing.
She'd better not try acting like she's my mother now that I've become famous.
But how do you know? She hasn't written a single thing that says she's your mother.
I know.
Note: Please take care of Kazuki -Atsuko.
The memo that was with me when I was abandoned had the same handwriting and name as the postcards.
Still, as for searching for her...
Since the postmarks on these postcards range from Hokkaido to Okinawa, all we know is she likes to travel a lot.
Well, never mind then.
I'll ask a different detective.
I think it's either a hotel or Japanese-style inn in Atami.
The place where your mother is.
Where was that written?
Ah, look at this. This picture postcard.
Isn't that the hand and head of some statue at the bottom of the photo?
Haven't you seen that statue somewhere before?
Oh yeah, where was that?
Ah, I know.
Here!
It's exactly like this pose.
It must be the statue of Kanichi and O-Miya at the beach in Atami.
Perhaps she used the top left section of a four-part picture postcard set.
She could have just used something she'd bought as a souvenir.
But there are three other postcards the same as that one, and they all are just the top left section.
If she was rich enough to travel all over Japan, I think she'd would have sent all four sections.
And wouldn't there be picture postcards of other sight-seeing places in here as well?
Ah, that's it.
I bet your mother didn't want you to know where she was.
So she used the top left postcard, since it would be hardest to figure out that this was the statue of Kanichi and O-Miya.
Probably she got this picture postcard because it was left unsold in the shop at a hotel or Japanese-style inn.
I figure she asked the guests staying there to mail these when they got back to their home towns.
That's right! People from all over Japan come to hotels and Japanese-style inns.
And she should tell by looking at the registry where they came from.
In other words, his mother could be an employee at a hotel or inn.
Hey, anyhow, let's go to Atami and check.
I don't mind going, but...
Will my fees be paid when we find her?
Yeah, I'll pay well.
Unlike that woman, I'm rich.
Come on, let's hurry there and get this over with.
My schedule's only open for today and tomorrow.
Lousy brat.
He's kinda like Conan-kun, isn't he?
Huh? What did you say?
Gee, I don't know.
We don't carry this picture postcard here.
Is that so?
Thanks for your trouble.
Geez, we bother to come all the way to Atami...
And even without going to a spa, I'm really sweating in this season.
I guess this postcard wasn't much of a clue after all.
Hey, onee-san.
Carry me!
Ah, you're tired so you want me to carry you on my back.
Hold me! Hold me! You have to carry me in your arms!
Hey, what's this?
You're really a pampered child, eh?
Ah, wait...
It was right here. That's where that woman had a mole.
I remember falling asleep while looking at that mole a lot of times.
But I was smaller back then than I am now, so it might have been a bit lower.
Hey, hey. A bit lower are her...
Hey, can you hold me one more time?
Yeah, that's fine...
It's fine, you don't need to. We know the approximate area.
But we need to make sure...
It's fine! We already know.
Huh? You sell them here?
These postcards?
These are a limited line that are only sold here, but this type of four-part set doesn't sell very well.
Kusano Mitsu (34)
Female Employee
There's nothing we can do, so we divide them among ourselves.
They've already been paid for anyway.
Wow! It's just like you said, Conan-kun.
Um, this might be an awkward question, but...
Might you perhaps have a woman named Atsuko who works here at this inn?
No, there isn't anyone like that here.
Ah, I see.
Ah, excuse me but, could it be that you're that famous...
Ah, yes. The great detective, Mouri...
Aren't you Kinukawa Kazuki-kun?
Ah, I knew it!
Hey, Bessho-san, come here! It's Kazuki-kun!
Bessho Toshiko (29)
Female Employee
G-Good afternoon.
That's strange, she's a real big fan of Kazuki-kun.
I guess she's feeling shy.
Ah, so, .why are you here today? Did you come to stay?
Ah, no, the truth is...
I bet you came looking for someone?
Kamoshita Yasuhiro (37)
Freelance Writer
The one who abandoned you —
your mother.
W-Wait a minute, who are you to say that?
A guest, just a guest.
I'm Kamoshita, the one who reserved room 205.
I was just planning to check things out today.
But here it seems the actors are all nicely assembled.
He'll make this a great scoop.
How did that guy know about his mother?
Ah, so, will you be staying?
Say, why don't we stay?
It might be that Kazuki-kun's mother is working here under a different name.
I was intending to say even if you hadn't mentioned that.
This way Kazuki-kun will be with us for a while longer.
Let's see now.
Well then, Saegusa-san.
Saegusa Tomoko (28)
Female Employee
Give them room 308, since the reservation was canceled.
OK.
This is room 308.
The bathrobes and futons are in the closet, so do whatever you want.
Hey, hey!
Can't you explain more thoroughly?
Well aren't you fussy?
I'm busy at the best of times, so I'm not dealing with a bunch of surplus guests.
Don't get all conceited just because you're famous.
Is that how she behaves in front of guests?
It's a deal, chief editor.
Please make space for my pages.
If this scoop turns out to be true, the volume will sell big.
The story that the number one star Kinukawa Kazuzi's father...
Was actually a murderer.
I'm so full.
Geez.
It's your fault that were so late getting to the bath.
It's because he drank too much beer.
What's that?
Ah, this is the lens cap for a camera.
Maybe it belongs to that Kamoshita man we met earlier.
That could be.
Well, I'll go and return it to him.
I remember he said his room was 205.
Hey, Ran! Leave that weird guy alone.
Geez. Nobody listens to what I say.
Whoa!
Mixed bathing!
I wonder if there's anyone there!
Moron. How could there been anyone there at this hour?
Ah, good evening.
Ah, excuse us.
Come in.
Being in the bath with Kazuki-kun will be the memory of a lifetime.
Ah, but...
Why are you acting so innocent?
Oh, my! On close inspection, all three of you...
Seems to have such sexy moles.
Do you always have your bath at this hour?
Yeah, we employees get to use the spa after the guests have had their bath.
But, what's the young lady who came with you doing?
Ah, you mean my daughter Ran. She went to Kamoshita-san's room to return something he'd dropped.
Ran!
If that jerk has done anything to my daughter!
Hey, what's wrong!
L-Look!
He drowned?
No, with these marks on his neck, he was strangled.
Say, look here. He dropped his cellphone.
What?
It looks like a picture was recorded just a bit ago.
Gould it be a picture of the culprit then?
W-What's this?
On the woman's chest. A mole!?
I see, you picked up Kimoshita Yasuhiro-san's camera cap in the corridor.
So you came to his room to return it, and that's how you discovered that he was dead.
Ah, yes.
It's just like Mouri-san said, it seems he was killed by having his neck constricted by a thin string-like object.
And the body was dropped into the bathtub in order to deceive us about the approximate time of death.
But nevertheless, they didn't deceive Mouri Kogorou.
There's a photograph.
Ah, I think it might be better not to mention that yet.
Aren't you the one who's on TV a lot...
I'm Kinukawa Kazuki.
For certain reasons, he's staying with us at this inn.
Come oh, you kids should go back to the room.
Inspector Yokomizo!
According to the people at the inn, Kamoshita-san's been stopping female employees and saying strange things.
Strange things?
"If you remember the twenty million yen the come up to my room."
"Or else I'll reveal just about everything."
I don't understand the meaning of the twenty million, but...
It seems the culprit is some female employee that Kamoshita-san had something on.
In that case we can find out real easily.
It's here on Kinoshita-san's cellphone.
We should just look for female employees who don't have an alibi for the time this picture was taken.
This must be a picture taken of the scene of the crime!
Look, isn't it displayed right there at the bottom? It says 11:48 PM.
Right there on the breast of the woman who's strangling Kimoshita-san's neck from behind - it's a mole!
Oh crap.
There's no mistake! The culprit has to be a woman with a mole on her breast, Mouri-san!
Ah, it's true.
Then the culprit is...
The culprit is my...
Kazuki-kun!
Handkerchief?
Kazuki-kun, where'd you go?
So you came to this inn to find Kinukawa Kazuki-kun's mother?
Yeah.
We had a clue that his mother had a mole on her breast.
And here the culprit has a mole on her breast too.
That's obvious enough.
But I wonder if this photo was really taken by Kimoshita-san.
Not only is the image blurry, but the culprit's face is conveniently out of the picture.
Perhaps in order to create an alibi for herself, the culprit took the picture on purpose and doctored the time display.
I don't think that's the case.
Him again.
The culprit was pulling on the string to strangle the man's neck using both her hands, right?
Since both her hands were occupied, she couldn't have pressed the shutter button.
And if the culprit took the picture, I think she would have put on some clothes so we couldn't tell if it was a man or woman.
That's true.
I'll bet the culprit didn't even realize she'd been photographed.
Isn't that right, Uncle?
But why would Kamoshita-san have his cellphone when he was attacked?
Maybe he was phoning someone?
Then why don't we press the redial button and check?
Stop butting into everything!
It looks like he telephoned someone ten minutes before the picture was taken.
What? Kamoshita was? Really, officer?
Yeah. If you don't mind, could you tell me your name and occupation?
I'm Izumiya, the chief editor of the "Weekly Hot".
Kamoshita was a writer who got a lot of exclusives for us.
Sometime after 11:30 he called to say a woman with a big scoop had come to his room.
He told me she said wanted to wash off her sweat before the interview, so she was taking a shower in his room.
He also told me not to worry because he was going to get a good portrait picture of her with his cellphone camera.
Who was this woman with the big scoop?
The woman who abandoned the star Kinukawa Kazuki in front of a church —
his mother, Atsuko.
It seems the woman was saying his father was a wanted murderer.
And that she blackmailed Kazuki's production company for 20 million yen...
Threatening that she would tell the world —
what an awful woman!
As for the production company, they were dubious at first.
But she knew the name of the church and details about the characteristics of Kazuki's body...
So they said they transferred the money into the woman's account.
Since all their exchanges had been through text messages...
It seems that they never knew the woman's appearance or her voice.
When Kamoshita-san got wind a scoop like that, he went out to get the firsthand story on that woman.
That's why he mentioned the 20 million yen, to scare up the right employee.
Inspector!
Here are the female employees who don't have an alibi for the time around 11:48.
Huh? It's you?
Ah, sorry about before.
So? What is it?
Has something happened?
He's been murdered.
The man who was staying in this room, Kamoshita-san, was strangled.
Really?
Now could you allow us to make a brief check of your bodies?
To see if, like the culprit in this picture that Kamoshita-san took as he was being murdered...
You have a mole on your breast or not.
Wait, what?
You want us to get naked right here?
Ah, no. Of course we'll call a female officer and you can do it in a different room.
W-Well, I guess that would be all right.
Then hurry and get to it.
We still have work left to do.
That's not necessary.
Look, I don't have a mole or anything.
H-Hey, Bessho-san!
You're right It's no big deal.
Come on; you too, Kusano-san. If you object they'll suspect you.
Y-Yeah.
Geez, Uncle...
You've got a mole on your chest!
Please look more carefully, it's on the opposite side from the picture you showed us.
Instead of checking us for moles, shouldn't you be checking the murder weapon for fingerprints?
Or haven't you found it?
The black string that was in that picture.
Ah, no, we're still searching for it.
But the murder weapon isn't anywhere here.
The thin black string we figure to be around one meter in length.
Exactly, the problem is the murder weapon.
And that mole...
What, you went in? Don't tell me you were peeking into the women's bath!
Now I see, that's what it was.
Kazuki-kun?
That sound reminds me of my mother.
That's how it happened.
Then the suspicious person was the one hiding this.
That person!
A SMALL CLIENT
(PART TWO)
Next Conan's Hint!
Video Tapes
Next time is at the spa too. Take a bath!
Don't catch a cold!
Brush your teeth!
See you next week!