Friendship. Romance, Mystery
Because we cherish them
we can continue
Three kimono beauties are suspects
Solve the mystery of
the mole on the chest
He. sees through
the one and only truth,
A child in appearance
with the IKQ. of an adult
No case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
<< 2D
(152 #7)
The Little Client Part 2
N.No murder weapon?
I don't believe it...
You haven't even found
the murder weapon...
We're going back to work.
WwW. Wait!
I'd like to question you all later
so please wait in another room
till then
If you insist that we wait,
we will, though...
«., a
I won't answer no matter
what you ask me!!
After all there's nothing
suspicious about us!!
Just because we were taking
an outdoor bath,
we're not going to take being treated
hike criminals!
Outdoor bath...?
Yes...
it seems that they all took a bath
at about 23:50,
whichtis near the time of the crime...
Then, about 20 minutes later.
Mr. Mouri came and joined them...
What?! He joined them?
Dont tell me you peeked into
the women's 'bathr.
It's for both men and women.
Oh. I see.
Just because it's for both
women and men
it doesn't mean that you can
go ahead and look in, you know!
Agh. I tell you! So listen!
It just thought that if somebody was
already inside, I'd be-lucky...
Huh
Isn't this movie"the one
that Kazuki acted in?
Why is something like that over ; ere
It's the video
hat Mr. Kamoshita rented.
They rent out movie videos
here at the inn...
Give it to me!
Let's take a look at it...
Mr. Mouri, we don't have time
to be taking a look...
Some clue could be hidden in it,
right?!
No --actl
It looks like a scary movie...
Phooey! It's only kid's stuff...
Don't worry...
your mother's not the killer!
I'm not worried at all about
that woman...
Kazuki...?
Mother's sound...
Huh?...
Ha Hey...!
Huh 7
Oh. I'm sorry. A guest suddenly said
he wants dinner so... Was it noisy?
Oh. no...
Oy, so you want to see your mother
after all, don't you, Kazuki"
Not really... I just thought that'd be
a hint to finding her #
Hey, stupid! Look behind you, behind!!
Behind you, I said!
Wait...Something's coming
from the ceiling...
Whaaao
Yikes!!
Ugh!
Yikes!
Talk about getting carried away...
It. It was quite amusing. wasn't it...
Yes...
But. we really got nothing out of it,
did-we...
I guess not...
I see...l get it
That's why the killer soaked his body
into the bath tub
a,er s ranging evic im...
There are only 2 mysteries left to.solve...
The reason why the killer took atbath...
and that mole.
The Killer could've gotten naked
to set the victim off guard.
But what about the mole?
Inspector Yokomizo!
Yes. what is it?
We were concerned about the trace
on the neck that we didn't notice at first...
but they were marks of the victim
being hit several times
on the back of his head...
Hugh
Then, was he struck to death?
No...he seems to have bled,
but it wasn't what killed him...
It's most likely that the killer hit him
and after he passed out,
strangled him to death
If so, the weapon
that was used to hit him...
If so. the weapon
at was used to hit him...
This shower nozzle sure is
worth suspecting...
Please do a luminol reaction test
right away...
I see...
So. that's the story
So. that's the story...
RCH SANSA RIM ES HS UIST USTR EIS O 1
would be the one
who tried to hide it...
Okay. I'll put Pops tgjsleep using
the tranquilizer gun and...
Hey. Conan...
Huh
What do you mean "Huh?!
Hat do you mean. "Huh?!"
It's past three o'clock already,
you'd better get to bed!
We've got to go look for Kazuki's mother
Who's 2 good Cook tomorrow, you know...
Good cook?
Remember...
He mentioned that he used to (0 to slee)
a lot wile looking at his mother s mole?
It seems that
he used to hear the rhythmical sound of
the knife cutting things too!
It means that she's a good cook. right?
I. I guess so
I'll be right over so will you lay
the mattress out for me, okay!
Promise, okay!
Oh, and if Kazuki gets up
please tell him...
Huh /
that his mother is not the killer.
Inspector. Yokomizo.
Luminol reaction was detected from
the shower nozzle!
The killer must've hit Mr. Kamoshita
on the head with this shower nozzle.
Knocked him out and then
strangled him to death after all...
And, diafiou find that thin, long. black
string that was used to choke him?
WwW. Well.
We looked all over where the three
suspects could ve hidden the string,
but no luck so far...
Hmm...
Which means that somebody out of
those three must still have it on her.
Okay, tell the policewoman to do a body
check on them...
I think us: would be useless...
You saw, didn't you?
The picture that was taken
on the cell phone
the moment Mr. Kamoshita was being
strangled to death!
There was a mole on the left side of
the chest of the woman, wasn't there?!
But, Ms. Kusano's mole on her chest
was on the right side...
Ms. Bessho's was on her left cheek...
And. Ms. Saegusa"s was
on the back ofiherineck...
They are obviously not the killers!
If you try to do a body check on them,
you're just going to get them angrier,
don't you think?
But. the only ones who don't have an alibi
among the employees of this inn
are those three...
Well, let's call it a day for now...
Huh 21?
And I'd advise you
to do a re-check on everyone in this inn,
including the guests...
It did poke him for sure...
W. What's going on!
It seems that there's an off-season
mosquito here too besides...
Huh? A mosquito?
See, I got a bite on my neck
just a while ago...Nee-hya?
What?!
Jalapeno, harami, pasta...
H. He's come!! The Sleeping Kogoro!!
So, the needle just didn't poke him
deep enough
Alright then, Inspector Yokomizo!
Please get together the things
that I ask you for
and bring the three suspects here...
Mr Mouri! Which means you've
figured it out after all!
Yes .let me explain,
the truth of what went on in this room
regarding the strangulation of
Mr. Kamoshita...
Hmm...
What you're 'saying doesnlt fit in at all
with what you've been saying
just a while ago...
AW right, Mr. Mount!
AL night. Mr. Mount!
Everything's set...
It's show time!»Sleeping Kogoro's
deduction show is about to begin, .!
Hey. hey!
Why do we have to be called in again?!
You saw for yourself already. didn't you,
that we don't have the same mole
that the killer had!!
Besides...
has the murder weapon been found?
You can't prove the murder without it,
can you...?
Ha, ha, ha! Of course we found it!!
Right. Mr. Mourn!
NO...
Wefhaven't found it.
we haven't found it.
What?!
It has most likely already been perished
P. Persnhed Mr Mourn?!
But. we know what the killer used
to strangle Mr. Kamoshita
because we have this screw driver!
Oh, it seems as-if your hands
have become a bit smaller'...
Ugh...never mind the details...
Inspector! I've rented it!
Shall we compare the two. then...
The video of the same movie that
Mr. Kamoshita rented from this inn
and the video that we rented from
the rental video shop
First we'll look at Mr Kamoshita's video
that was here in this room...
MM . Just as we've seen befo
it has a scary opening scene...
Next, let's look at the video from
the rental video shop.
Huh? Is that all?
The spot display of the video company...
Huh ?
and the spot display of
the movie company
the movie company.
Come on... hey. hey.
Besides,
this is... the prologue of the movie
So. let me explain the story of the cursed
stairs of the school
trange.:. the opening title appeare
mmediately in the video we just saw...
It's been cut off and
shortened about one minute,
For the killer to use it
to murder her victim!
I see! It's the video tape!!
The killer victim opened the video tape
using a screw driver)
and removed the tape from inside.
Then cut off enough tape
to use as the murder weapon.
Sheathen connected the tape together
with scotch tape again!!
Ifeshe adjusts the tape so that the opening
title comes out when the tape is played.
Even if the police were to check the tape
Iater she wouldn t be suspected.
But the black string that was taken
on the cell phone looked much thinner...
That's easy.
Hey disassemble the brand new tape
that Mr. Mouri told you to go buy!
Yes. sir!
Now, please look!
If you don't do anything
it's nothing but a plain black strip.
But if you twist itlike this...
Huh...
It doesn't look like a thinner string...
It sure... doesn't...
You don't twist it, you stretch it out...
Huh? SS. Stretch it out but.
How can you stretch it out even more
Aaagh?!
Yes... when you pull the tape really hard
it becomes thinner...
While I'm at it
the length of the tape taken
at normal mode is
about 30 centimeters per 10 seconds.
That is. 180 centimeters per minute,
so if you stretch it out, it«ll easily go over
2 meters...
It's long enough for the killer to. wind
around both hands
then choke the victim to death...
It's amazing how you figured it out...
That this tape was a minute short...
He looked at the recording time that is
posted on the box of the video!
WwW. Where were you; Conan?
See. it says 94 minutes
but the counter. of the video tape
that wesjust saw was
an hour and 33 minutes...
Right. Pops!
But. where's the video tape /
that was used to kill the victim?
She probably burned it
with a lighter or something
and shoved the ashes down
the drain of the bath tub...
Video tapes are after all made from
very easily burnable substance so
Well, there's no doubt
that the murder weapon is the tape!
The part of the tape that was connected
will probably be found
and the killer tried to deceive the police
by soaking the body in a tube of water.
Huh
Didn't the killer do that to complicate
he estimated time of death...?
Please look then!
Her left hand that is holding
the video tape...
WwW. What is
This black trace...
This is the black magnetic substance
substance that is on the surface of
the video tape in order to record images!
Substance that is on the surface of
% substance that-is on the surface of
the video tape in order to record images!
The killer tried to wash the. black
traces off Mr. Kamoshita's neck.
but his Yukata got wet
$0 she dunked his body into the water!
But the killer couldn't wash off
what she had to most...
The thing that would serve as
conclusive evidence, her red mole...
red... you're not talking abc
the mole in the picture.
Ell... that was no mole.
But something that flew on her
when she hit
and knocked Mr. Kamoshita out with
the shower nozzle
His blood!!
I. 1 OCC...
It looked like a black mole
because the scene was 'static!!
So. the killer took off allei™r clothes
to avoid getting blood on her yukata...
I CL...
-_ Be
That's why the killer said.
That she wanted to take a shower
when she came to this room...
She probably said something like
the shower broke
and lured Mr. Kamoshita into
the shower room.
When he came in, she hit him with the
shower nozzle and knocked him out...
Not even bothering to put on her clothes,
she cut the video tape...»
Shélthen used it
to strangle.Mr. Kamoshita!
She was not aware at that time that
her picture was being taken...
The killer wiped off the blood
that splattered on her,
Ieft the room
put away the scissors and screw driver
where they originally were.
She headed for the outdoor bath
to completely wipe off the magnetic
substance on her hand
and the blood that splattered on herself...
Am I wrong...?
the one who tried to hide the red mole
Ms Toshiko Bessho?
What the...?!
H... Hide...
Hide...
Don't be ridiculous!
She's the first one that showed you
her body of her own initiative!
Yes;
That is what bothered me!
Being as introvertedeas she is
what she did was way out of line of
her actual character...
That's when I realized.
That it's a*blind spot
under the collar bone...
That the killer didn't know that there
was blood by her chest until she saw...
that picture...
I said...
ere was no > ood on er C es.
Of course it
came off when she took a bath but...
the traces of if may be found
If a body check is carried out.
That's why Ms. Bessho,
afraid of this,
grabbed that place with her hand
so that it would be out of view,
and made the police confirm that
she had no mole
all to avoidrasbody check...
She didn't want the police to find
the bloodtthat had splattered on
the underwear of her kimono...!
O... Oh mo...
So. you did it?
You blackmailed Kazuki's agency
despite being his mother...
What?p
Well?!
It was a joke...
A joke?
Ilyprobably did it out of envy...
I wanted a child really badly...
So. you're...?
I'm not his mother...
The thing about his father
being a killer is also a lie...
I thought that if I said so,
his agency wouldn't give the postcards
that his mother had been
sending to him anymore...
But, a while later, money was
really deposited. into my account...
and was at loss what to do.
That's when that guy
sniffed things out and came around...
I==called him to this room and told him
everything honest...
hat everything' said was a lie...
But, that man had the nerve to laugh
and...
Ha. ha. ha.
I know how yeu feel about wanting to
protect your child, dear mother,
but!I'm doing business here. see...
Well:if-it's really all baloney...
this time it's my turn to blackmail you...
I'llsuck you up forever...
That's why I got scared and...
I was scared. so I.
How did you find out...
bout Kazuki and his mother...
I'll tell you about it at the station...
But. officer. I don't regret'what I did...
Because I think I made her understand
a bit of how it feels for a woman
to really badly want a child...
What?!
So. Ms. Bessho was the killer?
Pops said he was going to
Shizuok a Prefectural [Police
Shizuok a Prefectural Police
for questioning together
with the other officers...
He also said that he's leaving
his wallet behind
so go take the kids and go on home!
Goodness
Huh? Where's Kazuki?
he got dressed and headed
off to the front door...
saying that he was leaving.
Huh
Wasn't he going to look for his mother? »
He was...
But he's been acting strange ever
since last night before he went to bed...
He wouldn't answer no matter
what I ask him.
I wonder if I:'should've cagried him after
all instead of piggy-backed him...?
Come to think of it. Conan
you were saying that
Kazuki's mother wasn't the killer?!
Huh?
Does that mean you know
who Kazuki's mother is?
Here you go!
My. thank you so much. I'll treasure it!
Me too...
Same here!
Can I have one for my grandson .
Huh >1
Not carrying him in front
but with piggy-backs'
\Yep!
Because when Kazuki fell
asleep while looking at the mole
he heard his mother chopping
food with the knife, right?
She couldn't have done so,
if she carried him in front of her!
Oh. I see.
Kazuki was probably hugged
when he was raised at church,
so he probably mistakenlygthought that
the mole was on his mother's chest...
you're saying that his mother is the one
with the mole on the back of her neck...
Ms. Saegusan?
But, she seemed so stuck.up and cold?
She was acting that way deliberately .so
he wouldn't recognize her as his mother!
She figured it would cause
Kazuki problems if he found out...
I'm sure that
Ms. Saegusa talked to
the killer Ms. Bessho about him...
About having no other choice but
to leave him at church,
and about how much she loved him...
Ms~Bessho probably figured
outsfrom the-story and
thespostcards that she was
'sending out every month.
That Ms. Saegusai was hissmother...
probably because
Ms. Bessho blackmailed Kazuki's
agency just around that time,
so they stopped giving
the postcards to Kazuki
Pops was saying!
how does he know that she left him
at church because. she had no choice?
Because if the son that she used to
write to every month appears before her,
the first thing you'd expect
her to do is to hug him?
After all he's famous and rich...
But, she holds back her
feelings and acts indifferent
That goes to show how much
she must really care for hims right?
I guess-so...
Ran?
I'm going to tell Kazuki about this!
Eel sorry:for him having to hold a
grudge against his mother all his life!
On the contrary...
I think he's dyingfto see her...
The postcards from his mother
being all wrinkled uprand
stained only serves aiproof:
that he read them,
in tears over and over
And besides...
NAN] xs
I'm sunge Knzuki 1lready knows
who his mother us
Go on.
Why don't you get his autograph tooy?
Oh no... don't think so...
How come you're so hesitant!
You watched his videos and movies
over and over too!
Come on, come on...
I'm not giving you"my autograph!
But I'll give, you...
This... Instead...
If you don't send this out...
I'm coming again!!
Oh 1!
Hey. Kazuki...
- 7 kk
I'm sorry
I'm so sorry. Kazuki, honey...
I'm sorry...
Original Comic Books By
OSHO AOYAM
Pr 'OO of UC O r 'S
MICHIHIKO SUWA/
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music
KATSUO ONO
Character. Designs By.
MA SA 'ITO MU SU Do /
Story Editor
KAN]! KASHTWABARA
AZUNARI KOUCH
CHI MIYAS
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors
MASATPPMO SUDO
Arm/SH: AONO
Ala?) KAwAMukA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
LUILUI
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Directoff
KENJI KODANANA
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
In association with 4
YOMIURI TELECASTING
&O» &»
DETECTIVE CON
v GOSHO AOYAMA I SHOCAKUKAN YTV: IMS
All Rights Reserved
Three days later...
he received payment for
the job he was asked to do...
WwW WwW What
What the hell is this?! "
It looks like a piggy bank no matter
what angle you look at it from...
It.It can't be?!
You mean this,is-what,he's paying us! ?
+ Maybe kid actors don't make much?
135 yen. 185 yen.186 yen:196 yen...
grumbles...
I mean this doesn't even
cover the travel expenses!!
Whaaa! he's walking!
Oooh, he's walking!
It can't be?
How the hell is he...!
nN Ty
Thief Kids Wondrous Sky Walk"