Today's case is hard to take in
It may not be right,
but a person's warmth is hard to erase
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance with
the I.Q. of an adult
ENO case-is lefttunsolved with.
Detective. Conan.
Conan,
what do you want to eat tonight?
We had fish last night. so...
tonight let's have...
Right!! Let's have meat!
Huh'!
Meat! Meat!
I thought*we had meat
just the other day
Huh? Conan!!
I'll take it...
Ran=are.you sure we re eating
expensive steak like this tonight?
Of course not...
Ran...
I thought so...
Come on...
You're Ran. aren't you...?
Sachiko...
Ran... who is she?
Remember?
Back when I dropped my student pass?
She the one who found it
and delivered it to me.
Oh. she's"the-one...
There... How's this...
h... Yes. I'll take it.
You're the one
who bought that high grade
expensive steak meat a while ago...
Ufuh, fuh, fun.
Oh, Conan, stop that, will you...
But that wine sure looks
super expensive...
You see. «today is a specialiday...
My steady's coming over...
Oh!!!
Sachiko is a super career woman...
I didn't think she was interested
at all in men,
but I'm surprised she has a boyfriend.
Somebody that she can cook for...
Ran... You have people
you can cook for too. Ran
But. Shinichi hasn't been home at all...
No. I meant Pops and me.
oh? .
Right!
However, the following day...
She was killed?
She was living alone.
Sachiko?!
Illusionary Spring Lover
This is not 2 case where we need you 10
have come all the way out for Mr Mourn
My daughter owes her a lot...
I'd like to at least be informed of
the circumstances...
The body was found by...
401$
a colleague of hers
that had doubts about her nottfcomingato
work without reporting her absence,
came to visit her...
The cause of death is
fractured skull from a sharp blow on
the back of her head
The weapon is.a bronze figurine
at was found in the roon
The estimated time of her death is
Iast night from 19:00 to 20:00...
In the middle of dinner. eh...
Um. was Sachiko a smoker?
If not. this side is Sachikorgrseat
and the other side as
the seat of her guest who was a smoker
- Oar
It's no doubt that someone such as
«her boyfriend-came to visit her.
am» Ue
At about 19:30
am gar
Ms: Nishimura... the woman living next
door heard Sachiko talking to her guest.
Ms. Nishimura, the woman living next
Promise to take me with you next time,
okay?
It's not fair that you go to see such a
wonderful fenery all by yourself!
Agh?!
Maybe I over cooked it. the steak!
Aqgh 2!
Maybe I over cooked it, the steak!
It seems that her boyfriend's hobby
was mountain climbing.
We found this picture ihere
Her boyfriend's probably responsible for
this crime.
Why?!
If someone came in and attacked
Sachiko all of a sudden...
Where did her boyfriend disappear to
without even reporting
the incident to the police...?
Well...
rue.
Like I was saying, it's not an incident
that calls for your help...
Lo. < Fe.
Like I was saying, it's not an incident
that calls for your help...
The police thinks that
her boyfriend is the killer too?!
There is no other possibility'taking into
consideration-the circumstances...
Takagi here. None? Not even one?
All right.
It s from the forensic officer.
They found no fingerprints
what so.ever other than
that of Ms Sachiko Nishimura from the
bronze figurine
that is thought to be the murder weapon,
the picture of the mountain,
or the wine glass
that they both were thought to
have toasted with.
No fingerprints left?!
No traces of them
being wiped off either...
If so... this as a carefully
planned homicide
He came to visit her after he made sure
that no fingerprints
would bereft behind...
Promise that you'll
take me with you next time.
Aghvd=... Maybe I over cooked Ww?
And. a while after they began eating.
Me made Sachiko get up from her seat...
Why /!
Why?!
Why do you say it's her boyfriend
that did that?!
He was after her money...
There is nothing valuable
such as money and jewelry
anywhere in sight
That's hard to believe, isn't it. Conan?
UN AM
Because Sachiko looked so happy
yesterday. didn't she...?
Todayis~a special day...
My steady's coming over today...
That boyfriend couldn't have killed her!
Right, Conan?!
Y. Yep...
If so then, Ran...
where did that man disappear to?...
It's strange that he left no fingerprints
behind either.
Huh?... Something doesn't feel right...
I wonder what it is'?
62g)
I confirmed with a colleague of hers...
was told that she started going with
her boyfriend
about six months ago.
However,
It seemed that heywas really busy
or something that
he only came to visit her
on the 25th of each month...
So: it seemed that Ms. Nishimura
always seemed excited
from, morning on the 25th.
Yesterday was also the 25th...
I wonder if there's any meaning to
the fact that he only comes to visit her
on the 25th of each month?
It"seems that even that colleague though.
Was never told what
her boyfriend's name was.
Which means we have no clue
what so ever?
'Went to visit her best friend since her
school days who lives nearby too. but...
Ohno, Sachiko-couldn't have been
I just swung at air...
She didn't even know
she had a boyfriend.
She hid the fact from her best friend?
Why. .7?
Tyy/
At any rate, that does it, Ran.
It's her boyfriend.
[We'll try to crack who the Killer is
from among her acquaintances
as soon as possible.
Yeah... do so. please.
I'll try and trace what
the victim. did yesterday.
Maybe I'll get Vlead to her boyfriend.
Ye 'sin!
Now that they know who the killer is,
I guess there's no role for
a detective to play.
Let's go home.
Officer Takagi!
Please let me go with you.
Officer Takag!
I just can't believe that
her boyfriend is the killer!
Ran...
What?! You saw Ms. Nishimura's
boyfriend come running out?!
Yes- I think it was around 20:00
Iast night
But. how did you know that the man was
Ms. Nishimura's boyfriend? \
I think it was on the 25th of last month... Lg
There was a big fire.
My apartment is right opposite
Ms. Nishimura's condo.
WwW. When I happened to
Iook out casually...
You mean the man
that you saw a month ago during the fire
was the same man
who came running out last night?
His eyes were blood-shot and
he ran like he was lurching forward...
Excuse me,
may I have your name. please?
Me? I'm Suenaga.
Mr Suenaga. will you'help us.make
a composite picture of that mane
Okay. \.
But. let me go tell the boss.
There's even eye-witness...
I guess this is it.
There's even eye-witness .
Ran...
With a composite picture in hand,
If they go asking around the vicinity
where the victim lived.
It's just a matter of time
before they find the killer
But, there's something that bothers me...
I wonder what it is...
Oh! About time!
Oooh. Munch, munch...
What's the matter? Eat. you guys.
Okay. Conan?
Huh? .Oh...Yep!
Huh?...Oh\. Yep!
What?
- - >>
O0cC .
It's really good.
I'm glad.
I'm glad
What's this. Did you make me check to
see if it was okay or what?
Ufuh. no, it's not that but...
I wasn't sure if it was seasoned enough
Uh, Ran,
Sachiko 'must've been really hungry.
Why ?
Because the steak and salad
on her side of the table were eaten.
But her boyfriend's side was untouched.
So what, you brat!"Munch. munch...
Not possible That's strange,
really strange!
Not possible... Thalls strange,
What's so strange?
Maybe
But .
Maybe...
But...
The woman living next door heard
Ms. Nishimura talking to her boyfriend.
She only heard Sachiko's voice...!
Yeah,
if that's how it was, it's understandable
that there were no other fingerprints
If so. why did she put on such an act...?
Hey. what's all this about?!
I'm going with her,
because I'm kind of worried!
Hey!! You too?!
I'm going to eat all this up. you know!
Like I told the officer.
I really never heard
that: she had a boyfriend
She did have one before though...
She did...before?
About 5 years ago...
A man called Mr. Henma...
whose hobby was mountain climbing.
When was this?
About 6: months ago.
Was it on the 25th,
6 months ago 7?
Right. it was my husband's pay day...
Just as I thought...
Huh?!
The real killer is not her boyfriend?!
Huh /!
It's impossible for Sachikds boyfriend to
have killed her, that's totally impossible!
Otally impossible...
And, if it wasn't her boyfriend, then, the
real killer is none other than that person!
Mr. Izaak?
Yeah... Who're you. .?
There's something I'd like to ask you...
Mr. Suenaga.
Yeas...
About this composite picture...
I can't remember anything
more In detail than that.
No, it was impossible to make
a composite picture to begin with.
Huh 2
Because there was no boyfriend that
could've comeyto Ms. Nishimura at all...
Because...
Thissis strange.
If she prepared this for a boyfriend
that she was seeing after a month
First her boyfriend would take a bite,
and she would wait for him to say
something-abou her cooking...
It's only naturalsfor hergto start eating
after hearing what he had to say
It's unthinkable for a woman to start
eating and drinking-before her guest
In other words.
Nobody came to visit her last night!
Then
why is everything prepared for two?
Then,
It's for her boyfriend.
I don't Know what you're talking about.
Ms. Nishimura happily told
her colleagues and Ran
that her boyfriend was going to
come visit her...
But that was
ale.
Promise to take me with you next time,
okay?
It's not fair that you go to see such
a wonderful scenery all by yourself!
Maybe I over cooked it, the steak!
She acted the whole thing out-herself
"Where can be. no other
explanation for this.
He wasn't there to. begin with, so
of course there would-be no fingerprints.
You. Mr Suenaga said-that you saw
someonedhat didn't even
come to visit her!
And, you even helped makeup
something like this...
to divert our attention from
the real killer... You!
Why need I do something like that?
You have a friend named Mr. lzaki,
don't you?
You have a friend named Mr: lzaki,
don't your?
The owner of the liquor shop told us
about him and we went to see him.
I hear-that you were complaining ,
Iast month...
that a shopper who patronized your shop.
A woman who lived in the condo
opposite you
refuse when you asked her to
go out with you
You heldia grudge against her because
she brushed you off...isn't that right?
That's your motive for killing her. no?
Where's the evidence that I did it?!
Where's the evidence that.l-did it?!
You borrowed money from Mr Izaak,
didn't you?
But, you returned the total amount
to him this morning.
But. you returned the total amount
Fingerprints were found on all the bills...
Your fingerprints as well as
Five
Ms. Nishimurass!
You killed her, holding a grudge
against her for brushing you off
and stole cash as well as
valuables from her!
Am I wrong?!
'I _l
Exactly... But officer.
That woman was one hell of a liar too!
How dare she lie!
I'm sornry--Y can't go out withyou.
I have .afboyfriend.
He's coming today again too...
I thought that lit couldn't bérhelped then...
But. that night"
Her boyfriend wasn't with her!
She bought wine again yesterday...
Saying that her boyfriend was coming...
I went to check it out yesterday!
PP. Please. no!
P ease leave! Because he's coming!
Where is her ae
This boyfriend of yours?!
I'm calling the police!
Whaaaa!
It's your fault... for/lyingéto met. 4
It's your fault. for'lyingito me...
It's your fault... for lyingito me!...
It's your fault... for lyingito me.
It's your fault. for lyingito me
It's your faults. for lying'toime...
It's your faulte.for lying:to me...
It's your fault .-for lying-to-me...
It's your fault. .for lying to me...
She didn't even have a boyfriend,
but put on a front of having one...
If she wanted to just put on a front,
If she wanted to just put on a front.
Wouldn't it have been enough for her
just to buy steak for two?
She wouldn't have had to
really cook the steak
or pour the wine into the glass. right?
It was a lie, but not really a lie...
Yesterday, her boyfriend
really did visit her
and was-sitting
actually sitting there.
And was sitting
actually-sitting there _
Her boyfriend called Mr. Henmu.
Sachiko had a boyfriend during her
school days called Mr Henmi
But, five years ago...
I'll be fine. I'll be back on the 25th.
The 25th? I'll prepare a nice meal
and wait for you then.
I'd like steak then. A thick one like this!
But. Mr. Henmi never returned...
His body wasn't found either...
But. 6 months ago. 5 years later...
Mr Henmi's knapsack was found
in the mountains...
And inside the knapsack they found#films
that were already developed...
I had second thoughts about showing
this to you after 5 years...
I had'second thoughts about showing
this to-you after 5 years.
I had second thoughts about showing
this to you after 5 years...
But. ll thought that he would've liked
for you to sce it too so
Mr. Henmi:. Came home...
Just as he: promised::.on the 25th...
It was on the 25th. 6 months ago.
Since then. on'the 25th of each month.
Mr. Henmi visited her...
In Sachiko's heart... even last night
She decided to believe in him and wait.
She believed that by doing
so he would return
That her boyfriend would
never betray her...
Original Comic Books By
Prod U CGFS .
MICHIHIKO SUWA¢
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
Character. Designs By.
ARK TN : vf
To &. > AE so ~_ - rs
Story Editor.
KAN]! ASHYWABARA
CHI MIYAS
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
MASAVQMO $1100
UO OOGA /
ATSU HI AOND
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWACGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director
KEN] KODAMA
ENTERTAINMENT
in association with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CONAN
CC COSHO AOYAMA / SHOGAKUKAN YTV - TMS
All Rights Reserved
Which means for these past 6 months on
the 25th. she was talking all by herself?!
I just said she wasn't alone!
Uh, Ran...
Huh'...
I'm sure that'Shinichi will
come back one day too.
Thank you...Conan...
He'll open that door and say. "I'm home!
If he does...
Hey. Shinichi. where and what the hell
were you doing till now!
The first thing I'll do I's spin kick him!
Huh?! She has no intention of
welcoming me kindly
Notjonly will I'spinikick him!
I'll do a heel-drop...
I'm training for that time!
I don't think...
I'll be coming home for a while yet...
rah!
Oh. n.no. ll really went to
a c.class reunion...
Oh. that's...
Uh, well... .you see...
It's nothing much but...
Uh, well you see...
It s nothing much but
Uh, well...you see...
It's nothing much but...
W.What's this?
Love Story at Police Headquarters #5
Part 1
(By)
Love Story at Police-Headquartéers #5
Part-1