The stars of today's episode are these two -
A cute date with many chaperones
A very serious case also comes along
He sees through the one and only truth
A childfin appearance with the 1.Q ofran adult
No case is'left-unsolved with! Detective: Conan.
Spit it out!
Spit it out and relieve yourself...
You didn't go to a class reunion, did you?
You couldn't think of anything else to say. that's why you said so, right?
Oh, n.no, I, I really went to a c.class reunion...
Don't play dumb with us!
Do you think you can get away with something like that?
That's enough. spit out the truth,
Takagi!
Inspector Shirator!
We got back up info.
The thing about him having gone to a class reunion is a lie.
Moreover, we found this in his desk...
Oh, you deceive us and, moreover, have something like this on you.
O-On!
That's...!
It seems that you've taken action which
IS against the moral of the police...
Come on. and spit it out.
Your mother in your home country
IS crying...
Takagi!
TA NA
(51 %R)
Love Story at Police Headquarters #5
Part 1
Ah NA
(5148)
Andi? You mean you told them about today's date...
N.No. I haven't said a word!
I really pulled through this time!
1.1 didn't say a word.
Really?
I even went out of my way to leave a platinum ticket in my desk.
I even went out of my way to leave a platinum ticket in my desk...
So. I'm sure that everyone's been distracted by it by now
So. I'm sure that everyone's been distracted by itlby now
and is going to stake us out at Tohto Dome...
Really. I don't know why they get all heated up like that over a mere date...
You must be extremely popular,
Officer Takagi.
UwWh... I'm not the one who's popular .
Huh. 2!
Hat...?
WwW. What's this sharp glance that I sense?
What...?
W WhatSsthis sharp glance that I sense?
This is group D! Fukui and Kawanaka
We've spotted Sato and Takagi!
Our target is currently having a friendly chat at Cafe Aqua in area 3.
This isagroup E. Morita and Saito
We've succeeded)in*taking a picture of them from behind the counter!
His is group B, Oda and Miyazaki.
We have taken seats behind the two...
Roger...
Remember to keep on your guard.
Understand, our goal is not to watch over their dating with warmth...
If they should behave in a queer manner or make any moves,
be sure to report back to me immediately.
Talk about queer behavior... Ms. Sato's been acting strange since this morning.
What do you mean by strange...
Yes, sir
she's not her usual dignified self, but rather... don't know how to express it...
\ C,Cutel
That's bad... Officer Takagi may resort to immoral action...
Officer Oda and Miyazaki
I want you to carry out strategy 104 in manual C immediately.
And. you know that Yumi...
Hey. did you see yesterday's paper?
They specified the hide-out of a drug dealer and still let them. get away.
The police really are no good likeialways, eh
Hey!
Stop talking nonsense.
They:didn't fleeyg
It was misinformation to begin with!
M.Ms. Sato. please calm down...
W-Where are... you going?
To the ladies' room, the restroom.!
Does it bug you?!
O.Oh...
We did it. WW. We've succeeded.
She's back to her usual self!
Roger.
Oh. h.hey wait...
Officer Takagi is taking s.something out of his bag...
Arring...
ArRING .
Ar rnng...
No doubt about it, I'm sure he's going to give it to Ms Sato!
W.What shall we do? If we're going to coniscael, NnNnowss we Ime oO O SO.
Please calm down, that's within assumption...
I've already got something worked out.
Oh. what a relief
Huh? What...
Uh... Oh. well, no.
Uh... Oh, well, no.
What, what? Is it something you don't want me to see?
No. I mean well, I'll show this to you'a little later...
Agh!
It's Officer Takagi and Officer Sato!
It+s Officer Takagi and Officer Sato!
Ugh! Y.You kids... Huh?
D.Dr. Agasa...
7 TEX <
Ugh! Y.You kids. Huh?
D.Dr. Agasa...
Ugh! Y You kids Huh?
D.Dr. Agasa
WwW. What brings you here?!
WwW. well... Inspector Shiratori sent me the tickets to come here,
saying that it's his token of gratitude towards us Ha, haha.
Oh, Inspector Shiratori did...
B.But... w.what a coincidence... aha. ha
to run into everyone in a place like this.
Aha. ha...
The mascot of Marine Land, Marilyn brought us here.
So that we could take a picture together.
See... Huh?!
Huh? She's gone
Uh? She's gone...
She disappeared...
Huff-puff, huff-puff, huff-puff
Huff-puff, huff-puff. huff-puff
Hey. Shiratori! This is Takano.
I made the two kids join them
Iike you told me to!
Roger. Please continue watching them.
Yeah, Inspector Shiratori. Yep .yep.
Yes, thanks to you, we've all come to Marine Land...
Huh. oh. the case the other day...
U huh... what? You have something you want me tofverify 2
Yes, I'm passing nearby by car, so I'd like to see you there.
N.Now. over here?!
No. no!
Huh? No... That's... well, well...
I tell you what...
I'll send a FAX to your residence now
so after confirming it please call me on my cell phone by 3:00 this afternoon.
Goodbye...
H.Hey...
HiHey
Huh? Yeah... we,.ll have to go home now, or we won't make it in time...
We'll take care of the children,
SO you can leave them with us.
Huh 2!
O. Oh. .lvm sorryal guess so then...
IB.But, Officer Sato.
Don't worry! If worse comes to worse,
1 we can always call Mr. Mouri or Ran
N.No, that's.not what I mean
Pops nor Ran can come today.
Pops 1s participating In a community baseball game
and Ran is out cheering for him...
B.But, they could've lost the first time wound and gone home already...
on Mn SO...
Because Mr. Mouri*was bragging that they're a really strong team
that made it to the semi-finals last year...
Right?
He was polishing his glove till it got glossy .and he was going all out
Then. just as I thought...
Well, all's well, the more the merrier in a place like this.
0.Oh .
O.Oh...
Yawn
w... all's well at least for
We'll just have to wait and see what happens from here
I'm going to go take a rest,
so If any changes come up, be sure you let me know.
Yes, Sir.
I stayed up all night finishing up work that I had on my hands
that I haven't slept.
Oh, and of course be on guard for the case on the deal too.
What?!
30 men to stake out on a drug deal?!
Yes. sir
According to a tip
the deallis to be held at Tropical Marine
Land by Asakichi Yakura...
Oh, that big shot who's on the run after committing three assault cases
IS that tip okay or what?
IFS not mfiinformfitidn». W's it?
Inspector Shiratori is in charge currently at the site...
Don't worry.
God is on our side.
So he says...
1.1 see. If he's that confident. then...
I guess everything will go well...
2222227...
222227...
Mi... wako.
Whaaaa!
\ aaaa!
Ha. ha, ha... ha.
Wow!
Eels over rice!
Yahoo!
Sigh...
Hey. what kind of look is that...?!
Oh. I'm sorry...
Oh. Itm{sorry...
But. 'gee. we were on a date and yet...
Don't be silly, the world's not going to end today. is it?
Besides .
Just consider this a rehearsal.
Huh 2
Of when we have a family of our own.
So ge I
Well, you know!
N.Naha, ha. ha...
T.This is Sogawa!
They've entered a pretty dangerous mood must now!
Inspector Shiratori!inspector, please wake up! It'ssan e.emergency.
Funyah...?
Uh, this is not something...
MW that great... but...
Uh, this is not something all that great... but...
Huh?
Hat as it...
W . What's this...?
Ho Hun?
WwW. What s this.
Oh: what's this paper bag...?
Oh. that's not mine...
C.Come to think of it, although this bag looks like mine,
it seems to be a bit different...
Aaagh!
Hey... Hey
Thus us.
A narcotic!
W. What?!
Hmm!
It's approximately 1 kilogram
It's approximately 1 kilogram...
What!
What us it? What is it?
What's up?
Uh, did you have that bag on you at all times?
Yes... Come to think of it,
I let go of it just once.
Please wait a while 'more before we depart.
Please;give your belongings to: 1? thgu Win 6 ha
because there is danger that you may drop it.
That's right, when I rode the attraction
50,000 miles under the sea .
I'm sure someone made a mistake back then and took my bag.
Let's go check. Maybe that person has come to get-this bag.
This is Shiratori. Is anythingstheamatter?!
It.It seems like something has happened.
Officer Sam's facial expression has changed to one of a police officer...
Face of an officer...?
Yawn
He's sure taking his time,
InspectorsShiratori.
= Kc y t 1? . f - XxX
Oh. boy.
Huh? Nobody came?!
No one came to deliver a bag like that...
That's strange...
It's already been 2 hours since then...
Maybe he already went home?
Right. there's only one bag besides
SO maybe he didn't want it anymore.
Don't be silly... That amount would add up to some several million yen.
If he finds out that he has the wrong bag.
He would be going crazy
Iooking around for it
S.Several million yen?! (
The owner of the bag probably hasn't been told what's in the bag
and is probably just a mule.
If not.
It's unthinkable that he would so easily leave his bagsbehind
and enjoygriding an attraction ride...
Besides, he doesn't even seem to know that the bag had been switched...
In other words, it's still before the deal.
The deal's probably going to take place somewhere here in Marine Land soon,
and the drug will be handed over.
Then, we've got to find that person quickly
B'But.¥ How do we I6ok for him? »?
F. From among so many people...
Hmm... And if the contents inside the bag is heroin.
The dealer may be Asakichi Yakura, who is on the run right now...
Yes. .He's a heroin dealer.
We've alsoygot information that he's in hiding in this area too...
What's this thing called Heroin?
It's you know!
The American festival in October
when everybody wears ghost and monster costumes!
That's Halloween!
Heroin is a narcotic drug made from Morphine.
And once you become addicted
you're attacked by unceasing bouts of agony
and in the end become mentally deranged...
It's an extremely dangerous drug...
Anyway, the problems) how do we specif» this mule].
The only clue we have is this bag.
The other contents inside besides the paper bag with the drug are...
a brand new sports towel and a soiled handkerchief.
Isn't there anything on the bag anywhere
that is characteristic or has some kind of habit of its owner...
Like a scratch... blood stains and such!
No. nothing in particular...
Then, maybe we should just forget about it?
There wasn't anything really important in the bag that was taken away. was there?
On the contrary...
T there sure was!
The precious ring
I was planning to give Ms Sato
I was planning to give Ms. Sate
You've got a clue!
Huh 2!
the shoulder belt of that bag, only the hole on the left side us spread out wide.
T.True...
That means that the owner always carried the bag on his left shoulder.
If the owner carried it on his right shoulder. ;
the hole of the shoulder belt on the right side shouldebe spread out
But. what can you tell from that?
Well, which side would you carry the bag on. Officer Takagi?
Well, I would carry it on the side that
I feel comfortable with. On the right.
Oh, I see...!
Oh. I see...!
If you're right handed it would normally be carried on your right shoulder,
but the owner of that bag always carried it on his left shoulder...
Which means
the possibility of him being left handed
IS very likely.
Yep.
And if a large sports towel is inside
he could be working at a job where he sweats a lot
or somebody who does sports...
R.Right...
RR. Right...
But... how do we search when there's so many people here?
Yd BR we could only have a picture...
Sigh
There were a lot of pictures
pasted by the exit of the attraction
950.000 miles under the sea.
Yes, thespeople who got off the ride were gathered and looking at the pictures.
Is.Isn't that the service picture that's part of the attraction?
The one that is taken automatically at the peak of excitement
and sold to anyone who wants it...?
Come to think of it.
something like the flash of a camera shined when we were riding...
Yeah...
The picture may stillébe there if we go now!
This 1s the number to my cell phone
Understand!
If someone comes looking for-a bag that looks a lot like this one. )
call me right away!
Y.Yes. ma am.
Try and buy time until we get here. okay!
Ll understand...
Sighs
ha) mt.
We're... the police
fu) otts
We're... the police.
P.Police officers?!
What did the people who just came here want?
Yes,
well, that man seem to have his bag mistakenly taken away by someone else.
Hey. the bag. don't tell me that...
he one with the ring inside...
That's why he looked so desperate...
Uh, did those people do something?
What do you mean?
Well I heard them...
Saying things like blood stains... and Heroin
Blood (Marry. )
Blood (Marry )
Blood stains! (Kekkon=marry)
H. HRHeroin?! (This is similar in sound to the word wedding reception; in Japanese)
USO Nh... 7
LEE »*
S.Shiratori! This is an emergency!{
T.They're getting married!
A.A A wedding reception!
That Takagiphe just might get married here today!
Well. calm down and tell me gs what you have to say from the start.
I see,
so the bag with the ring in question was taken away by someone else by mistake?
Then, all we have to do is get a hold of that bag before the two get to it,
to prevent the worse from happening...
Dispatch all the officers at the site
and find the person who has this bag and get him.
I will be there too. of course!
Oh:ithere it is!
This is it, our picture!
Oh, there it is!
Uh. the people who rode with us are...
Five people
4. f we exclude the young man
2nd from the rear...
B But
with such a small picture
it's hard ts tell whether someone is
Ieft-handed or not
much less. what kind of work or sports he does...
Oh"; but the man next to Genta was practicing golf swings while waiting.
He look to be right-handed. though.
But: since there are -only a few golf clubs for left-handers.
Many péople though left-handed may start with theirdright hand
Oh. I guess so."
But the man who was behind me
IS surely right handed.
Because thus as what he was doing
He plays baseball eh
Come to think of it, the man in the very back plays soccer...
Both his feet were suntanned...
Soccer fashion calls for short-socks.
showing a bit of the shin guard.
That's how most people like to dress...
Then, the woman besides the man must be a swimmer.
She had a while streak about
1 centimeter on the side of her eye
that wasnst suntanned.
It's probably because she's always wearing goggles: right?
Hmm... Golf . baseball. .soccer... and swimming...
All of them use sports towels, don't they.
Oh, and I can tell that the man right beside Genta is a really timid person.
See. He's clinging on to Genta.
Come to think of it,
because he grabbed my shirt, I got something like blue ink smear on it
you were taking a survey using a blue ballpoint pen
while we were waiting. right?
Yes...
Would you show us the survey sheets?
-s ad
Here NS.
It's right after Genta's,
SO there's No mistake about it...
And this person is left-handed!
Huh? How do you know?!
See. look closely. . ."...
The characters are rubbed and stained to the right.
This is proof that he's left-handed.
When he writes something sideways,
he has to write the next character before the ink dries,
so it inevitably gets rubbed end hs ho I
After that. I think that the ink that was left on his hand
rubbed off on Genta's shirt, when he clung to Genta...
1.l see...
1.1 see...
Huh? P.Police...?!
Please announce his name that's on the survey sheet
and. have him come here immediately!
Es ada major wi ness or an inves iga ion.
Original Comic Books By.
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKO SUWA¢
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
BackoeroundiMushc.
\1sUD ONO
¢ ) (OD
Character Designs By
Story Editor.
KANJI SS IWABARA
YUFQHJJIIQURE
TOSHIKIANOUE
r If'! I p
MASAFTDMO SUDO
Kl ) KAWAMUR
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI,
Editor
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director
KEN]! KODAMA
JdMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD in association with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORAII N
DETECTIVE CONAN
« COSHO AOYAMA / SHOCAKUKAN YTV IMS
All Rights Reserved
Roger. Let's get hold of it before they do no matter what.
Did you have something very important inside it, after all?
S Its what I was plann to give you, Ms. Sato...
Ring, ring-a ling.
Huh, ring?
Huh? Don't tell me that... it's in the bag.
T.That's...