The exciting date heats up.
The hunt for the criminal is on!
A case with a spectacular finale!
Recognizing that single truth,
a child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
For their very first date, Officer Takagi and Officer Sato decided to visit Tropical Marine Land.
But Inspector Shiratori had other plans, so he interrupted the date by bringing us in.
When Officer Takagi reached into his bag to take out a ring he'd bought as a gift...
There were drugs instead!
I know! It was when we were on that "50,000 Leagues Under the Sea" ride.
Someone must have taken my bag on accident then.
But you do have a clue.
Look at the shoulder straps. Only the left strap's hole is stretched out, right?
A right-handed person would put it over their right shoulder.
So if the owner of this wore it over his left shoulder...
That means... He's probably left-handed, right?
Yep.
Got it!
This man's left-handed!
How do you know?
Look at how the ink is smudged.
Could you please announce for this man to come here?
He's the key to our case.
Metropolitan Police Officer Love Story 5, Part Two!
Takagi Noboru, please come to the entrance of "50,000 Leagues Under the Sea."
Takagi?
I see what he's doing!
He's inviting his relatives here!
Inspector, it looks like they're having their wedding reception here today.
Don't worry. Without a ring, there's no chance of a ceremony.
Anyway, check out anyone you pass with a similar looking bag and make sure you find it!
And show it to me!
Hurry.
Takagi Noboru from Chiba Prefecture.
Please come to the entrance of "50,000 Leagues Under the Sea."
There he is!
That's the guy!
' He was practicing his golf swing!
You're Takagi Noboru-san, correct?
The police?
Yes, I'm Takagi. What is it?
You're left-handed, is that correct?
Y-Yes.
Could you show me what's inside of your bag, please?
Sure, but all I have is...
Huh? No way!
This bag is nothing like Takagi-kun's!
Dad, I'm hungry!
Come on, Dad!
Hey, that kid...
That's the one from the picture.
Geez, what's with you people?
W-We're very sorry! Thank you very much for your time.
A drug dealer wouldn't bring a kid along, right?
But anyway, that's one down, three to go.
Then let's just get the next three surveys for their information.
I don't think so.
The next few surveys were filled out by a group of students.
So that makes me believe the ones we're after didn't do them.
Man...
If we could find those students, we could at least ask if they remember the other three's bags.
I just saw one of those students walk by...
Oh, there! That's them!
Aren't they the three lettermen of the D.C. Academy?
The three what?
What do you mean, "the three what"? They're famous high school athletes. They're number one!
You said there was a stained handkerchief in the bag, right?
Ah, yeah...
Here.
Well, I'll go ask them some questions.
There's no need.
I finally remembered something:
Certain things are considered taboo for sports players, right?
Something considered taboo for sports players?
Will that tell us whose bag it is?
What's "taboo"?
To sum it up...
It's something that isn't allowed.
Ohh.
Anyway, look carefully at those three over there.
They're famous high-school athletes.
The one on the right is Goto Yousuke, a dependable southpaw who took his team to the Koushien semi-finals.
In the middle is Nakajima Keita, a backstroke swimmer who set a record at the inter-high competition.
On the left is Maeda Kazuhiko, a renowned soccer player who's under seventeen.
Don't you notice something?
So, the carrier is left-handed, wears his bag on his left shoulder, and either swims, plays baseball, or plays soccer?
Then it's the soccer player! He's wearing it over his left shoulder.
I think that's just a coincidence.
Why...?
Well, it could be the swimmer, but you'd have to ask the person to find out their dominant hand.
I've got it! It's the baseball player!
Southpaw means left-handed, right?
So that means it's gotta be the baseball player!
Him being left-handed is probably a coincidence, too.
But still...
It's weird for him to have his bag on his right shoulder.
You're right! But why?
Maybe he used to throw with his right arm but switched to his left.
That means he used to be right-handed.
That's not it.
That isn't the reason he's wearing the bag on his right side.
It goes back to what I said earlier.
About what's taboo for sports players.
He has to protect that shoulder, get it?
Now that you mention it, I've heard of that.
Pitchers keep heavy things off of their dominant shoulder to avoid damaging it.
Genta, that guy you saw was a right-handed pitcher, right?
Yep, he was doing it just like this.
If he's a right-handed pitcher still playing baseball,
It's highly likely that that's why he's using his left shoulder.
But can you be sure with just this?
The soccer player and swimmer could be left-handed, too, you know.
I'm actually pretty sure.
Smell this handkerchief we got from the bag.
This is...
Ah, Mouri-san was using this earlier on his glove!
It's glove oil, isn't it?
Then we can be sure this bag belongs to...
The baseball player wearing the hat. No doubt about it.
But still, how're we going to find this guy?
Even more people are here now than before.
I can't see far enough with these things.
I guess these won't work.
This is Sugawa. It looks like they're on the move.
They're still in pursuit of the bag with the ring inside.
Good. Keep an eye on them.
Report back if they find their target.
We have to get it before they do
We could probably find him if he were somewhere outside...
But if he's on one of the rides or waiting in line...
Don't worry. Marine Land doesn't close until 8 p.m.
Since it's 5:30 now, he only has 2 1/2 hours left.
That means he wouldn't get on a ride in a long line.
And since he had the drugs and all, he probably came alone.
No doubt he has time to waste...
So, though I'm not 100% sure... He might be there.
I don't see him anywhere...
I told you I wasn't sure.
Um, I need to...
Um, I need to... go to the restroom!
Me, too.
It's this way, right*?
I think so.
Hey, you alright?
Oh, you're those kids from before, right?
Nice seeing you.
Later.
Hey, Mitsuhiko...
Got him!
Alright, Genta-kun!
Hurry, hurry!
Hurry!
I'm back.
I guess this place is the best after all.
His bag really is similar, huh?
He's gotta be the one.
Oh, direct hit!
What're we waiting for, Sato-san?
Let's hurry and get the bag.
Wait.
Leave him be until he makes the deal with the drug dealer.
B-But my bag has...
Oh? Is there something important inside?
Yes. It was actually for you...
It's a ri...
Eh?
Eh? A "ree"?
It's a ri...
Readable thing...
It's readable? You were carrying a letter around?
Geez. If you've got something to say, just be a man and spit it out.
Y-Yeah, you're right...
Alright, I want you kids to stay with me.
Inspector Shiratori, we've spotted someone with a similar bag.
Great, check him immediately.
W-Well, Sato-san and the others are near him...
Has the ring in the bag already been...?
No, but it looks like they're watching him, too.
Anyway, give me your location.
Let's meet up there.
Retro Game Park.
Park? Really!?
Roger.
Almost time. I should get going.
Let's go over there.
Wha... What're they...?
Where'd he go?
Don't worry. He's right over there.
You're right!
There!
Okay, everybody! Let's light up the sky with our spectacular fireworks finale!
Enjoy the show!
He wouldn't make the drug deal in such a public place, would he?
With drug deals, anything's possible.
T-That's... Yakura Asakuchi, the drug dealer!
Okay, here's whatever I've been carrying around, so give me the money and...
Hold on. We'll finish the deal during the fireworks show.
Right. Looks like the rumors are true. You're one cautious guy.
It's doesn't pay to rush things.
Especially when it's something like this.
Ladies and gentlemen, the moment you've been waiting for!
The big event's coming up. Don't miss it!
Watch the kids.
Sato-san!
We saw someone near him that looks like a fugitive.
What!?
Alright, put it in my lap now.
Police.
Police. Please cooperate.
No way in hell.
Did you guys hear something strange?
Yeah. A "bang"1
Yakura!
Sato-san! ?
What're you doing!?
What're you doing!? Let's move!
Right!
Shiratori, they're chasing Yakura!
He has a gun.
Roger that!
Everyone, back up Sato and Takagi. Keep any bystanders out of way.
Hey! Stop right there!
Even if you tell me too, do you think I will?
I'm pretty sure that just ahead...
S... Sato-san!
Wow! Fantastic job, Takagi-kun.
Inspector Shiratori, what are you doing here?
We've been staking out this place for a drug deal.
So, where's your bag that was taken mistakenly?
Well...
It fell into the water when I tackled the criminal...
A-Anyway, it doesn't matter. Nothing important was inside...
Oh, it wasn't anything important.
Thank goodness for that!
Well, this case is closed.
How about we go drinking tonight?
Yeah? Sounds good.
Well? Aren't you coming?
Yeah, after I take the kids home...
Sato-san, we caught the suspect
s...
S.. .Sato-san?
What's wrong?
Are you crying?
Hey, maybe it's because of that.
Could it be...
Looks like it reminded her...
Of how Officer Matsuda died.
You idiot! Why would you bring her here on a date!?
Despicable.
You call yourself a man?
I-I'm so sorry...
I didn't realize...
Hey...
Hey... promise me, okay?
That no matter what...
You'll never go away and leave me?
Promise me!
Even though Officer Takagi lost his special bag,
He found something way more precious.
Detective Takagi, hurry up!
Hurry? Hurry where?
We've got a lead!
Dirt?
What's that?
Next Conan:
A Mysterious Spring Beetle!
Next Conan's Hint:
Mobile Phone Strap.
A date, a ring, and things like that...
How humiliating...
Wait a minute. Did you just say "penguin"?