Today's stage is the pet shop
Something happens in Tokyo and Gunma
What is the thing that ties;them: together
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
- with the I.Q. of an adult
No case is. left unsolved with Detective :Conan
The other day
I found a cute one here!
The other day.
_lLfound-a-cute onc here!
A pet shop?
A cute one?
I wanted to show it to you guys...
It looks to be their day off.
True...
Oh...so here it is...
Huh?
Told them I'd be coming at 22:00. and yet
Hey: it seems like they're opening the shutter.
Huh? Oh. yeah
Is anybody in?
Croak, croak...
croak, croak...
Oh, there he is. He's the one! This one!!
Huh?!
Genta...Y.You mean this?
Yeah...
crumple, crumple
Yikes. how ugly!
Iuh...? What's this sound...?
Maybe something got away,
Iike a snake or something...
Huh 2!
S.Snake!
A.Agh?!
It's a beetle!!
I got it...
Why is a beetle in a place like this?
Furthermore. at this time of season...
What?!
What's up. Conan!!
Wow. talk about messy...
Stay away!!
Huh 2!
Mysterious Spring Beetle
#2 The victim Is the owner of the pet shop, k
Mr .Minoru Shirai age 41...
There are traces of strangulation...
The murder weapon hasn't been:found yet.
Yes, sir... okay...
There were traces of him having been strangled with a thin thread-like thing...
He seems to have been killed elsewhere then brought here.
How can you tell?
If he died here, his legs should be stretched
straight due to postmortem stiffening...
Oh... I see.
Mr. Ninomiya
You were scheduled
Oo come here at 22:00?
Yes,
I was told to call the shop at 18:00 to check if it came in or not. so I called.
Did you notice anything strange back then?
Nothing in particular, except for that frog croaking...
Croaking...
Hey. what were you planning on buying?
Huh. oh, a beetle.
A b. beetle? You mean they sell it in this season?
Yes, I was told something about a place in Gunma
where you can get beetles all year round.
Unma...
Please tell me, where were you yesterday?
I was sleeping till noon and
from 15:00 to 20:00 I was working at a family restaurant.
Huh?
Beetle...?!
What's that...?
Huh?!
T.This Is it!!
This is ith!
Yes! Mr. Shirai probably went here...
Gunma...
Officer Sato!
VV LU VOULID LVI 0 TEE AIC VVGAITTE SS DUOUGARLCLL.
There was nothing more inside?
No. ma'am...
Where's the lid?
The thing is. we can't find it...
But... Why would something
Iike this be here...)
Oops! Hey staysstill!
Hey!! What's that? It's a beetle...
I found Wt walking there a while ago.
Aha. ha. big. isn't it?!
How dare you all just come in like that...
Go on home!
Whaaa!
Gee: If she chases us out we won't befable to investigate. you know...
Sorry. sorry, but...
Fi Fwy
I guess. we can go to
the insect pavilion in Gunma for now...
Let's go!!
But. how do'we-get there?
That's true...
You guys...
Agh?!}
Hi there. kids!
Huh?
Officer...?
Takag...
Huh?!
Heh, heh; heh...
WwW. What's with all of you...
Hurry, Officer Takagi!!
Hurry. to where?
We've found a clue!
Huh?
Hurry, hurry!
Where dos ou-want me to go...
Straight! Straight ahead
S.Straight
Hey. it is dangerous, keepiyour eye on the road!
Ah ..: But straight ahead is
the expressway...
Hey. hey. where:are werheaded for?
Sn cic dgvoetulnme yeu gos
Kugh. kugh. kugh.
Aharha
you'll beissurprised out of your wits.
To the Gunma Insect Museum!
Uh, let's see what's on today...
Gunma Insect museum Oh. a museum
What?! G,Gunma!!
You gotta be kidding. Gee whiz, we're heading back. We're going home!
U OuUh!
Oh. so there was such an incident
Then, the more so. we've got to head back and investigate...
But, we've already come a long way...
Isn't it almost Gunma?
Well, no problem is there?
Ins your day off. right?
YO én.
Uh, isn't it a bit cold?
Oh, I'm sorry, this car doesn't have a heater.
Huh? I didn't know such a car existed in this day and age.
Junk...
Well, I'm s0000 sorry!
Huh?!
Don't tell me that, you're who
I think you are. but don't tell me
it'syou. Conan?
Officer klutz-of the Gunma
Prefectural Police Department...
an pads
Oh: he.s ..-»
The officer that goofed and let * a murderer getaway some time ago.
U.Uh, you know what...
N.C Mr Mourn is not withe ou today
N.Nope!
Oh, that's tog bad.
If Mr. Mouri were here we could've maybe seen the Sleeping Kogoro deduction show.
Oh well, but I guessthe wouldn't come out all this way
to~check outa beetle theft case...
being the renown Detective
KogoroMouri. Aha. ha...
Beetletheft...?
Beetle theft... .?
Is this the truck that was stolen?
Yes. sir. NO mistake.
The beetle.
Isn't there a beetle there?
The thief probably took it away with another car that he had prepared here.
This is bad. who would do this?
When was it stolen?
About 19:00 last night.
This is Mr. Araki of this museum here,
and he is beetle researcher. Mr. Haruna...
After loading the beetles onto the truck,
they went into the museum for a brief moment, and it was during this time.
Somebody stole their truck from them
I didn't think that yesterday after I went home
the precious beetles would be stolen...
Oh, he is the editor of an
Insect magazine, Mr. Ishida.
I'mysure glad that at least the truck came back.
Mr IHamana, let's deliver the beetles we promised to the childrenlonce again.
Yeah, let's do that.
Uh: why do you have beetles at this, museum even if it's not summer
Mr.,Hamanai succeeded in finding a way
to make them emerge into. adults all year round.
The larva that has been preservedrat. 1Ordegrees C
1015 degrees C is put into another container
and the temperature is raised to 28 degrees C
Adjusting the temperature is crucial.
But. isn't it cold when you transport-them by truck...7?
But, isn't it cold when you ansport them by truck.
That's nothing to worry about!
This truck is equipped with an air conditioner
In order to enable temperature adjustment.
When:we transpont adult beetles
we: keep theitemperatiure-at:28:degrees C.
The beetles are richer than you. Officer Takagt!
Yeah, yeah
Conant you mean the beetle that we saw back at Mr. Shrai's place was also...?
- CT -
Huh? Mr. Shirai?
Huh? Mr Shirai?
' >, *
Mr. Shiraii of the pet shop.
Do you know him? {
Yes, he came to ask us to sell him a beetle. He was extremely persistent...
All that man is ever concerned about is money...
I didn't continue my research on: beetles all thisjtime for money.
Did Mr Shirai do something?
Don't tell me he's the'one who stole it...
No, well, this morning he was found killed at his shop in Tokyo.
Huh?!
Killed?!
But, if he was killed in To « 0, why did you all come out to a place like this?
Oh. well
and where were, all of you last night...?
You mean were under suspicion....?
No. this is just to be on the safe side
I contacted the police and had them come right away
so I couldn't have murdered Mr. Shirai.
I was looking all night for the truck but ended upifinding nothing after all.
All by yourself?!
Yes, sir.
I was doing some interviews until 6:00 this evening. and then returned to Tokyo.
I had appointments for a continuation
for an interview today too, but:I'm not involved,
because I don't even Know this\Mr. Shirai at all.
Did you find something?
Yeah... that's hum.
It's used to raise larva.
Oh, Huh...? That's...
It"looks like the id of something...
«440)
Oh. No: no.Ydonxt touch it!
Cr >»
WHat happened?
I wonder if this was here before?
I don't think so...
Mr. Shirai was transported on this truck...
Officer Takagi?!
Yes!!
Huh?...0.Officer Sa...
What brings you here?!
WW. Well...
Taraaahn!! og
A.All of you...
Iii:
Heh, heh. we beat you to it.
Wow! ¥
Wow!
I want to keep beetle too!
If you want one Ill. give you on >»
What. really?
But, you've got-to raise it so that it lives as long as it can...
Why do you think we're researching beetles?
That's because through getting to know beetles
we*want to; relay to,everyone the importance of life.
AZ ed
Oh, I.I'm sorry!!
Oh. I.I'm sorry!"
Huh? Your cell phone doesn't have a strap. does it?
Huh?
Huh? «What happened to your museum strap?
You had-it hanging around your neck yesterday.
Oh, I gave it to a child of my acquaintance.
You mean there's a strap of the insect museum?
Yean. would you all like one too?
Yes. we'd like one. for sure.
Yes. we'd like one, for sure!
Well, well what a surprise...
To think that a mere insect theft may be connected to a murder case!
Just a minute! What do you mean by a mere murder case?
Oh, I'm sorry. my tongue sort of slipped...
Officer Sato... When was
Mr Shirai murdered...?
Oh, the estimated time of death was between 9:00 to 10:00 in the evening!
Right. Officer Sato?
Y.yes...
I just found out a while ago.
between 9:00 to 10:00 in the evening...
And. this morning at about 5:00
the sound of the shutler«of the pet shop being opened seems to have been heard!
500 in the morning? Strange.
If he was murdered between
9:00 to 10:00 at night.
Why would such a sound be heard at that hour?
It may be the ghost of Shirai
There's one other thing hat's strange too...
Considering his time of death, his body temperature was greatly decreased.
I see, so that's the story.
That's why the killer waited until daybreak
to transport the corpse that he had on him!
Which means that the killer is amongMherthree...
Strap!
- Of -
Look. look.
See, great. isn't it?
I. got one-too!
Hey: hey...
Here! This is yours: Conan...
Huh?!
T.Thank you ..Aha, ha...
Ufuh... Coordinated: aren't we!
Ufuh... Coordinated. aren't we!
Ufuh... Coordinated aren't we!
Aha, ha...
Accordingfto my deduction,
I think that the one who killed
Mr. Shirai is Mr. Hamana.
Mr. Hamana, after the truck was stolen.
You said you we ye driving» around
Iooking for it. didn't you?
B.But.
Back then! You found Mr. Shirai...
You took revenge on him for stealing your beetles and... Ugh, ugh!
Whaaaa!
Wrong! It's not Mr 'Hamana!
Huh?!
Right-alright!
Mr. Hamana is researching beetles to relaysthe importance
of life so he would never do something like that!
Right!
Oh...Oh... Well...
Oh»... Ohpr'Well.
Whew...
Oh, you do know what's going on, don't you.
Just as would be expected of members of the YouthiDetective Squad...
<> gS 5
Huh?
Levy
0... who is the real Killc
What is 'going on with him...?
We'll leave that aside for a while
and-think about the theft first...
The one who stole the truck withrthe
beetles in it was Mr. Shirai, who was. killed.
But according to what Mr. Ninomiya,
the one who was the first to find Mr Shirai says,
Mr. Shirai was at his shop at 18:00.
The truck was stolen at 19:00.
Wouldn't it have been impossible for Mr. Shirai to steal it NY
No, Mr. Shirai used Mr. Ninomiya to make up his alibi!
He told Mr. Ninomiya to call'him at 18:00,
then had the call transferred to his-cell phone.
He then made Mr Ninomiya hear the croaking of the frog
that he had in the bottle...
saying that it's the croaking of the frog that he is
selling at his shop or something to that effect...
Then. I'll see you tomorrow at 10:00.
That's why Mr. Ninomiya thought that
Mr. Shirai was at the shop yesterday...
Besides, he did see the frog in the shop this morning too.
However. the one who stole the?
Beetles was not Mr Shirai alone.
On the way transporting, the:beetles,
Mr. Shirai and the other thief...
for some reason got into an argument...
At that time.
The killer whose cell phone strap was cut
strangled Mr. Shirai with that strap
and killed him
I'm sure that the fingerprints of
Mr. Shirai are on the killer's cell phone...
If:he didn't tear the strap off himself. that ls...
The killer after killing Mr. Shirai figured that
he would make. it look as if the shop had been robbed.
And took the body to the shop at 5:00 in the morning
because he heard Mr. Shirai tell
Mr. Ninomiya that he would be at the shop!
The killer decided to use Mr. Shirai's alibi trick to'his own advantage...
But, why did he move the body at.daybreak?
Where was the body for
7 to 8 hours-before that .?
The truck that. we just saw!
There was a lot of hum spilled all over the bed ofithe truck. and a lot of that hum was
attached to Mr. Shirai's hair. Besides, the lid of the bottle that was
in the victim's pocket was found on the-'bed of the truck. .:
The bed of the truck is made so that the temperature cantbe adjusted.
After unloading the beetles, he killer turned on-the coole
and set the temperature to winter temperature!
Under normal conditions, the temperature of dead bodies
decreases at a rate:of about one degree C an hour...
But, if the body is left °
In winter temperature
Go Th oreo wil go down faster than usual...
By doing so, the killer was able to make it look as if the estimated time
of death was as early as 6-00 in the evening...
That's why something about the temperature of the corpse was unnatural!
Yes, then he messed the room up to make it look as if a robbery took place.
If it looks as if Mr. Shirai was killed at his shop in Tokyo...
and the killer gets back to
Gunmaby:6-00 in the:evening...
He figured he would've created an alibi for himself!
But, the estimated time of death between 9:00 to 10:00
was figured out on a-basis other than the body temperature...
How dare you make light of the police.
And the killer who had I promised to come herc today .
Drove the truck and abandoned it in the
mountains where it was found a while ago...
Huh? Which means.
Mr. Ishida; you knew
Mr. Shirai. didn't you?
Uh... . NNO...
When Mr. Ninomiya came to Mr Shirai's shop.
He seems to have used the map that:was in the magazine
that you work as editor for to find his way...
Oh, another person...someone else was in charge of it...
The mail that you got just a while ago...
Wasn't it from one of your clients,
Mr. Ishida? Sold out of males.
I heard that thisvis what you wrote in your reply male.
I was able to read the kanji characters
It was written "Sold out
You conspired with Mr. Shirai and
stole the beetles!
Furthermore! youfkilled him!
The cell phone:strap.
The same one as this was also on your cell phone yesterday. wasn tit
I'm pretty sure that it will match with the traces left on Mr. Shuratéé neck...
This strap!!
Mr. Shirai seems to have pulled extremely hard.
Becauseithe:same traces of the strapithat was found on
the late Mr:<Shirai's neck is also in view on the'back of your neck too!
Huh?!
M.Mr Ishida...
Uuugh H. He...
Well, I guess you get
10/0 Of the total this time...
Because you virtually did nothing.
What?!
All you ever do is follow me from behind...
You're lucky that I even give you a share each time.
You gotta be grateful. man.
W. What?!
All he ever did...was look down on me...
A AW,
Ugh...
Original Comic Books By
Producers
MICHIHTKO SUWA¢
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
BackorouTdiMushic... 4
YSUO ONO
Character Designs By.
MASATCDMCD sit/ma»
Story Editor
JUNIGHI 11OKA
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCH7?
Ay Ve er
1§VILY
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Lexan ES Abeer ow
SYEENENl 1 vr UL
MAS vw» . SUDO
KI KAWAMUR
Po, edd .
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
KATSUYGSHI KGB/WASH?
Editor
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KELNILKODA MA
in association with:
YOMI RI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CONA
¢ COSHO AOYAMA / SHOCAKUKAN YIV IMS
All Rights Reserved
Comfortable! Really comfortable!
This is the way cars should be...
Uh, Officer Sato...if you're planning to date Officer Takag:.
I'd advise you not to go driving.
Huh?!
Agh!!
WwW. Why do you say that?
Shoots. nobody's riding with me...
A. Achoo.
{ Huh...
W.Why are you in here?
Uh. where on earth am I headed?
I'm going back to Tokyo!
What?!
H.Hey. that's bad. Please let me off.
N.No! Freeway! We're on the freeway!
Huh? I wonder what's going on with Officer Takagi?
How dangerous! I wonder what
Officer Takagi's doing anyway...
Maybe he just wants attention!!
Drive safely. man.
2 years ago is before I enrolled here...
My grudge--has not yet
vanished .
The soil is muddy from the rain...
The thing that's supposed to be here
:5 not here...
(axfifi)
Teitan-High School 'Ghost-Story:.Part 1