Today's stage is Teitan High.
And like any other school,
Strange things happen within it!
The only one who sees the truth is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
A dream, just a dream...
What?
Your school is haunted?
Yeah! Recently our school has been bothered by ghosts...
It's pretty creepy...
Plus, those hauntings are always in the morning.
Rumor has it that two years ago,
A student died one morning in an accident,
And our school is cursed by his spirit.
Two years ago. That was before I entered high school.
So please, Dad!
Can you please come investigate after school tomorrow?
Just to see if it's real?
Leave it, leave it.
It's either some pranks or some natural occurrences.
That's why the hauntings are only in the morning,
Because the students don't have class then.
I guess, but...
As the famous detective Mouri Kogoro's daughter,
How can I ignore these events and not reveal the truth?
Wait, Ran-neechan.
Aren't you hall monitor next week?
Um... yeah.
I see.
You're afraid to monitor alone...
So?
I'm afraid of ghosts...
Just hit them with your karate!
Karate doesn't affect ghosts!
Ran-neechan,
I'll go with you!
I might even find some clues!
Teitan High School's Ghost Story
(Part One)
Conan-kun!
Over here!
Coming, Ran-neechan!
Wait, Ran.
This four-eyed brat's the one who's gonna help us investigate?
Well... my dad wouldn't come.
He says that such a small case doesn't need him...
As if this brat can help us...
I, the deduction queen, barely accepts him as my assistant.
What an honor...
These are our shoe lockers.
They're slightly larger than your school's, right, Conan-kun?
Y-Yeah,
I know...
I did go to school here for a year.
Conan-kun, I'm putting your shoes in my locker.
Ah, thank you, Ran-neechan.
Hey, Ran, who is this kid?
Is this the Conan-kun you always talk about?
Yeah! Isn't he cute?
The talkative Tashiro and Hidaka...
He's just like a mini Kudo-kun,
And even has the same expressions as him!
Boy, don't become a mystery nerd when you grow up, okay?
So what if I do?
But why did you bring him?
This brat with the glasses is helping us investigate,
He sometimes comes in handy!
Investigate the ghosts?
Really?
Soccer players Aizawa and Nakamichi!
I'm coming!
I've come to haunt you!
Stop scaring us like that!
Hey, did you guys pass that one test?
Barely!
It was a close one!
Yeah, yeah.
You guys need to be more careful...
Bye! Don't overwork yourselves!
If you solve the hauntings, let us know!
Leave it to us!
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
Oh, um... nothing!
That's right.
Originally I was supposed to go to school here,
Learn here,
Talk with my friends here,
And live a normal high school life.
Gin and Vodka...
If only I hadn't been poisoned by them,
And my body didn't turn small...
To change back...
To change back into Kudo Shin'ichi...
I almost had the chance!
That woman, disguised as Dr. Araide,
That woman named Vermouth.
She was most likely sent to kill Haibara,
The traitor of the organization.
Although she said she had given up on Haibara,
Can she be trusted?
That woman is a devil of many faces.
Her disguises are as good as Kaito Kid's.
Maybe she's disguised nearby right now,
Planning some kind of scheme.
W-What!?
Oh, Dr. Araide!
But I'd heard that after the trial,
You'd be sent to Aou Hospital to work there!
Yes, that was the original plan,
But it's changed.
I'm still worried about my patients,
And leaving you guys would also be hard.
So you'll be our school doctor again?
Yeah.
I came today to tell the school that.
Ow!
It's really him!
W-Wait!
Conan-kun, what are you doing!?
Are you okay, doctor?
Y-Yes, I'm fine.
I was told by FBI agent Jodie,
That a criminal impersonated me,
And planned to commit a crime.
So I temporarily went to America to hide.
But Hikari-san and my grandmother weren't comfortable there,
Plus the criminal escaped after being found out,
So we came back here.
But why are you telling me these things?
Jodie wanted me to tell you, and you alone.
Hey!
You can help us investigate the hauntings!
Good idea!
Hauntings?
We'll start here...
The Gym Storage Room of Sorrow!
One rainy morning,
A gym student came here to do morning exercises.
She heard voices...
Coming from this room which was supposed to be empty!
Somebody was crying!
And then...
Frightened, she ran away from the room,
But when she returned with her friends,
The weeping had stopped.
All that was left was this desk,
the desk of the student who died two years ago,
Hosaka Hideaki's desk!
How boring...
Who would be afraid of that?
Come on, Ran...
That's not a mystery.
Hosaka-kun tripped on the stairs,
Tsukamoto Kazumi
Karate Team
and just happened to take a bad fall.
Don't spread weird rumors.
Kazumi-senpai!
Mouri-kun?
What are you doing here?
Isn't there karate practice today?
It's the junior that used to be the karate team captain...
We came to investigate the hauntings.
You mean that weeping sound?
Everybody is saying that it was just the wind.
Look.
The wind blew through that broken window,
And people mistook it for weeping sounds.
But how did you know?
That this was that boy's desk.
I told everybody the details when the rumors got out of hand.
We used to be classmates.
I see...
Why is his table in here anyway?
It's raining...
Oh no, I didn't bring an umbrella!
Me neither...
Then let's take cover until the rain stops.
In the Library of Anger!
I was just about to head there anyway.
Want to go?
Of course.
What's this?
A signature?
Wow, the rain's pretty heavy!
Will it stop?
Don't worry.
The forecast said that it wouldn't rain for long.
Joining a student investigation like this,
You really are a good-hearted guy, Dr. Araide.
Huh?
Seko-kun!
Where were you? I've been looking for you!
Well, my stomach wasn't feeling well,
Kunishige Seko
Ping Pong Team
So I skipped class and took a nap in the infirmary.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
By the way, why did you want to see me?
Oh, it's nothing big. I'll tell you later.
Then I'll just rest some more and then go home,
Before that kind-hearted doctor takes me to the hospital.
Was he classmates with Hosaka too?
No, he was in a different class.
But he and Hosaka were childhood friends.
But I'm surprised,
I didn't think a jock like you spent much time in the library!
How rude!
I still read!
College exams are next year...
Plus, the library is part of our ghost tour!
Library
So books were left out here in the morning?
Right,
And what's more, they were all books that Hosaka-kun had borrowed in the past.
And it happened 4 days in a row. FOUR DAYS!
What could it be but Hosaka's anger at no longer being able to read his favorite books in death!?
Hey,
If the books were left out,
Why didn't the librarian notice them?
That's because the books were all found behind shelves or under tables.
Someone's probably just fooling around,
Using the ghost rumors as a scapegoat.
As for this someone,
I'm going to catch him and teach him a lesson!
And you're going to help me, Mouri.
Y-Yes...
Then...
The last place, the Cursed Stairwell.
One morning a student noticed that the floor here was soaked...
These are the stairs that he died on,
So the liquid was the cursed tears of Hosaka!
Was it because it rained and the windows weren't closed well?
We aren't like you. Of course we closed the windows!
And that's not all...
There is a different number of steps each time you count!
Why don't you two count it now?
Alright, we'll show you!
One...
Two...
Three...
Four...
Five...
Six...
Seven...
Eight...
Nine...
Ten...
Ran, how many?
I counted twelve.
I counted thirteen!
What!? Why?
The correct number was twelve.
When Sonoko-neechan got to the last step,
She counted it twice, once for each foot.
She was too frightened, so she messed up!
Okay, then I'll count it again!
Do you want to solve the mystery or not?
Monobe Masao
Art Club
Hey, you guys!
Can't you be more quiet?
I can't concentrate on painting!
Ah, sorry.
Sorry!
Huh? That student...
Huh? The rain stopped.
Then let's head home now.
Okay.
After hearing Conan-kun's explanations,
I have more courage to stay alone now.
Plus, its getting dark out...
W-What is that?
Huh?
That table...
C-Could it be...
His?
Conan-kun!
There's something on it!
"My hatred has not dissolved yet..."
Who did this?
The paper isn't wet,
So these things were moved here after the rain.
But that's strange.
Eh?
The ground is wet,
So something should be present, but isn't...
The footprints of the person who moved these things here!
S-So they are...
The table and chair in the courtyard
Are the ones we just saw in the storage room!
Yes, they ore the table and chair of Hosaka Hideaki,
Who died two years ago in this school.
But who moved them to the courtyard?
Well, there was a note on the table,
And it wasn't wet,
So someone moved it there otter the rain.
However...
The courtyard's dirt was all wet,
But when we arrived at the table,
There were only footprints of Conan-kun and me.
Ghost!
Hosaka's ghost must have moved it there!
It's possible, since ghosts don't leave footprints...
L-Look!
The table and chair disappeared!
What!? How can they?
Araide-sensei and I moved them back to the storage room.
It other students see it, there might be a riot,
Because of the strange words on the paper.
S-Strange words?
They were roughly written words...
My hatred has not dissolved yet...'1
S-So the paper wasn't wet
Because the ghost was covering it, writing words of hate on it!
Come on, stop it already...
I-Is something wrong?
H-He is still angry...
The ghost hauntings are Hosaka's curse!
You knew this student called Hosaka?
Yes.
He and I were both art students.
Two years ago, he fell down the stairs...
S-So you...
Y-You were present then?
I thought so.
This student was there that day.
Can you guys leave?
So I con prepare for the competition,
My teacher put me in this art room to paint alone.
Quickly!
I can't waste any more time!
Uh... yes.
Hey...
Let's go tell Kazumi-senpai about the table in the courtyard.
There's something here.
What is it?
Wax?
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
Hey, when the bottom of the stairs were wet,
Did the floor boards get wet?
Yes, the whole floor was wet.
All because of the tears of Hosaka, who died here!
Who found it?
It was an art student who came early...
Wait, is that true?
Hosaka's table and chair were moved to the courtyard?
Yes, and on the table was a note saying,
"My hatred has not dissolved yet..."
Oh, come on, when will the pranks stop?
When we catch the culprit,
We two are going to grab his neck, pull him in, and teach him a lesson!
But he'll die with just one hit of yours!
Hey, the books that Hosaka read before,
Do you know which ones they are?
All these books are so complex...
Plus, look at these borrow logs!
These four books were practically only borrowed by Hosaka.
It's because Hosaka wanted to be a mangaka.
To draw interesting things,
He studied what others rarely looked at.
He told me himself.
You know the signature on his table?
He said that it was for if he became famous.
So everyone knows that it is his signature.
Maybe his anger is from not fulfilling his dream!
With cursing tears, he soaked the floor.
And at midnight he perused the books he once read.
And then, he moved his lonely belongings to the courtyard!
H-Hey, Sonoko!
What, Ran?
Enough with the drama...
Speaking of the courtyard,
If we ask the principal, we might get some clues.
After you guys left the library,
On my way to the restroom, from the third floor,
I sow the principal standing in the courtyard, as usual.
Huh? He's fretting over the trees he planted in the courtyard?
Yeah.
He goes there every day and complains about those trees.
He's still worrying about those trees?
Hmm? But didn't you know that, since he told you before?
Eh?
Oh... right.
Of course he didn't know.
Because the Araide-sensei, at that time, was actually Vermouth.
Wait...
Since Vermouth was Araide-sensei,
She should've been the elementary school's doctor as well.
I'm eighteen, very close to your age.
Haibara, traitor of the organization, is about twenty.
If Vermouth wanted to look for her in schools,
She'd look in high schools and colleges.
But if she knew that Haibara
Took the same poison I did and turned small,
Why didn't she notice while at Teitan Elementary?
A transfer student should catch her attention,
So why didn't it?
Damn it!
Now I'm confused.
Because of this haunting case,
I have another mystery to solve!
So the culprit is...
Still in this school!?
Can you gather everyone by the door of the art room?
I thought of a way to catch the culprit!
So why don't we all just stay still and wait?
W-Wait for what?
Of course,
For the spirit of Hosaka to float down the stairs!
Next Conan!
Detective Conan
For making this show possible!
Next Conan's Hint!
Umbrella!
Weeping Storage Room,
Library of Anger,
The Cursed Stairwell...