Today's problem are ghost hauntings.
Our cooling hearts are opened again.
As the rumors are solved perfectly.
The only one who sees the truth is
The child with the brain of an adult.
He is Detective Conan!
Detective Conan
Would like to thank these sponsors
For making this show possible!
Recently ghosts have been haunting Teitan High.
Ran wanted Kogoro-occhan to solve this mystery,
But he refused because he thought that it was nonsense.
I was worried about Ran, who's afraid of ghosts,
So I went along with her to investigate.
After school, we started the investigation,
And in the usually empty courtyard,
A table and chair suddenly appeared.
"My hatred has not dissolved yet..."
The Teitan High Hauntings (Part2)
Principlas's Office
You're asking me if I was standing in the courtyard during the rain?
I didn't go there today...
During the rain I was in a staff meeting,
One concerning the rumored hauntings.
By the way, Dr. Araide,
Thanks to the stretches you taught me,
The pain in my hip has lessened immensely.
Hey, what's going on?
Did your friends lie to us?
Impossible!
She must've mistaken someone else for the principal!
Hey,
Let's go talk to Kazumi-senpai's friend,
The one resting in the health suite.
That health suite is very close to the courtyard,
So maybe he saw who it was!
Health Suite
Nope.
health suite.
I didn't see anything.
Seko Kunishige.
Table Tennis Team
After leaving you guys
I've been on this bed until now.
Plus,
See for yourself!
Even if I had left the bed,
I can't see the courtyard clearly from here.
Why did the principal have to plant those trees?
So even if anything suspicious happened,
I wouldn't be able to see it.
By the way, where's the school nurse?
Oh, he left early to go driving school.
He wanted me to go home and rest,
Since my house is nearby.
First the Weeping Storage Room,
Then the Library of Anger,
The Haunted Staircase,
And then the courtyard table and chair.
What is Hosaka thinking?
Um, we heard that you guys grew up together.
Yeah,
Together through elementary and middle school.
But in high school we rarely met.
Just as school started, because of a motorcycle accident,
I was in the hospital for half a year.
So about him falling off the stairs...
I found out after I returned to school.
Hey, have you seen anyone acting too scared?
Maybe the ones shouting, "Ghost! Ghost!"
Are behind these hauntings, laughing secretly.
Who, me?
It's possible...
Speaking of acting too scared,
Isn't that painter in the art room more suspicious?
No, that person in the health suite is also suspicious!
Because the storage room is close to the health suite.
And the courtyard is right across this hallway!
So we have two suspects...
No, there's one more.
Kazumi-senpai is also suspicious.
Huh? Why?
Since she went to the bathroom.
That means she left the library before.
Well...
Wait, didn't she also suddenly appear
While we were investigating the storage room?
That was just a coincidence!
If she really was behind all this,
Wouldn't she have gone home already?
No.
When Dr. Araide and I went to the courtyard,
Art Room
When Dr. Araide and l went to the courtyard,
We visited the shoe lockers.
The soil is wet from the front door to the school gate,
But no footprints were left there.
S-so the culprit is...
Still in this school!?
Yes...
The four events were all done by the same person,
So the people who know the most about the incident two years ago
Is most likely to be the culprit of these hauntings.
This hallway is always empty after school.
If the teachers all have the staff meeting to attend to,
Health Suite
The first floor health suite,
The second floor art room,
And the third floor library,
Are all places where one could
Secretly, without anyone noticing,
Move the table and chair from the storage room to the courtyard.
But how were the items put there without leaving footsteps?
And the motive?
These aren't just pranks.
The person behind this must have a motive!
Huh? What are these?
There are some water marks on the floor.
They weren't here when we came before...
Could it be!?
Conan-kun!
If it's what I think it is,
There should be marks in the courtyard!
I found it!
This is it!
Come on!
Don't wear slippers outdoors!
How could I overlook such an easy trick?
But if this method was used,
All three of them could've done it.
Gathering the proof will be hard...
Hey, Ran-neechan!
Can you gather everyone by the door of the art room?
I thought of a way to catch the culprit!
Monobe Masao, Art Student
Art Room
He's so slow.
How long do we have to wait?
He's here!
VVhat'd you do?
Oh, some things.
Can we really find the culprit by coming here?
Hey, wait! Brat with glasses!
Hey, didn't I tell you not to come in!?
Hey, are you prepared to go home?
Prepared to go home?
Well, my things are all over there, so l can leave any time.
Sorry for bothering...
S-seiko? What are you doing here?
That boy said that if I came, I'd know who the culprit is,
So I did.
He also said that this might take awhile,
Tsukamoto Kazumi
Karate Team
So I gathered my stuff before coming.
Hey, same here.
Kazumi-senpai!
Uh... Why is your umbrella muddy?
Yeah...
After seeing the morning forecast,
I quickly grabbed one.
I later found out that I took an old one...
Hey! Don't dust your umbrella here!
Sorry, sorry.
Well, has the culprit been found yet?
Not yet. We've just begun.
Wait, Conan-kun, are you sure about this?
I knew it.
The culprit is that person!
So, who is the culprit behind the school hauntings?
Conan-kun, didn't you say we'd know if we came here?
This time's school hauntings
Are rumored to be caused by Hosaka,
Who died two years age from falling of the stairs.
Y-yeah...
And those stairs are these right by the art room.
So why don't we all just stay still and wait?
W-wait for what?
Of course,
For the spirit of Hosaka to float down the stairs!
Ouch!
Hmphl
Our purpose for coming
Was to catch the real culprit behind the haungtings!
Mouri, forgive me, but I have to leave.
Me too.
I'm leaving also.
I can't concentrate with you guys being here.
What a shame!
That brat got us all excited for nothing!
Come on...
Sonoko!
Are you about to begin?
Begin?
Sonoko is just like my dad.
Doing that every time she solves a mystery.
But the way she fell wasn't normal.
Let me check her...
Oh no!
Don't touch me!
Now I, Sonoko the Deduction Queen, will begin my deduction show!
I knew it!
Yes, I know.
I know the hidden identity behind the ghost hauntings.
No matter what, that should be hidden.
I can see it clearly!
Sonoko!
Underwear, underwear!
Ah, excuse me!
After solving the mystery, my whole body just relaxed.
It was actually a simple trick!
Simple trick?
So you know,
How the table and chair were placed in the courtyard
Without leaving footprints?
And why note was dry?
Yes,
That note.
We were fooled by that dry note,
Forgetting one important thing.
If the table and chair were moved there during the rain,
The footprints would be washed away by the rain.
But even if the footprints are washed away,
The note on the table should've been wet!
To avoid the rain, Ran, what would you do?
I would find someplace to take cover.
Maybe wear a raincoat,
Or...
You mean...?
Yes, the culprit, to prevent the note from getting wet,
Used something to cover it; an umbrella with strings attached.
After the rain stopped, if you pulled the strings,
The umbrella could be retrieved.
It's possible to not leave any footprints
And leave a dry note on the table.
They're still there...
The marks left by the umbrella when it was retrieved!
Plus, the hall from the courtyard to the classrooms
Has water marks, proving my point.
Those were left by the culprit shaking the umbrella off.
But merely shaking it doesn't dry it off completely.
After a while,
Water will still flow out.
So the person behind the ghost hauntings is...
Yes,
It's the owner of that umbrella with the water flowing out.
Seiko Kunishige!
It's you!
First, you pretended to not feel well,
So you could go to the Health Suite.
Although the forecast said that there'd be a sudden rain sometime,
You did not know the exact time.
So you waited until it rained,
Then quietly moved the items to the courtyard,
Covering them with the umbrella.
Then you returned the Health Suite.
When the rain stopped,
You pulled the strings and retrieved the umbrella.
But what if someone else saw the umbrella on the table?
From the first floor, the view is blocked by the trees.
From the second or third floor,
You'd only think that someone was standing there.
So the principal I saw was...
You saw the umbrella and assumed it was the principal,
Who visited the trees often.
Hey, you're going to accuse me just because my umbrella's wet?
My umbrella's wet because it was too dirty,
So I washed it with faucet water.
Plus, using the method that you described,
Monobe and Tsukamoto could've done it also.
No, it's you!
Suppose we assume that you are culprit.
Then all the other hauntings,
Including the Library of Anger,
The Cursed Stairwell,
And the Weeping Storage Room, make sense.
First, in the Library of Anger, books that Hosaka once read
Were tossed on the floor.
But couldn't anyone do that?
The borrow logs say who took it out before.
Do you still remember the names of those books?
Names?
One was Electricity Communication...
It was Electronic Communications Discussion,
The Destruction of Tropical Rain Forests,
History of the University,
And How Crustal Plates Affect Sounds.
To be able to find these books and remember their names,
No person can accomplish that!
Unless that person is his childhood friend who knows him well,
Seiko-san!
Then what about the Cursed Stairwell?
There was a puddle beneath the stairs.
Did Seiko also do that?
Yes, isn't there a hole there where the extinguisher is kept?
After school, Seiko-san hid a piece of ice in there,
At night, the ice melted,
And the second day, the puddle was found.
Plus, there's some wax there, so the water didn't gather beside the hole,
And no one suspected that the water came from the hole.
The only one who could do this is Seiko-kun, who lives nearby.
I see...
After school, he took the ice from his refrigerator...
But why?
Didn't you grow up with Hosaka?
If you don't answer me, I won't let you go!
The beginning
Was the Weeping Storage Room.
To do morning exercises,
A gym student heard weeping in the storage room.
That was probably Seiko-san.
Seiko-san probably had table tennis practice that morning,
And saw Hosaka's belongings for the first time.
He probably thought that Hosaka didn't die of an accident.
Yeah.
I then understood,
That Hosaka was murdered when I was in the hospital!
And I knew what books he read, not because I grew up with him.
But because those four books were ones that
Hosaka brought when he visited me.
To help me recover faster,
He read to me a lot.
And after reading those, he'd think of amazing stories.
But one day he didn't come.
I thought that he had gotten a girlfriend,
But he had died.
Upon recovering, I asked around about how he died.
But all I got was that he had fallen of the stairs.
Then I found the table with his signature on it.
So to reveal the person who hid his table,
The person who pushed him off the stairs,
I faked the hauntings!
I-it's not like that.
Hosaka didn't fall because of any pushes,
But because of me!
What!
That morning, two sculptures needed to be delivered.
Hosaka and I were the hall monitors that day,
So we wanted to secretly move them to the art room,
Place them by the door,
And surprise the art teacher.
Maybe I was too hurried and careless,
I accidentally walked past the second floor.
Hosaka called me, and when I turned around,
My foot slipped!
Hosaka, to protect me, was killed beneath the sculpture and I.
So he wasn't pushed!
Don't lie!
Then why was his table in the storage room, gathering dust?
That's so it doesn't disappear,
Being the only thing that can prove he was here.
Because, his signature was written in ink, it'd soon disappear.
After his accident,
A notebook with pictures of his classmates was found in his desk.
So we asked the teacher.
If on the day we graduated, we could put his table with ours,
And he could graduate with us.
At first, the teacher hesitated,
But then we bought a new set to replace it,
And it was placed in the storage room.
I should've told you earlier,
But I found out you guys were close friends,
After the hauntings had already begun.
I see,
So that's why you appeared at the storage room.
Yeah, I thought that maybe he'd be by Hosaka-kun's desk,
S-so he doesn't have any hatred...
Yes.
He's only angry at me.
The plan was all my idea.
No, he doesn't hate you.
That day, the first doctor to arrive at the scene was me.
Hung on his mouth were his last words,
"If I lie here, won't the teacher be more surprised?"
How typical of him...
That's Sonoko for you!
Such a perfect deduction!
It was okay...
Why can't I remember anything?
But I was shocked,
That Dr. Araide heard that student's last words.
Actually, I didn't.
Hosaka couldn't have talked in that condition,
But I thought that saying that would comfort the three of them.
So it slipped my mouth...
Dr. Araide is just that kind!
Isn't it great to know there're no ghosts?
I'll have no problem being monitor next week!
I should tell my deduction to the newspaper staff,
And become a legend!
Forget it!
The hauntings won't happen again.
The rumors will disappear as time goes by...
Sorry, I got an important phone call.
Then we'll go first!
Bye bye, Dr. Araide!
Hello?
Ah, yes. I am Araide.
Really? That's great.
To not arouse suspicion and blend into the school again.
Yeah, I'm lucky.
Good thing I asked you first
What that criminal did as me in the school.
Then this will be my last conversation with you.
Forget about me!
W-well, I have a question to ask you.
The person that disguised as me...
Dr. Araide sure is helping, like always.
Was she really...
Before that kind-hearted doctor takes me to the hospital.
Thanks to the stretches that you taught me,
The pain in my hip has lessened immensely.
Really...
Dr. Araide is just that kind!
Was she really that evil?
After talking to school staff and students,
It's hard to imagine her as being mean...
Don't be stupid!
To be able to smile and kill at the same time,
How can she be good?
Yes, that lady's disguise of you was perfect.
She even copied your personality.
It's a frightening type of perfection.
That is all.
No, it must be.
It must've been planned.
Next Conan!
The Crows of the City!
Next Conan's Hint!
Lottery Ticket!
About the crows of the city,
Let the current events staff solve that!
Your purpose is?
The trash problem can also be solved on the internet!
Naruhodo