Today's stage is an ordinary housing estate.
Was it murder or an accident?
A blind spot in ordinary life!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Go away!
Get out of here!
You crows sure are a nuisance, I swear...
What's the point.
There's nothing good here anyway.
Looks like something happened over there.
I wonder what kind of case it is...
Hey, come on, stand back...
Oh, it's you kids.
Give us some details, Detective Chiba!
I really can't...
I-Is that...?!
A murder case?
Murder?!
I knew it...
N-No. It's not a murder case, it's an accident!
An accident?
You guys are really something...
It's true that someone died.
It was an old woman, Tatsue Egami-san, who lived here by herself.
A flower pot happened to fall
and hit her on the head
as she was returning home this morning.
That landed on her head?
But where did it fall from?
That looks dangerous...
They could fall off at any moment...
That's not very smart.
What kind of person lives there?
Flat 404.
That's the flat the late
Tatsue Egami-san lived in.
So this old lady was killed
with her own flower pot?
That's what we think happened.
Ah, poor old lady...
Poor old lady, sure, but...
Chiba-san!
How'd it go?
The neighbours had complained
to her about the danger.
They told her to hang them inside,
but she wouldn't listen.
I see...
If she had listened to them,
she wouldn't have died by a
little trick played by the crows...
A trick played by the crows?
Don't you see them? They're everywhere.
Since it's on the fourth floor, it's not likely
to have been the work of a stray cat.
One of them probably caught their beak or feet on the flower pot.
Crows sure are strong, aren't they?
But was this really the work of a crow?
There were no witnesses.
It happened early in the morning, so nobody was walking by.
Maybe someone who lives
across the street saw something.
Yeah... As you can see, that's not possible.
Being done in by crows... I'm starting to feel
more and more sorry for that old lady.
There are people joking that
a crow was killed by a crow.
A crow killed by a crow?
It seems like the late Tatsue Egami-san was
called 'The Crow Woman' behind her back.
The Crow Woman?
She would go out early in the morning to
go through the rubbish other people put out.
And she always wore dark clothing.
So that's why she was called the Crow Woman...
Nobody around here liked her very much.
They couldn't stand her always going through
their rubbish and invading their privacy.
There are even people who
moved away because of her.
So she was hated by everyone in the building...?
But why was she so interested
in other people's rubbish?
I heard it's because...
What a mess.
That raffle ticket she found
happened to be a third prize winner.
So I guess she figured she could
find something else valuable,
and that's why she started
going through the rubbish...
Searching for another golden ticket, huh?
So they took revenge on her because she
went looking through the rubbish...
Revenge?
The crows must've thought that she was
trying to steal their food and got angry.
That's why they knocked
the flower pot down.
I see, the crows took revenge
because she stopped them eating!
It's possible, because
crows are really smart!
So the old lady made her usual rounds
to the rubbish dump this morning.
But when she was walking back to the entrance to return to her flat,
the flower pot fell from above...
Hey, don't you think it's strange?
The old lady came from outside, right?
So she would've walked around like this.
To get to that entrance...
Yeah.
So why would she come this way when she was already at the entrance?
Now that you mention it...
That's true.
If she didn't go over there, she wouldn't
have been hit by the flower pot.
Actually, we thought that was strange too, when we first arrived.
The old lady had one hand
under that broken refrigerator,
and she died in a very strange position.
We found the reason when
we looked under the refrigerator.
In other words,
when Egami-san came back...
Oh...
When she was struggling
to retrieve the coin,
a mischievous crow
knocked the flower pot over.
It looks like that was what happened.
Yeah...
That makes sense.
I really feel sorry for the old lady.
Can this really be just coincidence?
She happens to drop her coin,
and it happens to roll under the broken
refrigerator, which is right beneath the plants...
Then just as she tries to pick up the coin,
the crow happens to drop the flower pot...
Oh?
Hey, stop!
You can't make it out onto
the roof, which means...
What happened? Conan!
The only way it could be done is from
that fifth floor flat...
EGAMI
IMAI
Ah... you're Imai-san, right?
Thank you for your help before.
Thank you for your hard work.
Have a nice day.
Ah...
Good morning!
G-Good morning...
Ayumi-chan, do you know her?
I think I've seen her before...
She's the one who lives
above that old lady, right?
Yeah, we asked her if she saw anything
during our investigation.
Does she live with her family?
No, I heard she was living alone.
Is something about her bothering you?
Is it love at first sight?
Do you like older women like her?
I wonder who she is...
I know I've met her somewhere before...
Huh?! That wasn't an accident?
It was murder?
Yeah.
If a crow had dropped the pot,
it should've landed either
upside-down or on its side.
Of course, if it fell like that,
it would smash into pieces.
But the pot was smashed
as if it had fallen bottom-first.
That means it came falling straight down.
In other words, the flower
pot wasn't knocked over,
but picked up and dropped.
Only humans are capable
of doing something like that.
But... If that's true, then
who killed the old lady?
It's that woman we met, the one who lives in the flat above her.
She's the only one who could've done it.
I checked, and found that
nobody can go up to the roof.
The only one who could fish up a flower
pot from the old lady's balcony
is the lady who lives
on the floor above her.
I guess you can't do that from a lower floor...
Wait a minute, Conan-kun.
Fishing the flower pot up
may be possible, but...
You're going to ask why the old lady
was under the window, right?
Right, because she only went there
because she dropped her coin,
and it happened to roll
under the refrigerator.
In other words, it was
just a coincidence.
Yeah! That's right!
Yes, that part was a coincidence.
That means your deduction won't work out,
because there's no way to bring
your target to the right spot.
There is.
And what is that?
Well, I've been thinking about that
all morning and haven't figured it out yet.
But I'm certain that...
You're wrong, Conan-kun!
She's not the kind of person
to do something so terrible.
She's a really nice person.
So you really do know her, Ayumi?
I didn't recognise her because she wasn't
wearing her uniform, but I just remembered.
I think she works in the bakery
in front of the train station.
You're only a first-year?
Yeah... I'm in Teitan Primary School.
You're really fantastic,
running errands on your own.
No... Is it that unusual...?
Here you go.
I was kind of dense
when I was a first-year.
Me too. That's how most
of us are in Year 1...
Yeah, that's how most of us are.
I haven't been to that shop since then,
because I was so embarrassed...
But she was still kind enough
to remember me...
I don't see how you can suspect
someone as nice as her.
It's not good to suspect people right
off the bat like that, Conan-kun!
Ayumi-chan!
Ayumi!
Conan-kun!
Conan!
There's no way.
No matter how much I think about it,
I can't see any way to lure the old
woman right under the window.
So the poor old lady did just happen to be
killed by a mischievous crow, after all.
No... There has to be a way...
Hey, kid, it's dangerous here.
Wait a minute, please.
So that's the story...
What happened, Conan-kun?
I figured out how she was able to lure
the old woman under the window.
It's this.
What's that?
Don't tell me that's...
Yes... It's the perfect bait
for the Crow Woman.
Conan-kun and the others
really get me mad.
How dare they suspect such a nice lady?
Geez, they still haven't given up investigating!
Excuse me, about that lady who works
at the bakery across the street...
Ayumi!
Look, Conan-kun, how sad do you think a person
would feel if she's suspected without any proof?
Cut it out already!
You see, Ayumi...
We found some evidence after all...
No way...
Were you waiting for me?
About what happened yesterday...
Miss, can I see your raffle ticket for a second?
You bought a ticket yesterday,
didn't you?
A single ticket from the raffle stand
near the bakery... Can I see it?
You do have it, don't you?
Let us see it.
You do still have it, don't you?
That's enough, Ayumi.
Yeah...
But...
It wasn't a coincidence or an accident
that the flower pot fell and hit the old lady.
Even though Ayumi-chan
insisted it can't be...
Only you, the lady living in the flat
above her, could have done it.
First, you hooked up one
of the old lady's flower pots.
Then you reeled out a long string.
You passed it under the refrigerator left for the rubbish,
sticking the raffle ticket you
bought onto the end of the string,
then placed it by the entrance and waited for the old lady to return.
When the old lady tried to
pick up the raffle ticket,
you pulled on the string.
Then you dropped the flower pot on her head when she tried to pick it up...
Though you couldn't see the old lady's head,
because the refrigerator was too big.
After that, all you had to do was
retrieve the raffle ticket, right?
You put the 500 yen coin there beforehand,
to camouflage the unnatural situation.
I couldn't figure it out at first.
But when the rubbish collectors
came a while ago,
I saw marks from string being pulled under the refrigerator.
As well as a corner of the raffle ticket,
that was torn off when you pulled it up.
If we check this piece, we should
be able to find your fingerprints.
There's no need.
You don't have to check.
But... Why?
Why did you kill the old lady?
She humiliated me in
the shop where I work...
Look, look! I read your letter!
What a laugh this letter is!
Look at it! Look!
Why do you have that?
I tore it up and threw it away!
No... My garbage...
You're that Crow Woman!
You must have picked the
pieces out of the rubbish...
Give it back!
What are you so worked up about?
I'm going to have some fun
with this letter.
It was a break-up letter
from my boyfriend...
She was so mean...
I was trying to forget him,
but she went out of her way to drag it out
and show it to everybody to humiliate me...
But...
You're still small,
so you might not understand.
But when you're older, you'll understand...
That there are things people can't forgive,
even though they may seem so trivial...
But... But no matter how unforgivable it is,
nothing's worth taking a life over!
You're right...
Here, you can have these.
I can't take them with me...
What is it?
Wow!
Even though I'm just a kid,
I do understand...
I can understand just how sad
she must have been at that moment...
But... Still... She went far too far!
You're absolutely right, Ayumi-chan...
The city crows sure are sinners...
That's... the man from before!
But that would mean these two cases
have no connection to each other.
They can only be explained
as a case of synchronicity.
If Takehiko-san was really killed,
it would have nothing to do
with the case in Beika.
That's right. Everything fits too well.
On the next Conan:
'A Case of Synchronicity (Part I)'!
Oh, look, the Next Conan's Hint is here! — Twins
What's synchronicity?
It means multiple things that happen at the same time!