Today's case is unbelievable complex.
Twin brothers at two different locations, both the same time...
How can this be possible?
Seeing through to the one and only truth,
the appearance of a child but the brains of an adult.
His name is: Detective Conan!
Meitantei conan is sponsored by the following sponsors.
Hitomi Shouichirou, (45)
I beg you, give me a few more days.
Please wait, somehow, just a bit more time...
It has already been too long. I can't delay it any longer.
Why don't you ask your brother for help?
That, I can't do...
The Synchronicity Case
(Part One)
What should I do? What should I do?
Going to the washroom, I guess.
Hello.
Dad.
Ran...
Mouri Detective Agency
What are you planning to do for lunch, dad?
Are you coming back?
I'm still working right now.
Really?
Then Ran-neechan and I are going to the Kekki
all-you-can-eat restaurant for lunch.
Good luck on your work, Uncle.
Going to Kekki all-you-can-eat buffet restaurant?!
But he really takes a long time...
Wait, could it be that he noticed me?
What happened? He has different atmosphere around him from before.
Oh well... Good enough.
D-ad.
Why are you two here?
Didn't I tell you over the phone?
So this is where you two were talking about.
No... This is not the time to think about that.
Excuse me!
I'm Minamisato from room 1015.
Minamisato Kaoru, (25)
Is there a package from Anzai-san?
No... There isn't.
Don't tell me. But just now on the phone, I was
told that the package was delivered here.
Can you please check it again?
It doesn't look like it's here...
I see.
Tasty!
Yeah... It's too bad that dad couldn't make it.
It can't be helped, uncle is working on a case right now.
What?!
Someone fell... Someone fell from the top.
Conan-kun.
Could it be the man from before?
But that would mean... Uncle!
How can something like this happen?
While I'm following him too...
Hitomi Shouichirou, 45.
I've been following him since this morning.
But I'm afraid I can't provide you with information on my client.
But Just what happened?
Let me explain then...
AH!!!!!!!!
If he realizes I've been following him, it would be bad, but...
NO STOP!!!
What's happening?! What happened?
Don't tell me...
Are you okay?
Oh!
YOU!
I'm sorry... I was totally out of myself...
What are you talking about? Come down from there first.
No... Please let me go...
Minamisato-san, what is your relationship?
with Hitomi Shouichirou-san?
None.
Huh?
I'm the one who wants to ask that.
Who was that guy? That Hitomi-san.
But weren't you attacked by him?
How can you not know him?
It can't be the case...
I'm telling the truth! I really don't know who he is!
But...
Minamisato Kaoru-san.
Yes.
Even though you called yourself by this name in the hotel,
But aren't you actually Hitomi Kanako-san, right?
Huh?
Who is that?
Shouichirou's brother, Takehiko-san's wife.
No, Inspector. I saw Kanako-san's picture
before. But why would you think that?
We investigated Shouichirou-san's cellphone record
and his last call was to Hitomi Kanako-san.
When was the call made?
11:20.
If that's the case...
Yes, he went into the washroom at 11:10 and came out at 11:30.
Which means, Shouichirou-san gave his brother's wife a call in the washroom.
Well... Can I be excused?
I'm sorry... But I want to be alone.
You're Anzai-san, right?
Before, when you were at the front desk,
ls there a package here from Anzai-san?
Anzai-san is someone I know. ls there something wrong?
No...
Really! Saying that she doesn't know Shouichirou-san
is way too easy a lie.
Maybe she really doesn't know him.
Impossible.
Huh?
What is it?
Don't you think this is weird, Uncle?
What is weird?
Didn't Shouichirou-san have a cellphone with him, right?
Then why did he have to use the public payphone?
There was probably no signal.
It doesn't look like there was no signal, look.
That's true...
Mouri-kun, this is bad!
What happened?
Look at the TV first.
The murder happened in this apartment
The male victim was the person living on the third
floor of this building: Hitomi Takehiko-san.
Shouichirou-san's brother?!
Same age, than they're not just brothers.
Could they have been twins?
The time of death is estimated as today at around 12:15pm.
No way... 12:15 is when Shouichirou-san...
It happened at the same time?
No way. How can something like this happen?
What did you say?
The person who hired Mouri-kun to follow Shouichirou-san..
Is the person who got killed in Haido city,
Shouichirou's brother Takehiko-shi?
Yeah...
Huh?
What did Takehiko-san wanted you to do?
To follow him and report back.
According to Takehiko-shi, Shouichirou-shi had been
using the fact that twins look exactly the same,
To pretend to be Takehiko-shi to do some illegal business.
Is that so?
I haven't confirmed it yet but he really
did have a large amount of debt,
And he was being pressured by the loan-sharks
to return the money this morning.
Could this mean, the reason that Shouichirou-san
came to Beika hotel is,
He found a good way to pay off the debt.
Synchronicity.
What are you talking about? Ran?
The twin brothers dying at the same time.
We may say it was a coincidence, but
maybe their fate also plays a part.
And that is synchro...
The principle of synchronicity.
The principle which is still being debated by psychologists today.
See, maybe Conan and I met dad at this hotel is also...
Oh, If you say it like that, I guess it is possible...
It could very well be two random events but
that's too much coincidence to say so.
Something's weird, we should investigate further...
The door was locked and there
wasn't a sign of forced entry.
What a complex lock. It's hard to make another key that would fit.
This is where the victim died...
As you can see, the window was broken from the outside.
We deduced that it is the work of a thief.
If Takehiko-san was really killed by a thief, than there is
no relationship between this and the one in Beika city.
Could all this really be one big coincidence?
So, you came back home at around 2pm.
Hitomi Kanako, (36)
And that's when you realized the death of your husband informed the police.
Yes.
Where did you go?
Beika City.
Beika City?
Be... Beika?
Is there something wrong?
Is this also related to the principle of synchronicity?
Actually, we were all in Beika City just a bit ago too.
Ah, I see.
Shouichirou-shi fell from Beika Hotel
by mis-step and passed away.
Huh? Shouichirou-san?
That can't be. Is that true?
I'm afraid so.
Did you go to Beika City to meet Shouichirou-shi?
From his cellphone record, we found
your number as the last contact.
Yeah.
Can you tell us what it was about?
Shouichirou-san said he wanted to make up with
my husband and asked me to be the arbitrator.
I see, to make up with...
Yeah... In fact, Shouichirou-san and Takehiko-san were working
together in their father's company for a long time.
There was much talk of which one of them should be the next
CEO after their father. but all of sudden he passed away...
Why is it you?
Being the younger brother, why do you get to be the CEO?
You can't blame me, it was in father's will.
But it is not hard to understand why dad picked me.
What?
Your wife took all your money and left you.
You didn't know she was a gold-digger, targeting
your money? That's also why dad...
Shut up!
You're fired! Get out of here!
Boomerang
Hitomi's trade company
ECHIGO
After that, Shouichirou-san tried to
start a new business of this own...
But the company didn't last long and he
was left with a huge amount of debt.
Then. a few nights ago...
I was wrong. I apologize, please...
No. I'm begging you... Lend me some money.
I don't have that kind of obligation to you.
If you didn't exist...
If you never had existed...
I wanted the two brothers to return to the peaceful relationship
they had before. So without letting my husband know,
I gave my cellphone number and spare
key to the house to Shouichirou-san.
On the other hand, Takehiko took some
actions of his own by hiring me,
He was worried that cornered Shouichirou-san
might use his name behind his back.
And to think, the two people at the same time, somehow...
What a coincidence... No, it's fate.
Hey, what did Shouichirou-san and Kanako-san
talk about on the phone?
Didn't you hear, He wanted to make up with his brother.
No, I wanted to hear it for myself too.
Please tell us what you two talked about on the phone in detail.
Okay.
Hello.
Is Takehiko there?
Huh? Yeah, he's home, do you want to talk to him?
No, that's okay.
I see...
I have something I want to talk to you about, Kanako-san.
I want to make up with Takehiko... Can you be the arbitrator?
Are you sure? That's great!
Of course I'll do it, I'll be glad to.
Can you come to Beika city?
Where in Beika city?
I will meet you at Beika city train station at 12:30, see you there.
But I waited for so long, and he didn't appear.
I didn't think it would end up like this.
Shouichirou-san probably wanted to meet with Kanako-san
after he finished what he had to do in Beika Hotel.
That is the most likely case if we can trust
Kanako-san's word as the truth.
I think we can trust her.
For example, the suspect used this tree
to climb into Takehiko-shi's house.
I don't think Kanako-san can climb up something like this.
You're right, so I guess it really is the work of a thief.
If that's the case, these two cases will be two
completely separate, unrelated cases.
The principle of synchronicity will then be the only way to explain.
Anyways, just to be safe, we will investigate Kanako-san's alibi a bit more.
Alibi?
If Shouichirou-san didn't fall but met with Kanako-san
than both of them would have had an alibi,
Shouichirou
Takehiko
Kanako
And that will rule them out completely from the
list of suspects to the death of Takehiko-san.
But, Shouichirou-san fell from Beika hotel and not only
that, he brought Minamisato Kaoru-san into this as well.
Kanoko
Shouichirou
Takehiko
Minamisato Kaoru
With her in the picture, the simple relations between brothers,
a husband and a wife became very complex.
Minamisato Kaoru, just who is she?
Even if you say so, I really don't know.
How can you not know him? You were
attacked by Shouichirou-shi.
There must be some reason behind
his attack such as revenge, etc.
To say that you don't know him is really hard for
me to believe even if it's not totally impossible.
How can I make you believe me then?
Tall me the truth!
I am telling you the truth! I'm not lying!
Why would I want to lie about such a horrible memory?
Honestly, why?
Why? Why is it like this?
Why does this kind of thing have to happen to me all the time?
We're classifying the Haido city case as a murder
case and will continue our investigation.
As for this one, we're classifying it as
an accident and treat it accordingly.
Only as an accident?
It may be true that Shouichirou-san
fell off The building as an accident,
But what about the one, Shouichirou-san had
attacked Kaoru-san in the first place?
Attack... Maybe it was an attempted murder.
However, no further investigation will be carried
out due to the death of the suspect.
How can it be?
Anyhow, just what is that person trying to hide?
Is she trying to cover for someone else?
I think the media will make a big thing out of this...
Twin brothers dying at the same time
but at completely different places.
Maybe it really is due to the principle of synchronicity.
Kanoko
Shouichirou
Takehiko
Minamisato Kaoru
No, it's not that...
It's not synchronicity.
The relationship between Kaoru-san and the others?
That would bring us closer to solving this puzzle.
What is it... The reason that Shouichirou-san
attacked Kaoru-san?
No, perhaps even tried to kill her...
In the wind I sometimes smile, sometimes cry and sometimes fight.
The two of us are just like this standing in front of our dreams.
Our dream is sure In be somewhere in the unknown future.
The colors of the seasons, always repeating let us experience a lot.
I look upon the side of your sleepy face with a smile.
Slaying in that moment, this becomes our future.
Next Episode Preview
Dad! Stop that person!
Oh... I'm so sorry!
The key to solving these two cases is,
To understand the unbelievably scary perfect
killing plan that the criminal had thought up.
Perfect Killing Plan?
Next Conan
The Synchronicity Case (Part Two).
Part 2
Meitantei Conan is presented by the following sponsors.
Next Conan's hint.
Kogorou's investigation.
Next time uncle's investigation finally has some uses. How rare!
It really is!