Today's case is beyond imagination.
Two unrelated cases will be solved with one key point.
Seeing through the one and only truth,
He looks like a child but has the brain of an adult.
His name is: Detective Conan!
Meitantei Conan is sponsored by the following sponsors.
The person whom Uncle Kogoro was hired to follow,
Hitomi Shyouichirou-san, died by falling
off the balcony at the Beika Hotel.
At the same time, his twin brother, Takehiko-san,
Was found murdered inside of his house in Haido City.
This must be twist of fate...
There's no other explanation for it other
than the principle of synchronicity.
No, it's not something like synchronicity.
The connection between Kaoru-san and others,
If I can find the link, I can solve this mystery.
But just what is it?
Why did Shyouchirou-san attack Kaoru-san?
No, perhaps he tried to kill her.
What's the reason?
(Part Two)
The Synchronicity Case
Hey, uncle! This picture...
What about it?
It was only after Shyouichirou-san used this phone,
That's Minamizato Kaoru-san
appeared at the front desk, right?
Yeah...
What did Kaoru-san say back then again?
I think it was...
Is there a package here from Anzai-san?
That Anzai-san person...
Aren't you going to ask her about him one more time?
Can it!
What's wrong, Mouri-kun?
I'd like to speak with Kaoru-san just one more time.
Wait a second, Dad.
Uncle!
Who?!
Wha... What the?
Isn't that Kaoru-san's room?
What?!
Kaoru-san?!
Damn it! Not Again, we just fixed this door not too long ago.
There's no other way.
Kaoru-san?
Grab him, Dad!
I'm so sorry!
There's still a pulse...
Call an ambulance.
Beika General Hospital
I was in a relationship with Anzai Manabu-san.
While In Kansai.
We were even talking about marriage, but half a year ago...
I lost contact with him after that.
I see.
I'm sorry for suspecting you.
That man probably got close to you just for your money.
By the way, did you report it to the police?
No, I wanted to confirm it with him person first so...
But if you don't even know where he is...
Actually, I heard someone saw him in Tokyo.
But even though I came to look for
him, I didn't know where to start.
I realized then, beside Anzai-san's name,
I didn't know anything about where he came
from or even what he did for a living.
I knew nothing about him.
He intentionally said nothing.
If that's true, then even the name "Anzai" is questionable.
The only lead I have is a picture of him.
W-What?
Let me see the picture, please.
I met Anzai on a diving trip, so I thought he might also go diving here.
I took the picture and a memo of my contact information
at Beika Hotel and walked around here and there.
Huh?
This person!
What is it, Conan-kun?
Hey, let me see the digital camera for a second.
Here, look at this person.
Dad, please try to remember.
Was there anything between this person and Shyouichirou-san?
I don't think there was anything between them...
Where did you see him? I want to go there.
No, we'll go.
I'm a detective, so I'm used to looking for people.
Besides, the person who attacked you earlier...
Couldn't that have been Anzai-san?
I'm not sure...
That can't be...
I don't know.
About the man in this picture...
Oh, Tanizaki-san.
Tanizaki? You sure it isn't Anzai?
Yeah.
He is Tanizaki-san for sure.
So that was a fake name after all.
Well, I can't be sure that "Tanizaki" is real either.
Tanizaki-san.
No, perhaps I should call you Anzai-san.
Wha... What is this about?
I'm sure you know Minamizato Kaoru-san.
Who is that? I don't know.
Please stop pretending.
Sorry, Shin-chan! Did you wait long?
Oh? And your relationship with this young woman is?
Who is this old man?
No one important.
He's got the wrong person.
Let's go.
Okay.
Oh, just now Papa sent me email.
He said he'd think of something for that money.
Oh? Thank you so much!
That would help a great deal!
It's nothing. Anything for my Shin-chan.
I see...
So it really was...
I'm sorry, but you were definitely deceived.
I see...
So it wasn't just this...
There's one more person involved.
Either Tanizaki or Anzai whatever his name is,
That man is definitely related to the case.
Kaoru-san's probably not the only girl he's duped.
Including that girl who was with him just now,
There were probably quite a few more.
If Kaoru-san found out about that, he'd be suspected.
So he wanted to silence her for good.
There is a motive for him to kill.
First of all, Shyouichirou-san and this man have
a common contact point in the sports center.
But if it's just a mere coincidence, then we can't go any further.
Shyouichirou-san's accident,
Takehiko-san's murder which happened at the same time,
And lastly, the attack on Kaoru-san.
I've got to find the link among them...
Oh? Wait a second.
I see! So that's it!
Ran-neechan.
What is it, Conan-kun?
The Uncle told me to take a picture of this diagram.
It'll be used later.
Mouri-kun, everyone's here.
Good. I want to thanks you all for coming.
What is this? What the heck are you trying to start?
To unlock the mystery of the two cases.
Cases?
Wasn't Shyouichirou-san's death an accident?
No matter if it were an accident or the principle of synchronicity,
It was all too strange.
This strangeness caused to much attention.
Meaning, this was all part of an unbelievably horrible,
perfect murder plan that the criminal devised.
Pe... Perfect murder plan?
Yes, if it had gone smoothly, it would have been.
Ran, are you finished with the TV connection?
Okay.
To tell you the truth, one thing had been
on my mind from the beginning.
Shyouichirou-san had his own cellphone with him,
Yet, he used the public payphone from
the hallway to call somebody.
There was no problem with reception, so why?
If he had used the cellphone,
We could have used the phone's call
history to find out who he'd dialed.
Would it be bad if it were found out?
Yes, because that could count as evidence.
If anything, it'd be evidence he cannot explain.
So, who did he call?
It should be the person who was staying in this hotel,
Minamizato Kaoru-san.
Kaoru-san, what was said during that phone call?
Well... I was told that Anzai-san had left a package for me at the front desk.
But when I asked about it, nothing was there.
Why would he call her to tell her such a lie?
Because he didn't know what Kaoru-san looked like.
Who exactly do you mean?
Shyouichirou-san.
He did it to confirm Kaoru-san's identity, and then...
He followed and attacked Kaoru-san, but because of my interference,
Shyouichirou-san, who tried to escape by the balcony...
But why would he want to kill me, someone he didn't know at all?
Ah... that's because it was very convenient
for the real criminal targeting you.
Not knowing you at all meant that he wouldn't have a motive.
In other words, it means that he wouldn't be suspected.
I don't quite follow what you're saying.
Kanako-san,
Do you know why Shyouichirou-san asked you
to meet him all the way here in Beika City?
Well... I thought he didn't want my husband to know.
No. It was because he wanted to create his alibi.
Create his alibi?
Shyouichirou-san didn't have the motive to kill Kaoru-san, but...
You're fired. Get out of here!
He does have a motive for murdering Takehiko-san.
But there are other ways to create his alibi.
Correct.
Actually there's a more import motive behind it.
He wanted to get Kanako-san out of the house
and leave Takehiko-san home alone.
It would be bad to have Kanako-san around
while he tried to kill Takehiko-san.
Please think back.
This first question Shyouichirou-san
asked you over the phone was...
Is Takehiko there?
Yes, he's here.
To see if Takehiko-san was there.
And when you said your husband was there, he refused
to talk to him and instead wanted to meet with you.
Can you meet me at Beika City?
All right.
I will meet you in front of the Beika City
train station at 12.30. See you there.
The call was made in the sport center's washroom.
There was probably someone beside him at the time.
Shyouichirou-san confirmed the whereabouts
of Takehiko-san for this person,
And invited Kanako-san out for a meeting.
Ran, change the picture to that connection chart.
Okay.
It looks like a very complex case at first glance,
But if you take Kanoko-san, who was only
used for an alibi, out of the picture...
That definitely simplifies it.
But who's that man on bottom right?
As opposed to Shyouichirou-san who
has a motive to kill Takehiko-san,
The person who has a motive to murder Kaoru-san.
He may have many names, but for our
purposes, let's call him Anzai-san.
The original two unrealized motives,
Became complete once Shyouichirou-san and Anzai-san met.
A murder exchange.
But you were pretty uneasy afterwards, Anzai-san.
You finished your part of the plan successfully,
But shyouichirou-san failed his part and accidentally died.
So you had no choice but to kill Kaoru-san yourself.
That's why you came to Beika Hotel.
A murder exchange?
You're saying whatever comes to mind!
But where's your evidence?
Is there any evidence that points to me?
Dad...
Sigh... It still ended up this way...
Inspector Megure, did you find that
thing in Takehiko-san's house?
Oh... We found it in the trash can at the nearby park.
That is my house key!
Kanako-san, is this the key you gave to Shyouichirou-san?
Yes.
Unbelievably, this key wasn't anywhere
near Shyouichirou-san's belongings.
That's because he lent the key to Anzai-san.
Since he probably never thought of taking the key back,
we might as well say he gave it to Anzai-san.
Anzai-san used the key to get into the house,
But the key could be used as evidence
against him... So he threw it away.
So what about the broken window?
To make it look as if it were a burglary.
There's no point in putting the key inside the house,
So you might as well make it look like the criminal
entered the house with the front door locked.
Unbelievable. When did you notice this?
Please remember, Takehiko-san's
body was near the front entrance.
If the window were broken first,
Then he would have entered the living room to check it out.
But in actuality, he heard the sound of the front door opening,
And was killed by Anzai-san who had just sneaked in.
Does that key have my fingerprints on it?
No. You probably erased them before you threw it away.
Whatever you say.
If you don't have any evidence, I'm going to go now.
How about this?
Ran, change to that picture.
Yes.
What?
It's to look for difference in two pictures.
Please look closely, everyone.
The left picture is Anzai-san before he went to the washroom.
And the right one is Anzai-san after he came out of the washroom.
Oh? The key!
You can't talk your way out of this one now.
You might as well admit to your crime.
When I saw that picture at the diving
store I used to go, I got scared.
I might have lied my way out of it last time,
But I thought, "What if Kaoru found out about me someday?"
Just then...
Damn...
Dam that Takehiko...
That jerk...
That jerk.
So... How about it?
A murder exchange.
Even if you are suspected, you'll have no
motive. And you'll have a perfect alibi.
Let me think about it.
I've already told you this much,
I really don't want to hear no from you.
That guy was indecisive at first,
But I convinced him that he won't be found out
for sure, and got him to agree to the plan.
Just as I thought, it was you who suggested the plan.
Shyouichirou-san seemed to be regretting his mistake.
I'm sorry...
I don't know how I lost myself...
Please forgive me...
He was probably really cornered in life...
So he took up your plan easily.
What a horrendous crime.
I'll make sure you'll pay.
In the wind I sometimes smile, sometimes cry and sometimes fight.
The two of us are just like this standing in front of our dreams.
Our dream is sure to be somewhere in the unknown future.
The colors of the seasons, always repeating let us experience a lot.
I look upon the side of your sleepy face with a smile.
Staying in that moment, this becomes our future.
But, looking at his picture in the newspaper,
And how he contacted the victim...
He's a really bad person.
"Really bad" just isn't enough to describe him.
It's people like that who can think of things like murder exchanges.
But I still think it's the principle of synchronicity.
Well, you following Shyouichirou-san at Takehiko's request,
And being around to rush into the room when
Shyouichirou-san was attacking Kaoru-san...
It was all a coincidence, right?
You can't forget the moment when that
person attacked Kaoru-san, either.
If I hadn't said that we should go back to
see her, she would've been in danger.
It was me who said that.
Oh, well...
Then, I wonder if this is also the principle of synchronicity.
What is it, Conan-kun?
How uncle always seems to fall asleep whenever
he successfully solves a case.
Mouri Detective Agency
WHAT?!
Dad!
That's due to my wisdom and keen perception.
Dad...
In the temple left in the mountains,
An unbelievably impossible case occurs.
Using the special location of a mountain setting,
The surprising trick the culprit uses...
Have you noticed?
Among all Conan cases up until now, challenge
this difficult trick with your family!
Detective Conan Encore Special.
The Kiri-Tengu Legend Murder Case.
On June 28th, Monday, 7pm in the evening!
Next Conan's Hint.
Fishing vocabulary
Next time is the big-scale, difficult trick case a one-hour special.