Today's stage is set on a fishing trip.
The vastness of the pier leads to a case
that human eyes have never seen.
Seeing through the one and only truth,
He looks like a child but has the intellect of an adult.
His name is: Detective Conan!
Meitantei Conan is brought to you by the following sponsors.
Here, everyone. Watch your step.
Ah... The wind feels so nice!
Listen up, everyone!
We'll be fishing at the pier today so you have to be careful.
Don't get too excited and fall into the sea, got it?
Yes!
But isn't this rare, the professor taking us to the sea?
Isn't it a nice change of pace?
It's like how we always seem to camp on the mountains.
Even the professor can come up with a good idea.
I guess.
I'm not really worried.
After so many things have happened,
You brought me, one who's been avoiding everyone.
Instead of the confinement of the mountains,
The broad openness of the sea is a much better choice.
This is probably someone's idea of being considerate.
That...
You guessed it.
Oh, well... The change of pace isn't so bad.
After all, the sea is the mother of life.
To feel the open wind once in a while isn't a bad thing,
But someone really should mind their own business.
She's really not cute at all.
Oh. well... At least Ai-kun looks happy.
You think so?
And just as Ai-kun said, the sea is the birthplace of life.
The birthplace of life?
This is a fitting place to release some tension.
Oh... Now that you've mentioned it, isn't today...
Oh! Are you kids going fishing as wall?
Yes, we are.
But we can only stay till just after lunch.
Then, until just after lunch,
What do you say to a friendly fishing bet between us?
A bet to see.
How many fish we can catch?
How about we bet one item from our lunch boxes?
One item from... our lunch boxes?
Shirane Kiriko (38)
Fishing Enthusiast
I'll bet my butter crabcake.
It is very delicious! Right, Kanetani-kun?
Yup, it's always great.
Kanetani Mineto (39)
Fishing Enthusiast
Just what you would expect from a fisherman's daughter,
Your seafood cuisine is unbeatable.
We're all very lucky tube able to eat a beautiful woman's cooking.
What are you talking about, Kanetani-kun?
But we all just learned how to fish.
Then you should go ask Ida-kun.
Ida-kun?
He's the fisherman who's steering the boat right now.
If it's about fishing, he will have the answer for it.
No, that won't do.
Ejiri Futoshi (41)
Fishing Enthusiast
You can't catch any fish Just by asking questions.
After all, both your hairstyle and your
age point to you being a kid.
Just kidding.
What's wrong with being a kid?
Are hairstyle and age even related to fishing?
"Boy" in fisherman's terms means that
you couldn't catch a single fish.
And you guys walked right into it.
Don't worry about it. This is just some
boring joke from an old man.
That guy.
All right!
We'll ask that fisherman for tips, and
catch lots of yellowtails and salmons.
There's no way you can find those kinds of fish here.
The Tragedy of the Pier in Plain Sight.
Part One.
Well, I'm going ahead. I'll be back in three hours. Good luck!
Ida Iwao (39)
Fisherman
If something happens, call me immediately.
I can be here in 20 minutes.
Huh? What happened? Why would you do that?
Because...
Right?
Right!
When we went to ask that fisherman about fishing tricks,
He treated us like kids, so we're very angry right now.
Well... What did he say?
He laughed and fold us not to play around with each other.
That's for sure.
It's just as he said.
Why is he right?
If you play too much around the pier,
The sound of your footsteps will be carried down info the water.
And that will scare away the fish.
What the fisherman wanted to say was,
If you get too excited and your footsteps are loud,
Then the fish won't come close.
But he didn't have to use a tone like that.
Yeah... That's right.
Did he say anything else?
Afterward...
It's dangerous to do something like that!
If the kids copy him, it'll be bad.
Ejiro-san always finds his fishing spot
on the edge of the pier's cement field.
He won't be satisfied with any other spot. That's just how he is.
But the pier's cement field is mostly on top of the water.
It's unbelievable. Even though we're in the middle
of the sea, the water can still be so shallow here.
Yes. It's because underground plating
system here very complex.
Look, the water over there is very deep.
Because of that, boats have a tough time coming here.
So most fisherman don't even know about this spot.
And that makes this the best fishing spot ever.
We should all thank Ida-kun's steering-skill.
I see. That's why there's no other fisherman here.
All right, good luck to you all.
I'm betting my lunch box, after-all.
But can we really catch any fish in place like this?
Sure.
To the fish, this pier is like a man-made hotel with a free buffet.
There are a lot.
Really?
A LOT of fish?
But the fishing season is already...
Oh, no...
A bit over...
We only brought this small box! What should we do?
We didn't give this enough thought.
What should we do if we can't fit them all in?
Don't worry!
We'll eat all the extras.
What are you talking about, Genta-kun?
Err...
Then my goal should be the youngest fishing record holder.
Oh! That sounds good!
Then I'll open the fish store!
Hmm... That sounds good, too!
They're not listening at all...
We aren't catching anything.
Are all the fish asleep?
There's no movement at all.
And the weather is so good too.
It's the good weather that makes fishing harder.
Huh? What do you mean?
Sunny days aren't good?
When the wafer is as shallow as this,
The sunlight makes the water really clear and
the fish are more alert of their surroundings.
So in fact, cloudy days and rainy days are better for fishing.
Despite all that, this is a good spot.
I'm sure we'll catch some fish soon.
Still, don't get your hopes up too much.
Fishing is a sport for the patient.
That's not always true.
There are a lot of famous fishermen who are very impatient.
That's right. An impatient man will figure
out beforehand if the bait works or not,
If the location is right or not and if the fools are useful or not.
They'd also read a lot of books,
Take notice of fishing news, and check the
condition of the tide on that particular day.
Spending a lot of time in research
will speed up your improvement.
But improving your actual fishing expertise is still very important.
Only if you put in a lot of effort will the sea reward you
and you'll be able to catch bigger and bigger fish.
But then again, even I haven't received any reward like that yet.
Conan, you said there're a lot of different
kinds of fish here, right?
Yeah.
Then can we catch a snapper?
No way.
Why not? Why is it impossible?
Snapper only live in the part of the sea where
the water depth is between 30-70 meters.
But isn't the sea connected together?
Maybe one will lose its way and come over here.
I remember a sea lion who did that once.
That's right, we can just aim for lost fish!
Even a whale can lose its way once in a while!
Come on...
Maybe we can catch a whale!
After all, we got nothing but time! Try your best, Conan.
Yeah... I'll keep trying...
Do you have a bite?
No... My marker got washed away.
Oh, well You probably didn't tighten your marker properly.
But still...
What is it this time?
Ai-chan's marker is moving!
A bite! Don't get excited, Haibara.
Pull! Pull!
You're almost there!
Your can do it!
Don't rush it. Yeah, like that!
Success!
Bu? it's so small...
Is it a baby tuna or something?
Well... It's better than nothing.
Why did you do that?
Releasing baby fish back to the sea is
one of the main principles of fishing.
Of course.
What a waste.
But next time, you should cool your hands in the
basket first before releasing it back to the sea.
Human body heat is way too high for fish.
They can actually get burned by it.
Do you have to say something for everything?
I'm just suggesting a better way of doing it next time.
But this proves that even we can catch some fish.
Okay, I'm gonna fish on the opposite side.
Hey!
Because I want to catch a snapper!
Don't run!
Oh, right! Snapper, snapper.
Didn't I say it's impossible?
We can't catch anything.
Really, not even one bite.
And who was saying that he's going to
catch lots of yellowtails and salmons?
Why isn't there any movement?
But improving your actual fishing expertise is still very important.
All right! Everything needs experience, lots of experience!
I'm going to go and sea how those uncles are doing.
Remember not to run.
I know, I know.
Everyone is slowly getting used to the rules of fishing.
Very nice. Very nice, indeed!
Thank you.
Good luck!
Who knows, you might become professional someday.
Ayumi-chan, did you learn anything from him?
Yeah, that Uncle taught me a lot about
the different ways to use fish baits.
Oh, really?
Maybe I should ask him something, too.
There should be a lot of fish underneath
here but why can't we catch any?
He said that the position of the tide isn't in our favor right now.
Is that it? The position of the tide?
I'll definitely catch it today.
If I can't catch it today, when can I ever catch it?
I can't catch anything.
Me, either.
But even the real fishermen with all their
experience aren't catching anything.
It can't be helped.
I really want to catch something, even if it is just one fish.
Yeah... If we can't catch anything, that
uncle will surely make fun of us again.
I'm sleepy again.
It moved!
Really?
There's no mistake. It's a bite!
Do you best, Mitsuhiko-kun.
I caught it! I caught it!
That's great, Mitsuhiko-kun!
Hey, You caught something, Mitsuhiko-kun.
It looks like a nice mackerel!
Genta-kun! I caught something! Look!
You caught something? Really?
Look! Look! It's so big!
Mitsuhiko-kun caught it!
Yup.
Th-that's good.
That's so small. I'm here to catch a really big snapper.
This is great, Mitsuhiko-kun!
And it's even a mackerel.
That's incredible! Looks like I lost.
By the way, is this marker yours?
My marker. Thank you!
It got washed away. But how did you get it?
Rememer to tighten if properly next time.
I will.
The butter crabcake that auntie gave us is really delicious.
What do you think? Lunch taster better
when you eat at a place like this, right?
Yeah, it's yummy!
Nothing...
Maybe Conan was right after all.
I can't catch any snappers here.
Right now's the worst time to fish. It'd be
better to fish around dawn or sunset.
Everyone seems to be having a hard time catching anything.
Not a single fish. Looks like I should change my fishing gear.
How are you doing over there?
Nothing, not even a bite.
Is the fish bait even still there?
What? Is it a bite?
Conan! A whale! It's a whale!
It looks like your fishing line is tangled up somewhere.
Tangle? Is there a fish called a tangle?
It's not a fish.
The line's probably caught on some seaweed
or some underwater reef.
It... It's not a fish? Then what should I do with this?
Don't pull so hard. Relax your hand a bit, then pull.
Like this?
Yeah, that's right. Keep going.
It's free!
What's this?
This is what you caught. Your big fish.
The bait's gone again.
Even Ejiri isn't having any luck today.
It looks like things aren't going well over there either.
Is it because of the tide?
Genta-kun? Aren't you going to eat?
I'm gonna fish a little longer before I eat.
Unbelievable. Genta-kun is skipping his lunch.
Does he really want to catch a snapper that badly?
Little snapper takes the bait.
Professor.
Ah... Sorry.
Even if it's like that... I'm so hungry right now.
Lunch or snapper? Lunch or snapper?
Lunch should still come first!
Eating lunch near the sea has its own special flavor, doesn't it?
Ai-kun, how is it? Aren't you glad that we brought you along?
You don't have to eat that fast!
I don't want to waste any time.
The lunch tastes great here. Thank you.
That's his fastest record yet.
All right, now that I finished lunch, back to fishing.
It's up to you now, little snapper.
Genta.
Oh, the boat's here.
Is it time already?
Then let's head back.
Yeah.
He's already here to pick us up? That was fast.
We're having a curry party over at the professor's house tonight.
Yeah, and we can have my mackerel sashimi, too.
Well, sashimi might be a bit hard.
That's a good idea.
Professor.
How did it go? Did you guys catch anything?
Of course... We ended up with the amount of my hair... None.
That's really too bad.
How about you guys over there?
I also have "boy."
I've only caught a small mackerel myself.
Too bad, too bad.
How about I take you guys to another location or for the afternoon?
Yes, but Ejiri-kun...
Ejiro-kun said he's going to stay here until late today.
Is that right? Then I'll go talk it over with Ida-kun.
Hey, Genta-kun. I think you should just give up already.
We're going back now.
He said he's going to take us to the
place where we went to last time.
Is he? That's great!
Changing locations?
Yeah... We didn't have any luck here today.
There's a place nearby where we caught lots of fish last time.
So we'll take the boat back with you.
Yeah, we're not that busy, so it's okay.
So we're all going together?
No, Ejiri-san is going to stay right there.
We're leaving him here?
No need to worry.
Ida-kun's boat will come and pick him up in the evening.
EJiri-kun really likes that spot, doesn't he?
I had so much fun! I hope we can come again sometime.
Yeah, next time we'll do some research before
we come, like the professor said.
Hey, we're leaving!
I still want to fish some mars.
The only catch I had is seaweed.
It's tangled again?
Then, we're going to go first.
Good luck!
It's useless to try to talk to him.
As soon as Ejiri-san settles down to fish,
It's impossible to make him move or even talk.
That's right.
He said if he doesn't catch anything big today, than he won't leave.
When he catches a big one, you will see him singing and dancing in joy.
He even fell into the water like that last time.
But he's so quiet today.
He probably has something to think about.
Then, let's go.
It looks like there's a bite!
It really looks that way.
There's a bite, didn't you notice?
Ejiri-san, you've got a bite!
Ejiri-san?
What happened, yelling like that?
He looks asleep, that uncle.
Fell asleep?
Ejiri-san?
No way...
What happened?
Ejiri-san!
Ejiri-san, Ejiri?
What happened?
What is it?
Did something happen?
Ejiri-san!
In the wind I sometimes smile, sometimes cry and sometimes fight.
The two of us are just like this standing in front of our dreams.
Our dream is sure to be somewhere in the unknown future.
The colors of the seasons, always repeating let us experience a lot.
I look upon the of your sleepy face with a smile.
Staying in that moment, this becomes our future.
Next Episode Preview
Bring him to the boat immediately and take him to the hospital.
Quickly!
Dear.
Don't move!
Just stand there and don't touch anything.
Hey, hey, what is this about?
Just who are you, kid?
Edogawa Conan, a detective.
Next Conan!
The Tragedy of the Pier in Plain Sight.
Part Two.
Next Conan Hint!
Celebration.
Next time we'll solve the mystery.
Fishing case finishes.
W-What?