Today's stage is still set at the pier.
Blended together in plain sight...
The trick and the culprit, we'all catch them both!
Seeing through to the one and only truth,
He looks like a child but has the intellect of an adult.
His name is: Detective Conan!
Meitantei Conan is brought to you by the following sponsors.
Hey, Ejiri-san!
Hold on... Just hold on!
His lips are turning purple. There are also purple dots appearing.
These are signs of oxygen deprivation...
But his pulse is still strong...
His heartbeats sound normal as well.
That means the problem originated in the brain.
Or maybe... It was a nerve toxin.
Artificial respiration!
Take him to the hospital on your boat immediately.
Hold on, Ejiri-san!
We've got to hurry.
Sweetheart. Sweetheart!
Don't move!
There's a high possibility that he's been poisoned.
And the person who gave him the poison is most
likely one of us on this pier right now.
Until the police arrive, please stay where
you are and don't touch anything.
Hey, hey. What is this?
Just who are you, kid?
Edogawa Conan, a detective.
The Tragedy of the Pier in Plain Sight (Part Two)
Well then, let's star with you and that
uncle's relationship with each other.
Shirane Kiriko (38)
Fishing Enthusiast
Kanetani Mineto (39)
We were in the same college fishing together.
Ejiri-san, who's being taken to the hospital,
was in the same club with us.
Do you guys often come to this pier to fish?
Yeah, using that fisherman lwao's boat.
Ida Iwao (39)
Fisherman
Then you four know each other pretty well.
Yeah, especially Ida and me. Our parents
are both fishermen and friends.
So I've known him since we were little.
That's right. Earlier, you said that
you were a fisherman's daughter.
Well, Shirane-san knows a lot about fishing, so
she was rather popular in the fishing club.
Not to mention that she's a great cook and beauty.
She was like a Madonna to us fishing club Members.
Cut that out, Kanetani-kun. That was a long time ago.
Is that why you killed him?
Because Shirane-san was taken away by Ejiri-san.
What are you talking about?
When that auntie called out to Ejiri-san just
earlier. didn't she call him "sweetheart?"
That kind of nickname is only used between
a couple in a romantic relationship.
So, the culprit is the one who acted on the
hatred he'd gained from his broken heart.
Kanetani-san, that's you!
Don't say such stupid things!
If that's the case, then the fisherman Ida-san
would also be a suspect, right?
Ida-san?
Ida-san was chosen to be Shirane-san's fiance
by their parents when they were younger.
Fiance?
That's not possible.
Why?
Because Ejiri-san and I divorced three years ago.
Eh? Why?
Because of several reasons...
But we both still really like fishing, so I still ask him out
to fish during the holidays with Kanetani-kun and me.
Then, do you always make lunch for everyone?
Look, this is the lunch box Ejiri-san just finished.
The size of the lunch box and the handkerchief used to wrap it,
They're both the same as the one Shirane-san
used on Kanetani-san's lunch box.
It does look the same as Kanetani-san's lunch box.
Don't tell me time was poison inside the lunch!
No way! I wouldn't do anything like that.
After all, I received those two lunch boxes from
Shirane-san and gave one of them to Ejiri-san.
Since they look exactly alike, she wouldn't
know which one I'd hand to him,
So she couldn't have put poison in the lunches.
Yeah... I guess you're right...
There's a fishing stand in the water.
This must be one of the two stands that Ejiri-san was using.
The other one is still standing there. so why?
Hmm... We don't have any leads on this case yet...
Maybe he put the poison on the fishhook and cast
it so that it'd catch Ejiri-san and poison him.
That's right! Casting is a basic skill for fishing.
That's not possible.
Having the hook touch his exposed skin
on one cast would be pure luck.
And if the poisoned fishhook was dropped into the sea for even a moment,
the sea water would've washed most of the poison away.
So... It still comes down to the lunch box.
Nope, the possibility of that is very low.
Had something like poisoned food gone past his mouth,
When I did artificial respiration on him,
I would have been poisoned as well.
I see.
Then you already knew that the poison wasn't
introduced through the mouth at the time.
No, I couldn't tell where the poison was introduced
just by giving him a quick scan.
All I know is that if I hadn't done artificial
respiration on him at that time,
He would've died over there.
Hey, say... Can't this boat go faster?
Stop rushing, Officer.
What's that smell?
Hey, hey... Isn't this boat smoking?
It's all because you kept telling us to go faster and faster!
The police sure are slow...
Yeah... But it should be okay.
The culprit is one of those two for sure, so
we just need to keep our eyes on them.
Yeah, the fisherman uncle wasn't here the entire time.
I wouldn't be so sure.
If he found some way to feed Ejiri-san
some slow-acting sleeping pill,
When he came here to pick us up...
He might have pretended to say that Ejiri-san was being strange,
gotten close to him, and pricked him with a poison needle.
Wait a second.
You let the professor go with someone
who could be the murderer?
Yeah. To save Ejiri-san's life, that was the only way.
And to make sure nothing happens, I've already
given the professor my stun watch.
Besides, the professor will call us if anything happens...
A call?
Hello? Professor? Hel...
Hey, Shinichi. We just delivered Ejiri-san to the ambulance.
And how is his condition?
We still can't be sure. We don't even
know what kind of poison it was.
Maybe the doctor can find out what it was
after taking a look at his left wrist.
His left wrist?
Yeah. Even though if was hidden by his
sleeve, there was a scratch mark.
The poison might have been introduced through that scratch.
Oh, yeah. Along with that, we also found
some glue-like substance on his sleeve.
Glue-like? Like plastic glue?
Yeah, but we don't use anything like that in
fishing, so isn't it strange to find it there?
I'll fill you in with the details when I gel back.
I'll see you later.
Hey, Professor!
Glue.
What did he professor say?
Ejiri-san is already in an ambulance
so the professor will be back soon.
That's great.
We can stop worrying about that for now.
But who is the culprit?
That uncle taught me about fish bait,
And that auntie... Look, she helped me get
my marker back when it washed away.
She told me that she got my marker out of the sea using a net.
And that fisherman uncle handed
Ejiri-san to the ambulance safely.
Even though he treated us like kids in the beginning.
Oh, he told you guys not to fool around, right?
Yeah, even if we're kids, we won't be dancing
or carrying carts around here!
Yeah.
Dancing? Carrying carts?
Hey, tell me exactly what the fisherman told you guys.
Let me think.
He said, "Don't get too excited. It'll be bad if you
start to celebrate festivals with one another."
I said, "I won't do something like celebrating a festival here!"
But than he laughed and said, "Go ask the other fishermen, then."
Note: Omatsuri means Celebrate Festivals
No, "omatsuri" here is used as a fishing term. It means...
Marker, glue... And "omatsuri."
I see, so that's what happened.
Conan-kun? Did you figure out who the culprit is?
Yeah. The culprit who used a poisoned
fishhook to fish away Ejiri-san's life,
And the trick behind it.
It's a snapper! It's got to be a snapper this time!
Alright, kids. I think that's enough of your detective games.
No way!
Saying such things... You're going to
destroy the evidence, aren't you?
Hey, now... Ejiri-san did look really uncomfortable
But we don't know if he was poisoned or not.
And besides, Ida-san, who used his boat to send
Ejiri-san to the hospital, is also a suspect.
If he's the culprit, then the evidence might
already be thrown into sea, right?
Yeah...
That's no problem. The professor, who's on
the same boat, is keeping watch on him.
Besides, the possibility of Ida-san
being the culprit is now very slim.
I determined so, when I heard he'd sent
Ejiri-san safely to the ambulance,
And he's on his way back here with the professor.
Really, Conan-kun?
Didn't I say? If Ida-san is the culprit,
He has to get close to an already sleeping Ejiri-san and apply the poison needle.
The poison used was probably some kind of nerve toxin.
Even though he'd have difficulty breathing, he would still
be conscious enough to remember that he was poked.
The culprit would be afraid of that so he wouldn't immediately
deliver the guy to the hospital like that.
Even if he could have done so to relieve suspicion at the moment,
he would have escaped sometime along the way.
Because when the poison is cleared out of Ejiri-san's system and
he can talk again, everything would be revealed immediately.
I see. So that means the culprit has to
be either Shirane-san or Kanetani-san.
Hey. just when is it going to be fixed?
Please stop rushing me, Officer!
Damn. I don't even know what kind of case it is yet.
One of us is the culprit who poisoned Ejiri-san?
Don't say such stupid things.
While it's true that we were both fishing beside Ejiri-san,
Ejiri-san was fishing at the front edge of the cement field.
It's at least ten meters away from us.
How could we poison him then?
It's "omatsuri."
"Omatsuri?"
In fishing term, "omatsuri" means one fishing
line is tangled with another fishing line.
You should know what you would do in that situation.
I see! In order to detangle the fishing line,
the person has to touch the fishhook. The culprit used this trick to poison the victim.
Then, what that fisherman uncle said...
Don't be too excited, it will be really bad
if you and your friend did "omatsuri."
He wasn't trying to make fun of us.
Yeah, the culprit made sure to tangle his
fishing line with Ejiri-san's fishing line,
So when Ejiri-san fried to detangle the lines, a slight pull on
the line would cause the poison hook to scratch his hand.
But, didn't you say it before as well?
Putting the hook in the sea for even a
moment would wash away the poison.
Yeah. It's impossible to have poison stick with the hook as it is,
But it's a different matter if you use plastic glue.
Glue?
Yeah. You put the poison inside the glue than cover
the poison with glue on the surface of the hook.
When the hook reaches the water, the glue will start to dissolve.
And by the time it gets tangled with Ejiri-san's fishing line,
The glue should mostly be gone. which is just perfect timing.
As for the evidence, there's a bit of glue on Ejiri-san's left sleeve.
The professor told me that over the phone.
He also said that there's a scratch mark on his left wrist.
I think that caused Ejiri-san's fishing
rod tripod to fall into the water.
His fishing rod tripod?
Yeah. It probably happened with the fishing line
was pulled to make the hook scratch Ejiri-san.
The pulled fishing line moved the fishing rod, then
pulled the fishing rod and the tripod into the sea.
But, can this really be done?
Intentionally tangling someone's fishing line with your own.
Of course... If there are a lot of poisoned hooks on the line.
If the fishing line floats on the water's surface and follows the
current, it'd be easy for it to get tangled up with a nearby line.
If the fishing hooks used for poisoning are the
kind used for catching a school of small fish.
Even when you pull up the line and see several
hooks, there wouldn't be any suspicion.
I see.
So? Which one is it?
Who did something like that?
Didn't I say it just now? The fishing line followed
the current to tangle up with the line next to it.
Didn't Ayumi-chan's missing marker get collected by someone?
Yeah, by that auntie.
In other words, if Shirane-san at the
right side picked up the marker,
The current is going from left to right.
If the culprit uses this current then...
Correct. it's the person who was fishing between
Ejiri-san and us... Kanetani-san.
The culprit is you. isn't it?
Hey... Is this true, Kanetani-kun?
Nonsense! Don't tell me you believe what these kids are saying.
Besides, why would I want to kill someone on this pier?
Wouldn't I immediately be suspected with so few people here?
Nope, the low number of suspects was actually by accident.
At the time, we all thought something was weird when
Ejiri-san didn't move at all even when he had a bite.
Otherwise, we wouldn't have found out he'd been poisoned.
If we'd left without knowing, the longer the time passed,
the less accurate the estimated time of death would be.
And there would have been more suspects.
Didn't you say that you couldn't catch anything
here so you wanted to fish somewhere else?
I see. You wanted to leave Ejiri-san here alone,
who said he wanted to stay here till nightfall,
Then go fish at some other place.
Then it would look like someone else came
here on a boat to kill Ejiri-san afterwards.
Yeah, there are a lot of witnesses here to prove
that Kanetani-san never got close to Ejiri-san.
But... Wouldn't he have some reaction after he got scratched by the fishing hook?
That's why you had to make sure you'd have perfect timing.
Like when the boat came to pick us up.
Ah! It's the professor.
I get it! The sound of the boat's engine covered
up Ejiri-san's reaction when he was scratched.
And the position of the boat happened to be on
the opposite side of where we were fishing.
Everyone's attention, would be away from Ejiri-san,
making it two birds with one stone.
But kid, you can't say something like this without any evidence.
The evidence is your fishing rod.
Your marker is under the surface
that means it should still be there.
Ejiri-san's fishing rod that was tangled up with yours.
Even though the poisoned glue on the
hooks has already disappeared,
The other thing is hard to wash away.
Something that was loft on the hook
by scratching Ejiri-san... His blood.
Kanetani-kun...
Please... Kanetani-kun, can you tell me why you did it?
Why would you want kill him?
We all went drinking together not too long ago.
I did at exactly because of what that man
said when we went drinking that time.
When you left your seat, I asked him...
The reason for your divorce.
Hmm? Another lover?
Yeah... It happened at the time when
I was starting a new business.
I'd gotten a little stressed, but my wife found out
about my little one-night stand and she left me.
Is that what the said?
Yeah... I didn't care if he had another lover
or one-night stand which led to divorce,
But the line he said right after was
something I just couldn't forgive...
In the end, my business, fishing, and women all turned out well.
Being young and sexy is still the best thing, I guess.
It's a secret to her, though.
Yeah It felt like he broke something in my heart
when he said that... I couldn't accept it.
You were really our Madonna.
That's silly. That man and I got divorced for my sake.
At that time, his business was almost bankrupt.
If he didn't start a new business, he wouldn't be able
to maintain the paychecks for our employees.
But to do that, he needed to loan a huge amount of money.
So he kneeled down to beg me to get divorced.
He said if his new business failed, than the debt collectors
will come and bother me about payments.
I was prepared to stick through it with him, but he's
weak against pressure even if he looks stubborn.
I was thinking of writing a cookbook at the
time anyway, so I agreed in the end.
So that story of another lover and such is just a lie he made up to save face.
But I guess it does make me sad that he said a
woman's better when she's young and sexy...
No, don't be sad.
I believe the young and sexy woman is you.
When the boat was on the open sea, Ejiri-san kept repeating:
"The best fish is the one living freely in the sea, don't you think?"
Stupid.
How can it be... What have I done?
It's all right. He's feeling a lot better already.
Before I arrived, Ejiri-san gave me a call
and he sounded pretty energetic.
He wanted me to relay a message to you.
"You better catch the freshest fish for her today."
I'll forgive you if you do that."
"I'll tell the police and the hospital that I scratched
myself with a hook that caught a blowfish."
"Don't come back to sac me if you can't catch any fish."
ls today a special day or something?
Come to think of it... Today is our marriage anniversary.
Anniversary? Wait. I think I remember... Today is...
What? Don't tell ma you forgot!
Happy Birthday, Professor!
Then, Kojima-kun, you were...
Yeah. I was trying to catch a birthday present for the professor.
No, you can't say it out loud yet.
We even hid it from Ai-chan just so that
we could surprise the professor.
Oh... Sorry, sorry...
So, that's why... That's why these kids wanted
to have a curry party at my place tonight.
I-I'm so touched...
Don't cry. I was hoping to catch a big snapper,
but I only got this weird black fish.
Hey, Isn't this a black snapper?
Black snapper?
This pier's most precious reward! The black snapper!
It's a very expensive fish!
Incredible!
Then, it's too big a waste just to give it to the Professor...
I want to eat it...
All right, Kanetani-kun. It's your turn this time.
Please catch me a bigger fish than his.
You have to make that person understand...
Fish that have been caught can also be fresh, too.
In the wind I sometimes smile, sometimes cry and sometimes fight.
The two of us are just like this standing in front of our dreams.
Our dream is sure to be somewhere in the unknown future.
The colors of the seasons, always repeating let us experience a lot.
I look upon the side of your sleepy face with a smile.
Staying in that moment, this becomes our future.
Even though a lot happened, wasn't it still
pretty nice? Coming here to the sea.
Yeah. I now understand how a fish feels.
Huh? What does that mean?
Human warmth is way too intense for the fish.
Yeah... It is also too warm for me, so I
feel like I'm going to get burned by it
Hey, it's still not moving yet?
Special
If the East is Kudou Shinichi, the renowned
detective of the West is Hattori Heiji.
This tanned high school detective will
do a great deduction with Conan.
The serial murder cases, all done in
the same way in the Osaka area.
Along with the uncovering of the unexpected real culprit,
Until the very very and, it's impossible
to look away from this case!
Detective Conan, Encore Special!
The Serial Murder Case at Naniwa!
Airs on 7/19 Monday, 7pm in the evening!
Next Conan's Hint!
Chocolate cake.
The stage next week is set in Osaka, a one-hour special.
As usual, that tanned is over-energenic.