Today's stage is set at a house of candy.
The trick, a sugary-sweet, simple trap.
Can be solved if you simply think outside the box.
Seeing through the one and only truth,
He looks like a child but has brain of an adult.
His name is: Detective Conan!
So then, the entrance fee for the museum is 500 yen.
Ecriture's cake is, on sale there for half-price!
If we miss this chance, we'll regret it forever.
Sonoko, the desserts won't run away.
I want to run away.
It's here! It's here!
Ecriture
Wow!
Alright. we're going!
Ran!
Sonoko.
Ran! And the glasses kid!
Hurry! Hurry!
It is just like the one in the fairy tale "Hansel and Gretel."
Were these all made from desserts?
Incredible!
There are so many!
All right!
Let's start with conquering the first half for the morning.
You said, "start with."
What does she mean, Ran-neechan?
Separated by lunch time, they'll have
more treats in the afternoon, too.
She says that we should just roughly
fill our stomachs in the morning,
So that we can go at full strength in the afternoon.
I want to go back even more now.
The Candy House the Witch Lives In.
The pastry chefs all have their own display stands.
What should I eat first?
The person in this photo...
Must be that man over there.
Incredible.
Making three different cakes at the same time is unbelievable!
Maeda Tsuyoshi (26)
Pastry Chef
He looks like a Warrior Pastry chef.
Huh? You didn't know?
He actually does have the "Warrior Pastry Chef" nickname.
He's that "Iron Pastry" chef?
Correct!
The one in the middle with the elegant movements
is called "The Prince of Pastries."
Fujino Yasou (30)
Pastry Chef
And then, the inner most pastry chef said to
use magic that makes sweets come to life,
Morimoto Yumi (26)
Pastry Chef
She's known as the "Candy Magician."
Just like a TV idol.
Do you want to try making it?
Eh? Me?
Yes!
How about it, little boy?
Do you want to try it?
It looks pretty fun, Conan-kun.
Nah, that's okay.
Here! Over here!
Yes! Yes, yes!
Don't worry. It's very easy.
Sorry, excuse me!
Yes!
Why don't you do it?
Yes! Yes! Yes!!!
Yes!!!
I'll pass.
It's not every day we come here, so why don't you do it?
Just follow a few very simple steps and you can do it too.
If you finish it, I'll give it to you as a present.
Put a layer of chocolate cream on the cake
roll first. Make sure to get it a bit thick.
Then use this fork to carve through the log pattern.
Try it.
A fork?
In the future, boys who know how to
make pastries will be very popular.
I think that's pretty good. Right, Sonoko?
Yeah, I guess.
She's holding a grudge.
Let me fix that for you, and I'll give it to you when I'm done.
You'll stay until the afternoon half, right?
Yes, of course. Right?
Yeah.
Wow! These candies look alive.
Just as expected from the "Candy Magician."
It looks like it's made from glass.
Thank you.
This kind of invisible feel is the real magic behind the taste.
Here.
Pretty candy tastes better.
I've always dreamed of the day when I can use these desserts,
To take home first prize in a competition.
Onee-san, this is so good.
Thank you.
Which should I pick? It's so hard to choose.
What are you talking about?
Why don't you just pick one from every kind?
Every kind?
Here, don't drop it.
We'll have this first.
This is good too.
So is this.
And this.
Ah, glasses kid! Do you want me to get you something too?
No need. I'm okay...
I can get it myself.
Oh, really?
We'll take this, then.
Dangerous, dangerous.
Are you okay, little boy?
Hashikaki Sachiko (45)
Ecriture Owner
Sorry about that.
I'm so sorry. Your cake is ruined.
No, don't worry about this.
That won't do.
Cake nowadays is also for your eyes to enjoy.
Whether it's the ingredients or the cake itself.
You can eat everything.
Hard to believe, isn't it?
Maeda-kun, can't you be more enthusiastic
and go out to greet the customers?
Why don't you learn something from Fujino-kun?
If greeting people can make things taste better,
I'll do that as much as you want me to.
You're still able to eat?
Of course.
Conan-kun, have you been making your choice all this time?
Yeah.
All right!
I'm going all out in the afternoon half as well!
I think I'm kind of thirsty.
I'm going to get something to drink.
Then, I'll come with you.
Then, please bring me something as well.
I can't eat any more sweet stuff for a while.
Or else Shinichi will probably say,
"I haven't seen you for a while. Did you gain
some weight?" or something like that.
I wouldn't say anything like that.
Why?
I'm a pastry chef, not a magician.
That's good enough, as long as the customers are happy.
Please judge if based on the flavor.
You're too naive. Delicious desserts can be found anywhere.
In the cake and chocolate dominated world of dessert-making,
Candy can only be sold this well due to my good management.
Don't misunderstand.
When I came here yesterday, there wasn't a "make a wood
chocolate cake roll with the customer's help" event.
You're so lucky.
Huh? Sonoko, you were here yesterday too?
No wonder she knows everything.
So here you guys are.
I've been looking for you for a while.
Here.
This is the wood chocolate cake roll you made earlier.
How is it?
He sure fixed it up well.
If you take off the surface, it's just like the ones sold outside.
It looks very delicious.
This is too cruel.
Ecriture
The morning event ended around 12 o'clock.
The body was found around 12:30 p.m.
During that time frame, where were you three?
I let the cashier out for lunch first,
And spent the rest of the time in the kitchen
preparing desserts for the afternoon event.
I went to look for them after I finished their cake.
What about the owner, Hashikaki-san?
Where was she when you left?
She was recording receipt data.
Because she was really concentrating in doing
that, I didn't speak to her when I left.
So after Fujino-san left the building and before
he handed the cake to Conan-kun,
The culprit committed the crime within this short period.
Were you also outside, Maeda-san?
I was told that there was a call for ma in the office.
So from 12:25 pm. until about ten
minutes after, I was in the office.
You seem to remember the time very well.
Ah, that's because I have a habit of looking
at clocks whenever I'm working.
Because I need to use the oven often.
Was there anyone else in the office?
I was the only one.
The rest of the staff was out for lunch.
Is that right?
After Fujino-san left this place,
Someone murdered Hashikaki-san,
And the body was found by Maeda-san
who'd returned from the office.
Is that right?
Yes.
You were the only one who was here at the time, Morimoto-san.
Did you notice anybody entering or leaving this place?
No.
The victim died due to a heavy blow to the back of her head.
The murder weapon might still be in this store.
Make sure to perform a detailed search for the murder weapon.
Yes, sir.
If the culprit is one of these three people,
What is the murder weapon?
And how they got rid of it is the key to this case.
Maeda-san and Fujino-san... One of
you killed the owner, didn't you?
What did you say?
Well, didn't you?
Maeda-san borrowed a large amount of money from the owner,
And Fujino-san, you'd been fighting with the owner
because you wanted to start your own store.
Everyone in the store knew it.
That may be true, but I'm not the only one
who has a problem with the owner.
What do you mean by that?
She's very confident in her skill, so she didn't
want to join the cake making event.
Didn't you have a fight with the owner
only minutes before she was killed?
I could even hear the noise from the outside.
It's true that there was an argument between
the owner and pastry chef, Morimoto-san.
Please judge it based on the flavor.
Morimoto-san who had stayed behind alone
did have a chance to commit the crime.
There's a separator in all three kitchens
so you can't sea her from here.
And there's a tree blocking the view here, as well.
You can't see much from Morimoto-san kitchen.
That means,
Fujino-san who went outside, and Maeda-san
also had a chance to commit the crime.
You went out immediately after I left.
Giving the cake to the kid shouldn't have taken that long.
It's a big layout here. It took me a while to find them.
The timing of your phone call is really perfect too.
By the time I picked it up, the other person had already hung up.
This proves that it was somebody's trick.
It's also possible that you called the office yourself,
And asked yourself to come to there.
What?
As soon as we find the murder weapon,
We'll know who the culprit is.
Out of the three of us, you're the most likely
one to have the chance to kill the owner.
Yeah.
There were so many cakes here before. Incredible!
A woodchip?
Inspector, we couldn't find the murder weapon.
I see. It didn't turn up, eh?
Did you guys ever think of the possibility that
the murder weapon has already been eaten?
So it would disappear.
What do you mean?
Well, this is a candy house.
Using a dessert as a murder weapon isn't that farfetched.
A dessert made into a murder weapon... Who would eat it?
But we should still locate the type of desserts
that could be used as weapons.
Cookies are impossible, it would break on contact.
We don't even need to mention pies.
My chocolate is impossible too.
Because it's too soft.
What?
Are you saying that I used my candy,
Then ate the candy with her blood on it?
Candy might be big enough to be a murder weapon,
That's hard to eat by oneself.
Ah, sorry.
Or...
Maybe it melted!
Throw it in a heating pot so that it melts?
I've never done anything like that.
The person who can distract others from the noise,
And who was alone here... She's the only
one who could commit the crime.
I really didn't do it!
When the detectives finish checking the pots
in your kitchen, everything will be clear.
Is she the culprit?
I've always dreamed of the day when I can use these desserts,
To take home first prize in a competition.
It's hard to believe.
This is.
As expected, it's hand to believe that it was her.
So messy.
Why are there woodchips in the kitchen too?
When I came here yesterday, there wasn't a "make a wood
chocolate cake roll with the customer's help" event.
You're so lucky.
I get it now!
I've been used by you. Huh?
But I won't let you stay freely outside the law.
No, the culprit is...
Ahh...
Ran...
Sonoko?
That's right, it wasn't Morimoto-san.
Sonoko, did that feeling come again?
What?
To let the owner recognize the flavor of her desserts,
She's been working very hard to prepare
candy for the afternoon half.
As evidence, in her kitchen,
There are candies that she wanted the owner to taste.
Take what's in my left hand and show it to everyone, Ran.
It seems,
This doesn't look like something half-way done or a failure.
That little candy is the best proof that...
She wanted to use the flavor of her candy to reach the owner.
I wanted to let the owner try it again.
Then, just who is the murderer?
The real murder is...
The Prince of Pastries, Fujino-san,
You!
First, you used the phone to get Maeda-san to leave,
And used your chance when Morimoto-san
was using the mixer in her kitchen.
I can say for sure that there's no way to
see Morimoto-san's kitchen from here.
Fujino-san used this blind spot.
Good work.
You, too.
I'll leave the rest to you.
Are you saying I hit her with my candy?
Nope.
The murder weapon is the wood chocolate cake roll.
A wood chocolate cake roll? How can such
a soft thing be used as a murder weapon?
Alright. Let me explain, then.
This house is called "The Candy House."
And with a rough look around, it looks
as if you could eat everything.
But in reality, it's just a wooden house
outfitted with a candy surface.
Fujino-san got his inspiration from this.
And used the cake to cover the real weapon.
You're saying that he made the murder weapon
looks like a wood chocolate cake roll?
Correct. The murder weapon is actually a log.
Since you'd thought ahead,
You first hid a wooden log that was slightly smaller
than the wood chocolate cake rolls in the kitchen.
Then, you hid the log under the tray
that carried Conan-kun's cake.
And then you took the log out and swung it at Hashikaki-san.
Where's your evidence?
The evidence is there in the middle,
on your display stand, Fujino-san.
Conan-kun, go take the wood chocolate cake roll here.
Okay.
Are you okay?
Thank you, Onee-san.
Conan-kun, It's on me,
So give everyone half of the wood chocolate cake roll each.
Okay.
Sonoko-neechan, there one that's too hard. I can't cut it.
Huh...?
It looks like there's a real piece of wood inside this one!
Fujino-san hid the real murder weapon
inside the chocolate cream,
And put the cake on the tray. and as he promised Conan-kun,
Walked out the door, with the real wood chocolate cake roll.
The owner was just like a real witch in this candy house.
She promised ma that if I won the pastry competition
and worked here for three years,
I could start my own business.
But even though I won the competition with the wood
chocolate cake roll and worked for three years,
Even though I'd never complained and
accepted her abuse for three years,
That woman saw that I was popular and kept putting
off my wish to start my own business.
She told me she could make ma stop
making my wood chocolate cake roll.
She even said that we'd never agreed
on something like my business plan!
I...
We'll continue this at the police station.
Shattering his dream of starting a business,
And taking away the wood chocolate cake roll
which has been with him from the start...
The owner was exactly like the witch in "Hansel and Gretel,"
Who lured children into the forest to eat them.
In the wind I sometimes smile, sometimes cry, and sometimes fight.
The two of us are just like this standing in front of our dreams.
Our dream is sure to be somewhere in the unknown future.
The colors of the seasons, always repeating let us experience a lot.
I look upon the side of your sleepy face with a smile.
Staying in that moment, this becomes our future.
Ecriture
Oh, no.
AH!!!
My chocolate cake!
It's ruined! What a shock!
Don't worry.
If will be the same in your stomach anyways.
That's true...
Of course not!
Here...
We can go to another shop that has good
chocolate cake next time, right?
Ah! That's right.
I remember, close to this station,
There's a delicious cake-baking shop.
Then let's hurry.
Wait a second. Right now?!
Hey, hey... For real?
If my deduction is right,
Something is about to happen right now.
I won't let anything happen.
I won't!
Next Conan: A Lucky Man's Suspense!
Meitantei Conan was presented by the following sponsors.
Next Conan's Hint:
Rumors.
Next time also has strange title.
The lucky people should be Inspector Megure and uncle...