Roulette, a drawing, and a lottery.
The lucky man who's envied by all.
Something's bound to happen if you're to lucky.
Seeing through to the one and only truth,
He looks like a child but has the brain of an adult.
His name is: Detective Conan!
Meitantei Conan is brought to you by the following sponsors.
First Prize
First prize for the red ball.
Second prize for the blue ball.
Third prize for the yellow ball.
I want to at least get the third prize.
Third prize's yellow ball, come on out!
It's white.
Congratulations! You won a pack of tissues!
Here.
Don't be so sad, Genta-kun.
Things can't always go the way you want.
Yeah, Genta-kun.
But... I really wanted those prizes...
Third Prize
At least the third prize digital camera.
Congratulations! You've won third prize!
Oh, it's him!
Oowada Yokoto (30)
Doctor
Isn't that Oowada-sensei?
Sensei's won again!
You guys know him?
He's a doctor in Beika Central Hospital.
Ah, a doctor?
An incredible doctor!
He's enthusiastic and skilled.
He's also really kind to everybody.
No one would say anything bad about him.
Ah! You should go see him sometime, too, Conan.
Yup, yup.
But there's nothing wrong with me...
Oh, Ayumi-chan.
You said he won again, didn't you?
Yeah. Let me see, I think it was last week...
Ah! So pretty!
Sensei won!
The lottery, eh? That's lucky.
Like nothing else.
I heard my mom saying something about him winning
the Union Bear drawing last week, too.
For a year's supply of beer.
That means that in the span of one week, Oowada-sensei
won the lottery, the roulette and even the beer drawing.
Mouri Detective Agency
I'm back.
All right!
Looks like I won a year's supply of beer!
What is this? The famous Union Beer...
Uncle, what happened to Union Beer?
And I thought it was a winning notice.
To think that it is only an apology notice saying that
the drawings being postponed until next month.
Honestly...
The drawings delayed?
It's true!
But that would mean Oowada-sensei's winnings are...
A Lucky Man's Suspense
Oowada-sensei didn't really win?
Yeah, there's no way he could've won.
The drawing hasn't even started yet.
It's true.
If this win is a lie, the others should also be suspected as such.
"The others?"
But winning the lottery is true.
Winning the roulette is also true.
Didn't you see it yourself, Conan?
I sure didn't.
You guys didn't see it... either...
The moment of the win.
Eh? Cheating?
First Prize
Cover for me for a second.
Let's go talk somewhere else.
It's true. I fixed the winning.
All right, go ahead.
Congratulations! You've won third prize!
In other words..
You cheated.
How sneaky!
I knew it.
Ah, but sensei didn't know about it.
The one who asked me to do it was his wife.
Eh? The doctor's wife asked you to do it?
Yeah. She said that if the doctor came
by, let him at least win third prize.
She said that because of his work, he's lost
confidence and has been very depressed.
She wanted to cheer him up somehow.
Oowada-sensei saved my life not too long ago, too...
So I wanted to return the favor.
So, it's about returning a favor?
But cheating is still bad.
That prize could've been won by somebody else.
No, his wife gave me that digital camera
when she came to ask for my help.
What? She prepared it herself?
In other words, his wife bought and brought the camera here,
Until her husband, Oowada-sensei, came to collect it.
Yeah.
Even though it was cheating, no one got hurt from it.
If you put it that way, it can't be considered a crime.
Oowada
I asked him?
I never did anything like that.
But, he said that the doctor's wife asked him to do it.
First of all, my husband's work is going very smoothly.
So there's no way that he's lacking confidence or depressed.
Nope, that's definitely wrong.
Somehow, it's a totally different story.
Yeah.
Very strange.
So, how about that Union Beer drawing? Is that true?
I heard a rumor like that was going
around but that's a mistake, too.
My husband and I don't drink at all.
There's no reason for him to enter a drawing
for a one-year supply of beer.
He didn't even enter the drawing?
Not the drawing or the roulette. Couldn't it be another Oowada?
What's going on here?
But really, the-person who asked
me to do it was the doctor's wife.
No doubt about it.
She told me that she was the Beika Central
Hospital, Doctor Oowada's wife.
She's tall, slender, and very pretty.
What would I gain by lying, anyway?
I'm very busy, so I'll be off.
She's tall...
Slender and very pretty?
Completely different.
No matter. The case is slowly getting clearer.
It looks like the lottery was the only true win.
Roulette was won by cheating and the bear
drawing is nothing but a baseless lie.
This is the work of someone, perhaps that tall and skinny lady,
To make other people believe that the doctor's lucky.
But why would she want to do something so weird?
She even went and bought the prize for the roulette.
That's the problem.
What would she get in return for making
the doctor become a lucky man?
Congratulations! You've won a pack of tissues!
There's got to be a reason. Some sort of goal.
It's so hard. There's no way we can win.
But the Oowada-sensei from Beika Central Hospital did...
I heard he won the third prize.
And the beer drawing.
The doctor keeps taking our luck, again and again.
But you know, people say that if you're too lucky,
Everyone around you'll get jealous and that will cause bad luck.
Envied by everyone?
Very possible! People's jealousy can be very scary sometimes.
For sure.
Too much luck can make everyone jealous.
Could that woman's goal be...
Everybody thinks very highly of Oowada-sensei, right?
Why are you asking that again?
Like I said, nobody would say anything bad about him. Right?
Yeah.
Oowada-sensei is someone who wouldn't
have any previous trouble with anybody.
That's why they have to set some foundation for their future plan.
What is it, Conan-kun?
Maybe that woman wanted to... Create a forest.
"Forest?"
What do yo mean by "forest?"
In other words,
There should be a lot of other rumors
about Oowada-sensei's good fortune.
"Others" meaning“?
And than, there's the saying that if you're
too lucky, people will get jealous of you.
The person who's spreading the rumors
is probably that skinny, pretty lady.
You three split up and try to find out where
that lady came from and what she does.
I'll investigate this from another direction.
Why are you acting like this all of the sudden?
If my deduction is correct, a case will happen very soon!
Even though he said to find out about that lady...
Oowada-sensei? The one from Beika Central Hospital?
Yeah! Yeah!
Oowada?
I heard that when he was digging in his backyard,
he dug up a bunch of gold bricks.
Wow, that's so lucky!
A bit too lucky!
People around him are actually getting pretty jealous of him.
Err... Just? now, where did you hear that?
About everyone being jealous of Oowada-sensei?
One hundred million yen! He found a wallet
with one hundred million yen inside?
Oowada-sensei did?
Sounds like it!
When he returned it, he got five million yen as reward.
That's just too lucky!
Who did you hear that from?
I think I heard it from a customer.
Was it a tall and skinny lady?
Why do you say?
That's because...
Even though it's not clear yet, it looks
like something big is about to happen.
Oh? People who don't like Oowada-sensei?
It's a woman. She's tall and skinny..
There's no body who doesn't like the doctor in this world.
Whether it's his patients or those of us who work with him
Oowada-sensei is someone that everyone loves!
Thank you.
Later, then!
Hello!
Ah, Oowada-sensei.
How are you feeling lately?
Doing well, thanks.
That's great. But be careful not to force yourself too much.
I'm fine, thanks to you.
Take care, then.
Maybe it's not the people in the hospital.
Hiroiki-kun, you can't run in the hospital like that.
So... Sorry.
But it's good to see that you've completely recovered!
Oowada-sensei was grabbed by the collar?
Yeah, using force on such a nice doctor.
Can you believe that kind of person?
It was actually a woman! Imagine my surprise.
Hey, uncles! You were saying a woman
grabbed Oowada-sensei by the collar?
Yeah.
When?
About a month ago, I think.
Shiina-san, Shiina-san.
Please calm down, Shiina-san.
Please, Shiina-san.
Her name is Shiina?
She is tall and skinny.
It could be her, then.
Come to think of it, she was wearing funeral dress.
Funeral dress?
It's me. I've found the woman who has been spreading the rumors.
Mitsuhiko.
Conan-kun, look! The one on the right.
I heard that she's Shiina akiko-san living
in the Sanchou apartment building
Shiina Akiko (30)
House Wife
Shiina?
I heard that we found her.
She's the one on the right.
I think I've seen her somewhere before.
Mama, come find me!
Wait for me!
Hey, Conan.
It's so good to see Shiina-san cheerful again.
That's true.
If she keeps going like this, I thought she'd collapse
just like that when her husband passed away.
Hey, Aunties.
Is that auntie's husband dead?
Yes, from a car accident one month ago.
He was brought to Central Hospital immediately, but...
That's her motive.
Actually, I heard it was already too late
by the time the ambulance got to him.
So does that mean that it wasn't the doctor's fault?
Just what could that woman be planning?
She looks like your everyday, kind mom.
Who is she?
Conan-kun.
What'd you ask them?
I remember now!
I knew that I'd seen her somewhere before.
It was at that time.
The time Oowada-sensei won.
How can he still smile? Like nothing has happened.
He's not guilty at all... He even looks happy!
So that's what happened.
She probably made her decision at that time.
Let's go home.
But didn't you say a case would happen soon?
Nothing will happen. Looks like I jumped to conclusions.
Jumped to conclusions?
But why would that lady spread all those rumors?
Yeah?
I heard that one of her hobbies is lying to people.
Hobby?
Honestly, troublesome eh?
What do you mean "Honestly?" Who's more troublesome, huh?
So Conan-kun can be wrong sometimes, too.
Yeah.
Yeah, so... Let's go, let's go.
Nothing will happen. I promise that.
Mouri Detective Agency
Where do you think you're going at this time of the night, Conan?
To the Professor's house. I forgot something over there.
Come back soon.
Okay.
Even if you beat Oowada-sensei to death, will
that make you feel better, Shiina-san?
I'm Mouri, a private detective.
I've come across a few of the strange
rumors about Oowada-sensei.
I did a little investigating and came
to suspect you, Shiina Akiko-san
I heard that you lost your husband in a car accident a month ago.
When he was transported by ambulance to Beika Central Hospital,
It was clear to anyone that he was beyond help...
Still, Oowada-sensei who was on duty
encouraged your husband to hold on.
Don't worry, we'll save you! Just hold on!
He did everything he possibly could to save your husband's life.
In Operation
Oowada-sensei did nothing wrong.
I think you know that, as well. Even so..
Why didn't you save him?
Why? Why?!
That hatred should have been aimed
at the person who hit your husband,
But because it was a hit-and-run, you
didn't even know whom to target.
Needing an outlet to release your hatred and
anger, you turned on Oowada-sensei.
And thus created an unreasonable sense of malice towards him.
That bitterness grew more intense as the time went by.
How can he still smile? Like nothing has happened.
He's not guilty at all... He even looks happy!
At that moment, you felt that he was unforgivable
and created the idea of killing him.
However, you knew that nobody had
anything against Oowada-sensei.
If you killed him, you'd be suspected immediately,
After all, a lot of people saw you grabbing
Oowada-sensei by his collar?
You wanted to kill Oowada-sensei
but couldn't risk being arrested.
If you're arrested, your two little
children would be left parentless.
And that's when you thought up the idea...
Of spreading rumors about Oowada-sensei's good fortune.
If Oowada-sensei were too lucky, there'd
be people who would get jealous of him.
Your goal was to make everyone around you think that way.
But not just by spreading rumors. You even took
the extra step to increase the lie's believability.
With this foundation, if you attack Oowada-sensei
somewhere on the street,
Then the police will start thinking,
If the victim was targeted by a lot of people,
it'll be very hard to find the criminal.
Yes, you wanted to create as many suspects as possible,
Who might have a motive to kill Oowada-sensei.
So you, the only one who really had a motive, could easily mix in.
The easiest place to hide a tree is in a forest.
Since there was no forest, you created one.
The reason you spread those rumors was
to create a forest you could hide in.
Anything wrong with my deduction?
But Shiina-san, no matter what kind of steps you take to hide it,
The committing of a crime will always be uncovered.
But, I'm glad that I stopped you in time.
Because nothing has happened.
Nothing has officially happened,
So, you can still go back.
Now, why don't you head home?
Before those cute kids of yours wake up.
Mouri-san.
I'll never do anything stupid like this anymore.
I believe you. It's okay.
I believe you can beat back that sadness you feel inside.
In the wind I sometimes smile, sometimes cry and sometimes fight.
The two of us are just like this standing in front of our dreams.
Our dream is sure to be somewhere in the unknown future.
The colors of the seasons, always repeating let us experience a lot.
I look upon the side of your sleepy face with a smile.
Staying in that moment, this becomes our future.
Did you see yesterday's Kamen Yaiba?
Yeah, the Super Yaiba kick was incredible!
Of course.
Morning, everyone!
Good morning!
Let today be a good happy day, too!
Okay!
Morning!
Nothing happened. Nothing at all.
Why does it feel like I did something
I don't remember doing again?
Oh. well...
The world's luckiest guy should be this one.
Next Episode
Gyadorin!
A handgun?
Just what in the world is going on?
We've got to getaway from here fast!
Genta-kun! Hurry, hurry!
It's game over... Now.
Next Conan: Running Away in a Game.
Next Conan's Hint!
Name tag.
The Detective Boys take the center stage next time.
It'll melt if we don't hurry!
But it's not ice cream.