Today's main characters are the Detective boys.
Who get into trouble due to fiddling
with unreleased game software.
Seeing through to the one and only truth,
He looks like a child but the has intelligence of an adult.
His name is: Detective Conan!
Ah! Over there! I can see it!
That's the company that made Gyadorin?
It is! Incredible!
Isn't it?
GYADORIN
That's so cool!
I'm so excited.
So this is the game you guys are crazy about.
This Gya... Gya... Gyado?
Gyadorin!
And here's the company that made the Gyadorin
game software: Shining Corporation!
Remember this by now, seriously, Conan!
Gyadorin is a super hot game right now.
GYADORİN
This is episode one.
Conan-Kun, you are the only one in class who still doesn't know about this game.
I don't really care.
The second episode will go on sale next week.
The seven mysteries that weren't solved in episode one,
Will be completely resolved in episode two.
I really want to know soon.
Even just one of the seven mysteries would be good.
Please tell us, Gyadorin!
Hey! You guys! Where do you think you're going?
Running away in a Game
What are you kids doing?
Umm... Hey. hey... Onee-chan,
Can you tell us about the seven mysteries in Gyadorin 2?
Even one would be enough.
Hachisuga Yukari (25)
Shining Corp's receptionist
I'm afraid I can't do that.
Just a hint, then. Please!
I'm sorry.
You'll have to wait for the release date.
Teitan Elementary School first grade B class's Kojima Genta-kun.
Onee-chan... Do you know me?
Of course, you're famous.
Impossible.
The name tag on the bag.
I see.
No! I can't hold it anymore...
You have to pee?
Honestly, Genta-kun.
It's not just the game. I can't even wait for the toilet now.
Onee-chan, let me borrow the restroom!
Little boy!!!
Hey!
G-Genta-kun.
This is bad, this is bad... Gotta hurry!
I can't hold it anymore... Where is it?
What are you guys doing?
You can't come in here.
But I can't hold it anymore! I need to use the toilet!
Genta-kun!
Wait a second!
Dont talk to me...
Hey!
Where is it?
Genta!
Hey!
It'll come out if I keep running. I can't run anymore.
Wait a second!
I can't believe it!
No, it's a dead and!
Faster! Faster!
To-toilet.
Where did they go?
Hurry! Hurry!
Is here okay?
Which floor is the washroom on?
Come in.
Director Michiba.
The order for Gyadorin 2 has already surpassed 2 million.
Michiba Nobukası (36)
Shining Corp's President
It'll definitely be a bigger success than episode one.
Of course.
I don't even know how many years this
little thing has sucked up my life.
If we can't sell it, then it's all over for me.
You're the genius producer Michiba Nobukasu.
You're a super star in the world of gaming!
You even took the risk of completely writing the script.
So, let's go on with the final check.
To make sure that nothing's missed right?
Michiba, both episodes one and two of Gyadorin were my ideas.
They're my work from when I was a student.
Kobayashi Shinzi (36)
Michiba's friend
You stole my work!
So, what are you trying to say?
I'm going to tell the media that Gyadorin is a stolen product.
I'll see you in court.
Damn.
What are you doing?
You think I'll let you do that?
Kobayashi was murdered...
Just the night before yesterday, in this very room.
Who are you?
Me?
I'm the detective Kobayashi hired.
Kobayashi also held evidence of you stealing his work.
It'll be quite useful in court.
I was hired to observe and collect evidence against you.
Looks like I didn't waste my time.
How about 200 million?
In exchange for this game disc of stolen ideas.
W-what are you saying?
Don't come any closer!
You still have the gun that killed Kobayashi, right?
I forgot to say this.
If something happens to me,
This master disc will be automatically published.
200 million.
That's pocket money for someone who's
earned billions from Gyadorin,
I'll say this first.
It's non-negotiable.
I got it.
As expected from the genius President Michiba.
Who would?!
What are you doing?
What are you..?
Just where did those kids go?
Looks like he's gone.
Huh? Where's Genta-kun?
Where's the master disc? Say it!
Or do you want to die along with it?
Engine refreshed. Thank goodness!
Huh? Where am I?
What a fancy room!
Game software?
Gyadorin 2...
No way! It's Gyadorin 2!
Genta-kun.
Where did you go? We were so worried.
The guard is pretty upset and looking for you everywhere.
What are you doing?
We got to get out of here quick!
Genta-kun! Hurry! Hurry!
K-kids?
Wait, you misunderstand!
Wait a sec!
What's happening?
Where do we go?
Di-Director?
Capture them! Quick!
They stole Gyadorin 2.
What?!
Go down the emergency stairs. I'll be right after you!
Yes.
It's over if someone sees that disc.
Hurry! Hurry!
Conan-kun! Hurry! Hurry!
Move it! Move it!
Hey...
Hold it!
Where did they go?
Outside. They went outside!
I got it!
A handgun?
What's going on?
Alright.
I'm sorry, uncle.
What are you doing? Are you with those kids?
Whatever, get out of here.
I'm sorry. They got away.
What?
All three of them are riding bicycles.
What do they think they're doing?
Those little brats! How dare they steal an unpublished game.
Is this true?
Where did those kids come from?
I don't know.
I think it was Teitan Elementary School
first grade B class's Kojima Genta-kun.
Kojima Genta from Teitan Elementary School?
Should we call the police?
That's no good, I'll go myself.
You guys get back to work.
Yes, sir.
It's Gyadorin 2 that people are going crazy to get.
They'll definitely try to play it as soon as possible.
If that happens, we're screwed.
This Kojima Genta from Teitan Elementary
School... Give me his address immediately!
I think I know what happened.
Make your way there as soon as you find it.
Hurry! B!
"B?" Is that the name of his accomplice?
To get to Beika City, kids would usually take thirty minutes.
If they're not home in thirty minutes...
Damn, this would be the bad time coincidentally that
the communication badges are in for repair.
This is bad. Those three are in danger.
Genta, Mitsuhiko, Ayumi!
Beika Station
Beika Station! Beika Station!
Please remember to collect all of your
belongings before getting off.
Hurry!
Here!
Cars Cannot Enter
What should we do? That uncle looked really mad.
I just used the toilet. Why are they so angry?
All this running is making me hungry.
It's all because Genta-kun broke info the
building without permission. Honestly...
What's this?
What is it, Genta-kun?
Well... I found this.
This...
This is Gyadorin 2!
No way!
I-it's real!
This is Gyadorin for sure! Although it's the evaluation copy.
I-is it?
Genta-kun? Just what's going on with this?
"Just what's going on with this...?"
I found it in the bag.
In the bag? How?
"How...?" I don't know where it got mixed in...
Ah! That really fancy room!
I see! That's why they were chasing us like crazy.
Hold it! Hey!
So it's because of this
Genta-kun! Now's not the time to look carefree.
Yeah!
No matter the reason, this was an act of theft.
Because you took an unreleased game.
A thief? Me?
That's why you were being chased.
Elementary school thief Kojima Genta who
is on the wanted list was arrested.
Other than Gyadorin 2, other crimes he
has committed were uncovered as well.
Genta-kun!
Genta!
Kojima Genta!
We've finished our investigation.
The person who broke the principal's vase was you, wasn't it!
Me?
You didn't hand in your homework for three consecutive
days and skipped a student cleaning day.
We also know that you didn't wash your hands before lunch!
Don't "Ah-u, ah-u" me. Speak clearly!
The criminal is you! Hurry up and admit it!
Kojima Genta!
I'm sorry...
You should go and confess, Genta-kun.
But before that, I want to eat one last helping of eel rice.
My mom said today's dinner is eel rice.
It's not too late if we go after that, right?
It's been a little over an hour.
Those people probably think that Genta and
them already saw what's on the disc.
If those three are discovered by them...
They're back!
Hey!
A car!
Everyone! Get away! Get away!
That guy definitely isn't going to forgive me.
Run!
Ayumi-chan, hurry!
Wait!
TAKE THIS!!!
Hey, hold on.
Use that gun to kill them, B...
H-hurry! Go...
It was B just now, the accomplice he was talking about.
That B is now chasing after Genta-kun
and everyone else with a gun.
Genta, Mitsuhiko, Ayumi!
Where? Where did you run to?
Where did those three run off to?
Genta-kun, hurry!
I'm so hungry... I can't move.
Whose fault was it again that we got into this?
Anyway, let's just return the game back to its original place.
And than we'll apologize. Let's go.
No one's here.
It was dropped here.
Then put it there.
Okay.
Ready? Start!
I'm sorry.
They'll forgive us for sure with this.
Yeah, Genta-kun?
Before we go back, can we peek at Gyadorin 2 for just a second?
We can't. No way!
What are you doing?
We'll just check out the seven mysteries...
It'll just take a second.
The seven mysteries?
Just a little peek.
Michiba, both episodes one and two of Gyadorin were my ideas.
What is this?
I'll see you in court.
You think I'll let you do that?
What are you doing? Michiba?
You bastard!
You didn't just steal my Gyadorin.
You didn't even regret it. And now you want to kill me!
You haven't changed. You've been like
this since you were a student!
Shut up!
Do you know how much I put into this?
No way! That was low, Michiba!
No way!
It's the Onee-chan at the reception desk.
That's right, it's me.
Since you saw this disc,
You're going to have to die, right here.
No. This isn't happening!
No way! My mom is waiting for me to come and eat my eel rice.
Is she? That's too bad, Kojima Genta-kun.
I thought it was you!
Hachisuga Yukari.
Co-Conan!
Conan-kun!
When Michiba called you B, it got me thinking
"Could 'B' be eight?"
"B" as in "bee?"
Receptionist
Hachisuga's character which is number
"eight" sounds like the insect "bee."
So, I thought "B" might be your nickname.
And you're probably President Michiba's...
Yes. We're getting married soon.
To keep our wealth and position in place, I'd do anything.
Anything!
Conan-kun!
Don't do it, Onee-chan!
Is that okay?
What we talked about just now was all overheard by the police.
A ce-cellphone?
Hachisuga Yukari, you're under arrest
for attempted murder on site.
Game over.
So Hachisuga Yukari and President Michiba were arrested.
The detective that Michiba was holding was also found.
And thus, the case came to an end.
Genta and them who got into trouble
by doing things without permission,
That's probably a lesson enough, too.
In the wind I sometimes smile, sometimes cry and sometimes fight.
The two of us are just like this standing in front of our dreams.
Our dream is sure to be somewhere in the unknown future.
The colors of the seasons, always repeating let us experience a lot.
I look upon the side your sleepy face with a smile.
Staying in that moment, this becomes our future.
If I hadn't wanted to go to the toilet, this
case would've never been solved.
Yeah, that's true.
That's great, Genta-kun.
Yup, the carrier of justice.
Starting from today, I'll also use my
power to punish all the bad people.
Detective Boys. Overwhelming victory!
Hey. hey! They didn't learn their lesson at all.
O-Oh no!
Next Episode
That is..?
A Jaguar uniform!
"The police?"
How did you know that?
Next Conan: A Course Without Protest (Part 1)
Next Conan's Hint!
Tennis ball!
Next week is Athens!
Go Japan!
And the week after is Okinawa!
Isn't that bit too sly?