We're in Okinawa Today.
An interview between Uncle and a baseball
player becomes a murder mystery!
Seeing through to the one and only truth,
He looks like a child but has the brain of an adult.
His name is: Detective Conan!
You haven't changed one bit, Nose.
You still have the habit of leaning your head
towards the right side when you're running.
Mo... Motoyama. What are you doing here?
It's only a bit after 9:30.
Didn't I tell you on the phone last night?
As long as it's for you... I'd fly aver right away.
Just like Hideyoshi.
A Course Without Protest. (Part 1)
Half a day before Tokyo
What? You're going to Okinawa tomorrow?
Why didn't I hear anything about this?
Didn't I tell you? I thought you knew.
The professional baseball team the
Jaguars' MVP, Nose Toshizou.
Nichiuri TV arranged for me to talk
with Nose-senshu face to face.
But why did they pick you, Uncle?
A professional baseball player and a detective
don't have too much in common.
Idiot.
Nose-senshu is one of few pitchers in pro-baseball
who plays the game using his head.
I'll use his ability to see through his opponents hearts,
To challenge my deduction skills.
But can you successfully talk to him?
Nose-senshu is famous for being hard to talk to.
Not to worry.
This sports reporter who has a good relationship
with Nose-senshu will also be joining us.
I'm here in Miyazaki with Kogure-senshu
who's doing some independent training.
To increase the Falcons' chance of winning.
We can feel the determination oozing from him.
Thank you very much.
And Motoyama-san will be talking with
Nose-senshu tomorrow in Okinawa.
Let's hope that it'll be just as interesting as today.
Don't worry. Nose-kun and I are good friends.
And we'll also be joined by the famous
detective Mouri Kogorou-san.
Told you.
When's your flight tomorrow?
It should be leaving from Haneda airport
at 6:35 tomorrow morning.
Because Nose-senshu only has the
morning free in his busy schedule.
Eh?! Doesn't that mean that we'll
have to wake up before five?
What?
Then we should get prepared and
go to sleep early too, Conan-kun.
Yeah.
Hey, hey... I'm the only one who's going.
Oh, yeah!
Let's use this time to go buy something
from the convenience store.
Yeah! Let's go! Let's go!
We've got to hurry or we won't make it in time.
It's all because Dad didn't tell us earlier.
He's being mean, isn't he?
Heeeeeeey!
Same Day Miyazaki
Hey, Nose. Did you see it?
My interview that just ran.
Motoyama Masaharu
Sports Reporter
Oh, the on Nichiuri TV night news
The Sports Corner segment that starts at 6:30, right?
That's it.
Same Time Okinawa
Sorry. I just happened to be out eating and didn't catch it.
Nose Toshizou
Pro Baseball Player
I'm just about to go train with some younger
players and probably have a few drinks.
Was there something you needed?
Not really. I just wanted to thank you in advance for tomorrow's talk.
I'm the one who should thank you for covering for me.
In case Mouri Kogorou asks any strange questions,
please follow up well to save me.
Don't be late for your flight tomorrow, Motoyama.
You were never very good at waking up early.
Don't worry. My Flight's at 8:15 tomorrow.
As long as it's for you... I'd fly over right away.
Just like Hideyoshi.
Hideyoshi?
So I'm Nobunago, huh?
It's true that it was me who introduced you to the
television aspect of sports after you retired.
But that's because we were on the same team.
You don't have to keep such a small favor on your mind.
Oh, the younger players are calling for me.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Yeah. Don't drink too much!
You have a chance of breaking the Japanese
record with your games so for.
Yeah.
"Nobunaga" you say...
You're more like Mitsuhide.
Number 931 (Tokyo Okinawa)
Honestly.
You still tugged alone in the end.
It's fine. We called the people at the TV station last night.
Didn't they agree to pay for both me and Conan-kun?
It's all because of you guys that my status
was downgraded to economy class.
And Okinawan food was great that last time we went.
Drinking and partying with beautiful Okinawan women...
My perfect plan is... Completely ruined.
Damnit!
Don't worry.
We'll only take a few pictures with the digital
camera. We won't interfere with your work.
Eh? You got a digital camera?
Yeah.
It's the one Dad won in the draw.
Sorry. I' m sorry!
Thank you very much!
Why did you bring tennis balls along?
The boys from our school baseball team
called lost night after watching TV.
They wanted me to ask for some Nose-senshu's autography.
I told them that we didn't have any nice paper for
autographs, but they said that anything would do.
So I brought along some tennis balls that Sonoko gave me.
Because the baseball you had was all covered in mud, Dad.
Bringing four balls means that there's
four baseball players in your class?
Actually, only three are in the baseball
club. The other one's for me.
It's for Eri, isn't it?
She's a Jaguar fan too.
Right. So please.
Would you please get mom's as well?
No way.
Asking a professional baseball player
to autograph a tennis ball.
How do you expect me to do something so embarrassing?
That's true.
Okinawa (Naha Airport)
I've been waiting for you, Mouri-san.
I'm Teranishi from Okinowa's Nichiuri TV.
Thank you for taking care of my
daughter and him as well today.
Your daughter? Where is she?
Hey! Where are you guys going?
I'm going to see if I can buy some autograph paper.
Honestly...
By the way what, happened to what
we spoke about lost time?
Ah, that one at night?
I've already reserved some seats at a very nice place.
No, no... I'm afraid we'll have to cancel that tonight.
I was actually asking about that other thing.
Ah, that thing.
I've asked our guest Motoyama-san
And have gotten it quite successfully.
Thank you for that.
Speaking of which... Is Motoyama-san
already here from Miyazaki?
Not yet. His plane won't be here until 9:50.
We still have to wait 30 more minutes.
That's the only plane that goes from Miyazaki to Okinawa.
Then, could you take us to the hotel where
we'll be interviewing Nose-senshu first?
Not a problem... But even if you go,
Nose-senshu isn't there yet, either.
Why?
Every morning between 9 o'clock and 10
o'clock is when he does his jogging.
He's probably... Jogging somewhere
around the hotel right now.
Okinawa (Naha City)
You knew, right?
Hideyoshi's counterattack.
That's right.
What he did to Mitsuhide who killed
Nobunaga to take over the world?
Rushing from Okayama to Kyouto in only three days.
Counterattacks have always been Hideyoshi's best skill.
Nose.
I'm sorry, but I can't let you have this world.
Okinawa (Naha Airport)
Hey, how long are you going to look around?
Motoyama-san plane should be here anytime now.
But there's no autograph paper anywhere!
I got it.
I'll help you get your friends those autographs.
Really? Mom's too, right?
No can do.
Why not?
Do you know anywhere around here
that sells autograph paper?
Autograph paper?
Let's see. The closest one...
C mon, Dad...
Ah. He's here! He's here!
Motoyama-san. This way, this way!
Sorry for making you all wait so long.
Pleased to meet you. I'm detective Mouri Kogorou.
Motoyama Masaharu. I've heard
about you from time to time.
I'm his daughter.
I'm sorry, but we don't have much time.
Let's finish the introductions in the car.
Okay.
All right. Let's go.
Okinawa is so nice!
But with this rain...
Hey, we're going, kid!
Motoyama-san looks really easy to talk to.
Maybe he can help me get Nose-san's autograph.
Yeah.
It looks like Nose hasn't returned to the hotel yet.
Maybe he got tired while jogging and took
a rest somewhere. He's getting a little old.
I'm joking.
You'll get a cold if you sleep there.
That' s...!
A Jaguar uniform.
Hold on... Conan-kun...
Hey! Isn't that Nose-san?
No way.
Nose-san?
Ah! This is terrible!
Call the ambulance and the police fast!
"The police?"
Hey! Isn't that Nose-san?
No way.
Nose-san?
Ah! This is terrible!
Call the ambulance and the police fast!
"The police?"
No. There's no use calling for on ambulance.
Nose-san's already died from a stab wound in his stomach.
Oh, no!
Ran, you've got the digital camera right?
I'll take pictures of the scene of the
crime before the police come.
Umm... Digital camera, digital camera.
Schedule
Go it!
Did you find it yet, Ran? Hurry up!
Okay.
Take two or three pictures from the top.
Be careful not to step in the grass.
What is it, Ran?
It's just that...
I wanted to bring Mom some pictures of
Nose-senshu in this signature poses.
But now I'm taking this kind...
I'm sorry. That's all right.
I'll do it. You can go back to the car.
Isn't this Nose from the Jaguars?
I heard on TV that he was doing independent training here.
The estimated time at death is around 9:30 this morning.
Cause off death is excessive blood loss due
to the stub wound on the stomach.
And it looks like we haven't found the murder weapon yet.
So, who discovered the body?
I think it's...
Who discovered the body?
We did.
Our car just happened to pass by this area
and found Nose-senshu lying there.
He was probably attacked while jogging.
Hmm... Aren't you?
That famous detective!
You guys know me?
Mouri Kogorou-san, right?
You're very famous in Okinawa.
We heard that you can eat a lot.
Right?
Yeah!
That's because of Uncle and Hattori's
eating contest in Okinawa lust time.
This way, the case is just like it's already solved.
We're counting on you.
Do these guys really mean that?
But I know someone who's better than Uncle!
Sports reporter Motoyama-san.
What are you talking about, kid?
Because when we first saw Nose-senshu
The rain had already washed the blood.
If you don't get close and look carefully enough, you'd
never notice that he'd been stabbed in his stomach.
And for someone who knew about Nose-son's jogging
Wouldn't they usually think that Nose-san
was sick and had collapsed?
You hadn't even left the car, but you
told us to call the police anyway.
Call the ambulance and the police fast!
That deduction is even better than Holmes could have made.
But how did you know? That this is a murder case.
Come to think of it, I do remember you saying that
before I even saw Nose-son's stab wound.
It was that phone call.
A phone call?
When I finished taping yesterday's show.
I culled Nose from the Miyazaki hotel and he told me
That some anti-Jaguar mun had
been harassing him by phone.
He was very angry about it.
So when I saw Nose lying there, my mind immediately
connected the two things together.
Is that true?
Even if you guys suspect me, you're
just wasting your energy.
I couldn't have committed this crime.
Why would you say that?
Because of Nose's estimated time of death.
Wasn't it this morning around 9:30?
I was just leaving from Miyazaki at 8:15.
And I was on the plane that arrived in Okinawa at 9:50.
Check the passenger list.
Right.
Hold on... My name isn't on that list.
Why not?
I'm a bit of a celebrity.
I don't want people to notice me, so I always
buy tickets under another name.
And put on a hat to mask myself
so people won't recognize me.
Then, what's your nickname?
Umm... It's Yamada.
No, I think it was Tanaka.
Well, if we can prove that Motoyama was in Miyazaki
yesterday night, then the alibi is solid.
Because this is the only flight between
Miyazaki and Okinawa.
If that's what you need, then just ask that hotel I stayed in.
Here.
This is Miyazaki Princess Hotel's... The room number is...
Is it this?
I used the hotel's phone to call Nose's cellphone last night.
You should be able to find it in the hotel's calling record.
All right. Go confirm that.
Okay.
I'll have to ask everyone to accompany
me to the police station.
Damn it. Just when we finally get to have an interview...
An interview?
Ah, he's from Okinawa's Nichiuri TV.
We were actually supposed to tape
an interview with Nose-senshu.
With the three of us, including Motoyama-san and me.
But suddenly on the way to his hotel...
We discovered Nose's body.
We'll get detailed information after we get to the station.
Inspector! We also found this on the body.
A schedule and o cardboard tennis ball box?
That's mine.
I'm sorry! It probably fell out when
I was getting out of the car.
Okinawa Providence Police Naha Headquarters
Inspector, we've confirmed it.
The hotel call record.
Yesterday, Motoyama-san called from 19:20 to 19:23.
So his calling Nose-san from Miyazaki.
Hotel should be the truth.
I told you.
Even if I didn't have that, yesterday evening,
I was live on TV in Miyazaki.
Viewers across the country can prove my alibi.
I see.
So, did you ask him what the threatener
harassing Nose-senshu looked like?
No...
All I know is that it was a strange man.
A strange man...
But it's strange.
I also checked with his other teammates.
They didn't hear anything about harassment.
Of course not.
Nose is the guardian of the Jaguars.
He could score the fear out of child.
Of course he wouldn't tell other people
that he was being harassed.
He told me because we have a very
deep, long-lasting friendship.
Now that you mention it... Motoyama-san and
Nose-senshu joined the team at the same time.
Yeah.
You even got the rookie MVP title in your first year.
But my shoulder was injured in the second year.
I was never able to return to my original status
after the operation, so I retired in my fifth year.
I lost to the "Second Year Jinx."
That turned out to be just a dream over night.
I wanted to tell Nose this while in Okinawa.
And to the young players doing independent training.
Like it is now...
Maybe we should cancel tomorrow's
interview with the younger players.
Anyway... Please catch that murderer as soon as you can.
The monster who destroyed my friend's dream
of beating Japan's notional record.
No, that's not right.
This man is the murderer.
Can I make a phone call? I'll be quick.
Sure, go ahead.
But he has an alibi.
Just what is going on?
What?
What is this?
This feeling?
In the wind I sometimes smile, sometimes cry, and sometimes fight.
The two of us are just like this standing in front of our dreams.
Our dream is sure to be somewhere in the unknown future.
The colors of the seasons, always repeating let us experience a lot.
I look upon the side of your sleepy face with a smile.
Staying in that moment, this becomes our future.
Next Episode
Conan-kun.
Conan-kun!
What is it? Are you okay?
You just had a scary face.
What was that just now?
There's an empty space, but you can't head in directly.
Well, if it's like that...
That is of course.
Because you killed him.
Next Conan: A Course Without Protest (Part 2)
Next Canon's Hint:
Schedule
Summer vacation is almost over.
Conan-kun, how are you doing with your homework?
Will Shinichi be okay?