Today's stage still Okinawa.
We must break through this airborne alibi,
And discover the trick behind the crime.
Seeing through to the one and only truth,
He looks like a child but has the brain of an adult.
His name is: Detective Conan!
To join in a TV program broadcast,
Of a talk between professional baseball player
Nose Toshizou and sports reporter Motoyama Masaharu.
We rushed to Okinawa.
We met Motoyama-san in Naha Airport,
And headed toward Nose-senshu's jogging area.
But on the way...
That's....!
A Jaguar uniform.
Hey! Isn't that Nose-san?
No way!
Call the ambulance and the police fast!
"The police?"
Naha City Police Headquarters
Anyway... Please catch that murderer as soon as you can.
The monster who destroyed my friend's
dream of beating the Japan national record.
No, that's not right.
This man is the murderer.
What is this?
A Course Without Protest. Part Two.
Conan-kun?
What is it? Are you okay?
You looked so scared.
No, it's nothing...
I see.
Yeah, I was shocked too.
I'll tell you the details later.
What happened just now?
Oh yeah.
Could I borrow the car keys, Teranishi-san?
I forgot something in the car.
Hey!
Con I ask you something?
What.. What is it, kid?
The Miyazaki Hotel key-card that you were carrying...
That's not a one-time use card, is it?
Why didn't you return it to the front
desk when you checked out of the room?
Well... I haven't checked out of the room yet.
I still have another interview
program in Miyazaki the day after tomorrow.
But...
Didn't you originally also have
on interview in Okinawa tomorrow?
Returning to Miyazaki Hotel and then coming buck to
Okinawa again... Isn't the plane ticket a little wasteful?
It's impossible to know ahead of time that
tomorrow's interview would be cancelled.
This little brat.
Did you find what you forgot?
Oh... Nah... It seems that I was mistaken.
Thank you anyway.
Anyhow, why did everyone come to the parking lot?
Well... They're going to investigate the scene again,
Where Nose-senshu fell.
Just making sure we didn't
miss anything. Normal procedure.
Hey, Onii-san?
Huh?
Are you left-handed?
No.
But just now, you used your left hand to catch the keys.
Ah, it's a habit.
Because I was the number 4
pitcher on my high school baseball team.
And...
Why did you take that small road to go
around on the way to Nose-senshu's hotel?
Because during that time, the
bigger road would have been very busy.
So, even though it's farther in distance,
The smaller road is faster to get to the hotel.
Wait a second.
I'm sure...
Run should have it...
This is it.
I see!
So that's what happened.
It's not that he didn't check out of the hotel room...
He couldn't!
There's no way I can be wrong.
The murderer is Motoyama-san.
He's the one who killed Nose-senshu.
Using a shortcut in the sky.
Inspector!
I've clone o brief search of the surrounding area.
Did you find any witnesses?
About that...
At around 9:30 am, when Nose-senshu was murdered...
No one had come near here.
In other words, there's no witness,
no murder weapon, and no evidence.
Take your time, Inspector.
There is still a lot of time left
before our plane leaves for Tokyo.
If you take your time,
Maybe you can find some
evidence the murderer forgot to get rid of.
What is this brat talking about again?
Umm...
Excuse me. Could I go eat something?
I haven't had anything since arriving here.
That's true.
I don't mind.
We'll be waiting here. Please go ahead.
Why don't we all go together?
That sounds good.
Then let's all take my car and go together.
Sorry to bother you.
I come to this restaurant quite often.
It's very good.
Then, let's grab a quick meal
and return to the scene of the crime.
Oh, it's a call from the TV station producer.
Then, we'll go into the restaurant first.
After you're finished with your call,
lock the door and come in to find us.
Let's go ahead, then.
Conan-kun.
Yes, this is Motoyama.
Did Something happen?
Huh? The phone ringed once just now, I checked
the call record and it said it was you, Motoyama-san...
That's why I called.
I wondered if there's any new
development in Nose-senshu's case?
Ah, no... I probably pressed
the wrong button on the phone.
If anything comes up, I'll let you know.
That's all.
What are you doing, Conan-kun?
Ah, no...
I'm thinking that
Motoyama-san really is a famous detective.
Idiot.
You're talking about how he knew Nose-senshu
was murdered by just seeing him lying down, right?
That's because he heard from
Nose senshu that he was being threatened.
That's why Motoyama-san thought of it.
It's not that.
What about what Motoyama-san said to me in the airport?
What?
"We're going, kid!"
Hey, we're going, kid!
How can you call him a famous detective because of that?
Because at that time, I wasn't
near Uncle Kogorou or Ran-neechan,
And I was talking to the guard.
So how did he know that I came with Uncle?
Isn't that an incredible deduction?
Now... Now that you mention it...
Thai is kind of strange.
It was the first time we saw him.
Oh well... Let's talk while we eat.
What a crowd!
Empty spaces are over at...
Everyone! Over here! Over here!
Even though' there's empty space,
we can't get to it walking straight in.
All right.
Then... We'll go around!
Look! I'm already here!
It was faster to take the farther way.
This is it!
As long as I destroy this..
No one will know my crime!
I'm sorry.
Can you help me get the schedule in my bag?
I forgot the time for our return flight.
Here it is.
Ah, thank you very much.
Oh, right!
My friend asked me to buy some souvenirs from Okinawa.
I want to go ahead and buy them.
Could you tell everyone not to wait for me?
When I'm done,
I'll just get some bread or something to eat
and meet you guys back at the crime scene.
Okay... I understand.
Naha Airport Parking
Hey, hey.
Looks like you're in good mood.
Didn't your best friend just
die? Quite a fast recovery you had.
That is, of course,
Because you killed him.
What... What kind of idiocy are you talking about?
Didn't I say it before?
I have on alibi.
Nose was killed at around 9:30 in the morning, right?
I was sitting on a plane from Miyazaki
to Okinawa that arrived at 9:50, wasn't I?
Furthermore, that's the only plane
that comes from Miyazaki to Okinawa.
I had a live broadcast at Miyazaki last night, too.
So how could I possibly kill Nose?
It's true. It's impossible if you come directly from Miyazaki.
But if you go around and come through Tokyo to get here,
Then it's possible for you to get to
Okinawa before 9:30 in the morning.
Yes, just like avoiding the busy
main street by taking a longer way,
It lets you reach your destination faster.
Taking the 8:35 pm plane from Miyazaki to Tokyo first...
And then if you take the 6:35
plane in the next morning to Okinawa.
You'll be able to arrive at 9:20 am.
And then, using a pre-rented car...
You went directly from the airport to
ambush and kill Nose-senshu who was out jogging.
Afterwards, you only needed to return
to Naha Airport's exit before 9:50 am...
Pretending that you just got to
Okinawa and appeared before us.
Wait... Wait a second.
I came out of the arrival
terminal of Naha Airport after 9:50 am.
If I arrived on the 9:20 airplane...
And left the airport once already...
How can I get into the arrival terminal again?
Well, that's...
Yes?
That's true, too...
Right?
Hey..
Mouri-san...
Didn't you bring us here because you
said you knew who the murderer was?
Ah, about that...
Honestly... There's no other way...
Hey, the people at that restaurant earlier...
Why were they all looking at us so weirdly?
Well, of course,
We've all entered the restaurant and found a seat.
But we didn't order any food and left immediately.
You got hungry, huh.
Do you want my orange juice?
Okay, thank you.
Entering the restaurant but not
ordering any food and leaving immediately.
Hey...
Come to think of it, Naha Airport's arrival
terminal and the departure terminal are interconnected.
Yeah... That's right.
In other words,
You only need to get a ticket
to enter the departure terminal...
And without boarding the plane, you
can still come out of the arrival terminal.
Yeah, like that! That's exactly right!
Speaking of that... The tact that you didn't
check out of your room in Miyazaki is also suspicious.
If you took the plane from
Miyazaki to Okinawa this morning,
You should've been able to check
out of your hotel room in Miyazaki.
Especially since you knew you'd
have on interview in Okinawa tomorrow.
Staying here for the night would be more logical.
But you couldn't do that because...
You'd already left Miyazaki last night.
Taking the night plane to Tokyo which is farther away.
Evidence. Where's your evidence?
Of course we have evidence!
Don't we, Detective Mouri?
What is it again?
We'll leave the rest to the famous detective then.
Uncle, why don't you drink some orange juice?
Oh, right. That's it!
For his plan, Motoyama-san was on
the 931 plane from Tokyo to Okinawa.
In fact, we were sitting on that same plane.
During the flight, my daughter
spilled a container full of tennis balls,
Which were recovered with the help of nearby passengers.
Among these passengers...
There was someone who caught
the tennis boll with his left hand.
A very suspicious man.
Could that be Motoyama-san?
But isn't he right-handed?
It's a habit.
He's used to catching balls with his left hand.
Furthermore, in his old job, he had to protect his right hand.
So, without thinking, he used his left hand to catch it.
Then, would you please take it out?
The thing you stole from Ran's
bag and hid in your inside pocket?
The person who took the title of the king
of new players and the savior of the team,
The ex-professional baseball
player... Motoyama Masaharu-san!
What... What are you talking about?
You're sweating...
Is it getting worm?
Why don't you drink some juice!
Yes, the fingerprints that were
imprinted on the tennis ball at that time...
Are the unshakable evidence
that points to you as the murderer.
I may have said it that way, but actually that's not it...
Hard tennis bolls with their furry surfaces,
Make it really hard to find fingerprints on them.
Even if there were some imprinted...
It can only prove that you and I were on the same plane.
It cannot prove that you are Nose-senshu's murderer.
That's why I let you steal the tennis
ball container and go with the flow.
I was hoping that maybe you'd lead us
To the place where you hid the murder weapon,
And the blood-splattered clothes that you wore.
Oh! This is definitely unshakable proof.
But...
To see the truth only by him catching the ball
with his left hand..no wonder you're famous!
Nah...
In fact, it was when we supposedly met
Motoyama-san for the first time in the airport...
He called this brat here to come
with us. That's when it came to me.
"Maybe Motoyama-san met
us before we met in the airport..
And saw us together somewhere before."
Who would've guessed that this
hyperactive brat wound actually be useful.
As expected, it would've been better if I
had put him to sleep with the stun needle.
Isn't this ironic.
I lost my pitcher spot because of my habit...
And now, I dug a grave for myself with my habit as well...
At the end of the first season when I received the
titles of King of Newcomers and savior of the team,
Nose said to me,
"You have a bad habit when you pitch."
I checked my pose with detail...
To the point where I became paranoid.
But still... I couldn't find the bad habit.
Instead, because of all the over
training I did, I sprained my shoulder.
I thought it was strange...
That when I retired,
Nose's attitude changed towards me.
He even got me a job at the TV station.
And then, last month...
I saw the unedited tape of u sports program by chance...
And the question was finally answered.
Is there any other topic that you feel is worth mentioning?
Please tell us something, Nose-san.
I see...
The way to break young pitcher is simple.
You only have to whisper into his ears that he has a
bad pitching habit, and then he'll self-destruct for you.
Please cut this part... It's not good broadcasting it...
Is it true?
No, someone else told me.
That's right. I didn't have a bad habit at all.
And yet, I was still grateful to him...
Because he become the savior of the Jaguar team after me,
I supported him like he was myself.
I feel unfair and ashamed.
That's why you killed him?
Yeah...
To stop him from making the Japan notional record.
Using Hideyoshi's counterattack.
Because the real person to break the national
record and have worldwide fame should have been me!
I wanted to make him realize!
No. No matter what you do, you'll never
have the right to break Japan's national record.
It's regrettable that you were deceived...
But the pitcher is a team's last hope...
They may lose the game, and be
yelled at for no reason by everyone else.
But in the next game, they have to recover, and return
once again to the pitcher's spot as if nothing's happened.
Someone like you, who could kill
someone else for stepping in your way...
Would never be able to sustain the hope of on entire team.
Uncle.
Dad.
Honestly, I'm the one who wants to cry...
It's all because of your doing something like this...
I was finally able to get...
No... It's nothing...
Take time to think about where you went wrong in jail.
Hey, what did you want to say just then, dad?
It's nothing.
In the wind I sometimes smile, sometimes cry, and sometimes fight.
The two of us are just like this standing in front of our dreams.
Our dream is sure to be somewhere in the unknown future.
The colors of the seasons, always repeating let us experience a lot.
I look upon the side of your sleepy face with a smile.
Staying in that moment, this becomes our future.
Damn it...
I worked so hard on getting this...
There's no way I can give it to her now...
No... Wait...
This is probably the last of the
last autographs out there right now...
It's a super rare collector's item! I'm rich!
Dad?
That's a poisonous black widow spider, right?
Don't touch it!
We have to leave the scene the
way it is until the police arrive.
This isn't an accident.
Uncle Kogorou said...
It is very suspicious that only the cure
for the black widow's poison is missing.
Next Conan: Deadly Poisonous Spider Trap.
Next Conan's Hint:
Telephone.
Next Time, it will finally be in new school term again.
Wait in excited anticipation for the next episode
It'll be a new start for both Conan and the school!
Ran-neechan turned black from over-tanning in the sun.