Today's case is about a poisonous spider.
Warp and woof, the sealed room trick.
Open up the hole to see inside this hollow mystery!
Seeing through the one and only truth,
He looks like a child but has the intelligence of an adult.
His name is: Detective Conan!
Hey, Mitsuhiko, Ayumi!
Hurry up!
Let's play soccer.
Let's play after we go to the library.
New books came in yesterday, right?
What? I came 'cause you said we we're gonna play soccer.
Hey! Say something, Conan.
If I have to choose, l sort of feel like reading books.
What? You're the one who said
we should play soccer, you traitor!
Such children...
Hey, what are you doing?
Shhh!
You're going, right, Mr. Detective?
Deadly Poisonous Spider Trap.
Why don't you give the professor a call?
My hands are full right now.
Why don't you do it?
Then, I will...
No, it's okay. I'll do it.
It's the lunch break signal for the construction crew nearby.
He's not picking up.
Call him yourself later.
All right, already.
A Seakagoke Spider.
Huh?
W-what?!
Look out!
Genta-kun, please don't push me.
We're not gonna fa...
What are you doing?
Well, you two disappeared by yourselves...
That's not fair...
Ayumi-chan, you, too?
Hey, what are you doing?!
Huh, Mitsuhiko-kun?
Do you know him?
Huh? Yeah, he lives in the apartment nearby my house,
Hitokawa-san.
Hitokawa Touru (32)
Beika Agriculture University Asst. Professor.
He's collage professor who's studying spider.
Hey, that's o Seakagoke Spider. The poisonous kind, right?
Urasaki Yoshiki (38)
Spider Fan
Yeah, that's right.
You know quite a bit, kid
When it was discovered in Japan a few years ago,
It created a stir in the news and stuff, right?
Wow!
You see how its back is red?
That's why it's called the "Seakagoke" spider.
It's also called the "Redback Spider."
It's a poisonous spider that's usually
found in Australia and Central America.
Huh... So there are poisonous spiders in the Beika area...
Yasuda Miwa (28)
Biology Magazine Reporter
No, we're just using the background here to take picture.
I'm a reporter.
It's for this magazine.
We're having a special issue
on poisonous spiders next month.
See?
Oh. What about that spider, then?
This is my pet.
P-pet?
Even if I look like this, I'm kinda famous!
In the spider mania world.
I own several different poisonous spiders.
We'll interview the professor
after this. Go ahead and call him.
Yeah, yeah.
Hello?
Ah, Professor Nino. This is Urasaki.
W-What's wrong, Professor?!
I've been bitten! I've been bitten by a Black Widow!
What's going on?
Take the anti-venom!
Professor, hurry and get the anti-venom!
The anti-venom!
It's not opening!
Here's the spare key.
Professor!
You guys stay here.
Uh... Okay.
I can't believe it...
He's dead.
The professor... Passed away?
Why?!
Look, there's no mark from the anti-venom shot.
Oh, no...
Urasaki-san, call the police immediately.
R-right...
Hey, hey! What are you doing, Miwa?
L-look...
The poisonous spider!
This is what bit the professor!
Stop it!
It's already dead.
This spider has neuro-transmitted poison that's
several times stronger than the Seakagoke Spider.
B-but a person shouldn't die from if immediately...
Ah, don't touch it.
You have to leave everything
just like it is until the police arrive.
Y-yeah...
H-hey!
Let me borrow this for a sec.
Hello, police?
Yes, yes!
So he was bitten here.
Hmm?
Oh? It's not here!
The anti-venom for the black widow spider is gone!
Huh?!
It's always here for sure.
Hey, look of this!
Looks like it escaped from here.
No one's ever forgotten to close the door. Ever.
It happens to everyone. People are human, you know.
That's... Huh?!
Got it? You can't enter while we're investigating.
What's up with him?
We're also witness for this case.
If you kick us out, you can't solve the case!
The only ones who have the key for this room are
Professor Nino and his assistant, Hitokawa-san, right?
Y-yes.
Urasaki-san just become acquainted with the professor.
Yeah.
You always lock the doors and windows?
Yes, because we have dozens of
poisonous spiders in individual cages.
To think, he forgot to close the
door of a poisonous spider cage.
Are you worried?
Well, fine! Why don't you just think it over?
Forever and ever...
I... Saw something.
What did you see?
The professor's ear has a scratch on it.
It seems that, without realizing the spider was on
the phone, he put it close to his ear and got bitten.
But... To get bitten by this spider and die is u bit unusual.
Ah, Conan-kun!
Hey, I told you not to barge in like that!
Hmm?
Ah, just for a little while...
Hey, isn't this heart medicine?
Huh?
Did the professor have a bad heart?
Y-yes.
Really? I didn't know that...
Well, then was this really an accident?
You called the professor, right, Urasaki-san?
Yeah, but Miwa called before I did.
At that time, no one answered the phone, right?
R-right.
Ah, Conan, that's a bit...
Be careful with...
Hmm?
Okay. A call to Uncle...
There's a record for getting a call from Urasaki-san.
If you want to call someone, just use my cellphone.
Ah, it's okay...
I already dialed him...
Hello, Uncle Kogorou?
If I remember correctly...
It's the same model as back then...
So I'll be a bit late.
Huh? Why?
This is no accident!
Huh?
What's wrong, Hitokawa-san?
Tomorrow, there's on academic conference.
I need to present in Professor Nino's place.
What?!
Normally, at times like this, people
aren't worrying about academic conferences!
B-but... It's a really important academic
conference that was scheduled long before.
So if I had the data, then I could prepare...
It's actually... Hitokawa-san's research.
Huh?! R-really?
The professor has been presenting
Hitokawa-san's research as if it was his own all this time.
Heh? So he's been stealing his apprentice's achievements.
That happens often.
That means, Hitokawa-sensei has been
holding a grudge against the professor.
You have, too, Urasaki-san...
What? You bastard!
Now, now, Urasaki-san...
But that means you also have something against him?
I... Don't have anything to do with this.
What is that?
Could you show it to us?
W-w-what...
I said it's nothing...
Well, please show it to us, Urasaki-san.
Dang it.
Those are rare spiders.
Ones that aren't in Japan.
What's up with this?
Urasaki-san bought spiders from the professor.
Spiders?
Yes.
Under the name of research, Professor Nino
got ahold of rare spiders from all over the world.
And he was pretty forceful about it, too.
He totally knew my weakness. Cornered me like a mouse.
So that's why you held a grudge against the Professor...
Stupid. This was just on accident.
It's punishment for playing with me who loves spiders.
Uncle Kogorou says he knows who did it.
Hmm?
C-Conan-kun!
You're still here?
He says it's not an accident?
It's suspicious that only the
anti-venom for the black widow spider is gone.
Yeah, that's a bit of o stretch.
If it's not an accident...
Hitokawa-san, you're the only
one who has the spore key, right?
Huh? Yeah.
But Hitokawa-san and Conan-kun and his
friends heard the professor's scream together.
Uncle Kogorou said to investigate this phone thoroughly.
The phone?
Huh?
There's something shiny here...
What?
Hmm. Somethings there.
Right about where you'd put
your ear against, in one of the holes.
It's a thumb-tack!
Something like this was hidden inside!
The tip of the thumb-tack is broken.
What's up, Conan?
Bathroom.
With a broken tip, you can't tell
from the outside of the phone cover.
Then what poked the Professor's ear is this thumb-tack?
So why did he yell out that he
was bitten by a black widow spider?
Hello?
Ah, Mouri-san.
Huh!
I heard about the situation from Conan.
The culprit placed the block widow spider
at the tip of the needle inside of the phone.
Huh!
Look thoroughly at the dead
spider there with the magnifying glass.
W-wait.
H-hey... Takagi...
I-I see!
T-Takagi!
Hurry and explain to us, too!
Okay, Mouri-kun, what's really going on?
Basically, Inspector, it's like this...
The culprit installed the thumb-tack inside of the phone first,
And then placed the already dead
spider on the tip of the thumb-tack.
So that the professor would mistakenly think
that he was bitten by a black widow spider.
As for the anti-venom...
The culprit stole the anti-venom for the spider.
Then, the culprit returned the phone to its cradle,
And waited for the professor to pick it up.
And that's it.
So, when the professor died...
Ah, Professor Nino. This is Urasaki.
I've been bitten! I've been bitten by a Black Widow!
Take the anti-venom!
Professor, hurry and get the anti-venom!
I-it's not here!
The anti-venom's not here!
I get it, Mouri-san.
Well, then...
Inspector, it wasn't the spider's
poison that killed Professor Nino.
Then...?
Since this is a poisonous spider research center,
He knew the danger of the black widow spider's poison.
He needed to get the anti-venom quickly,
But he couldn't find it at all.
Since the professor had a weak heart, in such a situation...
I see. It's possible for him to have a heart
attack if his heart was already weakened from stress.
Yes.
Then the culprit is...
The one who can freely enter this research
center and also knows about Professor's weak heart.
With what evidence...
Mouri-san says to check the
received call history on the phone.
Yeah.
12:50, Urasaki Cellphone.
I called.
The professor answered.
17:30 University Office.
This is yesterday's stuff. It doesn't relate to this.
That's weird.
Yasuda should have called before I called, at least once.
That was about twelve o'clock. A bell rang,
signaling the lunch break for the construction crew nearby.
Ah, I must have dialed the wrong number then...
Hmm?
Please show me your cellphone.
It seems she called the wrong number.
Huh? That cellphone is the some kind as Hitokawa-san's.
What? Ah, that's just a coincidence.
Uncle Kogorou says that
Hitokawa-san's covering up for Onee-san.
He said that you two are dating.
What?!
That's a pretty old model.
It's pretty rare that you two have been using
the some model in different colors all this time.
I-I see! If you two are dating,
Then Yasuda-san had a chance
to copy Hitokawa-san's spare key.
And she's knowledgeable about spiders,
listening to Hitokawa-san on top of her work.
And it's not weird for her to
know the professor had weak heart.
W-wait a second.
It's true that we're dating.
But just because of that, saying she's suspicious is...
There's evidence.
That blue flower seal in Hitokawa-san's pocket.
I saw Hitokawa-san secretly pick it up from the floor.
Please take it out.
That's a nail art decal that you use, right?
N-no...
Look, here.
Onee-san, show me the
magazine you just showed me before.
O-okay...
It's printed here.
Look.
H-he's right.
Didn't you drop it here today?
Well, then... Why did
Hitokawa-san feel the need to hide that fact?
You came here today before
the professor arrived, didn't you?
Hitokawa-san noticed it and tried to hide the evidence.
Hey, look at the antenna of that cellphone.
Isn't it all scratched up?
Hmm?
Ah, now you mention it...
If I remember correctly, the other
phone also had scratches, right?
I see.
Using the cellphone antenna, she
broke the tip of thumb-tack from the phone.
The scratches are from then...
Stop it!
You murdered Professor Nino and
tried to make it look like an accident.
You made Urasaki-san call him so that you and
Hitokawa-san wouldn't be suspected, didn't you?
Why did you do such a thing?
Professor Nino always presented the achievements
from Hitokawa-san's research at academic conferences.
I couldn't take it anymore.
In truth, I thought it would be fine if he
just got hospitalized from his heart disease...
I didn't think it'd turn out like this...
M-Miwa...
It's still an unforgivable crime...
To take away someone else's life...
In the wind I sometimes smile, sometimes cry, and sometimes fight.
The two of us are just like this standing in front of our dreams.
Our dream is sure to be somewhere in the unknown future.
The colors of the seasons, always repeating let us experience a lot.
I look upon the side of your sleepy face with a smile.
Staying in that moment, this becomes our future.
Just us I thought, the spider was innocent.
Yeah.
And if you look at them closely, they're small and cute!
That's true!
Hey, Conan-kun there's a spider right on our sleeve!
Ah, it's all good. It's not poisonous.
Ah, if I remember correctly,
That one's from the professor's cages...
W-what?! D-do something!
Hey, Haibara!
Just kidding.
You guys!
Just keep laughing.
"Do not involve yourself with this charity. You'll regret it."
"Signed, the Cursed Masks' Wearer.
Just what in the world are these masks...
Detective Conan, Autumn Genuine Mystery Special.
The Cursed Masks Are Smirking Coldly.
9/20 Monday Night 7:00 On Air!
I've solved... The curse of the masks!
Detective Conan was brought
to you by the following sponsors.
Next Conan's Hint!
Cigarettes.
9/20, 1 hour special-
On the pretty screen
The Cursed Masks!
Be sure to watch!