Today we're all watching the skies!
When looking for a comet, we find a skeleton!
Solve the puzzle of the scattered cigarettes!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Created by
Gosho Aoyama
"Detective Conan"
Serialized in Shogakukan's
'Weekly Shonen Sunday'
Planning
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Character Design
Mari Tominaga
Art Director
Yasutada Kato
Director of Photography
Takahisa Ogawa
Sound Directors
Yasuo Uragami
Motoi Izawa
Music
Katsuo Ono
Opening Theme
Performed by
Rina Aiuchi
Lyrics
Music
Aika Ono
Arrangement
Editor
Terumitsu Okada
Story Editor
Jun'ichi Iioka
Color Key
Fusako Nakao
Executive Producer
Makoto Moriwaki
Planning Support
Shin'ichiro Tsuzuki
Shin'ichi Mikami
Toyohiko Okuyama
Masahiko Ishikawa
Producer
Hiroaki Kobayashi
Associate Producer
Mitome Asai
Chief Producers
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Masahito Yoshioka
(Tokyo Movie)
Director
Masato Sato
A-Ass-to-what observation?
No, Genta-kun.
Astronomical observation, astronomical observation!
Hey, Doc, are we gonna see the stars?
Yeah. I found a little hostel in the Gunma mountains.
But why are we going out and looking at stars when it's so cold out?
It's better to go on a cold night.
The air is clearer on cold days. It's easier to see the stars.
Besides, tonight is the new moon.
It's a perfect night for stargazing.
But isn't it boring, just looking at stars?
Don't say that.
I'll teach you the constellations,
and if you find a new celestial object, you might just be able to name it!
Name?!
A star...
We can name it?
That's right.
Well, we won't be able to name an asteroid,
because it has to be observed multiple times and its orbit must be confirmed.
But maybe we can find a comet.
So how about calling it the "Beika Detective Boys Comet"?
Nice!
Right, right? That would be great.
No...
You can't give it just any name. That's only for asteroids.
Comets are given the last names of the people who found them,
and only the names of the first three people who spotted the comet are used.
Right. If the comet was spotted in different parts of the world at the same time,
it could end up having names of people from different countries.
Three people... Me and... uh...
Like the "Kobayashi-Berger-Milon" comet.
So if we find the comet and report it right away,
it could be the "Yoshida-
Tsuburaya-Haibara Comet", right?
Right? Right?
Well, yeah...
Huh? Yoshida... Tsuburaya... Haibara...
How come my name isn't in there?
I want Conan-kun's name on it too!
But you can only use three people...
Hey, Conan-kun too...
What are you doing, Conan-kun?
Ah, that's Masaharu Motoyama-san, the sports reporter
who murdered pro baseball player Nose in Okinawa the other day!
You were there when it happened, right, Conan-kun?
Yeah, I was wondering a bit about it...
Wondering?
Oh, uh, it's no big deal!
I just wondered who the other person was he was calling on his cell during a police questioning.
The police had already told Nose's family about his death...
so I'd think it was someone Motoyama-san himself knew, but...
Oh, damn!
I should've just asked him directly at the time.
Maybe it was Komori?
Considering he was teammates with Nose and Motoyama...
They did TV specials together during the off-season,
and they seemed like good friends.
Maybe he called him about their mutual friend's death.
He retired four years ago and took over his family business, running an inn.
I think it's a place in Tottori called Kurayoshi...
They used to advertise it on the TV specials.
It seemed like a nice place.
Oh, I see.
I guess it didn't have anything to do with the men in black...
Kurayoshi...
Kudo-kun, don't tell me you...
Agasa-sama, right? I've been waiting for you.
Please sign your name in the guestbook.
Ah, yes.
Hiroshi Agasa...
Hey, where is he?
Etsuko Nonomiya (28)
Guest
Asao invited you here too, didn't he?
Please, tell me...
I want to apologize to him.
Where is Asao?
Who's Asao?
Don't play dumb with me!
The guy wearing the same ring as me! Asao Kono!
He sent you an invitation too, didn't he?!
Hey, Nonomiya-san...
Invitation?
Uh, no... This is the first time we've ever been here.
Oh, is that so?
Sorry...
What a shock.
Sorry about that.
Who was that?
Ryoji Amatsuchi (34)
Hostel Owner
That was Etsuko Nonomiya. She was my kohai at university.
That Kono-kun she was talking about was my kohai.
They got engaged a while back.
They used to stay here often,
but last year they got into a huge fight here,
and after that he just disappeared.
She suddenly received an invitation from him last week telling her to meet him here,
and she's been waiting for three days now,
but he still hasn't shown up,
and in the meantime, she's been drinking nonstop.
But I don't even know him.
What made her think I'd received an invitation?
That's easy.
Heihachi Mikami (43)
Guest
Hajime Futagawa (35)
We don't know him either, but check it out.
We both got invitations from this Kono guy.
Well, we did meet him once, on that day a year ago.
And the invitation was so intriguing we decided to come.
Hey, can I take a look at the invitation?
Oh, sure.
Thanks.
"After a year's observation, I have made an unbelievable discovery..."
"that will shake the astronomical world."
"I would like to ask your advice,"
"so please meet me at the Amatsuchi Inn."
"Naturally, I will pay for your stay."
"If you are busy and unable to come, there's nothing I can do about it."
"Signed Asao Kono."
We've been waiting for two days now and he hasn't appeared,
so it looks like it was just a prank.
Ready to leave, Editor-in-Chief?
E-Editor-in-Chief?
Yeah. We publish an astronomy magazine called Space Sunday,
and Mikami-san is its editor-in-chief.
He ain't no ordinary editor-in-chief.
Hey, hey.
It's fine.
Hey, hey... What do you mean,
"he isn't an ordinary editor-in-chief"?
He's a great guy! He's even had a comet named after him.
He found one?
Where did you find it?
You have to tell us!
Er, it's hard to say where...
Over here? Or over there?
Hey, hey.
Try climbing the hill out behind the inn.
You can get a good clear view.
It's the perfect spot for stargazing.
I'll even rent you a telescope.
It's 5,000 yen.
There's a charge, huh?
Well then, take care.
Right!
Alright! We're gonna find our own star!
Yeah!
Rank amateurs.
No way they'll find anything.
Ain't that right, Editor-in-Chief?
Yeah.
Hey, you never know.
No matter how much you know, in the end finding a star comes down to luck.
If you're lucky, you can find your star...
Hey, Mr. Editor...
You were lucky to find a star, so can you look for mine as well?
He disappeared into the darkness of space, chasing stars of his own...
My dear, dear man...
It's further than I thought.
You can do it, Doctor.
C'mon, hurry!
Hey, that's gotta be the hill he told us about!
It's more of a cliff than a hill.
Are you telling me we've got to climb this?
L-Let me take a break...
Hey, if we're gonna do it, we'd better do it before it gets dark!
Be kind to your elders!
You're always telling me not to treat you like an old man.
How about a ten-minute break?
Good idea!
Sheesh. There's no helping them.
A rock... A rock...
But don't you think there's something weird about that invitation?
"If you are busy and unable to come, there's nothing I can do about it"...
Why write something like that?
Yeah, you're right.
There must be a reason.
Why invite those particular people?
Found one!
What's wrong, Ayumi-chan?!
A-A skull!
For real?
W-What's a skull doing here?!
There are more bones scattered here.
What?!
A lower jawbone...
An upper arm bone...
A leg bone.
And the rest of the body...
There it is!
I-I can't believe my eyes...
This person must've fallen off the cliff!
Right...
It's probably the skeleton of someone who died in an accident.
The bones were scattered by animals and the wind and rain...
No.
It's a murder. And a gruesome one at that.
Look. Quicklime.
When quicklime absorbs water, it gives off heat.
If you sprinkle it around a body, it'll produce heat when it rains.
That speeds up decomposition. Someone wanted to create a skeleton quickly.
That makes it just about impossible to determine the cause or time of death.
M-Maybe that skull...
is that Kono-san person those other people were talking about?
No way!
He only just sent them those invitations...
It probably is that Kono-san.
Look under this rock. A ring and a carton of cigarettes.
Engraved on this ring, it says in English, "Etsuko to Asao".
He must've hidden them before the killer came down here after pushing him off the cliff,
in the hope that someone would find them.
Or the killer planted them here on purpose.
In that case, the killer would've left the ring on his finger.
Besides, the killer went to all this trouble
to make the body unidentifiable.
Can somebody lend me a handkerchief?
Here.
Thank you.
So what's the cigarette carton for?
If my deductions are correct, this is probably...
Nothing in it but cigarettes.
Just as I thought.
Could this be...?
Yeah. Kono-san left them behind...
as a dying message.
D-Dying message?!
These cigarettes?
Yeah.
Most likely, Asao Kono left them as a clue pointing to his murderer before he died.
But isn't it just six cigarettes, with two of them broken in half?
Take a closer look!
The two short cigarettes both have filters, right?
This shows that he broke them on purpose and threw away the other halves.
And here,
if you look carefully under the rock where the cigarette carton was hidden,
you see the decaying remnants of the other cigarettes, including the broken halves, right?
In other words, Kono left this...
to tell us that the clue is in the four long cigarettes...
and the two short cigarettes in the carton.
A-Anyway, I'd better call the hostel about this.
Hold it, Doc!
If they find out at the hostel, it will be bad.
Call the police first!
What? Why?
Don't you get it?
All the guests at the hostel right now are people who received invitations from Kono-san.
If those bones really belong to Kono-san,
then the invitations were sent by someone else, right?
And the people who were invited were all staying at the hostel
when Kono-san disappeared a year ago.
If these scattered bones are not the result of wind, rain or animals,
but were placed like this on purpose...
Yeah.
Whoever sent those invitations may have wanted somebody to find Kono-san's skeleton,
as part of a fiendish scheme.
What kind of scheme?
I don't know...
Anyway, call the police! Tell them to come right away!
What's wrong, Doc?
Uh, well...
It looks like I can't get a signal out here.
Meh.
Let's go back to the hostel and call the cops...
P-Police?
Has something happened?
Amatsuchi-san! What are you doing here?
I forgot to include the weight for the telescope in the bag.
Not good.
What's going on?
Oh, nothing.
What's the matter?
Uh, er, weight? What for?
Is there something strange?
B-Bones?!
Hey, wait!
Drat!
What? You found Asao's bones in the forest?!
But they're just bones, right?
You can't tell if it's Asao or not!
No, near the bones we also found...
an engagement ring with your and his initials carved on it.
Well, maybe this Asao Kono guy's the killer, and planted the ring on his victim.
But we found the ring under...
Hey, by any chance did that Kono-san have a cavity?
In the second tooth from the back, on the right side of his upper jaw?
A back tooth in his upper jaw?
Then those bones aren't Asao.
He did have a cavity, but it was in a front tooth on the bottom.
No way!
So it really is...
No doubt about it.
W-Wait, what?!
What are you talking about?
Sorry to say, but we found a filling in the central incisor on the mandible.
In other words, a front tooth on the bottom, just as you said.
To see if you would lie or simply agree with his story,
he intentionally said the cavity was in the wrong tooth.
I'm sorry.
Oh no...
Then Asao...Asao is...
At any rate, you have to call the police.
I-I can't. The phone isn't working.
Hey, that phone's electrical cord is plugged in,
but the phone cable's missing.
What?!
Strange. It was working fine until just a moment ago.
Do you have any other phones or spare cables?
This is the only phone.
And I don't have any spare cables.
So we can't call the police...
You've gotta be kidding me.
I'm getting in my car and leaving!
Ah, Editor!
Sorry...
but you can't do that either.
I just checked outside,
and all the cars have flat tires.
Looks like somebody loosened the valves and let the air out,
so we wouldn't be able to escape.
We're all trapped here together.
I-I can't believe this.
Hey, don't tell me this has something to do with that Kono guy.
You bet it does!
It does, it does!
After all, he was mur—
Say, you kids were looking at something when I found the bones, weren't you?
Four long cigarettes and two short cigarettes that you'd placed in a handkerchief.
Hey, maybe it's a dying message?
Oh, I don't know...
No.
There's no dying message.
Asao's just playing dead to make me suffer.
He's so naughty.
Asao would never die.
What a cute guy...
Anyway, I think we should take not one step out of our rooms tonight,
and just wait for morning.
There are six cigarettes—four long and two short.
That's too many to spell Futagawa-san in kanji,
and one too few to spell Amatsuchi-san
And spelling Nonomiya-san or Mikami-san is out of the question.
Maybe it's katakana?
That's impossible too.
It would take 14 to write Futagawa-san,
12 to write Amatsuchi-san,
8 for Nonomiya-san
and 9 if we wanted to write Mikami-san.
What about initials, then?
See, "Haibara, Ai" would be HA, exactly 6 lines...
T-Then you're the murderer?!
Merely offering an example.
Ah, an example.
Come to think of it, "TM" for "Tsuburaya, Mitsuhiko"
and "YA" for "Yoshida, Ayumi" also use 6.
You're right!
Hm, "Kojima, Genta" is...
All three of us take 6! It's so romantic!
I take 6 too—"AH" for "Agasa, Hiroshi".
Eh, it's just a coincidence.
Hey!
Perhaps these initials could be the right answer.
What? The killer is Futagawa-san?
Well, if the cigarettes are meant to spell out initials, he's the one.
"Amatsuchi, Ryoji"-san is AR.
"Nonomiya, Etsuko"-san is NE.
"Mikami, Heihachi"-san is MH.
The only name you can get out of 6 cigarettes is "FH" for "Futagawa, Hajime", right?
B-But is it safe to confront that Futagawa-san?
Don't worry. We'll just trick him into confessing.
Huh?
Looks like Futagawa-san isn't here.
This cigarette filter's still damp.
It hasn't been long since he left his room.
Someone's walking around outside!
That's Nonomiya-san!
O-Oh, no!
It's not just Futagawa-san.
Mikami-san and Amatsuchi-san are gone too!
Dammit!
We told them not to go outside!
Anyway, Mitsuhiko, Ayumi-chan and I will bring Nonomiya-san back.
Doc, Haibara and Genta, go look for the other three!
A-Alright, will do!
Nonomiya-san!
Where are you?
Oneesan!
H-Hey, isn't this the path that leads to the skeleton?
Eh? You don't mean...
She wanted to find out for herself if those bones were really Kono-san?
Oh no...
What was that sound just now?
Futagawa-san?!
We're too late.
His neck is broken.
He's already stopped breathing...
H-He's holding on to something.
A cigarette carton?!
Is it the same dying message again?
No.
This time, there's one more cigarette.
Hey, hey! Don't turn the place upside-down!
Oh, you brought your own telescope?
How long are you going to search my room?
The only thing that could be used as a weapon is this umbrella.
All that's left, Amatsuchi-san, is you.
He kept looking at the guestbook!
Over and over again!
Wrong!
Next Conan:
It's the Next Conan's Hint!
Initials
Next week it's case closed!
Promise you'll watch my great performance.