Today's code is hard to solve!
Stars and criminals are both called "hoshi"!
Look through the telescope!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
We came to a hostel in the mountains to observe the stars.
Along with the hostel's owner, Ryoji Amatsuchi-san, we met
Ryoji Amatsuchi (34)
Hostel Owner
Etsuko Nonomiya (28)
Guest
Etsuko Nonomiya-san,
Heihachi Mikami (43)
Guest
Hajime Futagawa (35)
Hajime Futagawa-san,
and Heihachi Mikami-san, who had been invited.
And somehow, when we had gone to a nearby hill to look at the stars,
we found a dead body that was reduced to bones.
And in his hand he left six cigarettes as a dying message.
Then, that night...
What was that sound just now?
Futagawa-san?!
Is it the same dying message again?
No. This time...
there's one more cigarette!
You're right!
Now there are seven cigarettes!
What does it mean?
My first guess...
is that the six cigarettes
left by Kono-san who was killed a year ago, that we found earlier today,
and these seven cigarettes we found with Futagawa-san,
point to two different people.
Maybe it's a fake message the killer forced into his hand to confuse the investigation.
I don't think so.
We came running over here because we heard something fall.
You didn't see a flashlight or anything when we ran over here, did you?
It was pitch dark.
Then Kono-san and Futagawa-san's killers were different people...
Or else Futagawa-san left this hint behind for some reason...
One cigarette has blood on it!
So does the cigarette carton he's holding in his hand!
On this other carton in his pocket...
This could mean...
Your Detective Badge is beeping!
It's me! Can you see me? Look above you!
Oh, Doc!
Hey, did you see anybody up there?
Nope, nobody.
Nobody here but us.
But we did find something someone left behind.
Left behind?
It's a cell phone.
And there's an unsent message on it.
Hey, what does it say?
"My last words".
D-Did you say "last words"?!
Futagawa-san's dead?!
That can't be!
He fell off the cliff. Looks like death was instantaneous.
And we found his cell phone on top of the cliff,
with a "last words" text message, and no destination attached.
Last words on his phone?
Here's what he wrote in the text.
"I invited everyone to this hostel..."
"to make a confession about what I did to you when we were all here a year ago."
"That's right. The one who killed Asao Kono-san one year ago was me, Hajime Futagawa."
"Etsuko Nonomiya-san, his fiancée,"
"I'm sorry for killing the man you loved."
"Ryoji Amatsuchi-san, Kono-san's sempai at university,"
"I apologize for tainting your wonderful hostel."
"And Editor-in-Chief Heihachi Mikami,"
"please take good care of Space Sunday after I'm gone."
"He and I got into an argument on top of the cliff."
"I shoved him, and he lost his balance and fell."
"I was going to confess and beg for your mercy,"
"but I just couldn't bring myself to say the words."
"I will pay with my life before the police arrive tomorrow."
"— Hajime Futagawa."
Then he...
Asao is... Asao really is...
I'm sorry. As his boss, let me apologize.
Don't cry, Etchan.
But at least now we know why he disappeared, and who's responsible.
But why would a person committing suicide...
leave something like this behind?
We found those seven cigarettes the old guy had in his hand when he died!
Kono-san had six, and he had one more long one!
If Futagawa-san committed suicide
after realizing that his message pointed back to him,
why did he add another cigarette?
Furthermore, why was there blood on the additional cigarette?
There was also blood on Futagawa-san's hand, and on the cigarette carton in his pocket.
There were signs he had been struck on the head with a steel pipe.
Struck?!
The blood on his hand was probably from holding it to his bleeding head.
In other words, those seven cigarettes were...
from when somebody on the cliff struck Futagawa-san,
then stole his cell phone to type a fake suicide note.
While he lay there, Futagawa-san took a cigarette from his own carton,
and added it to the six cigarettes in the other carton,
most likely, I think, as a dying message.
N-No...
It's safe to assume he created the carton with six cigarettes
while trying to figure out whether Kono-san's message was pointing to him.
W-Wait a minute!
With seven cigarettes, you can spell Amatsuchi-san's name...
Doesn't that make you the killer?
H-Hey!
Mikami-san's first name, Heihachi, can be spelled with seven cigarettes too.
Your initials can be spelled with seven cigarettes too, isn't that right,
Etsuko Nonomiya-san?
Now, now, keep your cool...
So none of you saw each other in the woods?
Not me.
No.
Then let's try searching our rooms.
The thin, steel pipe-like object Futagawa-san was hit with has been hidden.
After all, the killer could use it to strike again.
Hey, hey, don't turn the place upside-down!
Oh, you brought your own telescope?
Yeah, it belongs to the editorial office.
Lens barrel, mount, scope, tripod...
The barrel of a telescope isn't hard enough to knock someone out.
And a tripod like that would just bend in half.
He's right.
Oh?
You were trying to figure things out with cigarettes too?
Yeah.
But I wasn't able to solve it.
Hey, will you cut that out?
How long are you going to search my room?
The only thing that could be used as a weapon is this umbrella.
But there are no dents in it...
Of course not! I'm not the murderer!
Hey, where's that bottle of booze you had with you?
I threw it away in the woods...
while I was waiting for you guys to pass by me.
Pass by?
You came after me, didn't you?
You, the boy with the freckles, and the little girl with the bobbed hair.
I was busy throwing up behind a tree.
Looks like you were trying to solve Kono-san's dying message too.
Yes. But I never guessed it stood for that Futagawa guy's initials.
I didn't know his first name anyway.
All that's left, Amatsuchi-san, is you.
But this whole hostel is like your room...
so we'll leave it to the police when we've called them in the morning.
Fine.
You should advise the cops to search the woods.
If I were the killer, that's where I'd get rid of the weapon.
Uh, right.
Well, Haibara? Any luck?
I searched every corner of Futagawa-san's room,
but I couldn't find it.
The thing you told me to look for.
Weird. If the murderer left that fake suicide note before killing him,
it's gotta be around here somewhere.
Uh...
While you were searching the rooms,
we kept an eye on the people waiting here.
That Amatsuchi guy's acting suspicious!
Yeah, very suspicious!
How so?
He kept looking at the guestbook!
Over and over again!
With a scary look on his face, like this!
The guestbook?
Come to think of it, Mikami-san and Futagawa-san said
that they had only met Kono-san once.
But it looks like they've stayed here several times since Kono-san disappeared.
Oh, I found it!
This must be the day!
The day that Kono person died!
I think you're right...
After Kono-san and Nonomiya-san's names,
there's Mikami-san and Futagawa-san.
This is it, all right.
Could it be?
I see, that's what it means!
Hey, Haibara...
I'm counting on you.
I got a favor to ask of Ayumi too.
Right, right?
A Fusae brand wallet.
That's my price.
Do we have a deal?
Oh, for the love of...
Ow!
Haibara-san! What's the matter?!
Are you okay, Ai-chan?!
Haibara!
This looks serious! She may have appendicitis!
What? You're in pain, Ai-kun?
What should we do? The phone's out...
and who knows how many hours it'll take to carry her down the mountain?
Haibara!!
It hurts, Doctor...
Doctor, do something!
Ow!!
Doctor...
Hello? Could you send an ambulance, please?
Yes, a child has suddenly—
Just as I thought.
Hello? Could you send an ambulance, please?
What? Oh no!
But I thought the phone cable was missing.
T-The address is...Gunma Prefecture...
Conan-kun?!
If we don't call an ambulance, Ai-chan will...!
What are you doing?!
No need. It was just an act.
We wanted to smoke out the person
who hid the phone cable
and let the air out of everyone's tires
to keep us trapped here.
You don't mean, the person who sent the invitations
summoning us here under Asao's name was...
It was you?!
So the one who left the suicide note on Futagawa-san's cell phone
and pushed him off the cliff to make it look like a suicide
was you, Ryoji Amatsuchi-san!
Uh, er...
Nope.
"Nope"?
Amatsuchi-san is the one who sent the invitations
and got us stuck here,
but he isn't the murderer.
How come, Conan?
Remember that suicide note left on the cell phone?
It just said, "I invited everyone to this hostel."
If Amatsuchi-san had been Futagawa-san's killer,
he would have tried to make us think
that Futagawa-san was also the one who trapped us here, right?
Besides,
he could have planted the phone cable in Futagawa-san's clothes, or his room.
I-I see...
Amatsuchi-san summoned everyone to the hostel
because he found the bones of Kono-san,
who died here a year ago.
He had found the ring and the dying message with the cigarettes.
That's how you knew, after just glimpsing them,
that there were exactly four long ones and two short ones, right?
That's right. I sent the invitations after finding the bones to those who were here that day.
I thought that once it got out that the bones and the message had been discovered,
the killer would confess.
But when Futagawa-san died, I was afraid to admit it.
So in that case, the one who killed Futagawa-san...
Ain't it obvious?
Maybe it's that Nonomiya lady?
How could you...?!
It's a possibility.
If she figured out the cigarettes stood for Futagawa-san's initials...
She'd have quite a motive for taking revenge
on the man who killed her old flame.
Nah.
Remember? Nonomiya said she passed the three of us in the woods.
She couldn't have gone ahead of us, met Futagawa-san at the top of the cliff
and pushed him to his death.
But the three of you rushed over to Futagawa-san after he fell, right?
Maybe she saw you looking down from the cliff.
From the top of the cliff, all she would have seen was the tiny dots of our three flashlights.
There's no way the killer could know which three people were standing at the base of the cliff.
In other words, through the process of elimination,
Futagawa-san's boss, Editor-in-Chief Heihachi Mikami,
you're the only possible culprit!
So just because the killer isn't one of the other two, it must be me?
But Futagawa-san was holding seven cigarettes!
That's a message that points to your name, "Heihachi"!
Pure chance!
Besides, what would my motive be?
Especially if he was the one who killed that Kono guy last year.
I have no reason to seek revenge for a man I only met once.
Right.
But that's only if it was actually Futagawa-san who killed Kono-san, right?
W-What?!
I noticed something when I looked at the guestbook.
Mikami-san's name is written after Kono-san's.
Kono-san had only heard the name Mikami—he didn't know how to spell it.
Only heard?
See, Mikami-san's "mi"
is written like the "o" in "o-tearai", right?
"O"?
Yeah, you usually write it "three" and "up".
How many strokes is that...
Uh...
One, two, three...
Six!
Exactly. The six cigarettes left by Kono-san,
and the seven cigarettes left by Futagawa-san...
were both dying messages spelling out the same name—Heihachi Mikami!
Futagawa-san added one to get the correct spelling.
And he probably chose the same brand to let us know the killer was the same person.
Come to think of it, when Futagawa-san was looking at the guestbook, he was smiling.
That's when he realized
that it was Mikami-san who had killed Kono-san.
And Futagawa-san was going to see if he was right.
That's absurd!
What proof do you have?
The proof is in this bag from your room!
If we can find the steel pipe you used to bludgeon Futagawa-san to death,
we'll have all the proof we need!
Hey, hey!
You already checked my bag!
Right. I didn't find a steel pipe.
But I didn't find something else either.
Something else?
The weight for the telescope.
You hid something in the barrel of the telescope
and took the weight out
to bring it back to its correct weight.
Well, want to open the barrel and show us what's inside?
No matter how carefully you cleaned it,
we should still be able to get a luminol reaction from Futagawa-san's blood.
It's still covered in the blood of that ungrateful creep.
So you did...
That's right. I was so good to him—I even made him assistant editor-in-chief!
But he blackmailed me for 50 million yen. I had to silence him.
I'd already had to teach Kono a lesson for his ingratitude...
Teach him a lesson?
What are you talking about?
A comet...
That day, one year ago, that Kono guy had a request for me.
He wanted me to check whether a comet he spotted was still a new sighting.
Then that comet with our name...
He found it. I went up on the cliff to see it for myself.
Don't tell me you killed Asao just to take sole credit for finding the comet?
I just wanted my name added along with his.
But that guy... That ungrateful guy...
I can't do that.
I've already decided to name it the Amatsuchi-Nonomiya-Kono Comet.
Then I really...
Come to think of it, didn't he say "I finally met the one"?
I really thought he had another girl.
Discovering a comet was my childhood dream!
But that jerk wouldn't listen!
I decided to beat him back to the hostel
and apply for the right name.
He grabbed me and tried to stop me! I pushed him away,
and he fell off the cliff.
And you came back the next day,
with quicklime to speed up the decomposition.
Yeah.
But I never guessed that Amatsuchi-san was the one who sent he invitation.
I thought it was part of Futagawa's blackmail scheme.
Hey, hurry up with that steel pipe!
Don't rush me!
A steel pipe is a steel pipe...
but this is no ordinary steel pipe!
A shotgun?!
Okay, all of you, against the wall!
When I killed Futagawa, I didn't want anybody to hear the shot, so I just hit him.
But this time, I'll just shoot the lot of you.
That's a lot of quicklime.
No need to be afraid, little girl.
In a few moments, you'll be a star in the sky...
What are you doing, kid?
Can't you see?
I'm tying my shoes.
Shoes?
You dumb kid.
You think you can run for it?
No. It's just like you, mister.
What?
These are...
no ordinary...
shoes,
are they!
I hope you're happy.
You're gonna be a star after all.
A star criminal, that is.
But why was Kono-san so hung up on using those names for his comet?
I can understand Nonomiya-san, because she was his girlfriend.
But if he'd agreed to use Mikami-san's name instead of Amatsuchi-san's,
this never would've happened.
The three of them had known each other since university, right?
They must've been best friends!
Yeah!
I don't think that's all it was.
Those names were perfect together.
The "ama" of "Amatsuchi"...
the "no" of "Nonomiya"...
and the "ko" of "Kono", if you put them together,
they spell "Amanogawa", or "Milky Way".
I see!
You're right!
That's our Conan-kun!
Hey, you kids, could you lower your voices a little?
Can't believe you called me out here so early.
And I was going to take a day off and visit my grandma out in the country.
Now I'll have to put it off for a while.
I'm so sleepy...
Where?!
Where'd you call just now?!
M-My grandma's place in Tottori...
D-Did he say Tottori?!
Ran!
Just who is it?!
Damn! Where'd they go?
What's with that siren?
Don't tell me it's...
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint:
Tent
Gotta finish this weekend's homework by the time limit!
It's already Monday evening...
Oh! Gotta watch Conan.
It just finished.