Today we really have close call!
Because of a mistake over a tent at
the campground, Ran is in a pinch!
Seeing through to the one and only truth,
He looks like a child but
has the intelligence of an adult,
His name is: Detective Conan!
Driving, driving!
It's like there was never a storm yesterday.
Yeah, there isn't a cloud in the sky.
That's what it's like after a typhoon.
Camping, camping! Fun camping!
Tomorrow we'll camp too! The day after...
Are you finished reading it?
Yeah, it was so
interesting I read until late last night.
Ah, I'm sleepy...
Sleeping Beauty's Close Call?
Yes, it's about a princess who
remains sleeping for many years,
And the various gentlemen who try to wake her.
The one who wakes her
will get her hand in marriage.
Ah... What a romantic story!
But, she couldn't still be alive if
she was asleep for so many years.
You'd be all right if you were on an IV drip.
She was just faking being asleep anyway.
Because there was no man good enough for her.
Eh? Conan-kun, you've read this book too?
You've ruined the dream!
The time limit is 3 o'clock!
Let's get the best spot!
Yeah!
Someone's already got
the location under the tree!
Aww, that's the only place that's in the shade.
Ok, it's ready.
Horikoshi Masashi
Misa, sorry, could you pass me those pegs?
Tsuneyama Misa
Huh? P-p... What?!
Posts, to nail down the tent.
See, I mean those.
Then say so from the beginning!
This is the first time I've gone camping.
Ah, sorry, sorry.
I'll get them myself.
And why do we have to stay in this cheap tent?
Don't you have something like that one?
There are no tents like that one for rent...
That's what I mean. Why are we renting a tent?
Let's buy one.
Eh?
If you're going to invite me
camping, then that's the least you could do!
Go buy one right now if you have to.
She's saying crazy things, that woman.
You know that's impossible.
Then let's go to a pension.
I don't like this tent.
But I wanted to show you the fun part
of camping; that's why I brought you here.
It looks like there's already someone here.
Well then, any place around here is good.
Yes! Let's hurry and get the rental tents.
We're done!
Yeah.
Okay! Now let's go over
there and put up the girls' tent.
Hey, wait a minute!
No! I can't stand it anymore!
Don't say that, Misa...
I'm really going home now.
Misa!
Yes! It looks like the spot is open.
Lucky! Hey, Conan, let's hurry.
These guys are really energetic.
You got this one up in no time!
Yeah, it was easy since we're experts.
You shouldn't push yourself.
Why don't you get some sleep?
I'm okay. I'll stay awake to make the curry.
You're all really hungry, aren't you?
Hey, what's this?
Why did you put your tent here?
Wasn't this our spot?
It's because earlier you
said you were going home.
You did, didn't you?
Well, that's true, but...
I see, you changed your mind.
Huh? Hey, no joking around!
This is our spot!
B-But... We've already set everything up!
We just went to exchange the
tent because it had a hole in it.
Come on, hurry up and move your tent!
You're right, let's move the tent.
What?!
It's true that these people were here before us.
Okay, now that you've
got it, start moving your stuff.
It's okay, you can stay here.
What are you saying, Misa?
They just said they'd move.
We can just put ours over there.
I'm telling you this is the best spot.
Under this tree.
Sorry.
Damn it!
You should cut them into smaller pieces.
Eh?
At home, when you prepare curry
you have a lot of time to let it boil.
But you can't do that here.
You really know about this.
Please, let me.
Even though I might not look like
it, I know a lot about domestic stuff.
Cool!
What happened to your boyfriend?
It doesn't matter.
Eh?
We're almost over anyway.
Ah...
Things like that... A woman can tell.
Do you think this is okay?
Looks good to me.
They sure have everything at this camping store.
Yeah...
Did she wake up already?
Someone!
Someone come help! Quickly!
What happened?
Ran-oneesan's been kidnapped!
Oh my God!
Ran-neechan!
Ran-san!
Damn it! Where did they go?
She's not over here!
Damn it! Why Ran?
Ran!
Conan-kun!
What... was that?
It smells like medicine inside.
Maybe she passed out because she was drugged.
The get-away car has been reported.
They should be found soon.
I hope that's true...
The problem is why
would the criminal kidnap Ran?
There are so many other campers here...
What are you saying? You're really irresponsible!
You're the one who wanted to stay at a pension!
Come on, let's go now.
One of the people at this
camp has been kidnapped.
We can't leave now!
Come on, it doesn't concern us!
Of course it does!
He's still breathing.
These are the sneakers the man who
kidnapped Ran-kun was wearing, aren't they?
There's no doubt, they're the
same as the ones that man was wearing.
Do you mean the kidnapper has been found?
There was an automobile accident near here.
This is what they found
with the man driving the car.
The driver is still unconscious in the hospital.
Then what about Ran?
Professor, what about Ran?
We don't know about her.
The car was a normal sedan,
and there was no sign of her inside.
From the driver's license we obtained,
We know that the man is
Takada Masaeki, 25 years old.
An unsent message was
found on Takada's cell phone.
It's likely that he was writing the
message while driving and caused the accident.
What does the message say?
It doesn't seem to have been a random act.
All is done
The woman will
die at 3 PM
Get the promised money ready
It seems someone had asked Takada to do this.
It seems there's another file there.
Professor, let me.
Sneakers?
Rubber fishing boots.
Why are these things here?
Is that Ran-kun? No, maybe it's not.
I see! It's the tent!
It was the tent!
If you're just going to
leave now, I'll hate you forever.
Please go ahead.
I plan to never go out
with a woman like you again.
You only think about me as
a servant anyway. Screw you!
Why didn't you answer before?
I called many times, you
know! You got the wrong girl.
Takada Masaeki is in the
hospital due to an accident.
The police called you from his cell phone.
Hey! Where's Ran!
I don't know. I really don't know.
I asked Takada to kidnap the
girl in the tent under the tree.
But everything got
complicated when we changed spots.
I tried to contact him, but
Takada didn't answer his phone.
This picture is very blurred; you
could confuse her with Ran-kun.
What's the connection between you and Takada?
One day I saw him push a
guy onto the railroad track.
And I followed him, and
told him how to contact me.
A few days later, when I asked him to kill Misa,
He couldn't refuse...
Not when I told him I'd pay him a million yen.
Why Misa-san?
She is such a nuisance.
I couldn't live my own way.
She's selfish, always spends all
my money, and she's very nosy.
I couldn't break up with her even if I wanted.
I don't want? to ruin my life because of Misa.
That's Misa-san's line.
You're really the worst.
İf you're going to hate me I don't care.
But I can't allow you to involve other people.
Where is she?
Who knows, maybe she's already dead.
Ran-neechan is still alive.
There's no doubt.
Conan-kun!
At least until 3 PM.
The unsent mail message
said, "The woman will die at 3PM."
Let's go find Ran-neechan.
There are only 30 minutes left!
L-Let's go!
Come with us.
We'll hear everything at the station.
Why are we going to the river?
The kidnapper Takada had rubber fishing boots.
Between the time Ran-neechan was taken
and the accident, around 40 minutes passed.
He couldn't go far.
Yeah.
During the time he changed cars,
the only nearby river was...
Only 20 minutes left!
Since Takada had changed
cars, Ran must be still around here.
First, let's look for that 4-wheel drive car!
Let's go.
Don't do anything rash!
If you find her, notify me!
Where are you, Ran?
A dam? The dam drainage Channel!
Professor! The dam, head to the dam!
You're right, but there's
not much time left. I'm going!
Don't tell me they're draining it!
The 3 o'clock in Takada's mail was about this.
I know. She's somewhere that'll flooded.
Professor! Professor!
It's no use. I can't reach him!
Look at that!
Tho moss is up to that point.
That means the water will reach that high.
Even a car would be submerged.
I found it.
Are you serious?
Conan-kun!
Don't come! Stay there!
Ran! Thank God!
It's no use, it's locked.
Let's break the glass with this!
It's too hard.
Opening the drainage channel now.
Roger.
W-What's this siren for?
Oh! Don't tell me!
We did it!
Ran-neechan! Wake up!
Wake up!
The siren has...
Stopped.
Conan, we're in trouble!
It looks like the water's level is rising.
You two, go back!
But...
It's okay. Leave it to me!
Hurry up!
Wait!
Who are you? This is a restricted zone!
I-I know that!
The river bed! Some
children are still in the river bed!
P-Please stop the flow!
What did you say?!
Conan!
If we're going to get out of
here, there's only one chance.
It's really... bad, Conan!
It's dangerous here too! Let's go up!
Conan.
Conan-kun!
Now!
Genta, catch this!
Okay, Conan! Leave it to me!
Come on! We'll pull them in together!
Okay! Let's do it!
Yes!
I hope everyone's all right.
Conan.
Conan-kun.
I'm sorry... This was my fault.
When I realized it, I had to that nostalgic river side
Envisioning the sequel the dream I had yesterday
Oh that day you seemed so grown-up
Unable to even say goodbye, I hid under my umbrella
If we cross paths again... Oh please
That time, forget-me-not
Not like love, not like loving, not something that's changing
It's only you I like, and that's how I think it will always be
Holding onto my aimless feelings, I look back as people often do
Stopping the scene were we chanced to meet from fading gently away
I'm sorry.
I totally overslept.
Oh, curry! Can I have some too?
What's wrong with everyone?
Nothing much. We're just tired.
Hey, where's Conan-kun?
He's sleeping inside the tent.
Geez, he's always like that.
He plays until he wears
out, never thinking about later.
Oh well.
Hey! W-Why am I wearing my pajamas?!
Why? No way!
Hey...
The view has been kept
as it was in the Edo period.
You guys are like Momotaro.
This is just like the Momotaro legend!
Let's do it! Let's do it!
Hey hey!
A peach?
It's Momotaro's peach!
It can't be!
Next Conan, The
Momotaro Mystery Tour (Part One)
Next Conan's Hint
Mirror image
What's next time?
I'll tel this to you only, Conan.
Okay.
The truth is I was born from a peach...
Eh?