Today's story is about Momotaro.
The riddle behind the legend is explained.
Dogs, pheasants, monkeys, and
even demons come into the scene.
Seeing through to the one and only truth,
He looks like a child but
has the intelligence of an adult,
His name is: Detective Conan!
Momotaro-san.
The millet dumplings that you're carrying...
Could you please give one to me?
Huh? Momotaro?
According to the legend of Momotaro
Around the 7th century, the raging
demon-god Ura came from a distant land.
The Imperial Court dispatched the famous
and honored Kibitsuhiko no Mikoto to defeat it.
It is said the fight between them was the story
behind the legend, but this isn't the true story.
The truth, told in the
Nihon-Shoki, is that around 663 AD,
Translator's Note: The Nihon-Shoki are the ancient chronicles of Japan.
After losing the battle of Hakusukinoe,
when the Yamato army returned to Japan,
Kinojo (Demon's Castle)
They built many mountain castles as
protection against the enemy troops.
One of those was Kinojou, a castle
in Kibitsu in the Okayama prefecture.
Okoyama Prefecture
It seems that here, in Kibitsu,
was there legend began.
There are many ancient burial mounds in Kibitsu.
Of course they reflect the culture of those times,
But is wouldn't be wrong to sat that
people's various feelings are also buried there.
The Momotaro mystery tour
(Part One)
Tada!
If we're talking about Okayama, we
definitely have to mention Momotaro, don't we?
And if we're talking about Momotaro?
Millet dumplings!
Genta-kun, you're always thinking about food...
Well, there's the dog, right?
The pheasant!
The monkey!
Translator's Note: Onigashima, Demon's Island properly called Megijima is an island Japan's Inner Sea.
And the demons of Demon's Island!
Well, that's true, but...
Since this is our long-awaited
weekend trip in order to study history...
That's right.
Since this is for our lessons,
we should be more professional.
Or that's what I'd like to say, but
first I want to eat some mamakari.
Translator's Note: Mamakari is a sardine like fish found in Japan's Inner Sea.
Geez!
Professor, you're saying stuff like that too?
Oh sorry, sorry.
We finally made it to Okayama!
Next we have to change to the San-yo line.
Hurry! Hurry!
Hey, hey...
We don't need to hurry this much.
Look, the train's leaving!
Kurashiki Station North Exit
Kurashiki is definitely famous for its Bikan area and its white plaster walled streets.
Yeah, it's every traveling girl's dream.
But even more than that,
I really wanted to come here.
Good afternoon.
Translator's Note: Chibari (Tivoli) park was modeled after the famous Tivoli Park in Copenhagen
Kurashiki Chibori Park
If we're talking about Chibori Park...
Quit it already, Seiko!
Eh?
Are you sure you can say that, Saruwatari-kun?
It was thanks to the article I wrote that you
had enough publicity to become independent.
How much money do you think I lost over that?
Really?
I thought I'd given my
ex-classmate a discount price.
Knock it off!
Are you okay, Ayumi-chan?
What are you doing to Ayumi?
Sorry, sorry.
Are you okay? I'm really sorry.
Did you get hurt?
On the contrary, maybe it's
we who should be apologizing.
No, we were really
embarrassed to be seen acting so childishly.
Do you think it's good we got invited too?
Yeah, you're right.
That's not how to think...
Hey, have you both apologized?
Yes.
Missy, does the ice cream
we bought for you taste good?
Yes, it's delicious!
I'm glad.
What kind of apology is that?
You guys are all friends, aren't you?
I don't think you should be fighting.
Friends, huh?
Well, it is true we were
classmates in elementary school.
Some of us went to Tokyo and Osaka so...
This is our first meeting after almost 15 years.
We stopped seeing each other
when we were around your age.
Which means this is like a reunion party?
Huh? Sort of...
Sorry, we forgot to introduce ourselves.
I'm Agasa.
Sort of these kids' companion land chaperone.
I'm Ayumi. Yoshida Ayumi.
My name is Tsuburaya Mitsuhiko.
I'm Kojima Genta.
A-Ah, I'm Edogawa Conan.
We're the Detective Boys!
How well-mannered.
Momoi Naota
I'm Momoi Naota.
Kijima Yoyoi
I'm Kijima Yayoi. Nice to meet you.
Saruwatari Kengo
And these guys are Saruwatari Kengo,
Inui Seiko
Inui Seiko,
And Onitsura Mamoru.
Onitsura Mamoru
Detective Boys, huh?
When we were young we
had a group like that too.
And this meeting is to...
I'll tell them. It was my idea originally anyway.
We're here to support Momoi-kun's candidacy
And to celebrate his engagement to Yayoi!
Cool, you're a candidate.
And soon to be married.
Congratulations!
T-Thank you.
Momotaro and the pheasant
lady are getting married then?
You noticed it too, Mitsuhiko?
Yeah.
You guys are like Momotaro.
What do you mean?
Their names, isn't it?
It's because your last names ideograms
are the names of the Momotaro characters.
Momoi Naoto
Kijima Yayoi
Saruwatari Kango
Inui Saiko
Onitsura Mamoru
Momo, Kiji, Saru, Inu, Oni.
momo
peach
kiji
pheasant
saru
monkey
inu
dog
oni
Demon
You're truly detective boys.
You're right. That's why...
Because of our names, we performed a
Momotaro play when we were school kids.
What an old story.
How nostalgic...
And moreover, we really did
enjoy doing it. Especially Shunya.
Shunya?
Let's not worry about old things.
Instead, what are we going to do now?
I've planned various things.
Tomorrow can be the treasure hunt, right?
Eh?
Okay...
Treasure hunt?
I haven't heard about that.
I'll explain at dinner.
Well until then, we'll have some free time.
Okay, that's fine.
Bye, little missy.
We should get moving too.
Kurashiki Bikan (Scenic) District
This is the real Kurashiki.
How beautiful!
The view has been kept
as it was in the Edo period,
Isn't that right, Professor?
Yeah, almost all of this was build
by the people of Kurashiki back then.
They'd row their boats down the Kurashiki
river here to transport their various goods.
The east wall of the
Kurashiki Archaeology Museum here is
Kurashiki Archaeology Museum
One of the Bikan district's most beautiful things.
Here, at first from Kurashiki,
and then from the Kibi area
All kinds of antique porcelain
are being displayed and collected.
This really is studying something...
Being in touch with the past cultures is...
Really useful...
But this is definitely better!
It's really delicious.
It's true when they say mamakari is so delicious
you'd pawn everything to keep buying it!
And we eventually ended up here...
A peach?
Hey! It's a peach.
It's Momotaro's peach!
Great!
It can't be!
Just a little more, Genta-kun.
Go for it!
Don't let go!
Be careful.
I didn't think it would be real, but...
And inside we have...
What's with these envelopes?
And inside these we have...
What are these?
Some kind of code maybe!
A code!
If it's a code, it's not that hard?
Just around primary school level, isn't it?
But this will be practice.
Resolving this code... Could it lead
to the treasure of the Demon's Island?
Really?
This is just like the Momotaro legend!
Let's do it!
Hey, hey!
I'll' be resting somewhere around here.
Good luck, everyone.
Take care it from here, Shin'ichi.
Professor, did you set up this?
I don't know anything about this; it wasn't me.
But this should be more fun than studying.
You're lucky you found
something to do, aren't you?
See you.
Give me a break...
Okay! The Detective
Boys' treasure hunt starts now!
What is this drawing?
An eye... with eyebrows.
Um, could it be fire?
Hey, Conan-kun.
Yeah, that might be the way to read it...
And if you put hi (fire) and me (eye) together...?
Fire... Eye's Fire eyes...
Ah! Fire eyes!
It's the fire lookout!
Fire Lookout
Do you see anything?
Did you find something?
What's this?
Did you find it, Conan?
Y-Yeah...
It's the treasure!
Open it! Open it!
What's this? It's just junk...
This doesn't even have a battery.
We can definitely say this isn't a treasure.
What're you looking at, Conan-kun?
They were 6 fun years (if you don't count that).
What's "that thing?"
Who knows?
Maybe this is as time capsule.
A time capsule?
If it's someone's time capsule, is it okay
that we took it out without permission?
Yeah, maybe wasn't such a, good idea...
But it looks like someone else
was digging here before we did.
Maybe...
A rival... A treasure hunt rival!
Then we can't loose to them.
Let's solve the next clue, Conan.
Inside a house, the letters P-I-B-T-I-J.
What the heck is this?
It doesn't mean anything.
No, this is a letter replacement code.
What do you mean?
Move the letters a place back in the alphabet.
In other words... Before P...
It's O!
Right.
Next; the letter before I is H, right?
The next one is...
OHASHI?
The chopsticks used when eating?
Translator's Note: O-hashi can mean chopsticks.
No, it's probably a place.
And what's more, a place here in Kurashiki.
Huh?
What are you guys doing?
It's the lady we met earlier.
We were just solving this riddle...
Onee-san, what are you doing?
Aren't you going out with everyone else?
Yeah, well...
That's because they all don't like me.
You noticed that earlier, didn't you?
Why?
You're all classmates...
I've never been able to lie so
The publicity article I was
planning for Onitsura-kun's business
Was all about his underhanded moneylending.
And when Saruwatari-kun started his beauty salon,
I wrote about his ability really honestly.
I mean, he's so bad...
Then there's Yayoi.
We kinda fought over Momoi-kun.
Until recently, he had been going out... with me.
I see. That's why there was
some awkwardness between them.
Didn't Shunya-san come?
Oh! You're a very sharp detective.
If I'm not mistaken, he was the one
who directed your Momotaro play.
We would have wanted him
to come... if he was still alive...
He died?
Fifteen years ago, in a car accident...
That is why we didn't graduate together.
How sad.
He had a very strong sense of
justice, and he was such a good boy.
I'm sorry I got so dark.
Well, I'm going now.
Keep it up, Detective Boys!
I found it! That's it!
Ohashi, Ouhashi...
An old house!
This seems like an old movie set.
If I remember correctly, the Ouhashi family were
the wealthy owners of a salt mine in the old days.
This building has stood for at least 200 years.
I'm impressed, Mitsuhiko-kun.
Ah, it's no big deal.
I'm so glad I studied!
Okay! Let's look!
Here! I found it!
Again, someone's been here before us.
This junk again?
An old manga.
Old stationary.
Again "that thing" is mentioned.
Someone is definitely one step ahead of us again.
Okay, let's go to the next one! The next one!
Is this a square clown's face?
What do you call the letters on a cell phone...?
Lower-case letters, right?
You're right!
This is the small "t", this is a "u", and this is a "t" too.
And this one's an "a"...
But why is it backwards...?
T-U-T-A. Tsuta?
Tsuta, the plant?
Tsuta is "ivy" in English.
And if you add "square" this means...
I know! There, it's there!
Kurashiki Ivy Square
Kurashiki Ivy Square. This is it.
There's a a lot of ivy here!
See?
What a large place!
This used to be a spinning mill.
The people used the same buildings
to build a hotel and a museum here.
Okay, let's go find it!
Yeah!
There was nothing that looked right anywhere.
What does it mean?
So that's the trick!
Not only is the "a" backwards,
the whole thing is backwards.
Which means it's in the Ivy Square's...?
I see! The back yard!
I found it! It's here!
Is it treasure this time?
This again.
What? This stuff again?
It looks like we missed it again.
How boring!
It's that lady!
It's no use, she's already dead.
A dying message?
O-N-I. Oni?
Oni?
The criminal is an demon!
From the Momotaro legend!
No!
So, you guys discovered the body?
The Detective Boys!
Huh?
There they go...
If the murderer is an demon.
We'll be Momotaro.
And hunt him... I mean, arrest him!
Geez.
Hey, Inspector, are these the victim's things?
Ah, that's right.
Huh? This is strange isn't it?
What?
The stamp.
Why is it on the back of the pamphlet?
Dunno.
So what?
N-Nothing, sorry to bother you.
Because of their relationship to the victim,
the other four were called in to be questioned.
Ho ho! So this means no one has an alibi.
To be exact it means we were all alone.
But there were a lot of people in Chibori
Park. I'm sure someone should remember me.
That goes for me too.
I was relaxing in the lobby of a nearby hotel.
There were a lot of people there too.
Sorry about that, but it will be
difficult to get a concrete alibi for you two.
There's no problem with us is there?
We were both together all the time.
You were going out for a walk, right?
Yes, we were together all the time.
We were only separated
when we went to the bathroom.
And that didn't take more than five minutes.
Sorry to be rude, but I can't just
accept the testimony of your fiancee.
Moreover, upon investigating, we found
that you were going out with the victim.
B-But that's...
It seems everyone else here had
various troubles with the victim too.
Inspector Tsuyama, here they are.
Is that the peach case?
Yes, this may not be related to the case,
But we thought just to make
sure, we should show it to you.
Even though we only discovered the body,
we are obliged to assist in the investigation.
Could that be...?
The codes to find times capsules we buried.
Wow! I'm surprised.
The codes were something they had made 15
years ago to reveal where the time capsules were.
Fifteen years ago the five of them put what they
wanted into the time capsules and exchanged them.
And everyone buried one that wasn't his own,
To ensure they wouldn't know
where their own time capsule was,
And could honestly express their feelings.
The truth is that last night a
vandal broke into your primary school.
We think this case was
among the things vandalized.
Then these guys contacted us
and let us know that they found it.
It seems fate has drawn us together.
But what was he planning to do with this?
He probably just threw it away once
he knew he couldn't get money from it.
How about that, Inspector?
Seiko went to report on the
vandal and was killed instead.
No...
No, we don't think so.
We think differently, Onitsura-san.
Examination Room
No! I didn't do it!
I'm innocent.
Don't get me wrong.
At present, all of you are all
still potential suspects in this case.
Then isn't it strange I'm the only one left here!
How do you explain this dying message?
It seems you were mad at the
victim for writing a bad article about you.
Hey, do you think Mamoru really did it?
Stop it, Saruwatari-kun!
It might be true.
You too, Momoi-kun?
In this world, who knows who might kill whom.
This is no time for a treasure hunt.
Hotel Kurashiki
So it was an demon (Oni) after all.
We should have caught him.
Really, Genta-kun! You're
using them the wrong way.
The knife goes in the right
hand and the fork in the left.
I can't help it! I'm a righty so I
want the fork to be in my right hand!
Should I get you some chopsticks?
Please say so at the beginning, Professor!
I see, so that's what it meant!
This would totally change the dying message.
Now I'm sure the murderer is among those four.
But to be sure, I need to
solve the other two codes,
And find the buried time capsules!
When I realized it, I had to that nostalgic river side
Envisioning the sequel the dream I had yesterday
Oh that day you seemed so grown-up
Unable to even say goodbye, I hid under my umbrella
If we cross paths again... Oh please
That time, forget-me-not
Not like love, not like loving, not something that's changing
It's only you I like, and that's how I think it will always be
Holding onto my aimless feelings, I look back as people often do
Stopping the scene were we chanced to meet from fading gently away
If you knew we would dig up the time capsules,
Why did you do that?
He said he had something to check out,
So he went alone to the library.
Thinking that something might happen,
I, Tsuburaya Mitsuhiko, took notes!
How wise!
Awesome, Mitsuhiko!
The Momotaro Mystery Tour
(Part Two)
Next Conan's Hint
Left Hander
The next time we'll get the demon!
No, Conan, I was actually born from a bamboo...
Huh?