One after the other, we unbury the time capsules.
From the scattered mysteries,
We dig up an unexpected culprit.
Seeing through the one and only truth,
He looks like a child but
has the intelligence of an adult,
His name is: Detective Conan!
Professor Agasa, the Detective Boys and I,
Went on a weekend cultural trip to
Kurashiki, Kibiji in Okayama District.
There, a woman from a group of
five friends we had just met was killed.
And now one of the men from this group
is being questioned as the prime suspect.
But... I had my doubts.
I see, so that's what it meant!
This would totally change the dying message.
The murderer is one of those four.
But, to be sure, I need to solve the other two codes.
The Momotaro Mystery Tour
(Part Two)
Kurashiki Bikan (Scenic) District Ima Bridge
I have no proof.
But if the murder's reason is
related to the time capsules,
That means...
Let's continue breaking the remaining codes.
Huh?
I agree! Let's do this until the end!
There may be no treasure, but kind of
feel we can't leave this for later. I'm in too.
I feel so too.
But... how?
The codes were burned up.
Ah... you're right.
Thinking something like that could happen...
Tada!
I, Tsuburaya Mitsuhiko, took notes!
How wise, Mitsuhiko-kun!
Awesome, Mitsuhiko!
Okay! The Detective Boys re-open the case!
Yeah!
This is... an umbrella, right?
And this, is the sun, right?
Hey, you did copy them exactly?
Could this mean...?
Yeah, that's it.
The professor's really late...
What could he be doing?
Ah! Maybe he's in that car!
Professor, you're late!
Yeah, sorry about that.
So, where exactly are we going?
To the neighboring the Souja
district. In other words, to Kibiji.
Roger that!
Kibiji?
To be exact, we're going to Koumorizuka mound.
It's a really famous burial mound in Kibijn.
Oh! I understand. That's what this is.
You're right, Genta-kun.
Kasa, or koumorigasa.
I see!
Oh, I almost forgot!
I have new information about the case.
Now, instead of Onitsura-san,
the prime suspect is Saruwatari-san.
He's being questioned now.
Of course, he denies everything about the murder.
Stop joking!
But, it seems this goes back to 15 years
ago, when the Momotaro play was presented.
It seems there was a switch in the roles.
A switch?
Onitsura-san was apparently
really bad at learning his part,
So he had switched his
demon role with Saruwatari-san.
So now the demon in the dying
message may have been about Saruwatari-san.
He doesn't have an alibi, and what's
more, he was the one fighting with the victim.
It seems they will arrest him soon.
I had a feeling he was the one.
After all, dogs and monkeys don't get along.
But, in the Momotaro legend, they
get along and hunt down the demons.
In the end that's only a legend.
I'm a little disappointed.
Anyway we have to hurry.
We won't prove anything
unless we check all the capsules.
How beautiful!
It gives me a nostalgic feeling.
This area has been known as
the land of millet since long ago.
Kibiji
The people boasted that it rivaled the
lands of the Yamato emperor in resources.
How impressive!
It's one of the so-called "keyhole shaped mounds."
We should be able to go inside.
H-How scary.
This Koumorizuka burial mound is
believed to have been here since the 6th century,
And there have been many more
burial mounds discovered here in Kibiji.
This is really getting to be like
a treasure hunting adventure!
But it's a really big place. It'll be hard.
Finding a treasure is a job for the Detective Boys!
And... it's almost sure
someone has already unburied it,
So it'll be easy to find.
Here! I found it!
Again?
Yes, again.
Someone is always digging them out before us.
There's just this paper inside.
What's this?
Another code?
Mitsuhiko, you got cheated!
The code you have is a dummy.
Eh, a dummy?
You mean it's a fake?
Yeah, look at that code very carefully.
Under a sun, a half opened umbrella.
No need to use it.
No meaning to it.
The real code is the one we just got.
Let's see, a Shinto archway and this is...?
Isn't this a Japanese pot?
Like the ones used to make rice?
And on top of it. Could it be a peach?
A Shinto archway, a peach and a Japanese pot...
I have heard that combination somewhere before.
Kibitsu temple!
Kibitsu temple?
Yes!
The actual basis of the story of
Momotaro confronting the demons
The defeat of the demon-god Ura by the
esteemed Kibitsuhiko no Makoto, is enshrined there.
There are the fruits of your studies.
Very well done!
I see! So the peach refers to Momotaro.
And the Shinto archway represents the temple!
Then what about the Japanese pot?
Umm... well that's...
That's something we'll find out there, I think.
Okay then, I'll wait for you here.
No fair!
Hey, hurry up, Detective Boys.
Kibitsu Temple
I'm tired.
I'm hungry.
Okay, let's go!
Ah! Wait, Conan-kun.
Wait up!
Let's take it easy.
I'm still hungry!
A Japanese pot.
So that's what it meant.
Yeah.
The special feature of the Japanese pot
Today it sounds again, the special
sound of the is a message a luck
By listening to the Japanese
pot, you can predict your luck...
Wow, that's interesting.
Okay!
There's no doubt we're close!
Let's look for it.
There's a chance it's already been unburied.
That'll be our approach!
I found it!
It seems it's not a dummy one this time.
Yeah, this one still just has a lot of junk.
Don't call it junk.
Yeah, this is a treasure from 15 years ago.
Shunya-kun, rest in peace.
Shunya?
The one who died in a car accident 15 years ago.
I understand now!
The notes in the time capsules up to
now were, all talking about Shunya-kun.
Yeah... that's likely.
So that means that in the last time capsule is...
We're going back to Kurashiki?
Could this be petals?
And this is a leaf, and the center...
But this is all broken apart.
Ah! Maybe you have to put them together?
This is... a water lily?
Huh?
Yep. And if we talk about water lilies in Kurashiki?
You're talking about that place!
Ah!
Where?
Oohara Art Museum
Here.
The Oohara Art Museum
Water lilies.
How cute!
So the capsule is here...
No, these water lilies are all too recent.
Sign: Regarding the water lilies, In the year 2000 (Heisei 12), to
celebrate the 70th anniversary of the founding of the Oohara Art
Museum, these water lilies were brought from Monet's pond in Giverny, France.
It says they were planted in 2000
to celebrate the 70th anniversary.
This means the code is referring to
the painting of the famous artist, Monet.
It's more likely that at the
time this painting was here...
This place is too big.
Until now, it was so easy to find them.
Walk 25 more steps.
What's up?
Hey, maybe the "walk 25 more steps" in this code,
Has something to do with this statue.
Is that right?
I see! If we walk 25 more steps in this direction!
Eh? Huh?
It's here!
I'm impressed, Ayumi-chan.
You're really smart to figure that out.
But this is strange.
This one has no paper inside.
I thought so...
Oooh, what's this?
It was pasted on the bottom.
It seems this one's different from the others.
Monmodanonkibou
What's this?
Ah, everyone...
You're related to that detective, Sleeping Kogorou,
I mean Mouri Kogorou-san.
M-Mouri?
Kogorou?
You mean...
We just received a call from Mouri-san,
Saying I should ask Agasa-san to explain everything.
Agasa...?
Ehh? Me?
Mouri-san said you had an exceptional
mystery solving ability, comparable to his own.
And who is this Kogorou-san?
What business could you have with us now?
I'm counting on you, Professor.
Yeah, well, you see...
Ehh, now I'll let you know what my deductions are.
Saruwatari-san here, whom
you believe is the criminal is...
Actually innocent.
The real murderer is another person here.
That's what I told you!
S-So, what now? Does this
mean it really was Onitsura-san...
Quit joking! I didn't do it.
Well, well, let me explain it in order.
Fifteen years ago, each of you put your
valuable things into different time capsules.
And then exchanged them.
And buried them in different places.
Seiko-san's capsule was buried
by Momoi-san at the fire tower.
Onitsura-san's capsule was buried
by Seiko-san in the Oohashi house.
Saruwatari-san's capsule was
buried here in Ivy Square by Onitsura-san.
Yayoi-san's capsule was buried by Saruwatari-san.
He actually put a dummy clue to Koumorizuka
mound and then buried it in the Kibitsu Temple.
And last, comes Momoi-san's
capsule in the Oohara Museum.
This one was buried by Yayoi-san, am I right?
These were all unburied by the Detective Boys.
But the problem is, they had already
been unburied once by someone before them.
I already told you, this was done by
someone who vandalized the school.
There's something we just couldn't figure out.
Why didn't the last capsule, Momoi-san's,
Have a note, like everybody else's capsule did?
Eh?
That's because I'm not the
type of person who does that.
That's all.
No, you had actually written one, didn't you?
To find it and destroy it was your goal.
And that's what Seiko-san
discovered, right, Momoi-san?
W-What did you say?
You?
Na-Naoto...
Quit joking!
What proof do you have?
Let me explain.
First, concerning the dying message.
The deceased's fingers position is the key.
The finger's position?
The deceased Seiko-san was a left hander.
So I believe that the dying message was
almost certainly written with her left hand.
But if that's the case, then there's something strange.
It shouldn't be beside the first
letter 'O' but on the last part of the 'l'.
Th-That's right...
But then, there are cases were
left handed people write backwards.
This is also true, isn't it?
Therefore, looking at the finger's position
She didn't write from left to right.
Rather, from right to left, backwards.
And if we link the missing bit...
I see. She didn't try to write "ONI".
"MO!" She was trying to write "MOMO."
Exactly.
This means "Oni" didn't mean
Onitsura-san or Saruwatari-san.
Momoi-san is the criminal.
Th-That's crazy!
This is all speculation!
I even have an alibi.
Yayoi-san.
You said you were walking with
Momoi-san in the Bikan district, didn't you?
And you were only separated for
about five minutes to go to the facilities.
Ah, yes.
It's not directly obvious, but it's
really nothing once you know about it.
How about it, Detective Boys?
Yes!
Ivy Square and the Bikan
district are actually wall to wall.
If you run through the front
part, it's a really long distance.
But if you go through the back part,
and through empty land it's pretty close.
Total time, 1 minute and 50 seconds.
I think you first had Seiko-san waiting here.
Then, you ran all the way
here, killed her, and ran back.
Na-Naoto!
You're wrong! That's a lie!
And, then...
After the criminal killed Seiko-san,
He dug up the remaining capsules.
This should have taken about an hour.
The murder occurred around two in the afternoon.
Yayoi-san, after that...
Did he leave you and go
somewhere... for about an hour?
Y-Yes.
He said he needed to do some research
And he'd go by himself to libraries and bookshops.
You're only supposing things!
You don't have a single shred of proof.
Of course I have proof.
Inside your wallet, in fact.
Eh? In my wallet, you say?
It seemed that Onitsura-san was the
criminal and also the school vandal.
To make that look right, you, the real
criminal took out the contents of the victim's wallet.
But you couldn't just throw them away like that.
You put them in your wallet, and you still have them.
Let me see that!
Where's the proof that Seiko's money is in my wallet?
Inspector Tsuyama, did you bring that thing?
Huh? Oh, you mean the
thing Mouri-san was talking about?
This is it, right?
Inspector Tsuyama, please check the wallet.
Do you see a bill with something strange on it?
Something strange?
Th-This!
A-And what are you saying this means?
Just because a bill has some dirt I'm the criminal?
Momoi-san... how do you explain this?
You could just say, "The
ticket stamp just got on the bill."
If this was a normal situation.
But having half a stamp in your wallet,
And the other half on the
museum pamphlet in Seiko-san's wallet?
Seiko-san probably kept the
pamphlet along with the bill,
And then they were stamped.
You didn't know that,
So you left the pamphlet at the
crime scene, and took only the money.
By coincidence, you took
the bill with the stamp on it too.
It was all because... Seiko
and that thing 15 years ago.
She started investigating now...
about what happened 15 years ago.
Fifteen years ago...
Everything started then.
At that time, the young Momoi
was always bullied by other kids.
That day when Momoi was being forced
into robbing, Shunya-kun saw everything.
Momoi-kun!
I thought I was going to be punished.
By my teachers, by my parents...
That's what i thought.
The young Momoi didn't tell anyone about it.
But he wrote in a memo he placed in the
time capsule about the sin he had committed.
It was almost graduation anyway.
I was going to be parting ways with all of them.
I thought I'd never have to unbury it... at that time.
Three days ago, I received a call from Seiko.
She said she wanted to unbury
the time capsule for some research.
And for that one piece of
paper you went into the school...
You didn't have to kill her!
That stupid thing, you could've thrown
it anywhere, and that would've been it!
Hey, where do you think I am now?
The capsule I buried had already been dug up!
Only you, Momoi-kun, knew right?
About me wanting to unbury the time capsules.
Why did you do it?
Could there be a scoop here?
Are you an idiot?
You know she's always been like that!
I was scared.
I felt like she had discovered everything.
Miss, we found this in the last capsule.
You can tell us the rest at the
police department, Momoi-san.
Wait!
Please, all together.
One last time.
There's somewhere I want all of us to go.
This cod, you put this in the capsule, didn't you?
It was a favor.
Some time before Shunya-kun passed away,
He asked me to put this in with the time capsule.
But after the accident I got
scared and I didn't even look inside.
That code is an anagram, right?
Yes, you write them all in hiragana, and
re-arrange them, you get the real answer.
Mo-no-mo-ki-da-no-n?
Monotano... What?
The Peach Tree Adventure Club
It's "Momo no ki bouken dan."
It was our group's name.
We used to come here a lot.
Yeah, to come out and play and
to talk about the Momotaro play.
This is Shunya's.
Momoi-kun looked so cool
in his Momotaro character.
Next time I'll! become
Momotaro and save Momoi-kun.
I'll make those guys leave Momoi-kun alone!
But, I'll keep this a secret
from the teachers and parents.
It will always, always be a secret.
Could it be?
Maybe Shunya-kun jumped in to save you, mister.
Don't you bully my friend!
If he had just remembered that time.
I felt it, when I was a kid.
That it hadn't been an ordinary car accident.
But I couldn't say anything.
I didn't do anything.
I feel awful.
I didn't even feel sorry.
My sin was way deeper.
I surely... I was sure...
I had the face of a demon.
Only you can destroy the demons in your heart.
Because you're Momotaro.
When I realized it, I had to that nostalgic river side
Envisioning the sequel the dream I had yesterday
Oh that day you seemed so grown-up
Unable to even say goodbye, I hid under my umbrella
If we cross paths again... Oh please
That time, forget-me-not
Not like love, not like loving, not something that's changing
It's only you I like, and that's how I think it will always be
Holding onto my aimless feelings, I look back as people often do
Stopping the scene were we chanced to meet from fading gently away
Sign: The Lover's Mermaid - According to legend a couple will gave good
fortune if they throw on the mermaid princess. Did you know that?
Kurasihiki Chibori Park
Eh? The lovers'...
Don't mind that!
Yeah! Now it's sure
Conan-kun will be Ayumi's Momotaro!
Huh?
N-No way!
What about us?
Genta-kun will be the pig, and
Mitsuhiko-kun will be the kappa.
Those are Son Goku's characters!
You guys! Then I'm a hot dog?
Furisode Hanya?
It means that this is a room locked by the snow.
What could Ran and the others be doing?
The legend of the Furisode Hanya!
The Case of the Long Sleeved Kimono at
the Hidden Hot Spring on a Snowy Night
(Part One)
Next Conan's Hint!
Open air bath.
A secret hot spring?
The long sleeved kimono case?
I don't understand.