Today's stage is an inn.
A hidden hot spring with a scary legend.
Leftover evidence reveals the hot spring's case!
Seeing through to the one and only truth,
I look like a child but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
Detective Conan!
Case of the Furisode at the Hidden Hot Spring,
Part 1!
Man, this pain in my shoulder has been getting worse lately...
Our hot spring will soothe away that shoulder pain.
Whoa...
Owner, are these the desserts for tonight?
Sorry to disappoint you, but a customer asked me to bring that.
It seems that she really likes to eat cakes.
I heard she's a famous writer.
Conan-kun, you wanted to eat that, didn't you?
Eh... Well...
Welcome. We've been expecting you for a while now.
Weren't you cold? Come, please come in.
Ah! These furisodes are so beautiful!
The garden is so spacious too.
Hey, isn't that Akechi Eri-san, the love story writer?
Ow... That hurts!
Father...
Could you be that Detective Mouri?
Mouri Kogoro-san, aren't you?
Mo-Mouri?
I'm right, aren't I?!
Yes. That's me.
It's an honor for me to meet you here, Mouri-san.
I'm Nichiuri TV's producer, Bandou Kyouichi.
Oh, really?
It's not very comfortable standing and talking here...
Eh... What are you doing all gathered over here?
Actually, the editor of Daigakukan Publishing and I...
are discussing scripts Akechi Eri-sensei wrote for a new drama airing next spring.
The drama is about three teenage girls trying to achieve their dreams.
Because of that, I'm interviewing young women who are active in each field.
Thus, we've invited three girls who graduated from Yoriko-san's alma mater, Oodou University.
A fashion model active in Paris and New York, Shibazaki Asuka-san.
Hi there.
Whoa... Beautiful!
Well, the next girl won the "Best Newcomer Award" in the Kyoto Art Show, oil painter Ansai Ema-san.
Nice to meet you.
Charming!
Last but not least, is the music world's recent
You're the singer and songwriter, Fukatsu Harumi-san, right?
I'm a big fan of yours.
Thank you...
Look, you've become quite famous for only having a one-hit wonder.
But that'll end soon, just like all the others before you.
The three of you sure have three different personalities. They're also all very beautiful, right?
It's this way.
Ah! There are beautiful furisodes here too.
Say, why is every room decorated with furisodes and obis?
It's because the temple to worship Furisode-sama is close by.
Every household has them decorated in this way. It's very common.
Eh? Furisode-sama, huh?
I'm eager to see your new work, Akechi-sensei.
Please, call me Eri.
But... My mother's name is also Eri.
And it feels weird saying "Eri-sensei."
They're written differently, though.
I know what you mean. When people call me "Akechi-sensei,"
it sounds like a detective investigating, and it makes me feel embarrassed.
I heard that a god called Furisode-sama is worshiped around here.
Yeah... However,
there's a dark side to Furisode-sama known as Furisode-Hannya.
Furisode-Hannya?
It's from an old folk legend.
A long time ago, a woman named Ohana lived in this village. She was kind and hardworking.
One day, Ohana found a wounded samurai and nursed him back to health.
In return, he gave her many beautiful furisodes and obis.
Seeing that, the sisters became envious and accused her of slander.
They called the magistrates to take away her furisodes.
The night of Ohana's execution, the sisters stole her furisodes and obis.
While they were celebrating, a cold breeze blew the lights out.
Awakened by the miserable screams, the rest of the family ran to see what happened.
The furisodes were spread out across the floor, and the younger sister had stopped breathing.
The elder sister was found dead in the garden pond, entangled by the obis.
After that, the villagers all knew about Ohana's deep hatred,
so they made a shrine to be the village's protector.
Thus, Furisode-sama could be worshiped anywhere.
That hotel is also known as "Furisode-sama's Mansion."
You seem to know a lot about it.
Yes... I stay in that hotel quite frequently and collect information for my writing.
H-Hey, isn't that Harumi-san?
That's her.
Harumi-san!
This tree is called "Furisode Sakura." It's nearly 500 years old now.
In the spring, the tree's branches will be covered in sakura.
It'll look just like a beautiful furisode.
Harumi-san, are you familiar with this village as well?
Huh? No.
It's because my senpai in the university liked sakura a lot,
and she told me about this sakura tree here.
I just remembered that, so I came here to see it for myself.
Hey, hey, Ran-neechan?
What's that shrine for?
Now, look! You little brat, you can't keep running off somewhere all the time!
That's the shrine to pay tribute to Furisode.
Tribute to Furisode?
Furisode-sama is also the god of vengeance.
V-Vengeance?!
According to the legend, those who wear furisode come to pay tribute at midnight.
They're unable to get revenge with their current strength,
so Furisode-sama will get revenge on their behalf.
The Chiyogami dolls in it were contributed by those who paid visits to Furisode-sama.
There are some new dolls here!
Two new ones!
What? What did you say?!
This means that someone has paid tribute to Furisode.
It means they have two people they want to get revenge on.
No matter what, it's just a practical joke.
Don't take it so seriously, Ran.
Say, that's not the shrine, is it?
Don't be annoying. It's just the guest room.
There is a place there to worship Furisode-sama, though.
C-C-Could there be even more Chiyogami dolls inside?
H-How could that be?
But I'm worried about it!
Come on, Dad. Let's go have a look at it.
You mean me?
Yep.
Really, that Ran...
How could there be dolls over here?
See? I was right.
Yeah...
There's nothing else here!
Really?! That's good!
Amazing!
It's just like the picture in the pamphlet!
This is paradise; it's paradise!
"This is paradise; it's paradise."
How beautiful!
Cheers!
Everyone, for being able to interview you all these past four days,
I want to thank you all so much.
Eri-san, please let me be the character who has the most screen time in the drama.
Now, now. I haven't even decided on how the story will go yet.
That's why I'm asking you now.
Oh yeah, Bandou-san!
Just let Harumi-san write the theme song!
Ah... That's a good idea!
I'm counting on you now.
If her popularity keeps up, that is.
This is tasty, Conan-kun.
Yeah.
What? Is it empty before I even opened it?
How could that be possible?
Ran-chan. Get me another bottle.
Just one. Just one bottle's enough.
Then I won't drink anymore, Ran-chan!
No way.
Come on. Conan-kun, you're tricky.
Hey, is now a good time?
Yes, please come in!
Oh, Harumi-san!
Actually, I wanted to find Mouri-san to discuss something with him.
D-Dad?
Dad!
Discuss?
Huh? What's going on? I thought something happened...
Five years ago, when I was a third-year in the university,
an illegal drug became popular on campus.
Searching for the seller of all those drugs,
investigators found the name of a girl.
She denied it, but drugs were found inside her locker.
So, in order to prove her innocence,
she jumped from the university's rooftop and died.
Her name is Suzuka Sakurako-san, and she was the senpai who loved sakura under the Furisode tree.
There's no way the senpai I knew could have secretly been a drug dealer.
Mouri-san, please.
One more time. Investigate this case one more time, please.
It's been five years already...
Actually, there was a rumor mentioning another culprit.
However, those students... They... are the children of a powerful family.
Nobody in school dares to speak badly of these girls.
G-Girls?
Shibazaki Asuka-san and Anzai Ema-san.
Asuka-san is the daughter of the senator Shibazaki.
Ema-san is the daughter of the Anzai Group's president.
These two were always fighting with Sakurako-san, who had a strong sense of justice.
Mouri-san, please look into this!
I understand.
I'll definitely try my best to help.
Thank you very much!
You must really like that senpai, huh?
I lost my parents when I was little.
My aunt and uncle brought me up.
Sakurako-san's parents also died, in a fire.
So, we got along very well.
Oh? You're going to bathe in the hot spring?
Are you going to take a bath in the hot spring too, Eri-sensei?
Yes. It's a little cold.
How about we go for a drink afterwards?
Sorry.
I still have some work I need to get done.
See you later then.
Eh? Someone already reserved it.
Really?
The door's locked.
We have no choice then. We have to wait another half hour.
In the meantime, let's go play ping-pong.
Yeah, let's do that.
They sound really busy in the next room.
What're Ran and the others doing?
I'm ready!
Good!
Huh? You finished your bath already?
Nope. We haven't taken it yet...
because the bath was being reserved for someone else.
Oh? You're wearing glasses, Harumi-san?
I forgot to bring my contacts,
so I just put these on.
It's 11:30pm now.
The bath was only rented until 11pm, and it's past that.
Yeah, let's go now.
Huh? Wh-Where are you going?
Women's hot spring.
Wh-What?!
Huh? They're still in there?
It's really locked up tight.
What is this thing?
That wasn't here earlier.
It feels a little cold in my hands. Gives me the chills.
What is this?!
Wh-What happened?
Furisode-Hannya.
Uncle, break down the door!
Stay back!
Dad...
Alcohol's worn off now...
Conan-kun, is anyone there?
Yes, but...
Asuka-san!
Asuka-kun!
Asuka-kun, hold on!
Too late. She's been stabbed in her chest.
The Legend of Furisode-Hannya...
Don't tell me that...
Conan-kun, where are you going?!
In the legend, both sisters were killed...
Huh? What's wrong?
Asuka-san...
What's going on?
Asuka-san was... in the bath...
She's been murdered by someone!
Wh-What was that?!
No way!
Where's Ema-san?
If I remember correctly, she went that way about an hour ago.
Footprints from Ema-san's boots...
Did she run over that way?!
Uncle, be careful not to step on these tracks.
Of course! What do you think I am, an amateur or something?
Just as I thought, is this Furisode-Hannya?
It's the same situation here. Her chest was stabbed.
There are only Ema-san's footprints outside.
This means that this is a secret room which was concealed by the heavy snowfall.
Excuse me.
I was sent to help Detective Mouri-san.
Really?
I'm the patrolman in this village, Omura.
Have you contacted the main police station?
Yes. I called them.
But because of the heavy snow, the earliest they can arrive is tomorrow morning.
Tomorrow morning...
No choice then...
It's up to us to search and protect the crime scene.
Landlady, bring me ten large towels.
S-Sure!
Everyone, please wait in the living room.
S-Sure...
A little slower, Omura-san.
Right. Cover the footprints lightly. A little lower...
If you walk along this route after the long corridor, you'd reach the back door.
However, there isn't a single footprint.
Eh... That's strange...
What is it? Something's just not right here.
Hey! The snow will cover the footprints if you open that!
All of you are here...
Oh, that. Eri-sensei told us that we needed to sit down.
Have you figured anything out yet?
Yoriko-san, Ema-san passed by this lobby around 10:30pm, right?
Yes. That's correct.
Did you see anyone else walk by?
No, no one else.
Well, this could be troublesome now...
Wh-What's going on?
First, the shrine where Ema-san was killed:
Snow revealed that only Ema-san's footprints were there.
So then, Ema-san committed suicide?
No. No trace of a weapon was discovered at the crime scene.
That can't be...
Next is the hot spring where Asuka-san was killed:
You'd also need to pass by the recreation area to get there.
However, we were there since 10:30pm.
If someone walked by, we'd know about it.
What if someone were to climb from the mountain valley to the cliff and got in there?
I checked the cliff. It didn't have any suspicious traces.
This means Asuka-san might've been killed before 10:30pm.
There was a knife and a stun gun found at the bottom of the hot spring.
The culprit most likely used the stun gun to make the victim faint,
then they killed her.
The knife's hilt is decorated with a shell-like design.
I'll need to confirm this with the landlady, but...
I heard that it's the holy knife that was donated as part of the shrine in the garden.
The holy knife...
One more thing.
Ema-san's bandana was found in the open-air hot spring.
The bandana had blood stains on it.
What does that mean?
That... In short...
In short, both of them were killed with the same knife.
So, we know that the culprit killed Ema-san first, then went after Asuka-san.
Also, Ema-san had to have still been alive before 10:30pm,
since Asuka-san hadn't been killed before that time.
How did the culprit get into the hot spring, though?
There weren't any footprints around the shrine in the garden.
It wasn't a ghost, so how could this happen?
It's the curse!
Furisode-Hannya's curse!
Wh-What do you mean?!
We saw them!
There were two new Furisode dolls in the Holy Mansion's shrine!
Asuka and Ema were killed by Furisode-Hannya's curse!
H-How could this happen?
That kind of curse definitely doesn't exist.
However, what kind of trick did the culprit use?
They visited Furisode!
Sakurako-san visited Furisode and wanted revenge on those two people!
So, that's how it is...
Exactly. That's why... That's why Senpai...
Wait! Why are your socks all wet?
Hold on. Ran-neechan, wait!
Next Conan: Case of the Furisode at the Hidden Hot Spring, Part 2!
Next Conan's Hint!
Obi.
Do you have an obi, Ran-neechan?
I have a black belt in karate.
That's not quite the same...