Today's deduction is really shocking.
The trick uses a normal time difference in sledding...
to create the perfect alibi!
Seeing through to the one and only truth,
I look like a child but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
Case of the Furisode at the Hidden Hot Spring,
Part 2!
Asuka-san went into the open-air hot spring around 10pm.
Ema-san went to the garden's shrine around 10:30pm.
Both of them were killed by this holy knife.
This knife was found in the hot spring, which means...
the culprit murdered Ema-san first, then went after Asuka-san.
Furthermore, the shrine, which is located in the garden,
has footprints only from Ema-san's boots.
In order to get to the hot spring, one would have to go through the recreation area,
but people were there from around 10:30pm onwards.
My, my...
They're both locked rooms.
They visited Furisode!
Sakurako-san visited Furisode and wanted revenge on those two people!
Sakurako-san?
Who is she?
She's my senpai from my university.
Those two framed her of running secret drug-dealing operations.
Because of that, she committed suicide.
The "two" as in the murdered, Asuka-san and Ema-san?
Exactly.
That's why...
That's why Senpai had...
Officer Masaki.
In the shrine, one of the corpse's earrings is missing.
This is the one that's left.
That's... a brand name.
Just a single one of them costs about 200 thousand yen.
Then a pair costs 400 thousand yen...
Even though it's not cheap, it can't be the only reason to kill someone.
Oh, yeah! I think Harumi-san has a pendant of the same brand.
Yeah. But...
Ema-san seemed unhappy when she saw me wear the pendant, so I immediately took it off.
I see. Other than that, we found this in Ema-san's coat pocket.
And the furisodes and obis left in the scene...
were those kept in the storage room of this hotel,
which is normally left unlocked.
So anyone could've taken them out?
The culprit most likely placed them there beforehand.
Now, let's review what each of you did last night.
First off, Eri-san.
You went to the open-air hot spring around 9:30pm...
and came out around 10pm.
Asuka-san went into it afterwards.
Yes, I went back to my room after that.
I met Mouri-san and the others halfway, and we talked there.
Yeah, I was thinking of asking Eri-san to have a drink at that time.
Then?
Yoriko-san was starting to reorganize the content of the interview here at 9:30pm.
This means...
Yes, I saw Eri-san.
Five minutes later, I saw Ema-san head toward the back door there.
That's around 10:30pm.
Did you see anyone else go to the back door?
No, no one.
At that time, Mouri-san and the others went to the open-air hot spring.
However, there was a "rented out" sign on the door of the women's hot spring.
Moreover, the door was locked.
So then, the two of you went back to the recreation room.
Yes.
Mouri-san, did anything strange happen while bathing?
There was.
We heard a strange splashing sound from the women's hot spring.
What time was it?
It was definitely around 10:50pm.
Wasn't that the time of the crime?
Yes...
But it was only the splashing sound and no scream.
Isn't that strange?
That's because the culprit used the stun gun to make her faint before she screamed.
Really?
Of course! You little brat, don't interrupt the investigation!
Ran-san and Harumi-san didn't leave the recreation room?
No, I forgot to wear my contact lenses,
so I went back to my room for about 10 minutes.
I understand.
And no one else passed the recreation room during that time?
Yes.
Mouri-san came out of the men's hot spring around 11pm.
Eri-san and Yoriko-san were here discussing at that time.
Wait, what about Bandou-san?
I joined their discussion around 11:15pm.
And that's when Mouri-san and the others found Asuka-san's body in the hot spring.
About the dolls of Furisode-Hannya:
They weren't on the ground in the beginning, right?
Yes, there's no doubt about it.
Next, Ema-san's body was found in the shrine.
Why did Ema-san go to the shrine?
Good question.
This is the reason:
"Ema-san, there's something I would like to talk to you about in secret.
Tonight at 10:30pm,
I'll be waiting for you at the shrine in the backyard.
- Bandou."
H-How can that be?!
I never wrote that letter!
You don't have an alibi before 11:15pm.
B-But I don't have a motive to murder them!
Now, the only one who seems to have a motive...
appears to be Harumi-san.
What?! I...
You felt hatred toward both of them because of your senpai who had committed suicide.
Besides, you don't have an alibi during the time you went back to your room for your contact lenses.
I... I'd never do that!
No matter who the culprit is,
if the mystery of the sealed-room isn't solved, we won't get anywhere.
If both of them were murdered by different weapons,
it'd be a bit easier to justify.
Besides, why did the culprit make the scene look like what had been described in the Furisode-Hannya legend?
Thank you. Thank you.
Here's the delivery.
It's finally here, the autopsy report.
The weapon which killed both of them is the holy knife.
I see...
If the weapon had been different,
this problem would've been easier to handle.
So the weapons were the same...
That bandana has traces of only Ema-san's blood.
Also, the dolls from the scene, the Holy Mansion and other areas,
and Ema-san's letter: We couldn't find any fingerprints or information that related to the culprit on them.
Thanks for your effort.
Then, I'll take my leave.
This really is troublesome, Mouri-san.
No lead, huh?
Next is about the children's ice-sledding competition.
Get out of my way! Get out of my way!
Looks like fun.
Huh? What does?
Those kids. The children on TV.
Get out of my way! Get out of my way!
Oh, I see!
That's why the footprints were...
The truth of this matter's starting to get clearer.
The snow over here is about 15cm deep.
Here it... can be pressed down about 5cm at the most.
15cm and 5cm.
But, why did that person...?
Conan-kun, where did you go?
Just took a walk around here.
Tokyo First?
Is Bandou-san...?
Wait... Don't tell me that person...
Wait! Why are your socks all wet?
Go dry them up faster.
Hold on. Ran-neechan, wait!
The culprit is that person.
It's definitely that person!
But... why?
If that person is the culprit,
when and how did they put the doll here?
What is this thing?
That wasn't here earlier.
It feels a little cold in my hands. Gives me the chills.
So, that's how it is...
Takagi-kun, right?
It's me, Mouri.
Actually, I need you to help me investigate something.
Ogura-san!
Mouri-san needs you to do him a favor.
Mouri-san? Really?
If my deduction is correct,
that person must be...
Mouri-san.
You've gathered everyone here. What's going on?
It's time to reveal the truth about this case, of course.
You already know who the culprit is?!
Who is the culprit?
Let me explain it in order. First,
let's start off with where Ema-san was murdered: the mystery of the sealed-room, Furisode-sama's shrine.
Officer Masaki,
can you turn on the digital camera that's on the trough?
I kept thinking that something was wrong with this footprint left by boots.
I didn't realize it until this morning.
What's wrong with this?
The footprint is too shallow.
Last night, when I reached the shrine,
my feet were pressing about 7-8cm into the snow.
In fact, it kept snowing after that.
Ema-san, who went to the shrine that night around 10:30pm, wore boots that...
should've gone in about 15cm.
However, in reality, it's only 7-8cm at most.
That's way too shallow.
I see. Then what's the reason?
It's because the footprints were pressed.
Pressed? Weren't they pressed already?
That's right.
In order for Ema-san's footprints to not be covered by snow,
the footprints from the back door to the shrine...
were covered by towels.
What would've happened if they weren't towels...
but planks?
The culprit wouldn't leave any footprints and could walk back and forth freely...
from the back door to the shrine.
It's that simple?
The tricks that cover people's intentions are just that simple.
The culprit most likely...
prepared 2 pieces of wood, which were about 1 meter each.
Then, taking turns covering Ema-san's footprints, walk to there.
And then, using the same method, went back to the back door after murdering Ema-san.
With these, the footprints would become more shallow,
while also being preserved.
However, Mouri-san...
How did the culprit walk in and out of the back door?
That's right! There was no one else passing by at that time!
The culprit was walking under the eaves of the house...
using the same method.
That's why nobody saw them, and they never left any footprints.
According to my investigation from this morning,
coming out from back door,
the snow on the right side leave footprints about 15cm deep.
On the left side, only about 5cm deep.
In short, the culprit was coming from the left side.
And then,
walking according to the path under the eaves of the house,
the snow gets deeper at a certain point.
A-And, where is it?
It's in front of your room,
Akechi Eri-san.
W-What?
Eri-sensei?!
Last night, after Asuka-san went to the hot spring,
Eri-san left the open-air hot spring and went back to her room.
By using the method described just now, she went to the shrine from the back door.
She then killed Ema-san, who had been called out using Bandou-san's name.
It's true. By using that method, I could kill Ema-san.
However, it's impossible to kill Asuka-san.
That's right. This hot spring was built on the mountainside.
Using the same type of method is useless.
And no one else passed by the recreation area.
In fact...
Asuka-san was killed before Ema-san.
Eri-san used the stun gun to make Asuka-san faint.
She then took off Asuka-san's clothes and killed her.
After that, she moved the dead body to the location that already had obis placed...
and threw everything into the hot spring.
The holy knife was probably stolen just before that night.
But if Ema-san was killed after Asuka-san,
why were the holy knife and the bandana, which had blood on them, found in the hot spring?
Y-You're right!
That doll is...!
That was a trick using dry ice.
By using small pieces of dry ice, you can fit the doll into the cracks in the ceiling.
If the time it takes for the dry ice to evaporate was calculated beforehand,
then one could make the doll drop down at will.
So that's why the doll felt a bit icy cold.
The reason Eri-san asked the owner to buy cakes every day...
was to obtain the dry ice.
The doll can now be explained,
but what about the holy knife and the bandana?
I didn't go to the women's hot spring after 10:30pm.
You don't need to actually come here to be able to get those objects here.
We will now have a real experiment.
Yes, I understand!
Th-This is...!
These planks...
were sent down the cliff from Eri-san's room.
Everyone, please imagine...
the holy knife used to kill Ema-san,
and the bandana which had traces of Ema-san's blood.
By using this method,
even if you didn't come out of the room, you can still get them into the women's hot spring!
When Mouri-san and the rest of you were bathing,
you heard a splashing sound.
That was the sound made when the sledding planks fell into the water.
Yes, it was.
Eri-san was using this trick...
to confuse us by assuming the wrong order of the victims murders...
and to justify her alibi.
But...
where did the two important pieces of wood go to?
Mouri-san, I've brought them here.
These are...
They're the other obis, which were stored in the storage room.
I've already frozen them until they were very hard.
Using water to soak the obis...
and placing them outside the room for one night will let them freeze until they're as hard as ice.
She used the obis, frozen, to replace these two pieces of wood.
I see... If it's like this...
If they fall into the hot spring, the obis will revert back to their original shapes.
If there were two floating obis next to the dead body in the hot spring, it would be suspicious.
That's why she put a few of the obis into the hot spring.
Also, she placed a number of furisodes in the shrine.
Imitating Furisode-Hannya's legend...
was a trick to hide this method.
That's an interesting deduction.
Do you have any evidence?
Please let everyone take a look at the bottom of your foot.
Please ensure that you've shown it to everyone.
Sorry, Eri-sensei.
It's fine.
It seems I stepped on something sharp a little while ago.
No, you got this when you were killing Ema-san.
You stepped on the earring she dropped, and it left this scar.
Last night, when we were preserving the crime scene,
when I had everyone gathered and waiting in the living room,
Eri-san said it'd be better to let everyone sit down, so we switched to the lobby.
Eri-san, your right foot's wound was still bleeding then, right?
That's why you wouldn't take your slippers off in the living room.
Do you have any evidence to prove that this wound was caused by that earring?
I found the lost earring!
Look!
Conan-kun...
Even a single earring of this brand is worth 200 thousand yen.
That means...
We only need to examine whether it has traces of her blood or not!
This is the evidence!
Good job... finding it...
Actually, this is the pendant borrowed from Harumi-san.
I've lost.
I'm the one who killed both of them...
Why?! Why did you do such an awful thing?!
Eri-sensei...
It's not Eri... It's Chieri-sensei...
You hid your real name...
because it's really rare to see the surname "Ake."
Thus, many people have wrongly regarded "Ake Chieri" to be "Akechi Eri."
I had an acquaintance of mine from the police station investigate for me.
Chieri-san...
You're Sakurako-san's older sister, the one who committed suicide.
E-Eri-sensei is Sakurako-san's older sister?!
You lost your parents in a fire when you were younger.
Only the younger sister, Sakurako-san, was adopted by the Suzuka family.
I'll tell you everything.
When my younger sister committed suicide,
I was working on writing novels in Boston.
I was only informed of her death a year afterwards.
Fragile Sakurako...
had unexpectedly committed suicide just because she was accused of dealing drugs.
I was so regretful and felt pity.
Why didn't she discuss the matter with me?
I'm her sister.
She's my only relative.
I couldn't forgive them.
Sakurako seemed too miserable.
Then, taking this job as an excuse,
I pretended to find my university's classmate, Yoriko-san, in order to call both of them here.
I imitated the legend of Furisode-Hannya's revenge in order to get revenge on them.
Do you think Sakurako-san is content with this?
Three people took part in this interview.
If the only one who trusted Sakurako-san, Fugatsu Harumi-san, didn't show up,
I wouldn't have learned about the fact that your younger sister committed suicide.
And, I wouldn't have accused you.
I can't stop to think that Sakurako-san...
wanted to console you, the one who wanted to commit the crime,
by letting Harumi-san and you meet each other.
Harumi-san...
Couldn't Sakurako-san's hope reach you,
who was being possessed by Hannya?
Huh? Why am I here?
This doesn't look good.
I knew it.
Uncle, just enjoy your hot spring bath and take a rest.
What are these murderous stares?
And the mystery of Kago Island?
Mouri Kogoro will hide it no more; the real Sakuma Shochu is the best!
Hey, do you taste something weird in your mouth?
The volcano erupted. It's probably the ash.
What's wrong?!
This is...!
Next Conan: Kogoro Gets Drunk in Satsuma, Part 1!
Next Conan's Hint!
Picky way of making sake.
Next time we'll be in Kago Island!
Uncle will be eating something!
What are we doing there?