A case where building blocks are the clues! Heiji's
and Uncle's deductions conflict! Which one will win?
Perceiving the one and only truth,
With the body of a child and the brains of an adult,
His name is: Detective Conan!
Here, Detective Samonji series, file 44. "The Last
Will and Testament Prepared by a Devil," final chapter.
This is it!
I knew you'd come by to buy one,
little boy, so I kept one especially for you.
Really?
Than you, Uncle!
Oh boy, oh boy! I'm so into this series.
OK, I'll eat dinner quickly and
finish reading this before I go to bed.
And when I get up tomorrow I'll read
it a second time. It will be just as fun.
I'm back.
Welcome home!
Which one's deduction show
(Part One)
Welcome home.
All right, so the little brat is finally home.
Let's go out and eat some good food now.
That's right, it's still early! We can go
somewhere that's slightly further away.
So what do you want to eat? Just name it, little guy.
Pass!
Pass? Pasta? Ah, Italian food, eh?
Oh yeah, I heard that a stylish
pasta restaurant opened up in Haido city.
In that case, let's go there!
Yeah, Haido City is close enough.
All right-then, it's decided!
Eh? What?
I'm so full!
Having genuine spaghetti once
in a while is really not that bad.
You're right! Coming here
was definitely the right choice!
It was so delicious!
So, what are you guys doing here?
Kazuha-neechan and...
This dark-skinned guy.
Hey, hold it, what's with that attitude?
Showing up without making an appointment...
I already had plans of my own, you know.
Exactly, plans. That's why we came
all this way, to discuss your schedule.
Schedule?
Yeah! We wanted to invite Ran and you guys over
again. There are still lots of great places in Osaka to see.
Great places in Osaka?
Of course it's...
Osaka's trademark...
Takarazuka?
K-Koushien?
Translator's Note: Koushien is the famous baseball field near
Kobe, Japan, known for hosting the Japanese high school baseball finals.
Aren't those both in Hyogo prefecture?
I wasn't aware of any plans to go to Koushien.
Translator's Note: The Takarazuka Review, based in Takarazuka, Japan, is
a group of all woman theater troupes known for their lavish performances.
Takarazuka is a bolt from the blue for me too.
Didn't I already tell you? The auntie
who lives nearby promised us tickets.
Now that you say it, you did
mumble something like that once.
Well, why can't we go to both places?
Good idea! I just wanted to take
everyone one to see the high school baseball finals.
Drats, then we can't go to both.
Kazuha-chan, what's wrong?
Hey, don't tell me that auntie is one of those five.
What do you mean?
They're a group of ladies in our
neighborhood famous for loving Takarazuka.
They save up money for a whole year and
use it during the summer vacation period
To go and see Takarazuka continuously.
But there is one day they
couldn't use their dearly bought tickets.
Co-Could that day be...
The Koushien finals?
Yeah, you see, president of the company
where those five aunties work loves high school baseball.
Every year, for the finals, he takes all
the employees of the company to go watch.
So they promised to give me
the Takarazuka tickets for that day.
I see now, since the Koushien finals
were rained out on their original date,
They couldn't know which day the
finals would be when the were buying.
Then I guess there's no choice. This
time, Kazuha, you'll have to give up.
We can go see the same Takarazuka show any time,
But the summer finals at Koushien is a
fierce competition that only happens once a year.
What are you saying! They show high school
baseball on the news and sports specials all the time.
Idiot! Baseball has to be watched in person!
What's the point in seeing the results on the news?
Takarazuka is always best live!
These Takarazuka tickets for such great seats
that normal people would never be able to get them.
So, Ran-chan. You want to go see Takarazuka too, right'?
Ah, yeah.
Hey kid, if you're a guy, it's baseball, right?
Ah, right.
How about you, Uncle?
Let's see. This time I'd definitely go for the
refreshing hot-blooded environment of Koushien.
But then again, the gorgeous passionate
environment of Takarazuka wouldn't be bad either.
Which one?
How about this: We'll go to the place
chosen by whoever wins a deduction competition.
Deduction?
Competition?
Wednesday last month I was told there
was a murder at the office of some company.
It seems there were some unusual issues, so
Inspector Megure asked me to lend him my wisdom.
The company is actually in this area. I was
going to drop by after dinner to take a look.
Now, I don't like using a murder case as the subject of
a bet, but it seems the criminal hasn't yet been caught.
If it's in order to solve a case, I don't think it's a bad idea.
How about it, Kazuha? Shall we have a competition?
That's so sneaky! How can I beat
Heiji at a deduction competition?
Of course, Kazuha-chan's side will
be supported by me, Sleeping Kogorou.
Really? Thank you, Uncle!
It's nothing. Sleeping Kogorou has
always been a friend of the underdog.
I've already seen through your
weakly-disguised ruse, Uncle...
So, Ran-chan, will you help me too?
Sure, let's work hard for Takarazuka.
How sneaky, finding two people to help you.
Well then, I guess there's no other
choice. I'll have to deal with this four-eyes kid.
The sneakiest one is you.
Oh! Mouri-kun!
Sorry to trouble you.
No, no.
Anyway, inside is...
Stop blocking the way.
H-Hattori-kun?
Hey, you can't just waltz into a crime scene!
Don't worry about it. Forensics has
already completely investigated the scene, right?
Well, yeah.
The murder victim was the president of this toy
manufacturing company, Tsugiya Kenshi-san, 53 years old.
This appears to be both the
president's home and the toy factory.
The presumed time of death is
Sunday, June 29th, at around 5 PM.
He was found the next day,
Monday the 30th, around 10 AM.
Who found him?
He was found by four employees of this company.
Four employees?
Apparently, those four always go just before
work to eat breakfast together at that coffee shop.
I see, that's why there were four people.
And so those four people discovered the president
tied up with ropes and beaten to death with a golf club.
How can you tell, Heiji?
See how the ink has mostly
been spilled near the victim's back.
Probably the criminal and the
president were struggling with each other
And spilled the ink that was on top of the desk.
Then, he tied the president up in this way.
That's when the ink adhering to
the ropes left marks all over the floor.
That proves the president was
still struggling when he was tied up.
If that's true, then how about the
evidence that he was killed by a golf club?
There are blood stains only near the head and
around the head are several 10 cm long, narrow stains.
Those are marks from an iron golf club.
These were made when the criminal
repeatedly struck the head of the fallen man.
But why did he bother to hit
him after he'd already tied him up?
He must've been asking him the number to the
safe. Look, the door of that safe has been left open.
I see, the criminal must have
been an outsider looking for valuables.
We still don't know if it was an outsider or not.
But, after the criminal tied up the
president and got the number to the safe out of him,
He beat the man who had seen his face to
death with a golf club. This point is indisputable.
Isn't that right, Inspector'?
Well, yeah.
Hey, Father, are you all right?
So far, those two have been taking the foreground!
Is that right?
Up until now, these are all things that 'even the police
can determine by just looking at the scene of the crime.
"Even the police..."
Hey!
Isn't there anything else? What was so unusual?
Out with it.
Ah, yeah.
These were found near the president's corpse.
These four building blocks.
Building blocks? There's
plenty scattered around the corpse.
No, for some reason only these four have
the president's fingerprints and ink stains.
Ink?
Yes, and if you line up the faces
with ink stains and finger prints,
This is what you get.
Translator's Note: (Omocha) = toys
Toys?
Hmm, toys.
Translator's Note: (omochi-ya) = rice cake store
No, wait, could it be a rice cake store?
It could be a rice cake store.
You're right, there seem to be
blocks with small 'tsu' and 'ya' on them.
Hey, Inspector.
Could you show me the spot where
the four pieces in this picture were laying.
Sure, this picture was taken when the body was found.
Then, this person is...
Yeah, this is Tsujiya, the murdered
president of this toy manufacturing company.
These four blocks were mixed in with
the pile of blocks to the president's left.
But as for why only the four with 'o-mo-chi-ya' on
them had the president's fingerprints and ink stains...
The ink stains must have come from the ink bottle
on the desk which spilled onto the president's back.
The question is, who put the
ink onto the building blocks?
Yeah, we might also consider that the
president's fingerprints on the blocks,
Might have been left when the criminal
forced the murdered president to hold the blocks.
Hey.
Were the president's fingerprints
really left on only those four blocks?
Ah, yeah. The other blocks piled
there also have the president's fingerprints.
But only these four blocks have
fingerprints imprinted everywhere.
Not just the six faces, but
also in the wells of the characters.
If that's so, then these four blocks...
Definitely look like a dying message left by the president.
Huh? How would you know that?
Take a close look at this crime scene photo.
The president's hands were tied up behind him.
Tied up like that; he couldn't pick
out the blocks except by touching them.
The reason his fingerprints were on each of the six faces,
Was that he was facing backwards and
searching the character wells with his fingers.
At that time, he touched the other blocks,
but he didn't leave as many fingerprints on them.
Each block only has characters from the same row of
the syllabary so finding the right one was fairly easy.
I see, so that's why only these four have ink stains.
Still, fingerprints are mostly composed
of sweat and oils left by the fingertips,
And the sweat and oils
I remain even after someone has died.
Even if you make a dead person hold the blocks,
you'll still get good fingerprints the first one or two times.
Maybe the president picked out these four blocks behind
his back while the criminal wasn't paying attention.
Then he rolled over to stain the chosen face with ink,
And then rolled back and returned it to the pile of pieces.
Since he didn't know when he would be
killed, his hands were sweaty from fear.
The ink stains all over the floor
from the ropes are proof of this.
In this case, the president was working quickly and may
have gotten the small 'yu' and the large 'yu' mixed up.
This is a toy company, so maybe the president
wanted to leave behind 'toy' as his dying message?
That's amazing! We just got here
and already you have all that figured out.
Isn't it? Isn't it? That's what we expect from Hei...
Dang it.
This isn't good, Ran-chan! We
can't keep getting pulled along by Heiji.
This is a competition between us and Heiji,
with either Koushien or Takarazuka as the prize.
Yeah.
To solve this case before Heiji, we've
got to solve this 'toy' dying message first!
Maybe one of the toys here contains a hint.
Nope, there aren't any suspicious toys here.
Are you sure?
Yeah, since we were also tenatively
considering those four blocks to be a dying message,
We've already thoroughly inspected this office.
Then, maybe there's another meaning to it.
Another meaning?
Aren't there many more
combinations of those four characters?
"Omoyachi," "ochimoya," "ochiyamo."
"Oyamochi," oyachimo," "mochiyao."
This makes no sense.
Well then, did you find anything else?
Yeah.
Just the golf club used as the murder weapon,
And a leather coat we think the criminal was wearing
during the crime, stained with the president's blood.
But, both the golf club and the coat are the president's.
So we can't determine who the
criminal was from these two items.
The thing I don't understand is,
why did the criminal put on this coat?
The blood on the left shoulder of this coat is a bit light.
Did it rub off on something?
Ah, that's another mystery.
No matter where we searched in this office, we
couldn't find a place we thought touched that blood.
The criminal's hand probably
touched it when he took off the coat.
Did you find the criminal's gloves or something like that?
Hey, speaking of blood stains,
There's a very weird looking blood stain here.
Where?
Right here, right here.
Why'd you crawl under there?
- This blood...
- Just a sec.
It's hard to see if you don't look
closely, but the tip of this stain looks cut off.
Maybe something was placed here?
You're right, but what would
be placed in a spot like this?
Let's see, the remote, the remote...
Hey! You can't go touching things! That desk
has been left-the way it was since the crime occurred.
It's been set up for external input. In that case,
The thing placed here was probably a video camera.
As for a video camera, there's
one in the president's bedroom.
Then, can you call forensics and have them
check to see if there're blood stains or not?
But what's odd is, if it really was a
video camera that was placed here,
Why did the criminal take it
away after committing the crime?
If he connected the camera and the TV together, and
put it here to observe president's actions while tied up,
There was no reason to take it away after the crime.
And what's more...
Something's been bothering me for a while.
This room...
It seems so contrived
somehow. It gives me a weird feeling.
Hey, Conan-kun...
What's up, Ran-neechan?
I want to ask you for a little favor.
This deduction competition,
can you let Kazuha-chan win?
It seems Kazuha-chan was really really
looking foward to going to Takarazuka with us.
So, if you hit upon anything
this time, can you secretly tell us?
You see, if Father hears it, it could lead him
to the solution to this case, just like always.
OK? Please?
No good?
Conan-kun!
Beep! Beep! Beep!
This brat is on my team.
Are you trying to make a pass for him?
Hey, you wouldn't ditch your fellow male's
friendship and run over to the girls' side, would you?
Friendship? Didn't you force
me to be in a group with you?
Whatever, I'll do anything I can to win
this competition so we can go to Koushien!
How very frank.
Oh, they matched?
With such an exceedingly small amount,
the criminal probably didn't notice it either.
But why would there be a video camera here?
It was probably connected to the TV,
And used to keep an eye on the
president until he gave up the number to the safe.
The question is, why would he bother to do it like this?
If he wanted to keep an eye on him, he
could've just tied him up in front of the the safe.
Perhaps the criminal put the camera to
threaten that he was watching him the whole time,
While he went into the other rooms to look for valuables.
Nevertheless, the president was able to leave
behind a dying message to identify the criminal.
Well, in any case, the criminal was
clearly very familiar with this office,
And it's also very likely the president knew him by sight.
Leaving behind a dying message
indicates he knew who the killer was.
Therefore the most suspicious people
would be those four employees you mentioned.
Yeah, those four are currently with Takagi-kun...
Inspector Megure!
We've obtained the alibis of the four employees.
Really? They all have alibis?
All four of them are designers.
The company's chief accountant, Aikou Nao-san,
Aikou Nao
Tsujiya Toy Manufacturing Account
At the time of the incident around 5 PM on
June 29th, had left to go fishing by herself.
The chief salesman, Hasami
Atsushi-san, was at home alone enjoying videos.
Hasami Atsushi
Tsujiya Toy Manufacturing Sales
Nakagami Isao
Tsujiya Toy Manufacturing Design
The chief designer, Nakagami
Isao-san, was at the horse racing track.
The vice president, Iwatomi Hajime-san, supposedly
went to go watch the final round of a gold tournament.
Tsujiya Toy Manufacturing Vice President
Iwatomi Hajime
Those are all very shaky alibis.
Yeah, for the time being Chiba is picking at their
back stories, but none of their alibis seem verifiable.
Back?
Wait a second, if it was like that...
Then the dying message contained in the blocks is...
Geez, it's so simple.
I can't believe we didn't notice that.
Kazuha, sorry, but I've won this competition.
Kazuha...
When I realized it, I had to that nostalgic river side
Envisioning the sequel the dream I had yesterday
Oh that day you seemed so grown-up
Unable to even say goodbye, I hid under my umbrella
If we cross paths again... Oh please
That time, forget-me-not
Not like love, not like loving, not something that's changing
It's only you I like, and that's how I think it will always be
Holding onto my aimless feelings, I look back as people often do
Stopping the scene were we chanced to meet from fading gently away
Now if we can just find that thing.
This mystery will be solved in one shot.
Kazuha-chan?
Sorry, Ran-chan, I can't talk right
now. I think I'm just about to solve it!
Kudou.
I've got it!
There's no doubt.
The culprit is...
Next Conan: Which One's Deduction Show
(Part Two)
Next Conan's Hint
Calendar
Next time, it's finally decided.
The winner be either Kazuha-chan or Hattori-kun.
But, which one?