Perceiving the truth hidden behind the dying
message, which one will win the deduction competition?
Perceiving the one and only truth,
With the body of a child and the brains of an adult,
His name is: Detective Conan!
Hattori and Kazuha came to see us in order to
invite us to the Koushien finals and to Takarazuka.
But once they found out that both were
happening on the same day, the two started quarreling.
Therefore, we used the murder case that Uncle was
asked to help solve as a deduction competition to decide.
Which One's Deduction Show
(Part Two)
Kazuha...
What's wrong, Kazuha-chan?
How can I possibly understand this weird dying message?
At this rate, we'll lose the deduction
competition and we won't be able to go to Takarazuka.
When I think about that, I feel so disappointed...
Competition?
Idiot. In deductions, there's no winning or
losing, there's no being superior or inferior because...
There is always just a single truth.
That's how it is.
Hey, Hattori.
You figured it out too, right?
He real meaning behind that dying message.
Nope, no idea.
The main thing is, why were only
these four blocks stained with ink?
These are photos, but if these were real blocks,
We could lift them up like this and see the
characters on the back and maybe figure something out.
But, you can't see the backs of the
blocks from the back of the pictures can you?
So that's it, this guy...
But, this murdered president looks like he spent a
lot of effort to get those ink stains onto the blocks.
Because with his hands tied behind his back, he had
to use his fingers to feel the letter wells on the blocks,
In order to figure out which
character to rub the ink on, right?
The characters on these blocks are all different,
and some even have pictures of animals on them.
If it were me, I'd get it wrong for sure!
If these were shougi pieces instead of building blocks,
Then figuring out the character on the back and
adding ink stains would be really simple, right?
Kudou...
Figuring out the character on the back?
Idiot! If they were shougi pieces,
wouldn't it be more complicated?
We couldn't tell it the ink-stained character or the unstained one was the one the president had intended.
Oh, really?
That's right, even though there
was a character stained with ink,
He might have just placed the
shougi piece in the ink spilled on floor.
Could it be? Those four blocks...
And so? Those four employees
who discovered the president's corpse,
Do they have any motives for killing the president?
Ah, right.
First of is the accountant, Aikou Nao-san.
She was president Tsujiya's ex-wife. They
divorced because Aikou-san had an affair.
Aikou Nao
Tsujiya Toy Manufacturing Accountant
They were still in dispute over the
question of the consolation money.
As for the salesman, Hasami Atsushi-san,
It seems the president said he would be fired
if this year's profits was lower than last year's.
Hasami Atsushi
Tsujiya Toy Manufacturing Sales
Nakagami Isao
Tsujiya Toy Manufacturing Design
The president said the same thing
to the designer, Nakagami Isao-san.
In addition, it seems he's had a big argument
with the president over the design of a new toy.
Next, the vice-president, Iwatomi
Hajime-san, didn't have any disputes.
Iwatomi Hajime
Tsujiya Toy Manufacturing Vice President
But if the president were to die, then he
would be the one to inherit the company.
So all four people have their individual motives.
'A-U-E'. 'O-U-l'.
'I'?
Just like that! Hurry and solve it!
Even though the relationships between
the president and his employees were so bad,
This company was able to keep going.
Yeah, that's? probably why they frequently
met up at vice-president Iwatomi-san's house,
To drink and complain about the president.
On the day of the incident, June 29th, three of them
spent the night at the vice-president's place drinking.
It wasn't until the four of them went to work the next
day, the 30th, that they discovered the president's body.
Oh, and also something else that may
not have anything to do with the case.
All four have strange collecting habits.
Strange collecting habits?
Aikou-san, who is sensitive to cold,
has collected over 50 pairs of gloves.
Supposedly when she goes fishing
she always wears at least three pairs.
Hasami-san, who likes to watch movies,
has collected over 30 pairs of sunglasses.
He's even bought limited edition
sunglasses that were worn by famous actors.
Nakagami-san, who likes horse racing, collects hats.
Depending on the race, he picks a
different lucky hat out of the forty he owns.
Iwatomi-san, who often played golf with the
president, has collected 30 pairs of white shoes.
All of them are name-brand golf shoes, and it
seems he polishes the entire collection once every week.
Incidentally, the murdered
president Tsujiya was a unrivaled idol fanatic.
It looks like he collected lots of idol goods.
Now that you mention it, there are a lot of
those idol goods in the president's room back there.
Look, there's even some on this desk
Pen stands with idol photos on them.
True enough.
Hey, Kudou, have you noticed?
Yeah, you mean how the things in
the room feel strangely out of place?
However, it's not just that.
Yeah, there's still one more that's bothering me.
Well then, I suppose this calendar
was also bought by the president?
That's right, apparently the
president particularly liked this calendar.
He stored all the past months
instead of throwing them away.
Hattori.
Did you buy it? That novel.
Yeah, my mother bought it
for me first thing this morning.
Kazuha-chan, have you figured something out?
Kazuha-chan...
Sorry, Ran-chan, I can't talk right
now. I think I'm just about to solve it!
What's going on? Calling us here at this hour...
Don't tell me that you're still suspecting us?
Ah, you see...
Didn't you say the criminal was
some outsider looking for valuables?
Your picking on us because there aren't
any witnesses for our alibis, aren't you?
Well that can't be helped! I really went to the horserace!
I stayed watching the finals of
the golf tournament until the end!
I was at home and watching the
three videos I'd rented one after the other.
I went fishing - and by coincidence, I went on my own.
In that case, who was it that first
discovered the president's body?
Who is this kid?
Er, well, anyway, could you please
describe the situation at that time?
I was the first to discover the body.
Just as I was about to sit down in my seat, I
saw the president lying here and started shouting.
We heard the vice-president shouting and so we all
ran over to look, and then we called 110 (emergency).
That's right.
Oh-yeah, was it always the president who
tore the months off of the calendar over there?
Of course! If we had done it and
tore it wrong, he would get angry at us.
It was always the president who tore the months off.
And then, after that, he would store them
away in his room as if they were precious.
Say, the one who wrote the daily schedules on the
calendar would have been the president himself, right?
Yes, in fact the president had finally been able to
schedule next Sunday for us all to play golf together.
Who knew that such a tragedy would occur.
Anyway, we're going to go look for something.
You guys continue your questioning.
All right, let's find it.
Yeah.
Why was the video camera placed
where the president couldn't see it?
The position in which he was tied up...
The strange out-of-place
arrangement of the things on the desk...
And the blood spurt on the shoulder
of the coat the culprit was wearing...
The strange collecting habits of the four suspects...
And the dying message left by the president.
Exactly. Now if we can just find that thing.
This mystery will be solved in one shot.
What? One of the alibis has been confirmed?
Yes, I just checked the recording at the TV station,
He was photographed, quite clearly.
Kudou.
Ran-chan.
I've found it, the June calendar.
Although it's very faint,
there's a smear of blood remaining.
There's no mistake.
The culprit is...
I've got it!
Ran-chan, I know who the culprit is!
Really? You know who it is, Kazuha-chan.
Look, this is the dying message left
behind by the murdered president, right?
Yeah, the four blocks where the 'o', 'mo',
'chi', and 'ya' characters are stained with ink.
This isn't some kind of bizarre code.
It tells us who the criminal is just like it is.
Just like it is?
I don't think any one of them looks particularly like a toy.
No, it's a name.
Name?
None of their four names are related to "o-mo-chi-ya."
Remember, Heiji mentioned it earlier?
It might not be the characters
stained with ink he intended us to read.
He might have just put the blocks in the ink.
In that case, the character on the back of the
one stained with ink contains the true message.
Even if that's so, you can't see the
character on the back-from the photos.
Should I have forensics bring the four blocks here then?
We can work it out without doing that.
For example, the ink stained block with the character 'o'.
If we expand it of it, we get something like this.
"U-E-O."
You can easily guess which
characters go in the blank spaces.
But, to be sure, I checked the remaining blocks
over there, and they were just like what I expected.
The each of the vowels "a-i-u-e-o" were
placed in the same order on all of the blocks.
That's right, isn't it?
Correct, the 50 Japanese syllables, 5 to a column plus 1
animal, meant that we had six sides to make a cube with.
Yep, yep.
After you've understood where the characters are
placed on the six faces of the blocks, the rest is easy.
On the opposite side of the ink stained 'o' is the letter 'i'.
Opposite 'mo' is 'mi'.
Opposite 'chi' is 'to'. See how it goes?
I get it! So the real dying
message was "i-mi-to" and one more...
Isn't this strange?
If Kazuha-chan is correct, on the fourth block,
below the 'ya' character should be 'yu', but it says 'yo'.
It's because that block is special.
Look, on the right of the 'yo' the character 'wo'
from the syllable line 'wa-wo-n' is written, right?
Which means that this block is actually
a combined line of "ya-yu-yo-wa-wo-n."
If you put characters onto the
block using the order I described before,
Using the character 'n' in the
place of the animal finishes it off.
In this case, the character opposite
the ink stained 'ya', is the character 'wa'.
Which means the dying message
becomes "i-mi-to-wa" doesn't it?
Which means...
"I-M-I-WA-TO."
"I-WA-MI-TO."
"I-WA-TO..."
That's right! What the president intended
to leave behind before he was killed was...
You name, vice-president lwatomi-san!
So that's how it is? You killed the president
so that you could have the company for yourself.
No, no, it wasn't me!
That's amazing, Kazuha-chan! You
solved the case before Hattori-kun!
Yep, we've won the deduction competition!
That means we...
Can go see Takaruzuka!
I'm sorry, Kazuha-kun, but lwatomi-san is not the culprit.
Chiba-kun called me earlier...
The time of the crime was about
5 PM on the 29th of last month.
Iwatomi-san was shown on television at that time.
No way!
How is that possible?
You might ask me, "How is
that possible?" but it's the truth.
Don't tell me you have a twin?
No, I don't!
Which means, I'm sorry to say,
Kazuha-kun's reasoning just now was incorrect.
Oh no.
No, She wasn't wrong.
The four blocks spelling out "lwatomi" was the actual
dying message left by the president before he was killed.
Heiji.
But, Hattori-kun, lwatomi-san has an alibi...
Which isn't surprising, seeing
as lwatomi-san wasn't the culprit.
Huh? Didn't you just say that
"lwatomi" was the actual dying message?
That's right, I did say that, but I never
said that it was the "correct" dying message.
Hey, hey. What are you talking about?
Haven't l said? The situation when the president used
the blocks to leave behind that message, think back to it.
Well, let's see. The president was lying
beside the desk with his hands tied behind him.
He picked up the blocks beside him and
stained them in the ink splattered on the floor.
That's right, it's the ink splattered on
the floor behind him that's the problem.
What's the problem with it?
This ink was probably spilled when the
president was struggling with the culprit.
Ah, that's what I thought at first.
But then I noticed how the things on
the desk look strangely out-of-place.
Out of place?
What's this? Isn't that strange? I just bumped
the desk lightly and the pen stand toppled over.
Because, wasn't it during the struggle with the
culprit that the desk was struck and the ink spilled?
Why didn't the pen stand fall over at that time too?
Now that you mention it...
It seems like...
The culprit deliberately spilt the ink, doesn't it?
Idiot! Why would the culprit do something like that?
Wouldn't the victim write something
that lead back to such a inept criminal...
Maybe.
Could it have been deliberate?
That's right. The culprit deliberately
spilt the ink to allow the president to
Leave behind a dying
message saying who the culprit was.
But, in that case, wouldn't he be
immediately revealed as the culprit.
It would only reveal who the culprit was
if the president had seen the culprit's face.
Now, how about lying down on the
floor like the tied-up president was?
You understand what the
president was feeling at the time, don't you?
That's it, shoes! Shoes!
The culprit used this desk to block the president's view,
So he could only decide who the culprit was by his shoes.
Which means that the culprit
put on Iwatomi-san's white shoes
To deliberately make the
president leave that dying message.
That the video camera was placed where the
tied-up president couldn't see it is the proof.
He observed the president on the monitor, and
then killed him after he left his dying message.
But who could have done it?
Hey, Uncle!
I found a strange calendar in the president's room. See!
I think you might be able to work out something from it.
Hmm, there's seems to be a slight
stain, but nothing else is suspicious.
What? You still don't get it?
This stain was left behind after
wiping off the blood from the calendar.
Also, don't you think it's strange?
The president was killed on June 29th,
yet the calendar in this room is for July?
The daily schedule for the 30th is
still written on the ripped off calendar.
We should assume that the
culprit tore it off for some reason.
Hey, hey, hey!
I figure the reason for tearing it off was
to hide the blood that had wiped off on it.
Wasn't there a place that looked as if
blood stains there had been wiped off?
Ah! The coat the culprit was wearing had
wiped-off blood stains on the left shoulder!
Well then, let's have the four of
them line up in front of the calendar.
Hey!
The one who could get blood from
their shoulder on the top of the calendar...
Ah, idiot!
You are the only person tall enough to do it, Hasami-san!
He said it...
When the president returned here, Hasami-san
beat him unconscious from the back with a golf club.
He came to and was leaving the mistaken dying message,
Hasami-san watched him on video camera,
while wearing Mr lwatomi's shoes, of course.
Now the reason why the blood
on his coat got onto the calendar,
ls because he leaned against the wall in
relief after being the president to death.
The reason Hasami-san didn't tear off the calendar
was because he only noticed the blood on it the next day.
Incidentally, secretly taking
lwatomi-san's white shoes was an easy task.
Apparently the employees often get together at
lwatomi-san's house, so there were plenty of chances.
But, just the blood on the calendar isn't
enough evidence to prove that Hasami-san did it.
Nope, the evidence is the shoes.
While Hasami-san waited for the president to leave
his message, he was wearing them the whole time.
This left a definite scent.
Let the police dogs have a
sniff and you'll know soon enough.
Still, since it was a risk to leave his scent in the shoes,
Hasami-san must have had some other important reason.
Why don't you explain to us?
I wanted the vice president to be
accused of the president's murder.
So that he would be forced out of
the toy production process. That's all.
Why? I can't think why you would bear a grudge.
I don't bear a grudge, the children do.
The children that bought this
batch of toys you and the president sold.
W-What do you mean?
Look, for example, these blocks. See
how the corners have been smoothed off.
To reduce costs, the president and vice-president
said that it would be easier not to smooth off the corners.
Not just the blocks, but the other toys too.
It's true that at first glance they look
fine, and have been selling well too.
But they could injure the children who buy them.
I opposed the idea at first, but I
was told that if I did I would be fired.
But that's no reason to go so far!
The company is having hard times, you know.
Hard times?
Guess what the president said when he was tied up.
Hey, lwatomi Are you doing this for money?
If you think there's no money,
you're wrong! Just look in the vault!
We had money?
Yes, although I don't know who or
how they cheated in order to save it.
But, regardless, I couldn't let them sell
those badly-made toys to unsuspecting children.
When I realized it, I had to that nostalgic river side
Envisioning the sequel the dream I had yesterday
Oh that day you seemed so grown-up
Unable to even say goodbye, I hid under my umbrella
If we cross paths again... Oh please
That time, forget-me-not
Not like love, not like loving, not something that's changing
It's only you I like, and that's how I think it will always be
Holding onto my aimless feelings, I look back as people often do
Stopping the scene were we chanced to meet from fading gently away
You know, you understood that trick really well.
It's thanks to a novel.
Novel Title: The Last Will and Testament Prepared by a Devil
The title of the novel my mother bought
for me this morning helped me work it out.
You'll really have to thank your mother then.
Because of her you've also
won the deduction competition.
Yeah, I guess it's Koushien...
Congratulations, Heiji.
Oh no. I accidentally won.
Translator's Note: Rokkou Oroshi (The Wind From Mt. Rokkou)
is the fight song for the Hanshin Tigers, Osaka's baseball team.
I guess I'll just have to practice the "Rokkou Oroshi" then.
W-Wait a second, Kazuha.
Kazuha-chan, would you like me to ask
Hattori if he'll consider going to Takarazuka?
You did solve the dying message, after all.
That's half of the work.
It's no use.
Besides, what I really wanted to
see wasn't Takarazuka or Koushien...
It was the shinning look on Heiji's
face when he finally solved the case.
That's strange, where did I screw up?
Dumb-ass.
Wow! It's Koushien!
What the heck is that? He
should come here and get it himself.
That can only mean he doesn't care
if we trace it back to him later, right?
Yeah, if we can't find him by the
end of the game, he'll kill himself.
He could still be there!
Next Conan Special: The Miracle at Koushien Ball Park
The Defiants Face The Dark Demon
Next Conan's Hint
Retried uniform number
Next time it's a two hour special Christmas present.
With Koushien as the stage, I play the lead!
Eh? Hang on...