Ta-da!
Today we have...
An early...
Christmas present!
A summer tale...
To send the winter chill away.
Right, and the stage is—
Koshien. So it's my turn.
Not just yours, Heiji!
A challenge from
a mysterious criminal...
A gripping race against time.
Don't miss a second.
With this episode, Detective Conan
has been airing for a whole nine years.
Then, doesn't that mean
next year's the tenth?
That's right! It's thanks to
the support of our viewers.
Yeah!
We'll keep doing
our best for you...
Whether on the TV show...
In the cinema...
- Or in Shonen Sun —
- Sunday!
Please continue to support us!
Torimitsu Precision Manufacturing
It's the morning of the goal so
many high school students aim for...
Koshien Baseball Stadium.
Japan's National Summer High
School Baseball Championship Finals.
This year, 4,146 teams and 160,000 students
participated in regional tournaments nationwide.
The 49 teams
who rose to the top
will be here at the opening ceremony
to represent their prefectures.
The teams gathered here
at Koshien are ready to do battle.
Those teams are waiting eagerly now along
the first baseline for the game to begin.
Koshien begins
National High School Baseball
Now, let's take a look
at the regional champions.
Representing Okinawa,
Okinawa Central High.
Representing Kagoshima
Prefecture, Sakurajima High.
Representing Miyazaki
Prefecture, Sadohara High.
Representing Oita
Prefecture, Meihoh High.
Representing Kumamoto
Prefecture, Kumamoto Tech.
Representing Nagasaki
Prefecture, Sasebo High...
We will now begin
the commencement ceremony
of Japan's National High
School Baseball Championship.
Presenting the teams...
Following Tadohara High School
is Oita's Meihoh High.
This makes the third time Meihoh has
reached this far in the tournament.
Representing Osaka
is Ohgane High School.
They're getting a big cheer
from the stands.
Now we move
on to the player dedication.
Representing the players...
We have the captain
of the Toyama High baseball team...
Kawakami-kun.
Sirs...
We, the players,
are overjoyed to have come
to this hallowed field.
We vow to show good sportsmanship, in
a manner becoming of high school students.
The players' representative...
Toyama Prefecture, South Koyama
High, Baseball Team Captain...
Tomoya Kawakami.
Koshien.
The top high school athletes
in the nation gather here
to test their strength
and skills and aim for the top!
It's a sacred place where
the gods smile upon the champions...
A merciless battleground where
warriors fight it out to the end...
And sometimes...
An unbelievable twist of fate awaits
those bewitched by the Koshien diamond.
A tale of hot suspense to break the winter cold!
A two hour special—Heiji's here too!
A difficult case unfolds on a grand stage!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid
but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
On the same day
of summer vacation,
the Koshien finals and a Takarazuka
performance were to take place.
To decide which we'd go to,
Hattori and Kazuha had
a deduction showdown.
The case was a murder case that
the old man had been called in for.
The murdered victim
left a clue—
a dying message with toy blocks.
Thanks to Hattori's subtle
pointers, Kazuha deciphered the message,
but in the end, it was Hattori who figured
out the identity of the real killer,
and won
the deduction showdown.
Well, I guess it's Koshien.
Nice work, Heiji.
Aw, shoot. I won.
I'll be sure to practice the Rokko Oroshi to cheer on the Tigers for ya.
W-Wait a sec, Kazuha!
Kazuha-chan, should I ask Hattori-kun if he'd mind if we went to Takarazuka?
You did solve the dying
message, after all.
That's half of the work.
Forget about it.
After all, what I really wanted to
see isn't Takarazuka or Koshien.
It's the shinin' look on Heiji's face
when he solves a case.
Koshien?
We're here! We're here!
Yoko-chan...
Huh? Yoko-chan?
Yeah.
Yoko Okino, the famous idol,
went to Kohnan High School.
Hey, are we there yet?
Hey, how're you doin', Kudo?
I give up.
Japan's National High
School Baseball Championship
So why's it called
Koshien, anyway?
They could've just called it Hyogo
Stadium or Kansai Stadium or something.
Koshien was completed on the first year
of both the ten signs and the Chinese zodiacs.
This was the meeting of monkey and mouse, which occurs every sixty years.
So they thought
it was a lucky year.
You know a lot, Conan-kun.
You don't know
a thing about baseball.
Just a lot of useless trivia.
Well, excuse me.
There's more to Koshien's
history than just that.
The total number of vines
of ivy on the walls is 430.
The leaves cover an area
equivalent to 8,000 tatamis.
Even though it's an old field,
it's a full-sized stadium,
which can hold 53,000 people.
See? Isn't that amazing?
Weren't you saying something
about useless trivia?
It's starting!
Top of the 1st, Ohgane High's
first batter, shortstop Inoue-kun.
Play ball!
Strike!
Strike two!
Strike three! You're out!
The starting pitcher, Sakuraba,
struck out the first batter.
One out!
The stands are cheering!
Kohnan's pitcher is Sakuraba,
a third-year student.
Here comes the wind-up
and the second pitch.
Strike!
Ohgane's pitcher, Inao,
with another fastball.
Here comes the second pitch...
Two strikes!
Three strikes
for Kohnan's batter.
Now...
Here comes the third pitch.
There!
Strike! Batter out!
Namioka's out after three swings!
Inao presses relentlessly
with his trademark style.
Kohnan High's third batter,
Kikuchi, is a third-year student.
He has achieved
a batting-average
of .429 at regional tournaments, and .400 at previous Koshien showings.
And now, Kikuchi
faces off against Inao.
And here comes...
...the pitch!
Strike!
The pitcher and catcher
carefully exchange signs.
And now, the second pitch!
Strike two!
Strike!
Now it's two strikes,
thanks to a mean curve ball.
The next batter,
Nagashima, is on deck.
Strike! Batter out!
Ohgane's Inao holds off Kohnan
with some aggressive pitching.
That's the end of the 1st,
as Ohgane and Kohnan are 0-0.
Kohnan High's Sakuraba now takes the mound.
Top of the 2nd.
Hitting for Ohgane is number 6, center fielder, Matsuda-kun.
Strike!
Foul ball!
The finals are amazing!
Strike! Batter out!
Third baseman,
Morita-kun, number 7.
Strike! Batter out!
Sakuraba #7 did a strikeout on
Morita, with this it's two-out!
Number 8, catcher,
Watanabe-kun.
The catcher, Watanabe,
steps into the batter's box.
The pitcher, Sakuraba,
with the delivery!
He pops it up.
It's swerved right...
Foul ball!
Foul!
Strike!
Strike! Batter out!
The top of the 2nd ends, as Sakuraba from Ohgane
prevents Kohnan from breaking the no-run tie.
Bottom of the 2nd. Hitting for Kohnan
High, #4, third baseman, Nagashima-kun.
And the batter we've been
waiting for takes the box...
Kohnan High's Nagashima!
Just listen to the response
his name gets from the stands!
It just happens that these two players have
faced off three times, in three Koshien finals!
Will last year's champions,
Kohnan High, win again?
Or will Ohgane High do it, achieving victory
in both the spring and summer tournaments?
The pitcher takes a big wind-up...
The first pitch!
Strike!
That's a strike, all right!
Strike, strike...
Say, old man...
What've you been lookin'
at all this time?
Dad, the game is that way.
I bet he's checkin' out
the cheerleaders over by the Alps stand.
What a lech.
We came all this way... At
least watch the game, Dad!
Gimme a break!
We're stuck all the way in
the back of the right field bleachers!
I can barely tell what's going on!
I thought you had tickets
for better seats than these.
Sorry about that.
I asked a guy I know who lives around here,
so I thought he'd line up early for 'em.
But it looks like
he overslept a bit.
Inspector Otaki...
Besides, the games between Ohgane
and Kohnan are really popular.
To get tickets for the infield bleachers, you
have to get up early and stand in line all day.
Then they should've
bought tickets in advance...
Nagashima faces off against the pitcher Inao.
Here comes...
the second pitch!
He pops it up!
It clears the field...
and goes just foul.
Here, crushed ice!
A bag for each of you!
Nice and cold!
Thank you very much!
You're very welcome.
But is this okay, Inspector Otaki?
What about your job?
Don't worry about it. He took time off.
Right?
Yeah.
Yeah, I've been watchin' since the
quarter-finals. Today's my third day here.
You must really like Koshien.
Of course he does!
Otaki-han used to play
baseball in high school himself!
Right?
You're exaggerating,
Kazuha-chan.
Oh, are you really?
I'm embarrassed
to tell the story...
So, did you walk
the dirt of Koshien?
Nah.
I only made it up to the best 8
of the regional tournament.
But it sure takes me back,
watching these kids play.
Struggling while covered
in sweat and dirt...
And just giving
the game everything you have.
What are you doing, Otaki?!
You can't even catch that?!
Otaki!
Maybe I just don't
have talent for baseball.
That's not true!
You shouldn't give up.
Just practice harder and harder.
Yeah, that's true...
I'll train until I get better!
Hey, Freshman Otaki!
Yes?
You made it! You'll be #7, catcher, when
facing off against Yakushiji in a practice match!
Yes, sir!
Hey, isn't that great?
Let's do our best!
Yeah!
Sempai, maybe I just don't
have talent for baseball...
That's not true.
Instead of quitting,
just practice twice as hard.
If you quit, it's over.
When I was in your year, I sucked pretty bad, too.
But I stayed
after practice everyday.
And before I knew it, I was team captain.
You were bad?
Sure! I was awful.
Really?
Yep. So never give up.
Japan's National High School
Baseball Championship Preliminaries
What're you mopin' about?
If you're sad, the underclassmen
will feel bad as well.
The reason this underdog team
got this far was you, Otaki.
Our underclassmen will be the ones to
make it to Koshien, so put them at ease.
There's one last thing I need
to tell you guys.
Never...
Never give up!
Y-Yes, sir!
It makes me feel like all my
hard work's worth somethin'.
It gives me the strength to go on.
Koshien's really somethin' else.
What a worthless place this is.
Don't you think so, Hiroshi?
Bottom of the 2nd, Kohnan batting,
Nagashima in the batter's box...
Pitcher Inao gets ready
for his fourth pitch.
And there it is!
He hit it right down
the third baseline!
Looks like a multiple-base hit.
He's fast!
That batter's fast!
That left fielder's
looking pretty sluggish.
Is he gonna make it to third?
Go! Go!
C'mon, Left, what're you doin'?
Nagashima rounds second
and heads for third.
The left fielder throws it to the
infield, a fast one to third base!
It's a good throw!
Nagasama's almost
to third! He dives...
The third baseman catches...
Safe!
The fleet-footed Nagashima
gets a three-base hit!
No outs and a runner on third.
Looks like they can't avoid
a run batted in.
No, it's too early to say that.
That pitcher's got spirit.
It's the first round of the spring preliminaries.
We're now in
the 18th inning of overtime.
This match between Teito High and Ohgane
has had its share of ups and downs.
At the bottom of the 18th with two outs,
Teito is hitting with a runner on first.
In the batter's box
we have #4, Yamamoto.
Inao faces off against Yamamoto.
Here's the pitch.
A mobile phone?
Was that there a second ago?
Maybe that guy
who walked past us dropped it.
Well?
Hello?
Are you the one
who dropped this phone?
Yeah.
All right, why don't you come
over to the right side stands...
Are you having fun?
I asked you if this place
is really all that much fun.
Who are you?
If you don't mind, why don't
we play a game that's more fun?
Something a lot more interesting
than some ball game...
Strike!
A little bloodsport
to liven things up.
Well, I say bloodsport, but I'm
the one who's going to die.
Idiot. If you wanna die, go do it by yourself.
Oh, I will.
But not by myself.
I'll be lonely
if no one comes with me.
What?!
The rules are simple.
When the 3rd,
6th and 9th innings end,
a phone hidden somewhere
in this stadium will ring.
Ball!
A phone with a lead
to my whereabouts.
I'll be near the phone that
rings immediately after the game.
Strike!
I'll call three times.
If you don't pick up,
then it's three strikes, you're out.
Of course, if you find all
the phones before the game ends,
I'll be glad to give up
and admit that you won.
Hey, quit jerkin' us around!
I'm hangin' up.
You'll find out
if I'm jerking you around...
at the end of the 2nd.
H-Hey, what're you talkin' about?
Well, the first hint is in a text
message I sent to the phone in your hand.
Oh, and tell that officer sitting next to you
that I look forward to possibly meeting him soon.
Well then, I'll talk to you later.
Hold on a second!
At least tell us who you are!
Me? I'm...
Let's just say I'm... The Demon of Koshien.
The Demon of Koshien?!
H-Hey! Wait!
Strike! Batter out!
All right!
Is the 2nd inning over?
There's only one out.
What's wrong, Hei-chan?
Weren't you watching?
The last three strikes
were amazing fastballs.
Here...
This is it.
96, 7, 13...
What's that?
The location
of the owner of this phone.
That's where he'll be, and where
he wants us to deliver this phone.
What the heck is that?
He should come here
and get it himself.
But I wonder what
that means, 96, 7, 13...
It doesn't seem
to be a seat number.
Could it be another code?
No thanks, I've had
enough of codes lately!
After all, it was thanks to some
code that we didn't see Takarazuka
and came here
to Koshien instead.
If it was 8, 1, 2,
then it'd be the Alps stand.
Alps stand?
Why's that, Dad?
See, the 8, 1, 2 make ha-i-ji.
And that sounds like Heidi, so...
She has to be in the Alps!
So lame...
Oh, dad...
Well, whatever.
Anyway, Otaki-han.
Come help us look.
But it's just getting
to the good part...
Don't worry. It'll only take
a minute if Otaki-san helps.
Oh? You're going
with them, Conan-kun?
Yup. It looks kinda interesting.
Don't worry.
I'll bring him right back.
Geez, what's all this about?
They're the ones
who brought us here.
Seriously.
W-What? S-Suicide?!
I-Is this for real, Hei-chan?
Yeah. If we can't find him by
the end of the game, he'll kill himself.
And take some poor
souls with him!
But couldn't this be some prank?
I'm pretty sure it isn't.
The guy who called
didn't disguise his voice.
And the phone he left had
its serial number intact.
That can only mean he doesn't care
if we trace it back to him later, right?
Moreover...
He did this knowing
that Otaki-han was an officer...
That proves it all.
Anyway, we have to use Otaki-han's police
badge to get us into the backstop area.
Huh? Why the backstop?
When he called before, I heard the umpire call a strike.
He could still be there!
Yeah!
Oh, no!
Oh, no, Hei-chan?
He's not gonna blow himself up
until the end, right?
That guy said he was gonna show us he was
serious at the end of the 2nd inning.
W-What?!
We'll go on ahead, Otaki-han!
If that cheer we heard was
for three outs...
We could already be too late!
Oh, no, I knew it!
The bottom of the 2nd is over!
Kid, you go low and I'll go high.
Otaki-han, search the middle.
It's a suspicious
middle-aged man with a hat.
Got it.
Damn it. He's not here.
But...
Nothing's happened.
Not a thing...
Top of the 3rd inning. Hitting
for Ohgane High, #9, right fielder, Seki-kun.
Sakuraba, with the first pitch.
Here it is!
Hit!
Straight down the third baseline,
the third baseman picks it up.
And a fast one to first!
And he's...
Out!
A picture-perfect play by Kohnan
High's third baseman, Nagashima.
Seki makes one out here
at the top of the 3rd for Ohgane.
Hey, Hei-chan, what's goin' on?
Didn't somethin' happen?
It's strange.
That guy said he'd show us
proof by the end of the 2nd inning.
Maybe it was a prank?
It is the Koshien finals, after all.
Hey.
What's that?
There, on the other
side of the highway.
What is it?
There's a lot of smoke.
Looks like a fire.
Isn't that over
by the Matoroku district?
Otaki-han, don't you have
a senpai at the Hyogo police?
Oh, yeah.
Could you call him
and ask what's goin' on?
I got it.
A-A bomb?
Are you sure, Wakusa?
Yeah. We'll get a detailed report from
the fire department once the fire's out,
but that seems to be the case.
The place was a shipping firm
called Takano Transportation.
According
to eyewitness accounts,
it looks like there was a big boom
before the place went up in flames.
I see.
Fortunately, that company had a holiday
today, so there were no injuries or fatalities.
But with an explosion in a building
that big with no one inside,
it probably was a bomb.
Hey, do you know what time
the fire started?
Let me see...
Oh, Namada-kun.
What is it?
About that bombing
that occurred earlier.
You know about
what time that was?
Let's see...
Wasn't it just about 1:40?
That's exactly when
the 2nd inning ended.
This is bad, Hattori.
If the proof that man
was talking about
was this fire bomb, then what
if he's going to kill himself by...
T-That moron!
If he sets off a bomb
in a dense crowd like this,
it'll be a disaster!
Hey, Otaki...
Weren't you going to
Koshien today?
Why're you worrying
about the fire?
Ah, well...
H-Hei-chan, what should I do?
Should I tell
the department about this?
We can't...
He said he'd kill himself
when the game ends.
If we stop the game in the middle
and try to evacuate,
he'll set it off.
It looks like the best course
of action is to decipher his code,
find the three phones,
and then catch him.
Regardless, if we
don't solve this riddle,
and find the next phone here
in the stands, by the end of the 3rd,
it's all over.
Top of the 3rd, one out,
runners on first and second...
Right on the other side of the backstop,
at Entrance 8, there's a map of the stadium.
Why don't we go there,
put our heads together,
and see if we can sort
out this 96 [7] 13?
Then I'll go see if I can borrow
a radio from Uncle Kogoro.
It'd be bad if we don't know
how the game's going, right?
Ah, sure.
#3, pitcher, Inao-kun.
All right, a clean-up hitter.
This round looks like
it's not gonna end soon.
Let's go, Hei-chan.
Right.
Ball!
Ball, the count is 3-0.
The pitcher hasn't thrown any pitches
in the strike zone against the clean-up hitter.
If this keeps up, we'll have a walk,
and we'll get to the fourth batter.
Heiji's sure takin' his time...
Maybe they haven't found
the owner of that phone?
In that case, then why don't
they just give up and come back?
That guy's the one who forgot it, so it's not like they have to find him.
I-I guess so...
Don't worry!
We'll find him, no matter what.
Just wait.
Conan-kun...
So Uncle Kogoro,
can I borrow your radio?
Otherwise, we won't know how the
game's going while we look for him.
Right?
Please?
Geez. Don't break it.
Here.
Thanks.
Oh, and if you see a strange guy wearing
a white hat, call Heiji-niichan's phone, okay?
Hold on, Conan-kun!
He looked...
Conan-kun's face just then...
Looked just like...
His...
He got all of that one, folks!
Going to deep right field!
Here it comes!
Is it comin' out?
The ball flies into the sea breeze
and toward the right stands!
H-He's got it!
Yuruyama tags and starts off!
A throw to second, and...
Safe!
From that fly ball to right field, one
out, and runners on first and third.
It went against the wind and still flew
the whole 96 meter wingspan of Koshien.
96 meter wingspan?
96, 7, 13...
Right Outfield Seats
First-Base Alps Open Seats
First Base Premium
Reserved Seats
Central Premium Open Seats
Third Base Premium
Reserved Seats
Third Base Alps
Open Seats
96, 7, 13...
Left Outfield Seats
Where is it? Where is it?!
Scoreboard
Right Outfield Seats
It has to be somewhere
in the stands.
Hei-chan, we're
running out of time.
Damn...
Where the heck is it?
Heiji-niichan!
I got the radio!
What's goin' on with the game?
The top of the 3rd just
ended, it's still 0-0.
Three more outs, then.
Nevermind that.
Does this stadium have
wings or something?
Wings?
Yeah. Earlier, the announcer mentioned the
whole 96 meter wingspan of Koshien.
Geez, you seriously don't know
a thing about baseball, do you?
Well, it ain't surprisin'
that you don't know,
since they don't use the term
for other sports' fields.
Kid, the wingspan means the distance
from home plate to the foul pole is 96 meters.
C-Could it be...
The 96 at the start of this code...
is talking about the seats right
before the pole?
But which one, Hei-chan?
There's two, one on the right
and one on the left.
Then, maybe we can figure
out by the bracketed 7?
7, 7, 7...
This is bad.
The first batter went
three strikes for one out.
Kid, turn around for a sec.
L-Like this?
That's it!
That's it, Hei-chan?
His jersey is #55, not #7.
But it's a jersey number!
And in high school baseball, which
position does #7 usually play?
#7's usually a left fielder, but...
Hei-chan, you mean...?
Yeah! It means
the pole next to left field.
T-Then what's the last 13 mean?
It probably means
the 13th seat in the section.
The first phone has to be there!
At the bottom of the 3rd,
two out with Kohnan at bat.
At the plate is the left
fielder, #1, Iwata-kun.
The pitcher takes
a big wind-up, and the pitch!
Third Base Alps Open Seats
Strike!
A fastball in and high...
The pitcher goes straight
to the second pitch.
Strike two!
Another fastball!
27...
26...
25...
The wind-up...
21...
20...
19...
The third pitch...
15...
14...
Here it comes!
13...
Here!
Strike three!
Don't! Give it here!
Hello?
Hello?!
Hey, punk!
What's so funny?
It's funny.
You're really
a funny bunch of kids.
How about competing a bit longer
and putting on another show for me?
I really enjoy watching people
struggle against the inevitable.
Hey, wait!
Hey! Hello?
Hello?
Damn, he hung up.
Hey, take a look.
He left the next code.
47, 3...
And 4?
47, 3, 4...
There's no use.
There's no such
thing as a victory...
that can be won...
through effort.
It doesn't exist.
Top of the 4th.
Hitting for Ohgane High, #5,
left fielder, Shigeta-kun.
Shigeta vs. Sakuraba.
The first pitch...
Here it is!
It's up!
Down the left line!
H-He's got it!
He caught it!
Great play!
That third baseman's amazing!
He is.
Anyway, we have to
figure out this code.
We've got until the end
of the 6th to figure out this 47, 3, 4
and find the next phone.
Before that guy with the white hat
kills himself by detonating the bomb.
I have no clue what
these numbers mean either.
No, we can figure out
more than half already.
See, in the first code,
96 [7] 13,
we figured out the first phone was
near the left pole in the 13th row,
because the distance from home
plate to the pole is 96 meters,
the 7 in brackets referred to
the jersey number of a left fielder,
and the final 13 meant
the seats in the 13th row.
So then, with 47 [3] 4,
the 3 in brackets is a jersey number,
and the 4 is
the seat number, right?
Yeah, but if we don't know
where to start...
The 47 is probably telling us that,
but it has to be along
the first baseline.
In high school baseball,
#3 is a first baseman.
But Hei-chan...
Kohnan High's #3
is a third baseman.
Out!
Yeah. But that's a special case,
so we shouldn't worry about it.
But what if that man tailored his code
for this final between Kohnan and Ohgane?
Then you really
can't say for sure.
Then let's do this.
I'll take the fourth row
seats along the first baseline.
Kid, you take the third baseline.
And me?
Otaki-han, once you get us into the seats
there, wait by the map of the stadium outside.
It's exactly between the entrances
to the first and third baseline areas.
It'll be easier for me to meet up with
the kid that way, once we find the phone.
Well then, while I'm waiting, I'll ask
my senpai at the Hyogo police department
if there's anyone matching
the man in the white hat's description
who might have a grudge against Takano
Shipping, since he bombed them earlier.
Yeah. We'd appreciate
it, Otaki-han.
Strike!
Three strikes!
And he fires off
a series of eight strikeouts.
He doesn't seem to be running
out of them anytime soon.
What's that boy doing?
Ah, I was just looking
for something...
Now it's full steam ahead,
after two strikeouts in a row.
Idiots...
Can't you make it go any slower?
What, really?
Yeah. Last month,
a Takano Shipping cargo truck...
A-A home run!
Bottom of the 4th, Kohnan High gets
a run on the board with one hit!
What am I doing? I don't have
time to be watching the game.
Anyway, I have to find it...
...is especially impressive, since he was
using a wooden bat, and not a metallic one.
47, 3, 4...
47, 3...
What?
Metallic?
Metallic...
Metallic... Metal...
Metal?
Strike! Batter out!
Kubota gets three
strikes and is out!
But in this inning, Kohnan High scored
a run from Nagashima's home run.
Ohgane is trying
to make up for it now.
In the batter's box
is #8, Watanabe.
Sakuraba throws
against Watanabe.
A hit!
Right down the middle!
Out!
Kohnan High's third baseman, Nagashima,
is really showing his stuff in this game.
Strike!
Inao's third pitch
against Sakuraba...
Strike! Batter out!
A swing and a strike-out.
Kohnan High with
no runs this inning.
As the 5th inning comes
to a close, the score is 0-1.
Kohnan still with a one-run lead from
Nagashima's home run in the 4th.
Out!
Top of the 6th,
hitting for Kohnan High,
#9, second baseman,
Michishita-kun.
Ah, Kudo?
You find it?
No. I made a sweep of the fourth
row, but it wasn't there.
How about you?
Same here.
Looks like we have no choice but
to try to figure out 47, huh?
Say, Hattori.
What is it, Kudo?
At Koshien, there isn't anything
like silver, is there?
Let me think...
The silver at Koshien would be...
The Silver Umbrella?
So there is?
You should be able to see it.
That big roof on the top platform
over the backstop...
That's what it is.
Then there's no doubt. That's
where the second phone is!
Why?
You know, 47 is silver!
That's right! 47 is the atomic number of silver!
Anyway, let's meet at the exit,
then head over to the 4th row
of the backstop area!
But can we make it?
Back there, there's gonna be
more than 100 seats in a single row!
If we search it all, then there'll
be three outs and it'll be over!
Then maybe it's either
by the first or third baselines?
There's a third
baseline under the 47!
Idiot!
I searched there already!
There's gotta be something else.
Some #3 that tells us where
to look under the Silver Umbrella.
I-I see!
I've got it, Kudo!
There's someone else
with the #3.
Otaki-han!
Oh, Hei-chan!
Have you figured out the code?
Yeah.
The first 47 is
the Silver Umbrella,
and the 3 in brackets...
is the jersey number
of the king of baseball...
Babe Ruth, who's
on this monument.
Then the second phone is...
The monument is just
to the left of the center.
In other words...
Advance-Sale Ticket Booth
Central Premium Open Seats
Reporter Seats
Information
You are here
...under the Silver Umbrella,
behind the backstop,
just to the left of the center,
and in the fourth row!
What's that?
What happened?
A runner reached first due to a fielding error.
But we have to hurry.
There's already two
outs—
only one left!
Ball!
Ball! 3-2!
Top of the 6th, two outs,
runner on first.
The count's 3-2.
If he walks this batter, the pitcher will have to
face the batter who hit a home run against him.
The pitcher chalks his hand,
and throws from the mound...
Here it comes.
Looks like a pop fly.
But it's on the first base side
in front of the Kohnan dugout.
The catcher Ono gives up on it.
Wait! Here comes the pitcher!
He's running down
the ball toward the Kohnan bench!
He dives for it!
Is he all right?
H-He's caught it! He's caught it!
The pitcher makes the final play
for three outs and a switch!
A-Amazing...
He didn't even think of
his own safety...
I wonder if all boys are like that.
Watching these Koshien finals,
a spectator can't help but get excited!
Hey, idiot!
We're gonna find the third phone
and then we're gonna find you.
So just shut up and wait for us, jackass!
Damn, he hung up
without saying anything.
By the way, Hei-chan, about
that lead with Takano Shipping...
Yeah?
According to my senpai,
there was a fatal accident in Tokyo involving
one of the company's trucks last month.
It seems one person was killed.
Could that accident
be the cause?
Maybe, but what's that got to do with Koshien?
I ain't figured that out yet.
Well, whatever.
Let's find this guy and ask him.
We've already figured out
the trick with his codes.
W-What's this?
There's nothing
but the row number here!
So we have no hints, huh?
Hiroshi...
Why?
Why isn't there anything but the row number?
Could it be because you
sounded too confident earlier?
We're gonna find the third phone
and then we're gonna find you.
So just shut up
and wait for us, jackass!
Damn, he hung up
without saying anything.
If he really wanted to commit suicide
by blowing himself up, and you ticked him off,
it's not surprising that he'd
give you less of a hint to find him.
That's ridiculous! If he wanted to do it that
badly, he would've already pressed the switch
and caused us some real trouble!
There's gotta be some meaning
behind the blanks in this message.
It's pointing to somewhere
in Koshien's stands.
It's really bizarre...
He wants to blow himself up, and
gives these incomprehensible hints...
Why is he making us try
and find him?
Maybe he wants us to stop him?
Some part of him doesn't want to do
this, so he's having someone stop him.
Though he might
not even realize it.
He wants us to stop him?
See, because his codes
are all things
that only someone who loves
baseball and Koshien would know.
It's hard to believe that someone
like that would do this at Koshien,
much less use a bomb to commit
suicide, don't you think?
I-I guess you're right...
Anyway, Otaki-han.
Could you call the Hyogo police back
and ask for the details of that case?
The accident related to Takano
Shipping he bombed earlier.
It bothers me though... What would drive
a baseball fan to do something like this at Koshien?
Got it.
Then the two of us will
figure out this riddle
and check the 13th row
of seats in the meantime.
As much as we can until
the time limit at the end of the 9th.
Yeah, you're right.
Though we won't know if there
will be a bottom of the 9th...
That's right...
As long as the score doesn't
change, and there's no comeback,
the game will end after the top of the 9th!
The game is at the top of the 8th,
one out, runner on third.
Ohgane has a chance
to even the score.
Pitcher on the mound...
The runner on third starts off!
It's a squeeze!
A short fly, right
in front of the pitcher!
It's caught! It's been caught!
A direct catch by third!
The ball goes to third
for a double play.
Getting a run in looks far away
for Ohgane High.
Trying to find an opportunity
to score, they're still at 0.
We're at 0-1, going into
the bottom of the 8th with Kohnan at bat.
Yes.
What? A h-high school student?
The one hit
by the Takano Shipping truck?
Are you sure it was
a high school student?
Yeah.
I was in charge of the case.
It was about the same time
I was transferred here from Tokyo.
I have the details
right here for you.
Let's see...
Ah, here we are.
You may know the kid since you
follow high school baseball.
Yeah, his name
was Hiroshi Torimitsu.
R-Right...
In the first round
of the spring preliminaries,
he and Ohgane's ace pitcher faced off and
took the game to the 18th inning of overtime.
They lost
by a pretty small margin.
You mean, that kid...
Yeah. On the way home from practice,
his bike was hit in the roadway.
The thing was, his bike was old, and
since he was exhausted from practice,
he couldn't get
out of the way in time.
Oh, and after the accident,
the kid's father went missing,
so we couldn't find him
for questioning.
C-Could he be...
Dad...
Strike!
I'll try my hardest!
I'll get to the summer Koshien,
work harder... and harder...
I'll go pro, make money, and then
you won't have to work so hard!
Count on it...
Dad!
Hiroshi...
Hey, Kudo, you find it?
No, it's not anywhere.
Looks like it's not in the 13th row
behind the backstop.
Damn, why is it blank
except for this 13?
At least write a jersey
number in the brackets!
Hey, Hattori!
Could that be it?
Look, there's a player without
a jersey number next to their bench!
Oh, the ballboy?
I searched the 13th row behind both
dugouts, but there wasn't anything.
Then all that's left is the Alps
and the outfield stands.
Strike! Batter out!
No swings and three strikes
to make two outs!
Ohgane's deadlocked runner hasn't
been able to take a step off second base!
Now only one out before Kohnan gets the win!
N-No! If the game ends, that
man's gonna blow himself up!
Damn it! We don't have time to
check the Alps or the outfield stands!
What is it?!
Why isn't there
anything written here?!
If there's nothing
written, that means...
Zero... Nothing... Blank...
It's hit!
A promising one down
the left line!
Will he catch it?
Will it go?
Is this a comeback?
Or the end?
Don't catch it, moron!
Now only one out
before Kohnan gets the win!
N-No! If the game ends, that
man's gonna blow himself up!
Damn it! We don't have time to
check the Alps or the outfield stands!
What is it?!
Why isn't there
anything written here?!
If there's nothing
written, that means...
Zero... Nothing... Blank...
It's hit!
A promising one down
the left line!
Will he catch it?
Will it go?
Is this a comeback?
Or the end?
Don't catch it, moron!
He missed it!
Nice! Now the game's tied!
Missed?
Wait, that was...
While the ball is in the outfield,
the runner makes his way to third.
Hey, Kudo! What happened?
He passes third!
The ball goes from
the infield back to home!
Safe!
A-An inside-the-park home run...
That's incredible!
It's a comeback!
Hei-chan, what's going on?
Have you figured out anything?
Ask the kid.
Here, take a look at this map.
Central Premium Open Seats
Reporter Seats
First-Base Alps Open Seats
First-Base Premium
Reserved Seats
Left Outfield Seats
Right Outfield Seats
Scoreboard
Third-Base Alps Open Seats
Third-Base Premium
Reserved Seats
The entrances to the park
are numbered 1 to 24,
Left Outfield Seats
Right Outfield Seats
Scoreboard
but they missed 17 and 22.
Missed?
The entrance numbers...
17 and...
22...
He's right!
The code is probably
referring to this.
I think they blocked off accesses 17 and 22
a long time ago to build some sort of facility.
But which is it?
Should we search
the 17th or the 22nd?
We're running outta time,
let's take a look at 17's area.
Hold on.
It looks like we won't
have time for that.
We're approaching
the home stretch.
Bottom of the 9th,
two outs, with no runners.
Ohgane is one run in the lead.
At bat is the young man who's 3
for 3 today, with one home run.
#3, third baseman,
Nagashima-kun.
Well, he's between a rock
and a hard place...
He'll have to walk him.
Nagashima's the only batter who's hit
against him, and he can't afford another run.
Strike!
M-Middle and center!
Oh geez, is this a duel?
I figured as much.
Those two are just like Shin'ichi.
Huh? Just like him?
They're just like Shin'ichi from
the football finals in middle school.
The other team was up by one point,
and they went into extra time.
Less than a minute before the end,
the other team scored another goal,
and all hope had been lost.
I saw Shin'ichi
in the center with the ball,
and wondered what
he was thinking.
So I looked through
my binoculars.
He was smiling.
Smiling?
I asked the other boys
on the football team afterwards.
Guess what he said
as he was smiling?
What, what?
He was like...
Oh, man...
If we can pull a win out of this,
we'll be legends.
That's so cool...
Well? How did the game end?
Yeah, how?
In the end, they lost...
The real world doesn't have
those kinds of happy endings!
In the penalty kick shootout.
Penalty kick shootout?
That means...
Yep. Shin'ichi got a goal and
an assist in the last minute to tie it up
and got them to the pens.
He ended up missing
the last penalty.
But the sight of him standing
all alone, facing away,
somehow looked kind of cool.
B-But...
Just kind of. A little.
So yeah, I was just thinking
that those two reminded me of him.
Not knowing when to quit...
Almost like a little kid
that hates to lose.
I wonder if Heiji's the same way...
I'm sure he is.
Strike two!
A swing! 0-2!
Damn, we're stuck!
We can't make it in time!
Otaki-han, it ain't
over 'til it's over.
If you've got time to complain,
then spend it thinking about the code.
B-But still, there's no time...
Now Kohnan's
Nagashima is cornered!
Can he fire off
the end of the inning?
Nagashima?
That's it! The blank number!
The blank in the brackets was
talking about a retired jersey number!
A retired jersey?
Between 21 and 23, there's a booth that
has the retired jerseys of the Tigers.
Their home field is Koshien!
Hei-chan!
Weren't the outfield seats on the right side
near where we were sitting in the first place?
Ran!
Damn, she can't hear
with the noise of the cheering!
Inao with the 100th
pitch of the game!
He pops it up!
Is it too high?
Idiot!
The centre-fielder spreads his
arms and calls for the catch!
There's nothing Kohnan
High can do but hope!
Don't catch it! Don't catch it!
I'm coming, Hiroshi.
I'll be with you soon.
Don't! Don't catch it!
Inao with the 100th
pitch of the game!
He pops it up!
Is it too high?
Idiot!
The centre-fielder spreads his
arms and calls for the catch!
There's nothing Kohnan
High can do but hope!
Don't catch it! Don't catch it!
I'm coming, Hiroshi.
I'll be with you soon.
Confident of their victory,
the Ohgane Nine start to rejoice!
The center fielder is still prepared
for the catch, taking his time backing up.
Backing up...
Further...
Back...
It's gone!
Home run! It's a home run!
It's even! The game is tied!
Kohnan hangs
on in the eleventh hour!
From two outs
at the bottom of the ninth,
they manage to stay in the game!
That crazy high pop fly...
It made it out!
Amazing...
What...
What in the world?
Ball!
Dead ball.
That's the second in a row!
Ohgane's ace pitcher
Inao's control goes wild.
Did the earlier
home run get to him?
That's why I said you
should've walked that guy!
Trying to act cool after they got a hit on you and
you're shaken up, leaving you to carry the team.
At this rate, the game'll be over
with a walk-off home run.
A swing and three strikes!
All right!
I don't believe that pitcher...
The game will go into extra
innings with the score tied at 2.
What's that sound?
Kazuha-chan,
it's behind your feet.
What, another phone?
For cryin' out loud...
Maybe you should pick it up?
Hey, you! We found
the last phone!
Hurry up and show yourself!
H-Heiji!
The game isn't over yet.
It's overtime.
Overtime?!
Sure. The Demon of Koshien will only
show himself when the game is over.
H-Hey!
You said overtime,
but where's the code?
Otaki-han, help us look!
He could still be around here!
G-Got it!
M-Mail?
I'll go right, you take
care of the left side!
Sure.
Wait!
Looks like there's no need
to search for him.
Man, the Koshien finals
never disappoint!
They're always great games!
Koshien?
This isn't that great a place.
If only...
These people weren't here...
And weren't so excited...
If only...
If only this didn't exist...
My son would still be...
Oh, no! He's dropped it!
An error on a simple catch!
Ohgane seems like they've been cursed
by the Demon of Koshien here in the 10th!
Several hits, errors, and the bases loaded
with two outs—
they're in trouble!
And the next batter they face is...
#3...
Third baseman...
Nagashima-kun!
That settles it.
The Ohgane Nine
assemble on the mound.
The catcher seems
to be hanging his head.
That's right...
He screwed up
at such a crucial moment.
The other nine will blame him.
His friends,
his relatives...
will be ashamed.
Because he failed.
He's smiling.
That pitcher's smiling.
Really?
The Ohgane Nine take their
positions, all smiles!
Ridiculous!
How can they be smiling?
At a time like this, why?
Because it's baseball.
You can't play baseball
without nine people, after all.
Ohgane's pitcher
is probably thinking...
For himself, for his team...
And for the catcher
who made the error...
He's gonna strike out this
batter even if he injures his arm.
Hit!
But it goes a little left, and foul!
But that batter's not giving up
until he brings his runners home.
So this game could go either way.
T-That's ridiculous!
If they overdo it and get injured,
they'll never go pro!
They might never play again!
W-What's the point?
What is it about Koshien?
That's a solid one headed right!
It's got the distance, is it a goner?
Foul! Another long foul!
It's nothing complicated.
Sure, there are plenty of kids
who aim for Koshien hoping to go pro.
But they leave that at the door.
The second they step
onto the field...
and hear the call Play Ball!...
it turns into a battlefield
with only two outcomes...
You either win...
or lose.
Out!
Three strikes! No runs!
Try to win, win, and win...
All to get first place.
Scores and statistics go away.
The game becomes simpler.
With your history in baseball,
you should understand.
Am I wrong...
Teito Industrial school
baseball team sponsor...
Yukio Torimitsu-san?
It wasn't the truck's fault or
Koshien's that your son was hit.
Your son worked so hard at baseball
practice that he was exhausted,
and couldn't brake in time.
That's right.
I know. I knew, but...
I wanted to blame someone!
So I could go on living...
To dull the pain
of losing my dear boy!
But in the end, it looks like you guys
wouldn't let me press the button.
You all...
And...
Both those teams.
Of course not.
This is the place where the worst
losers in Japan meet, after all.
That's right.
Well, shall we go?
Yeah.
Top of the 11th,
hitting for Ohgane High...
Yes.
That's right.
Please take things from here.
The authorities are on their way.
But I'm surprised you guys solved
that last one I thought up on the spot.
Ah, we knew the 812 meant the Alps seats...
Thanks the worst
punner in Japan.
You all right?
A cold?
Dummy, these are
the outfield seats!
It's not the Alps!
Right?
I'm hilarious!
Sure you are.
Ran!
Kimura-san!
On the next Conan:
"Target: Kogoro Mouri"
Next Conan's Hint: Service ticket
It's nearly Christmas!
I wonder what I'm gonna get.
You act like such a kid!
Well, I do look like one...