Today is the start of Conan's tenth year!
To start off this big occasion, Uncle will be the target!
Seeing through to the one and only truth,
I look like a child but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
Are you all right?
Do you need to call a taxi?
I'm fine.
Thanks. Good night then.
Please be careful.
Good night.
That was dangerous,
even though I was able to avoid it!
The Target is Mouri Kogoro!
I Come on, just bear with it.
It hurts, Ran.
Can't you be more gentle?
What are you talking about?
I have been gentle, Dad.
Just bear with it a little more.
I should go to that construction site tomorrow
and tell them to be more careful.
Who'd be calling at this hour?
What's this? A mail?
What?
Dad, what happened?
"I won't fail next time. I'll definitely kill you next time."
So it wasn't an accident? It was an
intentional murder attempt?
What a shameless guy, ambushing me over there.
Dad, have you found any clues as to who'd do this?
Nope! Absolutely no idea.
Well, it's a possibility someone has something against me...
Who would have something against you?
Well, if things continue like this, the
culprit will give themselves away.
A criminal act always has a motive behind it.
This time it's just because someone hates me.
I just need to check on those people who hate me,
then I'll probably find some leads.
Wait...
This cell phone isn't yours.
What did you say?!
Let me have a look.
You're right!
Wait!
This coat doesn't belong to you either!
There's a name on it.
Kimura.
So, this coat and cell phone aren't yours.
They belong to someone named Kimura-san.
Then, that means this mail wasn't for me.
I see. How boring...
Wait. Where are you going?
Going to sleep...
Here.
Ouch.
Conan-kun!
How lame...
Hey, what do you think, Conan-kun?
Uncle must have been mistaken for that Kimura
guy because he was wearing his coat.
Or, did you mean something else?
I know! I'll try calling Dad's cell phone and see if he's there.
I wonder what kind of person Kimura-san,
the owner of this cell phone will be like?
No one is answering.
Indeed, this is Kimura-san's coat.
Kimura-san, last night...
He came when you, Mouri-san,
were sleeping here last night.
He stayed for about an hour.
So, then? Where does Kimura-san live?
I don't know.
He's a new customer.
Danaka
Kimura
I only remembered his name because
of the sign on this bottle.
I see...
Well, he'll probably come again someday.
I'll stop troubling you by talking about this now.
By the way, do you have them?
The cheese made by the shopkeeper is very spicy!
It makes you sweat by causing the cells in your
body to feel like they're going to burst!
That's why, if you can't control the
cravings, you have to come here!
It's just that delicious!
I see.
That's the reason for taking off his coat.
The username of the person who sent the mail
was checked, but there were no matches.
From last night until now,
there hasn't been anyone named Kimura involved in a case.
Then it's just someone's practical joke.
Police are very busy...
You don't need to waste your time
on such an insignificant thing.
But...
Plus, the target wasn't me. It's that Kimura guy.
It was the culprit's mistake.
However, if the culprit doesn't realize their mistake...
and continues to target you, what will you do?
Ran-san is worried about this as well.
Takagi-kun,
don't take the words from a child seriously, okay?
About that Bar Lemon... It seems they've
opened quite a number of drink bistros.
About one week ago,
I was able to get the service coupons at their grand opening.
But, by the time I went to use them,
the cheese had just ran out.
The place suits me well, since I've had
cravings for spicy foods lately.
Takagi-kun!
Y-Yes!
We have a witness.
Last night, students who live near the construction site...
saw a guy running away from the scene
right after the iron pipe fell.
Even though their face wasn't seen clearly,
they noticed their right arm had a burn scar.
Does this give you any ideas as to who the culprit may be?
Unfortunately, there weren't any
suspicious fingerprints at the scene.
There wasn't anything.
So, then...
Find Kimura-san and start the investigation from there.
Dad!
We need to find him before another person involved in this!
I'm not Kimura-san after all.
All of this happened because you went to Bar Lemon.
Uncle, if we don't go look for Kimura-san ourselves,
something worse could happen.
Kimura-san?
His coat fits my dad perfectly. So, that person
has to have a similar height and body build.
Do you know of anyone like him.
I don't have any customers like that.
I see...
Watch out!
You bastard!
You won't get away!
A scar on the right arm!
Just as I thought, it was a stolen truck.
In other words, it's an intentional crime.
I agree.
What's happening, Mouri-kun?
Kimura
Next time,
I will kill you sure.
Inspector, the shopkeeper's treatment is done.
He'll be out of the hospital in two or three days.
How dare he involve other people!
M-Mouri-kun, where are you going?!
I've decided to find that bastard!
How?!
You don't even know where he is!
Where are you going to look?!
M-Mouri-san...
It's no big deal.
I'll use my instincts to find him.
What are you talking about?!
Please stay home and let us arrest the culprit.
That's right! They're trying to take your life, after all.
I can't do that.
The world famous Mouri Kogoro...
Amazing Work!
hiding because he's scared of having his life taken away.
Sleeping Kogoro
Great Det
It'd ruin my reputation.
So what?! It's time to put away that pride!
Right, Conan-kun?
Pride?!
You think that I'm being strong because of pride?!
Stop joking around.
Do we know who's trying to take my life?
Ha! We have no idea!
So, isn't this a good chance to find out?
As long as that Kimura keeps hiding,
use me as bait to lure the culprit out.
Wait, Mouri-san.
What are you talking about?
It's impossible to stop people who hide.
Okay.
Inspector.
In exchange, let these two people be your bodyguards.
I refuse.
If the culprit knows about this, he'll be
more careful and might not show up.
No! It's too dangerous to do it alone!
Even if it's your words, Inspector,
I can't follow them this time.
I'm involved in this case. If there's a second or third
victim because of me, how could I face myself?
However, if anything happens to
me, the rest will be up to you.
M-Mouri-kun...
He's acting the opposite of how he normally does.
Mouri-san.
He's not being honest with himself...
Now, we'll have to find this person named
"Kimura" quickly, before anything happens.
Yes, sir.
Let's go, Takagi-kun.
Okay!
It's been three days since that case.
Yeah...
Have you found Kimura yet?
We're still searching.
We think that the culprit is simply acting
out of hatred toward Mouri-kun.
Or, it might be because of the confusion
between Mouri-kun and Kimura.
We still have no idea who or where this person is.
Plus, he made sure both crimes didn't have any evidence.
Not even fingerprints.
This is hard to say, but we have no idea where to start now.
Fingerprints.
He's afraid of his identity being found out.
This means fingerprints of the culprit were recorded before,
which means he was arrested.
Plus, he knows Uncle.
However, he doesn't have any motive
for directing this to Uncle.
Wait!
The person has a record of being
arrested, and Uncle knows him.
Don't tell me...
It's Mouri. It's been quite some time since we last talked.
I have something to ask.
The cases live settled before...
How come it's so noisy outside?
Come out...
I know you're there even if you're hiding!
To ensure your personal safety, you'd better
come out before I eliminate you.
There's nothing to think about!
Make a decision and come out!
If not, I'm going to do it!
S-Stop.
Please forgive me.
I'm really sorry.
I'll return the things that I've stolen.
D-Dad!
What? What happened?
As expected of Dad, you've arrested the thief!
A case that happened unintentionally.
Take a little rest, Conan-kun.
Even though we've never seen Kimura-san.
before could he have looked like Dad?
Because some say that there are three people
in the world who look exactly like you.
Mouri Detective Agency
Case File
Three people with that face?
A Look-alike?
Yes. Kimura-san's wife is calling.
She says that the coat was taken by accident
It's really baggy.
I heard that Kimura-san is going out nearby to take photos.
But, Mouri-san...
His wife had unintentionally mentioned...
that there was a weird guy visiting
Kimura-san's house this morning.
He had a scar on his right arm?
Then, where did Kimura-san go?
Beika Lake?
That weird guy also followed him there?
Seems likely to me.
Mouri-san, you're going too?
It's dangerous.
He makes up his mind fast.
Money?
Yeah. It fell on the floor and rolled under the car.
Okay. I'll move my car and look for it.
Really? That's good.
Thank you!
Just like I thought...
Danaka
Kimura
Manicure?
Here you go.
Uncle, thank you.
Are you the inspector? It's Mouri.
I know where Kimura-san is.
Wh-What?!
Kimura-san!
Where are you?!
Answer me, Kimura-san!
It's so cold. Come out faster.
This is Mouri.
Inspector!
Kimura-san's location has been found.
He's in the forest.
Also, Mouri-kun,
It's quite a cold day. Don't get the flu.
Faster! Faster!
Kimura-san!
Inspector, isn't Mouri-san on that boat?
It's Mouri-kun! He's completely out in the open!
İf the culprit's targeting him now,
he could be hiding anywhere!
It's too dangerous!
Inspector, I saw something shine off the
left-hand side of the opposite shore.
Wh-What? I-It's a rifle.
Perhaps it's the rifle the culprit using to aim at Mouri-kun.
Takagi-kun, please hurry.
Yes, sir!
Mouri-kun!
Save Mouri-kun!
Faster! Faster!
Yes!
Takagi-kun, be ready with the boat.
Hurry!
No matter what, we have to rescue you.
Can the two of you also come with me?
Inspector!
Conan-kun?
Where's Uncle?
Inspector Megure...
This... Well...
I'm sorry.
Then?
I still haven't found Mouri-san himself.
The Bar Lemon guy...
Yes.
Kimura-san's wife suddenly called me.
I got the address.
For now, we must inform Mouri-san as fast as possible.
I was thinking about this all day.
I didn't think that this would happen...
After sunset, it gets colder, Kimura-san.
Mouri-kun, you're safe!
Yeah, but I picked this thing up.
I see.
You put the dummy in the boat...
to lure the culprit out.
That's great. That's great. As expected of Mouri Kogoro.
By the way, Inspector...
Have you found Kimura-san
Inspector, you don't need to worry about Kimura-san.
What do you mean?
Because there is no such person.
In other words, the culprit is targeting me.
In order for the culprit to camouflage
his motive for killing me,
he created this fictional person.
Create? Motive?
Yes. If I was murdered, the police would investigate
the people around me thoroughly.
Then, they'd be able to figure out the culprit.
But if I was being mistaken for someone else, the
investigation would become more difficult.
This is because the culprit and I don't have a connection.
Then the construction site, the escape after that,
and the mail that warned of killing.
Those were all to camouflage the culprit's plan?
What about the non-existent evidence?
So, the culprit is...?
Don't rush me to the ending...
Inoue-san, about that suitcase in your car...
Can you let me look at it?
Y-Yes, you may.
Then, let me do it.
It's in the trunk.
By the way, Inoue-san.
You gave me the service coupon in Bar
Lemon just to provide services for me.
You waited patiently for a chance.
After I fell asleep from being too drunk,
you took the coat and cell phone you prepared
and switched them with mine.
No. Kimura-san really did come.
He left after he had a drink, right?
But it was only water.
Kimura-san's bottle only had water in it.
Inspector, I've found this.
Th-This is...
The rifle he used to shoot me.
Do you have any evidence that I shot you?!
That doll's left chest still has the bullet from the rifle.
If the rifle marks on the bullet in the
doll match the ones from your rifle,
that's the best evidence.
But I don't have a motive to kill Mouri-san!
Yes, you do.
You hate me.
Take a look at this file.
Conan!
Yes!
This is for you.
What is this?
You hate me because I had you arrested.
This is how you looked back then.
You changed your name and face.
Even though I don't know how you did it,
you made yourself a completely new identity.
Ukita Hiroshi-san. That is your real name.
If you want to deny it, then wash away your manicure.
Use your fingerprints as the evidence.
Originally, I had a lover.
I needed money because I was getting married to her.
That was why I robbed you.
But you arrested me, so she left.
My beautiful life... You completely ruined it!
What the hell are you talking about?!
How did you think you could be
happy by using stolen money?!
And... what a reason to hate Mouri-kun!
Don't you think that the one who commits
a crime is the the moron in the end?!
Before I knew it, I had come to the riverside of memories.
Imagining a continuation of yesterday's dream...
you seemed so grown-up when you were a boy...
I couldn't say goodbye, so I hid under my umbrella.
If we ever meet again... just please remember
all those times, and don't forget me.
My love and affection are things that will never change.
You are my one and only love, and that's how it will always be.
Like many people, I reminisce while holding on to my feelings
So i can keep the memory of us meeting from fading away...
Being such a famous detective, I won't
know when I'll' be targeted next time.
I really don't know. There's this guy named
Kitada-kun in the class next to mine...
Thief!
Help me by taking this.
That person is...
Dad?
What's with that outfit?
Let me know as soon as you see anybody suspicious-looking.
You're the most suspicious one.
The client I'm about to go to is from a family of musicians.
I heard that one of them is a composer with perfect pitch.
Perfect pitch?
A Stradivarius!
Uncle, go and park your car under that window. Quickly!
Hey! Wait! It's too dangerous!
Next Conan: The Dissonance of the Stradivarius, Prelude.
Next Conan's Hint!
Requiem.
Please look forward to the next episode!
Conan has moved on to its tenth year.
Will something happen this year too?
Everyone, please continue supporting us!