Today sscene is a musical mansion
Where the melody played on a legendary
insturment brings disaster to the violinist.
Tek gerçeğin peşinde debelenirken...
Bedenim küçük ama zekam hala ayni!
Adim mi?
Dedektif Conan!
What? The area code for Tottori Prefecture?
Why do you want that?
Didn't I tell you before?
During the case in Okinawa, I was bothered
bythe phone call that Motoyama-san ma
That call was made to
/ Kurayoshi City in Tottori Prefecture.
And during that case the other day,
Detectrve Yamamura also made a call,
To his grandmother in the
Yazu district in Tottori Prefecture.
Both places sharean area code - 0858.
So what about it?
I've had the same impression before.
That Vermouth woman was keying in her
colleague's mail address when I was in her car.
But it wasn't just a regular colleague I'm sure I heard it.
That time, those mumbled words.
OK, Boss.
Then, that phone numbercould be...
Yeah, this 0858' might be...
The mail address of the boss that commands those guys.
Butthen again, my impression
applies only to the first four numbers.
Besides, this 0858' feels subtly.different somehow.
I'm back!
Wetcome back.
Hey Ran neechan,,do you
no anything like this melody?
What's that?
Er, it's a quiz that's popular right now
It's "Fa-Me-Re-Me" isn't it?
Or is it, "Sol Fa Mi Fa?"
Eh? It's "Ti La Sol La" Even though it's a bit off.
My, so confident.
So, why don't you trysinging, "Do-Re-Mi?"
What was that? İt was all messed up!
But it's definitely "Ti La Sol La!"
No, it's, "Fa-Me-Re-Me!"
How annoying! I'II go and ask about it later, so be quietl
Who are yougoing to ask?
The client I'm about to go to
is from a family of musiciaiis.
I heard that one of them is a
composer withiperfect pitch.
Perfect pitch?
THE DİSSONANCE OF THE STRADIVARIUS
PRELUDE
Mouri Kogorou-sama?
The master of the house does not have
any arrangement to meet with such a person.
Ah, you see, I'm here at the request
of the granddaughter, Shitari Hasuki.
Tsumagari Benin
Shitara Family Butler
Oh, so I see.
Miss Hasuki is currently practising in the house annex.
There, as you can hear.
Ohl So the piece we've
been hearing is being played live?
It's wonderful!
I don't know what arrangements
you ve made, but please don't distract her.
She has a very important performance tonight.
Pardon, but what is tonight?
Tonight is the masters 72nd birthday gathering.
Shitara Hasuki
Chamirhirou's Granddaughter
Miss.
A gentleman named Mouri-san has arrived.
Oh, excellent! You really came!
Why, of course Anything for a
young lady as beautiful as yourself.
Hey, are you the one who has perfect pitch?
Eh? Ah, that's not me.
Hey, Hasuki-chan, are you sure it s
OK to be slacking offion your practice
Shitara Genzaburou
Shitara Family's Third Son
You're performing tonight, aren't you? Along with that.
Ah, yes.
If you goof up, you'll be severely scolded by my brother.
Genzaburou-sama, you did not inform us
beforehand that you would be returning.
Now, don't say that I left İmeeting with
the orchestra early just so I could rosh here.
Anyway, I'm going to take a short nap in my room.
Like usual, please wake me up
when the birthday,banquet begins.
Oh, you haven't touched anything in my room, have you?
Of course not. I definitely wouldn't
want to be yelled at like your late wife was.
Is that so?
Hey, Miss, is that gentleman
the one who has the perfect pitch?
Nope.
Although my grandunde Genzaburou is a
famous conductor, I wouldn't say he has perfect pitch.
The one who has it is.
Ti So-Ti-So Ti:So...
Hage Kyousuke
Chouishirou's Nephew
Oops, that "Ti" was flat.
I'm sorry, an ambulance just drove past.
Oh yes, about yesterday's piece, would it be
possible to change the BPM from 120 to 130?
Might be more rhythmic.
Oh, yeah.
Could he be the one?
Yep, he's the one with the perfect pitch.
Hes a genius composer whos written the
soundtracks for lots of TV dramas and such.
Haga Kyousuke, my ünde!
Did you want me?
Ah, uhm, could you teli me what these notes are?
Eee, Unde? How was my performance7
It was good There was a
place that was 1/4 of a tone flat.
But I liked it that way
Thank you so much!
Eee...
Yes, hello?
Ah, that piece?
I'd like have the tempo a little finer
So, will that be OK? Yeah
That's what I want.
Furuto!
Where are you, Furuto?
Ah, Grandmother!
I heard theso d of a violin.
Furuto, stop hiding and come out.
Skitara Ayanu
Chouichirou's Wife
Are you saying that again, Grandmother?
My father passed away on this
day last year Have you forgotten?
This day last year?
N-No! Furuto is still...
Stop this unsightly display, Ayane!
Grandfather!
Shitara Chouchirou
Head of the Shitara Family
Stop living in he shadow of
someone that's already gone!
Our son Puruto has already passed away!
Do you still not understand?
Grandfather! Didn t the doctor
tell you not to come out?
Mouri-san!
Sorry, but I need to help these two get settled first.
We can tallk in the main building afterwards
There's also something
there that I want to show you.
Wowl Whatari old violin!
Yes, it was made almost 300 years ago.
This really is an antique then!
İt was made by the italian, Antonio Stradivari.
S-Stradi-vari? Oh no!
Just as I thought.
A Stradivarius!
Th This is one of the legendary, famous
instruments worth hu-hundreds of millions of yen?
Put it down, Dad! Hurry up!
M-My body has stiffened up, I can't let go!
So is something the matter
with this legendary instrument?
Yes.
This violin was given by my ünde Haga
Kyousuke's father, Shitara Danjirou-sama...
...to his'older brother, my
grandfather Chouichirou, as a birthday present.
Eh? If your uncle is your grandfather's
brother's son, then why is his surname Haga?
You see, on the day of my grandfather's
birthday, some burglars unfortunately broke in.
Burglars?
Grandfather Chouichirou and the others
didn't resist and were tied up, but they survived.
Danjirou-sama tried to resist and was severely
beaten. He died a few days later of his wounds.
Unde Kyousuke was taken in by his mothers
family, and so he took on their surname, Haga.
I see.
However, it's lucky that they didn't take this.
Because tt's likety the
burglars were after this Stradivarius.
I heard that theytook the wrong one.
Our Shitara family has a long history in
miisic, and so we own a large number of violins.
But, this all happened more than 30 years ago.
Eh? Don't tell me you want me to try
and catch the criminals from 30 years ago.
No, I want you to investigate the two
hairrfaising cases that occurred in the past two years.
The first case happened the year before last.
Grandunde Genzaburojs wife, who was
skilled at sports, slipped on the stairs and died.
The other case occurred last year.
My father, Furuto, fell from a rotted veranda.
My father was a very careful man! I can't
understand how such a thing could possibly happen!
Detective Moiiri, please
investigate these frightening cases!
Ah uhm...
Those aren't cases, are they? They were just accidents.
No! Both ofthem died'on my grandfather s birthday!
And also, both ofthem
played this Stradivarius at the time!
İt almost seems like It's been
cursed by the events of 30 years ago.
And this year, it's my turn.
Somethîng terrible will happen to me to.
Then, why don t you just not play?
I want to play!
But if you're free to bring itout like this,
why can't you play it whenever you want to?
I'm not usually allowed.
I asked my grandfather if I could borrow
it so that I could practise for tonight's
performance, you see.
Hey, I bet she's monitoring what we do.
But, I stupidly played itjust a bit ago.
That will be our secret of course.
Well then, what do you want me to do?
I want you to solve the curse affecting
this Stadivarius before my performance!
What? A curse I don't think that's
something a detective like me can solve.
Ha? I thought detectives couid solve everything!
Why is it so bright outside?
Are you having fireworks for the birthday celebration?
No, I don't think so.
It's on fire!
Grandimde Genzaburou is in there!
Fire Quick, look out the window!
Where's your grandunde's room?
Rightl The first room on the second floorl
Hey Unde! Can you hear me?
Hey! Damn it, it's locked!
Theres only one way then.
Granduncle!
Stay out! He s already beyond help.
Ayane! Where's Ayane?
Grandfather!
Ayane is stili in her room upstairs.
What? Grandmother?
Which room upstairs?
The one at the end on the third floor.
It's no use! Not without fire proof clothing!
Ah, olamaz!
H-Hey!
I guess this is just my nature.
I'II leave the others to you!
H-Hey!
Uncle!
Uncle, go and park your
car under that window Quickly!
I'm counting on you!
Hey! Wait' It'stoo dangerous!
Is he all right?
Hang on, Grandfather!
Hey, Father, what are you doing?
Damned if I know!
The kid toldrme to park here.
Why do I have to do what that kid tells me?
What the...
Hey, Auntie, hang on!
Grandma!
I see, they used the car to reduce the
distance they fell and the roof as a cushion.
The brat thought of that?
Isn't it lucky? That you just happened to bring a wagon?
It's a rental car, the repair bill
will cost me an arm and a leg.
Soori after, the fire engines arrived.
But the Shitara famîly annex
contlnued to burn for a while.
Almost like ît was performinga final movemen
in memory of the conductor Shitara Genzaburou.
No! I don't want to!
But you need to go to the
hospital for emergency treatment.
No! No! No!
I'm sorry, you'll have to excuse my wife this time
One year ago, our son was carried
away in an ambulance and never returned.
İt seems she doesnt want to rlde in the same kind of car.
Would it possible for you to treat
her at the mansion just for today?
OK.
Littie boy, thank you.
And you too, Kyousuke, thank you for saving us.
Youre welcome.
Young master Kyousuke, what about your injurtes?
I'm OK, and please dont cali me young master anymore.
That was at least 30 years ago.
Eh?
Tsumagari, thebutler, originally
worked for Uncke Kyousiike's family.
But because of the burglary case 30 years
ago and the death of both Danjirou and his wife.
Their heir, my uncle Kyousuke, inherited the Haga home
She's been with the Shitara famity since then.
Wasn*t it only Kyousuke-sama's father that died?
Yes.
His mother, Chinami-sama, was
already in a state of poor health.
She nursed Danjirou-sama while'he was unconscious.
And in the end, Chinami-sama
passed away because of the strain.
Oh yeah, what about your mother, Hasuki-san?
My parents separated and she returned to her family
house two years ago, just before Grandfather's birthday.
Because of that, my grandaunt Emi
decided that she would perform for the celebration.
İt was to commemorate my grandfather's
70th birtftday but also to cheer up my father.
She used the Stradivarius that had been
kept sealed away for more than 30 years.
The famous instrument had been sealed away?
That's right.
My grandfather was very happy when
my granduncle Danjirou gave it to him.
When he was 18 my father borrowed it for a contest.
But the strings broke repeatedly during
his performance and he didn't make the cut.
And another time, when my
grandaunt was to perform on a TV program...
...just before going on air, she
unexpectly broke out with a high fever.
My grandunde Genzaburou injured himself due to
repetitive strain while practicing for a concert overseas.
I see. No wonder it was sealed away.
Hey, what about the violin? Is it OK?
Didn't you leave it on the table in that room?
Oh no! Someone could have deliberately set
that fire so they could slip in during the confusion.
That's not the case I retumed
it to the storage room right away.
Also, do I look like an incompetent butler who would
neglect an antique when strangers are wandering about?
Ah, of course not.
Besides, it wasn't cause by arson, but by smoking in bed.
İt looks like the fire
originated near an ashtray in that room.
The door you all broke down was locked, right?
That would mean the room
was seaied, so arson is impossible.
I guess that's right.
Well, please be extremely careful with cigarettes.
İt would be best if you don t smoke at all.
Ah, yes. Of course.
But even if it was a coincidence, it's a
terrible one. The same day for three years in a row.
Yes.
And if you count Kyousuke-san's father who died
from the burglary case that happened 30 years ago...
...the total is four people.
At this rate, I think it'd be best for Chouichirou-san
to give up celebrating his birthday starting next year.
Heh, this guy's smoking already.
Well, that's going to happen anyway.
My uncle has lung disease
and only has half a year left to live.
It's that so?
Yeah, that why we wanted
have a celebration today at least.
That will no longer be possible The master
has already retired to his bedroom for the evening.
The mistress has been
treated for her injuries and is resting.
Well then, this doesn't look like much
of a case after all. We should begöing.
Hey, whose cigarette was this?
İt doesn't look like Uncle Kogorou s.
That brand looks like one of my
granduncle Genzaburous cigarettes.
Now that you mention it he did
come by here before heading to the annex.
If that's true...
Then this is..
Conan-kun!
Hey, kid! Where are you're going?
Hey!
Just as I thought.
This was no accident, this was murder!
Moreover, if my reasoning is correct...
The next target is...
This might turn out to be a series of murders!
Wh-What did you say?
Wait a moment if it goes D-E-F-G'...
Then the next target will have the initial "H" - Hasuki-san!
Oh no! It s dangerous for her to be alone!
THE DISSONANCE OF THE STRADIVARIUS
INTERLUDE
Gelecek Conan İpucu:
Initial.
Conan-kun, the culprit is the mother!
Why so?
Definitely the mother (zettai okkan).
Perfect pitch (zettai okkan)