A legendary instrument creates an incident.
The misfortunes happening to a
musician family are spreading at a rapid rate!
Perceiving the one and only truth,
With the body of a child and the brains of an adult,
His name is: Detective Conan!
By Shitara Hasuki-san's invitation, we
came to Shitara Chouichirou-san's mansion.
Hasuki-san's request was for us to investigate the
mysteries surrounding the legendary Stradivarius violin.
And the series of mysterious
events that began the year before last.
However, not long after our
arrival, the annex burst into flame.
And Genzaburou-san, who was inside, was killed.
Hey, whose cigarette was this?
It doesn't look uncle uncle Kogoro's.
That brand looks like one of my
granduncle Genzaburou's cigarettes.
Now that you mention it, he did
come by here before heading to the annex
If that's true...
Then this is...
Hey, kid! Where are you're going?
Hey!
Just as I thought.
This was no accident; this was murder!
Moreover, if my reasoning is correct...
The next target is...
The Dissonance of the Stradivarius
Interlude
What? You think somebody
deliberately started that fire?
Yeah, the cause of the fire was smoking in
bed, and it started somewhere around this ashtray.
However, if you look at these cigarettes
And then at this, the cigarette that
Genzaburou-san smoked in the main building.
Hmm, it's the same brand and
there's nothing unusual about it.
Eh? Bite marks!
Look!
Uncle Kogoro also has this habit.
When he's smoking while he's working or
needs to speak, he bites down on the filter.
However, these cigarettes don't have any bite marks.
Don't you find that strange?
I see.
In order to make the fire look as if it
were accidentally caused by smoking in bed,
Somebody smoked some cigarettes and started the fire.
That's what you're trying to say, isn't it?
But the door to this room can
only be locked from the inside!
How would the culprit have gotten out?
You've figured out something
for that trick too, haven't you?
Eh, not yet
Still a little brat, aren't you?
He could just have happened to bite
that one cigarette in the main building.
What's more, Genzaburou-san
hated having people tidy his room.
And yet, isn't it strange that we can't find any
other cigarettes in here that have bite marks on them?
Tsumagari Benio
Shitara Family Butler
That is not strange at all.
Whenever Genzaburou-san left his room
he would always bring his trash out with him.
And, by the way, why did you all
suddenly rush out of the room just now?
Er, actually this kid here...
But even if he took out his trash, I still find it strange
that he'd smoke several cigarettes before going to sleep.
Idiot! People do that all the time!
He must have dozed off while
he was smoking that last cigarette!
Even if that was true, is that good enough?
This might turn out to be a series of murders!
Wh-What did you say?
Stop talking rubbish!
It's the names.
Danjirou-san, who was killed by the
burglars 30 years ago, had the initial "D".
Emi-san, who fell down the stairs and
died two years ago, had the initial "E"
Furuto-san, who fell from the
veranda and died one year ago, had "F".
And then, Genzaburou-san, who died tonight had "G"
"D, E, F, G". They're in alphabetical order, aren't they?
Hmm, what connects all these people is that they
were in this house for Shitara Chouichirou's birthday.
What the brat said makes sense; there's something here.
Wait a moment if it goes 'D-E-F-G"...
Then the next target will have the initial "H"-Hasuki-san!
Oh no! It's dangerous for her to be alone!
What? I'm the next target?
How could that be?
You see, if we follow the order of the initials...
Haga Kyousuke
Chouichirou's Nephew
Now that you mention it, if we start.
alphabetically from my father Danjirou,
It would be "D, E, F, G."
Shitara Hasuki
Chouichirou's Granddaughter
Oh, come on! That's just a coincidence!
O-Of course.
Nevertheless; that's a problem for tonight's requiem.
Requiem?
It's a tradition in the Shitara family for somebody to play
a requiem whenever someone in the family passes away.
Up to last year, it was Genzaburou-sama.
And neither the master nor the
stress could do it in their present condition.
I can't do it either!
Well then, why don't I perform?
Would you all like to join us?
It's not everyday that you can hear a
live performance by Haga Kyousuke.
Yeah.
But, most of the instruments were in the annex.
The only ones left are the piano and that...
Hey, hey, anything but that Stradivarius.
My hands would start shaking.
Then, how about my violin?
It's okay. I'll go down to my
car and get the one I always use.
Although it doesn't compare with a
legendary instrument made 300 years ago,
It was the one gift bequeathed to me
by my father. For me, it's just as good.
Plus I don't want to have something
happen to me for using that antique.
Aunt Ayane would be upset if we
brought it out without permission.
Upset?
The mistress has come to think
that the Stradivarius is her son Furuto.
Master Furuto performed for the
master on that instrument, just before he died
Ever since that day, when the clock strikes midnight...
Shitara Ayane
Chouichirou's Wife
Shitara Chouichirou
Head of the Shitara family
Does Mr. Chouichirou know about this?
Yes, probably.
The room where the Stradivarius is kept is
between my grandfather's and my grandmother's rooms.
\ I think Father's image from that time is probably
still deeply imprinted in my grandmother's heart
Well now, please enjoy.
Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart's Requiem.
K. 626 in D minor.
How lovely.
Yeah, Uncle Kyousuke graduated from the
German Music Academy at the top of his class.
Say, why did Kyousuke-san open the window?
Probably so that my grandfather
and grandmother could hear too.
Grandmother's bedroom is directly upstairs
Are your grandmother's and grandfather's rooms
connected by the room where the Stradivarius is kept?
If my grandmother's room is locked from the
inside then you can!t get in from the storage room.
But you can get in from the
corridor using Tsumagari-san's master key.
They're husband and wife yet
they sleep in separate rooms.
That's because my grandfather's a heavy
smoker and my grandmother hates the smoke
I guess he's not going to quit until he gets lung cancer.
Well then, if your grandfather passes
away, who will get the expensive violin?
It would have been my granduncle
Genzaburou, but now I guess it'll be my grandmother.
I'm not sure what my grandfather will do.
To tell you the truth, I'm hoping it'll be passed
down to my Uncle Kyousuke, the genius musician.
Conan-kun, be quiet and listen.
What was that sound
Just now, could that have been...
G-Grandmother!
Quick! Call an ambulance!
Ah, yes!
The grandmother's name was Ayane. Her initial was "A".
What's going on?
Nobody can try to take it. What's mine is mine.
Which one is the storage room?
The last one on the right.
Hey!
It's locked from the inside.
And there's a chair beside the window.
Was it really suicide?
My, my. You're a harbinger
of death as always, Mouri-kun.
Oh come on, Inspector, it's just a coincidence!
Besides, it's inevitable for us great detectives
cases always seems to occur when we're around.
Which is why I wish you'd just stay put at home
The incident occurred around
midnight; she fell from that third story window.
It seems that was her bedroom
Where were you at that time?
Ah, I was with everyone in the the room
beneath, listening to Kyousuke-san perform a requiem
Requiem?
Yes, it appears to be a tradition in the Shitara family.
Hmm, so Mr. Genzaburou who died in
the fire was the youngest of three brothers.
The oldest is Mr. Chouichirou.
And the son of the second brother who died 30 years
ago, Mr. Danjirou, is this Kyousuke-san you mentioned
So, what do you think was the
motive for suicide then, oh great detective?
Um, ah, I'm still working on it.
The motive was probably the violin.
Ah, she is the Shitara family butler.
In any case, come with me to the mistress room.
Th-This is the Stradivarius!
Could it be burglars broke in again
d during the struggle with Ayane-san...
But this room was locked.
And there doesn't appear to be any sign of a struggle.
And no signs of any people entering or leaving.
Somebody must have broken it before the
mistress even opened the case. What a shock.
Bu-But, it's just a broken instrument...
Don't you realize? This is a legendary
violin worth hundreds of millions of yen!
And in Ayane-san's heart it was almost
like a replacement for her late son Furuto-san.
She must have decided to jump
when she found it had been destroyed.
That's not right.
I think that lady broke it herself.
This brat again...
She' broke it herself? Why do you think that?
Look, see the new scratches on this table?
They must have been from
when the old lady smashed the violin.
You idiot, she wasn't clueless like the inspector.
Why on earth would Ayane-san
break such a valuable instrument?
Yeah, that's what I would think too.
If this was real, that is.
Wh-What?
See, look at the label inside the violin.
The mark says GA
If it was really made by Antonio
Stradivari, wouldn't it be marked with A.S.?
Eh? How do you know so much about this?
Uh, it's because
Shinichi-niichan taught me about it before.
That detective boy?
Come to think of it Shinichi did know a lot about violins.
Probably because Holmes played one.
Well then, what does this GA stand for?
Probably the artisan who made this replica,
Used his own initials as a joke when replicating the mark.
here have been hundreds of Stradivari
replicas that have become famous over the years.
Look, at the bottom of the
label. It says "Made in Germany."
It's 100% sure this is a replica.
Who's he?
The Kyousuke-san I was talking about earlier.
Come to think of it, who was in the room
downstairs listening to him play the requiem?
Me, Ran, the little brat there,
Hasuki-san and the butler, Tsumagari-san
A total of 5 people.
And during the performance, Ayane-san...
But why would Grandmother do that?
Uncle Kyousuke had only just rescued her earlier.
Why would she kill herself?
Rescued her?
Yes, during the fire, the old lady didn't escape.
It was Kyousuke-san and Conan-kun that saved her.
But I still don't understand,
why would she destroy the replica?
Could it be that she thought it was real,
and just now realized that it was a replica.
That's not possible.
The master had the violin inspected
and it was certified that it was authentic.
But this is not the real case.
Are you looking for this?
Grandfather.
She hid it behind the bed
That Ayane treating it like this.
It does have the mark of Antonio Stradivari.
This must be the real thing.
I think so myself
Is it okay if I play a bit to check?
N-No, I don't think that's necessary.
If you think that it's authentic then it must be.
In that case, what's with that one?
Perhaps to surprise everyone, she bought
another Stradivarius, only to find that it was a replica.
I see. So she killed herself before her husband
could discover that she'd wasted so much money.
Ah, that makes sense!
That's not right!
When I came into this room just now, I
checked the bed and there wasn't anything there!
Somebody must have temporarily replaced the
Stradivarius with a replica and then secretly restored it.
Someone who came into the room
after I did must have, for some reason...
Conan-kun!
If that's so, we can find out by checking for fingerprints.
But now it's gotten mine all over it
Plenty of mine too, probably.
Yesterday during the day I was tuning the Stradivarius
in preparation for Uncle Chouichirou's birthday concert
In this room?
Yes, afterwards I called Hasuki-chan and handed it to her.
Yeah, I practiced on it for a bit
here, so my fingerprints are there too.
At that time, was there anyone else?
It was just me, my uncle Kyousuke had gone out,
And Grandmother was in the
garden so that she wouldn't disturb me.
After that, Mouri-san arrived and while I was
showing them the Stradivarius the annex caught on fire
And I took the Stradivarius that had
been left on the table to the storage room.
This means that every one of you
had a chance to switch the violin.
But Inspector, what does it
matter considering the circumstances?
We've got the real thing back, don't we?
Maybe the brat is just making things up.
But there's something really weird about this case!
Oh, come on! This was a sealed room,
and the door to storage room was also locked.
And there's a chair right next to the open window.
No matter how you look at it, it's definitely a suicide!
Does this room have a spare key?
Apart from the mistress' own key,
there is only the master key that I carry
Inspector, the key has already been found on the body.
I see.
You see, this isn't a series of murders at all!
Series of murders?
Well, this kid put the initials of the people who
died starting 30 years ago in order to get "D, E, F, G."
But, if Genzaburou-san who died in the fire is "G",
then Ayane-san who jumped out the window is "A".
In other words, there's no connection whatsoever!
Hey! Could it be a musical scale?
D, E, F, G, A. In Italian it's Do, Re, Mi...
But in English isn't it represented as C, D, E, F, G, A, B?
Isn't there some C-Major scale or something?
CDEFGAB
You're right That means the next letter is "B"
But who's name starts with a "B"?
Tsumagari Benio.
I suppose the next B must mean me then.
Come to think of it, I remember 30 years ago
when I started working here, the master mentioned it
He said if I were one of the family, that
would make a complete scale going from C to B.
You're right, if we start with Chouichirou-san
as C, we have the complete scale - C,D,E,F,G,A,B.
Did I ever say such a thing?
Well, for the time being, could I ask
everyone to please wait in their rooms.
Inspector, we've found the person's footprints.
ft seems she jumped on her own volition.
Hmm, she didn't even hesitate...
Inspector, of course it's a suicide,
this room was locked from the inside.
Locked from the inside?
Come to think of it, the room where Genzaburou-san
burned to death was also locked from the inside
Before the fire started everyone was in the annex.
Ali four of these people could
have had the chance to start the fire.
And this room was also locked from the inside.
But, there must have been some way...
Hey! What's that?
There, that transparent square
thing at the top of the window glass.
Say, is that cellophane tape?
There's one on the right side too.
Say, Uncle Kogoro wanted me to ask if
anything strange fell down along with the body.
Oh, yeah.
Ah, and one more thing.
This piece looks like the sharp end of a chopstick.
Ah yes, we found some kind of burned case.
Yeah, it's the perfect shape to hold two thin sticks.
You mean it was empty inside?
I see, if someone used that, then it's
possible that Ayane-san was murdered
All that remains is the mystery of the sealed rooms.
That's it! So this is how it was done!
But there's still one thing I don't understand.
Why would they insist on doing such a thing?
That person...
You know who the culprit is?
Two years ago; the real series
of murders began in this mansion.
But why do you need this
Stradivarius to solve the mystery?
There's just one thing I don't understand.
Playing two adjoining notes causes
a really painful sound! ...Could it be?
H-Hey!
Uncle!
Conan-kun.
POSTLUDE
Perfect Pitch
Next Conan's Hint:
What's next time?
Look forward to the next episode
Evenyone absolutely can't miss it.
minna to zettal akan yo
Is that a pun?
Yeah, well.