The case is being played on the sound of a violin string.
The family members are becoming nervous
The resounding chords lead to a conclusion!
Perceiving the one and only truth,
Bedeni küçük ama hala ayni zeka!
Adim mi? Dedektif Conan!
By Shitara Hasuki-san's invitation, we
came to Shitara Chouichirou-san's mansion.
Hasuki-san's request was for us to investigate,the
mysteries surrounding the legendary Stradivarius violin.
And the series of mysterious events
that started happening the year before last.
However, not long after our
arrival, the annex burst into flame.
And Genzaburou-san, who was inside was killed
Furthermore, that very night, while
Kyousuke-san performed a requiem,
Ayane-san fell from the third story to her death.
The violin left behind and
various suspicious objects.
What on earth do they mean?
THE DISSONANCE OF THE STRADIVARIUS
POSTLUDE
That was definitely the bridge of a violin.
But, both the replica and the real Stradivarius.
Still had their bridges.
That means that there must have been another violin
Ah, and one more thing.
This piece looks like the sharp end of a chopstick.
That must be from a conductor's orchestral baton.
Ah yes, we found some kind of burned case
Yeah, it's the perfect shape to hold two thin sticks.
You mean it was empty inside?
So this is how it was done!
But there's still one thing I don t understand
Why would the culprit insist on doing such a thing?
Come to think of it, a long time ago my mother said
Eh? Why do I play with my^fingers split apart?
Well now, you heard of chords' before, right?
For example...
This is a C chord.
This is D
And now..
See, that note didn't sound so good, did it?
Inspector, it was suicide! Suicide!
Because the entry door and the
storage room door were both firmly locked.
Since the room was sealed, Ayane-san must
have used the chair as a footstool and jumped out!
İt couldn't be anything but suicide!
But don't you find it troubling?
That the people should die in the order of
their initials D,E,F,G,A on the musical scale?
If you remember, Ayane-san's A came after
Genzaburou-san's G, so that was just a coincidence!
His room was also locked from the inside,
And the fire was probably caused by him smoking in bed
But still.
Anyway, I think İ d better call it a night.
Dad!
W-What is it? W-What s the matter?
You know! Whenever you start yawning and make a
funny face, then comes your sleeping deduction show!
Make a funny face?
That's right, and while you re
at it you make funny noises too!
Like "Ha-nya'...
Isn't it Ho hee?
No! Last time it was like He-nyo'
Na hyaaaaaa.
Yes, yes! That's the face. That's then noise!
It's Sleeping Kogorou!
I must say this time your pose is rather exaggerated
Why, of course.
Because I have solved the mystery that you,
have been puzzling over as well, Inspector.
The truth behind the series of murders
that have occured
during the last two years in this mansion.
What? But just now you were saying that it was suicide.
I had a sudden epiphany
Now then, please help me
prepare some things I'II tell you about
And when were ready, then
bring all four suspects to this room.
Of course, you mustn't forget the
legendary Stradivarius violin either
OK, so,.the things you need are?
Not you, Detective Takagi I'd
like you to standby in another room.
Eh? Why?
You'll find out later.
Don't leave that room until I call you.
Oh? You've found out who the culprit is
Then this really has been a series of murders?
Granduncle Genzaburou and Grandmother Ayane were...
Correct They've all been victims of the same culprit.
And that most likely includes Emi-san
who fell down the stairs two years ago,
And Furuto-san who fell from the veranda last year.
Shitar Hasuki
Chouichirou's Granddaughter
How could that be?
But why do you need this
Stradivarius to solve the mystery?
Shitara Chouchirou
Head of the Shitara Family
Probably because he already knows
Who managed to switch it with a
replica, and then went so far as to retun it.
Nope, I just thought I'd perform a piece
for you before I begin my deduction show
A prelude to my solution.
W-Wait a minute, Dad.
So, Hasuki-san, would it be all
right if I played like I did for you before?
Âh, no, it d better if you didn't.
Exactly! What do you think
you're going to do with my Stradivarius?
What would you have us do if an
amateur handles it and damages it?
Now, now, let's just do as he asks this one time.
I'm sure this man must have something in mind.
Or, unlike me, do you have some reason for
not«wanting to hand it over, Uncle Chouichirou?
T-There's nothing like that.
Now then, shall we enjoy the performance?
Just as I thought it was you wasn't it, Kyousuke-san?
Who switched the violins.
Hey now, I was just saying I wanted to hear you play
If I recall correctly, the series of people
who have handled this violin goes like this
This aftenoon, after it was tuned by Kyousuke-san,
He handed it over to Hasuki-sart
While she was showing it to me, the annex caught fire
We ran out, leaving it on the table
And Tsumagari-san returned it to the storage room.
If Tsumagari-san or Chouichirou-san, who could
easily have gone to the storage room, had replaced it
Then it means that it would have been
switched after I played it in Hasuki-san's room.
If my fingerprints are on it.
then the one who switched them .
Must have been one of those two.
İn that were the case, they should have
wanted me to touch the Stradivarius again here,
So as to obscure when my fingerprints got on it
It's the same for Kyousuke-san or Hasuki-san
in the case where they performed the switch
They should want me to touch it now
If my fingerprints cant be found on the real one,
That would mean that it had already been
switched with the replica before I played it
The two of them would then come under suspicion.
However, Hasuki-san, Mr
Chouichirou and Tsumagari-san all...
Just now refused to let me touch the
Stradivarius; only you encouraged me
Kyousuke-san, that is the evidence that you
are the culprit behind this series of murders!
What? My uncle did İt? How could that be?
B But might the replica not have been
substituted before Kyousuke-sama did the tuning?
That's-not possible.
With ears like Kyousuke-san's,
He would have realized it was a fake right away
(But why does that make him a serial murderer?
Ayane-san's room was locked from the inside, and when
the fire broke out, Mr. Genzaburou's room was also locked.
Hey, kid! >Show them that thing.
Yep Here it is.
This was the lock fixture on the
door to Genzaburou-san's room.
If you examine it carefully, Inspector, you'll
notice that only the top part has been warped
Wouldn't you think that when you force open a locked
door, both the top and bottom parts would be warped?
That's true.
When I found this, Mr. Firefighter told me something
Regarding the bolt on that door, the top
was the knob and the bottom was the lock.
Judging from the way it was opened, when
the door was knocked in, it hadn't been locked
But later when we went in
after the fire, the door was locked
Because Kyousuke-san locked it
At that time, he pretended the door
was locked, and so we broke it down.
Some one! Give me a hand!
He had the chance when our
attention was distracted by the fire
II see
But how does this have (
anything to do with switching the violin?
İt was done to make Ayane-san jump from this room
What do you mean? Wasn't he in
the room downstairs at that time?
That was also part of the plan.
He d d it to lure Ayane-san to the window.
Try to imagine...
The Stradivarius violin that she gazed at every
night as if it were her son turned out to be a replica.
Filled with anger, she smashed it
Then as Ayane-san was feeling this.
She was attracted by Kyousuke-san's
lovely melody, so she looked out the window
Hey, kid!
Show everyone that thing now
OK!
M-Mouri kun what is this?
What's going on?
This is what Ayane-san saw at that time
Could it be that Ayane-san
thought that was the real Stradivarius?
Indeed, from the room downstairs, if the
requiem that Kyousuke-san was playing
Sounded like it was coming from the
Stradivarius, it would be even more likely
And hence, she stood on a
seat and climbed onto the window
İn order to get the violin.
But could she have fallen so easily?
Why don t we do a little experiment
Hey, kid! Bring Detective Takagi in.
OK!
And Tsumagari-san.
Ah, yes?
Return the real Stradivarius to the storage room
Uhm, did you call for me?
You see, Detective Takagi, when
Uncle was explaining the culprit's trick.
We found the Stradivarius hanging outside the window
You're tall, Detective Takagi,
so you should be able to reach it
Ah, yeah, well...
There's something going on, isn't there?
No, no, no.
But do try to be careful. Is
worth several hundred million yen.
Well, if it drops it's not my fault, OK?
Takagi!
Be careful, Takagi-kun!
I-It moved!
The violin. As I reached for it...
I see, there are sticks attached
on both sides of the window frame.
The violin is suspended from a string.
So as window was opened
further, the violin would move further out
But Dad, if it had been hanging like that
Why didn't we find the violin or the sticks at the scene?
This is just simple demonstration 1
made using chopsticks I got from the kitchen
If the two sticks used for the crime were .
Conductor's baton's stolen
from Genzaburou-san's room.
Because they bend easily, when the violin
reached the tip, it's weight would cause it to fail
The violin was held by another string that was
attached to the window frame of the room below.
That's was so he could easily retrieve it in secret, after,
seeing Ayane-san fail, we had all rushed out of the room.
But, what about the batons?
They were also retrieved at that time
Because the batons were only secured by cellophane tape,
They could be easily retrieved by pulling
on a string attached to them beforehand.
The strange sound we heard
before Ayane-san fell from the window
Must have been the sound of the violin hitting the wall
The proof of this is the snapped-off bridge
and broken piece of a baton found near the body.
The setup for this must have been done
while he was in this room tuning the Stradivarius
The real one must also have been
switched with the replica at this time
As tor the batons and violin he retrieved,
They're probably hidden
somewhere in the room downstairs
And theyShould stil! have
Kyousuke-san's fingerprints on them.
Hasuki-san started crying on your shoulder at that time,
So you didn't have a chance to remove the
fingerprints, or to hide the things somewhere else
Lies! it's all complete nonsense!
Uncle Kyousuke can't be the culprit!
Didn't he just rescue my grandmother from the fire earlier?
Why would he do that? Why?
He did that because of a rule of the musical scale
that you as a musician should he aware of yourself.
Eh? Why do I play with my fingers split apart?
Because listen, if you play two notes next to each other
Dissonance.
Playing two adjoining notes causes a really painful sound
Could it be?
Exactly.
If uncle Genzaburou's G and Aunt
Ayane's A both died at the same time,
It would be really uncomfortable
You bastard, how could you treat people's lives like that?
Hah, you should be saying those
words to my Uncle Chouichirou over there
What?
The one who, 30 years ago, seriously injured my father.
And who even drove my mother to
death from her nursing Him, my uncle.
Thirty years ago? That was the burglary incident
I had forgotten all about it until two years ago.
I was asked to tune the
Stradivarius for my uncle's birthday party
That sound, that sensation...
İt was İt was the very violin that my
father had given to me when I was a child.
I went to ask Aunt Emi about it and
in a blood draining voice she told me
On his birthday 30 years ago, my uncle had
begged my father to lend him the Stradivarius
so his son Furuto could play it
Listening to its tone, he fell in
love with it and couldn't return it.
So he switched it with a replica which he sent to my father
İt was discovered immediately and a dispute broke out
During the dispute, my father slipped on
the stairs and fell, sustaining severe injuries
This old man, seeing my father's injuries, didn't
call an ambulance Instead he told the other four.
Genzaburou! Tie *me and
Ayane up and then you hurry home.
We'll act as if we had been attacked by burglars.
Don't you want a chance to
play on this legendary violin too?
If Danjirou dies, it will be mine! You'll
be able to borrow it whenever you like!
After she had told me everything,
Aunt Emi rushed out of the room
And so that's when you decided get
revenge on the four people who colluded in the lie.
Yeah, looking at Aunt Emi tying dead after
falling down the stairs, just like my father..
I knew it was a sign from the gods
From my mother Chinami, my
father Danjirou, and my Aunt Emi.
They died in the order of the scale: C,D,E.
Starting there, the dead would line up
starting from the initial Cr and with C they would end.
However, last year, after I
pushed Furuto-san off the balcony,
I found out the final initial, C, my
uncle Chouichirou,'was sick and soon to die.
So I became a little impatient.
As I thought, I was next, the one who came to;work
at this house, unaware of what happened 30 years ago.
No.
İn German, what comes after C,D,E,F,G..
Is the letter H
Pronounced 'Ha'
Like the Ha in "Haga".
Amca!
Uncle Kogorou asked me to have that prepared.
He said that Kyousuke-san might try to kill himself.
But if the next initial was H,
then that's the same as Hasuki-san's.
The next one could have been her.
Seeing as Kyousuke-san has already
returned the Stradivarius to this room,
I didn't think that would be so.
If, back then, Ayane-san hadn't smashed the replica...
It's likely no one would have
known there was a fake Stradivarius
The reason he brought back the real violin was
For the person who's father
had been killed, the same as him.
To leave the gift his father left to him,
İn order to pass on that legendary violin
Hasuki-san, he wanted to leave it to you.
Hey, when I asked you about the melody on
the cellphone, you said, "Did you want me?"
Heh. Did you want me?
Say, could you tell me what these notes are?
H-A-G-A.
İn German, it's read "Ha, A, Ge, A"
That's "Haga" right?
Yeah, that's right
little boy, you have good ears too
Then, that means that those
notes were definitely Si La So La
Hold on, Conan-kiin.
Hey, do you know any songs that start with "Si La So La"?
Maybe one that s a bit sad, or a bit nostalgic?
Or a song that gives someone that kind of feeling?
Well, that would probably have to be.
Right?
That was "The Seven Children" wasn't it?
Oh, crow. Why do you sing?
That's right isn't it Conan-kun?
Conan-kun?
Ohayou gozaimasu!
Is there something on my face?
We saw a suspicious person on the way to school.
S-Satou-san?
METROPOL POLİS
DEDEKTİFİ AŞK HİKAYESİ 6
(BÖLÜM 1)
Gelecek Bölümde Görüşürüz.
Next time is part six of the love story?
I thiink it will go to at least 100.
How pitiful.