Today's case takes place in
the Kagomma area of Kagoshima.
Uncle gets a sampling of the finest Shochu.
But the brewery smells of complicated human relations!
Seeing through to the one and only truth...
I look like a child, but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
Kagoshima Nichiuri TV
Beer is definitely the best form of alcohol!
Refrigerate it, put it in a mug, and chug it all down.
There^s nothing that can beat that.
İt's deliciousness comes from its bitterness and.
No...
Um, our topic is on alcohol, but beer is the wrong kind...
Huh?
Wasn't I supposed to speak passionately about alcohol?
Tokuzumi Yuka
Kagoshima Nichiuri TV Announcer
Yes, we're talking about the alcohol that's
booming in popularity these days.
O-Ohl
1 see... Well, wine is just splendid!
Even I know the benefits of the polyphenol...
Err, not wine...
This is a special program celebrating
the station's anniversary.
Kondo Yousuke
Kagashima Nichuri TV Director
Yoshidemo Shougo
Kagashima Nichuri TV Productor
Why did we invite such a stupid guy?!
I heard he's famous and likes to drink sake.
You'd think that this guy would get a clue
from hearing the word "sake" in Kagoshima.
The announcer lady is crying, isn't she?
Come on, Dad...
Whats with These murderous star es?
I came to Kagoshima and .
Wait, Kagoshima?
Kagoshima a ft sake...
Shoot!
Well, I mean...
Beer is good! Wine is also great!
But my absolute favorite is Shochu!
What?
The truth is, I wanted to give a comparison so
people can understand the greatness of Shochu.
So that's why you talked about
other alcoholic beverages first?
Oh! So t/iat's why!
But I, Mouri Kogoro, cannot hide it anymore.
I especially have to say that the Shochu
that's brewed right here in Kagoshima...
Is the absolute best!
Banzai for Kagoshima!
Ali right! Mouri-san saved the show
We were right to invite him, weren't we?
He fooled them somehow.
I'll give him credit for that
When you say 'Takakuma"...
Are you talking about that rare
type of Shochu, by any chance?
Yes.
The product is made in limited
quantities, so it's very hard to find.
D-Do I get to sample it?
When I asked Kuramato, he said it'd
be a pleasure to serve some to you.
Catch the ferry here in Kagoshima,
and it'll take you right to Tanimizu.
I get to drink it...
The rare Takakuma Shochu that most can only dream about!
You don't have to cry.
As we boarded, little did we know
of the gruesome case that awaited us.
Kogoro Gets Drunk in Satsuma.
(Bölüm 1)
Takakuma Brewery... I guess this is where it's made.
I thought it would be bigger.
Yes, but it's nice.
There's a clear view of the ocean, too.
Mouri-san, this is the owner.
Hello, sorry to bother you.
Shiraishi Satoshi(30)
Takakuma Brewery Owner
Welcome. I'm Shiraishi.
I've heard your name mentioned quite frequently.
Shiraishi Fumiko (27)
Satoshi'nin Karisi
I'm his wife, Fumiko.
My daughter, Ran.
And this freeloader...
Hey, Dad!
This is Conan-kun.
Hello.
Little boy, I don't think cellars full
of bottles will interest you very much.
That's not true, right?
Yes, they're very lovely.
That's Mt. Takakuma.
Oh...
I see. So that's where the name came from.
Well, let's go to the office.
Here you are.
Thank you, thank you.
Thank you for the drink.
What do you think of the Takakuma?
Amazing. Ali I can say.
It's just sake.
No, this is the best I've ever tasted
Simply exquisite
Well...
We all take allot of pride in brewing this sake.
The sake-brewing process
begins by washing and steaming rice.
Then we add koji mold.
Note: Koji is a special type of, mold which releases
enzymes that help break rica down into carbon dioxide and alchol.
When the koji is ready, we
transfer it into an earthenware pot...
Add water and yeast to ferment it.
Then we add steamed sweet potatoes to ferment it further.
During that time, we continue mixing
to maintain a constant temperature...
And to stop various bacteria from multiplying.
Next, we distill it and let it rest...
Dilute it with water...
And there you have it.
Some facilities us e machines to
brew it, but our sake is handmade.
İt may seem like bragging when
we call it a "limited" product, but...
We can't make too much.
We're already making as much Shochu as we can.
I understand.
Local, handmade... This is the real thing right here.
Excuse me...
Yes?
Last week, I requested permission to do a report here
My name is Maezono, from the Weekly Etta.
Report?
I haven't heard about it.
Ee... May I see the managing director, Tatsumura-sari?
Maezono Hitomi (25)
Magazine Journalist.
Why did everyone react to the name Tatsumura?
I was supposed to film the brewing process.
The brevving process?
Tatsumura-san agreed to that?
What the hell was he thinking?
He selfishly made a stupid promise.
Unfortunately, we cannot show
the brewing process to anyone.
You can't? But...
It's very important that we keep
the area free of any outside bacteria.
That's why we cannot let non-employees in.
That's true. There are many germs on the human body.
That's common sense, girl!
I apologize.
I love Shochu, so I accepted the task of doing the report.
I didn't know asking would make you so upset...
We're not mad at you.
We re just pissed off at that Tatsumura!
Hey, what a re you yelling for Kosugi?
Tatsumura-san!
Tatsumura Shinsuke (45)
Takakuma Brewery Managing Director
My, my... Looks like I'm not welcome here
Are you Maezono-san?
Evet.
Sorry, sorry. I'm late for your interview.
My physical checkup took longer than I
expected, thanks to a certain someone...
Doesn't the small size of this place surprise you?
Y-Yeah.
However, we re thinking of<remodeling this place...
Making everything machine-run so
we can mass produce our product...
Eh? You're planning to do that to Takakuma?
Mass production?
Tatsumura-san, you promised us that you'd never do that!
If we mass produce Shochu, its quality will suffer greatly!
As you can see, the president is very stubborn.
If we don't cash in on the recent
Shochu boom, what are we going to do?
Um, l!m also against mass producing the product.
II talk with my manager and
have him reconsider doing this report.
Özür dilerim.
W-Wait!
II let you take a bottle Home! We need the advertising!
Why don't you show more love and respect for your sake?
You don't even care about tainting the Takakuma name.
I cannot forgive you for that.
Well then, let's get back to work
Even if bacteria didn't go near the sake,
there's already enough scum here to ruin it.
Scum? Are you talking about me?
Geez, what's wrong with everyone...
I'm also against stopping the handmade process.
Who are you?
Oh, and thank you very much for the drink.
Wait, isn't that...
I've seen him before...
Oh, yeah! The famous detective, Mouri Kogoro!
He's perfect!
P-Please wait!
The personality for your brand's image?
Yes, you're perfect!
A famous person promoting us...
If you accept, you can drink as
much of our sake as you want!
Eh? Unlimited Takakuma?!
Dad, a re you serious?!
Uh, but, well...
Sake is too tempting for him.
I know! How about I show you around town tomorrow?
I II be off, and we can get some great food!
And it'll all be on me, so please consider it!
Huh, huh?
Mouri-san! I can do that.
Madam?
Take it as my thanks for enjoying our sake.
Please let me have the honor of being your tour guide.
Him, I guess a woman would make it more fun.
I'll let the mistress be the tour
guide and I'll just relax tomorrow.
Mouri-san, III be expecting an answer from you.
Dad! Why didn't you say no?
Ah! It's Saigo Takamori!
Note: Saigo Takamori was one of che most influential samurai in Japanese history, famously known as "The Last True Samurai."
Cool!
Stop changing the subject!
But, I've got a bad feeling about Tatsumura-san.
Everyone else seemed to dislike him, too.
He's not just disliked...
He's utterly despised.
But why do Shiraishi-san and his wife keep him on the staff?
Eh?
They're giving a report on the wind direction
coming from Sakurajima, even though this is Kagoshima.
Oh, you're right.
But I wonder why?
Because of the ashes.
Good morning
The wind often blows ash
here all the way from Sakurajima...
Don't you think it'd be a pain if ashes blew
onto your laundry while it was hanging outside?
Oh! So that's why people are so
worried about the direction of the wind.
Will there be ashes coming today, too?
Nobody knows.
Because it's completely random.
Wow! How did they write that?
Hey, Auntie?
Why don't you and your husband just fire Tatsumura-san?
What was that?!
Why you little. .!.
Conan-kun!
I, um...
I-I'm sorry!
Of course a chi 1 would be curious. But I can't fire him.
Because of an old promise.
Old promise?
Our sake plant has a history that goes back for generations.
But it wasn't very big or well-known back
then, so we couldn't sell as much as we had hoped.
We would have shut down a long time ago.
Luckily for us, Tatsumura-san, a salesman at
the time, worked very hard to help sell our sake.
However, we still couldn't produce as
much as the other big sake companies.
And we were about to be shut down.
This was ten years ago, five years before İ got hired there.
At that time, the former managers father spoke with
the workers who were still in training and made a decision
He said, "If this is the last batch of sake we'll make,
why not get the finest ingredients and make it perfect?"
That way, the best, most ideal sake would be
their final memory of the Takakuma Brewery.
And that became Takakuma.
Yes, and then we got to see our dream come true.
Everyone lined up to get a taste of the real thing.
But last year, the former manager became deathly ill.
Don't forget about the decision we made ten years ago.
Yes, sir!
Tatsumura-san started to change after that.
What Mass production?!
People a re only buying Takakuma for the brand name now.
Even if it loses its taste a little,
who would notice?
Business, business.
What the hell?
Are you going to let him get away with that, President?
Instead of letting him ruin the sake,
we should kick him out!
Dear...
I can't...
If it weren't for him, we wouldn't be here.
We're in his debt...
And I can never forget that!
He's a very stubborn person.
Or maybe "loyal" is a better word?
Never forgetting a favor...
As expected of a man from Satsuma.
He's wonderful.
Mouri-san, please decline the offer from Tatsumura-san.
If someone as famous as you helped him advertise...
İt would be like making him invincible.
İt would only help him carry out
his plan of mass producing our sake.
I see.
That must be why you wanted to
give us a tour today—to convince me.
I'm sorry.
No, it's fine! I was going to reject his offer anyway.
Right? Right?
Tatsumura-san's house is in Kagoshima?
Oh, good. İt looks like he's home.
Six o'clock, huh?
Does Tatsumura-san have a family?
No, he lives alone.
It's open.
I'll go look inside.
Tatsumura-san?
It's Shiraishi.
Hey, do you taste something weird in your mouth?
No w that you mention it...
It's the volcano.
İt has to be all the ashes.
What?
Ah... Yuck!
There's no car.
Madam!
What's wrong?
His is...
It's blood!
Could it be that it's Tatsumura-san's?
I can deduce what happened
While Tatsumura-san was resting...
Judging from the circumstances, it's definitely a kidnapping.
You guys said the lights were on when you came.
That means he must have been
kidnapped sometime in the evening.
We can be more specific.
When I tested it, I noticed that the blood wasn't dry yet.
Which means he was killed shortly before 6:00 PM.
I see.
Otakeyama, get the car ready immediately!
Yes, sir!
Excuse me, ma'am.
Are you the nurse who used
to work at the Chuo Hospital?
Yes. That was five years ago, before I got married.
Is that right?
I thought you looked familiar!
Hurry up and go!
Yes, sir!
I apologize for involving you in such trouble.
She's still worried about him, huh?
1 guess it's because even though Takamura-san
is ill-natured, he's the savior of the brewery.
If the motive was money, the
culprit will contact us with their demands.
That's when we'll catch him.
However, there was no
contact from the culprit the next day.
Why won't he contact us?
Another day passed.
There was an anonymous phone call to the police station.
We traced the call to Terayama Park in Kagoshima...
Tatsumura-san.
İt looks people wouldn't typically come here.
The phone call%as most likely from the culprit.
However, their voice was masked,
so we couldn't determine their gender.
Kidnapped and then murdered, huh?
How cruel
It's been two days since he died?
Yes.
According to the autopsy
report, he died about two days ago.
While it's hard to determine the
time of death accurately after two days...
We believe he was killed sometime
during the evening he went missing.
İt appears to have been an instantaneous
death, caused by a single blow to the head.
Huh?
What was that?
Regarding the statue lying in the living room...
We've verified that the shape of
the wound matches it perfectly.
Furthermore, Tatsumura-san's blood was on it.
So we can safely assume that it was the weapon.
Wait a minute!
His death was instantaneous?
So, the culprit didn't knock Tatsumura-san
unconsious and then kidnap him?
You're saying that they killed Tatsumura-san on the spot,
drove his body to the park, and just left him there...
Then called us two days later to tell us where to find him?
That's right.
What were they trying to do?
They took the time to move the body elsewhere...
But then told us exact!y where to find it.
Just what is going on here?!
Also, according to our investigation team...
Tatsumura-san's doors and windows
showed no signs of forced entry.
Moreover, the key is special and cannot be duplicated.
So how did the culprit enter the house?
There's only one way.
İn other words, Tatsumura-san knew the culprit.
In this case, no money was
stolen, so the motive wasn't robbery.
The only other possible motive is revenge.
The culprit was an acquaintance of
Tatsumura-san who hated him enough to kill him.
Which means...
What? The culprit is one of us?
There's no doubt about it.
The only ones who knew Tatsumura-san
a re those involved with this brewery.
Then why am I a suspect?
The others heard you voice your hostile
feelings towards him when you came to do a report.
T-That's, um...
It's true that we all hated Tatsumura.
But...
He was murdered two nights ago, right?
At that time, we were in the back room making a new batch.
Didn't I tell you already?!
Everyone was busy with work.
İt's possible that all of you
matched your stories beforehand.
As for you, Maezono-san...
You were staying at a hotel by yourself.
Which means you do not have an alibi, either.
I don't want to suspect all of you...
But Shinpuku-san is right. Any of you could have done it.
Dad...
True. No one here has a sol d alibi.
And everyone despised Tatsumura-san.
I feel sorry for the wife.
Everyone close to her is under suspicion.
That may be true, but...
They're here!
The culprit is most likely still here in this room!
Sake is filled with living organisms.
Once you start making it, you can't
take your eyes off of it for a second.
That's why none of us could have left during that time.
I guess that's true.
I looked into what you asked me,
and there wasn't even a trace on him.
Eh?
Um, well... The culprit is...
Uncle!
If you know who did it, go stand
V in front of everyone and tell them.
Right.
Kogoro Gets Drunk in Satsuma
(Part 2)
Next Gonan's Hint!
Physical Checkup
Gelecek Bölümde Göürüşürüz!
Next time, well have a really wild conclusion!
Just one more...
Dad!