Today's deduction will take place in Sakurajima!
While the battle over sake might have a sad ending...
Uncle will solve this case even if he's drunk!
Seeing through to the one and only truth...
I look tike a child, but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
We traveled to Kagoshîma with Uncle Kogoro...
There we visited the Takakuma Brewery,
home of the famous, but rare, Shochu.
While the company presidents wife,
Shiraishi Fumiko-san, took us on an enjoyable tour...
An incident occurred.
Someone attacked and kidnapped the
managing director, Tatsumura Shinsukesan.
And then...
His body was discovered.
What? The murderer is one of us?
There's no doubt about it.
The only ones who knew Tatsumura-san
well are those involved with this brewery.
I feel sorry for the wife.
Everyone close to her is under suspicion.
That may be true, but...
They're here!
The culprit is most likely still here in this room.
(Part 2)
Kogoro Gets Drunk in Satsuma
How did things go?
Did you get any useful Information?
No luck.
They all have a motive and a shaky alibi, if any.
There aren't even any leads to follow.
That's not true. There are two.
Why did the culprit bother carrying Tatsumura-sans
body out of his home and taking him somewhere else?
And why did they call two days
later to tell us where the body was?
If we figure out these two mysteries
Dad!
That's what he gets for pointing out such obvious things.
If it s so obvıous then hurry up and figure it out.
Mouri-san, will you be questioning us again tomorrow?
Shirashi Satoshi (30)
Takakuma Brewery Owner
Yes, tomorrow morning.
You're welcome to spend the night at our place.
Maezono-san will be staying as well.
Oh, that would be a bıg help! Thank you!
Well, then...
I don't think he's the«murderer.
Would a murderer invite a detective to stay at his house?
The most suspicious ones are usually
the most unnaturally innocent-looking.
Jeez, you're so untrusting.
No, I shouldn't be laughing
The two mysteries...
There must be something that can piece them together
There has îo be...
Good morning!
Ah, good morning.
it looks like everyone's already busy workıng.
Oh, they are.
The brewing process sure start s early, doesn't it?
Our staff wakes up at 4:30 AM and starts working at 5:00.
İt sounds like really hard work.
Sake is fılled with living organisms.
Once you start making it, you can't
take your eyes off of it for a second.
Shiraishi Fumiko (27)
Satoshi Wife
That's why none of us could have left during that time.
I guess that's true?
Ah! I came to call you for breakfast.
Özür dileriz.
Come in whenever you re ready.
They loved their sake so much that
they wouldn't have left the brewery.
If that's true..
Dad?
What's with the creepy laugh?
Realty?
The murderer is...
Maezono Hitomi.
Why do you think it's her?
She's the only female suspect.
The first mystery/
Why did she move he body out of the house?
Tatsumura-san was a tall, fit man.
No one would expect a woman to
have enough strength to carry him.
She's a woman, therefore she couldn't be the culprit!
Is what she wanted everyone to think.
What about the second mystery?
Why did she tell us where the body was?
That's obvious.
She wanted memorial services to be held for him,
concerned that his soul would be unable to rest in peace.
That feminine way of thinking...
Means the culprit has to be Maezono Hitomi.
hope Officer Shinpuku hurries up...
I want him to hear my perfect deduction.
But, Uncle...
What?
It's impossible for a woman to
have committed the crime, right
How was Maezono-san able to do it?
If it's impossible, then I guess it's impossible.
Well.
Maezono Hitomi ıs secretly a
heavyweight-class body builder
She probably lifts weights or something like that.
Yeah!
Hey, hey..
Hey, go take a quick peek inside her room.
Eh?
She probably has a very muscular body.
İt's okay if you peep because you're still a kid.
There's no way I'm doing that!
Hey! Help me out for once!
Why are you asking a child to spy on a naked woman?!
No, this is purely for investigative purposes.
Give me a break
Orita Seiichi (60)
Takakuma Brewery Employee
Just so you know, I'm not skıpping work or anything.
It's just that I'm old now,
and my back and neck are always aching.
I remember back in my day...
Ah! Is that you?
That was taken 20 years ago.
That's Tatsumura-san, and the one in the center
ıs the former president who passed away last year.
Eh? Who are these kids?
The current president.
Not his little sıster. That's Fumi-chan.
She s the president s wife.
Oh, they're childhood friends?
And that's her father, standing beside me.
used to work here with us.
The predecessor only had one son.
So he treated Fumi-chan like she
was his own cute little daughter.
Fumi-chan's father was also an excellent sake brewer.
But tragedy struck when he fell ili and
passed away while she was ın middle school.
However, the predecessor
didn't ignore his remaining family.
He gave her encouragement and supported her financially...
Even paying for her high school tuition.
He also helped her get into nursing school.
She really owes a lot to the former president, doesn't she?
Oh, by the way...
Excuse me, ma'am.
re you the nurse who used to work at the Chuo Hospital?
Yes. That was five years ago, before I got married.
She was a nurse, right?
Yes, that's why she scheduled an appoıntment
for the managing director to visit the hospital.
A physical checkup.
Oh, yeah... I remember him saying something about that.
Sorry, sorry. I'm late for your interview.
My physical checkup took longer than
I expected thanks to a certain someone
If she had known he would have died the next day,
Fumi-chan probably wouldn't have recommended it.
Eh? The mistress recommended that
Tatsumura-san get the physical checkup?
He used to have a physical checkup done annually,
but he's been busy as the managing director as of late.
However, the mistress was really
pushing him to get one this year.
And he was murderered the next day.
Physıcal checkup?
C-Could that....?
Is somethıng wrong?
No, it's nothıng.
Well, I guess I better get back to work.
I have to get things done before
the police start questıoning me agaın.
See you later, young man.
Things a re almost wrapped up.
No...
if they used that trick, then the
two mysteries are already resolved.
But there's no evidence..
Sakurajima?
Waıt a mınute back then...
That s it!
Oh, Mourisan.
I was just about to head there...
Huh?
Before you leave, I have a favor to ask of you.
Yes, I want you to examine Tatsumura-san's body.
No, I want to know if there was something on his clothes...
Come on
Show me them muscles, baby!
What are you looking at?!
I saw Shinpuku-san!
Okay!
Jeez...
I looked into,what you asked me,
and there wasn't even a trace on him.
What a re you talking about?
At last, the final piece falls into place.
But you just called and asked me to...
Oh my, Dad... You asked for something and forgot about it?
Oh! That thing, that thing!
I see. There wasn't any on him, huh?
You're pretty good at fooling people.
So, who is it?
Who?
Didn't you say that you knew on the phone?
And you said you'd reveal who
the culprit was when we got here.
So, who ıs the culprit?
I might have saıd that..
Well, the culprit is... a woman.
Maezono Hitomi!
Dad!
And that is based on the fact that...
Uncle!
If you know who dıd it go and
\in front of everyone and tell them.
Rıght.
We know that Tatsumura-san's death was a murder.
But who is the murderer?
The murderer is...
Wow! Look at Sakurajima!
Is something happening on the mountain?
No, i don't see anything strange...
Oh, Shinpuku-san!
Oh!
T-This is the famous Sleeping Kogoro!
www.Elzsubs.blogspot.com
Discort: ELz-FaN
What is it, Conan-kun
Huh?
Conan-kun?
He probably thought the volcanoes on Sakurajima erupted.
Orita-san, this is the famous Sleeping Kogoro.
Excuse me, may I take a picture?
Please, I need quiet.
The culprit used an alibi trick to murder Tatsumura-san.
Alibi trick?
I had a good idea about how the trick was done,
but I needed to get some concrete evidence.
So, I asked for something.
Ashes from Sakurajima?
Yes, Id like to know if you find
any on Tsumura-san's clothes.
İn the end, we couldn't find a
single trace of ash on his clothes.
But when I happened to see Kagoshima's weather report...
İt said that ashes would be falling continuously from
noon to around midnight on the day Tatsumura-san died.
Hey, do you taste something weird in your mouth?
Now that you mention it...
It's the volcano.
It has to be all ashes
Yes, ashes were definitely falling like rain that day.
Isn't it strange, then...?
We arrived at the house at six o'clock.
If Tatsumura-san had been murdered
and carried out side during that time...
Then some of the airborne ash would have
gotten on the clothes he had been wearing.
However, there was no trace of ashes on him.
Which means Tatsumura-san was not
attacked in the evening as we previously thought.
İt happened in the morning, before the ash started falling.
I see.
But then...
Yes, one thing doesn't match up.
İt's blood!
Now, I wonder how that blood got there, Madam?
l made a slight error in my judgment earlier.
Why did you offer to take us on a
sightseeing tour of the area that day?
Was it really just to get me to deny Tatsumura-san's
request to advertise their brand...
Mouri-san, please decline the offer from Tatsumura-san.
I thought that was the reason.
Wasn't it?
We were just there to set up her alibi.
İt was a setup to throw the investigation off...
By making us believe that one of your
co workers had killed Tatsumura san just before we arrived.
Isn't that rıght, Madam?
T-That can't be...
M Mouri-san.
I told you the culprit was a woman.
So the woman was t
İt was Shıraısh Fumıkosan.
That morning, after offering to give us a tour...
Madam?
Oh, Madam.
And then you told him you wanted to speak
to him in private so he'd get back in the car.
That's when you drugged him to sleep. I expect that...
Drawing blood from him was a simple task for you...
...as you had been in the nursing field for years.
Afterwards, you came to the hotel to pick us up.
You spent the entire day with us...
Then took us to Tatsumura-san's
house in order to make us your witnesses.
It's open.
I'II go look İnside.
Tasumura-san?
It's Shirashi.
And then you went to the living room to carry out your plan.
Mouri-san!
Madam!
What's wrong?
The first of the two mysteries was...
Why did the culprit carry the body out of the house?
The answer to that is actually quite simple.
The body was never ın the house from the start.
But why were the lights on?
Before she picked us up, she used Tatsumura-san's
house key, which she stole after she put him to sleep...
To enter his house, turn on the lights,
and then leave with the front door remaining unlocked.
So that's how it happened...
Wait a minute!
Regarding the second mystery .
I told you to wait!
There s something that doesn't sense.
I just don't get it.
You're accusing Fumiko of the murder,
but wasn't she with you the whole day?
She couldn't have done it!
When did she have have the opportunity to do all that?!
That s right, Dad. When did she?
İt was after that, wasn't it, Madam?
I apologize for involving you in such trouble.
İt was after she dropped us off at the hotel.
You had a sculpture prepared which was
exactly like the one that Tatsumura-san owned.
İn short, this murder case occurred only
after the police had started investigating.
That was our blind spot.
I don't blame you.
No one would think to check alibis for
where someone was during the investigation
You made us thınk Tatsumura san was
murdered just before we arrived at his house.
Because of that, you were able
to create a seemingly airtight alibı.
After all, you were with us the entire day.
As or the second mystery...
Why did the culprit tell us
where the body was two days later?
While it's hard to determine the
time of death accurately after two days...
We believe he was killed sometime
during the evening he went missing.
If the body was discovered immediately,
investigators would be able to pinpoint the time of death.
If too much time passed, the estimated
time of death wouldn't be specific enough.
Either one of those scenarios would render her alibi useless.
Mouri-san, when and why did you start to suspect me?
On the day before he died, didn't you
recommend that Tatsumura-san get a physical checkup?
Ah, şey...
What does that have to do with it?
Having an injection from a syringe
makes a small prick mark<appear on your arm.
The same mark would be there after having blood drawn.
She knew no one would question the prick mark's presence
if he had had a physical checkup done the day before.
Basıcally, you carefully injected the syringe in
the same spot he already had his blood drawn from.
I see.
But why?
Why did you kill Tatsumura-san?
I was scared.
I thought that if Tatsumura-san continued to work here...
People would start to care more about
making money than about the quality of the sake.
I didn't want people to start thinking that way.
No Madam! None of us are like that)
For now, but time can change a person.
Just like Tatsumura-san...
Just like he changed.
İt s my fault.
If only I had fired Tatsumura-san before this happened...
You a re unwilling to fire
people to whom you a re indebted to.
I like that side of you.
But, what drove you to do suchia thing?!
I wanted to be remembered.
I wanted to be remembered as
the one who protected this brewery.
Of course, murder is an unforgivable crime.
But she felt she had to protect the brewery
in order to repay the predecessor's kindness.
My father...?
You could never forget a favor.
Since your wife is also from Satsuma...
I believe that she shares the same sentiments that you do.
Fumiko...
Of course we feel the same way.
He's my beloved husband.
Don't bother with me.
You need hurry and get back to work!
Madam...
Fumiko.
There a re people all over Japan waiting for you r sake.
And I II be waiting for you...
Because just like our sake
my feelings for you a re the real thing.
And so, yet another case was solved.
Bunu fark ettiğimde, nostaljik
biri olmak zorunda kaldım.
Rüyanın devamı öngören dünlerimiz vardı.
O gün çok büyümüş gibiydi...
Veda bile edemeden, şemsiyemin altına sakladım.
Eğer yolları tekrar geçersek... Lütfen...
O zaman, unutma beni.
Değişmeyecek aşk gibi değil sevgi gibi değil...
Her zaman olacağını düşünüyorum,
sadece seni seviyorum ve bu...
Amaçsız duygularımı tutarak, insanların
sık sık yaptığı gibi geriye bakıyorum.
Sahneyi durdur, yavaşça
kaybolmadan buluşmak bizim tek şansımız.
Off, Takakuma isn't here after all...
Takakuma, Takakuma...
Ah, screw this! I don t care what I get!
You're still going to buy more?
So you re goıng with quantıty over quality, huh?
Black vinegar is really good for you!
Like father, like daughter