A love story between two police detectives!
When the detective boys are pulled in...
A surprising case rapidly develops!
Perceiving the one and only truth,
The body of a child and the brains of an adult,
His name is: Detective Conan!
Ah, excuse me...
S-Sato-san...
What did you want to talk about?
Oh, geez...
Takagi-kun, go ahead and get in.
Ah, yes, ma'am.
What? What could it be?
Did I do something wrong again?
Sato san's birthday was in April and I went out with her for karaoke like I was supposed to.
C Could it be?
She going to break up with me?
W Wait, w wait. This is no joke...
You fell for it! You fell for it!
What do you think?
Isn't it great, Takagi-kun?
This toy?
I'll try it out on Yumi next
But, S-Sato san, are you saying you asked me here just to try it out on me?
Of course.
Wasn't it fun?
You were just heading home after work anyway.
Now look here...
Or maybe...
You saying I shouldn't invite you somewhere except on business?
Police Sergeant Takagi.
Ah, no.
Looks like they're in love, eh?
No, not just yet.
The goal line might be getting near.
Stop it please, Sato-san...
Oh, so it's an official request sent by the Tottori prefectural police?
Yeah.
You know about it, don't you, Megure?
About the gang of thieves centered in that-area that has been breaking into locations throughout the country.
Bye, talk to you soon.
Oh, dear...
A joint investigation headquarters has been established in tottori...
And they'd like someone from our Division one there too.
But, Superintendent, theft is Division Three's job.
Have you forgotten, Megure? They're guilty of attempted murder here in Tokyo too.
Ah, that's right.
Of course Division Three will be going, but we should send someone from Division One also.
Whom should we assign?
Let's see now.
They should be single, skillful, perceptive, and healthy enough to endure the countryside.
And they should be familiar with the lay of the land around that area.
Hmm, oh yeah.
Say, Megure, isn't that guy's hometown somewhere near tottori?
W Who?
Huh? Which guy are you talking about?
You know, Takagi-kun. Takagi-kun.
Eh? T Takagi?
Uh oh!
He's a good choice, isn't he?
Yes, you're right
Yes, you're right.
Despite his appearance, he's a pretty sharp guy and I've heard he's solved a lot of difficult cases.
Well then, Superintendent, I'll go ahead and contact him tomorrow morning.
Yes, let him know.
It sure can be lonely to have to go somewhere far away.
Hide's really going to a foreign country?
We don't know if that's true yet
Well, England is where soccer originated, you know.
If you're a fan, wouldn't you like to see him play at the original location?
Well, that's true, but...
Well, if you ask me, I think going overseas is a good thing if his goal is the World Cup.
I guess so.
The World Cup, eh?
The World Cup... Ah!
It looks like the rain has stopped.
You're right.
H-Has it?
That guy's sure breathing heavily, like he's in pain.
That's only natural, since he's been jogging.
Come on, we'd better hurry if we don't want to be late to school.
You're right.
Let's go.
Eh?
That's what they said. And so...
Did you hear me, Miwako? Miwako!
Yeah.
Oh geez, I barely made it.
Ohayou gozaimasu!
Uh? Uhm...
Is there something on my face?
Y-Yumi-san?
Takagi-kun...
Yes?
Good bye!
W-Wait! What do you mean?
I'm being sent to the Tottori joint investigation headquarters?
T-They must have meant someone else.
Idiot! You're the only numskull named Takagi we have.
Don't play dumb.
According to what Yumi-chan said, Inspector Megure should already have contacted you.
N-Now that you mention it, the Inspector did phone me this morning.
But I was half asleep and didn't really understand what he was saying.
So, see, it must have been that call.
Well, in any case. I'm sure I'll be back once the case has been solved.
It looks like you don't know.
The headquarters has to investigate everything that gang of thieves has done throughout-the country.
Most likely they will have to handle a huge number of cases.
What's more, with so many criminals, even if you solve a case, how long do you think it will take?
Nah, it'll be OK.
With the talents he will bring...
It will probably be all settled within three years.
Three years?
Th-Three years?!
Three years? 1095 days! 26780 hours!
Heaven hasn't abandoned me!
Isn't it great? The air is great in Tottori and you can eat all the Matsuba crab you want!
Note: Tottori prefecture, located in western Honshu, is famous for Matsuba crab (pacific snow crab in the US. queen crab in Europe)
And you can ride a camel in the Tottori sand dunes!
Note: Tottori is also home to the Tottori Sand Dunes, the only large dune system in Japan.
I-I'm not riding one of those!
Takagi-kun.
Ah, er, Sato-san?
Get me some 20th Century pears!
Note: 20th century pears (nijiseki nashi) are considered the best tasting pears in Japan, initially cultivated at the beginning of the 20th century.
They're my favorite food.
W-W-What?
Yes! Fruit!
They're my favorite too.
The Matsuda crabs are my favorite.
Take it easy during your absence.
Hey! What's all the commotion about?!
There's a case.
The location is the 23rd floor of a high rise apartment building in Beika city's fourth district
One man has been stabbed to death.
According to this report, the body was discovered by a woman
Sato and Takagi, the both of you go to crime scene immediately.
Yes, sir!
And, as for the crime scene coordination, Megure, that's you.
Ah, no, Superintendent
How about Chou san this time?
Please let Chou-san do it
Chou-san.
Aye.
Please get going right away!
Chief!
Uhm, this is the first time we've worked together, isn't it?
I'm looking toward to it
Takagi kun!
Ah,yes?
Chou-san is my senior by two years.
Be sure to learn from the things he says.
Yes, of course.
Ah, and also...
This might be the last time he can team up with you.
Is this for real?
I think Hide's press conference started at noon, didn't it?
Ah, oh no!
If we don't hurry, We'll miss seeing it!
It's all right
After all, that conference will be today's top news item.
It'll probably be broadcast multiple times throughout the night
Huh? Looks like something's happened.
Yeah.
The stabbing victim is Nakamoto Hirotoshi-san, 27 years old, an office worker.
The murder weapon was an all-purpose kitchen knife with an 18cm blade.
The presumed time of death was in the period between 7:00 and 7:30 AM today
And you're a coworker at his company who came here at 1PM and discovered him, is that right?
Y-Yes.
I took today off work in order to go with him to make the reservations for our marriage ceremony.
How could something like this have happened?
And so...
Are there any people who disliked him?
Ah, yes. H-He was the type that made enemies.
It seems like he was acquainted with the culprit
Yeah, there's no sign the lock was forced.
Well then, could you pick out the people who you think hated him from an album for us?
We might find a lead.
Can you see anything?
Ah, it's Detective Takagi and Detective Sato!
So then, please take care of that for me.
OK.
Ah!
Did something happen?
It's a murder case, isn't it?
Ah-Ah, well...
Say, could it be...
It happened just after 7:00 this morning?
S-Sato-san.
H How did you know that?
We saw a suspicious person on the way to school.
It was on a street near this apartment building.
Oh, come on, Conan-kun.
That person was just someone out jogging.
Remember, it had stopped raining just before that man passed by, didn't it?
Yeah, it had been raining for about 10 minutes.
Yet, despite that, that man's clothes were just barely wet.
Why do you think that was?
Couldn't he have just taken shelter somewhere?
It must have started raining in the middle of his run.
And when the rain stopped, he started his run again.
Don't be silly, if he took a ten minute break, he wouldn't have been breathing so hard.
In other words, he wasn't breathing so hard because he's been jogging.
He may have been excited from killing someone in an indoor location somewhere nearby.
That's what you wanted to say, right, kid?
Y Yeah.
Say, was that man one of these?
Let me see.
Ah, this person!
He sort of looked like this person.
This person?
That's one of our co workers, Katou san.
I think he said he was staying at a friend's place though.
Do you know where it is?
Ah, yes.
Huh? Sometime after 7:00 this morning?
I've been here the whole time.
In this apartment.
Liar! It was you, wasn't it? The one who killed Hirotoshi'
What? I'm a murderer?
What are you saying all of a sudden?
What's all the noise about?
If it's a door-to door salesman, just tell him to go away.
Ah, no, it's...
In that case, what's it about?
Huh?
Ch-Chiba-kun?
Ah, this makes it interesting, doesn't it?
What? The suspect in a murder case?
You mean Katou here?
Yes, it seems so.
The murder victim was a coworker at his company, Nakamoto Hirotoshi-san.
The murder weapon was a kitchen knife.
It had been dropped next to the victim.
And so, when was the presumed time of death?
Sometime between 7:00 AM and 7:30 this morning.
Well, it was impossible for him to be the culprit then.
Because we were watching TV the whole time from when this guy woke me up at 7:00 until 8:00.
Right?
Yeah.
Are you sure?
Yes.
We were watching the 7:00 live broadcast of the news-variety program "Morning Live 7" on Nichiuri TV.
But, Chiba-kun, he woke you up, right?
In that case, couldn't he have recorded the program?
He could have shown it to you afterwards.
Th-That's not the case.
I have some good proof
More importantly, how did you come to suspect me?
It's because you're my former boyfriend!
There are eyewitnesses who saw you near his apartment just after 7:00.
They must have been half asleep that early in the morning and saw wrong.
We weren't half asleep!
I saw it clearly, this person's face!
You were wearing a gray parka!
You were running and carrying a black backpack!
As if you wanted it to appear that you were jogging.
In any case, let's have Detective Chiba show it to us.
The proof that this man was watching TV from 7:00 to 8:00 this morning.
H-Hey, what's this?
This place is a complete mess!
Now I can see why you always oversleep and get in late.
I've been trying real hard.
Haven't I been late a lot less recently?
Now that you mention it, you have, why is that?
Ah, well, I've been trying to improve myself.
What's with this mountain of toys?
Could it be you're a tokusatsu geek?
Note: Tokusatsu, literally special-fx, typically live-action movies and TV such as Godzilla. Ultraman, and countless sentai programs (like Power Rangers)
Is there something wrong with it? It's my hobby.
Gomera! It's Gomera!
There's a Kamen Yaiba too!
That's a rare tin-plated one! handle them so roughly!
You guys! Didn't I tell you to wait in the patrol car with Katou-san and Shimura san?
So where is it? whatever you were talking about.
The thing that proves you two were watching TV together.
Ah, yes. It's this video tape.
Hi! It's Okina Yoko's "Four Minute Cooking"!
It's Friday, February the 25th.
I tape this variety program, "Morning Live 7" everytime.
Last night I was drinking while watching a rental video with Katou.
We fell asleep in here and I'd forgotten to set the automatic recorder, so I recorded it myself today.
So he couldn't have made a recording of the program beforehand.
And we only use this one video deck.
But there's another deck here.
I only use that occasionally for dubbing.
If he'd used this deck, I could see the cord in front of the TV.
Now matter how groggy I was, I think I would still have noticed it
If you think I'm lying, please go ahead and inquire at the TV station for confirmation.
Today is Friday, February the 25th.
Nichiuri TV's "Morning Live 7" is the program just after the weather report
Wow, you've got a lot of others marked too.
Even cable TV programs.
There are a lot of programs I might want to watch.
I see, so that's why there are so many memos stuck up around the TV screen.
And then? After you watched until 8:00 like you said, what did you do?
We started watching a video after 8:00.
Which video was it?
Ah, well, you see...
Ch-Chiba!
Hey!
Don't tell me it was...
And adult video?
Eh? N-No!
This is the one.
This one.
It's Kamen Yaiba!
Awesome!
This has got to be episode one from the first series!
The original series looks a bit funny now, but this is still cool!
And so?
Until what time were you watching this children's program?
Each tape is 120 minutes.
Y-You watched this for two hours?
No, using level three extended recording, not including the time for commercials...
You watched for six hours?!
Say, Detective Chiba, did you record this video?
No, Katou recorded them a while ago and gave them to me.
And were you with him the entire time?
No, about halfway through watching, I took a shower.
That took about 30 minutes.
Then we started watching once again, and when we stopped watching the video after 12 episodes...
We started watching pro baseball directly thereafter.
Look, it was the Falcons vs. Jaguars starting at 2:00.
And we were in the middle of watching it when you and the others arrived.
I see.
It would take an hour and a half to get from here to the victim's apartment building.
If they were together watching an hour of TV and afterwards almost six hours of video then he has an alibi.
Just to be sure, will you let us search for the gray parka and black backpack the man was wearing?
What? Is that true?!
What?
Did you find something?
Ah, no...
Nothing important
Geez, if it's nothing, don't shout so loud.
Sorry-
So? How long will you be sent to Tottori for?
Our seniors from Division One said it would be three years.
And so? what did Sato-san say?
She asked me to bring her some 20th Century pears.
That's it?
That was it
That's weird. Normally you'd expect her to be a little more upset
W-Well, even if I get sent there, I guess I can take a vacation every month.
Until last month he was overseas on business for a whole year.
As soon as he got back, he called and asked if he could crash here.
The girlfriend he lived with took up with someone else.
And he had no place to stay.
And? And then?
Even though it seemed like he called her every day...
He would just complain that he didn't understand women.
If you're serious, Takagi-san, you need to tell her now.
Like what you're feeling, and what you intend to do in the future.
What's more, you don't know what will happen with you.
Eh? With me?
It might just be...
He might find a girlfriend over there.
Exactly.
If that happens, he might not be coming back for a while.
No way!
That's how it is.
They say time and a people's hearts are inversely proportional. The more it passes, the more they grow apart.
It's seems there are some rare exceptions though.
Hey!
I am not going to get another girlfriend elsewhere! Definitely not!
What do you mean "I"?
Who are you talking about?
W-Who?
Huh?
We were talking about Hide!
He might be going overseas.
Oh right, Hide.
Oh, as for Hide, I heard he decided to remain in Japan.
Really?!
You saw the press conference this afternoon then?
No, just after "Morning Live 7" began they superimposed a quick news announcement
"Tokyo Spirits player, Akagi Hideo, indicated he will remain."
"There will be a press conference this afternoon staring at 12:00."
Say, did the newscaster say anything about that in the news afterwards?
No, not really.
Wait a minute.
Could it be?
That's it! That's what happened!
But that's impossible. I still don't know how he performed this trick.
There are still parts I can't explain.
How did he do it? How did that guy create the time?
It doesn't seem there's anything here.
At least not here.
As for that, why don't you ask Detective Chiba?
Chiba, will you swear on this Sakura badge?!
I'm going to go over there and become a better detective.
So, before I go, will you...
W-Will you...
What-'s next time?
Two people!
Detectives!
At last!
A catastrophe?
Huh?