Today's suspect is the friend of a detective.
As it rises past the unsparing crime scene...
How far will two people's love go?
Perceiving the one and only truth,
The body of a child and the brains of an adult,
His name is: Detective Conan!
Hearing that he's being sen to the Tottori prefectural
police joint investigation team, Detective Takagi is in a fix.
Even though they will be separated for three
years, Detective Satou is no different from usual.
At the same time, we coincidentally
become witnesses to a suspect in a murder case.
And then...
Shimura Yu
Nakamoto Hirotoshi Fiancée
It was you, wasn't it? The one who killed Hirotoshi!
What? I'm a murderer?
Katou Akira
Nakamoto Hirotoshi's Coworker
What are you saying all of a sudden?
In that case, what's it about?
Huh?
Ch-Chiba-kun?
Ah, this makes it interesting, doesn't it?
The Metropolitan Police Detective Love Story 6
Part Two
Hey, Chiba, come here a sec!
Ah, OK.
What is it?
Chiba!
Now, Chiba, is it true?!
That you were watching TV with that man
at the time of the crime, that's not a lie, is it?!
Chiba, will you swear on this Sakura badge?!
Yes, I swear!
Ah, I see.
Sorry about that.
Chiba...
Ah, yes?
You know, being a police
detective can be an unpleasant job.
Think! Think!
Hurry to the next one! The next one!
The next one's finally episode four. It's where.
they introduce Yaiba's arch-enemy, Baron Potato!
The Intrigues of Baron Potato!
Oh yeah, if I remember...
It can't be wrong.
The culprit is definitely Katou-san.
He tricked Detective Chiba and used him to create an alibi.
He twisted the flow of time with his bloodstained hands.
Hmm, I haven't found anything.
Neither the gray parka nor the black
backpack the suspicious man was wearing.
What about you?
Nope, nothing.
What about you, Chou-san?
I haven't found a single thing.
It doesn't seem there's anything here.
Yeah. At least not here.
I guess it looks like the friend you have living
here with you, Katou-san, isn't a suspect after all.
Y-Yeah.
Then who could it be?
The children said the man they witnessed
near the murder scene looked like Katou-san.
It must have been someone else who looked a lot like him.
During the time of the crime, both Katou-san and Chiba
were here watching "Morning Live 7" so he has an alibi.
Well let's head back for the present.
The children need to be heading home too.
Yeah, we're done here for today.
Geez.
Inspector Megure said I could learn a lot
listening to what Chou-san said, since he's a veteran.
But it doesn't seem like it.
Hey, Chiba-kun.
I said "Chiba-Run!"
Ah, yes?
Could you go down and call Katou-san please?
We really shouldn't leave without saying something to him.
I-I'll go call him.
Now we have to start over from step one, huh?
I hope this doesn't drag on too long.
Drag on?
Wait a minute, if this case drags on...
Perhaps I won't be sent to the Tottori joint investigation HQ,
and I can remain here with Satou-san and the others.
Ah, you idiot! What are you thinking? You're a police
detective, so you have to solve this case as fast as possible.
Hey, hey. Don't stress about it.
There's no need to worry, this case
will be finished up before going to Tottori.
Ah, yeah.
Well, if it drags on, it can be handed
over to someone else, so take it easy.
Y-Yeah, you're right.
It'll be OK.
Huh? Eh?
Detective Takagi.
I don't think it will drag on much longer.
I already told you, didn't I?
At the time of the crime, from 7:00AM to 7:30.
I was watching TV with Chiba in his living room.
Calm down.
Hey, Mister.
What was the program you were watching?
Huh?
I already said it was "Morning Live 7"!
Which one?
Which one? Obviously the one at 7:00AM on Nichiuri TV!
But...
Look!
It looks like they showed "Morning
Live 7" on cable TV starting at 9:00 also.
It's true!
That means, assuming that you could get
here from the crime scene in an hour and a half...
If he went to kill Nakamoto-san just after 7:00AM...
And got back here by 9:00 to wake up Chiba-kun...
And they both watched "Morning Live 7" on cable TV...
It looks like he could have created a false alibi.
Chiba...
If I remember, you said you both were drinking last
night and passed out here in the living room, right?
Yeah.
Satou-san...
If he had Chiba drink so that he would
oversleep and would be groggy when he was woken up...
He might not have noticed that it was cable TV.
W-Wait a minute here please.
It's true that I might have been groggy, but
he wouldn't have been able to fake the video.
When I recorded the "Morning Live 7" variety program
this morning, the time display was also recorded, right?
If it had been the cable TV showing of "Morning
Live 7" at 9:00, the time wouldn't have been displayed.
It would have been two hours later.
I guess that's true.
Besides, after we finished watching
"Morning Live" at 8:00, we watched six hours of video.
And we were in the middle of watching the live baseball game
that started 2:00PM when Chou-san and you guys arrived.
And I said he was with me the entire time, didn't I?
The only time he wasn't with me was
the 30 minutes when I took a shower.
With only 30 minutes, he couldn't have driven
to the crime scene, since that takes over an hour.
Well, the time I took a shower was after we
watched half of the video, so sometime around 11:00.
So there's no way he could
have been the culprit from the start.
But, still...
You can do a lot of things in 30 minutes.
Like brewing some coffee.
Or watching TV.
Or dubbing a video.
D-Dubbing?
That's right, dubbing...
Ah, I see. If he set it beforehand to automatically
record "Morning Live 7" starting at 7:00...
He could use it to record over the
cable TV program that Chiba had recorded.
Furthermore, if what he recorded was
just Okino Youko's "Four Minute Cooking."
There are two decks, so thirty
minutes would be plenty of time.
B-But, if it didn't have the time display, I
think I would have noticed when I recorded it.
Ah, I wonder.
Those memos are stuck all over around the TV screen.
Normally, if you're used to having things
stuck there, covering parts of the screen...
Even if you didn't see the time
at the upper left of the screen...
You would unconsciously
assume it was covered by the memos...
And you wouldn't remember it as being missing.
Detective Chiba, since you know that
program is after the weather forecast...
Even if you didn't see the time, you
would know the time to start recording.
What's more, after "Morning Live 7" began, you said they
superimposed a news announcement about Hide, didn't you?
Y-Yeah.
If what you were watching was
really the 7 o'clock news-variety program...
I think they would have said something
about that news item during the program.
You're saying that even though it's a live program, if
it was recorded it couldn't have the latest news, right?
Chiba, they didn't mention the news
about Hide during the program, did they?
R-Right.
Actually, I think it was when Chiba went
to the restroom that they had that news.
More importantly, are you forgetting?
We watched six hours of Kamen Yaiba
on video starting at 8:00 in the morning.
And if you add in the 30 minutes in the middle
when Chiba took a shower, it was six and a half.
If we had really watched "Morning
Live 7" on cable TV from 9:00 to 10:00...
Morning Live 7
Kamen Yaiba
Then it would have been 4:30PM
when we finished watching the video.
The live baseball game was only shown
until 4:00, so it should already have been over.
Live Baseball
Kamen Yaiba
And you police arrived here before 4:00, right?
What you're saying seems, right.
Therefore I couldn't have had the time.
Say, what time was it when they
started watching the Kamen Yaiba video?
Didn't I tell you, it was at 8:00 in the morning!
I didn't mean you; I meant those guys.
It was just before we started
searching the apartment, so it would'be...
Around 4:10.
Then it's been about two hours
since they started watching, right?
That's right.
Hey, you guys.
Which episode are you up to now?
Here it comes! Attack, Yaiba Lightning Fist!
Hey, tell me! Which episode!
It's the final scene of episode six!
This is the best part!
Stop interrupting us, Conan!
Six episodes?!
How could that be? Six thirty minute
episodes should have taken three hours.
Tomorrow is a new day! Go, go, our Kamen Yaiba!
Mitsuhiko-kun, hurry! The next one! The next one!
Ah, right, right.
Let's see, next is...
Ah, I see. The commercials!
Not just the commercials...
Those kids can't wait for the next story, so they're
skipping the opening and ending songs, the previews...
And even forwarding past the recaps before the title screen.
That way it only takes 20
minutes to watch a single episode.
D-Did you do it that way too, Chiba?
Y-Yeah, possibly.
Then to watch 12 episodes would be 240 minutes.
That's only four hours, isn't it?
I see.
Assuming you watched the program
two hours late, from 9:00 to 10:00...
And after if you watched this
video, that fixes the discrepancy...
And you would have time to fit in the
live baseball game that started at 2:00PM.
That's very clever, kid.
What's more, Chiba took a shower half-way through, so
he would be somewhat uncertain about the exact timing.
And if you started watching the baseball game in the
middle, he wouldn't know how much time had passed.
That means you could have
skillfully manipulated the times.
B-But after Chiba went to the restroom, he
went into the kitchen to get something to drink.
Didn't you look at the clock then?
Y-Yeah. I didn't notice anything strange though.
That's because you messed with it.
Messed with it? The clock?
Before you woke Detective Chiba, you set the hands of the
clocks in the living room and the kitchen back two hours.
Then while Detective Chiba was watching the
video, you slowly changed them back to the proper time.
N-Now I see.
A The clock here in the living
room is on the wall opposite the TV.
And if the door to the kitchen was closed, no
one would know what you were doing in there.
So changing the hands on the
clocks would have been easy, right?
But there are clocks in the bedroom and the entryway also.
Last night Detective Chiba fell
asleep here in the living room.
And when he took a shower, the clothes he
changed into were probably in this dresser.
So he thought he wouldn't go into the
bedroom, and so he didn't change the clock there.
Then what about the clock in the entryway?
It would have been a bad idea
to change the one in the entryway.
If someone like a delivery man came who knew the time...
And the time on clock was
wrong, they might think it was strange.
Ah, that's right.
So I think that probably, if someone came to visit, this guy
would go out himself instead of letting Detective Chiba do it.
Come to think of it, when we
came here, it was you who answered.
Hey, kid! Where's the proof in this?
As for that, why don't you ask Detective Chiba?
W-What?
Katou...
All the clocks in this apartment were set five minutes early.
In order to stop me from oversleeping.
I just went to look, and only the clocks
here in the living room and in the kitchen...
Were changed back by someone to the proper time.
And that someone wasn't me.
K-Katou, it had to have been you.
D-Don't joke with me.
All I did was turn the clocks back
How does that make me a criminal?!
If you're suspecting me, then show it
to me! The proof that I'm the murderer.
Ah, as for that, I'm sure it will be on its way here.
They found it.
Just now.
On the bottom of the Teimuzu
river, between the crime scene and here.
A black backpack submerged by a weight,
and inside, a bloodstained shirt and pair of pants.
And a gray parka that I figure was worn
over the shirt, with bloodstains on the inside.
What's more, I hear that in several places on
the backpack there are some dark red fingerprints.
Probably they touched the blood when they took
off the blood-covered shirt on the way back home.
And you know who's fingerprints they were, don't you?
And it seems that the car you rented last night
has been discovered in a parking lot near here.
I'll have them inspect it later.
Now that's a pain. I had intended to
wipe those red fingerprints off carefully later.
They're still all over the place in the car.
So, it's true!
It's true that you were using me!
You tricked me to get an alibi for the time of the crime!
Yeah, I figured since you were a police
detective, the police would believe your testimony.
Katou, you jerk!
I'm sorry, but it's the only way I could think of.
The only way to get my
revenge on him for taking my woman.
I already noticed during my phone calls from
overseas that her feelings for me had started to cool.
When I heard she was engaged to
Nakamoto, I wasn't particularly shocked.
But when went over to Nakamoto's place to
tease him about it, and he showed them to me.
Those letters and postcards hit me pretty bad.
"You're such a sucker," he said with a huge grin.
And he tossed them right in front of me.
A pile of the letters and postcards I kept
writing to her when I was overseas on business.
The letters hadn't been opened.
Before she'd even read them, that guy probably...
That's what hit me; it's why I became furious.
I didn't even notice all the clocks
here had been set five minutes ahead.
Really? From the sneakers in the shoe rack?
Yeah.
The knots in the shoelaces were wet.
But strangely elsewhere they were clean and dry.
Wouldn't you think that was odd? If he had
washed his shoes, wouldn't he have taken out the laces?
That's when you figured
Katou-san might be the culprit, right?
He didn't want people to find out
he's been running on a wet roadway.
We washed the mud off with water
and hurriedly dried them with a hairdryer.
Yeah.
That's why later I sent the searchers to look for a place...
Between the crime scene and Chiba's apartment
where someone might discard a black backpack.
But first I had to confirm whether or not Chiba
was lying to protect his friend. I had to consider it.
If Chiba and that guy were in it together, they would
have been able to discard it somewhere further away.
Eh? What are you talking about?
You mean you suspected Detective Chiba too?
Well, you see, a police detective...
It can be an unpleasant job where you have to
suspect everyone, no matter how good a person they are.
Right now Chiba is facing that man in the
examination room, and is probably feeling that keenly.
See ya.
I'll leave the rest to you.
Ah, right. I'll take the children home.
I get the front seat!
What? Not again!
Genta-kun!
You should let us sit in the
passenger seat once in a while too.
Hey, hey, stop quarreling and hurry and get in.
OK, rock-paper-scissors then.
Conan-kun, you play too!
He doesn't need to.
Yeah!
A police detective.
A police detective is an unpleasant job
where you have to be suspicious of people, eh?
Isn't Satou-san suspicious of me?
Am I not going away to Tottori?
Might I not possibly be
surrounded by pretty coworkers there?
If she really likes me...
If she even cares about me a little bit...
All right, get in please.
Shouldn't she be at least a little bit upset about me?
S-Satou-san?
Who was it who put this toy in here?
How awful!
Geez.
This is a challenge against the police!
Ah, no. Satou-san put that there herself.
Huh?
Is she upset?
No way.
Hey, you won't, will you?
Be unfaithful?
Ah, no, of course not.
Even if a super-cute police woman in a
mini-skirt or a sexy actress becomes the police chief?
You really won't?!
S-Satou-san...
I'm going to go over there and become a better detective.
So...
So, before I go...
So, before I go, will you...
Will you...
W-Will you...
G-G-Get eng—
Where are you going?
I-Inspector Megure?
S-Superintendent Matsumoto!
When I realized it, I had to that nostalgic river side
Envisioning the sequel the dream I had yesterday
Oh that day you seemed so grown-up
Unable to even say goodbye, I hid under my umbrella
If we cross paths again... Oh please
That time, forget-me-not
Not like love, not like loving, not something that's changing
It's only you I like, and that's how I think it will always be
Holding onto my aimless feelings, I look back as people often do
Stopping the scene were we chanced to meet from fading gently away
W-What?! The one going to Tottori is Chou-san?
It's not me?
Idiot! How could we possibly.
send a spring chicken like you?
We're sending someone to act as the
representative of police headquarters after all.
B-But, Inspector, didn't you call me at home this morning?
Ah, sorry about that His name is Takagi Chousuke.
I got the phone number wrong
because you're both called Takagi.
Chou-san's name is Takagi too? Geez, that Yumi...
Oh dear, I wonder if someone is talking about me.
Well then, please take care of the children.
Get them home safely.
Ah, yes.
So?
Will I what?
Ah, that is...
W-Will you get eng—
What would be good?
Ah, that's it!
Will you go out for karaoke tonight?
Ah, that's a good idea!
Karaoke!
Woo hoo!
Let's go! Let's go!
Do you need a drink?
He's hopeless.
What on earth are you waiting for?
Eh? What?
110 centimeters?
Wouldn't that be a child?
But, how could this happen?
There's a reason why you stuck around for
five hours waiting for President Kitamura-san.
That is...
Next Conan: The Mysterious Height Difference Of 20cm.
Next Conan's Hint:
Chandelier
Next time's about stature!
As for us...
More than a height difference...
It's a weight difference!