Today's case involves Detective Takagi!
In a case with an unbelievable alibi trick...
Will he be able to see through it?
Seeing through to the one and only truth...
I look like a child, but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
I have a lot of things I need to buy today.
So, you'll help me, right?
Yeah...
She sure is in a good mood today.
Doesn't it feel so refreshing out here?
Yeah, it does.
Conan-kun!
I'll be right back!
Sorry for repeating myself.
But I want to make sure that what.
I have written here is accurate.
You found the corpse yesterday at 8:00 AM.
When you noticed that your boss was missing
from work, you called his office.
Yes.
It's over here.
Your boss works in a different building?
Yes.
It's right next to the office.
And that's where you found the corpse of the president,
Kitamura Katsugoro-san, on the ground?
Yes, that's right.
President.
Excuse me for intruding.
President, is there going to be a meeting today?
President!
President...
The Mysterious Height Difference of 20cm!
At that timer, I did you notice anything
strange at the crime scene?
I'm not really sure...
But wasn't the criminal caught already?
Why do you need me?
There's no evidence, right?
Yeah.
In fact, we discovered something odd-
Hey, what happened here?
C-Conan-kun...
Conan-kun!
Conan-kun, don't run off like this!
R-Ran-san?
Sorry about this.
Well, can you tell me what happened?
The victim is Kitamura Katsugoro-san, 47 years old.
He was the president of this construction company.
The time of death is estimated to have
been between 4:00 PM to 10:00 PM.
As soon as the body was discovered...
The crime scene was analyzed.
The suspect was found and arrested yesterday.
However...
The suspect is Minamida Yuuichi, age 47.
The owner of a small restaurant, as well as...
An acquaintance of the victim from high school.
Minamida Yuuichi (47)
Western Restaurant Owner/Chef
It's true that I went to visit Kitamura at work yesterday...
But I didn't kill him.
You owed Kitamura-san three million yen.
He denied you an extension on your repayment.
So, you took the knife and stabbed him out of panic.
Isn't that right?
Do you have any proof of that?
Did you find my fingerprints on the knife?
Even though no fingerprints were found...
The knife was discovered in his home.
In other words, the fingerprints must have been wiped
off the weapon after the crime had been committed.
Inspector.
It would seem that you had more than
one reason to kill Kitamura-san.
He wanted the property occupied by your restaurant.
In order to acquire it from you, he gave
your restaurant a bad reputation...
And, about three months ago, lent you three million yen.
Kitamura Katsugoro (47)
Town Factory President
Afterwards, you discovered Kitamura-san's ulterior motive,
and began telling people how you felt about him.
Then, on the day of the crime...
You confronted Kitamura-san at his office around 1:00 PM.
It's already 3:00 PM how long are
you going to make me wait?
Please, give me three days-no, two is enough
I gave you the money because we grew up together...
But if you can't repay me, you leave me no choice
but to take the deed as we negotiated.
K-Kitamura!
What is it?
Sorry to interrupt you, President, but the
machine's having some problems.
I understand.
I'll be right there.
Yes, sir. Thank you.
Jeez, guess I have no choice.
What are you doing?!
I know what you're after.
Don't you dare touch me!
You wanted my restaurant from the start!
Get away!
You were after the deed the whole time!
So what if I did?
Just leave the deed and get out of here!
You're such a loser.
Most likely, that was when you decided to kill Kitamura-san.
You patiently waited for Kitamura-san to return.
However, Minamida...
Yeah.
It's true that he came back after thirty minutes had passed.
I begged him to give me until 6:00.
PM to prepare the money...
But got kicked out instead.
Eh?
Were there any witnesses?
Who knows.
I see.
He has a motive, but no evidence was found on the weapon.
At least, that's what Uncle Kogoro would say, right?
You still haven't told us what's so strange.
Oh, I forgot about that.
It's the height difference between the victim and Minamida.
Height difference?
What do you mean?
He's a stubborn one, isn't he?
Not to mention...
His confidence only makes him more suspicious.
Inspector!
We got a report from the forensics team.
The victim was 166cm tall, and Minamida is 186cm tall.
Minamida is a full 20cm taller.
What difference does that make?
The suspect is taller than the victim, so the
knife should be angled downwards.
Conversely, if the knife was being held by a shorter person...
One would expect the knife to be
inserted at an upward angle.
The knife found in Kitamura-san's chest
came from someone much shorter.
In other words...
It's impossible for Minamida, since he's
20cm taller than Kitamura-san.
Th-That can't be...
I talked to forensics to find out how tall the culprit would
have to be in order to stab him at such an angle.
What did they say?
Well, they would have to be about 110cm
to be able to stab someone at that angle.
Only 110cm?
That's like a kid's height!
I get it!
What if the victim was at a higher spot than
the murderer? It makes sense that way.
The crime scene was a single-story building...
And there were no traces of the body being moved.
Then, maybe he stabbed the victim when he was off guard?
Hey! What are you doing?
The victim falling over would have made the knife appear
to have inserted by a much smaller person, right?
That's true, but did you really need to do that right now?
Sorry about that.
Inspector.
I'm positive that Minamida is the culprit as well.
But the victim's wound had an upward angle...
And it doesn't sound likely that the
victim was caught off guard.
Not to mention, Minamida happened
to injure his leg last week.
I don't think he could surprise someone with a cast on.
It's unlikely that he would bend down to stab him.
Maybe the victim was forced to a higher spot
so the knife would be at a weird angle.
Unfortunately, that can't be true.
Kitamura-san was a blackbelt in Judo.
So, if Minamida tried to threaten
him rather than surprise him...
He would've been able to counter it.
That's definitely true.
Minamida-san's height is the only thing
saving him from a conviction.
Hey, there's another picture!
D-Don't look at that, Conan-kun!
Ah-le-le?
That man is wearing glasses in this picture...
But not in the other picture.
Oh, those are reading glasses.
You only use those when you need
to read something, right?
Then, could Kitamura-san have been reading
something right before he was murdered?
But, in this room...
Right.
There's nothing here that he could've
been reading at the time.
That's the problem.
Minamida must have taken it before he left.
Nice thinking, Detective Takagi.
We still don't know why he took it
with him, much less what it was.
Hey, do these slippers belong to President-san?
Yeah, they do.
Was he wearing them when Minamida-san came?
Of course he was wearing them.
Minamida-san came barefoot, though.
But, why are the slippers in the middle of the room?
The slippers must have been thrown off
and landed here when he was stabbed.
Thrown off?
But, that doesn't really make sense, does it?
Because, if they were thrown all the way over here...
Wouldn't they would be scattered around randomly
instead of being neatly beside each other like that?
I swear I didn't touch them!
They're exactly as they were when I discovered the body.
They either simply fell off...
Or Minamida moved them after he committed the murder.
Why would he do that?
Good question.
Maybe Kitamura-san took them off himself?
That's it!
But, why would he do that?
I don't get it!
The difference in height...
The angle of the knife...
A ladder?
What was it?
What did he do?
President Kitamura...
What did you do...
With the ladder?
That's it!
But still, why would Minamida-san
go through all the trouble...
Of thinking of a trick to disguise his height...
When he's just a restaurant owner?
Why?
What exactly were you waiting for?
Our first impression was that you committed
the crime out of sheer panic.
But, now that we've looked into it further...
We can tell that you planned it in advance.
In that case, there must have been a reason for you
to stay in his office from 1:00 PM to 6:00 PM.
A reason other than requesting an
extension for your repayment.
What could you have been waiting so long in that office for?
A miracle...
I guess.
Takagi-kun?
We found something strange.
My deduction isn't complete.
He won't admit to anything without evidence.
Evidence?
Eh?
S-Something strange?
Something strange again?
I just hope it's not bad news.
Ten years ago, there was a serial murder
case in the Minato Prefecture.
The prime suspect was...
Minamida Yuuichi, who was just
a regular salaryman at the time.
Even though Minamida said he was innocent...
The prosecutor ignored his claim.
However, they didn't have the evidence
to give Minamida a guilty verdict.
The angle of the knife made it impossible.
The jury found Minamida innocent because
he couldn't stab the victim at that angle.
And during the proceedings, the real culprit was found.
The case was closed.
Then, Minamida would know that a difference
in height could be used as an alibi.
I see. That's how he was able to think of the trick.
That's right?
Minamida used the same trick from that
other case to commit the murder.
A trick using their difference in height to his advantage.
W-Well, how do we prove it was a trick, Sato-san?
I'm don't know yet.
Anyhow...
I'm going to go report it to Inspector Megure.
Come back to headquarters as soon as you can.
Well, I have to get back to headquarters.
Thank you very much.
Oh, no problem.
Hey, you said that Kitamura-san is 166cm.
Is that really tall for an adult, or too short?
I wanna be really tall when I grow
up, cause being short is real pain.
Like when I need something that's way high
up, I have to get a stool to reach it.
On the other hand, adults don't need to use anything.
That stepladder...
That's not necessarily true.
Some adults might need them when
turning on an air conditioner...
Or when changing lightbulbs.
Lightbulbs?
What if the lights were out at the time, and...
No way!
That'd be an unlikely coincidence.
Conan-kun!
My mom always used to tell me to turn
the lights on when it's getting dark.
Conan-kun!
She said that if you read in the dark, you'll hurt your eyes.
Reading in the dark?
Reading glasses...
Lightbulbs...
The slippers.
Th-That's it!
You guys should head home soon, all right?
All that's left is to find the evidence.
Detective Takagi looked like he found
something out, didn't he?
Minamida Yuuichi-san.
The reason you waited in Kitamura-san's
office for a full five hours...
Was because you needed it to be dark outside.
Dark outside?
W-Why would I have to wait for it to get dark?
You were waiting for Kitamura-san to turn on the lights.
But on that day, the lights didn't turn on.
You forced Kitamura-san to use a
stepladder to check on the bulbs.
You needed him to do this...
So you could stab upwards even though
you're much taller than him.
D-Don't be ridiculous!
Are you saying that the lights just
coincidentally broke on that day?
Or do you think I already knew they were broken?
They weren't broken.
You loosened them.
What are you doing?!
I know what you're after.
Don't you dare touch me!
You wanted my restaurant from the start!
You were after the deed the whole time!
In five hours...
You had plenty of time to unscrew the lightbulbs.
You probably loosened them when there was a problem
with the machine at the construction site.
That was when Kitamura-san was
away for at about 30 minutes.
K-Kitamura might not have checked
on the lightbulbs himself.
He could have asked one of his assistants to do it for him.
That's why you waited until the sun had set...
To give him some very valuable information.
I realized it when I noticed him wearing reading glasses.
Reading glasses?
That's evidence that he was reading something...
No, trying to read something.
That something was very important to him.
He was trying to read the deed to your land, correct?
So, you finally gave it up.
It doesn't seem like a blackout.
Jeez, honestly...
Why at a time like this?
You gave him no choice but to check the lights
himself, without an assistant's help.
W-What's this?
It was just loosened.
Do you admit to the crime?
The reading glasses and slippers may
prove that he used the ladder.
But it doesn't prove that I loosened the lightbulbs.
T-Takagi.
Takagi-kun...
Hey, hey...
Yes?
It's me, Mouri.
M-M-Mouri-san?
I heard about the case from Ran.
So? Did you get a confession out of Minamida?
We're close, but there's nothing that proves
he was the one who loosened the bulbs.
The evidence is what's not there.
Huh? What do you mean?
Yes, yes...
I see!
I understand. I'll check right now.
Inspector Megure, I'm going to go to forensics for a second.
H-Hey, Takagi! Takagi!
What on earth is he thinking...?
Here, can you please help me carry these for now?
For now?
Yep.
Minamida-san...
Every murderer makes at least one mistake.
You removed your fingerprints from the slippers...
And, at the same time, screwed in the rest of the bulbs.
This would erase all fingerprints on the lightbulbs as well.
That's right.
Sometimes the proof is in what's not actually there.
I just asked forensics to look for any prints on those bulbs...
And they came up with absolutely nothing.
Why weren't Kitamura-san's fingerprints on them?
I asked Kitamura-san's family, and
apparently, just one month ago...
A lightbulb went out and Kitamura-san replaced it.
However, his fingerprints are missing.
This is proof that someone erased them.
You knew that having Kitamura-san step on the ladder
before you killed him would work as a trick...
Because you knew that your difference in height could
prove you innocent, as in the crime from 10 years ago.
Minamida-san...
This is proof that you are the murderer!
I was innocent in the case ten years ago.
But on the same day that I was arrested,
I was fired from my job.
The only one who believed in me was my
father, who passed away last year.
He let me take over his restaurant after I lost my job!
And that Kitamura tried to steal it from me!
He's the real criminal!
The way I see it, no matter the situation...
No one's dream can benefit from killing another person!
Before I knew it, I had come to the riverside of memories.
Imagining a continuation of yesterday's dream...
You seemed so grown-up when you were a boy...
I couldn't say goodbye, so l hid under my umbrella.
If we ever meet again... just please remember
all those times, and don't forget me.
My love and affection are things that will never change.
You are my one and only love, and that's how it will always be.
Like many people, I reminisce while holding on to my feelings
So I can keep the memory of us meeting from fading away.
1st Street!
2nd Street!
There's a black demon on 3rd Street!
Hello, this is the Mouri Detective Agency.
Oh, Takagi-kun, what's up?
Yes! I was able to solve the case, thanks to you!
Huh? You solved a case!
What are you talking about?
Minamida? Huh?
Thank you very much for the help!
Well, then.
What a weird guy...
Hey, what happened, Uncle?
Takagi was talking about solving something,
and some guy named "Minamida".
He did it again.
Did I do something without knowing again?
Being a famous detective sure is hard.
You got that right, Uncle.
It's the police.
There was a kidnapping.
The time limit is 5:00.
There's only an hour and a half left.
Maybe the real motive for this kidnapping is...
W-What?!
A different person is dead?
This doesn't make ant sense...
Next Conan: A Kidnapping Case... So It Seems.
Next Conan's Hint!
Oil.
Please look forward to the next episode!
I got a cookie today.
From who?
You want some?
That's not what I-
Too bad!