A kidnapping case with a ransom note...
This type of case is usually motivated by money.
But today's case is a little abnormal!
Seeing through to the one and only truth...
I look like a child, but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
It's 2:30 PM, huh?
It's the time of day when you just want to take a nap.
Wha...?
W-What happened?
Call the police!
No, an ambulance! Call an ambulance first!
No need for an ambulance...
He died instantaneously.
He was speeding, wasn't he?
Serves him right for driving so recklessly.
What's with all this money?
Wow, it's a lot!
Wait, what is this? A letter?
Give me that!
"The ¥300,000 is all here. The police were not informed."
"Please hurry and release my father. Doumoto."
That means this money is...
A payment so a kidnapper will release their hostage...
A ransom!
A Kidnapping Case... Or So It Seems!
The name of the deceased is Hirano Takeshi.
Our records show past arrests for blackmail.
There's no doubt that he's the kidnapper.
It would appear that he was on his way
back from collecting the ransom money.
It would be terrible if he was the only one involved in this.
That would mean we wouldn't be able to
find where the hostage is being kept, right?
We don't have much time either.
My father has a kidney disease that requires treatment every six hours."
"You will find the medicine enclosed with
this letter, so please administer it to him."
This means the hostage won't be getting his medicine.
We have to hurry, or his life will be in danger.
But, where's he being held captive?
First of all, we don't even know who
the hostage is, let alone where he is.
There are many people with the surname Doumoto...
Wouldn't he need to go to the hospital a lot?
To check on his condition.
Beika Electronics.
We're here to deliver the television you ordered.
Um... We didn't order that.
There must be some sort of mix-up.
No, we're sure we aren't mistaken...
Anyway, we need you to come double-check the receipt.
Um... we never ordered a television.
This is the police.
D-Dear.
Police?
Hey! Long time no see!
It's your old college buddy. It's me, remember me?
And I'm his son!
Nice to meet you!
Why're you here too?
Bringing a kid along makes us look less suspicious.
There's been a kidnapping recently, right?
Yes...
My father.
We questioned every hospital in the area...
About a "Doumoto-san" who has a kidney disease.
We were able to identify the hostage as
Doumoto Shouzaburo-san, a patient of Beika City Hospital.
Doumoto Akanari (32)
Mitsuko's Husband
Doumoto Mitsuko (30)
Shouzaburo's Daughter
But, why?
We were told that if we reported this
to the police, our father would be killed.
Well, the situation has changed now.
Why do the police have this?
We placed it exactly where we were told to.
Well, you see, the culprit
died in a motorbike accident.
The culprit...?
Please don't abandon hope.
We're taking this matter very seriously.
We're searching for clues that will lead us to your father.
To think that my father didn't get the medicine...
He needs to have an injection every six hours.
When was the last time he got one?
At 9:00 AM.
So that means...
3:00 PM!
He's now overdue for his scheduled dosage!
Inspector?
He doesn't get sick immediately after missing a dosage...
But if he doesn't get it within eight hours...
So the absolute limit is eight hours, huh?
The deadline is 5:00 PM.
There's only an hour and a half left...
Please explain, in detail, how and
when your father was kidnapped...
As well as the terms you were given.
We have four people in our household.
Doumoto Shouzaburo (64)
Doumoto Metal Company President
My father, Shouzaburo, who is the owner
and company president of a metal factory.
His only daughter, myself...
My husband, Akinari-san...
And our housekeeper, Masayo-san.
Sudo Masayo (67)
Doumoto Family Housekeeper
Everyone had the day off today to celebrate the
factory's anniversary, thus we were all home at the time.
I am also employed at the same factory.
I see.
Since you're his daughter's husband,
you'd be next in line to succeed him.
I gave Father his injection at 9:00 AM,
then left to visit a friend for several hours.
I had already made plans to go somewhere in the afternoon.
Father left to take a walk around
9:30 AM, as is his daily routine.
Around 10:00 AM, I retired to my office to finish some filing.
Around 11:00 AM, while I was cleaning the bathroom...
There was a phone call from a young man.
Put a member of the family on the phone.
This is Doumoto.
W-What? Kidnapped?!
In short, Doumoto Shouzaburo-san was
kidnapped between 9:30 AM and 11:00 AM.
It's highly probable that he
was kidnapped while on his walk.
Did he always take the same route on these walks?
Yes, he always takes the same path.
Can you map it out for us?
Here, this might help to figure
out where the hostage is located.
Yes, sir.
After that, I told my wife to come home as soon as possible.
I'll gather the ¥300,000 ransom somehow.
Don't worry.
As long as we pay the money, Father will be safe.
Leave it to me!
Please do, Akinari-san.
This should be enough.
Akinari-san, thank you so much.
Hello?
The ransom?
As long as we paid and they confirmed that it
was real, they said they would return Father to us.
We believed those words...
We even prepared the medicine just in case!
4:00 PM? Only one hour left.
Don't cry. Father will definitely come home safely.
That's right. Even if he acts like that,
let's keep believing in his safe return.
Uncle Kogoro told me to ask you something...
What did you mean by, "Even if he acts like that"?
Well, Master frequently spoke coldly
towards Akinari-sama and treated him badly.
Spoke coldly?
What's wrong with you?!
You don't even recognize the significance of your position?
I've been trying my best for the employees' sake!
Well then, I guess you aren't fit to be my successor.
Just looking at your face makes me sick!
Father!
Even I don't understand why Master
started being so strict with Akinari-sama.
But his wife backs him up at times like that, right?
Well, you see...
When they first married, they
were always protecting each other...
But recently, even she treats him poorly.
Aren't you ashamed of yourself, Dear?
You're just going to sit there and take that?
Try being a man!
Mitsuko, why are you acting like this too?
I guess it's her father's influence.
But, everything changed once he was kidnapped.
Even Akinari-sama is praying for his safety.
That's why he gathered all that money together, right?
I guess that had nothing to do with this case, after all.
It's me.
According to Hirano Takeshi's friends...
He said he'd have a lot of money after
a "special job" he'd be doing this week.
That must mean he was hired
by someone to commit the crime.
Most likely, but we don't have
any leads as to whom that might be.
Keep asking around. Hopefully, someone will
have useful information relating to this case.
If only we knew who that person was,
we could find out where the hostage is being held.
That means there's an accomplice...
But something doesn't feel right.
Somethings strange, Inspector.
What do you mean?
If you were the one that hired
someone to do this, and he didn't return...
Wouldn't you normally call to see what's going on?
Like, "Are you trying to kill the hostage?" or something?
I see.
That is true.
Exactly.
Why didn't the person in question call him
asking why he hadn't brought the ransom money?
Father!
Mitsuko.
Maybe the real motive for this kidnapping is...
Of course! If you think about it this way...
Hello again. What do you need, young man?
Uncle Akinari-san stayed in his office all morning, right?
Yes. He said he had work to do.
Did he say anything to you during that time?
Did he say something? Um, well...
Masayo-san!
I'm going to be busy, so I won't be needing any tea, okay?
Just as I suspected.
That means...
Oil?
I've got it!
I know who the true culprit behind this case is.
However, if I try to question him
directly, he'll come up with an excuse.
And during that time...
It's not about the ransom!
That's not the culprit's true motive!
It's 4:30 PM. Only thirty minutes left!
Where is it? Where is the hostage is being held?!
Hey, brat...
What are you looking at a map for?
Just seeing if I can figure out where the bike was heading.
Obviously, he was going to where the hostage is being held.
That's what I'm saying.
After collecting the ransom, he would've rode
past Beika Park and Jikogenba High School and then...
Yeah, that sounds right. But, you know, Conan-kun...
Even if we knew the general direction,
it could be 10km or even 100km away.
Ah-le-le?!
There's a place over here that has
the same name as his other one.
Doumoto Metal?
Oh. That's our old factory.
About half a year ago...
We moved to a larger location in East Beika,
leaving the old one abandoned ever since.
In other words, it's an empty factory.
Oh?
That means nobody would have a reason to go there, right?
Inspector, that might be the location.
That seems very likely.
Conan-kun, the map, please?
Okay!
S-So you're saying Father is in that factory?
There's a high possibility that he is.
Oh, no! We only have fifteen minutes!
Ma'am, please don't lose hope until the very end.
Good choice of words.
There's only fifteen minutes left.
We've got to make it somehow.
Come on!
Come on, time, stop!
Father...
Give it to me, I'll do it.
Father!
Doumoto-san!
He's still breathing.
This is Takagi, please send an ambulance here.
Our location is...
Doumoto-san, hang in there!
Your wife will be accompanying her father to the hospital.
Sir, aren't you going with her?
O-Okay.
Hold up a second, sir.
Eh? Why?
Sleeping Kogoro has appeared!
Mouri-kun?
I believe that Doumoto-san will be fine.
But Akinari-san...
I know that you wanted the opposite to happen.
"The opposite", you say?
What do you mean by that?
When I discovered that the ransom wasn't
what the kidnapper was after, I figured it all out.
I instructed Conan to ask Masaya-san a question.
According to her, you and your wife,
Mitsuko-san were happily married.
However, once you were employed
as the husband of the boss's daughter...
Her father started treating you badly, saying
things like, "I guess you aren't fit to be my successor."
You kept getting scolded by her father,
and went through some tough times.
Obviously, you resented Doumoto-san for that...
Even to the point of wanting him dead.
You don't mean...
But you didn't have the courage to do it yourself.
That's when you thought up this scheme.
Scheme?
That's absurd!
I have no idea what you're talking about!
No. Akinari-san is the culprit, Inspector Megure.
T-That can't be!
Doumoto-san was kidnapped while he was on his walk.
That's when Akinari-san...
I was in my office the whole time!
Were you really working in your office?
Before you went into your office,
you told the housekeeper...
Masayo-san!
I'm going to be busy, so I won't be needing any tea, okay?
Afterwards, you left through the window using a
spare pair of shoes you had prepared beforehand.
You drove up to Doumoto-san, who was in the
middle of his walk, and asked to speak with him.
What did you want to talk about?
You even brought me to this place.
Honestly, you're the most despicable man I know.
No matter what you say, I'll have you know that I won't-
Akinari-kun, we have to go back quickly!
I don't have my medicine with me!
Akinari-sama, you have a phone call.
What?!
A kidnapping?
Then he put on an act for everyone,
pretending to be oblivious to the situation.
Of course, he made a big mistake in his haste.
If you look at his window ledge in his office closely...
You'll find traces of the same oil found here in this factory.
The oil is custom-made for this factory, as well.
That serves as evidence that he
came back in through the window.
I also found a discarded tissue he used to wipe off the ledge.
However, the biggest piece of evidence are the
footprints he made on the ground as he was leaving.
It takes approximately one hour to drive
between the Doumoto residence and this factory.
That's plenty of time to commit the crime, as you
going to be "in your office" from 10:00 AM to 11:00 PM.
That certainly is plausible.
However, why would he do it himself?
Wouldn't it have been simpler
to have the person he hired do it?
Most likely, that man was hired
without knowing about the kidnapping plan.
He helped without knowing about the kidnapping?
Yes. He probably said to him...
Call me between 11:00 AM and 2:00 PM...
And be sure to pick up a suitcase near Beika Park.
There's no need to know what's in
the suitcase, so don't worry about it.
He knew that if he informed others of
his plan, it might backfire on him later.
So, he planned this specifically for today,
when his wife would be leaving the house.
What?! Father was kidnapped?
A suitcase in Beika Park?
That means he was talking to
himself on the phone the whole time.
Yes. If Hirano hadn't gotten into an accident,
he would have gotten all his money back.
Everything would have went according to his plan.
There wouldn't have been a
need for the police or a detective.
All he had to do was act like he was worried,
and wait until just enough time had passed.
That's exactly right.
However, you're wrong about the motive, Mouri-san.
I did indeed hold a grudge against my father-in-law...
But that's not all.
I also wanted to use the money to
show Mitsuko that I wasn't insensitive.
I thought if I showed her how
desperate I was to get him back...
She would love me again, just like she used to.
Before I knew it, I had come to the riverside of memories.
Imagining a continuation of yesterday's dream...
You seemed so grown-up when you were a boy...
I couldn't say goodbye, so I hid under my umbrella.
If we ever meet again, just please remember
all those times, and don't forget me.
My love and affection are things that will never change.
You are my one and only love, and that's how it will always be.
Like many people, I reminisce while holding on to my feelings.
So I can keep the memory of us meeting from fading away.
It's Mitsuko!
Thank goodness!
They said Father will have a full recovery!
After he regains consciousness...
I'll tell him how desperate you were to save him...
And how worried you were about him.
After that, I'm sure Father won't
purposely make you feel bad anymore.
"Purposely?"
Father acted so horribly because he
wanted to mold you into a great successor.
The truth is, Father thinks a great deal about you!
He's always praising your determination and helpfulness.
These past few days, I've been acting just like my father too.
I really hated doing that, and I'm so sorry!
Hello?
Hello, Akinari-san?