"Star" is a fascinating word.
It can refer to both culprits and actors!
Because of the trick they find at the Karakuri Mansion...
The Detective Boys have a big adventure!
Let's find the treasure, and let's go!
Seeing through to the one and only truth...
I look like a child, but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
A man is like a mountain, isn't he?
Come on...
Genta-kun, don't just stand around!
Huh?
Please come help us gather some
wood for the fire, like you're supposed to!
I'm not just standing around!
I really am gathering some up!
See?
Oh, come on...
Gathering up that little pile doesn't help us at all!
I-Is that right?
But, you know... Why didn't Conan come with us?
That again?
Like I just got through telling you...
Did you catch a cold?
That's not it.
Shin'ichi...
Huh?
What was the thing you wanted to talk to me about again?
He wasn't even listening...
Oh, that song!
Nanatsu no Ko
Seven Children.
Was it actually "seven", or was it...?
But, you know what I mean?
Yeah...
"Crow, why do you cry?"
That's how it goes, right?
Yeah, that's it.
Back when I was a young lad,
I often sang that on my way home from school.
So, what about it? Is that your homework for music class?
No!
Like I said before, when you press
0-8-5-8 on your cell phone in rhythm...
Doesn't it sound like the first verse of that song?
O-8-5-8...
Crow
Ka-ra-su...
Let me see.
It certainly sounds like it, but...
I finally remembered.
During that time when Vermouth
was next to me, texting her boss...
I felt a sad, nostalgic aura coming from somewhere.
However, that wasn't from the look on her face...
It was from the sound of the buttons she
pushed when inputting the e-mail address!
What?!
T-Then, are you saying that...
Their boss' e-mail address goes
to the tune of S-Seven Children?
There's no way that could be true.
Why would they have chosen a
children's song as their e-mail address?
If they're using the sound to remember it...
What do you think?
U-Using sound?
Yeah.
That way, they could remember the e-mail
address without storing it in their cell phone's memory.
It'd be safer for them in many ways, don't you think?
So if the phrase "Ka-ra-su" is
produced from the tones of 0-8-5-8...
Why do you cry?
Then, "Naze naku no" is...
Well, it kind of fits...
It's true that it doesn't sound exactly the same...
But if we find the buttons that have
the tone which corresponds to each note...
And type them like this...
It becomes something like that.
This is the e-mail address
belonging to the boss of the men in black!
W-What did you say?!
Most likely, I'm not mistaken.
H-Hey, don't tell me you're going to mail that address...
You idiot...
Do you really think I'd do
something that would expose myself to them?
You're right...
What on Earth was I thinking?
Well, I'll send the e-mail address to
Officer Takagi so he can look into it for me.
They'll eliminate him, you know.
Officer Takagi.
It'll happen the very moment he reaches that person.
And their next target...
Will be the person who supplied him with
that e-mail address: namely you, Kudo-kun.
So if we inform more than just Detective Takagi...
Properly informing the rest of the police force...
They'll be able to outnumber them, and—
Pointless.
In that case, they'd just execute their backup plan...
Then cover their tracks by
making it look like a simple kidnapping.
And besides the over-trusting Officer Takagi...
Do you really expect anybody to believe you?
That's right, before involving the
police with their boss or anyone else...
You first need to find out exactly
who that e-mail address belongs to.
Because I'm fairly certain that they'll
find such a story hard to believe otherwise.
"Hard to believe?"
Hey, don't tell me that...
You knew it the whole time?!
You knew their boss' e-mail address all along?!
Do you also know who the boss is?
Hmm... Who knows?
But what a waste!
We may just have found their boss'
e-mail address, and can't do anything with it.
Well, we just have to let it go and forget all about this.
This e-mail address...
Is something that should never be opened.
Because it's Pandora's Box.
Big Adventure at the Unconventional Mansion:
Sealing Part!
Huh?
What did you just say?
What is that "Panda's Box?"
Conan, tell me!
Is it a treasure?
M-Maybe it's something with pandas inside!
No. That's not it, Ayumi-chan.
A god filled a box with all the evil and catastrophes
in the world, then gave it to a woman named Pandora.
He told her she must not open it, no matter what happened.
It's a box from a story in Greek mythology.
But being told to not open it
makes you want to open it even more!
Honestly, Genta-kun...
Exactly, Pandora disobeyed
that order and opened the box...
So all the evil and catastrophes
escaped and spread out across the world.
Isn't that right?
Yeah...
So, why were you talking about this "Pandora Box"?
Yeah, yeah!
No, no reason in particular.
Speaking of boxes, we found a strange
stone box while gathering firewood, didn't we?
A stone box?
Can you tell us more about it?
Yes...
There were two parts, and the cube-shaped
base had a round hole in it, making it look like a box.
And when we peered through the hole, we
could see characters engraved on the stone!
We think it was engraved with
something like the "Two Kings' Stone"...
But there were too many difficult kanji to be sure.
We couldn't read it!
Yes.
Say, could you take me to
where you guys found this stone box?
S-Sure.
This way, this way!
It's this way!
You don't necessarily have to run.
Hey!
O-Oh, I guess that's true.
But guys, how far did you go just to gather firewood?
Look, it's over there!
Yeah, yeah...
It's surprising that there's a mansion way out here.
If you look at it more carefully...
You can see it's all worn out, right?
T-This sure is a very old,
dilapidated-looking mansion, isn't it?
It somehow gives you the creeps, doesn't it?
Sure does.
From the look of it, we can assume it's
been many years since it was last occupied.
This is...
Conan-kun!
Over here, over here!
A-All right.
This is the stone box you wanted to see, Conan-kun.
When we first found this box earlier...
We could see it laying on the
bottom of this swamp, through the water...
And saw that there was a carp
swimming around inside of it!
We pulled up the stone in order to try to catch that carp...
And that was when we noticed
the characters engraved inside.
But the carp jumped out of the hole and escaped, anyway!
Isn't this a Japanese stone lantern?
Huh?
What? A Japanese stone lantern?
You know, it's one of those outdoor lanterns made
out of stone that you often see in Japanese gardens.
This is the part of the lantern is called
"Hibukuro", and is where you put a candle in the center.
Now that you mention it,
it certainly looks like one of those...
But in that case, the capping stone and the
platform must have been lost somewhere.
Aren't they here?
Right in this swamp.
And it's not just one or two of them...
It's true!
We were so focused on the carp
earlier that we didn't notice them at all.
Most likely, the Japanese stone lanterns
that were originally in this mansion's garden...
All ended up in the bottom of this swamp.
It was setup this way to make people believe
there never were any Japanese stone lanterns here.
I think that's what their goal was, anyway.
Someone threw them all in here so nobody
else would decipher the code they finally found...
And get to the treasure before them.
A-A treasure?
There really is a treasure?
Yes, probably.
No...
That's not all.
It looks like the Japanese stone lantern's
weren't thrown in simply to hide the code.
What do you mean?
It was also done to hide a crime.
A corpse.
The temperature of this
swamp is below 20 degrees Celsius...
And rigor mortis doesn't seem to have
set in on the body yet, which means...
It hasn't been very long since the murder took place.
And from the rope marks on his neck, we can
assume that after he was strangled to death...
He was tossed into the swamp, and had the lanterns thrown
on top of him to prevent his body from rising to the surface.
Who could have done that?
Who knows?
But it's definitely related to the treasure.
Tamai Teruhisa-san, 42 years old.
So, did you figure out anything?
No, I didn't find anything from his driver's license.
There's something in there...
Oh! Is it the treasure?
No, this is...
A comma-shaped stone, otherwise known as "Magatama".
Flame
And the character "Honoo" is engraved on it.
Could it be that this is the treasure?
What the heck?
Isn't this just a stone with a weird shape?
Come on... Enough with the questions, okay?
Stop thinking only about the treasure!
Professor, can you call the police immediately?
Yes, understood.
As I thought, it's impossible from here.
Outside of
Service Area
Since my cell phone can't connect from here,
I'm going back to the tent to try again from there.
Yes, that sounds good.
Be careful!
Well, the sun has started to set...
So it's about time we start heading back, too.
Aw...
Hey, Conan!
We're just gonna go back and leave things like this?
He's right! There might be a treasure right in front of us!
Isn't that right?
Yes!
You idiots!
The culprit who killed this guy may still be lurking nearby!
Guys, we may get attacked if we
keep standing around here like this!
But...
Listen...
We only know this guy's name...
We don't know why he came here,
or anything else about him, do we?
But he looks like a treasure hunter.
In this notebook, there's information and
maps of every supposed treasure location in Japan.
Really?
Yes.
There are also notes written about the
treasure he was in the middle of searching for this time.
"I teamed up with a partner of
whom I believe will be of use, somehow."
"This way, I will finally outwit this conceited sneak-thief."
Conceited sneak-thief?
"The magician who has tricked me time and time again."
"The resting place of the Two
Kings, near to that which brings life..."
"At the place where the elders
gather, full of prosperity and vitality."
"There, you will find the Two Kings' Stone."
"The person who does not
fear the wrath of the Two Kings..."
"Shall acquire the knowledge of the eternal truth..."
"In order to take possession of the
stone that will fill one's hand to the fullest."
"Samizu Kichiemon."
Eh? Samizu?
"Samizu Kichiemon..."
1853-1867
He's from the Bakumatsu Era, wasn't he?
Yeah...
He financially helped the wandering
samurai who supported the shogun...
By creating karakuri dolls.
Oh, wow!
Karakuri dolls?
The karakuri dolls...
Can do things like bring you tea, right?
Not only that...
But when you're finished drinking, and put
your cup on the plate, the doll takes it back for you!
So... It's like one of those radio-controlled cars, right?
No!
It could move entirely on it's own,
without anyone needing to control it!
What?
So how does it work, Ayumi?
I don't know, but...
The entire doll is made up of
only springs and cogwheels inside!
There are many of other kinds of dolls, too.
And a lot of them are still working, even now!
You sure are smart!
I just happened to see it on TV recently.
Those lifelike karakuri dolls,
constructed by Samizu Kichiemon...
Caught the interest of the Japanese
feudal lord and merchants of the time...
Which provided him with a life-long income.
That's how he earned the nickname "Karakuri" Kuchiemon.
So the Two Kings' doll that
"Karakuri" Kichiemon constructed...
Could possibly be hidden somewhere in this mansion?
Two Kings' Karakuri?
No, even if we assumed that such things were there...
If they were hidden in a 200-year old mansion,
which seems to have long since fallen into disrepair...
They would probably already be worn out.
Why'd they have to get worn out for?
The treasure is connected to the
aforementioned "Two Kings' Stone".
"The resting place of the Two
Kings near to that which brings life..."
"At the place where the elders gather,
full of prosperity and vitality."
"There, you will find the Two Kings' Stone."
Isn't that what was written on the stone?
But we don't understand that!
That's right! What do all those fancy words actually mean?
They're too difficult, so I don't understand very well.
Simply put, the place where the Two Kings sleep...
Is the place closest to the sun, and is a
lively place where older people gather
That's where the "Two Kings' Stone" is.
The "Two King's Stone"...
Isn't it just a plain, old rock?
Note: The first two kanji for "guardian gods"(kongou) combined with the kanji
for stone (ishi) creates the Japanese word for diamond (kongouseki).
Since the "Two Kings" are also
part of the four guardian gods...
Their stone would have to be "kongouseki".
Note: The Detective Boys are confused because the traditional
Japanese word "kongouseki" has mostly been replaced
by the English loanword (daiyamondo).
"Kongouseki"?
In English, "Kongouseki"
becomes the king's jewel: a diamond.
A-A diamond?!
Yes, it is said that diamonds were
introduced to Japan in the Bakumatsu Era.
So it fits with the historical timeline, doesn't it?
Oh, that reminds me! On the TV show I saw that time...
They said a map related to the
Two Kings was found in Kichiemon's basement.
Tamai-san probably heard about the map
on TV as well, and came to this place to get it.
And that's when he found the Japanese stone lantern.
But there, the partner whom he deemed
helpful, betrayed him and ended their cooperation.
Well, that certainly seems like a
logical conclusion as to what happened.
Please wait a second.
Inside this hole, it looks like there's more to the text...
Yeah, the part after that is the problem.
"The person who does not
fear the wrath of the Two Kings..."
In other word, someone who is
not afraid of the Two Kings' anger.
So, they are really here...
And, "...in order to take possession of the
stone that will fill one's hand to the fullest."
"The stone that will fill one's hand to the fullest"?
Hey, Conan...
What did you find? Tell us!
Hand... Fill to the fullest...
Big Jewel!
There's no mistaking it.
Hey...
Why don't we ditch Conan and start
searching for the treasure ourselves?
Huh?
I guess you're right...
Let's search for the treasure by ourselves.
But if Conan-kun isn't with us, we can't solve the codes.
It's okay.
It seems his ignition key was already turned.
Interesting...
Karakuri Mansion, I'm awaiting our meeting.
S-Skeletons!
Stop! That's a trap!
Huh?
Hey!
Next Conan:
Big Adventure at the Unconventional Mansion, Karakuri Part.
Next Conan's Hint!
The three Imperial Regalia.
The guy you've long been
awaiting will finally appear next week!
What
That guy?
Who?
A rival!