"Star" is a fascinating word.
It can refer to both culprits and actors!
During the big adventure at the Karakuri Mansion...
We come across some surprisingly life-threatening traps...
As the Detective Boys work together
to outwit that conceited sneak-thief!
Seeing through to the one and only truth...
I look like a child, but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
Yes, we felt the same light the moment we met.
Yes, lots and lots of the same emotions filled our eyes.
Although the signals you sent destroyed my theory...
These feelings were always beyond your reach
So, let's fight, go against our morals...
And aim for a wider world!
Oh, glimmering star, shine over us forever.
This way, we won't lose the dreams we had when we were young...
I don't care if this town changes someday.
The only thing I don't want to change is you.
Oh, glimmering star, shine over us forever.
This way, we won't lose the dreams we had when we were young...
The only thing I don't want to change is you.
From the melody of "Seven Children", I figured out the
e-mail address belonging to the boss of the men in black.
But according to Haibara,
we mustn't proceed any further with it.
Meanwhile, Genta and the others who
came to camp with us discovered a strange stone.
Inside, we found a coded
message leading to the "Big Jewel"...
And right next to it, we found the
body of a man who had been murdered.
"The stone that will fill one's hand to the fullest"?
Hey, Conan...
What did you find? Tell us!
Hand... Fill to the fullest...
Big Jewel!
There's no mistaking it.
Big Adventure at the Unconventional Mansion:
Karakuri Part!
I see.
It sure looks like this is the start of
"Diamond Cut Diamond", doesn't it?
What's that?
A Belgian proverb.
You know that the only thing that can
cut a diamond is another diamond, right?
Likewise, this is the beginning of an all-out
war between two equally level-headed people.
But exactly who are the ones that are fighting?
Idiot.
Neither him nor I are something as grandiose as a diamond.
That guy is someone covering up
the truth with a veil for the heck of it...
A simple thief.
While I'm itching to rip off that unsightly veil...
A simple detective.
Huh? Who's this "thief" you're talking about?
Could it be that he's talking about the
partner of this guy, who had drowned in the lake?
No, I'm talking about the guy who's
obsessed with stealing large jewels like "Big Jewel"...
The one known as "Kaitou Kid."
That conceited scoundrel.
Ka...
Kaitou Kid?!
Yeah.
We know that name!
The kind-hearted one who comes and goes with a bang...
The gentleman thief!
I heard from the Professor...
About this never-ending fight you're both involved in.
Never-ending fight?
Don't you have the feeling that you're always losing?
I-I don't ever lose!
He's never succeeded in getting
away with the treasure, after all...
Say, is Kid going to come here?
I said that's only a possibility, didn't I?
Don't you remember what that guy wrote in his notebook?
"This way, I will finally outwit this conceited sneak-thief."
"This conceited sneak-thief" is probably referring to Kid.
So that guy was murdered by...
Kid did it?
Who knows?
The rumors say that he never resorting to killing, but...
But Kid, or the culprit behind
that guy's murder, must be close by.
Exactly, since they still haven't
found the treasure they're after.
Which means the answer must lie inside that mansion, huh?
Well, since it started to rain...
Why don't we go in the mansion
and take a quick look until it calms down?
What?!
So...
The treasure hunt...
Is starting, isn't it?
Don't get the wrong idea, now.
It's only until the Professor comes back with the police.
Yay!
But now that we're about to enter the mansion,
I've noticed just how depressing it looks...
Is there really a treasure inside?
It's true that a treasure is hidden somewhere around here.
I noticed it earlier, but...
There's fresh mud along the point where
the wall meets the foundation of the house.
And it looks like it continues around the entire perimeter...
Why?
Hey, Conan...
Tell us what that thing back there meant again!
He's talking about the meaning of the
text carved inside the Japanese stone lantern.
Ah, that?
I'm pretty sure the Two Kings weren't here, were they?
That's right.
"The resting place of the Two Kings,
near to that which brings life..."
"At the place where the elders gather,
full of prosperity and vitality."
"There, you will find the Two Kings' Stone."
"The person who does not
fear the wrath of the Two Kings..."
"Shall acquire the knowledge of the eternal truth..."
"In order to take possession of the
stone that will fill one's hand to the fullest."
"Samizu Kichiemon."
If you interpret it figuratively, it says the place where
the Two Kings are resting is the closest place to the sun.
And it's a very busting place where the elders meet.
And "There, you will find the Two Kings' Stone."
So that's where the diamond is hidden, isn't it?
But what's intriguing are the words that come after that...
Oh, is that right?
That's fine and all, but Conan-kun stopped
explaining, so I don't understand what you mean.
"The person who does not
fear the wrath of the Two Kings..."
"In order to take possession of the
stone that will fill one's hand to the fullest..."
"You must understand its origin, from long ago."
What does that mean?
So the Two Kings really will get angry...
Yeah.
And then there's the thing we found
in the cuff of that guy's pants earlier...
The comma-shaped, magatama stone
engraved with the character for flame.
What connection does this have with the coded message?
I still don't understand it.
Hey...
In the meantime, why don't we just go in?
I know, don't rush!
Was there anything else written in
the notebook that guy had on him?
There is something else written here...
But we can't read it because it's all wet.
We might be able to if we wait for it to dry, though.
I can't wait that long!
Hey, Genta!
Genta...
Don't enter so carelessly!
This mansion was built by Karakuri Kichiemon, you know!
The diamond is at the closest place to the sun, right?
That's why it has to be at the very
top of this mansion, don't you think?
First off, let's go to the highest place!
Hey! Wait, Genta!
If I move softly, everything will be okay...
What?
H-Help me!
Genta!
What are you doing here, brats?
Genta-kun, are you all right?
Satou Unzou (40)
Treasure Hunter
Are you guys also looking for Kichiemon's treasure?
Ah, no...
Well, that's okay.
Look out for yourselves in the future, though.
These stairs are a trap.
If you want to go upstairs, you
have to think more outside of the box.
Karakuri Kichiemon was quite the jokester.
So if you take the most obvious approach you see,
hoping to get what you're after, you're going to get hurt.
Besides that, did you guys
happen to find a odd-looking stone?
Ah, about that
We didn't find it! Or anything else.
Huh?
Oh, is that so?
Well... If you find it, let me know.
Okay!
We'll do that.
Hey, Conan!
Why did you lie to him?
He saved Genta-kun, so he has to be a nice person!
We don't know if he's actually a nice person...
There's a possibility he's just acting friendly towards us
to get his hands on the comma-shaped magatama stone.
Yeah...
He'd definitely act like that if he was Kid...
Or even if he's the culprit behind the
murder of that guy we found earlier.
But right now, it seems he knows a lot about this mansion...
So it'd be better if we stuck with him for the time being.
Especially in order to prevent him
from escaping before the police arrives.
Speaking of which, did the Professor already call the police?
Is it further in?
This "old, run down mansion"...
Let me see...
It's completely black up ahead.
What?
Huh?
Which way was it?
H-Hey!
Oh, it's carp!
And there's a whole bunch of them!
Having a river flowing through the house
makes it look like a high-class restaurant, doesn't it?
Maybe it's connected with the lake outside.
Look! There's a bridge, too!
A trap?
I won't fall for that this time!
No, actually it's...
Awesome!
It's like an elevator, isn't it?
Conan-kun!
Hurry up and get on!
O-Okay...
So this means that we have to go down to get up...
And that if we go up, we end
up falling back down, doesn't it?
Once we understand the trick, it's really easy!
Sure is!
Looks like we arrived.
That was so easy!
Fools...
If things were that simple, we wouldn't
even have to bother looking for the treasure.
Akutsu Sarina (29)
Treasure Hunter
Isn't that right, Kid-Taking-Treasure-Hunter-san?
I didn't take these brats with me.
Anyway, even if they are brats...
What were you thinking, throwing a knife at them?
Take a good look at the knife's blade.
A poisonous spider!
This "Kichiemon" person is not just a jokester,
but also extremely malicious, wouldn't you agree?
If you're trying to get to the
highest point in the house, it's this way.
Could it be that this older lady is Kid?
Isn't Kid a guy?
No. I heard he sometimes
disguises himself as a young woman, too.
Come on, and watch your step, brats...
'Cause some of those deadly spiders are still around here.
Hey! Wait for me!
Conan!
Hurry and get up here...
Or you'll get bitten by a poisonous spider!
Yeah, I'll go now.
Oh, look! We reached the highest place!
But there's nothing here.
Then, is it on the roof?
Let me see, to get on the roof...
That's strange...
Why doesn't this floor have a support column?
Oh, there it is!
It's a ladder!
There were some on the previous floors.
We're the first!
Wait...
Knowing the nature of that person,
if there's a missing support column...
Stop! That's a trap!
Huh?
Hey!
Crap...
Genta!
Ayumi!
Mitsuhiko!
Haibara!
Hey, are you all right?
I'm sending a rope down to you right now!
Didn't we already tell you?
That if we go up, we end up falling back down...
Is everyone all right?
Yes.
Yeah.
Yep.
We somehow went down, but it
looks we can't go any lower, doesn't it?
Even though we wanted to reach the top...
I checked the roof, but there's nothing there.
Really?
Coming here was probably the right decision...
Huh?
What's that?
S-Skeletons!
Hey, Conan!
H-Hey...
Here... Skeletons!
Over there, over there...
Based on how they look, I'd say they were treasure hunters.
No!
And then there's this old man...
Senju Eri (72)
Treasure Hunter
I'm not an old man...
I'm an old woman!
I slept well.
Huh?
She's alive.
So this granny is also our rival?
Huh?
Aren't you a treasure hunter, as well?
I only came for a little leisure and to
visit a grave so I can pay my respects.
A grave?
Yes, Kichiemon-san's.
Samizu Kichiemon's grave?
Kichiemon's grave?
I'll be the first to see it!
If it keeps going on like this, these kids
will bring the treasure back with them.
"Wandering person, offer me the
Three Imperial Regalia. - Samizu Kichiemon."
Wait, Granny...
Isn't that a coded message?
Is that so?
I thought it was saying how to pay your
respects to Kichiemon-san at his grave.
But, I wonder what it means...
It tells us something like "offer me something"...
But, we didn't bring food or flowers with us!
Now that I think about it...
The thing that was hiding in the cuff
of the guy who drowned in the lake...
Was a comma-shaped magatama stone.
Say, Mister...
You asked us something earlier, didn't you?
You asked, "Did you guys
happen to find a odd-looking stone?"
That's because you have one, don't you?
A stone related to the Two Kings.
What?
Actually, we found one too.
A stone that was created as
one of the Three Imperial Regalia.
W-Wait, Conan-kun...
Didn't you tell us that was a secret?
What was written on it?
There was a some kind of character
engraved on the stone you found, wasn't there?!
I thought so! You really did find one, didn't you?
Ah, no...
Oh?
I don't think withholding information in
the predicament we're in is a very good idea.
That's right.
If you don't want to be excluded from our
group, hurry and show us what you found.
Understood.
I found this stone that looks like a mirror.
Eternity
It's engraved with the character "ei" from "eien", isn't it?
So, it is really linked to the sun!
Because it's always burning.
So, the comma-shaped magatama you guys found...
Flame
Was engraved with "honoo"
or something like that, wasn't it?
Yeah...
That's a great guess, Miss.
But I don't understand the
meaning behind "ei" and "honoo".
If we put these stones in the spaces in the grave...
We may trigger some
mechanism and the Two Kings' stone...
That is to say, the diamond may come out!
Why do you think that?
That's because, remember?
It was in the text engraved inside
the Japanese stone lantern, right?
"The diamond is at a lively
place where older people gather."
Is this what it meant about a
lively place where older people gather?
Yes.
Let's see... What was it again?
"The resting place of the Two Kings..."
Um...
"The resting place of the Two Kings,
near to that which brings life..."
"At the place where the elders gather,
full of prosperity and vitality."
"There, you will find the Two Kings' Stone."
Am I right?
Y-Yes.
A lively place where older people gather.
"The place where the elders gather,
full of prosperity and vitality"...
Do you honestly think that a such a
description refers to this mountain of dead corpses?
Yes...
That's not right...
These people are fools who were blinded by
their greed, lost their way, and ended up dying here.
Not to mention that when Kichiemon-san
built this mansion, not a single corpse was here.
Oh! That sounds about right.
So you also saw that Japanese stone lantern, Granny?
Yes, but it wasn't sunk in the lake...
Anyway, it doesn't look like the jewel is here.
It doesn't look like there's a mechanism that would
be triggered by putting the stones in this grave, either.
So, we really do have to find one more of
the Three Imperial Regalia to solve this mystery.
"One more...?"
The third of the Three Imperial Regalia.
We already found the mirror
and the comma-shaped magatama...
So there has to be one more somewhere around here.
The Three Imperial Regalia?
Yes.
Eight Hand Mirror
The mirror is known as the "Yata no Kagami"...
Tear of Benevolence
The magatama is known as the "Yasakani no Magatama"...
And the last one remaining...
Long ago, when a treacherous
warlord set a grassy plain on fire...
In order to send Yamato-dake Mikoto to his
demise by trapping him in the ensuing blaze...
He used a sword to mow the grass...
Ultimately saving himself.
It was the divine sword:
Grass-Mowing Sword
The "Kusanagi no Tsurugi".
The "Kusanagi no Tsurugi"?
Before I knew it, I had come to the riverside of memories.
Imagining a continuation of yesterday's dream...
You seemed so grown-up when you were a boy...
I couldn't say goodbye, so I hid under my umbrella.
If we ever meet again, just please remember
all those times, and don't forget me.
My love and affection are things that will never change.
You are my one and only love, and that's how it will always be.
Like many people, I reminisce while holding on to my feelings.
So I can keep the memory of us meeting from fading away.
Brat!
"Wandering person, offer me the Three Imperial Regalia."
Otherwise this water is going to sweep us away,
all the way down to the bottom of the valley!
Next Conan:
Big Adventure at the Unconventional Mansion, Solution Part.
Next Conan's Hint!
Note: Kekanbi is the name of a Frankenstein-like
monster dog in a Japanese horror movie.
It's Kekanbi!
Samizu Kichiemon.
Please look forward to the next episode!
By itself, "mon" means gate, while "emon" used
to be common ending for a male's name.
What type of gate is Kichiemon?
No!
It's a person's name.
And an ordinary one at that...