"Star" is a fascinating word.
It can refer to both culprits and actors!
Through reasoning, we finally
make it to the Two Kings' treasure!
But who will get it? Will it be Kid...
Or will it be the Detective Boys?!
Seeing through to the one and only truth...
I look like a child, but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
Yes, we felt the same light the moment we met.
Yes, lots and lots of the same emotions filled our eyes.
Although the signals you sent destroyed my theory...
These feelings were always beyond your reach.
So, let's fight, go against our morals...
And aim for a wider world!
Oh, glimmering star, shine over us forever.
This way, we won't lose the dreams we had when we were young...
I don't care if this town changes someday.
The only thing I don't want to change is you.
Oh, glimmering star, shine over us forever.
This way, we won't lose the dreams we had when we were young...
The only thing I don't want to change is you.
We went to camp with Professor Agasa.
Nearby, at an odd mansion, Genta
and the others found a strange stone.
Inside, we found a coded
message leading to the "Big Jewel"...
And right next to it, we found the body of a
man who had been mysteriously murdered.
Then, we decided to go in the
odd mansion and began to explore it.
There, we met two treasure
hunters and a strange old woman.
So, we really do have to find one
more of the Regalia to solve this mystery.
"One more...?"
The third of the Three Imperial Regalia.
We already found the mirror
and the comma-shaped magatama...
So there has to be one more somewhere around here.
The Three Imperial Regalia?
Yes.
Eight Hand Mirror
The mirror is known as the "Yata no Kagami"...
Tear of Benevolence
The magatama is known as the "Yasakani no Magatama"...
And the last one remaining...
Long ago, when a treacherous
warlord set a grassy plain on fire...
In order to send Yamato-dake Mikoto to his
demise by trapping him in the ensuing blaze...
He used a sword to mow the grass...
Ultimately saving himself.
It was the divine sword:
Grass-Mowing Sword
The "Kusanagi no Tsurugi".
Big Adventure at the Unconventional Mansion:
Solution Part!
Ah!
I know about the Kusanagi no Tsurugi!
It's the really powerful sword
that's in video games a lot, isn't it?
The Kusanagi no Tsurugi?
Akutsu Sarina (29)
Treasure Hunter
We may figure something out if we find that sword and see which character is engraved on it.
Before hunting for the treasure...
Wouldn't it be better if we combined our
power and found a way out of this dungeon?
Oh, if it's about getting out of this place...
That guy should know a way.
Huh?
If this was actually your first time coming here,
and didn't know you needed to find one more character...
You wouldn't have had any reason to hide
that stone mirror so preciously, would you?
Sutou Unzou (40)
Treasure Hunter
Yeah, yeah...
Just follow me.
But this sure is a huge mansion!
The basement is unexpectedly large.
Huh? The floor is wet.
Yes...
Where is that water coming from?
There, it's from over there!
What's this? It looks like it cracked...
Yes, now that you mention it...
There was an earthquake a few days ago.
It caused the mansion to shift a bit, and
made some water start flooding the basement.
Senju Eri(72)
Treasure Hunter
That exactly what Kichiemon-san said!
Don't you think that was caused
by "the wrath of the Two Kings"?
That's why you should stop looking for
the treasure and quickly get back home!
Say, the notebook that the guy who
drowned in the sunk in the lake was carrying...
It dried off, so I was able to read what he wrote in it...
But it seems like that guy really was killed by his partner.
"Regretfully, I teamed up with someone awful.
If I don't hide this stone I found, I know they'll kill me."
"This little rat said they want to kill me so he
can find the treasure and keep it all for their self..."
Looks like there was more after that,
but the page got torn, so I can't read it.
Woah!
Awesome!
Way awesome!
Hot water... Is this a hot spring?
Yeah.
Kichiemon probably dug it himself...
In order to hide the exit with this hot water.
I see.
Sure is amazing, though.
Besides that, the hot spring water is red, isn't it?
I wonder if it has a high iron content...
Hey, brat!
That's not the way to the exit.
Brat!
Conan-kun, what are you doing?
Are you okay?
Hey, do you know?
Do you know where the Kusanagi no Tsurugi came from?
Huh?
You guys had to have heard the story before...
In order to save Princess Kushinada...
Amaterasu Oomikami's
younger brother, Susanoo Nomikoto...
Forced the serpent that was holding her
captive to drink alcohol, then exterminated it.
The "Kusanagi no Tsurugi" was
then found inside that serpent's tail...
Sword of the Gathering Clouds Of Heaven
But was originally called the "Ama no Murakomo no Tsurugi".
Could that serpent be the same
one that's in many of the old legends?
Yeah.
The one with eyes as red as rubies...
With a stomach that longs for blood...
The legendary serpent that has one
body with eight heads and eight tails.
Look at this waterfall...
Doesn't it look remarkably similar?
To the Eight-Headed Serpent, that is.
I see...
So if the waterfalls are the snake's necks,
these tributaries are its tails, aren't they?
Then, the sword is in one of these tributaries?
Yeah. And according to the legend,
the sword was found in the center tail.
So the Kusanagi no Tsurugi must be in this tributary.
Don't tell me you intend to dive into the hot water?
Stop, stop...
There's nothing there.
What will you do if it leads to the bottom of the valley?
But since we've come this far,
we wanna see what's over there.
Something is rising.
And the water level is decreasing!
We can walk through the tunnel, now!
I did it!
All right, I'll go first!
Wait, Genta!
Move it!
Hey, Granny!
Damn it...
Oh, that has to be... the Kusanagi no Tsurugi!
As I thought, the old woman is aiming for the treasure too.
But that's a really troublesome trap.
If we get closer to the sword,
we'll be putting weight on the floor around it...
Causing us to get attacked by
blades coming from all four directions.
It looks like we can't pass, can we?
No...
The trap isn't there just to get us.
The blades may come from all four directions...
Conan-kun!
And seemingly cover every part of the room...
But if you find the absolute
perfect timing, you won't get hurt.
Furthermore...
Since there's such a conveniently-placed handle here...
We can simply utilize the blade and
actually have it take you right to the sword!
Wow...
He made it to the other side!
Conan-kun, you're amazing!
What character is it?
What's written on the sword?
Ryuu
Dragon.
R-Ryuu...?
Ryuu.?
Eternity
Flame
Dragon
"Ei", "honoo", and "ryuu"?
As expected from Kichiemon-san!
You'd be in pain for all eternity if you were
burnt by the dragon's flames, wouldn't you?
See? Let's stop looking for the treasure and go back home.
There probably wasn't even a
treasure there in the first place.
What's with her?
Her eyes were gleaming over
the treasure a few minutes ago.
"Wandering person, offer me the Three Imperial Regalia."
Ei... Honoo.. Ryuu.
Ei
Eternity
Honoo
Flame
Ryuu
Dragon
Offer me?
"Me!"
Hey, Conan!
Conan-kun!
Can you get back over here?
Oh, it's that proud, smug-looking face...
You figured something out, didn't you?
Really, Conan-kun?
No...
That's the face of someone who was defeated
and has to go home with their tail between their legs.
Seriously?
Hey, Conan...
Are we really heading back?
Right when we finally found
the Three Imperial Regalia, too...
Are we giving up on finding the diamond?
Yes, the meaning of the characters
engraved on the Regalia: "honoo", "ei", and "ryuu"...
As well as what was written
inside the Japanese stone lantern...
I don't understand a single word of it.
So, I'll take my leave here.
I guess I'll check out this mansion a little more.
We're finally out of there!
It looks like the Professor hasn't come back yet.
Professor?
Actually, the Professor was supposed
to have brought policemen here, but...
Oh? Then, you won't need an old
woman like me to escort you off this mountain.
If you haven't already been cursed by the Two Kings,
you'd better not loiter around and hurry back home.
Anyway, now that all those
people aren't here to get in our way...
Isn't it about time you guided us there?
To the treasure, that is.
What?!
Right, Edogawa-kun?
So you really...
Solved it, didn't you? That coded message!
It was from what was written on
the gravestone in the basement:
"Wandering person, offer me the Three Imperial Regalia."
Note: In kanji "Samizu" can also be read as "Sanzui" becomes a radical for water
which, when attached to another kanji, changes its reading and meaning.
This "me" refers to "Samizu" from Samizu Kichiemon.
It basically means to "attach the sanzui
radical to the kanji of the Three Imperial Regalia".
The three characters we found on the
Three Imperial Regalia were "honoo" and what else?
Eternity
"Ei" from "eien"!
Dragon
And "ryuu", right?!
So if you attach the sanzui, or water radical...
"Honoo" becomes the "awa" from Awajishima Island!
Flame
Awa
Eternity
Swimming
"Ei" is the "ei" in "suiei"!
Waterfall
"Ryuu" is "taki", isn't it?
Dragon
Waterfall
Huh?
Does that mean we can swim
at Aojishima Island's waterfall?
Waterfall
The gravestone had "Wandering person" on it, right?
That was a hint to help those who couldn't
figure out the code on the Japanese stone lantern.
The Japanese stone lantern basically said it's at "the place
closest to the sun, a bustling place where elders gather."
If we take that into account with the three
characters we just found and think about it...
Note: The Japanese word for Mercury is "Suisei".
"Sui" means fresh water, while "sei" means planet.
The closest place to the sun is the
first planet in the solar system, Mercury...
"Elders" means something that has a
beard, which is referring to a "carp".
The bustling place means a place
where the fresh water makes a lot of noise.
So, close to a school of carp that are swimming
around the place where the waterfall is noisiest...
Hides the Two Kings' stone, the diamond!
That's amazing, Conan-kun!
So it's at the waterfall in the basement!
The Eight-Headed Serpent place, right?!
Unfortunately, that's a hot spring, not fresh water.
Couldn't it be in the river inside the house, then?
That's right, a whole bunch of carp were swimming there.
But there wasn't a waterfall around there.
I-I see...
Listen? Don't turn your ears away.
You can hear it, can't you?
The thing that will lead us to the treasure.
That sound.
I see.
It's the lake we saw when we first came here!
Let's go and see!
Look...
That corpse disappeared.
I know.
The culprit must have hid it after we went in the house.
What are you talking about?
"A corpse"?
Can you see something?
Well...
It's very dark, so we can't see if we don't dive in.
It's a shame...
But it looks like someone got here before us, somehow.
A young man.
The lady from earlier.
When did you get here?
Take a look behind the waterfall.
Behind the waterfall?
There's something that looks like a card there.
"I've taken the Two Kings' Stone."
Kaitou Kid?!
No way!
It can't be!
Seriously?
As expected from the great thief from the sky.
Since this was taken by.
someone using the name of "Kaitou"...
This should satisfy Karakuri Kichiemon-san, don't you think?
Granny hadn't gone back home yet...
Jeez.
W-What?
Mitsuhiko-kun!
A-Are you all right?
Let's go, let's go.
It looks like there's nothing else here for us.
There was!
It was covered in mud...
But there really was a
shiny-looking stone at the bottom of the lake!
That's mine!
Hey, don't take it!
Hey!
"The person who does not
fear the wrath of the Two Kings..."
"In order to take possession of the
stone that will fill one's hand to the fullest..."
"You must understand its origin, from long ago."
Its origin, from long ago?
Stop, don't move a muscle.
Who would have thought it was hidden
in the mud at the bottom of a waterfall?
This is a dangerous place, you know...
And I was tricked by that card, so I
guess I didn't search thoroughly enough.
So line up there!
As soon as that guy comes out with the jewel in his hand...
How about I send you guys go down
there with him, to swim with the fishes?
So you've finally made your appearance...
Kaitou Kid.
That lady is...?!
Huh? I'm Kid?
You idiots, I'm...
You're the "little rat" of a treasure hunter who killed
their partner, just to have the treasure all to yourself.
Isn't that right?
Aren't you the one who said it?
When that guy first showed us the stone mirror...
So, the comma-shaped magatama you guys found...
Was engraved with "honoo"
or something like that, wasn't it?
Right?
At that time, I only said I found a
stone from the Three Imperial Regalia.
How did you know beforehand?
That it was the comma-shaped
magatama, and not the sword?
You knew because you had torn a page out of the
notebook of the man we found drowned in the lake.
The page where he drew a comma-shaped
magatama with the "honoo" character inside it.
How do you know what he wrote in it?
He was writing in the notebook with a pencil,
so faint marks would be imprinted on the opposite page.
You're kind of smart...
But you're really careless, boy.
You keep getting ever closer to the muzzle.
Yeah...
But if I didn't...
I wouldn't have been able to aim my
tranquilizer watch straight at you, now would I?
But that really surprised me!
With the lady being Kid and all...
No, Kid is-
I got the Two Kings' Stone!
This isn't good!
Hurry, and put the diamond back where you found it!
What?
Otherwise this water is going to sweep us away,
all the way down to the bottom of the valley!
Oh! Here it is!
This is this mansion!
That diamond was the switch for that big flood gate.
In other words, he didn't have any intention
of letting us take the diamond in the first place.
Yeah, diamonds are known for being harder
than anything else, so they were called "adamasu"...
Which basically meant that they
were "something no one can conquer".
So "understanding its origin" meant that
there's absolutely no way we could take it.
Well, back in his day...
Toba Kanizae-san ordered the seizure of
the Shogunate's assets after its collapse.
Being one of their financial supporters,
Kichiemon thought of this to protect his fortune.
Isn't that why you stopped trying to get it, Granny?
No, the great thief of the sky.
H-He came!
Kaitou Kid!
Great logic, you were right on the mark.
The fact that the mansion's walls were a little
higher than the water leak in the basement path...
That fact that you left your signature card,
even though you didn't take the jewel...
And that there was a person who kept
telling us not to take it, all pointed to one thing...
That Granny was really Kaitou Kid in disguise.
Correct!
But part of the reason I didn't take
it is because I have no interest in it.
That's why you said to stop looking for
the treasure and head back home, isn't it?
But didn't he push me out of the way
so he could hurry and get the sword?
That was to save you, Genta.
Huh?
If you had rushed in and stepped
on the trigger without noticing...
Wouldn't you have been cut into
eight pieces and sent to the other world?
So he was waiting for us in the basement so we
wouldn't do anything that'd get us caught in the traps!
My, my...
What a very heart-warming thief.
I'm very flattered by your compliment, little lady...
Well, you saved my friends, so I'll give
you my thanks and let you go this time...
But one day, I'll definitely catch
you and investigate your true identity.
Right before I rip off that arrogant monocle
of yours and look at your true face, of course.
You'd better not.
Like Pandora's Box, you want to open
it because you don't know what's inside.
But if you know what's inside before you open it...
It's boring, isn't it?
Idiot, knowing the facts before exposing someone...
ls the job of a detective.
Before I knew it, I had come to the riverside of memories.
Imagining a continuation of yesterday's dream...
You seemed so grown-up when you were a boy...
I couldn't say goodbye, so I hid under my umbrella.
If we ever meet again, just please remember
all those times, and don't forget me.
My love and affection are things that will never change.
You are my one and only love, and that's how it will always be.
Like many people, I reminisce while holding on to my feelings.
So l can keep the memory of us meeting from fading away.
So, what do we do now?
That's right...
I put the jewel back where I found it,
so it seems the water level is decreasing.
Looks like we have no other choice
but to wait for someone to find us.
That's right! What about the Professor?
Hold on to the tree as tight as you can!
The victim was the owner of this room,
Ozawa Fumie-san, 24 years old.
She was a secretary who worked for a trading company.
She put it on vibrate? Even when she's in her house?
It's either Madam or Shimizu-san, but which one?
Ah-le-le?
Uncle, whatever could this be?
Next Conan: Spicy, Bitter & Sweet Soup.
Next Conan's Hint!
Powder.
Please look forward to the next episode!
Guys, what are you doing for Golden Week?
Of course...
We're going...
To the movies!
Strategy Above The Depths!