"Star" is a fascinating word.
It can refer to both culprits and actors!
Today's case has a different taste.
We'll be solving three different-flavored tricks...
And savoring the pleasing feeling of solving a mystery!
Seeing through to the one and only truth...
I look like a child, but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan.
Yes, we felt the same light the moment we met.
Yes, lots and lots of the same emotions filled our eyes.
Although the signals you sent destroyed my theory...
These feelings were always beyond your reach
So, let's fight, go against our morals...
And aim for a wider world!
Oh, glimmering star, shine over us forever.
This way, we won't lose the dreams we had when we were young...
I don't care if this town changes someday.
The only thing I don't want to change is you.
Oh, glimmering star, shine over us forever.
This way, we won't lose the dreams we had when we were young...
The only thing I don't want to change is you.
What kind of problem could you have to sigh about?
No, I was just wondering if
Ran-neechan is doing okay in her karate match.
Of course she's doing fine!
She practiced all day yesterday, on top of going to bed early.
She's in great shape!
Yeah, you're right...
Huh?
What's going on?
Like I've been telling you all along...
Isn't that the lady from the
Yuuzuki Japanese-style confection shop?
The police officer must be Kinoshita-san.
Um, is there a problem?
Ah, Mouri-san, you came at a great time.
Please listen to this, Mouri-san.
Mouri-san, we have a problem!
Ah...
W-Wait a second.
I have a bad feeling about this...
Spicy, Bitter & Sweet Soup!
In other words, what both of you are trying to say is...
Aikawa Etsuko (58)
"Yuuzuki" Japanese-style Confection Shop Owner
Is that you, Madam, saw a man run out
of the first-floor apartment, number 1055.
You just said you saw this occur two hours ago...
That means it was about 9:00 AM.
And that was when you came to
take her statement, Kinoshita-san?
Yes.
Then Kinoshita-san found the body of
the room's owner, Ozawa Fumie-san...
And concluded it was a suicide.
It can't be a suicide!
But, Madam!
But you see, I saw the crime scene with my own eyes.
She had a will, and there wasn't
any sign of a struggle in her room.
But...
Besides, there aren't any other
witnesses for that mysterious person you saw.
But I'm sure I saw him with my own eyes.
Come on!
Please tell him to check more thoroughly, Mouri-san!
What?
Now, now...
And what makes you think it was suicide?
Just to be sure, I asked a medical
examiner to come investigate that.
Judging by the amount of rigor mortis that
has set in, we estimate her time of death to be...
6:00 to 8:00 PM last night.
If the suspicious person killed him like this woman says...
He would have had to remain in the victim's room for...
13 hours after he killed her, without
touching anything so it would look like a suicide.
If you think about it logically, that's unthinkable.
You guys can't get your nose out of your notepads...
So let's have Mouri-san decide the cause of death.
Mouri-san, I'm begging you!
Well, I...
This is so troubling...
Your face doesn't look the least bit troubled to me.
Kinoshita-san!
That's the man I saw!
I'm sure of it!
Ah, please don't touch it.
B-But...
The victim was...
The owner of this room,
Ozawa Fumie-san, 24 years old.
She was a secretary who worked for a trading company.
When I discovered her body...
I noticed she had tied a wire to the
shower head and wrapped it around her neck.
It looked like she was leaning
against the wall while sitting down.
It's a pretty unusual place for a suicide.
Mouri-san, please take a look at this.
She wrote her will on her laptop computer.
"To the one I'm loaning to, Shimizu-sama..."
"I know how much I've troubled you,
so I will repent for my sin by dying."
The contents of the will say...
That she spent over 30 million
yen of her company's money...
And wanted to repent by killing herself.
It appears the will was written to her superior.
Embezzlement, huh?
She sent it via e-mail at 5:45 PM yesterday.
We believe she killed herself shortly after that.
Go meddle around somewhere else!
She put it on vibrate? Even when she's in her house?
I've come to the conclusion that it's
a suicide, just as Kinoshita-san says.
Please take a look at the calendar.
Isn't there a dentist appointment on it?
C-Calendar?
It's true that it says she had a
dentist appointment scheduled for today...
But Madam, you must have really good eyesight...
Since you were able to read this from all the way over there.
Yeah... I guess so.
If she planned her suicide this precisely,
even preparing the wires to hang herself...
Would she really have scheduled a
dentist appointment the same day?
But, wait...
Kinoshita-san, could this really be possible?
As I thought, this is a murder
committed by the man in that picture, isn't it?
Well, I'm not sure about that.
Kinoshita-san, was the house
unlocked when you first arrived here?
Yes, the house was unlocked.
Then, that means...
She committed suicide without locking the door?
No...
Someone committing a well-planned suicide
wouldn't want to be found before they died.
The picture by the front door must
have been taken out of this photo album.
H-Hey!
Hey, Uncle...
Huh?
The lady who died must have
been close to the man in this picture...
I wonder why she didn't address her will to him.
Ah, le le?
Uncle, whatever could this be?
It's some white powder or something.
Ouch!
I think it's a powder that
doesn't smell, feels silky, and is edible.
Note: Katakuri starch is an ingredient made from the stems of katakuri lilies.
It's used a thickener, but has the sweetness of powdered/confectioner's sugar.
This is probably katakuri starch.
What else can you do with
katakuri starch besides using it in cooking?
Let me think...
You can use it on sweets.
Note: A daifuku is a Japanese confection consisting of a
small, round mochi (rice cake) stuffed with sweet filling.
You know the powder that daifuku are coated with?
That's katakuri starch.
Inspector, the company that Ozawa-san was working for...
Reported that it has 30 million yen deficit...
And that the victim's superior,
Shimizu-san, took a day off today.
So he doesn't know that Ozawa-san committed suicide yet.
Also, we discovered something unexpected.
The man holding the cooler box
is the one who got the e-mail...
And is also her superior, Shimizu-san.
So the supervisor was her lover?
It seems that none of the
employees knew they were dating.
And it seems that Shimizu-san enjoys
gambling and making hefty investments.
Inspector, doesn't something smell fishy to you?
Excuse me, Inspector.
That's him!
He's the one who ran out of the room!
You better explain what happened!
What are you talking about?
I'm sorry, but who are you?
Move away! Don't bother him.
It's this guy! It'd him!
Inspector, this is Shimizu-san.
He was resting at his house, and we asked him to come.
We'll get right down to it.
You knew that one of your subordinates, Ozawa-san...
Embezzled 30 million yen out of your company.
Is that true?
Shimizu Ryota (30)
Chief Executive of a Consumer Loan Company
No, I only found out from the police officers earlier.
I was shocked.
Weren't you Ozawa Fumie-san's lover?
I would think that you'd discuss
things like that with each other.
Lovers?
Oh, that picture the police officers asked me about?
That was when Ozawa-kun wanted to go on a fishing trip.
So I took her to the best spot I knew about.
Where were you today at 9:00 AM?
What do you mean?
There is a witness who saw you run out of this room.
Saw me?
Don't pretend you don't know! I saw you with my own eyes!
I'm going to ask you bluntly.
Did you break into this room at 9:00 AM
this morning, and murder Ozawa Fumie-san?
You think I used Ozawa-san...
Stole the money that she loaned...
And then killed her?
Yes, you took advantage of her
until you got everything you desired...
And then...
Wait a minute. It can't be me.
I was attending my elementary school
class reunion for the entire day yesterday.
At around 9:00 AM this morning...
I was at at the airport, waiting for my
plane which departed for Haneda at 10:00 AM.
Here's my ticket for it.
Then, where were you between
6:00 PM and 8:00 PM yesterday?
Like I said, I was in the middle of my reunion...
Here's the organizer's business card.
We'll have to hold on to this.
Yeah, go ahead.
Please check it.
Yes, sir!
Shimizu-san has an alibi...
But the lady said she's sure it was him who ran out.
If it wasn't suicide...
6:00 PM-
Dentist
Appointment
May Day
Constitution
Memorial Day
Mother's day
What did they say?
Everything the man said was a lie, wasn't it?
It was just like Shimizu-san said.
Both the class reunion organizer...
And the airline confirmed it.
Oh! Maybe she just mistook Shimizu-san for somebody else.
But she was able to read what
the calendar said from far away...
So she must have good eyesight, right?
Then, maybe she wanted to frame Shimizu-san?
But for what reason...?
I have no idea!
By the way, what happened to Horita-kun?
A deliveryman said he saw something...
So he's questioning him at the entrance.
Well, it seems like my alibi has been confirmed...
So I'll be leaving now.
You can't!
You can't let this man go, he committed a murder!
Madam...
What a bothersome person.
Do you have a grudge against me or something?
Do you have any proof that I'm the culprit?
Yes, I do.
I've known her since she was very little.
She treated me like her mother, and told me everything.
She told me how she was dating someone named Shimizu...
And that he told her to loan
out a lot of the company's money.
She confessed everything to me!
What on earth are you talking about?
Please, stop!
It really tickles me when it's on vibrate.
Yes? This is Mouri.
Medical examiner?
About what I requested?
There wasn't anything wrong
with Ozawa fumie-san's teeth?
But she had a dentist appointment, and...
Yes, thank you very much.
There was nothing wrong with her,
but had an appointment for the dentist, huh?
Excuse me, this might be unnecessary...
But isn't the handwriting on the
calendar different from Ozawa-san's?
As her superior, I see her handwriting often.
Ah, we're going to need expert to analyze them further...
Appointment
at Yamada
Internal
Medicine
Appointment
at Izumi
Dermatology
But the two handwriting styles do appear to be different.
Whose handwriting is on the calendar, then?
From what I heard, this woman was
the first to discover the body, right?
Oh, now I get it!
The true culprit is often the first to arrive at the crime scene.
It sure is sad that Madam is the culprit, though...
What do you mean, Mouri-kun?
Madam wanted to frame Shimizu-san as the culprit.
That's why she wrote that Fumie-san
had scheduled a dentist appointment.
That's also why the picture was in the
entryway instead of its usual spot in the photo album.
Madam, just to be sure, could you please write "dentist"?
Are you sure it was that woman over there?
Yes, I'm absolutely positive.
She hid it in here.
Inspector.
What is it?
What's this?
What?
Madam...
You entered this room around 9:00 AM today, didn't you?
No.
There's a delivery man outside who
says he saw you come out of this room.
Also, he said you were in a hurry,
which caused you to bump into him.
This is 5 million yen.
How did you get all this money?
And why did you hide it in the gas meter box?
Do you mind explaining?
I brought the money with me from my house.
I hid the money in there
because I found Fumie-chan's body...
And I was worried I might drop it
on my way to report it to the police...
That's the only reason.
So you really were in this room before, weren't you?
No, I wasn't!
You must have killed Ozawa-san,
and then tried to frame me as the culprit!
What are you talking about?!
Mouri-san, please don't believe what he's saying.
No...
This is troubling...
A lie.
One of them is lying.
One of them is the culprit.
This is...
A fish scale?
Why would one be here?
Could it be...
That's it!
So that's what happened!
Dentist
I wrote the fake appointment.
I also put the photo in front of the door.
Was it to frame Shimizu-san for your crime?
No, that's not it!
I knew Shimizu was the criminal,
and wanted to have him arrested.
I came here this morning...
To be with Fumie-chan when she
confessed about the money she had embezzled.
I also thought that if she
returned what was left of the money...
She might get a lighter sentence,
so I brought the money with me.
I saw Fumie-chan's dead body,
and my instincts told me right away...
That Shimizu was the one who had done that to her.
Because she told me she would tell
the police everything she had done.
But there wasn't anything in this
room that would get Shimizu-san arrested.
So you decided to put his picture in
the entryway, close to the front door...
6:00 PM-
Dentist
Appointment
May Day
Constitution
Memorial Day
Mother's day
And wrote that false appointment on the calendar.
The culprit is that man right there, Shimizu!
But Madam, that's just your assumption.
We have to take it with a grain of salt...
Since Shimizu-san has an airtight alibi.
I'm interested in hearing how you
came into possession of that 5 million yen...
So would you please come with me to the police station?
Mouri-san, sorry to keep you waiting.
This is the iceman, Inoue-san.
The iceman? What are you talking about?
You're such a jokester...
Just like you thought, Mouri-san...
That man really did buy ice from him.
Sato-kun, Korita-kun...
For the time being, take her down to the police
station, and we can listen to what she has to say there.
Yes, sir!
Please hold off on doing that, Inspector.
Eh, what is it?
Oh! Mouri-kun!
It finally started!
Please release that woman immediately.
The one who needs to be taken to the police station...
Is you, Shimizu-san.
Why do I need to go to the police station?
Inoue-san, when did this man come to buy ice from you?
Yesterday afternoon...
He bought four packs of ice.
About 15 kilograms worth.
I remember him distinctly,
since he had a big cooler box prepared.
Then, during this season...
About how long does it take ice to melt?
At room temperature, probably about half a day.
Thanks for helping out, even though
this is the busiest time of the year for you.
O-Oh, no problem.
Thank you for cooperating.
Officer Sato...
If you look underneath the
bathtub cover, you'll find a fish scale.
Please remove the wires from it and bring it here.
A fish scale in the bathroom?
Shimizu-san...
Around yesterday at noon...
You most likely gave Ozawa-san
a sleeping pill to put her sleep...
And then carried her over to the bathtub.
You then made her sit on a chair you had put
together using the bathtub cover and the block of ice.
As the ice melted, the seat got lower,
causing the wires around her neck to tighten.
By the time of her death, from 6:00 PM to 8:00 PM...
The ice would have been less than half of its original size.
So, by the time Madam found her...
The ice had completely melted...
And the water evaporated, leaving the floor completely dry.
The scale we found on the bathtub cover...
Must have been from the cooler
box you used to carry the ice in.
Like I've been saying...
You still don't have any definitive evidence that I killed her.
And did you forget?
Ozawa-san sent me an e-mail at 5:45 PM!
How could someone send me an e-mail if they
had already been drugged and strangled with wires?
Conan, put Ozawa-san's cell phone
in the open space on the bookshelf...
And have half of it leaning over the side of the shelf.
Okay!
Huh?
The cellphone is on vibrate right now.
Officer Sato...
Please call Ozawa-san's cellphone.
All right.
If you look at the cellphone's call log...
There should be a record of a call just before 5:45 PM.
No, there's no way I could've done it...
Since I was in Hiroshima.
You don't know when to give up.
Officer Sato, please take a close look at the wires.
There are strands of hair stuck in them, right?
Is there any other hair besides Ozawa-san's?
There is.
There's a single strand of straight, black hair.
Shimizu-san...
When you carried Ozawa-san to the bathroom...
You didn't notice that some of your hair fell off onto hers.
And you know, if we analyzed it...
Shimizu-san.
We could find out who it belongs to right away.
I'm sorry.
I couldn't let her waste the rest of her life in jail.
So, before she could confess to the police...
I...
Note: "Sweet soup" is a Japanese expression
meaning "to make good out what one has."
You had your taste of sweet soup...
Note: Megure makes it intro a pun by using
"bitter soup" to represent "having hard times."
And now, you'll be getting the bitter soup you deserve.
Before I knew it, I had come to the riverside of memories.
Imagining a continuation of yesterday's dream...
You seemed so grown-up when you were a boy...
I couldn't say goodbye, so I hid under my umbrella.
If we ever meet again, just please remember
all those times, and don't forget me.
My love and affection are things that will never change.
You are my one and only love, and that's how it will always be.
Like many people, I reminisce while holding on to my feelings.
So I can keep the memory of us meeting from fading away.
Wow, that really was incredible.
Mouri-san, Inspector Megure said
that move was a stroke of genius!
You pretended you didn't think it was
Shimizu, so he would fall right into your trap.
Note: This is an old Japanese expression meaning
"To trick someone, you first need to pretend to be tricked."
It's often said that, to taste sweetness...
You first need to taste something salty.
Note: Japanese men simply can't tolerate eating sweets,
which is why Mouri gags when eating one.
Do you need to eat something salty too?
They sure are ringing a long time...
It's that case from 12 years ago.
There was one, 12 years ago.
A case where the same method
as in our current case was used.
Doesn't that mean it's from Ran?
So, could that mean that...
Could that mean that...
This isn't good!
Next Conan: The Weird Family's Request, Part 1.
Next Conan's Hint!
Cell phone's lock.
Please look forward to the next episode!
Hey, where's Officer Takagi?
He's not here because the title is "Sweet Soup."
Sato-kun...
Eh?