"Star" is a fascinating word.
It can refer to both culprits and actors!
A cell phone with a secret...
Along with a lot of e-mails, conversations, and tricks...
Lead to one nearly-impossible case!
Seeing through to the one and only truth...
I look like a child, but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
Yes, we felt the same light the moment we met.
Yes, lots and lots of the same emotions filled our eyes.
Although the signals you sent destroyed my theory...
These feelings were always beyond your reach
So, let's fight, go against our morals...
And aim for a wider world!
Oh, glimmering star, shine over us forever.
This way, we won't lose the dreams we had when we were young...
I don't care if this town changes someday.
The only thing I don't want to change is you.
Oh, glimmering star, shine over us forever.
This way, we won't lose the dreams we had when we were young...
The only thing I don't want to change is you.
I really shouldn't send them a message just yet...
Guess I should just be patient and wait it out, huh?
After all, a chance to get in contact
with their boss will come sooner or later.
And when it does, I'll definitely...
Conan-kun!
What?! You're still in your pajamas?
Didn't I tell you to get dressed
since we have to hurry and get going?!
Come on... It's not the time to
play around with your cell phone.
Got it.
Honestly...
Oh, that's right!
I should send Shinichi a message before we head out.
Since he might come back while we're away, and all.
"We're leaving with my dad for his work today."
"So I'll be counting on your advice if
it ends up being a tough case, okay?"
And... send.
Huh?
Is this Conan-kun's?
He just got an e-mail.
Could it be the message I just sent?
There's no way that can be, right?
I definitely sent it to Shinichi's address, after all.
But, the timing was too perfect to just be a coincidence...
The Strange Family's Request:
Part 1!
Did you look inside?
I-I didn't look!
It rang because you got an e-mail...
And I just wondered, "Who could that be from?"
I-It has to be from the Professor.
Oh, I thought so!
It's because I asked him to repair my Detective Badge!
This is from Ran, isn't it?!
So don't tell me she... Don't tell me she...
This is bad!
Jeez!
Do you guys have to tag along with me every single time?
But your client requested that you bring your family, right?
And after all, we might think of something
that will help in your investigation again.
Don't you think so, Ran-neechan?
Exactly...
Like the great deductions a certain shameful
detective who's hiding somewhere always comes up with.
With that panicked behavior of his...
There must be something
suspicious about that e-mail he got earlier.
Shinichi must have ran off somewhere with
someone and didn't want her reading my e-mails...
So he told me I couldn't have his cell number, since
he's always "too busy with a case" to answer my calls.
But in the end, he gave it to Conan-kun!
If Conan-kun is always contacting Shinichi on the phone...
Conan-kun's great deductions...
Even the fact that he
sometimes knows weird things about me...
Everything matches up!
That rotten Shinichi...
I'll never forgive him for
taking advantage of a child like that!
Your cell phone?
Yes, I'd like you to find it.
And if you could somehow find it by the end of the day...
Otherwise, I can no longer stay here.
Kariya Tomoko (39)
Client, and Tsugutaka's Wife
Oh? May I ask why?
To be honest...
What?!
The man you're having an affair with
ls going to send you a e-mail tonight?!
You're the one who should "shush".
If my very jealous husband sees that e-mail...
Or if my strict father or my husband's talkative
brother happen to see it and tell him about it...
So if you call your partner right
away, and ask him not to e-mail you...
Well, about that...
The calls are always coming from
him, and the number is withheld.
Moreover, he has a habit writing me on the
weekend, but he rarely reads the mail I send him.
So I have no means to contact him.
That's a very selfish guy.
But there are some like that..
Egotistical guys, I mean.
Isn't that right, Conan-kun?
Y-You think so?
So when and where did you lose it?
I'm not sure.
I only noticed it was missing the day
before yesterday, some time in the evening.
But I'm sure someone in this
house has it in their possession.
And what makes you think that?
I tried calling my cell phone the moment I lost it...
And someone answered after ten rings,
but quickly hung up without saying a word.
At the time...
I heard the sound of my father's wooden flute being
played rather poorly on the other end of the phone.
Listen, it's that sound.
It certainly is being played poorly.
And my father only plays it in his room.
Since I heard that sound...
It means that my cellphone has
to be some where aim this house.
But each time l tried calling my cell phone
after that, the person hung up without speaking.
In that case, if you ask everyone in the house...
Y-Yes! Of course, I asked them!
But they all pretended to not know.
They're probably waiting for my sin to be exposed.
I'm not very welcomed in this
house and they all want me out.
But if I divorce, I'll have to pay a
lot of money for compensation.
Then, how about contacting your cell-phone
carrier and asking them to cancel your plan?
Even if I did so, the e-mails I kept in
my cell phone memory won't be erased.
Of course, I locked my cell phone
to prevent this kind of situation...
But if I terminate my contract with the carrier,
someone might become suspicious and try to unlock it.
Even so, what can we do...
Oh...
So you're Tomoko-san's friend from middle school?
Yes, I'm Mouri...
No, Mori Goro.
Mori-kun is going to have his house built soon...
And heard good things about this house you built,
Father, so he wanted to visit it for reference.
Oh, is that so? I see.
Kariya Daisaku (68)
Master of the Kariya Household
Well, you're welcome to visit as much as you'd like.
I get it now. That's why she
asked him to come with his family.
Shall I play a song for you on my wooden flute?
No, that won't be necessary...
Will you recognize your ringtone if we call it?
Yes, but it may be on silent, now that I think about it.
Okay, call it!
See, at my age...
It's annoying to often have to go to the toilet.
Excuse me for a moment.
Don't tell me that Father...
I don't think so.
It sounded like our interlocutor
answered the call and hung up right away.
But he didn't seem to be much of a strict person...
He might look like that, but he's actually pretty scary.
12 years ago...
There was this one incident...
And Father is responsible for it.
12... years ago?
Nothing. Let's talk to someone else.
Oh? You're Tomoko-san's classmate?
Might you be her ex-boyfriend, too?
No! That's way off the mark.
Oh? So, you're a novelist?
Kariya Shigehide (37)
Second Son of the Kariya Household
Yeah.
I'm not famous yet...
Note: The book reads "The Rest of Spring, by Kariya Shigehide.
New TV Drama Green-lit! Based on Kariya Shigehide's Renaissance Story of True Love"
But you may hear my name thrown about in
three months time, even if it's just for criticism.
"Kariya Shigehide"?
The author of those romance novels?
So those novels really are going to be adapted for TV?!
Yep.
How surprising! I always pictured you as being a lot older!
So it's going be made into a drama? How great.
Hey, Ran...
Call! Call!
Oh, it's from my publisher.
Hello?
So?
Looks like it's not him. It hung up right away again.
What?
A meeting right now?
I see. So let's meet at the family
restaurant in front of the station.
But you know, the timing with
your father and now this guy...
These coincidences just keep on coming!
Yeah, yeah!
Coincidences do occur often, after all.
Oh? But isn't it called a "coincidence"
because it's not something that normally happens?
I-I guess that's right.
But ma'am, for something like this...
You could investigate on your
own if you had another cell phone.
Are you telling me go through the
extra work to buy another cell phone?
Anyway, I'm not in a position where I can use money freely.
And instead of asking a friend, I asked
you, a pro, in order to protect my secret!
Oh? Your husband is an illustrator?
Yes.
But he doesn't seem to be here.
So this is our chance to do this while he's not here.
See? The string of coincidences
aren't continuing here, are they?
But I think I've seen this painting before.
I see. It was painted by Kariya Tsugutaka
who used to be renowned for his art.
Oh, you know my work?
Who are you three?
Dear, this is...
You're Kariya Tsugutaka?
I imagined someone much younger...
Kariya Tsugutaka (42)
Elders Son of the Kariya Household
As an example, younger are like e-mails...
While I am like a hand-written letter.
I wonder if that's a guest?
Leave it. It's probably the publisher
who came to ask for my latest work.
They sure are ringing a long time.
Huh? It wasn't a guest?
No, there was nobody when we opened.
Does this kind of thing happen a lot?
Every now and then.
The mistress says it's some child playing pranks, but...
But we're stuck, we have nowhere else to look.
Mouri-san, there's no need to worry any longer!
You see, I just found my cell phone.
Huh?!
Thank you for your cooperation.
And of course, I'll wire your fee over to you right away.
That was such a stupid case.
Yep! There are some people like that who
deceive others and laugh about it in the shadows.
They're really stupid.
Ah, um...
Can I sleep at the Professor's house tonight?
Sure... Are you playing games with him again?
Nope!
I have a lot of things I want to
talk about with Conan-kun today!
Then, how about if I just spend the evening there?
He did repair my Detective Badge, after all...
Oh, Shinichi!
What brings you here at this time of night?
It's beyond all sense!
And it's really bad!
Somehow, Ran suspects that I'm...
At 7:00 PM this evening, the body of a woman
was discovered in a car near the Teimudu River.
Based on articles found at the scene, the
deceased woman was a resident of Haido;
Kariya Tomoko-san, age 39.
The police has confirmed that it was a murder.
If you see anyone suspicious in
the Haido area, please contact...
What?!
The victim is Kariya Tomoko-san.
According to the forensics team, after
having been stabbed in the stomach...
Her head was bludgeoned with a heavy object.
Hit in the head after having been stabbed?
Yes, sir. There's a possibility of
there being more than one culprit.
It's hard to believe that one person carried both
an sharp-edged tool and a blunt weapon, after all.
Wait...
If my memory serves me correctly,
there was a case just like this before.
Her purse and money are nowhere to be
found, so I believe this is a case of robbery-murder.
We can't affirm that yet, Takagi-kun.
M-Mouri-san?
Come now, this is police work.
Outsiders shouldn't interfere, so please move along.
Not at all, Inspector...
I'm an insider par excellence.
Actually, that mistress asked for my services.
Huh?
What? The mistress was unfaithful?
No way!
Unfortunately, it seems that was the case.
So her partner killed her?
No, we don't know that yet.
Do you have any idea of who that person might be?
Now that I think of it... A suspicious-looking
mustached man came here today with his children.
That's right! I believe his name was
"Mori Goro" or something like that.
Mori Goro?
Ah, well... About that...
It's that guy!
How dare you do that to the mistress!
Like I was saying, it's not me...
Oh, Mouri Kogoro? The famous detective?
Yes, I had to conceal my name for various reasons.
So have you already arrested him?
The culprit who killed Tomoko-san, that is.
N-No, not yet.
Sorry to disturb you, but can you tell
me where you were at 7:30 this evening?
Oh, me? I remained here the whole time.
Right, Nakamura-san?
Yes.
He had been playing his wooden flute from
7:00 PM to around 8:00 PM, when you arrived.
The only time the sound stopped was
when I came to bring his dinner around 7:30 PM.
And it was just for a few minutes.
Did you see him at that time?
No, in order to not disturb him when he was playing
his flute, I simply placed his dinner in front of the room.
But he must have smelled tonight's
curry-rice through the paper-thin door.
We're having curry-rice today, huh?
Haven't had that for a while!
Huh? Around 7:30?
I was right here.
I came back from my appointment at 6:00 PM,
and have been working here ever since.
I'm pretty sure those two can confirm that for you.
Is that so?
Yes, indeed.
He turned the room's lights on around 6:30 PM, and we saw
his shadow casting across the paper-thin door ever since.
Even when I brought him his dinner...
So you didn't see him directly?
Yes. He always tells us to not come in while he's working.
Anyway, is it true that Tomoko-san got murdered?
Yes, that's why we're investigating now.
In that case, I hope you can hurry up,
close the book on this case, and leave.
I can't concentrate on my work with you
loitering in the corridor or asking me all these questions.
I'm amazed... Is that really
something to say with what just happened?
So now we're down to the last
remaining resident of this house...
And that would be Tomoko-san's husband, correct?
Yes.
Oh? He didn't even touch his dinner.
Please answer my questions, Tsugutaka-san.
What's happening?
He's refusing to tell us anything.
Even if you're asking me if I have any
ideas, I can't speak on what I don't know.
My wife and I generally don't speak to each other.
It seems you didn't even touch your dinner...
Are you feeling ill or something?
No, I was just immersed in my work and forgot about it.
So you didn't talk to him when you brought it?
Well, no...
But I think he was in his room.
I could smell the sweet scent from his pipe.
Well, you got what you want?
If you have nothing else, please leave.
His wife just got murdered,
and he's thinking about his work...
Anyway, those three have an alibi.
Yes. It takes 20 minutes to drive here from the crime scene.
So it's impossible for them to have committed the crime.
This means it comes down to her
partner being the main suspect, doesn't it?
But we don't know who he is or where he could be.
Should we try asking Tomoko-san's
friends to follow the trail back to him?
Hello?
Yes, this is the Kariya residence.
Um... A call for Madam Tomoko.
Hurry the hell up and put Tomoko on!
She didn't reply to my e-mail!
This is the police. What's your
relationship with Tomoko-san?
I see...
I see.
Yes...
Yes.
It's not him.
It seems her partner is working
at a bar in Hokkaido right now.
Tomoko-san didn't answer the e-mails and
voice messages he left on her cell phone...
So he got mad and decided to call her home number.
Then, he didn't know about the case?
But Inspector, it's only one or two
hours from here to Hokkaido by plane.
If he caught a flight
immediately after committing the crime...
No, there were colleagues there with him.
It seems they started to drink at 8:00 PM.
So he couldn't have perpetrated the murder, huh?
In that case, who on earth could have?
Anyway, it's a peculiar household.
All three of them eat their
meals separately in their own rooms.
Yes.
But everyone ate their meals together as
a family until what happened 12 years ago.
12 years ago?
Yes.
They would always eat together when
their third son, Eisuke-sama, was still here.
That's right.
Eisuke?
Kariya Eisuke...?
That's it! I remember now!
It's that case from 12 years ago!
Inspector?
There was one, 12 years ago...
A case with very similar circumstances to our current case.
The victim was Eisuke-san's fiancée, Aida Motoka-san.
Just like Tomoko-san, she was
bludgeoned to death after having been stabbed.
Eisuke-san originally was under suspect
because we couldn't find him.
However, since we found a large pool
of his blood next to the phone booth...
And all the money in his bank
account was withdrawn just after the crime...
We concluded someone had kidnapped Eisuke-san,
and murdered him once they got his money.
However, the crime scene was a
rather infrequently visited place...
So the investigation ended due to a lack of witnesses.
Now that I recall, we got a call
from Eisuke-sama's friend last night.
Was it for Eisuke-san?
No.
It was for Madam Tomoko.
It seems Eisuke-sama, his friend, and Madam
Tomoko were in the same theater circle in college.
When she answered the call, the mistress was very nervous.
Don't call me! And don't say weird things!
I smell something fishy.
Do you know this person's phone number?
I see. Okay.
If anything comes up, we're counting on you.
So?
It's not him either. He has a perfect alibi.
It seems he got a speechless call last night, and saw it
was Tomoko-san's cell phone number in the call history.
He tried to call her back on her cell phone numerous times...
But couldn't get in contact with
her, so he tried on the land line.
That sure is strange.
The mistress' phone should have been
locked since she lost it the day before yesterday.
Could it be that the person with her cell
phone unlocked it, then used it to call this friend?
If that's true, then that could be a motive for the murder.
A lot of e-mails from the partner she was in an
affair with were stored in the phone's memory, after all.
In other words, that person is the culprit.
But you found her cell phone
soon after you arrived here, right?
Ah, no. She found it herself.
And unfortunately, I didn't ask her where she found it.
Now, Conan-kun. You gathered all the information.
You're going to call Shinichi, aren't you?
Call him!
That's right.
And when you call him, I'll take the phone and I'll...
I'll talk to him directly.
That's impossible!
He definitely couldn't have done that.
Huh?
What are you talking about?
Well, you know that the combination on a
cell phone's lock is a four-digit number, right?
From 0000 to 9999, there are 10,000 different combinations.
Even I couldn't try them all.
Well, if I had a ton of free time, and was an invisible
man that no one could see, that'd be a different story.
Invisible man?
Indeed, even if it only took them 3
seconds per number, it'd take 30,000 seconds.
Eight hours.
Any normal person would have given up.
Which means the person who unlocked it
wasn't disturbed by anyone for quite some time.
In other words, it's one of those three who
were confined to their rooms the whole time.
In my daily life, where I could see no tomorrow...
I'm glad that I fell in love with you.
I never want these feelings to change...
So stop time, and preserve the present that echoes throughout my heart.
I was once afraid to be together with you.
But although I can't change others or the past...
I can change myself and my dreams for the future.
You're the only one I see...
As sorrow piles up in the darkening city.
Forever in a soft, warm breeze...
We 'll be together, believing in each other.
June Bride, I'll be with you.
I'll send that mail one more time...
And I'll catch you this time for sure.
So whose pipe could that have been?
Are you saying there's a double of me?
A double?
Ever since you police came to this house, I haven't been able
to concentrate and haven't finished writing a single line!
So, I can only think of one other possible explanation...
Conan-kun is actually... Shinichi!
Next Conan: The Strange Family's Request, Part 2.
Next Conan's Hint!
The case from 12 years ago.
Please look forward to the next episode!
The new ending theme is "June Bride"!
It's like our special song, isn't it?
You do realize that Sato isn't here, right?
I-I know that!