"Star" is a fascinating word.
It can refer to both culprits and actors!
Sight, hearing and smell...
All of their alibis relied on these three senses.
The hint that breaks them apart lies in a past case!
Seeing through to the one and only truth...
I look like a child, but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
Yes, we felt the same light the moment we met.
Yes, lots and lots of the same emotions filled our eyes.
Although the signals you sent destroyed my theory...
These feelings were always beyond your reach
So, let's fight, go against our morals...
And aim for a wider world!
Oh, glimmering star, shine over us forever.
This way, we won't lose the dreams we had when we were young...
I don't care if this town changes someday.
The only thing I don't want to change is you.
Oh, glimmering star, shine over us forever.
This way, we won't lose the dreams we had when we were young...
The only thing I don't want to change is you.
The Strange Family's Request:
Part 2!
So the suspects are...
Kariya Daisaku (68)
Master of the Household
The master of the house, who was confined to his
room while playing a wooden flute: Daisaku-san...
Kariya Tsugutaka (42)
Eldest Son of the Kariya Household
The eldest son who was drawing an
illustration in his room: Tsugutaka-san...
And the second son, who was
writing a novel: Shigehide-san...
Kariya Shigehide (37)
Second Son of the Kariya Household
Just those three.
No.
All the deductions made up to this
point stemmed from Conan-kun's guidance.
By saying things that would
ordinarily be pointed out by a child...
He's making it seem like the
Hints he leaves are just coincidences.
However, even he would be able to do that if
he was getting Shinichi's deductions secretly...
But he didn't make any calls when
he came across something just now.
So, I can only think of one other possible explanation...
This child is...
Conan-kun is actually... Shinichi!
So that's why the calls I get from Shinichi
are always listed as an anonymous number!
It's so I can't call him!
But they were both together during the school festival...
Am I overthinking things after all?
No, I can't fall for it!
This is Shinichi, I'm talking about!
He must have used some kind of trick!
What's wrong, Ran-neechan?
Oh, nothing.
A-Ah, I see...
I've got to make sure.
Come to think of it, just after I sent that e-mail to Shinichi...
Conan-kun's cell phone rang.
I'll send that mail one more time...
Arid I'll catch you this time for sure.
This time, you definitely won't be able to weasel out of it!
Because I'll have the perfect evidence!
No way!
It's not ringing.
A guest?
Were you expecting someone to be coming by?
No, not at all.
It says my message was re-sent, so was
what happened this morning just a coincidence?
Of course it was. Conan-kun couldn't be Shinichi, could he?
No, I'm up against that conniving Shinichi...
He might be using some kind of method
that a regular person like me wouldn't consider.
If you're going to play this game with me...
Then I'm not letting you out of my sight one second until
you slip up and do something that reveals your identity.
You better prepare yourself, Shinichi!
Oh? Is this another one of those pranks?
Huh? A prank?
There are times when the doorbell rings, but nobody's here.
But it's especially terrible today,
what with all the times it's been rung.
It normally only happens a couple of times a week.
A child playing a prank at this time of night?
It seems to me that someone among those three
found a way to ring the doorbell from their room...
And built their alibi during the time
the housekeepers went to the entryway.
It's true that their three alibis...
Rely on these women stating
that the three were in their rooms...
When they placed dinner in front of
their doors at 7:30 PM, the time of the crime.
However, they never saw them face to face.
In that case, the most suspicious is the
late Tomoko-san's husband, Tsugutaka-san.
If we assume he saw the e-mails about her affair
that were stored in her cell phone, we have his motive.
No, if anyone knew the mistress was having an affair...
I don't think the master would have kept quiet about it.
Why do you think so?
When Motoka-san, the fiancée of their third son, Eisuke-sama,
was found murdered in a phone booth 12 years ago...
She had actually been in the middle of a date with him.
At first, Eisuke-sama called...
Asking if Motoka-san could sleep at our
house, since she had missed the last train.
The master, who was in the living room
at the time, told me to let him speak to Motoka-san.
Keep in mind that if a filthy woman like you becomes
a member of our Kariya family, you'll lose your life!
Motoka-san was unfaithful?
We don't know where the master got that information...
But while she and Eisuke-sama were stuck
there with no place to go, they were assaulted.
Did you inform the police of that?
We only told them about the call.
Since it was not related to the incident, the second son,
Shigehide-sama told us to keep quiet about the affair.
So the only one who wouldn't have a motive
to kill Tomoko-san would be Shigehide-san, huh?
About that...
I actually heard Madam Tomoko and
Shigehide-sama quarreling in the corridor a month ago.
She said "How rotten of you to eavesdrop on me!"
No matter what, it was always about the main character's
parents in the novel that's being adapted into a TV drama.
She was saying that their conversation in the
drama was just lifted from her own conversation...
So Madam Tomoko stated that she would sue him if he
doesn't change the lines before the drama was completed.
She was really threatening.
In the end, Shigehide-sama
kindly agreed to change the dialogue.
Oh, it's you? ls there something else?
Did you find the culprit?
No, not yet.
By the way, when your dinner
was brought here at 7:30 PM...
We were told that you said "We're having curry-rice today,
huh? Haven't had that for a while!" through the paper door.
How did you know it was curry?
The smell. The paper door was slightly open.
Say, what are you using this for?
This?
I use it to listen to my flute teacher's
performance as a model to practice from everyday.
I can't go outside, so my wooden flute is
the only way I can keep myself entertained.
He never leaves the house since he hurt his leg at work?
Yes, and because he spends the entire day at home...
He found out his wife was having an affair, so they divorced.
I see. That's why he was much
stricter about infidelity than most people.
Curry-rice was his wife's specialty.
And that's why you don't make it very often?
You're minding the master's feelings.
Yes. Tonight's meal was originally going to be beef stew...
But ten minutes before we were about to
serve it, we were suddenly asked to make curry.
Come on! Can you give me a break already?!
Didn't I already tell you that I was in this room at 7:30 PM?!
You only moved your hand to show your
thanks when your"meal was brought here.
So she didn't see you directly; she only
saw your shadow through the paper door.
Are you implying that I used some kind of
trick to project my shadow on the paper door?
Well, no...
I don't think that's possible.
After all, I'm pretty sure l can
tell if it's a person's shadow or not.
Is that so?
So if you have nothing else to ask, get out!
Ever since you police came to this house, I haven't been able
to concentrate and haven't finished writing a single line!
A relative just passed away,
and he's not shedding a single tear...
Is he really a romance novelist?
It sure doesn't seem like it, does it?
Speaking of which, didn't you say
something like that when you first met him?
Hey, Ran?
Huh? W-What?
Didn't you say that you always thought he was older?
Oh, yeah... That's because Shigehide-san rarely
has people with brown-dyed hair in his novels...
And even when he does, it always seems to
be a bad person with little to no significance.
That's why I thought he was an elderly man.
Also, when the main characters make it to
the place where they are to meet each other...
They lean against a pillar and still can't see each other.
It's like a scene in an old movie.
They rarely get to meet, so their feelings are
very melancholic as they worry about each other.
It's completely different from a certain someone
who's living with his companion, secretly looking over her!
Right, Conan-kun? Don't you think so, too?
I-I'm a kid, so I don't really understand.
You think so too, right?
Yes.
You sure are exasperating.
I've been here the whole time,
so I can't tell you anything new.
However, the scent of the pipe that was
floating in the air when your meal was brought here...
Can't be considered valid proof of your alibi.
So whose pipe could that have been?
Are you saying there's a double of me?
A double?
You ate your curry?
Yes.
More importantly, did someone else show up again?
The doorbell was ringing earlier.
No. It seems it was another prank.
These pranks have been making Tsugutaka-sama very angry.
For example, when he's comes back from a outing...
He always asks, "Did another one
of those pranks happen again today?"
When we answer yes, he bursts into rage.
Oh, and he also became angry over those phone pranks.
Phone?
Yes. It's a bunch of weird calls
where they ring once, and then hang up.
Then they wait a while, ring, and then hang up again!
There was also one around 8:00 today,
shortly before you police arrived.
Are they anonymous calls?
No. But even though a call came in,
there's nothing in the call history!
Don't tell me that the doorbell earlier was actually...
Hey, Ran-neechan!
W-What?
You sent a e-mail earlier, right?
Huh?
You sent one, didn't you?
Yes, I did. Something wrong with that?
Did you make sure to check the e-mail address?
I don't need to check it if I'm only
re-sending a mail I sent this morning.
What? Whose e-mail address is this?!
Just as I thought.
That's why she was able to find her cell phone so easily.
Which means...
The culprit is that person!
They hid in the dark shadows from 12
years ago, and used them to their advantage...
In order to make themselves be
the only one remaining in the light!
Anyway, how about we stop for today?
Yes, sir.
After all, it doesn't seem like their alibis can
be disproved unless they used a magic trick.
A magic trick?
Oh, that reminds me! I saw a really
neat magic trick on TV the other day!
Huh?
There was a young lady in a vertical box...
Who had her face, hands, and feet sticking out, even
though the box was separated into three different parts!
I was really surprised!
You idiot! There were three people in the box!
Oh, I get it...
Even if something's impossible by yourself, you can
trick people like that when you work together with others!
So, what's your point...
Oh...
If the three of them joined forces, they
could have created a trick for their alibi.
That's impossible!
Their dinners were brought to them at the same time,
not to mention that their rooms are pretty far apart!
Tomoko-san lost her cell phone the day before yesterday...
But for some reason, she found it somewhere in
this house shortly before she was murdered today.
The three who live in this house certainly are suspicious.
Indeed.
Especially since we didn't find
her cell phone at the crime scene.
But Ran-neechan...
Don't you think the person who was secretly
carrying the lost cell phone was really stupid?
Huh?
Remember? When we were looking for it...
Didn't he answer the phone just before
hanging up, every time we called that number?
Of course he did!
If we heard their voice or something,
we would have figured out who they were!
But if it was me, and I knew that
those annoying calls would keep coming...
I would've turned off my phone!
So you really did turn off your phone, Shinichi?!
Are you an idiot?!
He didn't turn the phone off because he was
waiting for a message or call from his lover, Tomoko-san!
In that case, couldn't he have just turned down the volume?
They knew the same person
kept calling and calling, after all.
What if our perp doesn't know how to use a cell phone?
No way! They managed to unlock the phone, you know!
But even if it's locked, all they had to know is
that they heeded to enter four digits to unlock it.
So even if they didn't know how to use one,
it's still possible to unlock it if they had time.
And everyone knows how to use a cell
phone after fiddling around with one for a bit.
It took me a long time until I got used to it.
Oh? But wasn't that way back when
you first bought a cell phone, Inspector?
That's right, there's hardly anyone who
doesn't know how to use a cell phone nowadays...
Except, of course, someone who has been
locked up somewhere for the past 10 years or so.
10 years?
Now that you mention it, cell phone use only
started to become widespread about 10 years ago.
Wait! Wasn't it 12 years ago?
When the third son, Eisuke-san,
disappeared after his fiancée was killed.
So Eisuke-san was the one
who had Tomoko-san's cell phone?
Don't tell me that he's somewhere in this house...
If that's true, then one of those
three must be covering for him.
If he was isolated from the outside world for
12 years and saw a cell phone for the first time...
It's understandable why he would be
interested in it enough to take it with him.
That would explain why those calls to
Eisuke-san's friend came from her cell phone...
And why he had enough time to disable the lock.
But Tomoko-san caught him when
he was putting the cell phone back...
So, to keep her mouth shut, he and the person
covering for him came up with a plan to kill her.
That sure would break down their alibis.
All right, go get me a warrant so we can search this house!
Eisuke-san might be the culprit of the 12-year-old case!
Yes, sir!
Now the problem is how to find
the one who's covering for him...
The master of the house, Daisaku-san, is suspicious...
You know how he had a tape recorder in his room?
He could have recorded himself saying, "We're having curry-rice
today, huh? Haven't had that for a while!" beforehand.
Then, when the curry was brought to him around 7:30 PM...
He had Eisuke-san push the play button to build his alibi.
Aw, this is making me get hungry!
Then, would you like some curry?
There's still some left over.
No, that's okay.
But didn't you originally make beef stew before
you changed it to curry 10 minutes before the meal?
Was it because it seemed like it wasn't very yummy?
10 minutes before the meal?
That would put it around 7:20 PM...
Oh, no. It was nothing like that.
It takes over 20 minutes by car to
get to the crime scene from here...
Even if the crime was executed in less than 10 minutes,
he still would have had to leave before 7:00 PM.
Then, it was Tsugutaka-san who was drawing
an illustration in his room while smoking his pipe!
It would've be easy for him to have Eisuke-san smoke
his pipe enough to spread its scent around the room!
Oh! But since I love curry, maybe I should have some.
Huh?
You see, I love it so much that I was thinking
about eating the curry in front of Mr. Illustrator's room.
Oh, my.
But I didn't do it since everybody would have
found out right away if the plates were gone.
Hold on.
If Tsugutaka-san asked Eisuke-san to
sit in his room and act as his double...
Why didn't he take the curry in the room?
That would have proven he was in the room.
He must have left it out on purpose...
Since he wasn't supposed to be out here.
Even if that's true, Tsugutaka-san would have
noticed it when he came back from the crime scene...
And brought it into his room with him.
Even if he did leave it in front of his room...
It would only deepen our suspicion of him, since it would
prove that he wasn't in his room during the time of the crime.
And Tsugutaka-san actually ate the
curry later on, even though it was cold...
So there's no reason why he wouldn't have brought it in.
Then it comes down to our last suspect,
Shigehide-san, who's writing novels in his room...
I'm the culprit who killed Tomoko-san?
I'm covering for my little brother, Eisuke?
Stop joking around.
But you see, everything fits with this hypothesis.
If you asked Eisuke-san to get the same hairstyle as yours...
Something like answering with a sign
behind the paper door is a simple feat.
Yeah?
Oh, Nishiro Tsubouchi-san?
I'm kind of tied up at the moment.
Yes, I'll call you back.
You're mean, Mister.
Huh?
See? Even though you use a cell phone yourself,
none of the characters in your novels have one!
Why wouldn't they have one?
There's no way you couldn't know
about the existence of cell phones, right?
D-Don't tell me...
You make your younger brother write the novels?!
So that's why not not many of your
characters have their hair dyed brown!
It was still quite rare to see that 12 years ago.
And that means that you really did use a conversation
between Tomoko-san and her husband in your novel!
If there was someone living in the attic of this house,
they could hear every conversation that takes place!
No, about that...
That's enough.
You've done enough.
Brother.
It's you?
That's right. I killed my fiancée 12 years ago
and my older bro's been hiding me here ever since.
I'm Kariya Eisuke.
At that time, when I heard what
my father said over the phone...
Keep in mind that if a filthy woman like you becomes
a member of our Kariya family, you'll lose your life!
We started arguing about that, and I ended
up stabbing Motoka in a sudden burst of rage.
I felt really miserable after that...
But when I returned home all
dazed, my older bro found me.
Brother, it's horrible! I... Motoka...
You'll be fine! I'll figure something out!
So you've been living in the attic ever since.
Yes. I often thought of going to the police
and turning myself in, but I wasn't brave enough.
And I didn't plan on killing her!
So why did you hit her after you stabbed her?
You hit her, right?
No, I only stabbed her!
Huh? So it was you, wasn't it?
You're the one who killed Motoka-san 12 years ago!
W-Wait a minute!
Why would my big bro kill Motoka?
Perhaps Shigehide-san was the man
Motoka-san was having an affair with?
I see.
If the affair took place within the family, even Daisaku-san,
who doesn't leave the house, would have noticed.
Yes. And since Tomoko-san knew
his secret, he shut her mouth as well...
By killing her with the
same method he used 12 years ago...
Everything was set up in order to
frame Eisuke-san with the crime.
That's ridiculous!
I mean, my brother hid me for 12 years to protect me!
No, he only protected you because he knew that he
would have been exposed if you were caught by the police.
Since he bludgeoned Motoka-san in
the head after Eisuke-san stabbed her!
Tell me he's lying, Brother!
Yeah! There's no way I'd ever do such a thing!
By the way, didn't the lady tell us something?
She said the sound her cell phone
makes when a call comes in got changed.
You pest! What about it?!
Unless you're trying to frame me as the culprit...
Then show me proof that I did it!
Another guest?
No, I think that's probably the sound for incoming e-mails.
Remember?
When Tomoko-san was looking for Her cell phone,
wasn't there one time when she went off by herself?
She was carrying my cell phone at the time.
So she must have used it to
send an e-mail to her cell phone...
In order to look for it with this sound!
I see.
No matter what buttons I pushed,
I couldn't get that sound to stop.
I was panicking trying to stop it,
when Tomoko-san showed up in the attic...
However, I did manage to stop
the sound for when a call comes in.
You made the ringtone for incoming calls
the same as the Kariya's landline phone?
I understand now.
If she did that, she'd have a good pretext to drop
what she's doing and get away from the house...
Long enough to answer the calls or
e-mails from the man she was in an affair with.
And since that sound is ringing now...
It proves that somewhere in this room...
We'll find Tomoko-san's cell phone, which
Shigehide-san removed from the crime scene.
He should have just thrown it away.
He probably was afraid, and couldn't toss it out.
He must've needed to make sure she didn't
say anything about how he was hiding his brother.
Well, we'll find out in no time, once we analyze
the fingerprints and blood type on the weapon.
I didn't intend to kill her.
If only she hadn't said that...
Now, where do you think I found this cell phone?
In the hands of your curious younger brother.
What?!
You've been hiding him in the attic, making
him spend all his free time writing novels.
So you can take the credit, and receive
the spotlight as a famous author...
While he spends his life in a miserable place.
Let's see... I'll keep quiet, but first I'll need 10 million yen.
We can take our time talking over
the details somewhere more private.
So that's why you told me to keep
writing while you went out that night.
Yes. And the same thing happened
12 years ago with Motoka, too.
At first, I was worried about how
she was stabbed, so I came to help her.
I was relieved to find that her injuries were minor,
but just I as was about to take her to the hospital...
You're going to take responsibility for this, right?
Responsibility? Are you talking about marriage?
No, you freaking idiot!
How could we get married with that old geezer there?!
I'm talking about money! Money!
I'm going to hound you and siphon off every
last yen you have, so you better prepare yourself!
Brother...
Don't call me Brother...
If you didn't have such a talent for writing novels...
I might have killed you for my advantage, too.
Brother...
But probably didn't do that because I was the
one who wanted keep reading your novels the most.
In my daily life, where I could see no tomorrow...
I'm glad that I fell in love with you.
I never want these feelings to change...
So stop time, and preserve the present that echoes throughout my heart.
I was once afraid to be together with you.
But although I can't change others or the past...
I can change myself and my dreams for the future.
You're the only one I see...
As sorrow piles up in the darkening city.
Forever in a soft, warm breeze...
We 'll be together, believing in each other.
June Bride, I'll be with you.
They sure were a weird family!
As expected from of you, Uncle!
You solved it in the blink of an eye!
Yeah, that's just how it goes for someone like me!
As expected of you, Shinichi.
You've mastered the skill of acting like an
elementary schooler who's slightly smarter than usual.
It's like a large center forward that's
being controlled by a small mid-fielder...
The fantasista who makes the perfect pass leading to a goal.
Note: "Fantasista" is the Italian soccer term for "striker".
But why?
Why are you doing this?
Why won't you tell me?
I'm right next to you, and yet...
Why?
Ah... We're finally home.
Hurry up and get out! I still need to return the car.
Okay!
Ran, you need to hurry, too!
And make sure to heat up the bath water!
So he really has realized!
He's noticed that I have doubts about his true identity.
ii fuufu
11-22... A "nice couple", huh?
Hey...
What number do you think
you'd like if you had one, Shinichi?
If I remember right, back then...
Oh, Shinichi! What on earth did you say?
I can't remember...
There's only one way to find out!
Next Conan: Ran's Suspicions.
Next Conan's Hint!
A car's number.
Please look forward to the next episode!
Next time, we finally make it to the 400th episode!
Conan-kun, this is the start of a
new turning point in the story, isn't it?
Yep.