There's something fascinating about stars,
be they criminals or actors.
Ran's suspicions are stronger than ever.
A password locks the door to the truth.
A battle between love and deductions!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Thanks for the food!
It was great!
It's past midnight, so get to bed.
Okay!
Wait...
W-What is it, Ran-neechan?
Umm, well...
Don't forget to brush your teeth before you go to bed!
Y-Yeah, I know.
Why's he cowering like that?
So he has realized that I suspect his true identity.
Shin'ichi...
Oh no, I think I forgot to lock the office.
Then do it before going to bed.
I'm tired...
Are my suspicions right?
There's only one way to be sure.
I have to go return the car...
Okay.
It's Conan-kun's mobile phone.
If the e-mail I sent to Shin'ichi is on this phone,
then that proves that Conan-kun is Shin'ichi.
As I thought, he turned off his phone so the new e-mail tone wouldn't ring.
But prepare yourself, Shin'ichi!
If I turn it on, I'll finally know if...
But hold on, should I really do this?
If Shin'ichi really is Conan-kun,
how can I face him afterwards?
He's... so cute!
Her chest!
He's been kind of a tease since he was a kid, he's a big mystery nut, and he's pretty full of himself...
but he's also courageous, cool, and dependable!
I really love Shin'ichi!
I can't sleep.
But it was fun, wasn't it?
We washed each other's backs!
Oh, you have a nosebleed?
Maybe you stayed too long in the bath?
I should really just wait for him to tell me himself.
He must have his reasons.
And I really shouldn't be peeping into somebody else's phone...
But if all I'm doing is seeing if my e-mail's there or not...
If that's all I do, then it's fine, right?
Sorry, Shin'ichi!
Eh, really? Should've figured.
Well, for something like this,
most people use their birthday.
DIAL LOCK
INVALID PIN
Though I guess that would be too simple...
There's a total of 10,000 four-digit numbers, so it'd take me 8 hours to try them all.
And I can't think of any other number it'd be...
What if it's my birthday?
No, that's silly, it couldn't be.
No, no. No way!
But it can't hurt to try.
So my birthday is...
But what do I do if it's the right password...?
If it's the right password, I...
INVALID PIN
DIAL LOCK
Oh, I see. It wasn't it.
Then what number is it?!
Tell me!
Okay, Ran, calm down.
Looks like they're both sleeping.
So nobody's going to bother me.
They won't hear anything if I don't make much noise, and I've got plenty of time.
2036...
2037...
2038...
2039...
2040...
2041...
2042...
At this rate, I'll be here until morning!
So I have to guess what number
Shin'ichi would be likely to use...
Let's see...
What are some things he likes...
Holmes.
So then, maybe it's the year when Holmes solved a certain case.
No, that can't be. I just checked every number from 1 to over 2000.
INVALID PIN
Geez, they're so noisy!
yo-ro-shi-ku
The plate was 4649.
yoroshiku
What's thankful about that?
It's the middle of the night!
Now that I think about it,
something like this happened before...
Romantic movies are really great!
I was so moved.
tensaku
tōsaku
Perversion... Correction...
That actor was amazing!
busaiku
Ugly...
Ugly?
nii-san iku
No, maybe "Big brother's leaving".
What are you talking about, Shin'ichi?
What? I was talking about those cars' number plates.
1039 is Tōsaku and this one is 2319,
so you can read it as Busaiku or Niisan-iku.
I'm just looking at the number and playing with it.
Why are you doing that?
It's a little exercise for my detective brain.
And it's good practice for solving codes.
I'm surprised.
342 is "locked room".
mi-shi-tsū
misshitsu
ku-sa-ya-kyū
kusayakyū
9389 is "grass-lot baseball".
yo-ha-mu-shi
4864!
Coward!
yowamushi
ha-ku-sa-i
8931!
hakusai
Bok choy!
You come up with them one after another!
Earlier, I laughed at the number on the florist's van, which was 8083.
ya-o-ya-san
8083?
yaoya-san
Greengrocer?
See!
hanaya-san
ha-na-ya-san
A florist would be better off with something like 8783.
Yeah.
nikuya-san
Hold on, we can do the same for the butcher.
ni-ku-ya-san
See, 2983!
sa-nana-ya-san
sakanaya-san
The fish dealer's 3783.
Oh, there's more, Ran.
fu-ro-ya-san
furoya-san
The bathhouse is 2683.
tōfuya-san
And if we removed the tōfu seller's san honorific,
tō-fu-ya
it's 1028!
Nowadays you can request any number you want, but that wasn't the case in the past.
That's why no cars had 42 and 49.
Why?
shinin
shi-ni
42 makes you think about dead people,
shiku
shi-ku
and 49 about the agony of death.
Shinin... Shiku!
But people don't care about that anymore.
See, look at that.
yoroshiku
yo-ro-shi-ku
4649, there are a lot of cars with "thankful".
And the most popular numbers are assigned through a lottery.
i-i-fu-fu
Like "1122".
1122?
ii fūfu
"Happy couple".
Look, there's one there.
A happy couple? If Dad gets a car I'd like him to get that number.
No, the most appropriate numbers for your dad would be 1107 or 8109.
i-i-o-na
ha-i-re-gu
1107? 8109?
hai reggu
ii on'na
"Hot girls", "high-legs".
Stop saying perverted things!
Say, what number would you like to have?
ku-dō-shi-ichi
"Shin'ichi Kudo" is 91041. Oh?
That's a digit too many.
How about "Ku 1041"?
"Ku 1041"?
That's cool.
Right?
But it's no good.
Why?
We can't choose the hiragana, and hiragana starting with an H or K are forbidden on private vehicles.
Really?
If I had to choose a number, it'd be...
That car...
Shin'ichi! What about that car?
Sir, it's dangerous, please sit down.
Oh, crap.
Driver, please follow that car...
Obviously he can't do that...
Bus stopping...
Hey, what's going on, Shin'ichi?
Shin'ichi...
Crap.
Officer, I just a saw a car with a fake plate!
A fake plate?
A black saloon car with a Shinjuku 510, Shi 1564 plate.
But how do you know it's a fake number?
hito-go-ro-shi
1564.
hitogoroshi
Murderer!
Look, just because the number can be read as "murderer" doesn't mean that...
The numbers aren't the problem. It's the hiragana.
The hiragana shi and he aren't allowed on plates.
People who are using a fake plate do it on purpose to cover for their crime.
And they're probably carrying out their plan now!
You need to find that car.
Got it.
Leave it to me.
Ran, go on home.
Shin'ichi!
Sheesh.
This is the Mouri De—
Shin'ichi?
What were you doing?
You had me worried.
Sorry, sorry.
Looks like they weren't going to commit a "1564", but rather a "510".
go-tō
510?
gōtō
A robbery.
But thanks to my deduction, they were caught before they could do it.
So they were caught.
They wanted to provoke the police by explicitly using the numbers 510 and 1564.
It was just a prank, but adding in the "shi" got them caught.
Oh, by the way, about your father's car,
if he had to put a number, wouldn't it be 5545?
go-go-yo-ko
5545?
See you tomorrow at school.
Shin'ichi!
Say, Dad, if you buy a car...
Shut up. Yoko Okino-chan's concert's about to...
Yoko-chan!
"This concert's dedicated to everyone who's watching me on TV."
Go, go, Yoko! Let's go, Yoko!
Yoko... Go go...
"Go go Yoko", huh?
5545, huh? Might as well try that too...
DIAL LOCK
ENTER PIN CODE
INVALID PIN
Of course not, he's not my father.
But if I recall...
If I had to choose a number, it'd be...
What number would Shin'ichi have chosen?
Number plates are four digits too, so he might have used that number for his mobile phone.
But trying to figure out the code via wordplay might work.
hōmuzu
ho-o-mu-zū
Such as... Yeah, 4062... Holmes...
DIAL LOCK
ENTER PIN CODE
INVALID PIN
It's no good. It's still locked.
"Lock"?
shārokku
Now that I think of it, Holmes' first name is Sherlock...
shi-ya-ro-ku
Let's try 4869!
DIAL LOCK
ENTER PIN CODE
UNLOCKED
No way! I unlocked it!
What now? What now?!
No way, I actually unlocked it...
I have to be sure...
Is my e-mail here or not?
OUTBOX
INBOX
DRAFTS
NEW MAIL
GET MAIL
OTHERS
INBOX
FROM: Agasa
Re: What are you doing
. tomorrow?
Re: FROM: Conan
FROM: Ai Haibara
About the new game
TO: Conan-kun
What? My e-mail's... not here!
I see.
He deleted it just in case.
But I won't fall for that, my dear detective.
If I resend the e-mail from this morning, I'll know right away.
Eh? It's not coming.
E-MAIL SENT
SEND E-MAIL
Why? Why?
E-MAIL SENT
Strange... The e-mail address is right.
Weird...
A call! A call?
Hello.
What's going on?
Why do you keep sending me the same e-mail over and over?
What are you trying to do here?!
Shin'ichi?!
Do you have any idea what time it is?!
It's the middle of the night!
W-Who is it?
I was asleep, tired out from working on complicated cases all day!
For crying out loud...
Conan-kun!
Have you seen my mobile phone?
I've been looking for it, but...
Oh! That's mine!
Think a bit more about what time's good for me, won't you?
Sorry!
I picked it up in the car and forgot to give it back to you...
What, I thought I'd locked it...
Did you peek?
No.
I didn't, but why do you ask?
Isn't it obvious? I have some e-mails from a girl I like...
I see. Got it.
What the hell are you thinking?
Well, good night.
Good night.
You never change.
I see. That's why Conan-kun was all nervous.
Hey, are you listening?!
He was afraid someone'd see the e-mails he got from a girl.
I wanna get to sleep...
Asking me the same thing again and again...
Once is enough!
Hey, Ran. Are you even listening?
What was up with that mail?
Sorry, Shin'ichi. I made some wrong assumptions.
I was lucky the doc's phone is the same model as mine.
And with the strap on it, nobody can tell the difference.
But she took forever to send me the e-mail...
I locked the phone to buy myself more time,
but maybe 4869 was too hard a code.
But that's the only number common to "Conan" and "Shin'ichi".
But I'm glad I finally got to hear your voice again.
I wanted to hear it, but I couldn't call...
Don't misunderstand. There's nothing weird in that.
Idiot. Look at your phone screen.
Is this... Is this your phone number?
But is it really okay to give me something like this? I might call at an inappropriate time.
That's okay, I'm often busy so you'll
probably just get the answering machine.
But there are some things you just can't communicate without words.
You're right.
Giving her my number's a bit risky, but...
That kind of danger isn't too bad...
You two look pretty sleepy.
A little...
I was thinking about a case from six months ago...
Huh?
Six months ago?
Six months?
Oh, Dad, what's the number plate on Mom's car?
Eri's?
Yeah. I think it was Shinjuku...
ya-na-o-na
mi-ro
36 Ge 8707!
Eh?
The hiragana is ge?
Look! It's Ge 8707!
ge-iya na on'na
miro
Look, it's that annoying woman!
Geez, Dad!
fūfu kyū na
tsū-zū-ku-na
fu-fu-kyū-na
Maybe he should get 2297, "separated couple".
tsuzuku na
Conan-kun, what do you mean "don't continue"?
H-He smiled?
On the next Conan: A Jewel Robber Caught Red-Handed (Part I)!
Next Conan's Hint: Brooch!
go-tō
Next time, it's a "510"!
otō-san
I get it! Dad's the culprit, right?
gōtō
It's a robbery.