Hoshi no kagayaki yo
A BAARO FANSUB
There's something fascinating about stars,
be they criminals or actors.
A robbery that happened before our very eyes!
The cornered culprit crosses through space and time!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Here!
Tell Doc his cell phone saved my life.
So she didn't figure out your true identity?
Yeah, somehow.
Ran doesn't think I'm Shin'ichi Kudo anymore.
Well, the whole idea that a drug turned me into a little kid is so unbelievable,
I'm surprised she almost figured it out.
Don't forget to thank me too!
I'm the one who sent all those childish text messages
to make it look like Agasa's phone was really yours.
More importantly, she doesn't suspect you anymore, right?
Yeah.
But this morning was just awful.
You're so smart, Conan-kun!
That...
Here! A big helping for the future sleuth!
and that...
Hey, listen! It's Shin'ichi's voice!
Shin'ichi Kudo here! Please leave a message after the beep...
You get the idea.
You gave her your cell number?
It's okay! I set it on voice mail whenever I'm with her.
All well and good, but don't let your guard down.
If she finds out...
I know!
Believe me, I'm not about to get Ran involved with the men in black.
She's strong, you know.
A lot stronger than you think she is.
No! Don't move!
Stop!
You mean her karate?
Hey, look! That guy!
What about him?
Isn't that Detective Takagi?
He's acting strange.
Like he can't decide whether to go into that store!
He's definitely suspicious.
Yes.
Looks like he's going in!
Maybe he's gonna rob the store!
Seriously.
It's far more likely he's just going to buy a gift.
It could be for anyone. His mom, a sister...
But when a man goes into a jewelry store with a face that red,
it's gotta be for a woman he's trying to impress, or a girlfriend he wants to please.
80,000 yen...
It sure is expensive...
And I still haven't finished paying for that ring I lost at the amusement park.
But...
I'm sure of it!
I caught Miwako staring at this brooch like it was Japan's most wanted!
If you want to wow her, this is the one to buy!
But remember, don't tell her I told you.
If she thinks it's a coincidence, it'll deepen your love!
Love...
Sir?
Would you like to take a closer look?
No thanks...
If it's for one of your children, we can adjust the size.
My what?
Whoa! Go for this necklace with all the diamonds!
Don't you think it's a bit too glitzy for Detective Sato?
H-How long have you kids been here?
You know, Detective Sato's birthday is in April...
So her birthstone's diamond.
Then it's perfect! Buy it!
I didn't say I was getting anything for Sato-san!
Are you?
Er... yes.
May I take a look at that brooch, please?
Yes, sir...
This one, right?
Hey, not bad!
I like the design!
Detective Sato's so lucky...
Y-You think so?
Jewel Robber Caught in the Act
(Part 1)
Hey, you!
A jewel robbery?
What's the matter?
Hurry! Your tranquilizer gun!
I can't.
A tranquilizer dart won't go through that helmet or that heavy coat.
And I can't tell if the gun is real or not.
I can't use my Power Kick Shoes in this situation either.
Now, guys...
Don't do it!
Yes! Now!
Police!
This neighborhood is swarming with plain-clothes detectives!
If you're smart, you'll drop your gun and turn yourself in!
H-He laughed!
Wait!
Hey! Where's all the detectives?
Stop! Stop!
I was just bluffing!
I'm off-duty myself!
He's going into that alley...
W-Where'd he go?
The fire escape!
You won't get away!
Stay right here, kids!
Yes, sir!
You've got nowhere to run!
Now...
drop your gun, and calmly...
H-H-Hey!
Oh no!
Did something fall?
Yeah, what was that loud noise?
Did you see anything?
No.
Hey! Somebody go up and check!
P-Police...
Is this your truck?
Y-Yeah...
What happened? I heard something fall.
Er, well...
What's going on? What was that noise?
A-A-A dead man!
What?!
So, er, please don't move the truck or its contents
until the ambulance and police arrive...
Its contents?
Right.
Don't disturb the crime scene.
C'mon, you gotta be kidding!
I have to finish moving this stuff!
I'll wait until the ambulance arrives, but after that I've gotta get back to work!
Let me talk to the person who hired you!
Nekota-san? He's probably in his office.
Hey, call him over.
R-Right.
What's all this fuss about?
Oh, Nekota-san...
Somebody's here for you...
You've barely moved anything yet.
Come on, hurry up.
Seems a guy fell on our truck.
A guy?
That's right.
I'm afraid we have to put this delivery on hold.
Well, hurry up and do whatever you cops have to do!
I've got a schedule to keep!
Maybe it's our fault...
Yeah...
If we hadn't cornered him on that rooftop...
He wouldn't have jumped off...
Not at all!
We were just five kids and one unarmed man.
Even if the robber thought he was cornered,
he could've turned back and broken his way through at gunpoint.
Do you think he was planning to commit suicide from the start?
Yeah.
Or else he thought he'd survive that fall.
Something about this case...
makes me suspect it's not an ordinary robbery.
Or an ordinary suicide...
Let me get this straight.
You just happened to bump into a jewelry store robbery in progress,
and when you went after the guy, he jumped off a building?
Right.
He vaulted over the barrier around the rooftop,
and fell on top of this truck.
What the heck were you thinking?
An overzealous police officer kills a suspect...
No doubt about it. The media will eat us for lunch.
N-No...
He wasn't over-jelly!
He was just chasing the robber like he was supposed to!
When we got to the roof, the robber went crazy!
It all happened so fast, we couldn't stop him!
Right?
Yeah. He jumped off the roof with no hesitation.
Almost as if he'd planned it from the start.
Were you kids in the jewelry store when the robber attacked?
Uh-huh! We saw Detective Takagi go into the store and we followed him!
In a jewelry store on your off hours...
Why, may I ask?
Oh, er, I...
I... um...
Oh...
I never knew you were into jewelry, Takagi-kun.
What a surprise!
It was for you!
Did you get what you went in for?
Er, no.
The robber stole it first!
He surprised Ayumi and she dropped it...
He took it?
Uh-huh!
He put it in the pocket of his coat!
Then it should still be there.
That's a weird thing.
Before you showed up, I climbed up and checked the body,
but I couldn't find that brooch!
A brooch, huh?
A present for your mother?
It was for you!
Yeah, right.
Well, I'm sure he threw it away or dropped it while running.
Or maybe it fell out of his pocket when he jumped.
At any rate, you can forget about that brooch.
Even if we find it, it'll have to be kept as evidence for some time.
And who'd want a piece of jewelry with such a gruesome past?
Oh yeah...
I wouldn't mind!
If there's nothing wrong with the brooch itself,
you can just wipe off the blood.
That's right!
You know...
There's other weird stuff!
The robber was wearing a helmet.
But after the fall, his head was smashed open,
like he'd taken the helmet off in mid-air!
Come to think of it...
And back at the store, when you said you were a cop...
the robber...
just laughed...
like he wanted the police to appear!
He did?
Is that true?
Y-Yes...
If he was that cocky, he must have had a perfect escape plan.
Or he thought he could survive jumping off a building.
Is that why he took his helmet off? Was it part of his plan?
I don't know.
But I think we need to find the identity of this robber.
Sir, you can't come in!
No, he looks like someone I know...
Hey, isn't that Atomura-san?
I run a restaurant in the neighborhood. He's in all the time!
I think he worked for Nekota-san's company...
Nekota...
You know the name?
Yeah. The truck the robber fell on was moving office equipment...
for Nekota, that man over there...
A-Atomura-san?
This is Atomura-san!
But... But how?
Then he does work for you?
Yes... Until last week.
Until last week?
He's worked for me since I started my company.
But we're in the middle of tough times, so I had to let him go.
It was part of our restructuring.
I can't believe he was driven to do this...
You're trying to downsize your company?
Yes.
The office space in this building is smaller and the rent is cheaper.
Where was your company before this?
The top floor of that building there.
Right across the way...
Why don't we take a look at your old office?
What?
But why?
If he's been planning this robbery for a while,
he may have left evidence in the old office space.
I-I see.
Hey, mister!
Have you met these detectives before?
O-Of course not.
I've never done anything wrong in my life!
This was his locker.
And this was his desk...
You've still got a lot of stuff here.
Er, yes...
I wanted the new space to represent a fresh start,
so I left the old furniture here.
Well, I don't see anything in his locker that might connect to the case.
Nothing in the desk either.
But this is strange...
If you fired him a week ago,
how come all his belongings are still here?
Oh... well...
I didn't want to upset the other employees with the news that he'd been laid off.
I was going to tell them he was on a business trip until we got the new office running.
I told Atomura to come back after we moved and collect his things.
Hey, look!
Isn't that the truck the robber fell on?
You're right!
If the truck's down there...
We must be across from the building the robber jumped from!
Maybe the robber was trying to jump to this building!
Not likely.
The gap is almost 9 meters across,
and the robber was carrying a heavy bag full of jewelry.
Unless you were Kamen Yaiba,
you'd never try a stunt like that.
What are you saying? Kamen Yaiba would never steal!
You're probably right.
Hey, kids...
Look, you can't go there.
Sir, where were you when the movers were moving things out of this office?
What? Oh, in my apartment downstairs.
Your what?
You live under the balcony we were just on.
The office was on the ninth floor, four floors above us.
What's this?
What a funny-looking helmet!
Oh, hey!
A bicycle racing helmet?
Oh, well, I used to do triathlons when I was young...
Seen enough yet?
I knew Atomura for a long time, but you won't find anything connected to him here!
Oh, I'll answer that.
Oh? What's the matter?
I heard the police were here...
May I help you?
Are you a cop?
There was a robbery just now, right?
I was wondering if this had anything to do with it.
My name's Isaka. I live on the sixth floor.
Three days ago, around 2 AM, I woke up to a heavy thudding sound.
I saw a thin, stick-like shadow projected against the curtain by the moonlight.
I woke my husband up and went out onto the balcony, but it was empty.
My husband says I was dreaming, but I thought I should tell you about it.
Hey, do you live over this apartment?
That's right. Room 605, right above this one.
Did you hear that same sound at the time of the robbery?
No, but I was watching TV.
I didn't know anything about the robbery until I heard the police sirens.
Hey...
Can we get back to work already?
We still need to make a bunch of round trips.
How much stuff have you got?
I expanded my company too far.
It used to cover the entire ninth floor.
Something smells fishy here, but there's no reason not to rule is a suicide.
Right.
We've taken pictures of the crime scene,
and we've got all the evidence, except that brooch.
We found the fake gun and stolen jewels in the bag near the body.
I see no reason to hold up the movers.
Please keep the plastic sheet on top of the truck.
And we'll need to confiscate the truck when you're done.
Okay, okay...
Let's get this done!
Right!
Mister! Hey!
When you started carrying stuff down to the truck,
where did you park?
At the back door of this building,
on the opposite side from the street with the new building.
Then we drove around a back alley.
Did you hear anything at the time?
Yeah, I did.
What was it?
The from that sewer construction they've been doing all week.
Man, what a racket.
Lots of noise...
A narrow back alley that not many people use...
Speaking of noise, that Nekota guy was a pain in the rear too, wasn't he?
Oh yeah! He insisted on giving us exact procedures for moving his stuff out.
He made everyone, even the driver, come up to the office for a meeting.
Once we got there, he kept us waiting forever!
And he cancelled twice, remember?
He did?
Originally we were going to do the move two days ago,
but he called that morning and told us he'd had a sudden change of plans.
Same thing happened yesterday.
And it was a perfect day to move! Nice and sunny!
But he did tell us beforehand that he might need to reschedule the move,
and he paid us for all three days.
Sure, it was good pay...
Still, I hope I never land a client like that again.
That's it! The rain!
Thanks, mister! Good luck with the moving!
Oh, Conan-kun!
Bedroom, bedroom...
Found it!
This is it!
If my deductions are correct, it's probably...
Yes! It's wet!
I knew it. This was no suicide.
Nekota murdered Atomura and covered up his crime...
by jumping through time and space.
NEXT EPISODE
Why haven't you yelled at us?
We're kids!
You know we're key witnesses to the jewelry store robbery.
Next Conan:
Jewel Robber Caught in the Act
(Part 2)
Next Conan's Hint
Rain
Look forward to the next episode!
高木刑事「佐藤さんにブローチ渡して猛アブローチ！」
哀「なに、それ・・・」
高木刑事「あれ？(・_・)」