There's something fascinating about stars,
be they criminals or actors.
The Detective Boys work together
to explain the teleportation trick!
ブローチ決め手で告白だ！
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Created by
Gosho Aoyama
"Detective Conan"
Serialized in Shogakukan's
'Weekly Shonen Sunday'
Planning
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Character Design
Mari Tominaga
Art Director
Yasutada Kato
Director of Photography
Takahisa Ogawa
Sound Directors
Yasuo Urakami
Motoi Izawa
Music
Katsuo Ono
Opening Theme
"Hoshi no kagayaki yo"
Performed by
Lyrics
Music
Arrangement
Izumi Sakai
Aika Ono
Takeshi Hayama
Editor
Terumitsu Okada
Story Editor
Jun'ichi Iioka
Color Key
Fusako Nakao
Executive Producer
Makoto Moriwaki
Planning Support
Shin'ichiro Tsuzuki
Masato Hayashi
Toyohiko Okuyama
Masahiko Ishikawa
Producer
Hiroaki Kobayashi
Associate Producer
Mitome Asai
Chief Producers
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Masahito Yoshioka
(Tokyo Movie)
Director
Masato Sato
(Title Card)
All else aside,
it's incontrovertible fact that Takagi-kun witnessed a jewelry store robbery
and managed to corner the robber on top of a building,
but allowed the suspect to commit suicide before his very eyes!
Yeah.
It seems fishy that he happened to fall onto a moving truck
that was relocating furniture from the office he was just fired from.
But there's no reason to believe it wasn't a suicide.
Then let's call it a day for now.
Nekota-san, can you drop by the police station tonight?
What? W-Why is that?
As his former employer, maybe you can answer some questions
about his personality and what might have driven him to this.
Ah, right.{charcard for Sakanobu Nekota (51)
No problem.
A little lower... Lower!
Just a little more!
What are you kids up to?
N-Nothing!
Oh, ma'am! We have questions!
Questions?
Yes.
Two questions for Nekota-san...
Me?
As we recall, when you arrived at the scene of the crime,
you told Detective Takagi to "hurry up and do whatever you cops have to do."
Yes, so?
What made you say that?
Well, of course I was very busy and—
That's not what we're asking you!
So how did you know he was a police detective?
W-Well, a criminal had fallen to his death! Of course I assumed the police were there.
But you also asked what was goin' on!
And you told us you'd never met the detectives before!
You're right!
If he didn't know anything about the case and had never seen us before,
it doesn't make sense that he knew Takagi-kun was a cop!
I-It was just the atmosphere of the crime scene!
I-I could tell that something terrible had happened and figured the police would be there...
And now for the second question!
We've been in your apartment for a while now.
So why haven't you yelled at us?
We're kids!
If we were grown-ups, you might assume we're with the police.
But if a group of strange kids ran into your house, surely you'd say...
"What are those brats doing here?"
T-That...
Since you haven't questioned our presence, you must know we belong here.
You know we're key witnesses to the jewelry store robbery.
Do you?
Oh, er...
Waitasec...
If he knew I was an officer,
and also knew the kids were involved...
t-then...
You must have been...
The robber!
Right. That would answer both of Mitsuhiko-kun's questions.
D-Don't be absurd!
Think about it!
The robber jumped off the building across the street and fell onto the truck, right?
If I was the robber, where did I disappear after I jumped?
And how do you explain Atomura-san's body on the truck?
Anyway, I'm 51 years old!
I don't have the strength to lead the police on a chase.
The triathlons.
For someone who trains for such a grueling sport,
it wouldn't be much of a problem!
That's Conan-kun's voice!
I was wondering where that kid had gone.
Where are you, Conan-kun?
I'm climbing the fire escape...
to the roof of the building the robber jumped from!
I wanted to test something,
so I asked the others to buy me time with their questions.
W-What are you testing?
Can you see me from there?
I-I can, but...
What are you planning to do?
Remember that lady who lives over Mr. Nekota's place?
She woke up around 2 AM to a heavy thudding sound.
When she looked over at the window,
she saw a thin, stick-like shadow against the curtain.
I thought you should know I've solved the mystery behind that!
C-Conan-kun!
Cut this out at once!
I'm cooperating with the police out of the goodness of my heart
because a former employee of mine was involved!
Now it looks like these children want to pin the crime on me!
But who'd believe a silly children's story?
Again, like I said,
if I was the robber,
how did I disappear from the top of that building?
It's impossible! It couldn't happen!
Not unless I had the power to teleport from the roof...
It is possible.
You don't need magic powers.
You see?
C-Conan-kun?!
How'd you get here?
With this rope I borrowed from the movers!
Rope?
First, I measured the length from the balcony of the old office
to the balcony of this room, four stories below.
Then I found a rope that was about twice that length,
wrapped it around the railing of the upper balcony
and tied the ends together to make a big loop!
I added a smaller loop, just big enough to fit me,
and threw it to the rooftop to the building across the street,
just like the robber did.
The robber climbed onto the rooftop and pretended to be cornered.
He tied the rope around himself, hiding it under his heavy coat.
When he jumped, the rope swung him down to this balcony.
Once he made it across the street,
he just needed to untie the rope and hide it in his room!
I see...
Conan, you could've been hurt! Slamming into a wall like that...
I wore a helmet, just like the robber.
And I got this big soccer ball from Doc's ball-shooting belt...
and used it as a cushion! I'm fine!
I think Nekota-san used a mattress as a cushion instead.
Mattress?
I checked it a while ago, and it's wet!
It was out in the rain, huh?
Then the strange noises and shadows Isaka-san noticed
were Nekota practicing his moves...
W-Wait! When you looked down after the robber jumped,
you saw a body on the truck!
Where did that come from?
It was on the truck from the start!
Mr. Atomura fell onto the truck and was killed
after the movers parked outside of the back door of the building this morning.
You called Mr. Atomura over, saying you needed help with the moving or something,
then shoved him out the window and onto the truck.
Come to think of it, Nekota said his company used to take up the whole ninth floor...
He could've easily lured Atomura to a window and pushed him!
But the noise!
Someone would've heard a body falling!
Not with that construction work in the alley.
It'd be entirely possible to shove someone out a window without attracting notice.
B-But the truck would shake when the body fell! The driver would notice!
That's why you made everybody, including the driver, come up for a meeting in the office!
The movers told me you kept them waiting for a long time.
That's when you shoved Atomura-san out the window,
created the rope gimmick and shut the blinds!
Even if the movers went into the office, they wouldn't see anything wrong.
I see. It was like this...
First Nekota had all the movers come up to the top floor,
where his company used to be located.
He made them wait while he killed Atomura-san by shoving him out the window,
then threw the rope over to the rooftop of the building across the street.
While the movers were moving boxes into the new office,
he put on his disguise, raided the jewelry store,
ran to the roof of the other building with Takagi on his tail,
and used the rope to swing across the street into his apartment.
It looked like a criminal cornered by the police
had committed suicide by jumping from the building!
Right!
And if he dropped the bag with the jewels,
or the extra helmet he'd placed on the rooftop beforehand,
he could still use the noise to make people think something had fallen on the truck!
That's why the body wasn't wearing a helmet!
Then the reason the robber grinned when he found out I was a police officer...
was because he needed someone to chase him and watch him jump off the building!
If you hadn't been there, he probably would've stalled for time until the police showed up.
But this plan relies too much on luck.
If anyone had found the body too early, or seen the rope setup,
it would've fallen apart.
It's such a sloppy plan, a child saw through it!
It wasn't because of luck that nobody noticed those things.
What?
It was the weather.
Rain...
I get it!
Nobody was out on their balconies or looking up at the sky!
Everybody on the street had umbrellas over their heads...
And nobody would see the body unless they went out on a balcony and looked down!
And the truck drove along a little-used back alley.
To get caught, he'd have to be very unlucky.
I see.
Come on! He couldn't have predicted the weather! It was a lucky break!
No it wasn't!
You changed the moving day twice, didn't you?
You were waiting for rain!
All we need now is proof...
W-We ought to find plenty of evidence in this building.
Nekota-san appeared downstairs not long after the robber jumped.
So the rope, helmet, raincoat, and the brooch I was going to buy...
should all still be around here.
That's right. He didn't have time to destroy the evidence or throw it far away,
so it should still be in or around the building.
If the brooch is still in the coat,
and we find your fingerprints and hair on the helmet,
you'll give up, won't you?
But why'd you pocket that brooch?
It was a token of apology, I guess.
Huh?
My company was going under, and the only way to rebuild it
was to fire all the employees who were close to retirement.
He was one of them.
If you fire me, I'll go public about our long history of deliberate food mislabeling!
What?
Let me stay on until retirement.
I just want to be able to buy this brooch for my wife's birthday.
You know, she may want even more expensive jewelry later on.
But let's not worry about that for now.
That's why you did it?
Yes.
I was afraid that if I agreed, he'd continue to blackmail me.
But why take the brooch?
I was going to give it to his wife on her birthday,
and claim he'd entrusted me with it before his death.
He'd worked hard for this company since the day we started.
And here I was, his murderer, about to frame him for a crime he didn't commit.
When I saw that brooch, I grabbed it out of guilt.
Guess it ended up convicting me.
Where's the brooch? Where's the coat?
In my bedroom closet.
You heard him!
Check it out, Sato-san!
Uh... sure...
Here it is!
It must be the damp one!
I'm sure you'll like it!
Detective Takagi spent a long time picking it out!
It doesn't have any big gems!
It's a decent choice. The man must know your tastes.
Why don't you look at it?
That's right, Miwako.
I caught Miwako staring at this brooch like it was Japan's most wanted!
If you want to wow her, this is the one to buy!
But remember, don't tell her I told you.
If she thinks it's a coincidence, it'll deepen your love!
Let's deepen...
our l-l-love...
Oh...
This
brooch...
Isn't this the brooch Yumi wanted?
Y-Yumi-san?
Yeah. She saw it in some magazine!
Say, I saw Yumi-san wearing a bracelet that looked a lot like the one I gave you once...
Oh, I loaned it to her!
She said it was just her style!
I've never had much interest in sparkly stuff.
Ooh, what a gorgeous necklace!
I'll get Lt. Takano to buy this one...
Hey, Conan! Come here, come here!
Someone asked us Detective Boys for help!
And this time it's...
Yay!
Look out!
Everyone, hurry!
Next Conan: "The Mysterious Angel's Mansion (Part 1)"!
Next Conan's Hint: Charging Bull
高木刑事「次こそベストなプレゼントを！！」
佐藤刑事「え～っ、牛ぃ？」
高木刑事「ダメっすか？」