The star of a show is usually charming.
However, the same could be said for the culprit or victim...
An statue of an angel without a smile...
The Detective Boys go to a mansion,
and find themselves in a bizarre labyrinth!
Seeing through to the one and only truth,
I look like a child, but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
Yes, we felt the same light the moment we met.
Yes, lots and lots of the same emotions filled our eyes.
Although the signals you sent destroyed my theory...
These feelings were always beyond your reach
So, let's fight, go against our morals...
And aim for a wider world!
Oh, glimmering star, shine over us forever.
This way, we won't lose the dreams we had when we were young...
I don't care if this town changes someday.
The only thing I don't want to change is you.
Oh, glimmering star, shine over us forever.
This way, we won't lose the dreams we had when we were young...
The only thing I don't want to change is you.
Ah-le-le?!
Now, what would an elementary schooler be sighing for?
Hey, Conan! Come here, come here!
Someone asked us Detective Boys for help!
And this time it's...
Yay!
Isn't she cute? Even her clothes are pretty.
Uh, sure.
The Mysterious Angel's Mansion,
Part 1!
There's a man who calls himself "Tokei."
"Tokei," as in clock?
Yes.
There's no first or last name, just "Tokei."
This man is your mother's grandfather.
So he is your great-grandfather.
His name is Isegawa Gozoushi.
Great-grandfather...
There's actually someone else in my family...
With resilience, he dominated Japan's
stock market after the war.
Note: Corrida means "bullfight" in Spanish.
And he's been referred to as "corrida."
He was a legendary speculator who
earned a huge amount of money.
But unfortunately,
Last winter...
T-Tokei...
Yes.
M-my lord?
The one who solves this riddle will inherit
all properties of the corrida."
But, the time limit is 24 hours.
Once the time limit is over,
the person will lose the right to both inherit and accede.
The entrants include my wife, my
sons, and my grandchildren.
The order is determined by their order of heirship.
I want you to supervise this and make
sure my wishes are carried out.
Do you have anything else to say, my lord?
Even now, no one comes to visit me.
I don't have much time left, and yet
I have to endure such loneliness.
What a family!
Don't push yourself. Your body can't handle it.
I'm already like this, yet they still won't come to see me.
Those were my great-grandfather's last words.
And then...
As Isegawa Gozoushi's secretary and
the deliverer of the testament,
Matsunaka Yuriko-san...
Yes?
It's your turn as the seventeenth heiress.
Me?
Of course, you can choose whether or not to participate.
By the way, isn't there a group called
the "Detective Boys" at your school?
He told you to come to us?
In other words, if we accept the
commission to solve the riddle,
we would also be accepting the challenge.
What did your family say, Yuriko-chan?
My dad got in a car accident not long after I was born,
and last year my mother became very ill.
So, I am all by myself.
I'm sorry.
Because of the opposition between the families,
my father and mother went far away and eloped.
Since I don't know any other relatives, I came to you.
So, how do you feel about this?
I'm a little scared.
But if I accept this challenge to solve the riddle,
I'll get to see where my great-grandfather
and my morn lived when she was young.
That's what Tokei-san said.
The house is called Angel's Mansion,
Yuriko-san and all of you Detective Boys.
Tokei-san?!
This man...
Nice to meet you.
It's really far away, this Angel's Mansion.
We'll be there shortly once we get out of this forest.
I've already told your parents that you're
going camping for a couple days.
And they agreed.
That means he has already done some research on us.
I see it. There it is.
That's the Angel of the South.
That's the Angel of the West.
That's the Angel of the East.
And finally, that's the Angel of the North.
It is said that every one of them is facing
either north, south, east, or west.
Every angel also has the face of
Madam when she was young.
Great-grandmother?!
Yes. Without even a second thought,
Madam left for another man.
The children were left with the cold-hearted father.
After they grew up, they all left the house.
Eventually, he was the only one left.
Even when some of his children
came to visit him on occasion,
they quarreled restlessly.
He was a sad man that no one understood.
Southern Mansion
The southern mansion is guarded by the southern angel.
It's also the house where my lord passed away.
And the west mansion is typically where we work.
Western Mansion
Northern Mansion
The north mansion is where the children and servants live.
They're all In really good condition even
though no one's living there now.
We've always been keeping them up and caring for them.
But what about that one?
The east mansion looks like ghosts
could be haunting the place.
Eastern Mansion
My lord decreed no one's allowed
to approach that mansion.
Why?
I don't know, actually.
What is that?
Oh, that's Minotauros.
Minotauros?
The legendary monster whose body
was half man and half bull.
You're really knowledgeable.
If he was the speculator called "corrida"
who dominated the stock market,
it's a very suitable decoration.
That's right! Everywhere I look... Bulls, bulls, and more bulls.
In the stock market world, the bull
represents strength and power.
Even in the center of finance, New York's Wall
Street, a copper statue of an bull is there.
So, to your great-grandfather, the bull was a protector.
What is that?
It's one of the security devices my lord left here.
It starts up automatically when the sun sets.
Has it been like this since Isegawa-san passed away?
Yes, as long as the treasure and the riddle are still here,
the security devices and I will be here.
The angel's really scary...
In the day, it's the angel's mansion. At
night, it becomes the witch's mansion.
There are two faces.
Mansion of Corrida
Don't be afraid, I'm here with you.
Me too. I will do whatever I can.
This is the Fifth House that sits in the
middle of the angel's mansion.
It is usually referred to as the Mansion of Corrida."
Really? My mother used to live here?
After your parents left the mansion,
My lord was always worried about them.
He would always wonder whether
or not they would come back.
Hey, Tokei-san...
Can you tell us the riddle that Yuriko-chan's
great-grandfather left with you?
Yeah, that's our goal.
Unfortunately, it's not time yet.
In other words, the riddle has something
to do with the time...
Please, have dinner and rest in the north mansion.
Northern Mansion
I'm stuffed.
That was delicious.
Now it's time...
...for me to announce the riddle.
"When the bull's horn disappears,"
"and its tail becomes its head,"
"the angel comes down and starts playing the horn."
"That melody is my treasure."
That's all?
Yes.
"When the bull's horn disappears,"
"And its tail becomes its head,"
"the angel comes down and starts playing the horn."
And what was that last part...
"That melody is my treasure."
The 24 hour time limit begins now and
ends at nine tomorrow evening.
However, which bull is it?
Please be careful.
There are traps that are even more horrific
than the security devices my lord installed.
Some participants got lost and injured.
My lord's mansion is also called a huge labyrinth.
There's no mistake!
It has to be that really big bull!
Even if that's true,
it's not a good idea to act by ourselves.
Every time we just go along with Conan,
Doesn't it make you feel ashamed?
That phrase when the bull's horn disappears,"
It must mean that bull!
But, Genta-kun...
It must mean the horn opens a hole in its head.
And that horn must have a map inside
that says where the treasure is.
Genta-kun, you're so cool!
Yuriko-chan...
Is it that simple?
Mansion of Corrida
Isn't it dangerous to act by ourselves?
I haven't seen Yuriko-chan smile at all.
She always looks sad.
I want to help her solve her great-grandfather's riddle,
so she will be happy.
If that's the case, how could you help
her without looking at this bull?
But it's scary.
"When the bull's horn disappears,"
"And its tail becomes its head,"
The bull's horn disappears...
It disappeared!
That's amazing, Ai-chan!
I know!
The angel that comes down must be the Angel of the West!
Ayumi-chan said the Angel of the West is suspicious.
We need to be a "director to our original goal."
Director?
Director from where?
How would I know?
I mean we need to keep trying to reach
our original goal until the last minute.
Note: "Director" and "carry through" sound similar in Japanese.
If that's the case...
It should be "carry through to our original goal", Genta-kun.
But, anyway...
Don't you think something's suspicious
about the eastern mansion?
My lord decreed that no one is allowed
to approach that mansion.
If this whole riddle was made up,
and the treasure is actually in the eastern mansion...
Gen-Genta-kun...
Eastern Mansion
Thank you, Mitsuhiko-san.
No problem.
I can do this.
What is this thing!?
Angel of the West
Hey, Ai-chan...
How could the angel come down?
That's what we're...
...looking for right now.
Look out!
A power grid.
Ai-chan!
Just as I thought, someone's trying to make us go back.
As expected, it's in the eastern mansion.
The treasure must be here.
This bull has no horn.
"When the bull's horn disappears,"
"And its tail becomes its head,"
Its tail becomes its head...
Head?
How strange...
Open, open...
This is...
H-help me! I'm falling!
Anybody here?
Is there anybody here?
Mitsuhiko!
Tokei-san?
Genta-kun!?
In this fireplace,
Deep inside, there's a sk-skeleton!!
A skeleton?
Is that so?
It must be an unknown thief that
got lost and died in the labyrinth.
B-but if we don't call the police...
I understand, I will take care of it.
However, don't waste your valuable time anymore.
Northern Mansion
They all asked to go to the bathroom a long time ago.
Why is no one back yet?
Yuriko-chan?
I can't fall asleep.
I'll walk around a bit, then come back.
But...
It's okay, I'll be back soon.
Even now, no one comes to visit me.
I don't have much time left, and yet
I have to endure such loneliness.
Ah-le-le? Where am I?
Conan-kun?
Ah! I can't hold it anymore!
Tokei-san, where is the bathroom?
This way!
Can we trust what Tokei-san says?
What do you mean?
All this stuff about the great-grandfather, the riddle...
And that Yuriko-chan is the seventeenth heiress.
That makes sense.
Just in the recent past months,
There have been already 16 challengers.
But there's no note, no record...or any clue.
It's really weird.
Right?
Couldn't the story have just been made up
to trick Yuriko-chan into coming here?
Trick her into coming here, and then what?
Then... I don't know...
I don't think Tokei-san is lying.
I just have this feeling.
One thing's for sure,
Even if the previous challengers did leave some clues,
That man has erased them all.
Do you think it's so all the challengers are on equal terms?
Yeah, but what's his reason for doing so?
Damn, only ten hours left.
I'm sorry.
For causing you all trouble, I am...
It's all right, Yuriko-san.
Because there are many other bulls to check in this house.
If we still have ten hours,
I'll definitely find that bull!
And I'll break its horn to show you.
Wait a minute...
Why is it a bull?
And there's that line... "the bull's horn disappears..."
That's because Yuriko-chan's great-grandfather
was referred to as "corrida."
Last night in that Mansion of Corrida,"
Genta-kun was within an inch of falling off that bull.
And it was an bull with horns.
Wasn't there a decorative golden bull
with horns in the East Mansion?
I bet you were extremely scared of that, too.
No way! Why would I be "extremely scared" of such a thing?
That's so mean to say, Genta-kun!
The bull in that riddle...
...isn't a particular bull in this house.
It's actually...
The kanji?
"The horn of the bull disappears," that is to say...
Sh-Sheep!
That's not right, Genta-kun.
This is the character "go", which means noon."
Although, if it refers to the Chinese
zodiac, it would mean horse.
Horse?
There aren't any horses here.
It's not related to animals.
This "go" indicates a direction.
And the other thing is that-
Wait a minute...
Angel of the South
The Angel of the South...
In this case, "go" means south.
Watch out!
There's a power grid here.
No...
If my deductions are right, it's not dangerous now.
Because "go" also means 12:00pm.
Like the noon in "noonday."
It opened!
How strange.
It's stuck, so I can't pick it up.
Why?
Is this the treasure the riddle was talking about?
No.
This crystal is the key to solving the next part of the riddle.
"When the bull's horn disappears,"
"And its tail becomes its head..."
That would point to the character "ne."
The direction of "ne" is north.
So, the next clue must be...
In the Angel of the North.
What are you doing?
So, that's why...
Everyone, hurry and-!
In all those days where a future was unsure
I'm glad that I fell in love with you
I want to stay loving you forever
by stopping the time echoing in my heart
I used to be scared of being together with someone
Although I can't change others or the past
I can change myself and my dreams for the future
You're the only one I see
Sorrow piles up in the darkening city
Forever in a warm and soft breeze
we'll be together, believing in each other
June Bride, I'll be with you
That skeleton you found in the Eastern Mansion...
Which way was its head facing?
If the skeleton was the infamous burglar...
Oh, is the time limit up?
No, we still need to solve the next part of the riddle.
Bring it on!
Cut it out!
Next Conan: The Mysterious Angel's Mansion, Part 2.
Next Conan's hint!
Direction.
I'll solve the puzzle so Yuriko-chan
and I can bull it up together...
Please look forward to the next episode!
What are you saying, Genta-kun?
That's a lot of bulls.
I'm fired up!