The star of a show is usually charming.
However, the same could be said for the culprit or victim...
Today is the conclusion to the case!
The angel will finally come down.
We must find the real treasure!
Seeing through to the one and only truth,
I look like a child, but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
A girl asked the Detective Boys for help.
Her name was Matsunaka Yuriko-chan, from the class next door.
The case was to solve a riddle left by her great-grandfather, Gozoushi Isegawa.
Afterwards, we followed the instructions of a mysterious man named "Tokei".
Then went to Angel's Mansion to hear the puzzle and search for clues.
Now it's time...
...for me to announce the riddle.
"When the bull's horn disappears,"
"and its tail becomes its head,"
"the angel comes down and starts playing the horn."
"That melody is my treasure."
What are you doing?
So, that's why...
Everyone, hurry and-!
Yuriko-chan!
The Mysterious Angel's Mansion,
Part 2!
Angel of the South: Dungeon
Hey, guys... Are you alright?
I'm alright.
Same here, even though it was a long fall.
Genta-kun, Genta-kun!
Help! Genta-kun is...
Hey, Genta! Genta!
Another bowl of eel rice, please...
He hasn't slept since yesterday.
Genta, the time limit is only 9 hours now.
W-Where am I?
Just like Tokei-san said,
The Angel's Mansion is like a huge labyrinth.
Labyrinth..
Labyrinth!?
What do we do? There's nothing we can do but wait!
No way...
Then, there's no way out?
Mitsuhiko, it's all your fault!
Why me?
That's right! You were trying to show off to Yuriko-chan,
and yet you got nothing in spite of your eagerness.
If that's true, it's also your fault.
You said you wanted to beat Conan-kun and went off on your own.
Haibara-san and Ayumi-chan did as well.
I was just...
And Conan-kun,
you ran into the Angel's tower, acting all self-righteous.
Isn't that why this happened?
Then, why didn't you guys wait outside and watch?
What did you say, Conan?
Are you saying it's our fault Yuriko-chan got captured?
You want to fight?
Bring it on!
Cut it out!
Stop fighting! Aren't we friends?
But he said it was my fault.
If the Detective Boys are fighting,
Who's going to rescue Yuriko-chan?
She's always lonely.
She's alone even now.
It's my fault.
No, it's my fault.
No, it's mine.
Conan apologized?
Yeah.
Everything will be alright, right?
With the united power of the Detective Boys,
even two labyrinths mean nothing!
Yeah, that's right!
It must be really tiring trying to cheer up the kids.
Shut it.
Hey, Mitsuhiko...
Yes?
That skeleton you found in the Eastern Mansion...
Which way was its head facing?
The direction? I think it was...
This is south,
and from here to the east Mansion...
It was facing that way!
It was pointing towards the fireplace and facing down.
According to what Tokei-san said,
it was a thief who got lost and died in the labyrinth.
We know its head is facing down,
and that the head is pointing towards the exit.
Mitsuhiko also confirmed that the bones' location is connected to the fireplace.
That means this labyrinth must be
connected to the Eastern Mansion.
Wow! I knew Conan-kun could figure it out!
But, the question is how we can get from here to there,
before we turn into skeletons as well.
The Minotauros's Labyrinth.
Remember? It was here, in front of the house.
The half-man, half-bull creature.
According to Greek mythology,
Minotauros was born to a Cretan King, who had offended God.
So he inherited the blood of a bull.
The Minotauros grew up to be a frightful, brutal beast,
so the King of Crete sent his own son into the "Labyrinth of No Return."
Will something like that be here?
That's impossible.
The important thing is that...
the King would annually send seven Athenian children into the labyrinth as tributes.
When the hero Theseus heard of this,
he went to challenge the labyrinth, and defeated the Minotauros.
He returned from that so-called "Labyrinth of No Return",
using just a ball of yarn.
Yarn?
How could yarn help?
Ah... He tied one end of the yarn to the labyrinth's entrance,
and let it unwind itself as he walked.
To return from the labyrinth, he just followed the yarn back to the entrance.
I get it.
Oh, yeah.
I'll do it too...
Yeah, me too!
You don't have to, being a girl and all.
Right, Conan-kun?
Looks like we've gone in a circle.
So at that corner, we should have turned right instead of left.
Are you okay, Mitsuhiko-kun?
Don't worry.
I wouldn't catch a cold at such an important time...
Do we have enough?
But at least we're closer to the exit now.
I'm going to help too!
Sorry, sorry.
It's okay.
It's our job to find the way out,
and it's your job to solve the riddle.
Genta?!
That's right. Everyone should do what they are best at.
Mitsuhiko, you guys...
What's wrong?
Oh, is the time limit up?
No, I solved the second part of the riddle.
But...
Found it!
Over there, it's him!
That means we're close to the exit!
We're saved.
That was so scary.
Yuriko-san!?
Are you okay, Yuriko-chan?
Are you hurt?
You bastard!
You wanted to kidnap Yuriko-chan from the start.
That's crazy.
I just wanted to save Yuriko-san from the trap.
I was just scared, since he grabbed my wrist so suddenly.
I'm sorry that I worried you,
and also that I caused you so much trouble...
N-no. It was fun, right?
Yes. It was like an adventure.
Wasn't it, Conan-kun?
Yeah, it was.
Edogawa-kun, you said you had solved the second part of riddle, right?
Yeah.
But, we only have 3 hours left.
It's impossible to get the treasure.
Why?
The part with "And its tail becomes its head," indicates the direction "ne," which is north.
"Ne" also means midnight.
In order words, the Northern Mansion will only open at midnight.
Our time limit will be up at 9:00 PM tonight.
No way...
Tokei-san...
You had already solved the first part of the riddle, right?
That's why you didn't care who found the dark crystal,
so you only saved Yuriko-chan.
No, you purposely let us fall into the labyrinth to waste our time.
There are only 3 hours left.
I wish for your success from the bottom of my heart.
Only one hour left.
The way to open that Angel's door,
is it really gone?
Everybody is trying their best.
Think back carefully, think back carefully.
"When the bull's horn disappears, and its tail becomes its head,"
"the angel comes down and starts playing the horn."
"That melody is my treasure."
The angel's really scary...
It couldn't be...
But if that's true...
I see. That's why it's like this.
Ladder.
Get a ladder!
Uncle, where is the ladder?
The direction of "ne" is at the Angel of the North, right?
It's the Angel of the East, the east.
East?
Be careful, Conan!
Good luck!
Just like I thought.
Now, let's see where it is...
This is the horn that we've been waiting for.
The moment the light strikes the Angel of the North.
"The angel comes down and starts playing the horn" made from that dark crystal.
"That melody is..."
Hey! Look over there!
The angel came down to the forest!
Really?
It's the shadow, the shadow of the angel playing its horn.
"That melody is my treasure."
It's on the hill by the fire house.
There's a shadow of the horn.
It's the melody of the angel.
Got it.
And we still have 30 minutes left, too!
Alright, let's go.
Tokei-san?
That treasure belongs to Yuriko-san.
You're an adult. Stealing other people's treasure is cruel.
Tokei-san?!
That's not it. You misunderstood me.
Yuriko...
Don't get in my way, there's no time left.
Why did it have to be another labyrinth?!
It's so shiny!
This is the treasure left by Isegawa Gozoushi,
Yuriko-chan's great-grandfather?
That is...
Game over, Tokei-san.
Tell us the truth.
You were after the treasure from the very beginning.
As his secretary,
you were the first to hear the riddle, and you had solved it entirely.
Entirely?
There was, however, a timing error in your deduction.
The evidence of which, is the announcement of the riddle at night.
Unfortunately, it's not time yet.
If the riddle is announced at night,
you would have to wait until the next afternoon to open the tower of the Angel of the North.
After solving the second part of the riddle,
even if the challenger noticed the Angel of the North's tower,
they would have to wait until midnight to open the door.
Therefore, no matter who the challengers were, it would be an impossible task to accomplish in just 24 hours.
It's not like that, I...
But...
If he was after the treasure from the very beginning,
after Isegawa-san passed away,
he could have tested his deductions,
and found their flaws.
No, he couldn't test his deductions yet.
If he did, then it would've been a crime.
He wanted the money legally.
Legally?
In other words, Tokei-san,
is the eighteenth heir.
That's why he erased all the clues left by the former challengers,
and at the same time scouted us out, while secretly waiting for his turn.
You're wrong.
It was my lord, Isegawa Gozoushi, who instructed me to announce the riddle at 9:00 PM.
You think we'd believe you?
I believe him,
because of the knife.
It was meant to warn us about the power grid.
The escaping footsteps were that of an adult,
and there's only one adult here.
It wasn't to scout or to confuse us,
I believe that it was all to protect Yuriko-san and the rest of us.
There are traps that are even more horrific than the security devices my lord installed.
I don't think Tokei-san is a bad man either.
Yuriko-san?
Because at that moment...
It's obvious.
The ones abandoned by their family are hated by them.
Ai-chan, that's...
Although he is Isegawa Gozoushi's secretary,
he would not have been allowed to solve the family riddle,
unless he was somehow related to Isegawa Gozoushi.
He's related to my great-grandfather?
But Isegawa Gozoushi deprived him of his last name,
and forced him to carry out his will.
So, until the riddle was solved, he had to remain here.
Thus, he's a hated man.
So, it has to be him.
You, could you be...
That's enough questions.
What Tokei-san wants is not the gold...
...but that.
Yuriko-chan?
No, that's his granddaughter,
Tokei-san's wife.
Then that means Tokei-san is Yuriko-san's...
He's her father.
He's also Isegawa Gozoushi's most hated relative.
The one who satisfies all these requirements,
is the one who ran away with Yuriko-chan's mother.
Isegawa-san's most treasured person before he passed away...
was his cute granddaughter, Yuriko's mother.
He said she looked like his former wife.
So, no matter the cost,
he would try to get his granddaughter, who ran away with me, back.
He was affilated with the Yakuza.
Once he was angered, his actions became unpredictable.
In order to protect her and the newborn Yuriko,
I vanished from their sight and met with Isegawa-san.
In turn, I promised to work for him.
To soothe his anger, I worked for him with all my heart.
My lord, it is windy.
But, I like it like this.
So, I understood.
In his heart, he deeply loved his family,
he just never showed it.
He seemed ill-tempered,
but he was just a kind old man longing to be with his family.
Last year, Isegawa Gozoushi suddenly said he wanted to see...
...his granddaughter, Yuriko's mother.
So I went to find her.
That's when I discovered that she had passed away.
Isegawa was disappointed and became sick.
Announce the riddle at 9:00 PM.
Once the riddle is solved, you will be free.
Forgive me, Matsunaka-kun.
My real name is Matsunaka Yoshito.
I'm Yuriko's dad.
Your mother also tried to solve that riddle when she was your age.
My mother?
Yes.
But, your great-grandfather said that only his great-granddaughter would be able to solve the riddle,
and that leaves only you, Yuriko.
I think that's what he honestly thought.
Dad...
Yuriko, I'm so sorry.
Forgive me, Yuriko.
The Angel's Mansion and the fake skeleton ended up becoming a theme park based upon bulls and labyrinths.
Yuriko-chan said that it was her great-grandfather's dream.
Haibara?
I felt the same way...
Isegawa Gozoushi probably made that riddle for the children,
so that the family could bond.