The star of a show is usually charming.
However, the same could be said for the culprit or victim...
Today's case is about a misunderstood dying message.
Work hard on today's case, Officer Takagi!
Solve the case involving "Smiling Peace"!
Seeing through to the one and only truth,
I look like a child, but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
Um...
Are you sleeping?
You'll catch a cold doing that.
A-ambulance!
There's a man who fainted!
His head is bleeding a lot!
Where is he?
This is...
The ambulance is so slow.
Why aren't they here yet?
The station isn't far from the bus stop...
If they're not coming, then I'll go there myself!
That's right.
The man who found the victim,
disappeared after he called for an ambulance.
The first one to find the victim disappeared?
So that means he escaped right after calling 911.
What's the matter?
Are you looking for me?
It was you?
The person who found the victim and then ran away?
I didn't run away!
I just wanted to get an ambulance quicker...
An ambulance, huh?
There was no need for that.
The victim was dead long before that.
That's right.
It was an immediate death from being hit in the back of his head by a blunt object.
Sorry to take up your time.
Understood.
Doesn't it seem odd to call for an ambulance unnecessarily?
What's your name?
I didn't know whether he was dead or not!
Your name!
Nothing else!
It's Hiromatsu Hiroshi.
Looks like he's a hot-headed policeman.
Take this.
Address, name, age, and occupation.
Write down every detail.
It's Hiromatsu Hiroshi no matter which way you read it.
What a weird name.
I can't help that.  It's my real name.
Occupation, comedian?
I've never seen you before.
Well, I'm not that famous, to be honest.
If this random man was the first to find the victim...
The victim...
Have I seen this hand gesture before?
Peace!
What the...?!
A smile and peace?
What could the meaning behind this be?
Oh, you're finished?
Yes.
Give it to me.
Is something wrong...?
Hey,
Iwaii Hirono!
Yes.
Find out as much as you can on this man for me.
I'm counting on you!
Yes!
Did I write something wrong?
Officer Takagi!
I'm Takagi from the metropolitan area.
Takagi-san!
Hiromatsu-kun!
I'm Officer Sakurada from the Eastern side.
You know this man?
He helped me with a robbery case in the past.
Why are you here?
I found the victim during my routine jogging.
So you're the first one to discover the body?
Only "found", eh?
What do you mean?
It seems like the officer considers that man a suspect.
Conan-kun?!
Anyway, Sakurada-san,
Why do you suspect Hiromatsu-kun?
Suspecting the first one who found the body,
is the first law of investigation!
I'm not the culprit!
I know Hiromatsu-kun. It couldn't be him.
The reason why I'm suspecting him is because...
I'm the one,
who received your message at Yasunaga Agency, Yasunaga Yukiko.
I'm Officer Sakurada from the Eastern police headquarters.
Who's he?
You're Mizuhara Ryoji-san, right?
You're always in TV dramas.
Oh yeah, that actor!
I'm Mizuhara.
Okubo was Mizuhara's manager.
Okubo-san?
We believe Okubo Iwao-san was the victim.
Please verify the body for us.
What is this?
Smile?
A "V" sign?
Is it him?
There's no mistake.
He's my manager, Okubo-san.
Hiromatsu-kun, why are you here?
How should I say this...
You know this man?
We live in the same apartment.
I see, so that's how it is.
On the phone, you said Okubo-san worked very late yesterday.
He was in my room just a while ago.
He visited very late last night.
We mainly discussed my future in the business.
We talked until morning.
Afterwards, he left at 4:30 AM,
to catch the first bus.
Okubo-san left Mizuhara-san's room,
for the bus stop here.
He died at 4:40 AM,
only 10 minutes after he left Mizuhara-san's room.
We haven't found the weapon yet,
but looking at the wound, it was most likely a blunt object.
Then, 20 minutes later, at 5:00 AM,
you found the body during your jog.
That's right, yes.
Both of you live at the 4th Street Apartments.
The bus stop is here,
and the station is just ahead.
It's something like this, right?
Takagi-san,
I never got to finish my explanation.
I'll tell you why I suspect him.
This man killed Okubo-san?
You did?
I said it's not me!
First of all, you were the first to find the body.
When a culprit commits murder,
he doesn't know if he left anything at the scene.
If he pretends to be the first to find the body,however,
no matter what he left behind,
he could just say it's from when he found the body.
N-No way...
Second,
you went to the station to get an ambulance.
People usually wouldn't do that.
Most likely, you had an ulterior motive for going there.
What do you mean?
For example...
This is Sakurada.
You found the weapon?
There's no doubt about it.
It's a steel pipe with traces of hair on it,
and blood that hasn't had time to dry yet.
Yes.
We found it under...
Kamitakada Bridge.
Just as I thought.
Good work!
Kamitakada Bridge?
It's between the murder scene and the station.
In other words,
you didn't go to the station to get an ambulance,
but to dispose of the weapon.
That's nonsense!
Why would I do such a thing?
Of course, we can speculate on your motive.
Although you're a comedian, you're not very popular.
So you begged your manager, Okubo-san, who visits Mizuhara-san frequently,
to find a job for you.
He didn't even consider it, so you got angry.
Wait a minute.
Most importantly, is the victim's dying message,
which clearly indicates that you're the culprit!
Dying message?
You mean...
It's the strange way Okubo-san died with a smile on his face and forming a "V" sign with his hand.
That's the dying message?
In other words, the name of the culprit is...
Here.
"Smiling Peace"?
I knew you were a comedian,
but this is your stage name?
But, that doesn't mean I'm the culprit!
Please believe me, Takagi-san!
Hey, do you have an alibi?
Alibi?
If the murder happened at 4:40 AM,
I was still in my room at that time!
I left a little before five to go jogging!
If we could only prove that...
How do you find proof of that for someone who lives alone?
Oh yeah, after Okubo-san left,
I set my alarm clock before going to sleep.
That was when I heard the toilet flush next door.
That was at 4:40 AM right, Mizuhara-san?
Exactly.
Your alibi checks out, Hiromatsu-kun!
Yeah.
What is with his expression?
Um, can I go now?
You must be shocked, having this happen to your manager.
Mizuhara can leave now, right?
Although I want to do a survey again,
that's it for today.
May I also leave?
I still need you to tell me the circumstances in which you found the body!
Oh, yeah. That's right...
Is that right?
Got it! Good work!
I hate to break it to you,
but your alibi has just been broken.
After I began suspecting you,
I asked others to search for the traces you left.
You appeared in the video in front of the store on Third Street.
The time was 4:30 AM!
I'm sorry.
I lied!
I left the apartment and started running before 4:30 AM!
Hiromatsu-kun...
But, if I told you the truth, I'd become the main suspect!
So you couldn't help lying?
So that's why you had a weird expression earlier.
Mizuhara-san was either confused or just heard something,
I don't think he would lie for me.
So you kept what Mizuhara-san heard a secret.
So, that's what happened...
You shouldn't lie, even if you'll be suspected.
Please come to the police station with me,
Hiromatsu Hiroshi-kun.
No. "Smiling Peace"!
Takagi-san!
Sakurada-san only took the weapon and motive into consideration!
The main problem is that dying message.
"Smiling Peace"...
To think that was his stage name...
How did Okubo-san know about it?
I've never heard of it.
I've only heard of the man living next door.
Although I don't see Mizuhara-san anymore,
he used to be on TV a lot.
He was a handsome guy who always kept his cool and never smiled.
I can't leave Hiromatsu-kun alone.
I'll attend his interrogation.
"Smiling Peace"...
A smiling face and a "V" sign...
Smiling face...?
Could it be?
Um...
I'm Edogawa Conan.
So, Conan-kun, what's the matter?
Officer Takagi wanted me to come and ask you,
"What did Okubo-san talk to
Mizuhara-san about yesterday?"
It was about the future of his career.
Yeah! He asked me to ask what that is.
The future of his career is...
Just as I thought.
The mystery behind that dying message is solved.
And...
...the true culprit is that person!
Yasunaga-san?
The president of the agency?
Yes, she told me to tell you something that might be helpful.
What?
The future of his career is in his smile.
His smile?
Mizuhara Ryoji is famous for always keeping his cool and never smiling.
That path has come to a dead end now.
So, Okubo-san suggested that he try to change his image to that of a smiling person.
Since he's very charming when he smiles.
"Change his image to that of a smiling person?"
Yeah, but that request just came out of the blue.
It's probably hard for Mizuhara-san to accept it.
It's not only hard to accept, but it might even infuriate him as well.
It's hard to change your behavior like that so quickly.
Could it be?
And she said that Okubo-san really cares about Mizuhara-san.
Okubo-san was really sick.
It was diagnosed that he only had 6 months left to live.
He should have been in the hospital.
But, no matter what, he wanted turn Mizuhara,
his first client,
into a famous star again.
Even his life didn't matter to him.
Compared to Mizuhara, nothing else mattered to him.
More than his own life...?
If it's like that,
then I understand the meaning of the dying message.
Really?
Yes. If I'm right,
this case is a really sad turn of events.
That's right. This isn't a typical case.
What's going on?
Why is everyone gathered at the crime scene?
Sakurada-san...
The culprit behind Okubo-san's death isn't Hiromatsu-kun.
Rather, the true culprit is someone else.
First, the culprit disposed of the weapon and fled from the scene.
But, which way did the culprit go?
The weapon was found under the
Kamitakada Bridge, over there.
However, that doesn't mean the culprit went there.
In fact, he could have gone this way.
So the culprit was just trying to turn the police's attention away from himself, right?
What a childish trick!
I see!
Now we know the culprit lives here.
Ah-le-le?
Doesn't Mizuhara-san also live in this apartment complex?
Yeah...
Second, is the alibi.
Most likely, this murder was unplanned,
so the culprit didn't prepare one beforehand.
Rather, he thought of a really air-tight one later.
You lied to create an alibi so you
wouldn't be under suspicion, right?
The culprit took advantage of that lie.
What do you mean?
Who's the one person who benefited from your lie?
That's right, it's Mizuhara Ryoji-san.
You're the one who killed Okubo-san, aren't you?
That was when I heard the toilet flush next door.
You weren't confused and didn't mishear anything.
Based on that statement, we thought you had been in your room that whole time.
But yesterday, Okubo-san suggested that you change your image.
He told you that you needed to show your smile.
But for you, being the "cool guy who never smiles",
you didn't agree with that suggestion.
You were probably thinking something like,
"If things continue like this, I'll be forced to change myself. What a joke!"
Isn't that right?
How could I, Mizuhara Ryoji...
How could I smile like a silly little kid?
Mizuhara, how could you do that to Okubo-san?
This morning, you followed Okubo-san from your room.
That's right, Officer.
How do you explain the odd position that he died in?
Just like you thought,
it was his dying message.
However, it wasn't "smiling peace", but a smile and a "V" sign.
It's Okubo-san's final testament,
as Mizuhara-san's manager.
What Okubo-san wanted to say is,
"Mizuhara, smile, always try to smile."
"Your smile is the best."
I didn't know.
You idiot!
Why would he encourage the person who killed him?
There's a good reason.
And it's that Okubo-san cared about Mizuhara a lot.
Even in the final moments of his life,
he was still thinking about you.
Okubo-san!
Okubo-san was thinking of you until the very end.
Repent for your crime and try to start over, Mizuhara-san.
We'll talk about the details at the police station.
Sakurada-san...
Hiromatsu-kun...
Please apologize to Hiromatsu-kun.
Apologize to him for accusing him of being the culprit.
All he did was lie about the alibi.
It's certainly not right to lie,
but you need to hold those who force others to lie accountable.
It's what I believe.
Am I wrong, Sakurada-san?
Suspecting the first one who found the body may be the primary law of investigation.
But, it could also lead to the wrong conclusion.
This could be a lesson for us all.
It's absolutely unacceptable for police officers to be biased.
Absolutely unacceptable!
I understand.
I apologize.
No, it's okay.
Excuse me.
Thank you very much,
Takagi-san!
What a relief.
You were great, Officer Takagi.
But, when you said the smile and the "V" sign led to the culprit,
I thought it was the end for me.
It was an unreasonable explanation from the beginning.
Yeah, I thought that Okubo-san wouldn't know
the comedian called "Smiling Peace."
Not even the professional managers?
Am I really that unknown?
Continue to try your best, Hiromatsu-kun!