There's something fascinating about stars, be they criminals or actors.
Time for a magic show with the Osakan duo.
A mysterious and superb magic trick sets off a mystifying case!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Yeah, we're both goin' to watch it.
That sounds pretty good.
To reach the hall, go straight down that street.
Why? Why am I this stressed?
Guess who?
H-Hey!
It's me!
Stop doin' that, Kudō!
And after that, Ran-chan—
Hey, Hattori!
kudoi
U-Uh, that's loud!
Stop talkin' so loud!
Heiji?
Geez...
Hey, Hattori...
Sorry for makin' ya do this, Ran-chan.
It's fine.
Hey, Hattori.
What are we doing here?
Why are we coming to Dōgo Hoshikawa's magic show again?
"Because I'd totally love to be bewitched by the mystery!"
So I had to come for that stupid girl's stupid sake to watch a stupid show full of stupid tricks—
Hey!
Don't call me stupid, stupid!
Huh?
They're over there, Kazuha-chan.
So let's go.
C-Conan-kun.
Ah, it's these seats.
Hurry up, Ran-chan.
Aren't there a lot of young people here?
You think so?
So this guy's Dōgo Hoshikawa-san?
Hey, ain't he cute, Ran-chan?
And he's got more than just looks—he's an amazing magician, too!
Man, those chicks are hot!
Yeah!
So there really ain't no wires?
I was thinking that too...
That was amazing!
You think so?
Not really.
No way!
He disappeared!
Wow, amazing!
He's a wizard!
Ya stupid or something'?
There ain't no such thing as wizards in this world.
What he said.
That birdcage looks like it's impossible to escape, but it actually has a secret door in the back.
He sneaked out through it after they dumped the cloth over it.
But it's been on the stage the whole time!
Them eight gals dancin' around are the trick.
Most likely, the magician dressed himself like one of 'em and got out that way.
Nobody was counting how many assistants there were on stage,
so nobody noticed that they went from eight to nine by the end.
By walkin' close to the girls, he went into the wing unnoticed.
And while people were watchin' the clothes burnin', he sneaked onto the audience seats.
Yeah.
But that levitation trick was amazing, too!
It really looked like he was flyin'!
And I didn't see any strings...
He supported his body with a rod and used a crane placed behind the curtains to move himself up and down.
The curtain had horizontal and diagonal slits, and the audience was primed to look for ropes...
Knock it off!
You two shut yer traps!
Oh, geez. You told me to let ya know how the tricks were done if I figured 'em out.
And now for our grand finale!
Our most dangerous act—the underwater escape!
With his arms and legs cuffed, he'll try to escape from this sealed water tank.
If he makes it through, please give him a big round of applause!
It's been too long, hasn't it?
Yeah.
H-Hey, ain't it been about ten minutes since he went in there?
Draw the curtains!
Somebody get an axe!
T-There's been a minor complication.
Please wait a minute!
This is the same trick the legendary magician Houdini used to do.
Yeah, it's a classic escape method.
Let's go, Ran-chan!
Okay!
Now they've done it, Hattori...
Y-Yeah...
E-Excuse me!
Stay back!
Umm—
Move!
Ran-chan, use your karate to break open the tank!
I-I barely made it.
Thanks to my luck, and to these two brave ladies who made this show even more of a thrill!
Please give them a big round of applause!
Hey, Hattori...
Yeah?
They did come here just to watch today, right?
Probably.
Dōgo Hoshikawa's Dressing Room
We're so sorry!
We thought you were in danger, right, Ran-chan?
Yeah. Our sincere apologies.
It's fine.
Besides, I couldn't have escaped without your help.
Dōgo Hoshikawa (27)
Magician
I could hear your lovely voices calling me from inside that tank, just as I was losing consciousness.
Your love brought me back to life.
Really?!
What a load of BS.
He hid a pin or somethin' in his mouth and used it to pick the locks on his cuffs.
He left that tank long before you saw him.
Yeah.
They initially showed the tank with the door open and sealed it with a chain.
That led the audience to believe it couldn't be opened.
But actually, he was able to leave from a part of the lid that wasn't locked.
After that, he just had to wait behind the curtain to make the audience nervous,
and after the staff started acting berserk, he poured water over his head and showed up.
Another thrillin' great escape!
That was an amazing show, Hoshikawa-kun!
Riki Handa (41)
Magician
How about next time, you team up with me?
If you're up for it, sure.
You bet! I wouldn't mind riding your coattails!
Oh? Then I want in on that show too.
We can find out once and for all which one of us is the rightful heir to our master, Mr. Masakage.
Tenko Himemiya (32)
Magician
Mr. Masakage?
A mysterious magician who broadcast his shows on TV often. But he went missin' about ten years ago.
Rumor has it he's alive and hidin' out somewhere.
Mr. Masakage...
I had no idea these three were students of his.
Hey, I know!
Let's recruit Kazumi Sanada-kun, who's just as popular as Hoshikawa these days,
and put on a real dream show—The Four Kings of Magic!
Kazumi Sanada?
Fine with me, but...
I don't know if he'll be up for that.
I've never met him, even though we're both magicians.
Oh yeah, Ran-chan! You've met Kazumi Sanada, ain't ya?
Yeah.
When Sonoko invited me to her family's cruise party for the Suzuki Financial Group's 60th anniversary.
Kid had just sent one of his heist notices,
and Sonoko's mom hired Sanada, who showed up disguised as Kid to make it more exciting.
And on another occasion, the genius magician Motoyasu Tsukumo-san's wife hired my dad
to find out the reason behind her husband's death, and Sanada-san was one of his three disciples.
You know Sanada-kun?
Then could I ask you to call Sanada-kun?
And now, shall we discuss this at Masakage-sensei's place?
You girls want to join us? I'll put on a little magic show after dinner...
Really?
You sure you don't mind?
But why go to the master's house?
Don't you remember?
He disappeared ten years ago today.
You never know—he might suddenly reappear.
Welcome!
Mari Masakage (54)
Mr. Masakage's Wife
Oh, could that be Tenko-chan and Hoshikawa-kun behind you?
Greetings.
Long time no see.
Yes, indeed.
It's been ten years, hasn't it?
And who are these?
Our special guests for tonight!
Hello!
I'll have to go out and get more groceries.
Don't you worry!
I thought about it ahead of time.
Voilà!
Wow.
You visit every year on this day, Handa-san?
Yes, hoping our master will come back.
But unfortunately, he hasn't contacted me at all during these ten years.
Does this place ever bring back memories...
The three of us lived here together while we were learning the tricks of the trade from him.
But Hoshikawa-kun, you used to come here
even before my husband started accepting disciples, remember?
Then you were his first disciple?
It doesn't matter if you're first or last.
The question is which of us will finally surpass the master.
Now, now, Tenko-chan.
If we're really going to do a show together, my grand finale will be the 'resurrection of the witch'!
A huge cross will be placed in the middle of the audience.
I'll be tied to the cross, and the audience will set it on fire.
And before it burns out, I'll disappear...
...and then rise miraculously from the ashes!
Sounds exciting, doesn't it?
Y-Yeah...
I'll call you when dinner's ready.
We'll gladly help you.
Maybe I'll take a look around the old place. It's been so long...
Good idea.
I'll find a spare room and sleep for a bit.
I got up at the crack of dawn...
Okay. I'll let you know once dinner's ready.
Hattori, that was one hell of a sudden mood change...
Yeah.
Huh? You want me to call up the magician Kazumi Sanada?
How am I supposed to do that? I don't even have his phone number!
I guess we only met him a couple of times, huh?
Where are you, anyway?
I'm starving over here!
Sorry, but I'm eating out tonight.
Why don't you get dinner at Poirot?
Ran-chan, help me out here!
Hey.
Hey!
There's too much for me to do alone!
Where's the missus?
She went shoppin' 'cause she ran outta seasonin', but she ain't come back!
I asked the guys to help, but...
Yeah, no.
Guess this knife ain't as sharp as my deductions.
Since we're so good at piecing clues together, I guess our vegetables come out in one piece too...
This was pretty hard.
In the end, you had to do most of the work on your own. I'm sorry.
It's fine, isn't it?
How's it going?
Oh, it looks great!
Where are your friends?
Treating their wounds in the kitchen.
They cut themselves choppin'!
I'll go wake up Handa-san—he's probably in the room at the end of the first floor, as usual.
Hoshikawa-kun, could you go find Tenko-chan for me?
Sure. Knowing her, she's probably in that room.
"That room"?
Mr. Masakage's room.
It's filled with photos, props and memorabilia from his career.
Magic props?
Would you like to see it?
Oh, yes!
Of course!
Mr. Masakage designed and
built this house himself.
His room's in the second floor.
This is one narrow hallway...
And so dark and gloomy...
The door to the right is the master's room.
Looks like the light's burnt out.
What's goin' on?
A blackout?
Where's the breaker?
There doesn't seem to be one in this room.
Ah, ma'am. Where's the circuit breaker?
Right next to the bathroom.
Found it.
Hattori!
Right!
What is it?!
What happened?!
What the hell...
What is this room?
This is the library where Mr. Masakage-sensei documented
all the magic he learnt while traveling abroad.
This must be the famous christmas tree trick!
What's that supposed to mean?!
Who are ya callin' a kid, short stack?!
This photo...
It's those three when they were young.
Ya know what this could mean?
On the next Conan: "Conan and Heiji's Deduction Magic (The Mansion)"!
Next Conan's Hint: Narrow hallway!
Next week is our battle!
A magic trick contest?
Yeah, I can turn this red-and-white handkerchief into a white-and-red one!