There's something fascinating about stars,
be they criminals or actors!
A big case at a magician's home.
Conan and Heiji figure out the tricks and gimmicks behind it!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
At the famous magician Dōgo Hoshikawa's show
we were invited to the home of the legendary magician, Mr Masakage.
That day was the 10th anniversary of Mr Masakage's disappearance.
Dōgo Hoshikawa (27)
Magician
Riki Handa (41)
The magician's disciples had all gathered there.
If we're really going to do a show together, my grand finale will be the "resurrection of the witch"!
Tenko Himemiya (32)
Magician
A huge cross will be placed in the middle of the audience.
I'll be tied to the cross, with volunteers from the audience holding the ropes.
My assistants will set fire to the cross, but I'll disappear before it burns away.
Then I'll rise miraculously from the ashes!
Looks like the light's burnt out.
Found it.
What was that scream?
Upstairs!
What?
It's Tenko-san!
She's bleedin' from her head and won't move!
What did you say?
Forget it. Her body's already cold.
Oh no...
Tenko-chan!
I-I don't believe it...
Looks like she's been dead for more than 30 minutes.
Did you two find her?
Yes, but Hoshikawa-san was with us too.
He's in the next room callin' for an ambulance an' cops.
Please hurry!
Right...
Right.
Hey, Hattori. Take a look.
The window's open.
If the killer jumped out an' landed in the bushes,
they could get away through the back gate no problem.
Heiji, c'mere!
Huh?
Check out the room next to the one where we found Tenko-san!
What the...?
What's this room?
It's a library of reference works on magic that Mr. Masakage-sensei gathered from around the world.
Did ya keep any valuables in here?
No... It's mostly books and magazine clippings, nothing too rare.
We used to flip through them all the time.
But maybe...
Mari Masakage (54)
Mr. Masakage's Wife
The intruder was looking for the forbidden notes?
My husband wrote down the secrets to all his original illusions in a notebook.
He wouldn't even let me read it.
He called it "The Masakage Notes".
The Masakage Notes...
Oh? If it isn't Hattori-kun.
When did you get here?
This mornin'!
I'm on summer break. I came to Tokyo to catch a magic show
'cause some stupid girl wanted an "enchanted experience".
Who're ya callin' stupid, stupid?
The way you pop up at all these crime scenes has to be black magic.
But why are you here?
We met these three magicians after the show.
They invited us to their master's house.
Then one of 'em got killed!
She's a magician too?
Tenko Imemiya.
She's pretty famous overseas.
We were just talking about doing a show together.
Then this happened...
Who found the body?
Me and the two girls behind me.
We went looking for Tenko-san to call her for dinner.
We should she'd be here in the master's room.
We didn't see anything at first.
It was dark, and when I tried to turn on the lights, we had a blackout.
Then when the lights went back on,
we saw Tenko-san's body at the end of the hall.
The killer darkened the hallway by loosenin' the light bulbs.
The only lights that went out were the ones in that hallway.
It was set so if somebody tried to switch the lights on, they'd trigger a blackout.
This switch's been tampered with to cause a short circuit.
The library next to the body contained a valuable notebook,
but it ain't got no windows or exits.
But the window in the master's room next door is open.
So the murderer must've stole the notebook an' escaped out the window.
E-Escaped?
Yep.
Speakin' of which, if there was a blackout, wouldn't you need to go flip the breaker on the first floor?
The thief planned to use that moment to escape through the window in the master's room.
But the heist didn't work as planned.
Normally this lady is the only person in the house.
But today she had seven guests.
Tenko-san entered the library without turnin' the blackout switch on.
She saw the thief's face, so he had to kill her.
While the thief was lookin' for the notebook in a panic,
Kazuha an' the others came lookin' for Tenko-san.
This time the blackout trick worked, so the murderer dumped the body in the hall an' ran for the window.
Everybody was so shocked by the stiff, they didn't see the killer escape.
I see...
The only possible conclusion is that this was the work of an intruder who broke in to steal the magician's secrets.
Unless, that is...
Unless...?
...the real killer was Hoshikawa-san, the guy who flipped the blackout switch!
Durin' the blackout, there was more than enough time
for you to move Tenko-san's body, which you'd hidden in the library beforehand,
an' come back to Kazuha and Ran before the lights turned on.
Not true!
Right?
Yeah.
These two girls were hugging me tight the whole time!
Hugging?!
Why?
"Why"?
'Cause it was dark an' creepy!
So you clung to this jerk!
That's right!
I was holdin' on to him like this!
And I was holding Kazuha-chan like this...
See? He couldn't have done it!
This is just like that case with Araide-sensei, Conan-kun!
Uh-huh...
Ya big dope!
It was just a blackout!
Actin' like a little baby...
Now, now, Heiji-niichan! She can't help it, she's just a girl!
What're you on about?
And where were you two during the blackout?
I was taking a nap downstairs, in the room below the library.
I'd just gone in to wake Handa-san up when the blackout happened.
All three have solid alibis.
Looks like the work of a burglar.
Say, what's this valuable notebook I keep hearing about?
The Masakage Notes. It's a collection of all the original illusions invented by my husband, Mr. Masakage.
Mr. Masakage? I used to watch him on TV when I was a lad!
His illusions were amazing, and he and his lovely assistant worked so perfectly together!
I heard about them too!
I never forgot them!
I was that assistant.
Ah! Is that so? But where is he now?
I think I remember hearing that he went missing...
You're kidding!
It was ten years ago on this very day.
He often went off on trips without telling me, so I wasn't worried at first.
But then six months passed.
Dogo, Riki and Tenko, who were all living here, moved out,
and started their own careers.
Now, ten years later, we're back together.
Then you're the one who invited everyone here?
No, that was me.
I wanted to talk about the three of us doing a show together.
But I come here every year, on the anniversary of the master's disappearance,
to eat Mrs. Masakage's cooking.
Do you know of anyone who had a grudge against Mr. Masakage-san? A jealous rival, maybe?
If what Hattori-kun said is true, the murderer knew Mrs. Masakage lived alone,
and also knew the layout of the house by heart!
With Mr. Masakage gone, his book of tricks would be worth a lot of money to the right person.
Is there anyone who used to visit this house and might want to exploit him like that?
But Masakage-sensei wasn't the kind of person who made enemies...
Now that you mention it,
there was one man...
He came by several times, saying that he wanted to meet my husband.
I thought he was a fan, so finally I invited him in.
But as soon as he got to my husband's room...
Come out, you petty, thieving trickster who stole my act!
He was shouting like mad!
I've told you about this, haven't I, Handa-san?
Yeah, I think so...
What did he look like?
It was over five years ago, so I don't recall him clearly.
But around that time, things around the house seemed to have moved slightly.
Then again, maybe I imagined it!
Things moved?
What's the matter, Ran-chan?
Oh...
I think something in the room changed before and after we found the body.
You think so too, Ran-chan?
You noticed it?
But I can't quite remember what was off...
Maybe I should call Shin'ichi and ask him about it.
Huh?
I thought he wouldn't give you his number.
He finally told me the other day!
Shoot! I haven't turned my cell phone off!
Then why don'tcha call him?
Kudo-kun's such a smart guy!
If you tell him about the case,
I bet he can solve it... in... no...
Sorry, but I'm gonna hang on to this phone 'til I close the case!
Heiji?!
Hey!
Well, smart guy? What brilliant theory have ya got?
Let's hear it, eh, Kudo-kun?
You just solved the whole case a minute ago.
Liar!
There's some detail buggin' ya.
Yeah, okay, maybe.
Like how the thief happened to choose this particular day?
Right. Today's the anniversary of Mr. Masakage's disappearance.
If the murderer was a thief who'd been casing the house,
they should've known this was a special day,
and that Mrs. Masakage wasn't alone.
An' it's funny there ain't no blood at the spot where Tenko-san was bludgeoned.
If things happened the way I deduced, she shoulda been attacked in the hallway or the library,
but I don't see a trace of blood there.
Right.
The murder site's too clean for this to be anything other than a premeditated crime.
Yeah.
If it was just a thief, we'd find blood in the floor tiles or wood grain or somethin'!
An' third...
Huh? There's more?
Kazuha.
What?
I dunno why, but she's been buggin' me.
I can't concentrate on my detective work when I see her all flirtin' an' smilin'.
What's with that?
By any chance, do "flirting" and "smiling"...
come before the phrase "with other guys", or "trying to date other guys"?
Yeah, yeah! That's it! You got it, Kudo!
Kudo?
Damn it, Hattori!
No, no... I mean, could-uh— could go for a fresh drink.
I saw on TV that the temperature
went up to 39 degrees yesterday.
It was hot, wasn't it?
That's right. I remember seein' it on the news at the airport this mornin'.
So? Ya got any idea what's up, Kudo?
Kudo...
Oh, Hattori.
You're...
...such a kid.
K-Kid?!
What's that s'pposed to mean?! Who ya callin a kid, short stack?!
Heiji!
Whaddya thinkin', losin' it at a little boy!
Poor Conan-kun!
Poor Conan-kun my arse.
The brat's sayin' stupid stuff!
Who's being stupid?
What can you recall about the suspicious man who visited you five years ago?
Apart from your husband's students here, did any other magicians visit this house?
Certainly.
Before my husband vanished ten years ago,
he often had guests,
but I didn't know them all.
My husband designed this house,
and sometimes he'd invite people over just to show it off.
He designed the house?
Yes.
He had magic tricks that could only be performed here,
and many guests came to see them.
Especially the Christmas tree trick.
That was very popular. It always got a big cheer.
What is it?
O-Oh, nothing, I'm sorry.
That had nothing to do with this...
What kind of trick was it?
Oh...
Only Mr. Masakage can tell you that.
But now that he's gone missing,
there's no way to know how his illusions were done.
Can you tell us more about the suspicious man who came to visit you five years ago?
If he was a rival magician who thought your husband, Mr. Masakage, had stolen his tricks,
he was probably looking for the Masakage Notes.
If somebody broke into this house
with the intention of getting the notebook in the library,
but had to kill Tenko-san to silence her when she caught him,
Then he's sure to be the man from five years ago.
Can't you remember anything about him? Height, facial features, anything?
No, not really...
How about race? Was he Japanese?
Oh, yes!
He spoke fluent Japanese and had dark hair!
But he was wearing a hat, so I didn't see his hairstyle.
And I couldn't see his eyes, since he was wearing sunglasses...
And his face was hidden behind a beard.
I think he was slightly taller than me.
A hat, sunglasses and facial hair, huh?
It could've been a disguise.
Most likely.
Come to think of it, did you check to see if the Masakage Notes have been stolen?
I can't.
I don't know where he kept the notebook,
except that it was in the library.
For all we know, he took it with him ten years ago.
Hey, ya got any photo albums?
Photo albums?
With all those guests and parties, you must've taken pictures!
Maybe there's a photo of the guy from five years ago in there!
I see.
Where are your photos?
In my husband's room.
What's the meaning of this?
Why does the door get stuck in the wall?
My husband designed it that way so he could have larger rooms.
Oh, geez.
I guess the master's talents didn't extend to architecture.
I'll say.
Hey, Kudo.
Yeah.
What're ya two doin'?
Aren't you going in?
Oh...
Uh-huh...
Well?
See anyone who looks like that man from five years ago?
No, not yet...
You sure have a lot of photo albums.
Hey, Heiji! There's no way we're gonna find the guy in these photos!
Well, duh! That ain't what we're lookin' for!
Found it!
This must be the famous Christmas tree trick!
Looks like the tree was placed at the end of the hall where we found Tenko-san's body.
I think we're on to something.
Aha! Take a look at this, Kudo!
This picture.
It's those three when they were young.
Ya know what this could mean?
Hey, there's something suspicious about that woman.
What's suspicious?
Look, over there.
That thing on the ceiling!
It's a screen for a projector!
Looks normal to me.
But don't you usually hang a screen from a wall?
You need room to sit and watch!
But that's not the case here.
See, it's really far from the wall.
Isn't it weird?
Now that you say it, yeah.
That's no ordinary screen, boy!
It has a slit so people can walk through it.
Have you ever seen a magic trick where real people seem to walk right out of a movie screen?
Yeah, I have!
We used to rehearse magic tricks in here. That's why it's not close to a wall.
That's really nostalgic.
Back in the day, we'd all gather here and practise together.
But now, you're all fantastic magicians, and no longer have use for this room.
It's thanks to the master and this room that we're as good as we are today.
There's always a trick behind magic.
That's why practising is so important.
If you want your audience to not see through the trick, you must practise it over and over again.
So the screen has a hole in it, huh?
I had no idea.
Back then, we used to come to this room every day.
My husband needed to make sure the timing was right
and no strange shadows would appear on the screen.
Shadows...
That's it! The shadow!
Yeah! The shadow of the vase was different!
The shadow of the vase?
The first time we were in the hall, the moonlight was shining on the vase from behind, throwing it in shadow.
But when we found Tenko-san's body after the blackout,
the moonlight was shining on the vase from the side!
The patterns on it were clear as day!
What the...? The moon don't move that fast, dummies!
The shadow of the vase...!
Next Conan: "Conan & Heiji's Deduction Magic (The Resolution)"
Next Conan's Hint: Shadow
Next time, we'll solve the case
with our famous comedy act!
What are you trying to do, make me laugh?
It's a combo, it's a combo!