Stars are sometimes good to see, I guess it's the same for the criminals.
Soon we'll solve this magical murder mystery.
Conan and Heiji figure out the trick and solve it.
Seeing the one and only truth with a body of a kid but the mind of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan.
Yes, we felt the same light the moment we met.
Yes, lots and lots of the same emotions filled our eyes.
Although the signals you sent destroyed my theory...
These feelings were always beyond your reach
So, let's fight, go against our morals...
And aim for a wider world!
Oh, glimmering star, shine over us forever.
This way, we won't lose the dreams we had when we were young...
I don't care if this town changes someday.
The only thing I don't want to change is you.
Oh, glimmering star, shine over us forever.
This way, we won't lose the dreams we had when we were young...
The only thing I don't want to change is you.
We are invited by legendary magician Hoshikawa Dogo
to the house of the famous magician Mr. Masakage.
Because today is exactly 10 years after Mr. Masakage disappeared,
some pupil magicians gathered, and one of them, Tenko Himemiya, was killed.
It looks like it's been about 30 minutes since she died.
You two found her?
No, we were with Hoshikawa.
Eh? What's happened?
What's this room?
It's the archives room. It contains the collections of our master, Mr. Masakage.
Here it is.
This is "Chrismas Tree Magic". This chrismas
tree was at the place where Tenko died.
It's strange.
Look at this picture, Kudo.
It's his pupils when they were young.
I think it is...
It's the shadows.
Yes, a difference in the shadow of the vase.
The shadow of the vase?
At first, the moonlight comes from the back.
After the power failure, the moonlight comes from the side.
What's that? The moon can't move that fast.
The shadow of the vase...
Conan and Heiji Reasoning Magic
Solving part
Moonlight and a vase...?
What does that mean. It's impossible.
Maybe, at first, it was cloudy.
Dogo Hoshikawa (27)
magician
After power failure. the clouds disappeared find we could see the shadow.
That could be true...
I agree.
Did you hear any voices or the sound of a criminal running away?
No, we were crying. It was dark and frightening.
Hoshikawa talked to us, and calmed us down.
Talked to you?
Hm...?
"It's alright. Don't worry. I'm with you, he said over and over.
He's really reliable.
Oh? Well, I'm glad.
Really...
Please show me the room Handa was sleeping in, just to make sure.
Handa Riki (41)
magician
Ah, okay.
Ouch.
Kazuha, you stay in here with Ran.
Why?
I'm irritated because of you.
Why is that?
Oh, I think...
Note: Yaiteru means to be jealous or to get sunburned.
he's YAITERU.
YAITERU? He didn't get sunburned.
Uh... I didn't mean sunburned..
Is this the room you stayed in when you were Mr Masakage is pupil?
Yes.
The bed they used was thrown away 10 years ago.
Masakage Mari (54)
Wife of Mr. Masakage
When the power failure occurred, where were you?
Riki was lying on that sofa when I opened the door. He didn't move.
It was dark, so I said we shouldn't move until we could see.
Who fixed the breaker?
It was me. I was near the breaker with Conan.
This room is under the archive room. But...
No one could get out that small window.
I think this house has some trick, because it was designed by a magician.
There is no elevator that could have lifted up Tenko.
Mari and Handa were here, so the murderer
couldn't have killed Tenko in this room.
Hoshikawa was being held by Kazuha, so he couldn't have moved Tenko's body.
Well then, the murderer must have come from outside.
Megure!
What is it?
We inspected that shrubbery. We found broken branches and a footprint.
That shrubbery is under Mr. Masakage's room.
Hattori, maybe what you said is right.
The criminal hide in the archive room, planted her body in the dark,
entered Mr. Masakage's room, then escaped out the window.
OK. Let's investigate.
Yes, sir!
If the criminal came from outside...
The rest is police work.
No. It's not. It's...
...our work.
Hmm... I see.
I understand.
What!? You found the criminal?
Yes, I found the criminal who killed Tenko and hid the trick he used.
Trick?
I will show you now, Can I use a thin policeman and a fat policeman?
Thin and Fat? Ok, then Takagi and Chiba.
I don't mind, but what are you going to do? Is it a dangerous trick?
Don't worry. Just help me a little, ok? It's good
to worry about your subordinates but...
Hey, are you alright Hattori?
It's, it's alright. Tenko disappeared and was found after 10 minutes.
Please take everyone to the corridor on the second
floor, and maybe you'll be surprised,
That's what you were saying, right Heiji?
Oh, yeah.
Come on, Hattori.
Okay, I will call Takagi and Chiba to this room.
Handa Mari, please go another room and wait there.
Also, please get Hoshikawa and everyone else.
Ok, we will go to the living room.
Hey, Kudo.
Huh?
I get it.
What? We gathered everyone because you already figured it out.
No, no. I figured out why I get irritated when I think about Kazuha.
Oh, I'm... I'm glad.
It's been 10 minutes.
Sorry to make you wait.
We will all now enter the stage where we will solve the case.
Of course, the murderer is here, too.
Eh?
The murderer is...
...here?
But you said that the murderer who killed Tenko came from outside.
The murderer came to steal Mr. Masakage's magic file in archive room.
But Tenko saw him, so he killed her.
Then Hoshikawa, Ran, and Kazuha came, so he put
Tenko in the corridor, entered Mr. Masakage's room,
and jumped out the window.
There is also a switch that caused the power failure.
Handa and Mari were in the room on the first floor.
Hoshikawa was with Ran and Kazuha. So, who
took Tenko and how did the person do it?
Oh, yes...
Mari said that a weird man came here 5 years ago.
That man may be a suspect.
Did that man have any distinct habits?
A habit? Hmmm... I can't remember. It was 5 years ago.
For example. a habit where he adjusted his sunglasses with his left little finger.
Oh, yes! He had that habit. ...Ah!?
Eh?
Do you know something, Heiji?
I don't know, but I can guess.
Mari is talking about the man in this photo with the cap and mustache.
Couuld he be...
Mr. Handa in his youth.
Yes. Mr. Handa has the habit of adjusting this sunglasses with his left little finger.
So, the man that Ms. Mari met 5 years ago was Mr. Handa?
Idiot. If that man was Mr. Handa, she would have noticed.
Yes, certainty.
You know when somebody lies, they think about a model. To make it seem real.
The model is a young Mr. Handa.
I see. So the man's habit was like Mr. Handa.
But we don't doubt Ms. Mari.
But, why did you lie?
Because she knows.
Because of where Tenko was and the situation,
she knows that Hoshikawa is the criminal.
So, Ms. Mari was protecting Hoshikawa?
Are you kidding? I was hanging onto him when we found Tenko.
I will solve that trick now.
See this corridor'? It's the same as it was back then.
Yes, It was like this.
It is dark, but I can see there is nothing at the end of this corridor.
And what's more, I was holding Hoshikawa's arm like this.
Idiot, you're grabbing too hard.
I won't let you cheat!
Hey...
Hey, come on, explain the trick!
Ah. when Hoshikawa turned on this switch, a power failure occurred.
Fix the breaker.
Oh, Conan!!
When did you get here?
What's going on?
I was here the whole time.
Stop joking. You must have come out from the archives when it was dark.
No. I was in here. The door was not opened.
But I couldn't see Conan...
AAAAAAAAhhhh!
Eh? What is it?
What is it? Conan ...Eh!?
He disappeared?
Not disappeared.
Conan.
Heiji just moved the door of Mr. Masakage's room.
Just like Hoshikawa did in the dark.
Can it be...
Ohhh? What's this?
This hallway is identical to the end of the corridor.
This closet is like the archive room.
The left-hand wall is a screen and.
The small window at the end of the corridor is
a large window half hidden by this cabinet.
The door to Mr. Masakage's room is this.
The back of Mr. Masakage's door is a mirror. Do you get it?
Whet you saw before the power failure occurred is the inside of this room.
So, the body was planted at the end of the corridor from the beginning?
Yeah. When the power failure occurred Hoshikawa closed this door.
But when we entered that room, the back of the door wasn't a mirror.
Yeah, there wasn't a strange door like this one.
Conan?
This door is designed well. It can combine and become one ordinary door.
But this door too thick This line is strange.
Yea. and also, Kazuha and Ran noticed the difference.
You said before, the shadow of the vase changed.
Before Tenko Found
After Tenko found
I remembered, and I am convinced.
They were different places before Tenko was found and after Tenko was found.
But, this house is really tricky.
Of course. Mr. Masakage designed this house to do this trick.
Eh?
He would bring guests to this corridor. and make
Christmas trees appear to surprise them.
So, Ms. Mari immediately realized that Hoshikawa was the criminal.
But, the person who invited us here was Mr. Handa.
At that time, Hoshikawa didn't have the will to kill her.
Maybe it was when Tenko said she was going to perform "Return of the Witch".
No. At first, that show was called "Return of the Devil".
Mr. Masakage thought of it.
Eh?
It has the same setting and direction.
She stole our master's idea.
But that magic is too dangerous to show.
But she only wanted to steal the idea.
It's impossible for her to know about it.
We decided not to show this magic before she became the pupil.
Ms. Hoshikawa protected me and said "the file is in the archive room".
But in fact, he had always had the idea written down.
10 years ago. he said "I forgot that notebook,
I must go fund it "but he never came back.
I wondered how she saw that notebook I called
her to our master's room and asked her.
That's right. I stole it. I'm pretty dexterous.
I will return it if he comes back. I don't think he'll ever be so surprised.
But he may retire because he didn't notice I stole his notebook.
But I think he will be happy if I perform his unpublished magic to the entire world.
Then, you killed her.
Yes. I wasn't thinking.
When I came to, I found her dead.
I remembered the master's "christmas tree" magic, and used it.
And, you broke branches and left a footprint.
Yes.
Maybe the murder weapon is that vase. There is blood in the bottom.
Perhaps Hoshikawa's clothing is stained with blood.
Yeah. The proof is everywhere. I am not very good as a magician.
You are not good because you are not a magician!
You must make up your mind.
Your crime will not disappear like magicians do.
Let's stop the time and hold me tight
I want you to be close
I loved you so many times
Crying till the dawn comes up
Your warmth makes it painful
I'm fearing that I lose my hair when you touch me
This attraction makes us closer
I will find out what tries to tear us apart
stop the time and smile softly
I will be on your side forever
light of the dawn shine on you
and let us shine
What great deduction, Hattori.
Hmm?
Your reasoning may be better than Kudo's.
Oh, you think so too? Hehe.
Oh, I remember something that Heiji said.
Hmm?
"I am irritated when Kazuha us with other men".
Ehh?
What does that mean?
Oh, yes. I understand that now.
Eh? Ehhhh?
Maybe, maybe I...
Ehhhhhh? Stop it, Heiji. Everyone is watching!
I think you are my follower.
Eh? What did you say?
A follower That's it.
A leader feels bad when his follower has fun with others.
So I was irritated.
Why am I your follower?
Your father is a follower of my father. So you are a follower of me.
Haha.
That night, Ran sent me a message.
PS. Shinichi, do you think I am your follower?
Hey. now...