"Star" is a fascinating word.
It can refer to both culprits and actors!
When the heroine gets kidnapped...
What will happen after tonight's show?
Come on! Let's go, Detective Boys!
Seeing through to the one and only truth...
I look like a child, but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
Yes, we felt the same light the moment we met.
Yes, lots and lots of the same emotions filled our eyes.
Although the signals you sent destroyed my theory...
These feelings were always beyond your reach
So, let's fight, go against our morals...
And aim for a wider world!
Oh, glimmering star, shine over us forever.
This way, we won't lose the dreams we had when we were young...
I don't care if this town changes someday.
The only thing I don't want to change is you.
Oh, glimmering star, shine over us forever.
This way, we won't lose the dreams we had when we were young...
The only thing I don't want to change is you.
Halt, ruffian! Heed the words of thine prince!
Thou shall go no further!
Surrender, or prepare thineself for battle!
Forgive me!
Note: The Oyabun" is the head of a Yakuza family, who is similar
in power to that of the head of an Italian Mafia family.
Thank you, Oyabun-san.
All right, that's enough!
Itou Tamanosuke (17)
Tamanosuke Theater Troupe leader
Very good, Guys.
Really?
Especially Conan-kun!
Itou Megumi (7)
Tamanosuke's Little Sister
Oh? Thank you very much!
I'm so glad you think so!
Um... Wait a second, you two...
Hey, Tamanosuke-san?
Is it really okay to let amateurs like us perform with you?
Of course.
You're our special performers that
are separate from the rest of the troupe.
And you guys aren't the problem...
I bought it yesterday.
Why are you just sitting around?
You can still practice, even if you're not on stage!
We're sorry, sir.
Kataoka Renge (17)
Tamanosuke Theater Troupe Member
You shouldn't need to check your lines now!
How long do you think we've been practicing for?
I'm sorry.
Don't apologize so easily...
If you can't put your heart and
soul into acting, just get out of here!
I'm sorr-
I mean... Yes, sir!
Scary. He seems like a completely different person.
No, Genta-kun. He's an example of a great actor.
Very admirable.
By the way, doesn't Renge-san
kind of look like Ran-oneesan?
All right, let's get started!
Itou Tamanosuke.
This young leader and his popular traveling
theater troupe came to our town to perform a play.
Simultaneous Stages of Advancing and Kidnapping.
Part 1!
Ran! Hurry up, hurry up!
Tamanosuke-san's rehearsal will end!
But I have to make my dad's lunch.
Just leave him, just leave him.
He's probably drinking or sleeping anyway.
Wait, Sonoko!
Do I have a cold?
Ah, or is it...
That?
You feel guilty towards your detective husband?
Come to think of it...
Tamanosuke-san does resemble him a little.
I'm talking about Shinichi-kun.
You think so? I don't think they look alike at all.
Anyways, the performance was "The Legend of
the Bamboo Cutter," about Princess Kaguya, right?
Yes! Princess Kaguya is Tamanosuke-san's lover!
Oh, how I wish I could be her!
Oh, Sonoko...
Sure looks like an expensive car.
I wonder who that could be.
This way, sir.
Gosh.
What was that for?! How rude!
No, that isn't right!
No way.
I've come to take you home, Renge.
Come on, let's go home together.
I refuse! I'm staying right here!
Renge!
Oonuki.
Yes, sir.
Please follow me, Milady.
I don't want to.
Let go of me!
Milady!
What? What's going on?
If I remember right, that's the
actress who playing Princess Kaguya...
Hold on.
What is this? Who are you?
My name is Kataoka Hanshirou.
Kataoka Hanshirou (60)
Head of the Kataoka Family
I'm Kataoka Renge's father.
Ichimura Kikuno (40)
Tamanosuke Theater Troupe Member
Bando Hikoemon
Kataoka?
Hanshirou?
Isn't that...
He is the founder and chairman of the Kataoka Company.
What? That means...
That girl's rich.
Wow.
Renge, you didn't tell us anything about this.
That's because...
It doesn't matter!
My acting has nothing to do with this!
Well...
Renge-chan, could it be that you're...
Running away from home?
I haven't heard from her for half a year.
That's why I've had Oonuki
searching for her this whole time.
Onoe Mataroku (35)
Tamanosuke Theater Troupe Member
Sawamura Kantarou (23)
Azuma Yoichi (28)
Tamanosuke Theater Troupe Member
What a surprise.
Well, we're in a similar situation ourselves.
We can't do anything for our
parents because we're always traveling.
That may be true...
But it's not good to worry them like she did.
Oonuki.
Yes.
Oonuki Souichi (38)
Kataoka's Private Secretary
Come on, let's get going, Milady.
No, I'm not going home.
I'll..
I'll never go home!
Milady!
Oonuki!
Yes, sir.
We're sorry for getting you involved in this.
To compensate you for the trouble that she's caused you...
I don't need anything from you.
I have no reason to take it.
L-Leader...
Go home now, Renge.
Renge, go home and clarify things, then come back.
Wait, Leader!
How are we supposed to practice without her?
The show is in three days, after all.
True, that could be bad.
But we can't let things stay the way they are.
That's right.
Go home, Renge.
Wait!
Milady!
Please wait, Leader! I'm-
Ran-chan, can you come over here for a second?
Oh, sure.
Someone, go get the props and dress for Princess Kaguya.
H-Hey, could it be that...
No way!
Don't tell me you're going to
have Ran be Range-san's substitute?
What?
It's true that we cannot practice without Kaguya.
We need to be ready by the first day of the show.
That's why you want her to help until then?
Well, I guess there's no other choice.
True.
Well then, let's get started!
Miss!
He's cruel, isn't he?
The leader?
True.
That's not it!
He believes Renge-chan will come back!
Yes, that much is obvious.
Wow! You're so pretty, Ran-oneesan!
You really are beautiful.
You should be in the real show, too!
I agree!
Hey, hey...
But I think that'd go over badly with her...
Look.
W-What?
Ah! A love scene!
You mean they will be performing this scene?
Ran-san and Tamanosuke-san?
Whew, it sure is good he didn't hear that.
Good thing that mystery maniac isn't here, right?
He's right here.
Anyways... why didn't I get to play the princess?!
But Renge-san never came back.
The morning of the opening day of the show came.
A Theatrical Production Performed by the Renowned Tamanosuke Theater Troupe
The Legend of the
Bamboo Cutter
Only three more hours, huh?
We can't just cancel the show at this point.
We're going to perform without a protagonist?
Leader.
What are you going to do?
I'm going to get her.
By "going to get her," do you mean...
Renge-chan?
That'll be tough to do with that old man around...
Maybe she changed her mind
and doesn't want to come beck.
That can't be! That would mean this play is...
Canceled, of course!
I've never heard of
"The Legend of the Bamboo Cutter" without Kaguya!
I'm going.
Leader!
Wait, Tamanosuke-san!
I also have something important to
tell Renge-san, since I'm her substitute.
Please hurry, Driver-san!
Kataoka
Conan-kun!
Ah-le-le? It's Taka-
Y-You guys?
What are you doing here?
Dad?
Takagi-kun.
Sorry. I don't know where the culprit could
be watching us from, so I had to let them in.
Culprit?
You again? What is it this time?
Don't you know?
Where is she?
Where's Renge?
I had thought she was at the
theater with you and the others.
She's been missing since last night...
Ever since she left to go shopping.
What?!
What happened, Dad?
This is none of your business.
Conan-kun?
Hey, Conan!
A ransom of... ￥1,500,000?!
Renge-san.
"...Emai Electronics, Kato Network, Nakao Media..."
"Each of these three companies pay a third of the ransom."
"Get the money ready by 2:00 PM..."
"And have your secretary bring it to the
parking lot in the first block of Yoshioka."
A ransom?
Could it be...
A kidnapping?
So you received this about an hour ago?
This e-mail threat?
Yes.
Who sent it?
I've never seen something like
this done on such a large scale.
This technique is typically seen in
international crimes and is a worldwide problem.
Kataoka-san, the message says each of the
three companies need to pay a third of the ransom.
Oonuki.
Yes.
We have been doing business with those three companies.
But why do they have to pay the ransom?
Well...
Go ahead, explain.
Yes.
To be honest, the CEOs of those three companies
have all asked for Milady Renge's hand in marriage.
What?
Ah, that's like...
Um...
Yeah, it's just like Snow White!
Dad! Don't you mean Princess Kaguya?
Oh, yeah... Some people call her that, too.
That's the only name people call her.
But still, what is it?
Something about this is bugging me.
Excuse me.
Tell them to leave.
I don't want to hear any more excuses.
What happened?
One of the companies can't prepare the ransom
money because of their current financial situation.
That's ridiculous.
The CEO just got scared of the scandal
It would get the company involved in.
I will never forgive him for choosing his
company over my sweet daughter, Renge!
But what about the ransom?
I'll use my own money and
prepare it under that company's name.
However, I will no longer
consider giving my daughter away to him.
Dropping out from the marriage race, huh?
It's just like...
Forgive me!
Snow White.
Princess Kaguya!
Ah, that's right... That's right.
Also, the other two companies
have already brought the money.
And I will take the money to the
designated area when it is time.
For now, we should go along with the demands...
And observe their reaction.
I'll personally make sure that your
daughter's safety is the police force's top priority.
I'll leave her in your care, then.
This is...
This video was cut and spliced together.
The culprit probably stopped the camera and
closed the windows and curtains to get rid of the glare.
No, wait a minute...
What's this?
There's something on her head.
Was it from that spiderweb?
No, it couldn't be, because it's too far away from her.
That place...
I think I've seen that place somewhere before.
Hey!
How many times do I have to
tell you to get away, you brat?!
Dad!
Sorry!
Damn it! I was so close.
Renge-san was kidnapped?
We won't be able to get back to the theater for a while.
Ayumi-chan, how are things going over there?
Everyone is worried, since there's
less than an hour before the show.
What are we supposed to do, Conan-kun?
Get it off! Get it off!
Sonoko-oneesan?
Jeez...
It's because you keep going inside weird places.
And it's just a spiderweb...
You could get it off yourself, you know?
I'm asking you because I can't do it by myself!
Especially since I hate spiders!
By herself? Because she can't do it by herself?
Oh, I get it!
A fake kidnapping?
Renge set it up?
Why would she do that?
Maybe she didn't want to get married.
What do you mean?
I'm not sure, but...
The reason she demanded money from the
people who proposed to her was probably because...
She did what Princess Kaguya did in the
story, in order to tell her dad how she felt?
Yep, I think that's probably what happened.
Even so, that doesn't give her a reason to do such a thing.
Hey, kid. Renge was in a warehouse, wasn't she?
Yeah, it seemed like it.
Then she has to be at that place!
Let's go!
Ah, wait!
Tamanosuke-san!
Our group rented this place to
store our extra props and costumes.
I'm guessing Renge had a spare key.
There's no mistaking it, this is the place.
Should we inform my dad?
It doesn't seem like anyone is here, though.
Renge!
Renge-san!
I knew it.
Look!
R-Renge...
At that moment, the kidnapping was no longer a hoax.
Somehow, Renge-san was actually kidnapped.
And her kidnapper is most likely the person
who helped her carry out her fake kidnapping.
I will be off.
Huh? Where's Ran and the others?
Where on earth did they go?
Inspector, he left.
All right.
The case started to progress...
Just as the curtains rose.
Stop the world and hold me tight.
I want to be closer to you.
I've fallen for you time and time again.
My tears overflow as the dawn approaches.
The warmth you give me makes me forget to take a breath.
And I'm afraid of losing the feeling of your fingertips stroking my hair.
The attraction that pulls us together...
Should we be separated tomorrow, I would search for you to no end.
Stop the world and smile gently...
Because I will always be by your side.
Let the light of dawn shine upon you...
And envelop the two of us like this forever.
Once upon a time, there was an
old man who harvested bamboo.
Please let me do it.
Ran...
Ran-chan...
They got away!
After them!
We'll find Renge-san for sure!
I found it, Conan-kun!
Come back quickly, Renge-san... Tamanosuke-san...
Next Conan:
Simultaneous Stages of Advancing and Kidnapping, Part 2.
Next Conan's Hint!
A phone call from the culprit.
Please look forward to the next episode!
I'm Princess Kaguya in the next episode!
Thank you very much!
Um, what?