"Star" is a fascinating word.
It can refer to both culprits and actors!
Time is running out, Detective Boys!
Let's solve this case...
And get her back before the show starts!
Seeing through to the one and only truth...
I look like a child, but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
Yes, we felt the same light the moment we met.
Yes, lots and lots of the same emotions filled our eyes.
Although the signals you sent destroyed my theory...
These feelings were always beyond your reach
So, let's fight, go against our morals...
And aim for a wider world!
Oh, glimmering star, shine over us forever.
This way, we won't lose the dreams we had when we were young...
I don't care if this town changes someday.
The only thing I don't want to change is you.
Oh, glimmering star, shine over us forever.
This way, we won't lose the dreams we had when we were young...
The only thing I don't want to change is you.
Itou Tamanosuke's popular traveling
theater troupe came to our town to perform a play.
This time, they'd be performing an
adaptation of "The Legend of the Bamboo Cutter."
However, Kataoka Renge-san, who was supposed to
play Princess Kaguya, the main character, was kidnapped.
Once the police started investigating...
I discovered it was a staged
kidnapping that Renge-san had planned herself.
However, Renge-san was not at the confinement area.
Somehow, she was actually kidnapped.
The case started to progress...
And now, the curtains begin to rise.
Simultaneous Stages of Advancing and Kidnapping:
Part 2!
Once upon a time, there was an
old man who harvested bamboo.
What's going on?
The play started!
But Princess Kaguya isn't here.
I wonder if she's okay.
Leader could it be that...
You really...
You really intend to let her be in the actual play?
She's the main character, she's Kaguya!
Azuma Yoichi (28)
Tamanosuke Theater Troupe Member
Sawamura Kantarou (23)
Her lines aren't easy either.
That's true...
No worries.
I've changed the script.
Everyone, please memorize this quickly.
Onoe Mataroku (35)
Tamanosuke Theater Troupe Member
I added more scenes from Kaguya's childhood
and removed the scenes that show her later years.
Later on, I'll redirect Kaguya's stage direction as
well as the lighting so that her face is mostly hidden.
However, she has to show her face during
the climax scene where she goes to the moon.
Itou Tamanosuke (17)
Tamanosuke Theater Troupe Leader
I'm telling you, this isn't going to work...
"Traveling and performing this is our life."
Ichimura Kikuno (40)
Tamanosuke Theater Troupe Member
"When it rains, it pours."
Bandouhiko Emon (50)
Tamanosuke Theater Troupe Member
"If we combine our efforts in times like these,
we can create an outstanding performance."
That was a famous line.
From the old man -l mean, the predecessor.
Let's trust Renge-chan to come back
and just do the best we can for now.
No, but-
Please let me do it!
Ran.
The audience is out there waiting for us.
Cancelling it on them would be...
Please let me do it!
I'm begging you!
Ran-chan.
Let's do it!
Since she asked so sincerely.
Yeah. We have to, since she asked us so sincerely.
That's true.
I'll be under your guidance then.
Thank you.
Thank you, you guys!
Hey, Tamanosuke-san...
When is the climax in the performance?
Well...
The whole play is two hours, so
it'd be about an hour and a half in?
Although that's just an estimate.
So that means we just have to
find Renge-oneesan by then, right?
Do you have a clue or something
that could help us find her, little boy?
Huh?
Well, I guess...
We've been waiting for this!
Please leave it to us!
This is a call for the Detective Boys!
Yeah!
Hey, hey...
I never asked for help from you guys...
Then I'm coming, too.
Tamanosuke-san...
My part isn't until the second half, which is in an hour.
Until then, I'll help look for Renge.
Leader...
The case was progressing.
Oonuki Souichi (38)
Kataoka's Private Secretary
Can you hear me, officer?
We are approaching the parking lot.
Oh? He seems to have received
an envelope with something in it.
It says to drive in the designated car.
License plate number...
This is the car.
Officer, there is a cell phone.
I will answer it.
Hello?
Yes.
I understand.
I was told to drive north of Takayama Road.
I will follow their directions.
The girl was incomparably beautiful.
Her presence lit up the dark room.
You're almost up, Ran-san!
Calm down.
I need to relax.
Wasn't this the place where Renge-san was kept?
Yes, although that turned out to be a sham.
So what you're saying is that Renge's
accomplice turned out to be her actual kidnapper?
Is that right, little boy?
Yeah, I think so.
There's no doubt about it.
So, the problem is figuring out
who that person could be, huh?
But there aren't many people a
young woman could easily turn to for help.
What is it, Conan-kun?
Do you happen to see something?
Hold on...
Oh, isn't that just a construction site?
Hey, if I remember right, wasn't there...
Yeah, there was!
There was!
Huh? What?
What's going on?
What is it?
Meanwhile...
In another part of town...
What? But...
Yes.
I understand.
Inspector!
They got away!
After them!
Hey, Mouri-kun!
Wait up!
He turned right at that corner, Inspector!
Takagi-kun!
Yes, sir!
Oonuki-san!
Are you all right?
Get a hold of yourself!
What happened?
They ordered me on the cell phone
to ditch the police and come here...
And when I parked my car, all of the sudden-
I'm very sorry.
Emergency, Takagi-kun.
Yes, sir.
Well? What about the hostage?
He will return her after he has confirmed her safety.
He told us to wait until then.
Damn it, making this some kind of joke...
Ah, Officer Takagi?
Uncle Mouri told me to ask you to
check something really quick for him.
Sorry, I'm really busy right now.
Eh? What do you mean?
The play was also progressing.
The first nobleman, Prince Ishizukuri, was told to bring
the stone beggar bowl that the Buddha himself had used.
The second nobleman, Prince Kuramochi, was told to
travel to bring back a branch from a tree on Mt. Horai.
The third nobleman, Sadaijin Dainagon, was told to
find a robe made from the pelts of flameproof rats.
Oh, I'm so nervous.
Come back quickly, Renge-san... Tamanosuke-san...
Yes, of course I was not looking behind me.
Hey, you guys can't come in here!
You're not allowed to cross the yellow line!
We're sorry!
Well, did you catch him in the emergency deployment?
Huh? It hasn't even been a minute...
Ah! I just said you can't go in there!
Were there any witnesses?
Um, aren't you...?
That doesn't matter. What about the witnesses?
When that guy was attacked!
So no one was watching?
It happened immediately after I got out of my car.
Those are...
Security cameras.
Thank you for your cooperation.
How is it, little boy?
Yeah.
There's no mistake.
What do you mean, Conan-kun?
Are there any clues in that video?
But that camera doesn't show the actual scene.
Yeah. But the culprit-
Hey!
Stop fooling around!
I'm sorry.
I thought you were okay with it, Mouri-san.
I knew it was something like that, so-
Huh? Where'd he go?
Huh? Did it come?
Mouri-san?
Officer Takagi.
Yes?
Gather everyone here.
What? S-Sure.
I also have one more request...
Y-Yes?
What is the meaning of this, Mouri-kun?
Officer Takagi.
Yes.
It's already here.
I requested that the
investigation headquarters forward this to us.
The problem is the chimney in this picture.
This was actually demolished four days ago.
What?
They got rid of it because the
public bathhouse was being remodeled.
In other words, this picture was
not taken at the time it was sent.
Which means...
If they had the e-mail prepared beforehand,
the sender could have been with the recipient.
S-So you're trying to say that the
culprit was someone she knew personally?
Officer Takagi.
Yes.
Mouri-san asked me to look into some things.
And I found that this time, the culprit sent
the e-mail they had prepared beforehand...
Always took the phone calls...
And is someone who could come into
direct contact with her without being suspected.
L-Let's not joke around.
Please take a look at the video from the security camera.
Oonuki-san, you said you followed the
culprit's directions and tried to ditch the police, right?
That is precisely correct.
When was that?
"When?"
At the traffic light.
I'm pretty sure the officers also heard the conversation.
But we didn't hear the culprit's voice.
W-Well, I was on the phone...
Did you really receive a call?
What are you implying?
So, why did the culprit take the
cell phone in addition to the money?
That's because...
What? But...
Yes.
I understand.
This is...
As you can see here, he isn't using his cell phone.
If you checked his cell phone, there
wouldn't be a record of a call in the call log.
That's why he didn't leave it there.
He most likely hid it somewhere, along with the ransom.
If we searched the whole area, we'd probably find it.
But before that, we must rescue the victim.
What do you mean?
Only the culprit knows.
I don't know!
I don't know anything!
Don't lie, Oonuki!
Where is my daughter?
Where is Renge?
Chairman...
If something happens to my
daughter, I won't let you get away with it!
Remember that!
T-T-That's not it!
She asked me to help, so I-
Help?
That's right. It started out as a fake kidnapping.
Of course, Renge-san would be
able to mention her accomplice's name.
And since her accomplice is also her real kidnapper...
He can't allow her to return safely by any means.
So you intended to murder her from the beginning?
I don't know!
I don't know anything!
I'm definitely not going to tell you people anything!
You're not going anywhere, Oonuki-san.
In order to protect Kaguya, Mikado sent an
entire troop of 2,000 soldiers to prevent her departure.
Don't worry.
We'll definitely find Renge-oneesan.
Leave it to us!
Detective Boys! Let's go!
Yeah!
Big brother, hurry and come back.
If I'm right, it should be around here...
Here it is.
This.
What is that?
Weeds?
But why are they muddy when it hasn't even rained?
Were they growing near water?
Yes, that's it!
I shan't let her go!
Tamanosuke-san...
I shan't let you return to the moon, Kaguya.
Oh my gosh, no way! Seriously?
Or, if thou wilt not cease, be but sworn my love...
And I shall depart from this country and my family.
Tamanosuke-san's eyes aren't
looking at Princess Kaguya nor at me.
Won't thou trust me and stay by my side?
Kaguya, always and forever...
Since the culprit was alone, and
was thinking of all of this on the spot...
I don't think he had enough time to have taken her too far.
That means the next possible place is nearby.
It's probably...
Somewhere with water, right?
Roger!
Leave it to me!
The light that shined in the dark night
seemed brighter than the sun in midday.
A great cloud descended from the moon
bringing with it a great host of moon-folk.
We found her, Conan-kun!
Are you all right, Renge-oneesan?
What about the play?
What happened to the play?
Now, Kaguya, come with me.
To the moon where thou belongs.
So this is it, huh?
Oh, I can't watch.
Renge-san!
Renge?
I can't.
I've caused so much trouble...
I can't go out there now.
What are you saying, Renge-san?
You have to do it.
For the sake of both Tamanosuke-san and yourself...
I know...
Ran.
Renge-san.
We shalt meet again.
I believe we shall.
Kaguya.
No, Renge.
Yes.
I'm sort of disappointed, but it was a beautiful play.
Stop the world and hold me tight.
I want to be closer to you.
I've fallen for you time and time again.
My tears overflow as the dawn approaches.
The warmth you give me makes me forget to take a breath.
And I'm afraid of losing the feeling of your fingertips stroking my hair.
The attraction that pulls us together...
Should we be separated tomorrow, I would search for you to no end.
Stop the world and smile gently...
Because I will always be by your side.
Let the light of dawn shine upon you...
And envelop the two us of like this forever.
After that, Oonuki was arrested.
The ransom was also found.
Like Princess Kaguya, Renge-san returned home...
And finally convinced her father
to let her stay in the theater troupe.
She is now traveling the world with
Tamanosuke-san and the rest of the troupe.
It was also the beginning of
Tamanosuke-san's and Renge-san's new life together.