Hoshi no kagayaki yo
A BAARO FANSUB
There's something fascinating about stars,
be they criminals or actors.
Today's stage is a village shrine.
Another meaning to the letters we've been seeing hides an unexpected secret!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
Rhinoceros beetles, rhinoceros beetles!
It's fun to catch beetles!
Yay!
It's gotta be around here...
Why do I have to look for bugs
on a hot day like this?
Hey, Mitsuhiko. Are you sure they're around here?
Wait just a second...
And there's trash everywhere! Way up on this mountain!
It can't be helped!
The villagers usually keep this forest tidy,
but the place was swarming with revelers last night, thanks to the festival.
F-Festival?
It's called the Tentō Festival, or Festival of Light!
Giant carts carrying images of the Shinto gods are pulled through town!
See that shrine over there?
That's where the festival carts begin!
They shoot fireworks behind the gods!
What a magnificent sight it was!
Were you there?
Oh, er...
Why didn't you invite us?
No fair!
I wanna see fireworks too!
The Surprising Code at the Shrine Tori'i
(Part 1)
W-We were out past your bedtimes.
Right, Ai-kun?
No kidding. I barely got any sleep last night.
You never sleep enough.
What were you two doing?
Catching bugs?
Well, something like that...
We haven't found any big beetles...
You'll never find them by wandering blindly around.
We weren't wandering blindly!
We were looking around the sawtooth oak trees the beetles prefer!
Try touching the ground beneath the tree, Mitsuhiko.
It's hard, isn't it?
Y-Yes...
Also, you hardly see any fallen leaves or twigs, just trash.
The larva of the rhinoceros beetle lives in soft ground created by decaying leaves,
and the larva of the stag beetle lives in dead trees.
You won't find either species in areas that are cleaned regularly and kept free of dead plant matter.
You sure know a lot.
If you want to find big beetles, try the forest on the other side of our tent.
The best time is probably the break of dawn.
Then let's eat dinner and go to sleep!
But don't get your hopes up!
Beetle catching season runs from June to the Obon festival in August.
This late in the summer, the trees may not be giving off enough of the sap the beetles love to feed on.
Now, now! No long faces!
I have a special treasure for you!
A treasure!
Yup! Something you'll love!
W-Where is it?
In order to find it...
First...tada!
you'll have to decipher this secret code!
"ma..."
"marumushi
ni
tento?" (round bug and tent)
What's that?
Does that mean the pill bugs (marumushi) that curl up into a ball when you touch them?
We're supposed to pitch a tent on top of them?
Maybe "tento" means "tentomushi" (ladybug)!
I don't get it.
At times like this...
After all...
Right?
Right.
We can ask Conan-kun!
No! Don't ask Edogawa-kun for help!
Why not, Haibara-san?
It's a bad idea to rely on other people all the time!
If you lie down and think about it, I bet you can figure it out!
If you still can't solve the code, splash some water on your faces and try again.
Try again...
You say that, but...
You two are so mean!
Why do you say that, Ai-chan?
Shin'ichi, can I ask you a favor?
Could you sneak over to the location in the code and check it out?
What? Sure...
If Ai-kun or I try to sneak off, they might catch us.
Oh? Don't tell me you can't solve my secret code!
Well, excuse me...
Oh, really?
Blame Ai-kun! She came up with it!
Don't let him fool you.
You're just pretending to struggle with the code to pump up Doc's ego, right?
Really?
There's no way he can't solve it.
It's such a simple children's trick.
Isn't that right, Mr. Modern-Day Holmes?
She really knows how to get on my nerves.
You can't solve the code either, Conan-kun?
Just like us!
It's okay! It means you're an ordinary first-grader after all!
Fine, fine! Here's an idea!
Marumushi, or "round bug", doesn't actually stand for a bug.
It refers to crustaceans like crabs or prawns.
You know how they protect themselves from enemies with their tough outer shells?
It's just like the way a person sleeps in a tent on the mountainside!
And they can both curl up in a ball too!
And?
S-So...
So?
By figuring out what they have in common...
We won't get anywhere.
A text...
Let's talk about the code later!
Conan-kun?
Huh? From Sonoko?
A photo...
W-What is this?!
Just what the heck is this?
Now I've got a call.
It's Ran...
Voice changer, voice changer...
What's he doing?
I don't know...
R-Ran?
What's up?
I'm sorry, Shin'ichi!
Sonoko just sent you a weird photo, didn't she?
Delete it right now!
No, don't delete it!
It's a special sexy shot of your sweetie, taken by yours truly!
Hey, what are you telling him?
Special sexy shot?
This is...?
Ran?!
There goes my nose.
Come to think of it, Ran said she was going to the beach with Sonoko...
Hey...
Who are you talking to, Conan-kun?
"Conan-kun"?
Is Conan-kun with you?
Y-Yikes!
E-Er...
Not Conan! Cocaine!
You see, the case I'm connecting on is connected to a drug bust...
Don't get tangled up in anything too dangerous!
Um, right...
Okay, if that's all you called for, I'd better hang up...
But... The photo...
I know! I'll delete it! Bye!
Save... Save...
But...
If she finds this on Conan's phone, the jig's up.
Hey! I saw a marumushi!
Where did you find it?
Under a rock or something?
No! On a sign!
On the other side of the forest!
A-A sign?
You're not pulling our legs, are you, Genta-kun?
See? Made it! Look! Over there!
Look at that!
It says "Marumushi", right?
"Marumushi Hot Spring"
"Marumushi Hot Spring"?
I've heard of the Asamushi Hot Spring, but...
It's a run-down old inn. The sign's falling off.
I bet there's a tent inside!
And the clue to solving the code will be hidden inside that tent!
Then let's go!
Let's go!
Yeah!
I don't see why they said "Yeah!" so enthusiastically...
I sense another dead end.
I don't get it.
I was so sure something was hidden there.
The inn was closed, and I didn't see a tent anyway.
It looked empty...
Well? Give up?
Yeah, yeah.
I hate to say it, but...
Show us the treasure!
Very well!
The secret code is actually...
Wait, Doc!
We still have one person who hasn't given up...
C'mon, Conan!
Just say uncle!
Desperate times call for desperate measures!
It's funny, though.
Conan-kun loves codes and solves then all the time with no problem!
Maybe the sun fried your brain.
Knock it off.
It's just...
I can't really get into it unless a case is involved.
A phone call...
Ran again...
Geez, what is it this time?
Yes? Hello?
Shin'ichi!
You have to help us!
There's been a murder! Sonoko and I were attacked too!
What's going on? Are you running from the murderer now?
No, we're safe.
We're not hurt, and the police are here.
Who was killed?
A man named Miyama who was staying at our hotel!
Miyama
University Student
Were you attacked because you saw the murder?
No, we didn't see it.
We only found out somebody had been murdered after the police arrived.
You were attacked with cops around?
No, it was later, in an alley as we were leaving the police station!
But it was too dark to see who it was...
You think it was the murderer?
I don't know.
Whoever it was grabbed Sonoko's bag, so maybe it was just a purse snatcher.
What are you doing?! Give that back!
Wait... Why were you at the police station in the first place?
Sonoko remembered seeing some strange writing
on the window of the room where the murder took place,
so we went to tell the police about it.
Strange writing?
Like some kind of code...
A code?
What are you so happy about? A man just died!
Uh, sorry...
Well? What did it say?
According to Sonoko, it was written sideways in red, like lipstick.
It was four lowercase letters...
"t", "e", "i" and "u".
"teiu"?
Right. Sonoko told the police it was probably a message left by the victim...
Not "probably"! I'm sure of it! It was his dying message!
The victim was trying to write "te iu ka", "y'know", when he died!
S-Sonoko...
I dub this case...
The Y'Know Murder
"The Y'Know Murder"?
Are you kidding me, Sonoko?
This is no joke!
The word "teiu" was written on the window of the room where Miyama was killed!
T-E-I-U, "teiu", what else could it mean?
He must've tried to write "te iu ka", slang for "you know"!
To be honest, Miyama-san did use that phrase a lot when he talked to us at the beach.
That's right. Face it, Shin'ichi, y'know this is "The Y'Know Murder!"
That "i" in "teiu"...
Could it have actually been the letter "l"?
"l"?
N-Now that you mention it, maybe it was...
But so what?
And the fourth letter, "u".
Was the right side slightly shorter than the left?
Maybe it was the hiragana character shi (し).
When you put it that way...
Maybe it did look a bit like that...
The letters T-E-L and the hiragana "shi"... Put them together and what do you get?
TEL... TEL SHI...
I've got it!
"TEL shite" - "please call"!
He was trying to ask someone to call for help!
I knew you could do it, Shin'ichi!
Yeah, yeah... Your hubby sure is something!
W-We're not married!
What are you saying, Sonoko? No way...
Ran, you're turning red!
Can you tell me more about the murder?
Oh, right.
According to the police, he was found near the window of his hotel room, bleeding from the head.
He'd been bludgeoned with something hard.
Then those letters on the window were probably written in his own blood.
They were red, right?
Who found the body?
Three of Miyama-san's friends!
Kano-san, an old friend from college...
Kano
Miyama's university classmate
Yanuma-san, his girlfriend...
Yanuma
Miyama's girlfriend
and Bito-san, a friend from his part-time job.
Bito
Miyama's co-worker
They were going out to dinner together.
When Miyama-san didn't show up on time, they went to his room and found the door unlocked.
They went inside and found Miyama-san lying on the ground under a broken window.
At least, that's what they told the police.
The window was broken?
Yeah.
The police think the murderer smashed the window to enter the room from the outside.
After Sonoko remembered seeing those letters, we went to the police to tell them,
but they didn't find any sign of writing on the fragments of the broken window.
They wouldn't believe us, especially since "teiu" made no sense.
That's when I told them, "Fine, I'll get you the proof!"
Wait. Do you have proof?
I sent it to you, didn't I?
That super-special sexy shot of Ran I took with my cell phone!
I noticed the red writing when I took that photo,
so it should be visible behind Ran.
"Should be"? Haven't you checked it?
No!
I thought I left my phone at the hotel, so we left the police station to get it.
But on the way back I noticed it was in my bag after all, so we turned around,
and that's when the purse snatcher stole my bag!
I can't let the police think I made it all up!
That's why I made Ran call you, so you can send us your copy of the photo!
I told her to forget it. You've already deleted it!
You did delete it, didn't you?
Uh... Yeah... Of course...
See?
For real?
Er... Anyway, now that you know what the message meant,
you can go back and tell the cops!
Thanks! I'll call you if anything else comes up!
Um... Sure...
That sexy shot... Is he kidding?
Photo... Photo...
Aha! There's the red writing she was talking about.
Sonoko was right. It looks like it's written on the window.
The curtain's closed, so I can't see inside the room.
And Ran's waist is in the way, so I can only make out one letter.
There's a little red mark to the left of the "t".
A comma? Or just a blotch?
What a strange case.
If the victim wrote "please call" on the window as he was dying,
I guess the murderer noticed it later and broke the window to take the fragments with writing on them.
Maybe the murderer did that to delay the discovery of the body.
But breaking a window is so risky...
Hey!
What're you looking at, Conan-kun?
What, what?
What's that?
Whoa! It's a naked lady!
What?!
Conan-kun?!
I think it's against the law for kids our age to see that kind of thing!
No, it's not...
I-It's just a prank mail!
I clicked on a strange e-mail I got, and it sent me to a site with this picture!
So, have you solved Doc's secret code yet?
Nope. Not even close.
How can we?
It even stumped you, Conan-kun!
Doc let us have the paper with the code.
"Marumushi ni tento"...
"Marumushi"...
I wonder if we'll really find where the treasure is after solving the code...
I'd rather have gone to the festival last night with Doc...
Festival?
Come to think of it, that festival is called the Tentō Festival.
Huh? What did you just say?
See that lighted shrine over there?
Doc said the festival carts start from that point.
Then maybe the "tento" part of the code refers to the Tentō Festival!
Even if that's the case, I don't understand the "marumushi" in front of it.
Maybe it's about that inn we found, the Marumushi Hot Spring!
But that inn was closed.
The door was locked and no one answered, even when we raised our voices.
What is it?
Look! There's a light over there!
That's in the direction of the Marumushi Hot Spring!
"Marumushi ni tentō" - "Light up the Marumushi"...
That's gotta be it!
We've figured it out!
Let's check it out!
Yeah!
NEXT EPISODE
You give up, right?
You guys give up too easily.
First of all, the code is written entirely in katakana.
Secondly, if you look closely, each character is strangely crooked.
And thirdly,
we've got the clues Doc and Haibara gave us.
Wait a minute!
That means...
Damn! I should've realized it sooner!
Next Conan:
The Surprising Code at the Shrine Tori'i
(Part 2)
Next Conan's Hint
Front and back
Look forward to the next episode!
It's the same word as "backward"!
The bamboo grove burned down.
Wow!
Ear!
Huh?