(ムラマツリノトリイ MU RA MA TSU RI NO TO RI I)
There's something fascinating about stars,
be they criminals or actors.
The weird code that Doc came up with...
It's tougher than the Detective Boys expected!
Who will solve it first?
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Created by
Gosho Aoyama
"Detective Conan"
Serialized in Shogakukan's
'Weekly Shonen Sunday'
Planning
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Character Design
Mari Tominaga
Art Director
Yasutada Kato
Director of Photography
Takahisa Ogawa
Sound Directors
Yasuo Urakami
Motoi Izawa
Music
Katsuo Ono
Opening Theme
"Hoshi no kagayaki yo"
Performed by
Lyrics
Music
Arrangement
Izumi Sakai
Aika Ono
Takeshi Hayama
Editor
Terumitsu Okada
Story Editor
Jun'ichi Iioka
Color Key
Fusako Nakao
Executive Producer
Makoto Moriwaki
Planning Support
Shin'ichiro Tsuzuki
Masato Hayashi
Toyohiko Okuyama
Masahiko Ishikawa
Producer
Hiroaki Kobayashi
Associate Producer
Mitome Asai
Chief Producers
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Masahito Yoshioka
(Tokyo Movie)
Director
Masato Sato
One hot summer day,
we were out to collect bugs.
Doc gave us a code quiz,
"marumushi ni tento", which would lead us to where a treasure was hidden.
But I couldn't solve the code either.
Meanwhile, Ran and Sonoko called me from the beach,
saying there was a murder at the hotel where they were staying.
Sonoko remembered seeing some strange writing
on the window of the room where the murder took place...
Strange writing?
Like some kind of code...
Who found the body?
Three of Miyama-san's friends!
They were going out to dinner together.
When Miyama-san didn't show up on time, they went to his room and found the door unlocked.
They went inside and found Miyama-san lying on the ground under a broken window.
At least, that's what they told the police.
After that, we...
Then maybe the "tento" part of the code refers to the Tentō Festival!
Even if that's the case, I don't understand the "marumushi" in front of it.
That's in the direction of the Marumushi Hot Spring!
"Marumushi ni tentō" - "Light up the Marumushi"...
Huh?
There's a lot of people...
It's some mysterious gathering...
Get real. Take a closer look!
They're carrying washbowls, see?
You're right!
The village probably bought this run-down inn on the cheap and turned it into a public bath.
I see...
Bath... sentō...
Maybe tento is really sentō! You know, a public bath!
Now see, Genta-kun.
No matter how you look at it, that "te" doesn't look like a "se".
And it's not tentō, as in "light", either. It's clearly spelled tento.
Damn it!
I just don't get it!
C'mon, Genta. You can't just collapse and give up!
I'm not giving up!
Remember what Doc said?
He said we might be able to solve the code if we lay down and thought about it!
Yeah, but...
Come to think of it, Ai-chan said...
if we're stuck, we should splash water on our faces!
Well, we've got a public bath here.
Let's take her advice and wash off!
Ooh, good idea!
Forget it.
Ai-chan?
Trust me, you won't find anything in that inn.
Nothing at all!
Then tell us!
Where's the treasure?
Please, tell us!
Sure... I'll tell you...
if a certain someone also gives up.
Give up, my arm!
A text...
It's Sonoko.
Hey. I thought Sonoko had her bag stolen with her cell phone inside it.
"I found this bag abandoned on a street,
but there was nothing to identify the owner by.
I checked the cell phone I found inside the bag
and decided to send a message to the most recent person on the list of calls.
I would like to send the bag to you, so please give me your name and address."
Huh. I guess the purse snatcher threw Sonoko's bag away after stealing it.
But why isn't this person asking me for the address of the owner of the bag?
And why text me? Wouldn't it be easier to just call someone?
You give up, right?
H-Hey, time out!
Or they could hand the bag over to the cops!
Hello, Ran?
I just received a text from someone who claims to have found Sonoko's bag.
What? Really?
Yeah.
They may contact you too. Wait for the call...
I can't!
What's up?
My phone's almost dead!
I'm at the police station now,
but I'll call you back as soon as we get to the hotel.
Then you told them the message might be "tel shite", "please call"?
Yeah.
The police and Miyama-san's three friends said that could be a possibility!
But it doesn't identify the murderer,
so we're going back to the hotel for the night.
Hey, be careful. That purse snatcher could still be out there.
Don't worry!
I asked Kano-san to drive me and your wife to the hotel!
Wife?!
Who's Kano?
Ran told you, didn't she? Miyama's hot college friend!
Sonoko!
What's the big deal? It's true!
Are his other two friends there?
No... It'll be just us and Kano-san, I think.
The police are taking a long time to question Yanuma-san, the late Miyama-san's girlfriend.
Kano-san's been waiting for her to finish.
Bito-san walked back to the hotel on his own.
Yanuma-san is crying and the police still have questions for her,
so Kano-san's going to drive us to the hotel and then come back for her.
Oh, really?
Well, I'd better hang up! My phone's almost dead...
Geez.
Wish I'd gone to the beach with them...
The beach?
Speaking of the beach, I found a jellyfish!
What are you talking about, Ayumi-chan?
You can't find a jellyfish in the mountains!
I did!
See? Over there!
Really?
Look!
A jellyfish!
You're right...
The hot spring logo looks like a jellyfish when it's upside-down...
See?
A jellyfish!
It does look like one!
The hot spring logo looks like a jellyfish when it's upside-down...
I see... So that's what it means...
Lie down and splash water on your face, huh?
I can't believe
a code like this gave me trouble.
But sometimes, simple codes are the hardest to decipher.
Doc!
It's been long enough...
Why can't you just tell us the secret code?
What does "marumushi ni tento" mean?
Right...
No! Until you all give up, my lips are sealed!
Okay, I give up! Whisper it to me! Where's the treasure?
No fair, Genta-kun!
Why did I suddenly think of Ran?
Come on, Conan-kun...
You haven't solved it yet?
Uh, nope.
It doesn't make any sense to me.
I don't have a clue.
Then give up already!
Don't be a sore loser, Conan-kun!
You guys give up too easily!
Looks like even Shin'ichi is stumped.
Let's think about this carefully from the beginning!
First of all, the code is written in katakana.
I can understand "marumushi" and "tento" being written in katakana.
At the same time, doesn't it seem strange that a word like "ni" would be written that way?
Right...
Secondly, if you look closely, each character is strangely crooked.
You're right!
Doc's just got bad handwriting.
And thirdly,
we've got the clues Doc and Haibara gave us.
D-Did they ever give us clues?
Yeah.
"Lie down and think about it"...
...and "if you don't get it, splash some water on your face."
Those aren't things they normally say.
They must be clues!
Maybe they want us to lie down and look at the message!
Nice!
Lie down, huh?
I don't see anything different...
Whoa!
W-What is it, Genta-kun?
Did you figure it out?
Huh?
Geez, Genta-kun, what's up with you?
Uh, well, for a sec I thought I had it...
You thought you did?
Did you or didn't you?!
Shut up! I was sure the message would say something sideways!
Whew. That was close.
Nah.
Look at the smirk on his smug little face.
I bet he's solved it already.
Even sideways, it doesn't look like anything.
Then let's think about the other clue.
The thing about washing your face?
How are we supposed to wash up in the mountains?
I still think we're supposed to go to that in the villagers use as a public bath!
No way!
Haibara and the Doc already told us there's nothing at the inn!
Then where are we supposed to wash up?
Yeah!
Dunno...
Maybe she didn't literally mean "wash your face".
Let's think. What do you do when you wash your face?
Turn on the tap...
Wash up in the running water...
Wipe my face with a towel...
And after that?
After that...
Er...
Chow time!
Geez, Genta-kun, we're talking about when you wash your face!
After I wash my face, I eat dinner!
The mirror!
After that, I look in the mirror!
Mirror?
What? You don't see anything in the mirror but yourself!
This just gets more baffling!
No, I think you're on to something.
Look,
see how that hot spring logo looks like a jellyfish
when it's upside-down.
But none of these letters look like fish upside-down!
They don't look like words either...
Wait a minute!
Maybe you have to do both!
Turn the message sideways and reflect it in a mirror!
If we turn it sideways, flip it over,
and hold it up to the moonlight...
"muramatsuri no tori'i" - "the shrine of the village festival"!
"muramatsuri no tori'i" ?!
Oh, it's that shrine!
Right? Doc? Ai-chan!
Bingo.
That's right!
Hooray!
We did it!
We did, we did it!
Let's go see what it is!
The treasure!
Well, well.
Looks like you taught the kids they can figure things out on their own if they put their minds to it.
Yup. I'm a heck of a guy, huh?
Aren't you going to go look?
Don't you want to find out what the treasure is?
I already know that!
The code points to that brightly-lit tori'i gate.
If you smeared some tree sap onto it,
I bet it's swarming with...
Found it!
Wow! Awesome!
Rhinoceros beetles and stag beetles!
Exactly.
At any rate...
I'm impressed that you came up with this secret code.
A message that can be read from different directions...
It's all thanks to Ai-kun!
I was going to use animals for the code first,
so I taped animal names to the window to get ideas!
As I was doing that, Ai-kun was watching from outside.
Isn't 'oxygen' too advanced for the kids?
...she said.
I see... "kirin" (キリン) or "giraffe" looked like "sanso" (サンソ) from the other side,
and then you thought of the code...
Shin'ichi?
Glass...
Other side...
Shining through...
Wait a minute!
That's it!
Damn! That's it!
Shin'ichi!
Kudo-kun?
That's what it meant!
That's why I thought of Ran a minute ago!
Ran's...
Ran's in serious danger!
Shin'ichi?
Where am I?
I told you, we're on the way back to the hotel in Kano-san's car.
Get out of the car right now?
I've figured out the real meaning of "teiu"!
There was a small splotch in front of the "t"!
The message was written sideways,
but stand it up and flip it over,
and it spells the murderer's name!
Hey! Ran!
Ran! Ran!
The battery's dead...
What was it? What'd he say?
Geez, Sonoko!
Something about standing up and flipping over the car...
Sounds like your husband's jealous!
Yeah, right.
What? Ran and Sonoko are involved in a murder case?
Yeah.
Sonoko happened to see the letters of a message written by a man who was bludgeoned to death.
Letters?
It was written horizontally in lowercase letters that spelled "teiu"!
More precisely, there was a little mark in front of the "t",
the "i" was an "l" and the "u" looked like a hiragana "shi" (し).
It's exactly like "muramatsuri no tori'i".
The message is written sideways and backwards!
"marumushi ni tento" ?
If you turn "sanso" on its side and read it backwards...
"Kirin".
Then, what's "teiu"?
T-That would be...
かのう - the characters for "Kano".
Yeah.
Kano?
But why did the victim leave such a difficult code as a dying message?
It's no code!
He collapsed on the floor and wrote the name on the window,
and Sonoko saw it from the outside.
You have to tell Ran-kun and Sonoko!
I know, but Ran's phone went dead!
And to top it off...
Ran and Sonoko are in Kano's car right now!
Say.
This isn't the road to the hotel, is it?
Don't sweat it.
I'm taking a shortcut.
Hey. Where's the hotel they're staying at?
If I knew that, I would've called the cops already!
All Ran told me was that she was going to the beach...
Damn! I should've realized it sooner,
when I got that weird text message from Sonoko's stolen phone!
He wanted to delete the picture with the dying message from my cell phone!
That's why he asked for my name and address...
Wait a minute.
That means...
So, that Shin'ichi-kun guy you were talking about...
He's a teen detective, huh?
Yeah, something like that...
That's cool! Dating a detective!
Oh, no! He's not my boyfriend!
They're such a cute couple!
That's why I sent him a photo of Ran in her swimsuit this morning!
Hey, Sonoko!
A pity Shin'ichi-kun isn't here with you today.
I would've loved to meet...
that sleuth...
If the murderer is waiting for me to contact him,
he must have Sonoko's phone on him!
Listen to that ringtone, guys!
He's the murderer!
Huh?
That ringtone's the same as your phone, Sonoko!
Or, rather, it...
is my phone...
You're right!
B-But why?
Isn't it obvious?
I grabbed it off you...
...to get rid of the evidence!
What?!
Well, then.
Once we get deeper into the woods, I've got some questions...
about the whereabouts of that Shin'ichi brat.
They still haven't picked up?!
Shut up for a minute!
E-Er...
Someone's picked up!
Hello? Hello?!
Don't "hello" me! Where the hell were you when Ran needed you?!
Hey! Are you listening to me?!
Oh, um, I was...
We could've been hurt when the car crashed into that tree!
The car?
Why did it...
Whatever it was, we had no choice!
Ran's side kick went straight into the driver's face!
I see...
After that, Sonoko called the police, and the murderer was arrested.
The victim had been blackmailing Kano,
threatening to reveal the fact that he'd cheated his way into college.
It was the same old story of one crime snowballing into another.
And...
Huh?
I thought I saved it here...
Oh, we deleted that swimsuit photo.
Huh? Why?!
Why? Kids can't look at that stuff!
Sorry...
We had Ai-chan erase it for us!
Haibara?
Why, you...
DAMN!
Magure's such a great show, isn't it?
You really outdid yourselves with the trick that time.
That person is one of the drama's three scriptwriters, isn't he?
Such an aggressive look in his eyes...
He's definitely the culprit.
Yet he has so much confidence in his trick.
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: Two cups
The next episode's title...
If it's half-finished, then maybe it's a boxed eel lunch...
Eh?