Stars are marginally fascinating.
They can represent culprits or celebrities!
Today's stage is a television network.
The passion of a drama quickly results in a case!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Yes, we felt the same light the moment we met.
Yes, lots and lots of the same emotions filled our eyes.
Although the signals you sent destroyed my theory...
These feelings were always beyond your reach
So, let's fight, go against our morals...
And aim for a wider world!
Oh, glimmering star, shine over us forever.
This way, we won't lose the dreams we had when we were young...
I don't care if this town changes someday.
The only thing I don't want to change is you.
Oh, glimmering star, shine over us forever.
This way, we won't lose the dreams we had when we were young...
The only thing I don't want to change is you.
So, a drama scriptwriter has requested
the presence of me, Mouri Kogorou?
Yes, we all want to hear Detective Mouri's opinion.
Inoue Ryouko (40)
Nichuri Tv Film Department Producer
Have you seen the show "Detective Megure" before?
It's a detective drama, right?
I may have seen it a few times.
I watch it every week!
Thank you.
There are three people who take
turns writing the drama's script.
It's been on air for five years now...
So we're almost out of ideas for motives and tricks.
And, I presume you would like to delve into
the past cases of one Mouri Kogorou?
Magure's such a great show, isn't it?
Not every episode is great, but every once in
a while the deductions will blow you away.
For instance...
In Secret Chamber No. 52," the trick was unbelievable.
Wait, Magure-kun, that chamber is...
It was something that was only
constructed later, Inspector.
By using a crane to lift up the entire house.
No one would've guessed that
such a large-scale trick was used.
However, even that didn't escape the
eyes of yours truly, Magure Rintarou.
Episode 99 [Secret Chamber No. 52] Final
You really outdid yourselves with the trick that time.
I really enjoyed watching it.
I agree, Secret Chamber No. 52" was
produced quite well for a mystery, but...
That aired at least two years ago.
Conan-kun, how old are you now?
I watched it on video a while ago!
Oh, so that's how it is!
That was close...
Understood.
Allow me to tell your drama script
writers about every case I've solved.
Say, can I go too?
I really want to see who writes the
scripts for Detective Magure.
The Half Completed Crime Mystery
Did we come too early?
We still have an hour left.
There's a cafe on the top floor, I think
I'm Yagami, a scriptwriter.
Inoue-san, who oversees the production of
"Detective Magure," asked me to come.
Yes, please wait a moment.
That person is one of the drama's
three scriptwriters, isn't he?
He looks like an arrogant fatso to me.
Yagami Jouji (50)
Scriptwriter
Yagami-sensei, it's been a while.
My taxi got stuck in traffic jam.
Kouda Morio (29)
Scriptwriter
This is the first time in half a year
that the three of you got together.
Now, before Mouri-san comes, please
discuss the direction of the series.
I'd like something drink.
Anyone else?
It's all right, I'm not thirsty.
I'll get some drinks.
What would you guys like?
Coffee... hot.
Me too.
Same here.
Got it, I'll be right back.
Sorry to trouble you like that.
You can leave that to me.
It's all right, I'm used to it.
He's like some kind of servant.
Isn't discussing the drama more
important than getting the drinks?
And to think someone like him can
be considered a drama scriptwriter!
Haven't his scripts been fine?
I'm not talking about his work.
I'm talking about the way he acts
on a regular basis, Saguma-chan.
Since he's still new, it's normal for him
to have a lot of things to worry about.
Just fire him already, Inoue-san.
We only need Saguma-chan and
I to work on Detective Magure.
Yagami-san...
Sorry for making you wait!
Thank you.
You wanted to add milk, right, Inoue-san?
I forgot about that.
I'll go get it.
Honestly, if that klutz isn't dropping
something, he's forgetting something else.
Sakuma Akira (45)
Scriptwriter
He's still young, and isn't used to everything yet.
Yagami-san!
Yes?
Oh, Inoue-san!
What'd you say!?
Yes!
That's correct!
The address is...
Mouri-san...
The smell of almonds.
The cause of death is potassium cyanide poisoning.
Four people...
And four drinks, huh...
The cup on the floor is poisoned, as expected.
But none of the other three cups are
showing traces of the substance.
Which means that the culprit only
poisoned Yagami-san's coffee.
That's pretty much it.
The person who prepared the drinks
was you, Kouda Morio-san, correct?
Yes.
I asked what they wanted.
Everyone wanted hot coffee, but I had Japanese tea.
But aren't the drinks normally prepared by
someone who works at the TV station?
Yes, they are, but...
I just started my scriptwriting career.
I'm trying my best to help everyone out.
It's not strange, but...
What's so strange?
That's right!
Maybe someone placed the poison in a random cup...
And it just happened to be served to Yagami-san.
Are you saying that this was an indiscriminate murder?
I can't think of anything else.
So you're saying that Kouda-san refused your help.
He said he could do it himself, and didn't need any help.
Inspector, a moment.
Inoue-san, can you come with us for a moment?
Yes.
After some investigation, the only person who
could have placed the poison was Kouda-san.
Suggesting that someone committed indiscriminate
murder was pretty much his last resort.
Only he could be the murderer.
But we still don't know his motive.
You brat!
Didn't I tell you to stay in the room?
Aren't they all co-workers working together on a drama?
Why would they poison someone?
It's true that they're co-workers...
Do you have any clues?
Please tell us everything.
This is a murder case.
At first, Yagami-san and Saguma-san took turns
writing the scripts for Detective Magure.
Some time later, a self-proclaimed loyal fan of
the show sent us one of his own drama scripts.
That person was the newcomer, Kouda-san.
After reading his work, I thought it was pretty interesting.
So I let him on board as the drama's third scriptwriter.
Saguma-san thought highly of his work, but...
For some reason, Yagami-san absolutely hated him.
And...
Yagami-san told me to fire him on several occasions.
Did Kouda-san know about this?
I think he probably had an idea of what was going on.
He must've been hurt.
What do you mean by that?
Inoue-san.
I'll do whatever I can to write more for this show.
I really want to make a name for
myself as a drama scriptwriter!
Kouda-san gambled his whole
future on Detective Magure.
Yet Yagami-san did everything he could to get him fired.
It's obvious, Inspector.
It has to be him.
We have the motive now.
But... if he's the one that did it...
Hey, Mouri-kun! Wait up!
I already know who the culprit is!
But you don't have any evidence.
And there are still things that haven't been cleared up.
Shut up and leave it to me!
I'm the famous detective Mouri Kogorou!
Is that really all right?
You think that... I killed Yagami-san?
No way...
It may be true that I didn't get along with him...
But Mouri-san...
Even if I had put poison in the coffee, how
would I get Yagami-san to drink it?
Of the three cups, only one had poison in it.
Moreover, when I was getting the milk,
I wasn't at the scene of the crime.
Which means that I didn't give him
the cup; he took it himself.
I couldn't have predicted which cup he would take.
Isn't that right?
That's exactly the problem.
If this person is the culprit...
How did he get Yagami-san to choose
the cup with the poison in it?
I see!
Mouri-kun?
You brought in the cups.
First, you gave Inoue-san the cup with no poison in it.
Only two cups remain.
Both cups are the same.
How would I know which cup Yagami-san would pick?
That's easy-first, you arranged the cups like so.
At the time, in that room, Yagami-san's
seat would have been over there.
Of course he would take the cup closest to him.
Furthermore, Saguma-san is Yagami-san's junior,
so it's not like he would just reach for a cup.
I see.
Is that really what he did?
No, even though we're each other's senior and
junior, we're already familiar with each other.
At that time, I was definitely the first one to take
a cup, and passed the last one to Yagami-san.
In that case, wouldn't I be suspicious?
Mouri-san, you really are quite suspicious of me.
Please tell me the trick that I used to get
Yagami-san to drink the poisoned coffee.
Solve that mystery first.
Such an aggressive look in his eyes...
He's definitely the culprit.
Yet he has so much confidence in his trick.
Two people and two drinks.
There's a 50% chance for someone to choose either cup.
What exactly did he do to get a probability of 100%?
Mouri-kun...
To be honest, my suspicions of Kouda-san are a bit shaky.
Because if the person he wanted
to kill was really Yagami-san...
But then Saguma-san took that cup of coffee...
He would have stopped him no matter what.
But he said he forgot to bring the milk.
If he were the culprit, would he have
left the scene of the crime?
That's true.
Didn't he think it through that
something like this could happen?
Hey.
Are you listening, Mouri-kun?
I wonder what's going to happen to Detective Magure.
It won't be canceled, will it?
I don't know.
But for something like this to happen...
We worked hard to get to where we are today.
Is that the Detective Magure episode list?
Can I see?
Sure.
Thank you.
What is it?
This one was written by Kouda-san, wasn't it?
[Secret Chamber No. 52.]
You also said that it was worth watching, didn't you?
Actually, that one was Kouda-san's first drama script.
For a newcomer that skilled to join us...
Even I was amazed.
[The Club of Supporting Actors]
was also written by Kouda-san?
Yes, what about it?
Does this mean...
Most of the scripts were written by
Yagami-san and Saguma-san, huh?
That's because the two of
them were the main writers.
Which means that anyone else who was
talented wouldn't have the chance to shine.
So that's how the motive for this murder came about.
With that, every riddle is now solved.
What is it, Conan-kun?
Inoue-san!
We've finally solved this case!
We finally saw through the culprit's trick.
Are you serious?
At the time, there were two people and two cups.
After thinking about it, getting the
victim to choose the right cup...
Could be accomplished using only one method.
That was...
To pray for a miracle to happen.
Mouri-kun, was that supposed
to be your great explanation?
Inspector, I kid you not.
The success rate was 50%.
There was a chance of failure, but
Kouda-san took that chance.
How could you be satisfied after
being driven away like that?
You were so desperate and determined that,
in the end, you did something this shocking.
That's enough, Mouri-kun.
No, Inspector, I'm absolutely sure!
Mouri-kun?
Could this be the legendary...
Sleeping Kogorou?
You're saying I took such a drastic risk?
Are you kidding me?
I really did consider it.
Mouri-kun...
Please hear me out, Inspector.
Kouda-san...
You said earlier that...
We should first discover how you made Yagami-san
drink the poisoned cup of coffee, right?
But, there's no way of finding out.
I say this because you never used a trick to begin with.
Didn't use a trick?
That's right, he didn't use one.
Then, how did he get Yagami-san
to drink the poisoned coffee?
Before we get to that, allow me to
first explain how it all happened.
Conan, bring it in.
Here!
This was what Conan borrowed earlier
the list of Detective Magure episodes.
After seeing this, I was amazed.
In the Magure drama, there would be a mystery
with an amazing deduction every few episodes.
It would have a unique trick, and yet remain logical.
And most importantly, it would
always keep the spirit of fair play.
"Secret Chamber No. 52," for example, was like that
Same with "The Club of Supporting Actors"...
"Massacre at the Empty Well"...
And "When the Green Door Opened."
Those are all...
That's right-scripts that I happen to admire.
Kouda-san, you wrote them, didn't you?
After discovering this...
I began to think back.
You, who could write such perfect mysteries...
Would never gamble on a 50% outcome.
Afterwards, I noticed something you
had done that raised my suspicions.
At the time, why did you leave the scene?
Forgetting the milk must have been
something you planned beforehand.
Saguma-san or Yagami-san...
Not caring about which coffee each of them chose...
You probably wanted to stress this point, didn't you?
But it would have still been suspicious.
Inspector Megure said this earlier:
Because if the person he wanted
to kill was really Yagami-san...
But then Saguma-san took that cup of coffee...
He would have stopped him no matter what.
That's right...
It didn't matter what fancy method you used since
something this unpredictable could still happen.
You, who could write such seamless deductions,
would never fail to consider such a possibility.
In spite of this, you left the conference room.
Why is that?
There's only one answer.
Whether or not you killed Yagami-san didn't matter.
Mouri-san...
What's going on, Mouri-kun?
It didn't matter whether it was
Yagami-san or Saguma-san.
That's why he didn't need any sort of trick.
So you're saying, he would be satisfied as
long as Yagami-san or I was killed, right?
That's quite a haphazard way of committing a crime.
Inspector, this wasn't done haphazardly.
No matter who was killed, there would only be one result.
As long as one of the two main writers was eliminated...
The chances for Kouda-san, the third writer, to
prove himself would have greatly increased.
Doing whatever you could to write
more for Detective Magure.
That was the real motive for the whole
incident, wasn't it, Kouda-san?
Inoue-san...
I'll do whatever I can to write more for this show.
I really want to make a name for
myself as a drama scriptwriter!
Kouda-san...
This incident may seem to have
only a 50% chance of succeeding...
But as long as one of the two drank the
poisoned coffee, he would have been in luck.
That's why his method of committing the crime
had, in fact, a 100% chance of success.
So that's how it is.
I'm already 29...
Become a prominent drama scriptwriter.
Before turning 30, I wanted to...
That was my goal.
What does it matter if you're prominent...
Or if you're only writing one out of every ten episodes?
Those who love your work will watch it.
Inoue-san is also a fan of your work.
I remember what you've done. Everyone does.
Every one of your episodes blew me away.
You were really foolish...
Stop the world and smile gently...
I want to be closer to you.
I've fallen for you time and time again.
My tears overflow as the dawn approaches.
The warmth you give me makes me forget to take a breath.
And I'm afraid of losing the feeling of your fingertips stroking my hair.
The attraction that pulls us together...
Should we be separated tomorrow, I would search for you to no end.
Stop the world and smile gently...
Because I will always be by your side.
Let the light of dawn shine upon you...
And envelop the two us of like this forever.
I wonder if Detective Magure's still canceled?
"Detective Magure" finished,
"New Detective Magure" starting soon?
I hear the main character underwent a name change.
Magure Rintarou became Magure Kogorou.
Magure Kogo...
Somehow, it sounds a lot like Fluky Kogorou."
Isn't that you exactly?
Looking at you, one would think you just
Deducted something unthinkable.
Tsuburaya Mitsuhiko. This is a failure of a lifetime!
We should tell Conan-kun about something like this.
If we don't make it... What will we do?
-Genta-kun!
Let's try the back too.
Next Conan.
The Detective Group Chasing The blue Bird
Next Conan's Hint.
Soy sauce.
Next week is 'Aoitori.'
What? Aodori?
No, Inspector Mogure
I'm Megure.