Stars are marginally fascinating.
They can represent culprits or celebrities!
Yuka-chan's keeping a blue bird as a pet.
But instead of bringing happiness, it brought us a case!
Gotta save the day, Detective Boys!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
The Detective Boys Bluebird Chase
It's really cold today.
They say the temperature's gonna be like it
was in late November for three whole days.
Ah, there's Yuka-chan.
That's Konno-san from Class C, isn't it?
She's always standing there, looking
into that large parakeet cage.
Yuka-chan!
Konno Yuka (7)
Ayumi-chan...
So you like birds?
Yep, I love them.
I have a pet parakeet at home too.
A blue budgerigar.
What's its name?
Chichi.
It's a domesticated two-year-old male.
It also can chatter a little.
It can chat?
I'd love to see him!
Stare, want to come to my place?
Can I go too?
May I, too?
And you're Edogawa-kun and Haibara-san right?
Will you two come as well?
But, wouldn't it be impolite for all of us to intrude?
It's all right.
My mom doesn't come back
from work until after dark.
So you're from a dual-income family?
Mine too!
Well, mine's a little bit different...
Yuka-chan's dad died of illness two years ago.
So that's why...
Hey, let's all go, Conan-kun and Ai-chan!
Sure, let's all go see a real domesticated budgie.
Let's go!
Let's do this!
Do what?
Do you know how to tell the difference
between a male and a female budgie?
By the size?
Feather patterns?
No.
The "cere" is the waxy membrane above a parakeet's beak.
You look at the color of the cere above its beak.
Males have blue ones, while a female's is brown.
Bingo!
But Chichi's cere turned brown
recently, even though he's a boy.
I wonder why?
Aren't we there yet?
Huh?
It's already unlocked.
What now?
Could it be a burglar!?
Everyone, stay back!
All right!
You guys...
We're ready!
Anytime is OK!
Who're you?
You a burglar!?
Yuka-chan, welcome back...
Someone you know?
No, he isn't.
She doesn't know him!
So we do have us a burglar after all!
No, I'm Sakaguchi Shinya.
Sakaguchi Shinya (40)
Beika University Research Employee
A researcher at the engineering
department of Beika University.
I'm also her mother's friend.
Yuka-chan's mother works in a
gardening store in Haido District.
She said she had to work late today...
And asked if I could take Yuka-chan out for dinner.
But she said she'd already told
Yuka-chan about it, though...
I didn't hear about it.
Yuka-chan...
Please wait!
How did you get in?
Her mom told me where the spare key was hidden.
Everyone, ignore him and come in.
All right!
Excuse us.
That must mean that you and her mother are close, right?
Excuse us!
Hey, don't push me.
It's huge!
The backyard is beautiful.
But why are the windows wide open?
Well, I thought it'd be nice to have some
fresh air before Yuka-chan came back...
Chichi, I'm back.
He's cute!
Pretty colors too!
What is it?
Somehow, Chichi looks smaller than before...
Nonsense, it's just your imagination.
Chichi, Chichi...
Chichi, say, "Welcome back!"
Strange...
Every time I came home, he
would say, "Welcome back."
I guess he must be nervous from
seeing so many of you here.
Did he say anything this morning?
Yeah, he energetically said "Good morning."
It tickles.
Looks like its cere really is brown.
Yeah.
Oh, a cold?
Yeah, kind of.
So that's why you kept your distance from us,
because you didn't want your cold to spread?
That's right.
Why would he open all the windows
and glass doors if he has a cold?
Intriguing.
Want some juice to drink?
Say...
Could it be you let the bird loose?
And then, bought a substitute from a pet shop, no?
You opened the windows and glass doors
hoping that the escaped bird would fly back.
I see!
That's why you bought a smaller budgie!
No wonder it can't speak!
Tell the truth!
That's not it, what're you all saying?
You spilled the soy sauce, didn't you?
When I opened the fridge, I sensed
the strong smell of soy sauce.
That's right.
I tried to put Yuka-chan's cake in the fridge earlier...
And accidentally knocked over that bottle of soy sauce.
Don't just go and open our fridge whenever you want!
Konno Masako (35)
Yuka's Mother
Why the loud voice, Yuka?
Mom!
Sorry to bother you.
Welcome.
I came home early because of a client's cancellation.
Sakaguchi-san, let's dine out.
No thanks, I'll excuse myself for the day.
But...
Well then, Conan-kun, Ai-chan, bye!
Yeah it's getting late so you guys
head straight home, all right?
We know!
It's you two that we worry about hanging out late!
Well, that's a good idea.
Stop talking nonsense!
Oh, why are you so agitated, Edogawa-kun?
Conan-kun's as sharp as usual.
But we have to check this out.
Let's go!
Yes, I believe...
This person did buy a blue budgerigar.
About two hours ago.
Really?
So it's true...
It's like Ai-chan said...
That guy let the parakeet escape!
But this guy...
Brought a dead parakeet here.
"Please find me a parakeet that looks like this."
That's what he said hastily.
That was a surprise, that Chichi was dead.
But Yuka-chan said it energetically
greeted her with, "Good morning," right?
Yeah, which rules out illness.
But since it's in a cage, it's hard
to say it died in an accident.
Could it be that guy did it?
But he hastily bought a similar parakeet...
So it's unlikely he just wanted it dead.
Maybe he caused it to die without realizing it?
The contents of his work?
Yes.
Sakaguchi-san said he works as a researcher in
Beika University's engineering department.
We were just wondering what he researches.
Well...
I'm not sure, but it seems like some kind of drug research.
Drugs?
Then... could it be...
But I don't know what drugs.
Conan-kun!
Don't, Ayumi-chan.
He's the one who always gets all of the glory.
This time, let's do it ourselves.
But...
OK, Ayumi-chan?
Ah, sorry make you wait.
We're sorry for bothering you while you're busy.
Excuse us.
So, is your research lab inside there, Sakaguchi-san?
That's right.
Can we check it out?
No, I'm afraid not.
Why's that?
Because there are dangerous chemicals and drugs.
Dangerous drugs.
As we thought.
Actually, we went to the pet shop yesterday.
We learned everything from the clerk.
Will you explain to us what really happened?
Sorry... I lied yesterday.
When I arrived at Yuka-chan's place...
Chichi was already dead in that cage.
Since Yuka-chan adores Chichi...
I figured she would be heart-
broken when she saw that.
That's why I hurried over to that
pet shop to buy a look-alike.
Then, what happened to the dead Chichi?
After I left Yuka-chan's house...
I went to a nearby park and buried it.
Will you show us the burial site?
We'd like to pray for it.
But right now is a little...
You saying we can't!?
I'm in the middle of an experiment right now.
Sorry, but let's discuss this later.
I'm sorry.
Sakaguchi-san!
Hey!
How suspicious.
He must've killed Chichi.
There's no doubt!
But why did he let Chichi die?
Thank you very much.
Could it be like this?
That guy accidentally spilled a drug he
brought from the lab near the cage.
That chemical splashed into the water dish...
And killed Chichi when he drank it!
But that'd be too much of a coincidence.
Maybe it was an evaporative poison?
What's that? Eva-something?
It's evaporative, Genta-kun.
A process when liquid becomes gas.
That is the poison evaporated and
killed Chichi when he breathed it in!
If you think about it, every puzzle is solved!
The reason why Sakaguchi-san opened every window and
door in Yuka-chan's house was to let the poison gas out.
And Sakaguchi-san's red eyes and coughing
must have resulted from his inhaling the gas.
That's why he stayed far away from us.
He didn't want to be near the place
where the poisonous gas was!
I see.
So saying he had a cold was a lie.
Good afternoon.
Good afternoon?
Yuka-chan!
Good afternoon!
Thank you for yesterday.
Don't mention it.
Shopping?
Yes, we're having hand-rolled sushi tonight.
Ah, what a coincidence!
We're all going to the Professor's
house to eat hand-rolled sushi too!
Professor?
Professor Agasa.
He's an inventor who lives on 2nd Street.
He's real old.
Even talks like an old man.
Say...
Is Sakaguchi-san going to eat with you too?
Well, I did invite him.
But he said he'll be really busy tonight.
Well, please come over and play again.
All right, bye!
Say...
Is it all right if we don't tell them about that man?
I'm not sure...
Let's tell them only when we're absolutely sure.
Sorry to bother you!
You came!
Professor, where's Conan-kun?
Hand-rolled sushi, I smell hand-rolled sushi!
Still thinking about Conan-kun?
It's nothing.
He'll be by soon.
Haibara-san, can I help?
Sure.
How about setting the table for me?
Sure, you got it!
So the question is why Sakaguchi-san
brought poison to Yuka-chan's home.
Could the poison have been for Yuka-chan's mom?
I would hate to think that, but...
It's a possibility we cannot ignore.
So where would he put it...
Ah, the cake.
The cake!
He tried to poison the cake they bought!
Genta-kun...
We all ate that cake yesterday!
Ah, I can't get enough!
Oh, yeah.
Speaking of which, Yuka-chan didn't eat any, did she?
I guess she really hates Sakaguchi-san.
Then, where the heck did he put it?
I think he only brought the poison,
but hadn't put it anywhere yet.
Otherwise, he wouldn't have been so calm.
Ai-kun, will this be enough soy sauce?
I accidentally knocked over that bottle of soy sauce.
Damn it!
Don't tell me it's in the...
That's why Sakaguchi-san declined the invitation
to eat hand-rolled sushi at their house tonight!
This is bad, we have to stop him!
What?
I'm going too!
Hey, wait!
What's going on?
Who knows?
Hurry, Mitsuhiko! This is a matter of life or death!
If that's the case, we should have talked to Conan-kun!
"Conan-kun" again?
If we can't make it... what do we do!?
Genta-kun!
It's red!
Maaan!
Hurry... hurry!
Turn green, I beg you!
Please, let us make it!
Let's cut through the backyard!
We made it!
They're still alive.
Thank goodness.
What's going on, everyone?
Don't dip that in the soy sauce!
It's poisoned!
Poisoned?
What are you talking about?
There's no poison in it.
We already dipped it in and ate it.
Yes?
Conan-kun?
Sakaguchi-san?
As I thought.
You guys were here after all.
Conan-kun, why are you here?
I can tell by your faces that you've
jumped to some weird conclusions.
Then...
When Sakaguchi-san arrived,
Chichi really was already dead?
Yeah.
When birds are sick, they typically try to act as if
they're all right by zealously pecking at bird food.
Why?
When birds are in a group...
A bird who appears to be weak will face the
risk of being attacked by predators, right?
Even if a bird is domesticated...
It can't forget its natural instincts.
I see!
So that's why it energetically said,
"Good morning" yesterday morning.
But there are other clues.
When a male budgerigar is ill...
Its cere turns from blue to brown.
Yes.
The reason why Chichi's cere changed
color was because he was ill.
I didn't know that...
Then, that means Sakaguchi-san's
red eyes and coughing...
Weren't because of a poisonous drug?
No, Sakaguchi-san really had a cold.
He couldn't bathe for three days...
So he was likely concerned about his body odor.
That's why he opened the windows and doors.
As well as standing away from us
when Yuka-chan came back.
I felt that if I stayed...
I'd ruin the cake you bought.
I'm sorry, Yuka-chan.
Earlier, that kid came and
advised me to tell you the truth.
He said it was better for you to
know what really happened.
I should've done this from the start...
But I'm an idiot.
Life is precious.
I know you're heart-broken about not
realizing what was happening.
But...
I think Chichi was lucky to have a kind owner like you.
Yesterday, because Chichi's cere had turned brown...
I ended up buying the wrong gender.
A parakeet!
And the cere is blue, so it's male!
Awesome!
After Chichi's death, I'm still not sure if
buying a substitute was a good idea, but...
Thank you.
I'm glad they can become a family.
Stop the world and smile gently...
I want to be closer to you.
I've fallen for you time and time again.
My tears overflow as the dawn approaches.
The warmth you give me makes me forget to take a breath.
And I'm afraid of losing the feeling of your fingertips stroking my hair.
The attraction that pulls us together...
Should we be separated tomorrow, I would search for you to no end.
Stop the world and smile gently...
Because I will always be by your side.
Let the light of dawn shine upon you...
And envelop the two us of like this forever.
They're so late, what are they doing?
You should just start eating without them.
That's true.
roll ill
Even if they don't "roe" back, I can't speak "eel" of them.
Though I wanted to scream like a bream, that's too fishy.
enjoy
Roll it and dip it, "en-soy" my soy sauce!
Geez...
Be it sushi or a cheesy pun, you need good material.