It's almost the tenth anniversary of Conan!
We made it through the first, now let's aim for the next!
After all, the butsumetsu calendar bugs me.
Psychic phenomena brought on by a nightmare!
Passing through security, a case breaks out!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
An evil spirit?
You want me to break the curse of an evil spirit?
W-Well... To put it simply, yes.
Come on! Detectives solve crimes! Human crimes!
We've already had priests and mediums in
to get rid of the spirit, but no luck.
That's why we decided to ask you, Detective Mouri,
Kenzo Akatsuka (50)
Kunitomo Family Butler
to investigate from a scientific standpoint.
So what's this spook doing, anyway?
It all started with a nightmare my master had two years ago.
Nightmare?
He gave an unearthly scream and jumped out of bed,
moaning the same things over and over... "It's a curse... I'm going to be killed..."
But it was just a dream, right?
That's not all!
Six months later, the brakes of this car malfunctioned and we almost crashed!
Masashi Watabiki (28)
Kunitomo Family Chauffeur
Isn't that right, Watabiki-kun?
Er, yes...
I'm so sorry about that. I didn't notice the brake oil had leaked out.
The accident was such a shock to the master
that he started having heart problems.
His eyes sunk into their sockets
and his hair turned white.
But still, that's just an accident.
Where does the evil spirit come in?
We have reason to believe we've been cursed!
We received this card!
Card?
"Repent of your sins before I awaken."
"I am the fifth soul."
When did you get this?
Last year, not long after New Year's Day.
It had been left in the mailbox.
At first I thought it was just a prank.
But when I showed it to the master,
both he and the mistress were horrified.
His wife?
Yes.
Six months later, a cupboard fell,
shattering all the fine china inside.
And this April the staff went on vacation, leaving the master and mistress alone in the house.
They started hearing strange sounds...
Hey, do these weird things
happen on a certain day?
Like Friday the 13th or something?
They've happened on different days of the week. But the date...
is always the 4th.
Maybe something significant happened
on the 4th of some month in the past.
I asked the master, the mistress and the staff,
but they couldn't think of anything.
Wait...
Today is October 3!
The curse is going to strike tomorrow!
Oh, you're right.
Hey...
There have been five incidents, right?
Do you remember the exact dates they occurred on?
No, I don't recall every detail...
I know!
The first incident was...
two years ago on February 4.
That was the master's nightmare.
The car accident occurred
on July 4 of the same year.
We received the strange card
last year on February 4,
and the cupboard fell down on July 4 of that year.
And the mysterious sounds
were heard this April 4.
You make a note of everything, huh?
Yes... If I don't write things down, I'll forget them.
Just like you, Conan-kun!
Uh-huh...
Maybe the card was sent by someone trying to get to your boss...
Anyway, do you feel anything from it?
What? You mean like a psychic vibe?
Oh, er...
If you don't feel anything, that's fine.
Oh, come on!
This isn't what I was told!
I thought we were only going to have
one guest at the house tonight!
Er, I'm sorry...
My daughter pestered me to let her tag along.
I-I'm sorry...
I'm not angry at you! I'm annoyed
at this silly old man for not calling me!
Namika-chan, please... I'm not that old.
Anyway, I'll have to go get more groceries.
She's a pretty outspoken daughter, isn't she?
Oh, no... She's our chef.
Chef?
Her father was the Kunitomo family's personal chef for years,
Namika Senzaki (28)
Kunitomo Family Chef
and after he died in an accident, she took his place.
Oh... And she's still so young...
Speaking of which, he followed in his father's footsteps too.
Oh, Watabiki-kun! The master has an appointment at the hospital at 8:00 tonight!
Oh, okay...
Huh?
I'm out of ink.
Here.
Use this.
Ah, thank you.
I'm sorry. No hard feelings.
I had food poisoning when I was small,
and ever since, I've suffered from mysophobia.
Here you go. Thanks.
Conan-kun! We'll go in without you!
Leave him, leave him.
What? The master and mistress?
I saw them in the bedroom on the third floor.
I see...
Hey...
What?
You look a lot like that chef I just saw...
Dad!
Shigeko Senzaki (52)
Kunitomo Family Housekeeper
Of course I do!
Namika is my daughter!
Makes sense.
And could you not point your finger at me? I have belonephobia.
Is that so?
Belonephobia...
Dad...
You want me to deliver a message to the master?
No, I'll see him in person.
By the way, Shigeko-san,
could you fix that painting for me?
It's about 5 mm off to the right.
5 mm?
Y-Yes, sir!
Please.
Let's go, then!
That's a strange place to have a door.
Oh... A friend of the mistress installed this after that strange card arrived.
It's quite something!
You type in the PIN,
and place your index finger here...
Who is it?
Akatsuka, the butler.
I've brought Detective Mouri with me.
Ah... I'll open the door.
Like so!
Wow!
The doorbell won't ring until the machine has registered
a fingerprint from a member of the household.
It's like sci-fi!
It's not fiction.
Yasue Kunitomo (42)
Wife of the Head of the Kunitomo Family
These days, some apartments have fingerprint authentication systems too.
Toshimichi Sekiguchi (43)
Security Company President
It just hasn't caught on with the public yet.
This is Yasue-sama, the mistress.
The man on the left is her friend Sekiguchi-sama, who installed that door.
Somebody opened the door for us this time,
but what if nobody is on the third floor?
Then it can't be opened
by anyone but my husband.
But the members of the household can leave this floor by entering their fingerprints.
What if somebody else sticks a finger in?
Don't touch it!
If the system doesn't recognize a fingerprint,
all the alarms in the house will go off
and the security company will dispatch guards here!
Oopsie.
I wanted to install surveillance cameras too.
But I turned him down.
I'm okay with having one at the entrance.
Atsuhiro Kunitomo (56)
Head of the Kunitomo Family
But I didn't want to cover this fine house my father designed with ugly machinery.
Their security's already over the top...
Oh, you must be Mouri-san, the great detective.
Y-Yeah.
I'm Kunitomo. I'm the one who invited you here.
I hope you can get to the bottom of this case.
Er, sure...
Well then, if you would like,
I'll show you around the house.
Sure, why not.
Hey, kid, hurry up!
R-Right.
Is it safe to have a detective snooping around?
What if he finds out about it?
He won't.
The evidence is long gone.
But judging from what was written on that card...
That's why I hired a detective.
I want to catch the person who's threatening me
and find out how much they know.
Hold on! I'll get your medicine!
Your medicine...
Hey, are you all right?
At this rate, you're gonna kick the bucket
before we capture this guy.
Watch how you talk to him!
This is all your fault to begin with!
That's what I came down here for!
It's tomorrow, right?
The big day...
Yeah.
The rat hiding in my walls will scurry out.
Well?
What do you think?
What do I think? It's delicious!
Not the food! The investigation!
I can't say anything yet...
If somebody tampered with the cupboard and created those sounds,
they've probably gotten rid of the evidence by now.
Hey! You're wearing gloves at the table again!
I wash everything, you know! How rude!
S-Sorry...
Oh, I have to take the master to the hospital soon.
Sheesh.
Well, have some coffee before you go!
Those two seem close.
Their parents were friends. They've known each other since they were children.
Miss Chef, can I have some coffee too?
Ah, sure...
Here, I'll do it!
Sorry, mom...
She has acrophobia. Can't get close to any window that's higher than the second floor.
And the butler is a perfectionist who can't stand to have things the tiniest bit out of line!
A crooked tablecloth drives him crazy!
See?
Sheesh!
What's with this house?
Mysophobia—fear of germs. Belonephobia—fear of sharp objects.
Acrophobia—fear of heights. And a butler with OCD.
I took this job so I could get a taste of the high life at a millionaire's mansion.
If I'd known there were ghosts involved, I'd have stayed home with Conan-kun.
Hey, what are you looking at?
The dates of the five spooky incidents.
Two years ago, there were events on February 4 and July 4.
Same thing last year—February 4 and July 4.
But the first incident this year was on April 4.
Why do you think it happened in April this time?
I don't know...
But the 5th is usually a busy day, isn't it?
Dad was out on February 5 and July 5
last year and the year before...
You went to weddings, helped people move and went on neighborhood association trips!
Come to think of it, I want to a wedding on April 5 this year too.
Hey, people usually choose to do weddings,
trips and moves on taian days, don't they?
Y-Yeah.
I think you're right.
And the day before a lucky taian day
is always a butsumetsu—the unluckiest day!
B-Butsumetsu, you say?
Wait!
There's a poster up in our neighborhood
about a supermarket re-opening on October 5!
And your point is?
Then October 4 is a butsumetsu day! Are you saying something will happen tomorrow?
Today! It's already the 4th!
W-What was that sound?
A-A shoe?
Hello, Akatsuka-san? It's me, Yasue.
We had a flat tire and took some time replacing it.
Sorry we're running late, but we'll be back shortly.
What?
Sekiguchi-kun?
Y-Yes...
From the balcony of the upstairs bedroom.
I've called for an ambulance and the police,
but the master is the only one who can get into the third floor.
Please hurry back...
What's going on?
It's the curse...
An evil spirit...
Darling!
Your medicine!
Watabiki-san, hurry!
All right!
The deceased is Toshimichi Sekiguchi-san, age 41.
Estimated time of death is approximately four hours ago, around 8:30 to 9:00 PM.
I've been told Sekiguchi-san was a friend of yours.
Yes, ever since high school.
He ran a security company.
Is he the one who installed the fingerprint authentication system
on the door to the third floor?
Yes.
And where were you two at the time of his death?
My husband and I were in our car
on the way to the hospital.
My husband has heart problems,
so he visits a doctor for a checkup on the 3rd of every month.
When did you leave the house?
Around 8:00, I think.
Do you think we killed him?
The master and mistress had most certainly left the house by 8:00 PM!
Is that so?
I came up to the third floor at 7:45 PM sharp to take them down to the car.
Sekiguchi-sama was definitely alive at that time.
I see.
At any rate, he committed suicide, didn't he?
Well... This is a bit strange for a suicide.
The noose around his neck...
is unusually close to the balcony railing!
It's not impossible, mind you.
I have to suspect that this is a murder
set up to look like a suicide.
I don't know if it's suicide or murder.
But this card, "Here I pay for my sins from 13 years ago",
may be the key to the case.
M-Mouri-san!
Where did you find that?!
We found it on Sekiguchi-san's person before the cops arrived.
You interfered with the crime scene
before we could examine it?
Don't worry. I gave him a good wallop for it.
Right, kid?
But what does the card mean?
"My sins from 13 years ago"...
Dunno. It looks like some kind of suicide note...
But I bet the three people behind me,
whose faces turned pale after seeing the card,
can fill us in.
What's wrong?
Do you remember something that happened thirteen years ago?
Thirteen years ago...
The master's cruiser sank into the sea.
His ship?
Yes.
Back then, the whole household
used to go out on an annual cruise.
The cruiser was shipwrecked off the coast of Suruga Bay.
The master, mistress and Sekiguchi-sama,
who was there as their guest,
somehow managed to survive.
What about anyone else on the ship?
Everyone else on board was lost,
and the cruiser itself was never recovered.
Then maybe Sekiguchi-san caused the accident
and someone had a grudge against him for it.
I don't know.
I've never been fond of the sea,
so I never attended those cruises.
But the two survivors
know what happened, right?
About why the ship sank.
Not at all.
I was taking a nap inside the ship when Sekiguchi-san suddenly told us to escape.
In the chaos, we never found out what happened.
Say... Did the people who died in that accident leave any family here?
Yes indeed.
In that case,
this may have something to do with the five strange incidents in this house...
Five incidents?
That's what I was hired to investigate.
The master had a nightmare, the car almost crashed because the brakes malfunctioned,
a cupboard fell in the middle of the night, and strange sounds were heard inside the house.
And last but not least...
The family received this card.
Huh? Wait a second!
It looks just like the card found on Sekiguchi-san.
And all five incidents happened on an unlucky butsumetsu day.
It's only natural to suspect an inside job, right?
I see...
You suspect one of the shipwreck victims has a relative working here,
who blamed Sekiguchi-san for the accident and decided to kill him.
Please call for anyone who fits that description!
Yes, sir...
Sekiguchi-san's wristwatch...
There's something carved on the dial plate!
"E" and "N"?
Usually when you see "E" and "N"...
Fingerprints?
That means...!
That...can't be!
And that rope bugs me.
If my deduction is correct...
M-Mistress!
I-It's a curse!
The master must've seen that ghost!
I'm warning you! Open this door right now!
Intruder alert!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint:
Fingerprints
Conan-kun, show me your fingerprints.
Sure.
Ah, these fingerprints are Shin'ichi's?!
Are you surprised?
Eh?