What?
It's almost the tenth anniversary of Conan!
We made it through the first,
now let's aim for the next!
The suspicions become more evident
with the second case.
The distance to something
that shouldn't be real scares them.
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
A rich family with a mansion at Shizuoka called us.
They requested help with their problem:
the exorcism of an evil spirit,
using the science of reason.
In that mansion, events took place
during the last two years,
always taking place on the 4th, a butsumetsu day.
And when October 4 came along,
the first victim appeared.
The deceased is Toshimichi Sekiguchi-san, age 41.
I don't know if it's suicide or murder.
But this card, "Here I pay for my sins from 13 years ago",
may be the key to the case.
Atsuhiro Kunitomo (56)
Head of the
Kunitomo Family
Yasue Kunitomo (42)
Wife of the Head
of the Kunitomo Family
Thirteen years ago...
The master's cruiser sank into the sea.
Kenzo Akatsuka (50)
Kunitomo Family Butler
Did the people who died in that accident leave any family here?
Yes indeed.
Please answer me one at a time.
Introduce yourself and tell me how you're related to the victims of that shipwreck.
Well then...
Er... Let's start with Shigeko-san...
All right.
I'm Shigeko Senzaki, the head housekeeper.
Shigeko Senzaki (52)
Kunitomo Family Housekeeper
I lost my husband, who was the chef here.
He was cooking for the cruise.
My daughter Namika and I
were going to attend too,
but we both came down with a cold.
Namika Senzaki (28)
Kunitomo Family Chef
After my father died, I took his place here.
I'm Masashi Watabiki. I followed in my father's footsteps and became the chauffeur.
Masashi Watabiki (28)
Kunitomo Family Chauffeur
I lost my father in the accident...
and my younger brother.
Two people?
Er, yes.
My father was sailing the cruiser,
so he had to be there.
But my brother's death seemed especially wrong,
since he'd just happened to tag along for the trip.
And the last victim was my wife,
who worked as a maid here.
She was a fine, caring woman
who supported me in my post as butler.
It... It came as such a shock...
Akatsuka-san...
Hey, what's the meaning of this?
Why are you forcing us to relive that tragedy?
To be honest, we suspect one of you
may have murdered Sekiguchi-san.
You've gotta admit, you look pretty suspicious.
Even though you all saw that card
with the "I am the fifth soul" message,
none of you mentioned the shipwreck.
Maybe the rest of you are protecting the murderer!
O-Of course not!
Four people died in that accident, you know!
That's four souls, not five!
One, two, three, four...
Hey, you're right.
Besides, the accident occurred
on September 29, on a taian day.
It wasn't a butsumetsu day or the 4th of a month!
I see...
I don't think the chef or the housekeeper lady would've been able to do it.
What?
Think about it.
Sekiguchi-san was hanged from the balcony!
Right! Namika-san has acrophobia,
so she can't get close to it!
T-That's true...
But what about Shigeko-san?
The murderer hanged him to make it look like a suicide, right?
They'd have to look down from the balcony,
to make sure nobody was watching.
But it'd be really scary for the maid to look straight down from here,
because she'd see all the sharp prickly bars of the iron fence below.
I see! Shigeko-san is afraid of sharp objects.
If she were the killer, she'd have hanged him off to the side of the balcony!
Pretty clever, Conan-kun!
Watabiki-san was in the car with the master and mistress during the time of the crime,
so he couldn't have done it either.
That leaves just you, Akatsuka-san...
N-No...
I don't think the butler did it either!
What?
Take a look at these two cards.
The printing is slightly crooked, don't you think?
N-Now that you mention it...
An obsessive-compulsive like Akatsuka-san
wouldn't do such a sloppy job.
Yeah. But...
On the other hand, one of them
could be faking their condition, to fool us.
What?!
C-Conan-kun...
Conan-kun's right.
These quirks and phobias could all be an act.
Come downstairs with me
so I can question you separately!
We'll need your fingerprints too...
For crying out loud.
Why do we have to get fingerprinted?
Sorry.
We need to distinguish your fingerprints from the rest.
So?
Did the suspects have alibis?
Apart from Watabiki-san, the chauffeur, none.
But we've gotten prints from everyone except the master.
And we've only found Sekiguchi-san's prints on the rope, so we're kind of at a standstill...
How come you haven't taken the master's prints yet?
Well...
He's locked himself on the third floor,
saying he won't see anyone until this unlucky day is over.
Hey, would you quit this?! Dear?!
Calm down, dear.
We can talk this over once we learn more...
I'll talk to you later.
Dear...
That...can't be!
Dear!
Is somebody in there with him?
That's impossible! He said he wasn't going to see anybody, right?
Hey! Which room is this intercom connected to?
O-Our bedroom...
That's the room where Sekiguchi-san was hanged.
It's right above our bedroom!
Conan-kun!
A rope?
Hey, Conan-kun!
The pills have been crushed.
Somebody else was here...
But there are no signs of the balcony door being forced open.
And surely Kunitomo couldn't have forgotten to lock it!
So how did the murderer get inside?
Anyway, I gotta call an ambulance right away.
Though it may be too late...
And that rope bugs me.
If my deduction is correct...
the killer is still...
What?
The four-eyed kid went up to the third floor?
Yes!
There was a rope hanging down from the balcony,
and he climbed it to the third floor!
What?!
Hey, kid!
Open the door!
Hold on!
I'm warning you! Open this door right now!
Intruder alert!
What's going on?!
Hey, why's that alarm going off?
Did you do something?
Oh, Conan-kun?
Sorry...
Dad was trying to force the door open
and put his finger in the fingerprint reader!
He forgot that only people who have registered their fingerprints can touch it!
Can you stop the alarm and open the door?
Please try!
Okay... I'm opening the door.
But don't let anybody in except Inspector Yokomizo and old man Mouri.
You say that, but...
M-Master?
Oh geez, now everybody's coming at once.
He's not breathing. No pulse either.
Darling...
Why?
I'll call an ambulance!
I'll tell the other police officers downstairs...
Wait!
I already called for an ambulance.
Everybody, just stay put!
Ran-neechan?
Are you still standing in front of the door?
Um, yes...
Stay right there and make sure nobody leaves!
Inspector Yokomizo and Uncle Kogoro,
can you check the other rooms to see if there are any signs of a window being forced open?
Huh? Why?
Look over there!
Somebody stepped on those pills spilled on the balcony.
Who could've done that?
Someone deliberately surprised the master, who had heart problems,
to give him a heart attack, then crushed his pills so he couldn't take them!
And this rope!
The murderer must've used it to make his escape.
It wasn't moving.
It took less than a minute for me to find this rope
after hearing the master's cry from the intercom.
Wait... You mean...
That's right. The murderer saw me climbing up the rope,
and went back into the room, rather than making a run for it.
Right...
If the murderer surprised the master to give him a heart attack,
stole his medication and crushed it, tied the rope to the balcony,
then watched him die before making an escape,
that'd take well over a minute.
There wasn't time to climb down the rope!
So there's a good chance...
that the murderer is still hiding somewhere on the third floor.
T-Then we should split up and search!
Right!
No, don't!
You could be attacked!
But while we're all standing around, the killer could escape!
Wouldn't it be better for us to search this floor?
How about this?
We'll search one room at a time.
First I'll enter the room to check the windows.
The rest of you, follow after me.
Mouri-san will stake out the hall to make sure no one comes out.
U-Understood.
It looks fine. Come on in.
I don't see anyone.
Me neither.
Let's move on to the next room.
Well, we've searched every room, but we haven't found anyone.
All the windows on the third floor
were bolted from the inside,
and there were no signs of forced entry.
Hey, Ran! Can you hear me?
Did you see anybody go out the door?
No.
Three ambulance crews went in with a stretcher and came out again,
but that's all.
That means...
The kid's got it all wrong!
What are you talking about?
No, there's one other possibility.
Maybe the murderer hid among us when Conan-kun opened the door...
and let the rest of us in!
It can't be...
Wait a sec!
Are you saying the killer is among us?
N-No...
We all came running up here when the alarm went off!
Didn't you see us enter after you?
Not really...
I remember the lady of the house being with us the whole time, but that's all.
How about you, Mouri-san?
Nah.
That's why I wanted to keep the suspects out!
At any rate...
I'll station officers in front of the fingerprint reader. The third floor will be off-limits.
As for all of you, I have more questions.
You got that?
When we heard the master's scream over the intercom,
his wife was with us.
But none of the rest of you have alibis!
What do you mean?
We were just waiting in our rooms like you told us to!
We each have a private room.
If you don't trust us, you should've had somebody guarding us!
Er, well...
The biggest question is how the murderer got inside
after the master said he wouldn't let anyone in for the rest of the day.
Come to think of it, when I heard my husband's voice over the intercom,
I'll talk to you later.
I heard something like a knock on the door.
And my husband didn't seem surprised by it.
A knock?
But then he started screaming, like he was in agony!
R-Right.
Maybe he let somebody in.
But why?
He kicked out the police who were investigating Sekiguchi-san's hanging
and locked himself on the third floor.
Why would he do that?
Even if that's the case,
there was some distance in the bedroom between the door and the intercom.
I find it hard to believe that the door opening would scare him enough to kill him.
Even if the murderer had a weapon,
he had his finger on the intercom,
so he could've easily called for help
and unlocked the door.
What kind of fear would stop him
from doing that much?
Let's look back at those strange incidents in the past,
before we have any more deaths.
First the shipwreck 13 years ago,
off the coast of Suruga Bay.
Do you recall anything unusual
before they set sail?
I went down to the harbor to see everybody off.
Apart from the fact that Sekiguchi-sama decided to join them at the last minute,
I don't remember anything odd.
Why did Sekiguchi-san suddenly decide to join?
Oh, he'd been angling to get in on our annual cruise.
When Namika-san and Shigeko-san came down with a cold,
we had some extra room, so we agreed.
I remember one strange thing.
Sekiguchi-sama brought a huge bag on board!
Any idea what it was?
I think he said it was full of scuba-diving equipment.
I see.
So, the people who died in the shipwreck were...
Shigeko-san's husband and Namika-san's father, who was the family chef...
Watabiki-san's father, who was the chauffeur...
Watabiki-san's younger brother,
who was a guest on the cruise...
and Akatsuka-san's wife,
who was a maid here, am I right?
Yes.
You, your husband and Sekiguchi-san
survived by getting into a life raft.
Were there any other rafts on the ship?
There were,
but we were so desperate to escape that we never saw whether anyone got into them.
We don't even know if anyone sent a distress call.
More recently, the master had a nightmare, the car almost crashed,
this strange card was delivered to the house, a cupboard fell in the middle of the night,
and strange sounds were heard in the house.
Didn't any of you notice these things always happened
on the 4th of a month, on an unlucky butsumetsu day?
We did notice it was always on the 4th.
The master may have figured it out.
He was very picky about dates.
He always chose a lucky taian day for the cruise.
And Sekiguchi-sama was always at the house the day before an incident.
Was he there on the night the two of them heard strange sounds in the empty house?
Yes.
Ma'am?
What kind of sounds?
Hm, well...
It was like something bouncing off the wall...
and slapping against leather.
Sounds like somebody throwing a ball against a wall and catching it in a baseball glove.
Does anyone in this house play baseball?
Oh, yes.
Well, not now.
But my late brother was a baseball player.
W-Wait a minute...
Then it...
Then it is a ghost!
The nightmare happened in bed,
which a maid makes.
The car represents the chauffeur.
The cupboard goes with the chef.
And the sound of someone playing baseball...
Each incident is connected
to one of the accident victims!
Then the message, "Repent of your sins before I awaken"...
means their ghosts will arise to haunt this house!
Ma'am? Ma'am, are you all right?!
I-It's a curse!
This house is haunted by an evil spirit!
That's ridiculous.
There's no such thing as ghosts!
B-But only a ghost could slip past that electronic security system!
That's right... The master must've seen a ghost!
Are you kidding? Yokomizo, tell her she's being—
Uh, sorry.
My cell phone started vibrating at the perfect moment.
Yokomizo speaking.
Sheesh.
Forensics...
You found fingerprints on the rope and the medicine bottle?
Yes...
Yes.
And you're sure they're the prints
of the last person who touched them?
The case is as good as solved!
We have everyone's prints!
Well? Whose prints did they find?
W-W-Well...
T-They don't belong to anyone who works here.
That's crazy!
Then how'd the murderer get past that door?!
I-I don't know...
It's a ghost...
It's a ghost after all...
This just got interesting.
The president of the company disappeared on September 26, 13 years ago?
If that's all, I'd like to get back to work!
Did you see anybody new or not?
W-We didn't...
No, there was an extra person.
Now, allow me to explain...
how the two murders in this mansion really happened.
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint:
Siblings
Next time, the solution!
But if it really was the work of a ghost...
Hey!
Ow.