It's almost the tenth anniversary of Conan!
We made it through the first,
now let's aim for the next!
The climax of the butsumetsu case!
An unexpected comment from Ran leads to a deduction we overlooked!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult.
His name? Detective Conan!
A rich family with a mansion in Shizuoka called us.
In that mansion, for the past several years,
a series of events took place, always on a butsumetsu day, on the 4th of the month.
Then on the October 4 butsumetsu,
there were two victims.
You found fingerprints on the rope and the medicine bottle?
Well? Whose prints did they find?
W-W-Well...
T-They don't belong to anyone who works here.
Well, now we know this was an outside job.
Can we go back to our rooms?
Okay...
But I'm going to have to station officers in front of your doors.
Rest well.
Hey...
Where did Sekiguchi-san live?
Kenzo Akatsuka (50)
Kunitomo Family Butler
Er, his company is in...
Do you know, Watabiki-kun?
Masashi Watabiki (28)
Kunitomo Family Chauffeur
Ah, yes...
Sekiguchi Security. It's in Yokohama, Nishi Ward, the Umeda neighborhood!
You're very informed.
I pick him up at his place whenever he visits here.
And this guy takes notes on everything.
Everything?
We know someone in Yokohama...
My brother!
Why are you bugging me at this hour?
Toshimichi Sekiguchi?
Sure, I met him a couple of times when I was a rookie.
I remember him 'cause he got on my nerves.
What do you want from him?
He was found hanged here in Shizuoka, at the home of a man named Kunitomo.
If he hanged himself, it's suicide, isn't it?
It may be murder.
The master of the house was killed shortly afterwards.
I met him for questioning while we were searching
for the president of his security company...
Searching?
Yeah.
The president of the company went missing!
It's been 13 years and he still hasn't been discovered.
T-Thirteen years?
Yeah.
If I remember correctly, he vanished around the end of September.
Yeah. It was on Mom's birthday.
The president of the company disappeared on September 26, 13 years ago?
Kunitomo's cruiser sank off the coast of Suruga Bay that year on September 29!
Three days before!
That Sekiguchi guy took over as president of the company.
Sir!
Wanna go out for drinks?
Yup! As long as you're paying!
Sheesh... Buy your men a drink now and then!
You're such a miser!
Call me frugal!
See ya!
Yeah...
A miser...
All the suspects have strange habits and phobias.
You three should get some rest, Mouri-san.
Yeah.
Hey, why don't we look around the suspects' rooms before we go to bed?
Let's find out if their funny hang-ups are real!
Why I'm afraid of sharp objects?
When I was a little girl, I was trying to grab my mother's sewing kit,
Shigeko Senzaki (52)
Kunitomo Family Housekeeper
when I fell and stabbed myself in the forehead with a needle!
That had to hurt.
Hey!
Is that why you taped that calendar to the wall?
That's right.
There are marks on the calendar.
Oh, those are our birthdays. Me, my daughter Namika, Akatsuka-san and Watabiki-kun.
My husband, Watabiki-kun's father and Akatsuka-san's wife,
who died in the accident on the ship,
were all childhood friends.
We used to throw a big birthday party for the three of them.
Twenty years ago, Watabiki-kun's mother died from an illness.
There used to be eight birthdays on this calendar, but now we're down to four...
The reason I'm acrophobic?
You're better off asking Akatsuka-san or Watabiki-kun.
Did you fall from a high place because of them?
No, they saved me!
Namika Senzaki (28)
Kunitomo Family Chef
When I was in fourth grade,
I fell out of a tree in the garden, and Watabiki-kun caught me.
At that time, his left hand...
You were hurt?
No, Watabiki-kun was.
I'd forgotten all about it until I saw the scar on his left hand a couple of years ago.
He nearly always wears gloves because of his fear of germs.
My memory's so fuzzy. Before I saw the scar, I always thought it was his brother who saved me.
Your room's very clean, by the way.
Of course!
A chef has to keep everything hygienic!
I suppose so.
Hey! Don't poke around in a lady's room!
Er, sorry!
Here's the scar from that injury.
What about it?
You even wear gloves in your room!
Yes.
I only take them off to sleep, bathe and touch the fingerprint reader upstairs.
No, wait... I also take them off when I drive or use a pen because the gloves slip.
Hey, this must be the baseball glove your brother used!
But only when he was a little boy.
Where's your baseball glove?
Unlike my brother, I've never been much of an athlete.
Your calendar has a lot of notes on it!
Yes.
I once forgot an important errand for the master.
Ever since then, I've kept notes on everything.
Huh? Why am I a perfectionist?
Do I need a reason to be neat and tidy?
It's a little extreme...
It seems true that you're very well-organized, though.
Everything in your room is perfectly straight.
I feel uncomfortable otherwise.
Hey, is there anybody here who's the opposite of you? Really sloppy?
I don't think "sloppy" is the right term to use,
but Shigeko-san can be a bit like that.
There was a time when the plates she stacked in the cupboard were 3 mm off.
Watabiki-kun and Namika-chan always stack them perfectly.
Huh?
Is this your compass?
Yes. I like to go hiking.
By the way, did you notice the letters carved on the dial plate of Sekiguchi-san's watch?
What?
I did. E and N, wasn't it?
But it's strange.
If it were like this compass,
the N and E would be switched.
I wonder why...
How should I know?!
Well, we've checked out
the rooms of all four suspects...
but we didn't find anything, did we?
Nope! The kid wasted our time again!
Let's continue the investigation after we get some rest.
Yeah. Good idea.
What is it? There's something bugging me...
Something I've overlooked...
Something that's not right... but what?
By the way, Conan-kun...
I bought you a new pair of jammies!
Want to wear them tonight?
We'll be twinsies again!
Twinsies?
I see!
I never considered that possibility!
And if that's the truth...
the unusual way Sekiguchi-san was killed...
the way the murderer got past the fingerprint authentication system...
the murderer's ability to disappear from the third floor...
and the reason Kunitomo was frightened to death
can all be explained!
Ah, nice work!
Hey!
Uncle Kogoro asked me to call the four suspects and the mistress to the third floor!
You mean Mouri-san's figured out who the murderer is?
Uh-huh! I think he has!
And it's someone in this house,
so he wants you to keep an eye out!
Then he's going to start his deduction show now?
No, he said he'll start in three hours!
T-Three hours?
Yup!
But only if you follow the instructions I'm about to give you!
Sure thing.
Why'd you wake us up at the crack of dawn?
Allow me to explain.
I called you here to reveal the truth about the two murders that just occurred here.
And to tell you...
the murderer is among you.
In the first murder, Sekiguchi-san was hanged from the balcony of this bedroom.
I thought we were all cleared because of the time of death and the details of the crime!
That's right!
Yes. Namika-san has acrophobia,
so she couldn't have hanged somebody from a balcony on the third floor.
Shigeko-san is afraid of sharp objects,
so she would've avoided hanging the body over that iron fence.
The message printed on the card planted on Sekiguchi-san by the murderer was crooked.
That's something an obsessive-compulsive like Akatsuka-san would never do.
And Watabiki-san was driving the master and his wife to the hospital at the time of the crime...
so they couldn't have done it.
Then who was it?
Are you going to accuse one of us of faking our mental condition?
No.
Namika-san's room was very clean, but there was dust on the windows.
You really are unable to get close to windows, aren't you?
Shigeko-san had no sharp objects in her room.
Even her calendar was held up with tape instead of thumbtacks.
And Akatsuka's room was impeccable.
I think it's safe to say none of you are lying.
Let's look into the second murder.
Somehow the murderer managed to get past the fingerprint authentication to enter the bedroom on the third floor.
This person appeared before the master, inducing a heart attack, crushed his heart pills...
then disappeared from the room without a trace.
One possibility is that he or she hid somewhere on the third floor
after seeing Conan climb up the escape rope...
and hid among us when we all crowded into the room.
But you found fingerprints on the rope and medicine bottle, right?
I suspect they belong to the accomplice.
A-An accomplice?
In other words, there are two murderers!
Are you saying one of us let the mystery person in here?
But the master said he wouldn't see anyone until the day was over.
And we looked all over the third floor after the crime, but we didn't find anyone!
That's right. I didn't see anyone go out into the hall,
nor was there any sign of escape from a balcony or window.
Then where is this accomplice?
That's why we asked you all here. So we can reenact the search.
After all, we might have overlooked something.
Listen up, everybody! We're going to search one room at a time!
But unlike last time, I'll be the last person to enter the room!
I want to keep my eye on each and every one of you!
Watabiki-san, you take on the job of entering the room first and searching the window and balcony!
Do you hear me?
Er, yes!
Start with the study next to the bedroom!
If you see anything unusual, report to me!
You don't need to yell so loud! We can hear you!
Oops, sorry!
I get carried away when I'm worked up.
Well, then. After you, Watabiki-san!
Er, okay...
Uh...
Looks like the window's locked.
And I don't see anybody out on the balcony.
Can we go in now?
Yes, of course!
You really think this will turn up something new?
Oh, yes.
Well, then. On to the next room.
Right! Move on, everyone!
No suspicious people came out into the hall.
Ah, sorry, Conan-kun.
Sheesh. We didn't find anything!
If that's all, I'd like to get back to work!
Quiet! First, one question.
You really didn't see anybody new?
Huh?
Did you see anybody new or not?
Well?!
W-We didn't...
No, there was an extra person in the rooms you just searched!
Weren't you listening? We didn't see anybody!
But there he is. One more person, right behind Inspector Yokomizo.
Twins?!
Yeah. This is my younger brother, who works for the Kanagawa Police.
Howdy.
Okay, I'm heading home.
Don't tell your boss I got involved in this investigation!
Sure, bro.
What are you trying to say?
It happened like this...
The murderer stood behind the rest of you
to make sure they were the last to enter and leave each room.
Before reaching the room where the accomplice was hiding,
the murderer dropped back and stayed behind.
The accomplice joined the group when the others entered the room,
after Inspector Yokomizo had finished checking the window.
If the accomplice was a twin wearing the same clothes,
just like with Detective Yokomizo, nobody would notice they'd switched places.
It'd look like the room had been empty from the start.
But...
Where is this person?
No one here has a tw—
Right.
I started to catch on when Shigeko-san showed us her calendar.
She told us that 20 years ago she would circle the birthdays
of herself, her husband and Namika...
Watabiki-san, his brother and their parents...
and Akatsuka and his wife. That's nine people.
But Shigeko said there were eight birthdays, so maybe two of them shared a birthday.
I knew for sure when Namika-san told us about falling out of a tree in fourth grade.
She wasn't sure which brother caught her...
because they looked the same!
In other words...
Watabiki-san, this murder was committed by you and your twin brother!
What are you talking about?
His brother died 13 years ago in the shipwreck!
What if he didn't die in that accident?
What if he survived and managed to swim ashore?
As proof, earlier, we saw a scar on Watabiki-san's left hand
from the time he saved Namika-san from falling out of that tree.
But earlier, when he borrowed Ran's pen, his hand had no scar!
And although the handwriting on Watabiki-san's calendar looked roughly consistent,
the circles before each note were drawn differently from day to day!
I suspect you switched places from time to time.
If you took careful notes of everything in a single shared notebook...
you could pass as one person without raising any suspicions!
You waited for the opportunity to kill Sekiguchi-san and the master of the house!
First the younger brother drove the master and mistress to the hospital to create an alibi.
Thirty minutes later, the elder brother, who had been hiding in the house,
used the fingerprint reader to ring for Sekiguchi-san to open the door for him.
Once inside, he strangled Sekiguchi and hanged him from the balcony.
A few hours later, he entered the third floor again and killed the master by giving him a heart attack!
But the master had refused to see anyone...
Sekiguchi-san agreed to let Watabiki-san in because he'd been with the master when the murder took place.
He had no reason not to trust him.
But the master got the shock of his life...
when two identical men walked into the room.
And one of them had been dead for 13 years!
The younger brother deliberately left his fingerprints on the medicine bottle and rope
to make it look like the work of a stranger,
completely clearing the household staff.
So where is he?
We never found anyone!
That's why I told Watabiki-san to check the windows...
and why I shouted at you when I gave you orders!
So the accomplice, hiding somewhere on the third floor, would also hear me...
and know it was safe to hide on the balcony!
This house is surrounded by officers!
Go in and get your brother...
There's no need for that.
Brother!
Then you confess to the murders?
Yes.
Wait a minute! If you're alive...
What about Dad?
My wife?
I'm sorry, but no.
I'm sure they were left to drown.
What's going on? What really happened all those years ago?
When we got out to sea, the ship started having problems.
I dove into the water to check.
That person's bag was entangled in the screw propeller.
And I saw an arm sticking out of it.
An arm?
It was probably the president of Sekiguchi-san's company, who went missing 13 years ago.
Sekiguchi-san talked his way onto the cruise so he could dispose of the body.
He's the "fifth soul" mentioned on the first card.
Did you and your husband know about this?
I don't know. I didn't know anything!
And when I had warned everyone,
Sekiguchi suddenly shoved my father away from the wheel and sped the ship up.
He must have been trying to get the bag off the propeller.
But instead, he capsized the ship, throwing everyone into the water.
The only life raft bobbed up right in front of Sekiguchi.
That piece of filth helped the master and mistress into the raft, then the three of them fled.
T-That's not it!
My husband and I were planning to come back with help!
But Sekiguchi-kun...
They're already dead.
We're all in this together now, so you'd better keep quiet!
That's what he said.
For a while, we all managed to cling to a life preserver together.
But it was clear we couldn't hold out for long.
Since I had the most strength left, I volunteered to swim for help.
But I lost consciousness before I reached the shore.
When I woke up, I was in a hospital bed...
with no memory of anything.
I ran away from the hospital and started traveling Japan to figure out who I was.
Two years ago, in the summer, I ran into my older brother by pure chance.
He helped me regain my memory.
It was the day after that near-fatal car accident.
Even though it was entirely my fault, the master kept apologizing to me.
When my brother told me his story, I finally understood why.
Then it was just a coincidence that the master's nightmare and the car accident both happened on a butsumetsu day?
Yes.
It was our only hope of revenge.
We had no evidence to take to the police.
But if we'd managed to find the sunken cruiser...
You'd never have found it.
Sekiguchi lied to the police about where it sank.
The real location was 34°45′ north, 138°30′ east.
What?
The N and E carved on Sekiguchi-san's watch.
It stands for north latitude 45 minutes, east longitude 30 minutes!
If the cruiser sank somewhere in Suruga Bay, it's roughly 34° north and 138° east.
I see.
But why use a butsumetsu day on the 4th?
The shipwreck happened on September 29, on a taian day!
October 14, 13 years ago, was a butsumetsu day.
That's the day the master told the police to call off the search.
The cruiser had been moved by the tide.
But the police managed to find it...
with the bag that caused all the trouble still entangled in the propeller.
Speaking of trouble...
I was left with a crisis on my hands.
C'mon, Conan-kun! Wear it just once so we can take a photo!
I think it's cute...
You'll never get me in those pajamas.
Seriously, pandas?
It just seemed like someone was watching us.
Was I imagining it?
The window in the grenier...
A-A camera?!
The detective office? Why?
Is it to get the old man?
Don't tell me...
The men in...
Y-Yikes!
Yikes, yikes!
Next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint:
Name Plate
Next time, it's those two after a long time!
Those two?
You'll have to wait until next week to find out!