Soon it will be Conan's 10th Anniversary!
Overcome one and begin the next.
A mysterious old couple is living in a new house...
What is this strange feeling?
Is their target me or Haibara?
Perceiving the one and only truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Beika, right?
Very good.
Hey, Conan-kun, did you see that new
house for rent in your neighborhood?
New house?
Really?
What kind of house is it?
Is it big?
No, it's small but it's a really beautiful house.
You like those types of houses, don't you, Yoshida-san?
When I get married, I want live in that kind of house.
M-Married!?
Conan-kun, do you want to see it on the way home?
What is it?
Nothing.
So, Ayumi-chan, how about just we go?
Let's leave those guys alone.
Right?
Why are you coming with us?
Oh yeah, what about you?
Conan-kun, hurry up!
Why are you calling Conan?
That's right!
What's wrong?
Nothing. It just seemed like someone was watching us.
Must be my imagination.
THE HOME OF BEIKA'S GRENIER
I see...
This is the house?
Here, Mitsuhiko-kun.
Jees, you've already finished eating, Genta-kun?
Hey, hey...
Don't get to imaginative.
It's true that it's small and cute.
Isn't it?
So?
What kind of houses do you like, Conan-kun?
Me?
That's right.
Ayumi-chan!
Why are you asking Cohan-kun?
It has nothing to do with him!
Because, if he's the one that becomes my husband...
I would like to know what he likes.
Hey, Ayumi-chan...
Well then, let's have a look inside.
It's just as you heard.
Can we look inside?
Quit joking around...
I haven't listened to a word any of you all said.
That girl's father is looking for a house.
lf she likes it...
He might buy it.
Right this way!
The first floor has two six-tatami mat rooms,
a washroom, and a bathroom with a toilet.
I guess these rooms are usually used for children?
Yeah, that's right.
The architecture of this home is
aimed at couples in their thirties...
With the design being based on an image
of two children and a family of four.
On the second floor, we have a living
room and kitchen with sixteen mats.
It's big!
The lighting is great, isn't it?
Across the corridor, we have a room of eight mats.
Is there also a third floor?
Yes, this house is special due to its grenier.
This place is really interesting!
There's a window in here too!
I can see the sky!
And in the evening, you can see the stars.
The detective agency...
You can see it from here.
What do you think?
The grenier and the second floor's living room are great, but...
The rooms on the first floor both seemed a little dark.
I expected more of the garden.
The stairs are a little too steep...
Still, for the amount of space, it's a fair enough deal.
So, how about recommending this house to your parents?
What?
What do you mean "What"?
Well, we're done looking at the inside.
Let's go.
The layout of the room's wasn't bad.
My house's layout is better.
That house was sold?
My mom and I were passing by yesterday.
There was a "sold" sign on it
We even asked about.
That's really a shame.
It isn't easy to find a house you like.
But, I really didn't like the inside.
No need to be sad, Ayumi.
I'll build you a better house!
Why is it you want to build Ayumi-chan a house?
If anyone's going to build it, I'll be the one!
I wonder if those who bought it were
in their thirties with two children.
Well, that would be just right.
I heard it was a grandfather and
grandmother in their seventies.
A grandfather and grandmother?
How strange...
That house wasn't designed for older people.
That's true.
The stairs are too steep for them, aren't they?
But, everyone has different reasons, so it doesn't matter I guess.
Udohisashi
Udohisashi...
lt's a strange name, huh?
You guys!
So, since the name plate has already been posted...
I guess they've already moved in.
Why are you all here?
We thought Conan-kun would come here to look.
Even if it's something this small, we must investigate.
That's the foundation of being a detective.
Hey, hey...
Oh!
Good afternoon.
G-Good afternoon!
Do you kids live in this neighborhood?
We just moved in today.
I would love for you kids to come
in and tell me all about this area.
Yeah, that's fine!
You can leave Beika to us.
I know where to buy delicious eel rice for cheap.
Really?
All right...
Well, I'm going out for a while.
Have a safe trip.
Have a safe trip!
Oh, so you're all detectives?
Yes!
At Teitan Elementary School,
we're known as the Detective Boys!
There's no one in Beika who doesn't know us.
The namesake is almost as famous as mine, Kojima.
Here.
Thank you.
I'm sorry that the furniture hasn't been delivered yet.
It's OK.
Hey Old Lady, do you and your husband live here together?
That's right.
Do the steep stairs not scare you?
Not at all.
I've wanted a house like this since I was young.
I know that feeling well!
My grandmother always says she'd
Like to live in a high-up apartment.
Not to mention, I can leave this house
to my only son who lives nearby.
I see.
But, you should be careful, you know.
Thank you.
You're so kind.
Thanks for the meal.
Goodbye!
The mystery has been solved.
The reason they bought that house
is because their son lives nearby.
She did say that's why they bought that house, right?
But, there's something they're hiding...
Something?
No, I can't say for certain...
The day after tomorrow?
Yeah.
What is it that's making me feel strange?
I've wanted a house like this since I was young.
That...
That's what they're hiding?
But any old man could do it...
And then, at that time...
Why did she make that face?
Hey, hey...
Conan-kun, are you listening?
I said...
The day after tomorrow, we won't be back until really
late, so come back and watch the house, please.
Conan-kun!
I see.
Sorry, sorry.
Jeez, why're you spacing out and not eating?
Father!
Oh no!
Taxi?
How troublesome.
Damn it!
Shinichi, what are you doing out here?
Professor?
Great!
You came at just the right time!
Sorry to ask, but...
Could you follow that taxi ahead?
Hurry, Professor!
But even if you say that...
Those actions aren't unusual for an old man.
Isn't it normal for an old man to use a hand to stand up?
I considered that.
And the old woman being upset with him...
It's probably because she'd been telling
him to stand up without using his hands.
Maybe so he won't appear so old.
It's like when Genta calls me an old man.
You look like an old man!
Sorry for troubling you.
You can head back now.
I know you won't stop until you're satisfied, but...
Is all this all right?
No need to worry.
Shinichi!
At times like this, I wonder what Ai-kun would do...
Yes, yes...
I'll help you in every way I can, rest assured.
In any way I can.
Shit!
Shit! Shit!
In the end, I had to come back...
Who was that old Chinese guy?
And just who is that old man...
Exactly?
That place...
The grenier window...
Could it..
The window in the grenier...
A camera?
And...
Why is it directed at the detective agency?
Is it to get Uncle?
Or...
What is it?
Nothing...
It just seemed like someone was watching us.
Is the target me?
If so...
Could the Black Organization be...
How is it, Haibara?
Have you seen them in the Organization?
I see.
But, it's possible that they're just disguised...
Disguised?
Yeah.
Disguised, huh?
Shin-chan!
So it was you, Mom.
It's been awhile, Yukiko-san.
Professor Agasa...
You fell into their trap, Yukiko.
The professor was on his side this time...
As revenge for last time.
But...
How did you figure it out?
You should explain me before quizzing me.
What's the meaning behind all this?
Actually, we're here gathering material for Yuusaku's next
project and only arrived in Japan the day before yesterday.
Beika, right?
Very good.
We went home first, but after I got worried about you...
So I went to your primary school to see how you were doing.
At that exact moment, I saw you and your friends walking out.
Conan-kun, hurry up!
Why are you calling Conan?
That's right!
You're really sharp, Shin-chan.
I knew you'd find me out.
And then, I was relieved that you were doing well.
But I realized I didn't know anything about your new life.
I wanted to watch Shin-chan's daily life after becoming Conan.
What's with all that?
But, I was walking and started thinking,
"How can I hide so he won't discover me?"
I then found that house by chance.
Even though it was small, it was just what I needed.
I decided to have a look inside.
And what was right across from the grenier's window?
The detective agency!
That's when she came up with the plan.
We disguised ourselves-as an old couple for a week
so we could watch your daily life from that window.
Even Yuusaku loved my idea!
And then, we went to the real estate agent about that house...
Only to find out he was a big fan of mine!
Here.
He agreed to it immediately.
But, I was surprised when you showed up with your friends.
You see, I...
Am a former actress, so I knew I could trick you, but...
Yuusaku...
Right.
Dad's acting is what made me suspicious.
But that was...
Yeah.
It's as you said...
It's not unusual for an old man to use his hands to stand up.
But...
That's usually when there is no one around to see them...
To show they aren't weak.
Right, even in the world of acting...
Young actors do it when playing older
people, and can ruin plays with it.
That's why you were upset then, right?
You saw that?
That's right...
I was thinking, "Now you've done it."
I couldn't help it.
I'm a mystery author, not an actor.
But, your perception was impressive.
You noticed the professor and I were following you, didn't you?
Somewhat.
That old Chinese man was the leader of
bandits in the mainland in his younger days.
I was gathering information for the next Night Baron series...
The title of which is Night Baron vs.
The Mysterious Man from China."
And when I was talking with him in a low voice...
Well, I was surprised he threw a sword at you.
Yuusaku!
Anyway, don't you think you overdid it?
I'm sorry.
I was just really worried about your current life.
You live so far away from us...
But you always say you're doing "all right," don't you?
I really...
I really just wanted to know how it truly is.
Mother...
And...
Every time I saw one of our pictures of the little Shin-chan...
I wanted more of them!
Mom, you never change...
That old couple already moved out, huh?
As we thought, this house isn't suitable for old people.
But their name sure was interesting...
What was it...
Udohisashi...
Why didn't I realize it until now?
If you read it separately, it's "u-do-ku."
And if you turn "u-do-ku" around...
Kudou
Isn't that right?