It's almost Conan's tenth anniversary!
Overcoming one obstacle, and aiming for the next.
Is this a prank by the God of meetings?
Patterned after the legend of the Eight-Headed Serpent...
Conan tackles the mystery of this case!
Seeing through to the one and only truth...
I look like a child, but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
Well, then...
We'll do a little sightseeing...
And then eat and drink a lot!
You sure are acting differently
than you were on the plane.
Scary, scary scary...
The place we traveled to this time...
Izumo Grand Shrine
Is the old, mythical village of...
Izumo.
Sword of the Eight-Headed Serpent:
Part 1!
We came all the way to the Grand
Shrine of Izumo, the God of marriage.
I understand why Ran absolutely had to see it, but...
Please find me a good match.
Jeez, what kind of lover's hopes are those?
Let's do this here!
Wow, quite an impressive number here.
Note: The "knot of love" or "en-musubi" is a Japanese amulet which is said to
bring love and marriage to its owner when tied to the tree Izumo blessed.
Well then... Tie the knot of love, tie the knot of love.
Note: A Shimenawa is a braided rice straw rope
used for ritual purification in the Shinto religion.
That's the biggest Shimenawa in Japan.
I-It really is huge!
Absolutely unbeatable...
It weighs five tons.
Oh, five tons?
You're Mouri Kogoro-san, aren't you?
The famous detective.
Y-Yes.
Doesn't it look even better than on television?
It's better to see it in person.
Um... Are you working here?
Ah, I'm Ezumi Eiko.
Ezumi Eiko (25
Sunrise Shop - Eldest Daughter
I work at a small shop in front of the path to this shrine.
Oh, a small shop?
Ah! I'm his daughter, Ran, and this is Conan-kun.
Good afternoon.
Say, Miss...
What's that money up there for?
Oh, you're right! There are a lot of coins stuck to it.
There's a legend that says...
If your coin gets stuck there, your wish will come true.
So that means it can also bless my wish for a good match.
Here goes!
Damn!
It doesn't stick.
Damn it!
It looks like your wish will never come true.
But I'm jealous.
You live in a town that's so well-known for marriage.
Yes, but I just wish I could get a real marriage proposal...
A "real" one?
Does that mean someone already popped the question?
I got it! The guy who proposed must be too poor.
He has quite a bit of money,
since he deals with a lot of businesses.
Then, does he have a bad personality?
A rich person with a bad personality,
that's the absolute worst combination.
Getting married to him is a tragedy waiting to happen.
Dad!
But the circumstances won't allow me to decline.
Marriage is about bonding
with the person one really loves...
So, what's this guy's name?
His name is Wanibuchi Kouji-san.
You told us that there are some circumstances,
but marrying Wanibuchi-san when you don't love him...
Isn't that like throwing your life away?
Dad!
I'm sorry, please excuse him.
No, Mouri-san was just telling me that for my sake.
Say, Conan-kun...
Would you like to go see an interesting model?
An interesting model?
Izumo Grand Shrine originally looked like this?
Ancient Izumo Grand Shrine- Museum Model Exhibition
It certainly was hard to get to.
It must've been one of the world's wonders!
It was said to be the biggest temple in Japan.
If you're interested in hearing more...
Note: The Heian period was from 794- 1185,
and the Kamakura period was from from 1185- 1333.
We believe this piece of art dates back to the late
Heian period or the beginning of the Kamakura period...
Ryou-chan.
Sorry, wait a moment.
Sure.
He's Fukuma Ryousuke, a childhood friend of mine.
He's been interested in the ancient
times ever since he was a young boy.
Fukuma Ryousuke (25)
Museum Curator
Researching about them made him so happy,
he decided to make a living doing it.
Eiko-san's true feelings for Fukuma-san are...
She's definitely in love with Fukuma-san.
So this guy is the problem?
Haven't you realized that a rich guy with a
bad personality can't snatch Eiko-san away?
Yes?!
Mouri-san!
Dad!
I'm really sorry.
No, that's okay.
Thank you for today, Mouri-san!
No problem. Best of luck to
you in getting out of that proposal.
You're talking so seriously again,
but what are you really thinking about?
And then, the next day...
A case occurred.
Worth 10 million yen?
Inome Cave
That settles it.
He was stabbed in the back with a knife, huh?
Outsiders aren't allowed to come in here!
Don't tell me that you're...
My name is Mouri.
I'm a private detective from Tokyo.
I thought so. I often hear about your great work.
I'm Yamane from the Izumo Police.
And I'm Komura, from the same prefecture.
Formalities aside, what are you doing here?
I just happened to be in the area.
But it doesn't seem like this case will
require the abilities of a famous detective.
W-What do you mean?
The victim is from Izumo,
a man renowned for his business skills...
Founder and president of Wanibuchi Enterprises...
Wanibuchi Kouji-san, 35 years old.
Wanibuchi Kouji?
The man Eiko-san told us she was engaged to!
That guy sure was killed at a convenient time.
Do you know him?
He was famous in this area for
being a powerful businessman.
The first to discover the body was this couple.
They're also locals.
Well, this isn't really a place where tourists would come.
We estimate the time of death to be around 1:00 PM.
If we assume that Wanibuchi-san's
watch broke when he fell over...
He died when the watch hands stopped at 1:05 PM.
So that certainly confirms the time of murder.
Do you think the murderer was
someone who held a grudge against him?
Since he was a powerful businessman with a
bad attitude, he must have made a lot of enemies.
While it's true that he didn't have the best reputation...
The culprit's goal was to steal a katana,
which was valued at 10 million yen.
A katana worth 10 million yen?
It was Wanibuchi-san's property.
He went to an antique shop in the city this afternoon, and
received the katana as a repayment of the owner's debts.
We went to that shop earlier, and he
confirmed that he gave it to Wanibuchi-san around noon.
After he received the katana, he walked
across the bridge and came here, to the Inome Cave.
I don't know why he came here, but he was witnessed
carrying the katana on this bridge shortly before 1:00 PM.
But when the corpse was discovered,
the katana was nowhere to be found.
So we can guess that the culprit saw
Wanibuchi-san get the katana at the antique shop...
And followed him here.
Therefore, this murder was carried
out simply to steal the priceless treasure.
So, there's no need for a detective.
I see where you're coming from now!
Come on...
Is this a really such an open and shut case?
Why would the culprit have
waited until he got to this specific place?
Moreover, walking around with
a katana worth 10 million yen...
What are you snooping around for?
I wasn't doing anything!
I feel bad that we can't do
anything about Wanibuchi-san's death...
But isn't it good that Eiko-san
won't have to marry him anymore?
Ran...
I know, I shouldn't have put it that way.
But didn't you also say something like that yesterday?
Don't you always say "If you're forced into
marriage, it's like throwing your life away?"
W-Well, that's...
Oh!
Doesn't this murder remind you of
"The Extermination of the Eight-Headed Serpent"?
It's a legend about Susanoo's admirable act.
There once was a pitiable princess who had been
taken by the Eight-Headed Serpent against her will.
Then the admirable Susanoo appeared and
killed the Eight-Headed Serpent, saving the princess.
This case reminded me of this story
because he also obtained the serpent's sword.
Aren't they similar?
Susanoo's act may have been heroic...
But our case's culprit isn't.
He may have coincidentally saved
Eiko-san from being stuck in a doomed marriage...
But he's no more than a robber and a murderer.
I already know that much.
I was just saying this is almost like
the extermination of that serpent.
Right, Conan-kun?
But, just as I suspected...
This case wasn't a simple robbery-murder.
Inasa Beach
"Once a year, all the gods in Japan gather
together in Izumo to discuss Everyone's issues..."
"Here on Isana beach."
They weren't even listening.
Can't you pay attention when I'm saying something to you?
Something is going on.
Huh?
Don't tell me that this is...
I've just got confirmation from one
of the antique shop's employees...
There's no doubt that this is the same katana.
I thought so.
I don't understand.
Why did they take the time to steal the
katana, only to hide it in the sand later on?
They didn't hide it, they threw it
away because it was worthless for them.
They took it from the crime scene as camouflage.
They wanted to lead us to believe that their goal was theft.
That's the most likely scenario.
And that means that the culprit's true intention was...
To kill Wanibuchi-san.
I'm guessing that their motive was
that they held a grudge against him.
Hurry up and get me a list of those people!
Include his business rivals, of course...
But also include anyone who has
had any problems with Wanibuchi-san.
Yes, sir!
Something wrong?
Oh... Uh, no...
Shimane Prefecture: Izumo Police Station
The list was completed the next day...
And four people were called to the police station.
Two of those people were... Eiko-san and Fukuma-san.
So, we're ready to begin the questioning.
But before that, I'd like to introduce you to
someone who will be helping us in our investigation...
The detective, Mouri Kogoro-san.
I'm Mouri.
T-The famous detective?
No, it's just that I never imagined I'd get
to see such a famous detective in Izumo.
Fujie Takehiko (40)
Manager of a Marriage Ceremony Hall
First, Ishitobi Kazuya-san...
Y-Yes?
According to this information...
Ishitobi Kazuya (35)
Manager of the Izumo Soba Restaurant
Wanibuchi-san offered you a joint management deal...
To help revive your dying Izumo Soba restaurant.
What "joint management?"
Wanibuchi Enterprises will take
care of all the restaurant's capital.
But in return, I'll get the rights to use the Ishitobi name
and to mass-market your soba throughout Japan.
Quite a delicious proposition.
No way...
You're not in a position to decline the offer, are you?
That guy was using financial threats to take over the
restaurant that's been in my family for over 200 years!
I see.
Moving on, the next suspect is...
Fujie Takehiko-san, who manages the
Ryouunkaku Marriage Ceremony Hall.
I'm in the same situation as Ishitobi-san.
Wanibuchi Enterprises was planning
on opening a marriage ceremony hall.
But it would be hard to draw customers away from
an old, well-known establishment like Ryouunkaku.
That's why I want to make a deal with you.
I'll teach you our methods,
then we'll both manage this place my way.
What do you think?
Fujie-senpai?
That's what happened.
Why did he address you as "Senpai?"
Wanibuchi was my kouhai at the
Teito University of Business in Tokyo.
Ah, university?
Crocodile Snake
His name is "Wani", but he seems more like a "hebi".
He's a monster that's always meddling in other
people's business and appropriating whatever he wants.
Indeed, he's just like an evil serpent!
I see.
Iezumi Eiko-san, you also met
Wanibuchi-san for your first time at work, did you not?
Yes, my family and I own the old Hinode Inn...
And while the building was deteriorating a bit...
It wasn't in need of repairs yet.
At that time, a Tokyo-based firm
wanted to remodel it into a modern hotel...
So they came and talked to us about selling it to them.
And just when my parents started to lose hope
because they might need to part with their inn...
I can't believe that you would let a
historical site like Hinode Inn be destroyed.
Please let me help you with the reconstruction fees.
For all of Izumo!
It was surprising...
Because we heard he was
someone that acted only on his self interest.
So my parents accepted his offer and renovated the inn.
But...
You want to marry my daughter?
What are you saying all of a sudden?
It's not sudden.
If she becomes my wife, I'll be compensated
for all the money I lent you for this renovation.
After all, who do you think I am?
He had this planned from the very beginning.
If I declined his marriage proposal,
we would have to repay all the money he lent us.
No way.
My parents didn't want me to marry that man...
So they? told me they'd abandon their inn.
But I knew how precious this inn was to my parents,
since it had been passed down for generations, so...
Fukuma-san...
As you couldn't leave Ezumi-san alone in that situation...
You begged Wanibuchi-san
dozens of times to withdraw that deal.
Yes, I did. I also hated that guy.
Next, let's discuss the time of the murder.
Please tell me where you were and
what you were doing yesterday at 1:00 PM.
Let's start with...
I was at Matsue Castle!
Matsue Castle?
Matsue Castle
I went by myself, so I have no witnesses.
Note: The register states that Fujie Takehiko came to the castle at 1:05 PM.
Ah! But I signed on the castle's entrance register!
And you, Fukuma-san?
I had the day off yesterday...
So I went to the former Grand Shrine station.
I was there from a little before noon to 3:00 PM.
Former Grand Shrine Station
I often go there to unwind.
But since I went there alone, no one can vouch for me.
Then, Ishitobi-san...
I-I was at the Izumo Traditional Cultural Museum.
Izumo Traditional Cultural Museum
And... I was also alone.
Finally... Ezumi-san?
I went to Hinomisaki...
I also went alone.
Hinomisaki
I had heard that seagull season arrived earlier than usual...
But I didn't see any there.
Komura, go and confirm their testimonies.
Yes, sir!
Everyone went to famous tourist spots...
So wouldn't a lot of people have seen them?
If they really did what they said, then yes.
Exactly...
How'd it go?
I got confirmation for Fujie-san's story.
It's his handwriting.
And based on the times of those before and after him,
it's also true that he was at Matsue Castle at 1:05 PM.
1:05 PM.
He signed the register at the exact same time as the murder.
Travelling from Matsue Castle to the crime scene in Inome...
Would take between 40 minutes to an hour by car.
I see.
So I shouldn't be under suspicion anymore, right?
The problem lies with the three others.
It seems that none of them had a witness.
No one at all.
Not even one?
Not even one between the three of them.
As we couldn't confirm your alibis, we
can't remove you from the suspects list.
Therefore, I'm going to have you re-testify, but this time...
In a private, one-on-one discussion.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Eiko-san and Fukuma-san aren't the culprits right?
Yep.
But no matter how we look at it, no one had a witness.
That means someone is probably lying.
Yes, Yamane.
What?
I see, understood.
Go and catch him before he leaves!
Fukuma Ryousuke.
Y-Yes, sir!
We found a witness who states he saw someone burying
Something at Inasa Beach around 2:00 PM yesterday.
They described the man as a "tall, slender individual?"
We had forensics analyze your shoes, and found traces of
sand from Inasa Beach and soil from Inome Cave on them.
Do you want to confess... to killing Wanibuchi-san?
Absolutely not.
He's keeping silent?
Yes, but if we assume he's the culprit...
We can build some theories, even though there
weren't any witnesses at the former Grand Shrine station.
After he murdered Wanibuchi-san in Inome,
he must have gone to Inasa Beach to dispose of the katana.
Then, that settles it. It had to have been Fukuma Ryousuke.
No way!
While it's true that there's a witness
and that forensics found sand on his shoes...
That only proves he removed the katana
from the crime scene and buried it at the beach.
But...
It doesn't prove that he's the murderer...
I went to Hinomisaki...
That reaction... Fukuma-san knew!
He knew where Eiko-san really went!
So that means...
H-Hey, where are you going?
Interrogation Room 1
You brat!
Walking into the interrogation room without permission!
You can't do that, Conan-kun.
But since Fukuma-san won't talk,
I thought he was covering up for the real culprit...
Just as I thought.
Told you so!
He must have seen something at the Inome cave...
Where the real culprit attacked Wanibuchi-san!
But who could the real culprit be...?
There's only one person he would cover up for.
You witnessed Ezumi Eiko-san committing the murder.
That's why you took the katana to
make it look like a robbery-murder.
Isn't that right?
It was me!
I was the one who killed Wanibuchi!
Say whatever you want, but it's already too late.
Me? I didn't do it!
Then, where did you actually
go during the time of the murder?
You said you went to Hinomisaki,
but no one saw you there...
Neither the lighthouse nor the souvenir shop employees.
That's because...
This woman's doing the same thing as Fukuma-san...
She's covering up for someone.
I had the day of yesterday...
So I went to the former Grand Shrine station.
Could it be that...
Say...
You know that Fukuma-san is the culprit,
so you're covering up for him, aren't you?
I thought so.
Ran-neechan, come with me for a second.
Conan-kun, what is it?
What does that mean, Mouri-san?
They are both protecting their lover...
So, who is the real culprit?
You're saying that neither of them are the true culprit?
That's what I wanna check.
Where are you going?
To the former Grand Shrine station.
So, all of the suspects are innocent?
Exactly.
What's this?
There's an extra row that's not on yesterday's page.
I don't think that's right.
A mutual misunderstanding?
It's Mouri. I need to meet with you as soon as possible.
I'll let you know why when you get there.
Next Conan: Sword of the Eight-Headed Serpent, Part 2.
Next Conan's Hint!
A false testimony.
You tied your knot of love
thinking of Shinichi-niichan, didn't you?
Nope!
T-Then, who?
W-W-Who?!