It's almost Conan's tenth anniversary!
Overcoming one obstacle, and aiming for the next.
Amidst the feelings of love and kindness...
We continue to look further into this case...
To find the true culprit of the mythical village!
Seeing through to the one and only truth...
I look like a child, but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
We traveled the old, mythical village of Izumo...
Where we met Ezumi Eiko-san,
a young woman working at the Grand Shrine.
Ezumi Eiko (25)
Sunrise Shop - Eldest Daughterd
Inome Cave
The following day...
Eiko-san's fiancé was found dead...
And a katana worth 10 million yen was stolen.
Later, the police called four suspects to the police station...
And Eiko-san and her childhood friend were among them.
Please tell me where you were and
what you were doing yesterday at 1:00 PM.
Fukuma Ryousuke (25)
Museum Curator
I had the day off yesterday...
So I went to the former Grand Shrine station.
What about you, Ezumi-san?
I went to Hinomisaki.
Eiko-san and Fukuma-san aren't the culprits, right?
Yep.
But no how we look at it, no one had a witness.
That means someone is probably lying.
Sword of the Eight-Headed Serpent.
Part 2!
Former Grand Shrine Station
Are you sure you're not mistaking her for someone else?
How could I have mistaken her?
I've known her since the day she was born.
That cute little Eiko-chan from Hinode.
You saw her here yesterday afternoon?
It was 1:00 PM...
And she was sitting in that seat over there, as always.
That means Eiko-san was here
at the time of Wanibuchi-san's murder!
Because we found a witness...
Eiko-san has the perfect alibi.
Ezumi= Hinomisaki
But I wonder why she said she went to Hinomisaki?
Let's just inform Uncle and the others for now.
Shimane Prefecture: Izumo Police Station
It's exactly like Conan-kun and the other girl said...
I was actually at the former Grand Shrine station.
I go there whenever I have time.
Because that's the one place I can truly relax.
It's where my mother and father first met.
My mother often visited Izumo on a whim...
And happened to stay at my father's inn.
They were both charmed by the other...
So they tied their knot of love,
and eventually gave birth to me.
Although the station is closed down now...
When I go there, I feel like I can see
the beginning of their lives together.
I like that station.
So that's why we couldn't find a witness at
Hinomisaki no matter how hard we looked, isn't it?
Because you were never there.
You should've told us that you were at the
former Grand Shrine station in the first place.
Why did you lie about that?
That's because...
It was because Fukuma-san said that earlier, wasn't it?
I had the day off yesterday...
So I went to the former Grand Shrine station.
At the time, didn't Eiko-san
seem very surprised by his statement?
That's because Eiko-san didn't
see Fukuma-san while she was there.
I couldn't believe he killed Wanibuchi-san for my sake.
So that's why I hid the truth.
If I said that I was also at the former Grand
Shrine station, it would've contradicted his testimony.
But since I went there alone, no one can vouch for me.
There's no way we wouldn't have seen
each other if we were at the same place.
So, Fukuma-san lied first, giving
Eiko-san no choice but to lie to cover it up.
Hinomisaki was the first place I could think of.
Since I also like that place.
I see... So that's what happened.
But if Ezumi-san is innocent,
that casts doubt on Fukuma-san's behavior.
In that case, removing the katana from the
crime scene to make us believe this was a robbery...
Was not to cover up for Ezumi-san,
but cover his own tracks.
I don't think that's right.
I think Eiko-san and Fukuma-san
just had a mutual misunderstanding.
A mutual misunderstanding?
If we tell him we stopped suspecting Eiko-san,
Fukuma-san will probably tell us the whole story.
Bring Fukuma-san here immediately!
Fujie-shi = Matsue Castle
Fukuma-shi = Former
Grand Shrine Station
Ishitobi-shi = Izumo Traditional
Cultural Museum
Ezumi-san = Hinomisa
Eiko, it wasn't you?
No, because I was at the former
Grand Shrine station the entire time.
But then, why?
Why did I find this there?
What is that?
Where did you find it?
Where? So...
Can you give us more details?
Y-Yes sir.
Yesterday afternoon, I actually went to Inome Cave...
But it wasn't to kill Wanibuchi-san.
I spoke with Eiko two days ago...
You got a call from Wanibuchi?
He told me to be at Inome Cave at 1:30 PM tomorrow.
Why would he tell you to go to such a deserted place?
Whatever he's scheming can't be anything good.
I'll go in your place...
Talk to him...
And get him to give up on you, Eiko.
Ryo-chan...
Tomorrow afternoon, at 1:30 PM.
So yesterday, in order to have a discussion with him...
Wanibuchi?
Eiko?
It was there?
I noticed it right away, since I'm the one who gave it to Eiko.
L-Let me hold on to it.
Is this pendant the key?
So I thought she had went there,
even though I told her I would.
Thinking it was Eiko-san's doing, you decided to
hide the katana, masking it as a robbery-murder?
Y-Yes.
That certainly seems like a plausible explanation.
I'm sorry Ryo-chan, but I actually
lost this pendant a few days ago.
I couldn't tell you.
So that's what happened.
Like Conan-kun said, the two of you
misunderstood each other...
And each thought the other person was the culprit.
And then they lied to cover up for each other!
Funny, so funny!
It's not funny at all!
You two screwed up the entire investigation!
Fukuma-san, removing that katana
was the worst thing you could've done!
Yes, I'm sorry.
And if you hadn't picked up the pendant,
the true culprit's fingerprints might have remained on it.
I was under the wrong impression that Eiko did it.
That doesn't matter!
You can't cover up a crime for the sake of love!
Ryo-chan...
I understand...
So that means Wanibuchi-san's
murderer is Ishitobi Kazuya.
It's true that Ishitobi-san's
frightened response was strange...
Ishitobi Kazuya (35)
Manager of the Izumo Soba Restaurant
But Fujie-san's surprise when you
first introduced me is bothering me.
The true culprit was carrying this pendant, right?
That's the most likely scenario.
If it fell when he killed Wanibuchi-san...
It didn't fall!
It was placed near the corpse on purpose!
You said you lost it a few days ago, right?
Did you happen to meet with
Ishitobi-san or Fujie-san around that time?
Now that you mention it...
I'm begging you, Eiko-san!
Wanibuchi will understand my situation
if you're the one speaking to him.
Fujie Takehiko (40)
Manager of a Marriage Ceremony Hall
Marry him and talk him out of taking my company.
I beg of you!
What are you saying, Fujie-san?
You want my daughter to sacrifice herself
just to protect your marriage ceremony hall?!
I'm asking you to not be selfish!
I'm begging you, Eiko-san... Please!
Let me think about it for a while.
Eiko, you don't have even have to think about it!
Go away, Fujie-san.
That's horrible, asking you to
sacrifice yourself for his own personal gain.
Eiko...
Thinking back now, I noticed I lost my pendant that night.
Fujie-san did it?
But Fujie-san was at Matsue Castle and has an alibi...
The name register?
Let's go to Matsue Castle, Mouri-san.
That's true...
If the culprit hadn't tried to frame
Eiko-san for committing the murder...
Fukuma-san wouldn't have stolen the katana.
Matsue Castle
There's no doubt that this is Fujie-san's handwriting.
And judging from the times of the people before
and after him, I don't think he lied about when he came.
We didn't gain anything from that, did we?
Fortunately, we've already considered this possibility.
That means only one person could have done it.
Let's hurry and get back to the station!
Conan-kun?
I'll catch up with you soon, so you can go on ahead.
All right, but make it quick!
Something about this is bothering me.
These times are too good to be true.
What's this?
There's an extra row that's not on yesterday's page.
Hey, could I borrow your eraser for a second?
I have to write this perfectly.
That might have been possible with a pencil but...
This is...
No, could it be that...
Hey, could I also borrow your eraser for a second?
Hey, Ran... Hurry up!
Just a minute, Conan-kun is still in there!
That brat again?!
Wait a minute, Uncle!
We're leaving!
Yes, Yamane.
What?
U-Understood!
Ishitobi-san couldn't have committed the crime!
Yesterday afternoon...
There was a car accident just outside of Izumo...
Which occurred at 1:00 PM.
That was shortly before
Wanibuchi-san was murdered in Inome.
And?
According to a witness testimony, the
driver who committed the hit-and-run...
Is currently being held on DUI charges.
That driver was Ishitobi-san.
Huh?
I see.
The reason why he was frightened a couple
days ago wasn't because he killed Wanibuchi-san...
It was because he didn't want us to find
out he'd been driving under the influence.
But if that's true, who is our culprit?
It's neither Fukuma-san nor Ezumi-san...
Fujie-san has a valid alibi...
And the likelihood that Ishitobi-san could
have committed the crime is next to nothing...
So, all of the suspects are innocent?
Exactly.
Mouri-san!
Dad, are you okay?
We didn't progress in the investigation at all...
Say, Uncle...
This is the manager, Fujie.
It's Mouri. I need to meet with you as soon as possible.
I'll leave the time and place we meet up to you.
I'll let you know why when you get there.
Yes, Mouri...
It's Fujie. I have something I need to discuss with you.
You want to discuss something?
I'm waiting for you in front of Hinomisaki.
Oh, this is a wonderful lighthouse.
Hinomisaki
Yes. It's 43.65 meters, and is said to be the tallest in Japan.
It sure is a pretty lighthouse.
It was built in the 36th year of the Meiji era,
which corresponds to 1903 on the Gregorian calendar...
So it was built over 100 years ago.
100 years ago?
So, we were told to wait at Hinomisaki...
That's right.
The lighthouse is already closed for the night,
but I'm pretty sure there's a viewing platform in front of it.
Then, let's go.
Yes.
What could he want to discuss with me?
Sorry to keep you waiting, Fujie-san...
How can I help you?
Huh? You're the one who called me here
Please find me a good match...
He's here! The Sleeping Kogoro!
The Sleeping Kogoro?
This is just like the rumors said.
Fujie-san, I recall you describing
Wanibuchi-san as a serpent earlier...
Crocodile Snake
His name is "Wani", but he seems more like a "hebi".
He's a monster that's always meddling in other
people's business and appropriating whatever he wants.
Indeed, he's just like an evil serpent!
Note: According to legend, the serpent demanded that the people of
Izumo sacrifice one of their daughters to it every year for seven years.
While it may be true that Wanibuchi-san forced others to
give him what he wanted, like the Eight-Headed Serpent...
That's no reason to kill him, Fujie-san.
What are you talking about?
That again, Mouri-san?
He's right, Mouri-san.
Didn't you also confirm his alibi at Matsue Castle?
That was a well-planned trick.
A trick?
You started thinking about killing Wanibuchi-san
when you visited Eiko-san several days ago, didn't you?
You intimated Eiko-san...
In the hopes she would marry Wanibuchi-san and
prevent him from taking over your marriage ceremony hall.
But such a selfish wish had no chance to be granted.
So, in your desperation...
You found something that was forgotten at the time.
And that's when you got an idea.
Two days ago, you made a couple phone calls.
One was to Wanibuchi-san.
It was something along the lines of...
I'll show you the best way to win Mezumi Eiko-san over!
It would be best to talk in a place away from the crowds...
So, let's meet in Inome at 1:00 PM tomorrow.
The second call was to Eiko-san, imitating Wanibuchi-san.
I won't to meet you tomorrow.
Please come to Hinomi at 1:30 PM.
Wanibuchi-san wasn't the one who called?
He imitated his voice.
Now that you mention it, he said he caught a cold
which made his voice sound different than usual...
He arranged a half-hour time difference
between the two appointments...
Because he didn't want Eiko-san to see
Wanibuchi-san's murderer while she was there.
So, yesterday afternoon around 1:00 PM...
You carried out your plan.
You checked Wanibuchi-san's watch to get the exact time...
Which was 1:05 PM.
You placed the lost pendant beside the body...
Then, you went to Matsue Castle by car...
And perfected your alibi using the name registry.
It's impossible for him to have signed that, Mouri-san!
No matter how fast he drove, he couldn't
have arrived at Matsue Castle before 2:00 PM.
It wasn't impossible.
That's because you went to
Matsue Castle twice yesterday, didn't you?
Twice?
The first time was in the morning, to set up the trick...
Being the first to sign the registry for the day,
it was easy for you to add an extra row for the time...
And replace the ballpoint pen at the same time.
He replaced the ballpoint pen?
He exchanged it for an identical erasable ballpoint pen.
After killing Wanibuchi-san,
you went back to Matsue Castle...
Found someone who registered at 1:05 PM...
Erased their name, and wrote your own, making it
look like you were there during Wanibuchi-san murder.
That's how you built your alibi, knowing that it takes
an hour to get to Matsue Castle from the crime scene.
It's a false alibi.
If you test it, you can easily see...
That all of yesterday's names were
written with an erasable ballpoint pen.
If you think about it, it's normal to write
your name, address, and the date in a registry...
But you don't usually write the time.
In fact, no one wrote the time in until yesterday morning.
Since you were the first to register yesterday,
everyone who registered after you also wrote in the time.
If someone had already filled the time in, one would
naturally assume they're supposed to do so as well...
And wouldn't suspect anything.
You used that psychological trick, didn't you?
What do you have to say about that, Fujie-san?
Where's the proof that I was the
first to register yesterday morning?
The name "Yamada Ichiro" is indeed a credible false name.
The problem is with the address: "Narisei City, Tokyo".
Narisei City, Tokyo?
That's ridiculous!
How does that prove I'm the one who wrote that?!
Why is Narisei City a problem, you ask?
Fujie-san, you lived in Tokyo
when you were a student, right?
Wanibuchi was my kouhai at the
Teito University of Business in Tokyo.
That statement settles it.
You lived in a dormitory in Narisei
City during your four years as a student.
That's right, but it doesn't answer my question.
Isn't it possible that someone named
Yamada Ichiro living in Narisei City wrote that?
No, that's not possible.
Because Narisei City is no longer a part of Tokyo.
It merged with the neighboring Haido City...
And the Narisei name was dropped.
Just last year.
This is the first you've heard about this, isn't it?
I see.
So Narisei City no longer exists...
Mouri-san, the truth is that I knew I was
done for from the the first moment I saw you.
I'm Mouri.
T-The famous detective?
I thought it was only a matter of
time until the truth was revealed...
And I was right.
Beautiful!
I like watching the sunset here at Hinomisaki.
But this is probably the last time I'll be able to see it...
I wanted to meet here so it would
be engraved in my eyes for eternity.
I know I was being selfish.
But Ezumi-san, I didn't want
Wanibuchi to take over what's important to me...
I didn't want to become
another one of that monster's heads.
That was my motive.
I understand...
Fukuma-kun.
Yes?
Protect Eiko-san.
You never know what hideous
monster will rear its head next.
I will!
Wow, what a beautiful sunset!
Conan-kun, where were you this whole time?
Say, those two look like they're getting along well.
They sure do!
The knot of love must have
finally brought their love to fruition.
We aren't going back to Tokyo until this thing sticks!
I'll definitely get it this time.
I did it!
No way!
Huh?
Crap!
Dad...
Hey, hey...
Isn't it wrong to mess up other people's love lives?