It's almost Conan's tenth anniversary!
Overcoming one obstacle, and aiming for the next.
"Let's meet again in ten years."
A promise, and a blurred letter from the past.
This is the Professor's love story!
Seeing through to the one and only truth,
I look like a child, but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
Gingko-Colored First Love
(Part 1)
Gingko-Colored First Love,
Part 1!
Hey, Professor...
What does this letter look like?
It's in an envelope the size of a postcard.
I guess it can't be helped.
We'll have to look for it together.
What type of letter is it, Professor?
It's a invitation to my friend's son's wedding.
He even sent a stamp with it, since they wanted to know, by today, whether I was attending or not.
You should be more careful with important things like that.
That's right!
Stop complaining, will you?
The house got all disorganized because you were here playing games all last night.
I guess so...
You know... You've been looking pretty tired recently.
Is that bad?
But, it's no wonder, since you get up early with Ayumi-chan to see the rabbits at school.
H-How did you know!?
Were you spying on us?
It's because both of you have gingko leaves in your hair.
The rabbit cage is behind the school near the gingko trees.
Those are the only gingko trees around here.
On top of that, I heard some girls talking yesterday about how the rabbits weren't feeling well.
Amazing!
Then, why don't you find the letter already, Detective-san?
Well, every time the Professor finishes reading his mail...
His habit is to put it on the TV. So I'd check behind the TV.
But, you've probably already...
There are so many letters behind here!
Look! This much!
Are you serious!?
That should have been the first place you checked...
But, there sure is a lot here...
Let's see. A greeting card, a letter, and even a notice for you to renew your driver's license.
And these are all things that I've been looking for!
Oh! Cute handwriting...
A card from a child?
This is it!
We found it, Professor!
Professor...
What is it?
Did you find something cool?
It's the card that was sent by a child!
Well...
Could it be a love letter?
No, it's from a friend I had a long time ago...
It was 40 years ago...
Forty years ago?
So, that means... you were a sixth-grader at the time?
Yes.
It was on the first day back to school after summer break.
I was almost late, so I took a shortcut.
On the road was a younger girl, afraid to move.
She was a cute little girl, who was wearing her hat low to cover her large eyes.
She was afraid to walk forward because there was a mean dog in her way.
The dog was a large breed, and belonged to a neighbor named Noi-san.
So, the girl hid behind me and we walked past the dog.
Afterward, I asked why she was afraid of dogs.
She said she was bitten by her dog when she was little,
and had a fear of animals ever since.
I felt bad for her,
so I took her to my friend Ghouno-san's house to play with his hamster.
At first, she was very scared,
but she got used to it after a while.
In a couple months, she came to like animals again.
She could even walk past Noi-san's dog all by herself!
So, Professor, that must mean...
you walked to school with her every day, right?!
Yeah...
But, only during that fall...
"Only during that fall"?
It was a rainy day late in November.
As usual, I waited by Noi-san's house,
waiting for the girl so I could walk with her.
I waited, and waited, but she never came.
I thought she might be sick, so I went to visit her after school.
But, her neighbor told me her family had moved that morning.
She moved away?!
And she didn't even tell you?
She didn't even say goodbye?
W-Well...
She probably couldn't say it even if she wanted to.
'Goodbye' is a very hard,
sad word to say.
It can't be...
But, she left without saying anything at all...
That's just cruel.
No, she did thank me later.
That day, in my mailbox,
I got that postcard.
But, there's no stamp on this card.
That's probably because... She put it in the Professor's mailbox herself before she left.
What does it say?
"Thank you for these past three months!
I hate having to say 'bye bye', so let's say it later!
In 10 years from today, before the sun sets,
please wait for me at the place of our memories...
If we don't meet, I'll wait another 10 years.
Even when I become an old lady, I'll keep waiting for you.
Please come whenever you can.
To my most, most, most favorite Agasa-kun...
November 24th, Class 4-A, Kinoshita..."
...and then the words are illegible.
It probably got wet when she put it in the mailbox.
So, what happened next? Did you go meet her?
No, because I didn't know where the 'place of our memories' was.
Hey, hey...
But...
Today is November 24th, isn't it?
And it's been exactly 40 years to the day.
Maybe that lady...
...will be waiting at the place of memories today!
But, the Professor doesn't know where that place is.
S-Sorry...
Geez.
The Professor has always been bad at remembering things...
Could it be in front of the house with the big, scary dog?
That might be it!
Because that's the place where they met.
That's what I thought at first too, so ten years later,
I went there and waited the whole day, but she never came.
How about the house with the hamster?
That's where I waited after 20 years.
I even stayed at my friend's house the night before.
But, unfortunately, she didn't show up.
So, those must be the wrong places...
And you didn't get any letters from her after that?
Not long after that, my family moved to the country.
Then, why didn't you write her a letter?
I didn't even know her full name or address!
What? Not even her name?
Couldn't you find out quickly by asking your old teachers?
I was going to...
...but then I thought that we were going to meet in ten years anyway.
I know!
You went to Teitan Elementary, right?
Then, let's call and ask!
But, all of the schools are closed today...
And even if we did find her name and address,
and managed to contact her to meet again,
it would only break her heart.
Because she would find out that Professor almost completely forgot about her,
never found her special 'place of memories' in 40 years,
and made her wait for so long for nothing.
You didn't have to go that far...
Anyway, that's only if she's still patient enough to wait there today.
Then, as we thought, the best thing is for the Professor to find that place and meet her there.
However, it's been 40 years already.
I don't think I can remember...
But, there's a clue here.
A clue?
The hint is: "Animal"
See? There are numbers beneath the Professor's name.
Also, there's a hint for finding that place!
There really is!
But, what does "4163 33 6 0" mean?
And the hint is "animal."
Professor, what does this mean?
Well, uh...
If he knew, he would have met her already.
I'm ashamed...
But, maybe Conan-kun can...
Nope, I don't know.
I see...
Hey, didn't she say that she'd wait until sunset?
That means we only have four more hours.
Maybe we should ask "Sleeping Kogoro-san" to help figure this out, then.
We can't. Uncle Kogoro's off attending Okino Yoko and Nakayama Misa's concert right now.
Misa?
What?
Did you remember something?
Kinoshita-san's name!
I think her name was something like that...
Hey, if Sleeping Kogoro can't help,
then let's ask that annoying Sonoko-neechan to help us!
That's right! She has been bragging ever since she solved that one case!
Sonoko-neechan's not home, either.
She went with Ran-neechan early this morning to get a new brand name item released today.
Anyway, neither of them can solve the case if I can't...
It's probably the celebration of the purse designer Fusae Campbell's releases in Japan.
Fusae...
It might have also been something like that...
Wait, was it Misae?
Fusako? No, that can't be it...
Speaking of which, why is that leaf-covered designer purse so expensive?
What's so good about it?
Those aren't just any old leaves, they're gingko leaves!
They're the trademark of the 'Fusae' brand!
And that brand doesn't only have expensive items...
there are also a number of cheaper things.
Can I have that for a minute, Conan-kun?
What is it, Ayumi-chan?
Maybe this clue is hinting at the number of animals in our school!
See, there are 6 rabbits,
and all the fowl, chicken, and pigeons added together is 33.
And the 0?
That might be,the turtle that died over summer break.
Not a chance!
When I was in school, the turtle was still alive.
And besides the turtle, the only other animals we had were chickens.
Also, what about the 4163?
I guess you're right...
But, that turtle sure lived a long time, for 40 years...
No, it's actually the third turtle we've had.
Every time one dies, the zoo sends us a new one.
You're right about that.
A kind man, who had been an alumni of Teitan Elementary, later became the owner of Touto Zoo.
I believe his name was Kobata Yoichirou-san...
As a toast to the children's health
he gave the school a turtle.
Since turtles live such a long time.
Professor, what did you just say?
Turtles live a long time...?
Not that!
The name of the owner of Touto Zoo!
It was Kobata...
Yoichirou-san?
Yoichirou-san!
That's it!
Hey, hey...
Original Broadcast Date:
November 21st, 2005
Based on manga:
Vol 40 Files 7-9
Alright! Look carefully!
Yeah, she has to be here!
The Professor's first love!
We'll definitely find her!
Yeah!
W-Wait...
I never said she was my first love...
But, it's obvious.
But, even if 4163 stands for Yoichirou-san,
what do the 33, 6, and 0 have to do with it?
Pandas are so cute!
Yeah!
I want one!
Hey, you guys...
Hey, what's that number?
Look, the one next to the animal's name.
I'm pretty sure it's to classify the animals.
The numbers are pretty random though...
That's the order in which the owner brought the animals in.
That means this panda is the 58th animal to enter this zoo.
Then, what animal is number 33?
I think it was the donkey.
Donkey?
Yes!
Yoichirou-san's...
...thirty-third animal...
Note: In Japanese, "Donkey" sounds like "six".
...is the donkey!
That's it!
Hey!
Aren't you forgetting about 0?
Hurry up, hurry up!
Okay!
Looks like they're really into it.
Number 33, number 33, number 33...
Donkey, donkey, donkey...
Woman, woman, woman...
Number 33!
Donkey!
Woman!
We found her!
Hey, you guys...
She's there, we found her!
Seriously?
She's even wearing a hat that covers her eyes, so it's her no doubt!
Then, let's go get her!
Hey!
Excuse me...
Are you...?
Oh? Agasa-kun?
Yeah, it's been 40 years, hasn't it?
You've lost so much hair...
So, that's her?
This old lady is that big-eyed, pretty girl...
from 40 years ago...
The first love of the Professor!?
Well, this is a good example of memories being better than reality.
But, don't you think she's too old?
When Professor was in sixth grade, she was in fourth.
So, she should be either 49 or 50.
Maybe she just aged quicker than usual.
Maybe so.
Well then, it was nice to see you again!
Take care of yourself!
Hey... is that all?
Isn't she your first love?
No, that was Noi-san.
Remember? She was the owner of the big, really mean dog.
That dog's grandchild died last month.
She feels lonely now, so she decided to come to the zoo.
What?
So, it wasn't her?
No wonder she looked so old.
But, there's something weird here...
The 4163 refers to the owner of this zoo, Kobata Yoichirou-san.
33 is the thirty-third animal, which is the donkey, or "6".
So, I wonder why she isn't here?
I told you before, we didn't solve the 'O' part yet.
Well? Are there any more clues you can give us?
Well... she had big eyes, her last name was Kinoshita.
She liked to take care of the roosters.
She had freckles, and she always liked to wear her hat low.
Always?
Yeah...
Except when she took it off during school hours, of course.
What reason would she have to wear that hat?
Maybe she's bald.
She's probably just shy.
We'll just have to go back and find the right solution to the code to find this place.
If 4163 is the zoo,
then what is the 33, 6, and 0?
Mimimure... mimiroku...
Do you think it might mean 'owl'?
That's not it... 'Owl' sounds like '3329'.
Sasarokuwa...
Sasarokure...
(Flying Squirrel)
Sasamu...?
The flying squirrel!
Dummies. You still haven't figured out the 0 part yet.
No, that's not true.
Didn't the postcard say to meet her "before the sun sets"?
Flying squirrels are nocturnal animals.
So, how many of them will you see before sunset?
You'd see zero, wouldn't you?
But, wouldn't having nocturnal animals out in the zoo during the day be bad for them?
Idiot!
This zoo has a special section for nocturnal animals, so it's dark for them during the day.
Yeah!
Nocturnal Museum
Wow! It's true!
There's so many nocturnal animals!
But, there's a lot of snakes and bats, so it's kind of creepy.
That's true...
Let's see... Flying squirrel, flying squirrel...
There!
The flying squirrel's over there!
Professor, there's a lady there!
And she looks like she's waiting for someone.
Although she's not wearing a hat, it's probably her.
Look...
You haven't seen her in 40 years.
Just get a hold of yourself and go meet her!
Then, could it be...?
Could it be...?
Blonde?
My memories with her shall remain untouched and beautiful, deep inside my heart.
So, that's it! I see now.
I've got it, Professor!
I know the place where she's waiting!
Gingko-Colored First Love
(Part 2)
Next Conan: Gingko-Colored First Love (Part 2).
Blonde
Next Conan's Hint!
Blonde.
Who was your first love, Haibara?
The Professor.
Just kidding.