It's almost Conan's tenth anniversary!
Overcoming one obstacle, and aiming for the next.
Time is running out.
Will Agasa be able to find his ginkgo-colored first love?
Seeing through to the one and only truth,
I look like a child, but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
While searching around the Professor's room, we found a 40-year-old letter.
The letter, which was written by his first love,
said she'd wait to meet him again at "the place of our memories" once every ten years.
It also had a code which hinted to where that place is.
Coincidentally, it was exactly 40 years from the date on the letter.
Using our deductive reasoning, we ended up at the zoo.
Alright, look carefully.
Yeah, she has to be here!
The Professor's first love!
Hey, you guys...
Hey, what's that number?
Look, the one next to the animal's name.
The flying squirrel!
Professor, there's a lady there!
And she looks like she's waiting for someone.
Gingko-Colored First Love
(Part 2)
Gingko-Colored First Love,
Part 2!
Professor, there's a lady there!
And she looks like she's waiting for someone.
Although she's not wearing a hat, it's probably her.
Look...
You haven't seen her in 40 years.
Just get a hold of yourself and go meet her!
Um...
Excuse me, are you...?
Huh?
Hiroshi-chan, is that you?
A man!?
Long time no see!
How are you?
Um...
Who are you?
Aww... Have you forgotten?
You used to come to my house to play with my hamster!
You're my old friend, Chouno Haruo?!
What a relief!
I thought you had forgotten me.
Hey, do you think I've changed much?
Well, you were only a first-grader at the time, and always had snot dripping down your face...
Oh, stop it!
Wrong again...
Yeah...
And why are you here?
Oh, you silly!
Isn't it obvious? I have a date with my boyfriend!
He likes rodents just as much as I do.
So, that's why I'm waiting here!
This isn't the lady...
But, if she's here at the zoo,
I'm sure we'll see her somewhere!
Wait a second...
We don't have much time left.
There's only an hour until sundown!
Then, maybe we need to call the "Sleeping Kogoro" or annoying Sonoko to help us after all?
Can you call them for us?
Like I said, Uncle can't come because he's at a live show.
But, maybe Sonoko-neechan, who's with Ran-neechan, can stop by and help...
Then, please hurry and call her!
Or the Professor will have to wait another ten years!
I'll call, but I know she can't actually do anything...
Hello?
Oh? Conan-kun?
Yeah, we're still waiting in line for Fusae's limited-edition, brand-name purses.
Is Sonoko-neechan there?
Sonoko left a little while ago to buy us both a hamburger.
Then, never mind.
Talk to you later!
She's not there...
N-No way...
Ran!
I'm back!
What?
Were you on the phone?
It was your husband, wasn't it?
That's not it! That's not it at all!
Conan-kun just called and asked for you.
It's true.
He called just now, and asked if you were here.
What? What did he say?
Since you weren't here, he said to just forget about it.
Do you want to call him back?
Forget that little brat!
Nothing good happens when you're with him.
But, isn't it weird for you to want to buy a brand-name item?
Yeah, a little.
But, I made a promise with someone.
A long time ago.
I'm sure that person already forgot, though.
It doesn't look like she's here, sir.
I see.
I'm sorry for troubling you.
That was our last chance.
Did you think of anything else?
The!zoo is the "place of memories", right?
I don't think so. To be honest, this is my first time here.
What?
You didn't come here with the girl in the letter?
She wanted to go, but we never did.
So, the zoo was wrong from the beginning.
Why didn't you say so?
Sorry.
You guys looked like you were trying really hard.
But, this is enough.
I'm already happy.
My memories with her shall remain untouched and beautiful, deep inside my heart.
Anyways, I really don't want her to see me bald.
Professor...
So, let's go home...
Here you go, hold on to it more tightly from now on.
What happened just now made me remember something about her hair.
Her hair?
Although she had black eyes, her hair color was special.
It was a sort of light brown-ish color...
Blonde?
One of her parents was a foreigner, right?
So, that's why she wore that hat.
She didn't want to be made fun of because the color of her hair was different.
I understand because when I was in America,
All because my face looked too Asian.
Yes, my mother is British.
Didn't I tell you?
Ayumi-chan...
Can you hand me that letter for a minute?
Did you figure something out, Conan-kun?
Conan-kun?
Then, the clue actually means...
The meaning of the numbers...
Professor, did that girl have any pets?
Well, she had a dog when she was really young.
But, it bit her, so she never had another pet after that.
Wait, Conan-kun!
Then, could it be...?
Could it be...?
So, that's it! I see now.
And that's what the numbers meant.
I've got it, Professor!
I know the place where she's waiting!
We all know this place.
It has to be there!
Original Broadcast Date:
November 28th, 2005
Based on manga
Vol 40 Files 7-9
You've figured it out?
You know where the Professor's first love is waiting?
It was actually pretty easy to solve.
It's somewhere we all go to.
Even us?
Where would that be?
Genta goes there around five times a week.
Five times a week?
I eat at a cake shop everyday on the way home...
Then, there's the steakhouse I go to once a month...
Hey.
Stop making us guess and just tell us already!
Since that lady is only going to wait until sundown.
Don't worry!
It won't even take 20 minutes if we go by car.
The first thing is the clue at the bottom of the card.
4163, 33, 6, and 0 all stand for animals.
What else haven't we tried?!
Both the donkey and flying squirrel were wrong.
The numbers don't refer to their names...
..but their calls.
Their call?
It's the number of letters in their call.
"The number of letters in their call?"
So, what do you think the '6' means?
A cat's 'meow' has four letters...
'Katydid' has seven...
That's an insect, not an animal call!
The crow's 'caw' has three...
And the horse's 'neigh' only has five...
'Squeak.'
It's the sound of a mouse.
A mouse?
But, don't mouses go 'ki-ki'?
Look, there at the sign for the bat.
In English, bats go 'squeak.'
And bats and mice sound the same.
Since she's also half-Japanese,
one of her parents probably knows English.
It's exactly six letters,
so the probability of this being right is high.
I get it.
True.
But even if 'squeak' has 6 letters, how do you know it's a mouse?
Do you remember the animals you had in your memory?
I know!
It's the hamster!
Then, the 'place of memories' is Chouno's house, where the Professor and the girl played with the hamster!
But, Conan said I go there everyday,
and I've never been to that guy's house.
Also, didn't I say that I already waited there 20 years ago, and she didn't show up?
Now, hold on a second. We've only solved the '6' part.
But, '4163' and '33' are animals as well.
But, there aren't any animals with a call that long.
Then, think of each digit as a separate number.
4163 and 33...
Sb, a dog goes 'wan wan', and that sounds like '11'...
What about cicadas?
Their 'min min' sounds like '33'.
Could it be... it's referring to chickens and dogs?
In English, a rooster's call is 'cock-a-doodle-doo'!
And a dog's call is 'bow wow'
Caka-doo-doo-duh?
Don't they say 'coo coo coo'?
That's how Americans interpret the animal's sound.
So, the rooster refers to the elementary school,
and the dog to Noi-san's house.
She always liked to take care of the schools chickens,
and they first met at Noi-san's house!
But, what about the '0'?
Could it be an animal with no call?
No, that's not it... It's a place with no animals!
I've got it! How about her house?
Her parents didn't allow pets there after she got bitten.
So, '0' is referring to Kinoshita-san's home?
But, where exactly is she waiting?
She can't be at all four places at once.
Then, just say the places in the order they are in on the card.
Note: shogakkou = Elementary School
Let's see. The first one was shogakkou...
Noi...
Chouno...
Kinoshita...
(Elementary School)
Shogakkou...
Noi...
Ghouno...
Kinoshita...
Shoga noi chouno kinoshita
Under the elementary school's gingko trees!
Most likely, she's waiting there right now.
If her feelings from 40 years ago haven't changed, that is.
Hey...
Hey, wait a second, Conan...
There's no one here.
That's weird.
She should definitely be here.
Well, it's fine even if she's not here.
It has been 40 years, after all.
Professor...
Huh? It's still there.
Look! There's a white car over there.
It's been parked there ever since we went to look at the rabbits this morning.
She must have been waiting in it since this morning!
Let's hurry and go see!
Hey...
There's nobody in it.
Maybe she went out to eat or something.
The fast food and cup of coffee is still warm.
She must have just finished eating.
And she sure ate a lot...
There's enough food here to feed three people.
If she's really fat, don't be upset—
She's beautiful...
Could it be? Is it really her this time?!
Let's hope so.
Hey, Professor, don't just stand there!
She's been waiting for 40 years!
But, it might not be the right lady.
Just get over there already!
Um...
Fusae?
Billy, would you mind stepping aside for a moment?
Okay, you don't have to hurry.
Excuse me.
Um...
Your grandchildren are so cute.
Oh... Well...
Um... are you...?
I passed by one morning and fell in love with this grove of gingko trees.
The colors are so vibrant.
So, I decided to come back here.
Do you not like gingko?
Ah...
It really is a magnificent tree...
Huh?
Wait...
That lady is...
Hey, little girl...
Are you, waiting for someone too?
I forgot to bring an umbrella, so I'm hiding here for now.
Oh, is that all?
That doesn't matter.
I feel like getting wet today.
But...
Then, how about this?
When you grow up, can you buy a purse that I designed?
Promise?
If this lady is the same person...
There's no doubt that she's the Professor's first love.
Then, bye.
My husband is starting to become impatient.
Sorry for keeping you.
Professor, what happened?
It was her, right? Your first love?
Are you alright, Miss Fusae?
You finally met the man you've waited 40 years for...
But, I didn't tell him who I am.
Because it looks like he already has a happy family.
If he knew I waited for him for 40 years,
he'd be heartbroken.
How do you understand him so well?
You haven't met in 40 years.
Well, when my hat was blown away here...
My hair is weird!
Really?
See,
it's as beautiful as a gingko leaf!
I think he probably forgot already.
I'm sorry, Billy, for asking you to come with me every ten years.
You're only my step-dad's friend.
It's fine.
If I refuse, my wife would be angry.
She's a big fan of the Fusae brand.
But, this will end here.
Please drive.
Are you absolutely sure?
Okay, Boss.
Even now, I love gingko leaves!
Um, Billy?
What is it?
C-Can we come back in another ten years?
No...
I think that the next time you two meet...
will be much sooner than that...
That was a difficult code.
It can't be helped.
The person makes up the code however he or she wants.
Besides, she was in elementary school when she thought of it.
It's a cute, childish code.
You're a child, too.
But, the Professor's first love was so pretty!
Yes, she was.
A gingko leaf...
Professor?
You're grinning too much.
"Hey, Kinoshita!"
"Even now, I love gingko leaves!"
Hey, stop making fun of adults!
"Hey, Kinoshita! Even now, I love gingko leaves!"