It's almost Conan's tenth anniversary!
Overcoming one obstacle, and aiming for the next.
The boy who witnessed the case...
What is he hiding, and why is he acting so strange?
The hint and reasoning are in the cabbage worms and olive trees.
Seeing through to the one and only truth...
I look like a child, but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
Shimura
Hey, you!
The Detective Boys and the Four Cabbage Worm Brothers
The Detective Boys and the Four Cabbage Worm Brothers!
A new friend?
Yep!
We'll have to take a slight detour in order to introduce you.
Follow me!
When she says "new friend"...
It couldn't be another boy, could it?
Hey, hey...
What's this place?
So, allow me to introduce...
Taro-kun.
Taro-kun?
Look carefully. On the other side of the leaf.
The other side of the leaf?
Eh, what is it?
It's a cabbage worm...
And a big one at that!
Next up is...
Jiro-kun!
And last but not least, the smallest one...
Saburo-kun!
They're cute, right?
R-Rather than cute...
I'd call them gross.
Gross?!
Uh, no...
It's true. They are cute.
Look at how they nibble the olive leaves with their cute little mouths.
Indeed, now that I look carefully, they have a small horn on their bottoms.
They're cute, aren't they?
Hey, what type of butterfly do you think they'll turn into?
Don't they turn into swallowtail butterflies?
I can't wait to see!
These cabbage worms...
I hate to break it to you, but they won't turn into butterflies.
What?
If I'm not mistaken, in my "Illustrated Encyclopedia of Bugs"...
Hey, hey...
Do you always carry that with you wherever you go?
Here it is.
As I was expecting, it'll become a Speckled White Sparrow moth.
A Speckled White Sparrow moth?
V/hat's that? They're not butterflies?
Look, moth or butterfly, they're still cute cabbage worms, right?
Exactly, they're really cute!
Right?
I found Taro-kun three days ago as I was walking by.
Two days ago, I found Jiro-kun...
Finally, I found Saburo-kun yesterday.
Note: It was once popular to name Japanese boys according to birth order:
Taro (first), Jiro (second), Saburo (third), Shiro (fourth).
However, these names are now far, far out of style...
Then, does that mean you found Shiro-kun today?
Hey...
All joking aside, I really found another one.
One more worm, that is.
They might be brothers!
The Four Cabbage Worm Brothers!
Strange...
Yesterday, I looked for other ones right after I found Saburo-kun...
And they're too big to have just been hatched...
What if a new one arrives here everyday?
This is some sort of mystery.
Maybe it was just hidden behind a leaf and you didn't see it?
What are you kids doing?
Matsuura Senkichi (52)
Manager of Matsuura Heights
Is something wrong with this tree?
Oh! Good morning!
We were looking at the cabbage worms.
Cabbage worms?
See? They're right there.
Oh? Let me see...
Is something wrong?
No, just a stiff shoulder...
Wow! That's a big one!
There's one here and another over there...
There's also one right here!
It's true. I'm going to have to get rid of them.
Wait!
Don't kill the cabbage worms!
Please, they're my friends.
I ask the same of you.
But, if the leaves on my precious olive tree are eaten...
Look, even if they do eat some leaves, it's not like every one of them will be gone.
Besides, even if they're eaten, they'll regrow eventually.
But if you kill the cabbage worms, they'll never be able to come back!
Okay, okay...
I'll leave them alone.
Yay!
Besides, were they always so many of them?
I didn't see any when I last watered the tree.
When did you last do that?
Thursday evening, so...
Four days ago,I suppose.
Four days ago?
That was the day before Ayumi-chan found the first cabbage worm...
I love olive trees.
The coffee shop near Beika station has an olive tree too.
Ah! Welcome back, Yoshikawa-kun.
Yoshikawa Minoru (23) Matsuura Heights Resident
Thank you.
That person...
You know him?
He works at the convenience store near school.
Convenience store?
What's up, Matsuura-san?
There are a bunch of bugs on these olive leaves.
Bugs?
Every now and then, I'll stop at that convenience store on my way home from school...
To browse through fashion magazines. Do you have a problem with that?
Not at all, but...
Is it normal for a first grader to be reading fashion magazines?
Oh, yeah...
It looks like some sort of incident happened over there.
Over there?
You mean by Shimura-san's house?
It's Detective Takagi!
You guys!
You can't just walk in here!
Yeah.
An old man who lived by himself was murdered.
Hey, did that person discover the body?
Right.
He's the old man's neighbor, Shouginakawa.
It seems the old man was saving millions in his bureau, which is nowhere to be found.
Hey, Takagi-kun
What are you talking about?
N-Nothing.
Do you kids have information regarding the case?
Well, not really...
Then hurry and get your butts off to school!
You're going to be late!
Yes, ma'am!
I wonder how the incident this morning turned out...
Was the culprit caught?
Let's check it out on our way back home.
Hey!
It seems we won't have to.
What? You got a witness?
Yeah, the taxi driver...
Ah, no. Can't talk about the case...
It's fine, you can talk about it.
Really?
Well, then...
The taxi driver drove by the crime scene around 10:00 PM.
So, you saw a boy next to the man?
Yeah...
Did you see the man's face?
No, he was too far away by that time.
Yeah. I think so, anyway.
Any ideas on how old he was?
Anyway, you should focus more on the young boy.
The victim's approximate time of death is 10:00 PM.
We don't have any evidence to suggest that this person is the culprit...
But it wouldn't hurt to look into it ourselves.
Hey, if this man really is the culprit...
Isn't it possible that the boy left his house in a hurry...
Causing him to collide with the culprit in view of the taxi?
Yes, that's what I was thinking.
If that's true, there's a good possibility that the boy saw the culprit's face.
Y-Yes. I was thinking the same thing!
But the taxi driver didn't see the kid's face.
He only recalled that he was wearing pajamas and a white baseball cap.
Pajamas?
So, doesn't that mean he lives nearby?
Yes. That's why we wanted to ask you guys...
Do you know anyone who lives in that area...
Who usually wears a white baseball cap?
Someone who lives in that area...
Who wears a white baseball cap?
It's Keiichi-kun!
Keiichi-kun?
Mitsui Keiichi-kun, from the class next door!
We went to kindergarten together...
His mother died from an illness this past summer.
Before she died, she gave Keiichi-kun that white cap.
That's why he's always wearing it.
Is that so?
Conference Room
Thanks again, and I apologize for the trouble.
It's all right.
You can go back now.
Well, I'll be going as well.
Th-Thank you.
How did it go?
Did Keiichi see the culprit's face?
The thing is...
It was no good, was it?
That's right. He denied everything.
He denied everything?
Keiichi-kun said that he didn't go outside that night...
The previous night, or the one before that.
Original Broadcast Date:
December 5th, 2005
Based on manga:
None (Anime Original)
Scene of the Crime
The scene of the crime is right here.
Keiichi-kun's house is over here.
Keiichi-kun's House
Matsuura Heights
The taxi came down this way, while the boy traveled in this direction...
Although there's a high possibility that Keiichi-kun is the boy in question...
The problem is that he denies everything when we confront him directly.
Is he afraid because it pertains to this case?
But, besides that...
Do you have any other information about the culprit?
Yeah, according to the taxi driver...
The culprit was grasping his left arm with his right hand.
His left arm?
That old man did that too!
He said he was suffering from pain in his left arm.
"That old man"?
The old man with the Four Cabbage Worm Brothers!
Four Cabbage Worm Brothers?
His name is Matsuura-san.
He lives here.
It's on the same block...
That old man was suffering from pain in his left arm?
He told us that it was just a stiff shoulder, though.
A stiff shoulder?
Should I go talk to him now?
I'm counting on you.
I'll search for the child.
I wonder if that old man is the culprit...
He didn't look like a bad person to me.
But he wanted to kill the cabbage worms!
What are you going to do now?
I was planning to go to Keiichi-kun's house and talk to him myself.
But before that...
The person from this morning!
How did this guy know about the case?
Traveling from this store to the apartment complex...
You wouldn't normally pass the house where the case occurred.
I see, that makes sense.
Should we ask him about it directly?
Well...
When I was almost at the apartment complex...
I saw the neighbors running toward the house.
I had a bad feeling about it, so I went to see what had happened.
So why did you go back home immediately after that?
I wanted to get to bed quickly.
I can't survive with just this part-time job, so I have a second job in the afternoon.
That guy isn't the culprit!
His left arm didn't look like it was in any pain.
That's right.
Let's hurry and go to Keiichi-kun's house now.
I guess so. Let's go.
Everyone, go on ahead of me.
I'm going to look though some magazines for a while.
Keiichi-kun!
Oh, Ayumi-chan.
What beautiful roses!
They're seasonal roses, right?
There's an olive tree here, too.
Compared to Matsuura-san's olive tree, this one is pretty small.
And there aren't any cabbage worms on it.
Are you the one who always take care of these plants?
Because they were Mother's favorite...
I take care of them after they bloom and even after they wither.
I see.
When does your father usually get back home?
Around 11:00 PM.
Because he's so busy with work.
So you're alone until 11:00 PM?
How do you make dinner, then?
My father makes it in the morning, then I heat it up and eat it when I'm hungry.
You're living a really hard life...
It's okay, really.
I'm used to it by now.
Anyway, about last night...
Sorry, I have something to do.
Keiichi-kun, wait!
Keiichi-kun undoubtedly came into contact with the suspect.
What is he hiding?
And why did he sneak out last night around 10:00 PM?
Branches that were cut off with scissors?
Could it be that...
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
Hey, what is it?
Conan-kun?
Just as I thought.
Eh? What is it?
Listen. The cabbage worms on this olive tree...
Used to be on Keiichi-kun's olive tree.
Keiichi-kun probably, noticed these cabbage worms four days ago.
He must have became concerned when he happened upon them.
The leaves of the olive tree that his mother had loved so much...
Were being eaten away by the cabbage worms.
But, the kind-hearted Keiichi-kun...
Was not able to kill them.
That was when Keiichi-kun remembered that there was another olive tree on the other side of the block.
He knew it had plenty of leaves, and that it could withstand having some of them eaten.
So Keiichi-kun came up with a plan to relocate one cabbage worm a day.
He waited until 10:00 PM when no one was around...
To take a cabbage worm from his own house, and carried it over to the bigger olive tree.
He took the branch that the cabbage worm was on, snipped it off with a pair of scissors, and then...
Because it would seem strange if someone noticed him doing this...
He went south, then west.
He purposely took a detour and passed the house where the case occurred...
So no one would notice him coming or going.
But one of the cabbage worms had been on a branch that was too high for Keiichi-kun to cut off.
That's why Keiichi-kun's olive tree is littered with other cut-off branches...
And why there are some branches in this tree that were cut with scissors in the same way.
And, on the fourth night...
After having finally moved the last cabbage worm...
The case occurred.
Keiichi-kun thought that he'd get into trouble if someone found out what he was doing.
That's why he denied it when he was questioned by the police.
He said he didn't go outside that night, the previous night, or the night before that...
So his switch would remain undiscovered.
You're amazing, Conan-kun!
You sounded just like Holmes.
You even looked like a real detective!
That's because I am a detective.
But I feel sorry for Keiichi-kun.
He must be really scared and worried right now.
That's true.
The next time we see him, let's...
Edogawa-kun?
Yoshikawa is no longer here.
What was that?
According to the other employees, he clocked out shortly before noon.
You see...
He was cleaning the sliding glass doors when we were there, right?
Maybe, in reality, he was waiting for a boy wearing a white cap to pass by.
So you're saying he's trying to ambush Keiichi-kun?
But that man's left arm...
The culprit didn't hurt his left arm when he ran into Keiichi-kun.
He couldn't have hurt his arm, because he would have been hit much lower.
So, why did he clutch his left arm?
Most likely, that was because...
The culprit stole the millions that his victim had saved, and hid the cash in a pocket on their left sleeve.
When he ran into Keiichi-kun as he left the house...
He had to prevent the cash from falling out, so he instinctively grabbed it with his right hand.
If Yoshikawa really is the culprit...
Keiichi-kun is in grave danger!
Keiichi-kun, Keiichi-kun!
It looks like he's not home.
How should I know?
Huh? Those roses...
There were a lot more earlier.
They were cut with scissors?
Why the roses?
Because they were Mother's favorite...
I got it!
Mother, I saw that man's face...
What should I do?
As I thought, you remember my face.
You should thank me...
Because I'm gonna let you meet your mother again real soon.
Keiichi-kun!
Keiichi!
Damn you!
Eat this!
Keiichi!
Keiichi-kun!
I'm okay.
Y-Your cap?!
It only pierced through the cap?
I'm so glad!
It seems you were saved by your mother up in Heaven.
The cabbage worms aren't here anymore?
Hey, old man, don't tell me you...
N-No, I didn't...
I didn't do anything.
They probably had to migrate somewhere so they can transform into pupa.
Pupa?
Oh, so that's it!
But what's a pupa?
Next spring...
After they become full-grown adults, do you think they'll come back and let us see them again?
Yeah.
And by that time...
I hope that my adult form...
Will also return.