Conan is approaching its tenth anniversary!
And once we make it through the first decade,
let's aim for another one!
A costume party takes an unexpected
twist and becomes a case!
This is the sad tale behind a clown!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid
but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
What do you think?
Pretty cool, right?
I assume you're familiar with the Animeland theme park.
They asked me to be the director for a day.
There wasn't any point in doing it without a twist,
so I figured I'd give it a personal touch.
And that surprise was a big hit.
So I'll be the honorary director for a day next year again,
and every other year after.
I'll come and rent a costume off you, so make sure you stay in business!
I don't remember them saying anything like that...
Didn't he see how shocked everyone was at how weird he was being?
I guess this will do. I'll give it to you as a present, signed and all.
Oh, there's no need...
Wait, were you dancing?
Oh, there was
an earthquake at about 3pm.
It was pretty strong, too.
You're going to be directors for a day, too?
No, we're going to a party,
Minoru Kijima (30)
Makeup Artist
to celebrate these two getting married.
Ah, a costume party?
Yeah, it's a bit embarrassing,
Jiro Ishikawa (28)
Photographer
but someone said a normal party would be boring.
Yoko Nakamura (25)
Fashion Model
And we couldn't really argue with her,
since she's pretty influential.
A smile in your face,
and tears in your heart.
The makeup hides the tears,
just like with clowns.
Oops, I forgot my hat.
What kind of costume
should I wear next time?
This one? No, maybe this...
It's Umeda-san.
The one in charge of the party.
The earthquake shook me up,
but the preparations for the party are still underway.
No wonder, the editor-in-chief hates earthquakes.
She says this is the costume she's wearing.
Oh, a clown?
Yeah. This is Umeda, our editor-in-chief.
Surprise! Don't I look great?
I got an e-mail from Umeda-san.
She says she'll leave the door unlocked,
and we should come in as soon as we arrive.
Roger.
It's 4:30pm, so we'll get there
at 5pm sharp.
A party, huh?
Right, kid.
We'll go play pachinko and then get something tasty to eat, okay?
Sure!
Could you look after this
for us, too?
Very well.
Well then, goodbye.
Get something tasty to eat, my foot.
You splurged everything you had playing pachinko!
Some people are heartless.
There's nothing wrong with picking up the balls somebody else dropped.
The world's turning more
and more miserable.
Who's more miserable, the world or you?
Yeah, an e-mail with a photo of a woman dressed up as a clown.
It was on that girl's
mobile phone at 4:30pm.
The cause of death is extreme pressure on the neck.
In other words, strangulation.
I'm certain of it, this is the woman we saw in that e-mail.
Mouri-kun saw an e-mail from the victim at 4:30pm.
The corpse was found at 5pm.
Taking all the information into account,
we can say she was killed between 4:30pm and 5pm.
Hey, what information?
Conan! Stop bothering
people with questions!
I'm sorry, please don't mind him.
Don't worry, it's fine.
When a person dies,
their muscles stiffen up.
Rigor mortis, right?
I read about it in a book.
The body usually stiffens up about two hours after death.
But if it's outside during a summer day,
or in a warm place like here, where the heating's on,
it stiffens up faster.
But her body doesn't seem to have stiffened up yet.
Therefore, I can conclude
that it hasn't been long since she died.
Since it's 5:30 now, we can conclude she died just after 4:30.
And who was Umeda-san?
Do you know anything about her?
She was a talented editor-in-chief for a women's fashion magazine.
Kijima-san, who found the body,
is a famous makeup artist.
It seems the victim was the one who discovered him,
and helped him become who he is today.
And Ishikawa-san, who was with her,
is a photographer for the same magazine.
And there's also Yoko Nakamura-san, who worked as a model.
The victim's rings and necklaces are all missing from her jewelry box.
Could the young man we saw earlier have stolen them?
You saw the killer?
When they reached this block of flats,
these two saw a suspicious man running off.
It was 5pm.
We saw him at the entrance, just after parking the car.
He was wearing
a black leather jacket.
A thief?
He looked like one.
Or maybe he was a killer.
Don't say that, Kijima-san!
I was just joking.
Good evening, editor!
Wow, it's so warm.
It feels really nice, coming from the cold outside.
What's this?
Footprints? No way...
Editor! There are
footprints in the hallway.
Did something happen?
Editor?
Editor!
Don't move!
We mustn't tamper with the footprints. The phone.
Damn it! He cut the line.
I didn't bring my mobile phone.
What about the editor's?
I don't know where it could be.
Ishikawa-kun, let's split up and look for a public phone to call for help.
No, we can't leave
Yoko-chan here alone.
Kijima-san, please stay here.
Afterwards, they went off to search for a public phone.
It was hard, but we eventually found one in front of the station.
They called 110 at 5:15.
We got here at 5:30, and saw that Umeda-san was already dead.
Hey, how come neither of you were carrying a mobile phone?
She had hers before.
Hey! Don't bother people with questions!
Though to be honest, I was about to ask the same thing.
We left our mobile phones at the costume shop.
She hated mobile phones, since wherever she was, she'd get hounded by calls.
Particularly during parties, she would forbid anyone from bringing them.
And she told me not to e-mail her.
I see.
Five years ago, you could find public phones anywhere,
but these days, they're a lot more scarce. What a strange time we live in.
I don't know if we're
better off or worse.
Either way, whether the killer knew it or whether it was a mere coincidence,
the fact is somebody broke into this unlocked house.
Umeda-san was so focused on the preparations that she didn't notice the killer lying in wait.
She was attacked from the back while she was laying down the cutlery here.
If somebody came in through that hallway, she'd have noticed.
And she'd have escaped.
But there are no signs of a struggle in this room.
Hey, is this room identical
to how you found it?
Right.
You remind me of a mystery series I watch on TV.
I don't know anything!
It wasn't me!
I didn't do anything!
It's him, it's him!
That's the man we saw running away from the block of flats.
I saw him in the park in front of the station looking pretty nervous,
so I decided to interrogate him.
Then he tried to escape,
so I caught him right away.
Masataka Shimizu (25)
Part-Time Worker
I don't know anything about this!
He was carrying this.
Sato-kun, can you show this to Kijima-san and the others outside?
Yes, sir!
The footprints even match his shoes.
Yeah, I'm certain.
These were her favorite jewels.
Thank you. Please wait here a little longer.
You were asked to do it over the Internet?
Yeah, I got a really interesting request.
The job consisted of
coming here at 5pm,
taking the jewelry on top of the table,
and taking it to the park in front of the station.
Stop making up stories!
You killed her for money, didn't you?
No! When I got here, that clown was already dead!
I ran away because I didn't want to get in trouble.
Geez, this guy's pretty stubborn.
But isn't it strange
that instead of running away from the crime scene,
he stayed around the park?
Maybe somebody did hire him.
Being a theme park's director for a day is exhausting...
I'm getting sleepy.
Oh geez, he actually fell asleep.
Beef stew?
It's cold. The stove's been out for a while.
But according to the stove knob, it should be on low flame...
Detective, please! You have to believe me!
All right!
What's this?
What's wrong?
Conan-kun?
Mouri-san's going to get started soon.
Oh, really?
He's not starting anything, he's sleeping for real.
As usual.
By the way, do you know what this is?
Oh, this?
I asked the maintenance company in charge of this block of flats,
and they told me it's an earthquake detector for the gas.
An earthquake detector?
Yeah.
It's a device that cuts off the gas distribution when there's an earthquake.
Umeda-san wanted one installed.
It cuts off the gas when there's a strong earthquake.
It probably cut off from the 3pm earthquake, and she forgot to light up the stove again.
Did she forget to light up the stove again?
No... What if was she unable to?
She was probably already dead by the time the earthquake hit at 3pm.
But the approximate time of death is between 4:30 and 5pm.
If she died before 3pm,
rigor mortis would've set in by 5:30,
when Inspector Megure
and the others arrived.
The heating was on,
so rigor mortis
should've set in even faster.
But that wasn't the case.
So what did happen?
That would mean she was left somewhere cold.
There's no way...
But there aren't many cold places in an ordinary house like this...
To slow down rigor mortis...
What are you looking for?
Do you need any help finding it?
No, don't worry. I'll get it myself.
There's not enough space under the bed.
And the closet wouldn't work, either.
Maybe here?
Hey, is there a ladder in this house?
A ladder? I don't know.
Wait, there's one on the balcony.
I used it last week.
On the balcony? Okay, thanks.
Grey makeup? It's fresh.
Brrr, it's cold!
Conan, where'd you go?
Artificial hair?
There was no need for a ladder...
I know who the killer is!
Please wait, Detective!
Please believe me!
Right. You came here, but didn't kill the victim.
Who'd believe that?
We'll hear the rest at HQ.
Hey, Detective Takagi!
Inspector, can we go too?
Oh, right. By all means, feel free to go.
What a disaster.
The costume party was a complete wreck.
And even worse, you lost an important person to you.
Mouri-san?
You fell asleep again?
No, that was a rehearsal.
Now witness, as Sleeping Kogoro solves the most complicated of cases.
Kijima-san, I'm sorry, but we can't allow you to leave yet.
What do you mean, Mouri-kun?
Ishikawa-san,
at what time did you meet Kijima-san today?
At 3pm, in front of
Beika Department Store.
Kijima-san, before 3pm, where were you and what were you doing?
A lot of things.
It sounds like you want to confirm my alibi.
That's indeed the case.
Inspector, Shimizu-san, who you just took away, is not the killer.
The man who killed Umeda-san is Kijima-san, who is right here.
What are you on about?
Kijima-san was with us the whole time.
He didn't have time to kill the editor.
The only time he wasn't with us was when we went to look for a public phone.
But the editor was already dead by then.
No, Umeda-san was killed long before that...
Most likely, before you even met up with Kijima-san.
But the approximate time of death is between 4:30 and 5pm.
Besides, Mouri-kun, didn't you see the e-mail from Umeda-san?
That only means that Umeda-san's mobile phone was used,
not necessarily that she sent the e-mail herself.
But, Mouri-kun, the rigor mortis hadn't set in yet.
Umeda-san's body wasn't in this room.
He hid it in a cold place before you arrived,
in order to delay rigor mortis.
What are you talking about?
I saw her body at the same time as those two!
Otherwise, what was that dead clown?
It was a doll.
A doll with clown makeup,
with a similar stature to Umeda-san.
Who suggested that today should be a costume party in the first place?
The editor.
Ishikawa-san, did she tell you that herself?
No, Kijima-san told us the editor had suggested it.
By the way, Kijima-san...
Did you know that this floor's gas setup has an earthquake detection device?
Earthquake?
You didn't know, did you?
Detective Sato, can you bring the cooking pot here?
Sure.
Please tell us what's inside it.
It seems she was making beef stew,
but it's not cooked yet.
If she'd left it as it was, I doubt it'd be ready on time for the party at 5pm.
Umeda-san was setting everything up so it was ready in time for the party.
As proof of that, the stove's flame had been set to low.
She intended to have it cooked on time for the party.
But because of the earthquake detector, the stove went out.
But Umeda-san never turned the gas back on.
No, she couldn't turn it back on.
Why? Because she was already dead.
Kijima-san, you killed her.
You have no evidence!
This is ridiculous, I'm going home.
Mouri-kun is not done yet.
Kijima-san, before meeting up with Ishikawa-san and Yoko-san,
you came here and strangled Umeda-san,
who was setting everything up for the party.
Afterwards, you switched her body with a doll you'd set up.
And why did you do that?
Because you had to leave Umeda-san's body somewhere cold.
If you wanted to have everyone believe
that she was murdered shortly before the three of you arrived,
you couldn't leave the body in a room with the heating on.
Kijima-san, you left without turning off the gas,
because you wanted to ensure that the beef stew was ready
once you found Umeda-san's body hours later.
But unfortunately for you, there was an earthquake around 3pm...
and the gas was stopped.
Not knowing that, you went shopping
and went off to the costume shop.
And with Umeda-san's
phone that you'd stolen,
you sent that e-mail to make it look like she was alive.
And finally, you made sure everyone left their phones there.
Upon finding the body,
you asked Ishikawa-san to look for a public phone with you.
But you knew Ishikawa-san would never leave his girlfriend alone with a corpse.
And you'd be in this flat, under
apparently normal circumstances.
Afterwards, you took
Umeda-san's real body,
which you'd hidden
on the balcony,
and ditched the doll.
At that moment, the gray clown makeup stained the balcony's curtains.
You're lying!
You're making it all up!
You have no evidence!
Sure I do.
Please come out to the balcony.
Takagi-kun!
Kijima-san, this is your car, right?
Damn it!
That woman deserved it!
It's true that she made me who I am today,
but every time I found a girlfriend, she'd always step in the way.
She told me that if I ever broke up with her,
she'd make sure I'd never find work!
I was just like a clown,
always hiding my true feelings under a veil of makeup!
Fire chief for a day?
The old man never changes.
Wait, is this going to...
I knew it!
The transmitter's signal disappeared.
They're going to assassinate someone.
The old man's in danger!
Just 90 metres...
I have to make it in time!
Haibara, do you know anything?
Who's DJ?!
On the next Conan special:
Next Conan's Hint:
A transmitter and a bug
Next time, it's the tenth anniversary...
...special!
At last, the Black Organization!