Detective Conan:
10th Anniversary Celebration
Happy New Year!
Detective Conan has been
on the air for 10 years now!
All of us...
...will keep doing our best!
The TV series...
T-The movies...
Shonen Sunday...
And the Detective Boys, too!
Detective Conan:
10th Anniversary Celebration
Please keep supporting us!
Now then, we've got something exciting in store for you today!
We've got a song from our Shi—
C-Conan Edogawa.
It's called Boku ga Iru.
If you will...
If you will?
You don't mean...
Conan's singing...
That must mean...
Yeah.
Four-Eyes is...
No way!
Oh geez, seriously?
Oh, come on!
This can't be happening...
We apologize for putting you
through that first thing in the new year...
S-Sonoko...
Today, we have an extra-long
10th anniversary special story!
Black Impact!
When the Organization Reaches You.
I don't like the sound of that.
It's a jam-packed
two and a half hours!
Look forward to it!
Ran, I'm not in this one!
Now then, let's move on
from this segment...
Start!
While operating
as a high school detective,
some men in black used a weird drug on me,
changing my body into that of a child.
They were part of an evil criminal organisation,
which thinks nothing of taking people's lives.
Black Organization
Thus, my days spent fighting
against the Black Organization began.
Right... My fight as
the detective, Conan Edogawa.
Ai Haibara
The name of that drug
was Apoptoxin 4869.
It was something I developed for the Organization.
Although it was still
in the prototype stage.
Ai Haibara.
Real name: Shiho Miyano.
In the Organisation,
she was referred to as Sherry.
Having become distrustful of the Organization, I took the same drug and made my escape.
Because he murdered my big sister...
Gin.
Gin
He's the one directly responsible for doing this to my body.
Vodka
Along with his partner Vodka, he seems to have been involved in many crimes.
We happened upon
Gin's car in town.
We tailed him,
but one of them caught Haibara.
Haibara, we're in trouble!
They're coming!
I instructed Haibara
to drink baiganr,
a liquor capable of temporarily restoring her original form,
so that she could escape.
But Gin ambushed me there.
Get into the chimney!
Who the hell are you?
Haibara was in serious danger,
but somehow, I was able to get her back and away from them.
FBI
FBI agents Jodie and Akai started their own private investigation.
They were following...
Vermouth
Vermouth.
Vermouth disguised herself as Dr. Araide,
the school doctor, and looked for Sherry.
And eventually,
she managed to zero in on her.
I didn't know, and had her come do a house call,
since Ai-kun's cold
was pretty serious.
We'd been discovered.
Both Haibara and I.
My apologies
for being so last minute,
but would it be all right if
I headed there to pick you up now?
Disguised as Haibara,
I took up Vermouth's invitation.
The FBI had also set out a net.
Vermouth, the FBI and I ended up in a three-way showdown.
Vermouth's plan
to target Haibara failed.
With this case, we were able to get more information about the Organization.
Right. Specifically, that the dialing tones when typing their boss's e-mail address
form the melody of a children's song,
Nanatsu no Ko.
It would seem I have given you too much free rein.
Return to my side, Vermouth.
Nanatsu no Ko (Seven Baby Crows)
And tonight, alongside the melody of Nanatsu no Ko,
they will attempt to execute an assassination plan.
Just who are they targeting?
Ladies and gentlemen,
thank you for waiting.
We are proudly presenting to you the next vice-president candidate from our town,
Kevin Brown!
Please give a big hand!
Got him!
500 yards, clear!
You're up next!
Impressive.
600 yards, clear!
Kevin Brown bit the dust
three times now.
Four.
They're pretty good, Bro.
Too bad.
If I clear this distance, I win.
He's mine!
It seems 600 yards is their limit.
That's enough.
Gin!
Wait!
Let me try again!
There's no need.
Our next target only
requires 200 to 300 yards.
Oh? Then...
Chianti, Korn...
We have work to do.
Office of
the Deisankai
What are you
dawdling around for?!
I'm so sorry!
Black Impact!
When the Organization Reaches You
How did you enjoy
Yoko Okino's Four Minute Cooking?
Today's guest was the great detective,
Kogoro Mouri-san.
See you at the
same time next week!
And OK!
Good work, everyone.
That's a wrap!
You were great, Dad!
It's true.
You kept your cool,
despite being on a live broadcast.
You did wonderfully.
No, no, it was a failure...
Yoko-san.
The noodles got so hot and excited
by your incredible beauty...
that the ones in the
Yoko-style soy sauce ramen I made
were knocked out, to the point of being all soft and mushy!
The only thing soft and mushy is your mind that's melting from all the dirty thoughts.
We were pretty lucky,
weren't we?
We got to watch a live broadcast of Morning Live 7
being put together on a holiday.
Y-Yeah...
Come to think of it,
we haven't had breakfast yet...
How would you like to eat with me at the TV station's cafeteria?
That sounds great!
Then go ahead
and wait for me, please.
There's someone I'd like to introduce to you, so I'll call her right now.
Huh? I see...
Hello, it's me, Okino.
Did I wake you?
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
Oh, i-it's nothing...
This is bad.
Every time I see someone
on a mobile phone,
I'm instantly
reminded of Vermouth...
The e-mail address of the boss of those
men in black who shrunk my body with a drug...
The melody of Nanatsu no Ko...
You must never pry
into that e-mail address.
It's Pandora's box.
Yeah, yeah, I know.
Do you now?
I wonder if a rice omelette
would have been better...
Mouri-san!
Thanks for waiting!
Hi!
Huh? Aren't you often on the Sunday evening news?
Right. This is Rena Mizunashi-san,
one of the news presenters.
Nice to meet you.
I am the great detective,
Kogoro Mouri.
I'm Ran, his daughter.
And this is Conan-kun.
Hello.
Nice to meet you.
Oh, come on...
Now, Yoko-chan...
You really want me to ask a great detective to look into that?
It'll be fine!
I'm sure Mouri-san will help you.
But...
Is something troubling you?
Yes!
Geez, Yoko-chan...
A-A ding-dong dash?!
You want me to find out
who did that?
You see?
I told you it'd be insulting to him!
But it doesn't seem
like an ordinary prank...
What do you mean?
Yes, well...
It happens every Saturday,
in the early morning.
I was on the watch for the dasher,
trying to catch them red-handed today, but...
When the doorbell rang,
I opened the door right away,
but there wasn't a
single person in sight.
No way...
Ever since, I've been afraid of opening my front door.
And this was at your home,
Miss News Presenter?
Oh, yes...
It's a flat in Haido City.
Why don't you have Mouri-san
come over to your place to investigate?
I can't go because
I've got work to do after this, but...
What do you think, Mouri-san?
Sure?
There doesn't seem to be anywhere near the door someone could hide...
Yeah...
Then, how about we ring the bell,
and try it out for real?
Ready?
Okay, I'm going to ring it.
Dad?!
A-Are you okay?
Yeah, sure...
But now we know there's barely any time to find somewhere to hide.
Yeah...
Now, why don't we discuss this in more detail inside?
Oh, of course.
Please, come in.
Pardon us.
Oh, let me get
you some slippers.
I don't need any!
Of course you don't!
You're just a kid.
Oh, sorry.
Come on in.
Pardon us.
But you've sure got
a lot of locks on your door...
You're right!
There's four of them...
That's because it's not safe
for a woman to live alone.
You're probably right.
Can I get you
something to drink?
I'll take some coffee.
I'll give you a hand.
All right...
So I can hear what's going on out front when the doorbell rings,
I'll set up a bug for now.
I'll put it on the wall,
just outside the door.
Here, I can quickly
retrieve it again later.
And just in case it comes off and lands somewhere,
I'll hide it inside this
chewing gum with a tracker.
That ought to do it.
I think...
I think someone was
watching me just now.
Conan-kun!
Do you want to drink
something sweet?
S-Sure.
Is something wrong?
Oh, no, it's nothing.
Okay, Conan-kun,
a sweet drink it is.
Did I imagine that?
Or was it...
So the ding-dong dash started two months ago?
Yes, and it's been happening around 6:30 every Saturday morning since.
Did something happen
two months ago?
All I can think of
is that I was transferred from Morning Live 7
to the Sunday evening news.
But I'm not the main presenter for either of those programmes.
So you met Yoko-san while working on Morning Live 7?
Yeah.
At the time, Yoko-chan and I
were both handling the show
on Tuesdays, Thursdays, and Saturdays.
In which case,
this may have started
as a prank two months ago.
Yes.
On Saturdays, when I worked on Morning Live 7,
I had always left my place at 4 AM.
Say...
Have you consistently been getting pranked for the past two months?
That's right.
Every Saturday...
Ah, but wait...
There was one time I wasn't.
Two weeks ago, I had been overseas covering a story between Monday and Friday.
And nothing happened that Saturday,
the day after I got back home.
Though I was
sleeping out of exhaustion...
So maybe I just couldn't
hear the doorbell ring.
And one time, the same prank
happened on a Tuesday,
after the three-day
weekend in October.
But that was the only time
it happened on a Tuesday.
A-And one time, I found something
strange outside the door...
Something strange?
They had left a bottle,
filled with some kind of pills there!
When I had a doctor
I knew look at them later,
They turned out
to be sleeping pills.
S-Sleeping pills?!
Sounds like a stalker.
That was probably a notice saying, I'll put
you to sleep and then do awful things to you!
O-Oh, no!
Has anything else
strange happened?
Other than the
sleeping pills being left behind.
Anything else...
What is it?
Three nights ago, I thought
I saw someone in the flat next door,
even though it should be vacant.
What?
Three nights ago?
So, on Tuesday?
Yes.
It was a little before midnight.
I had just left the bath
and was relaxing in bed.
I thought,
Wasn't the flat next door vacant?
So I took a look
from my balcony.
But the next-door
flat was pitch-dark...
So I thought, Maybe I heard that noise coming from outside?
And in the morning, I called the company that manages the building,
but all they would tell me is
that I must've been dreaming.
There's a good chance
that the guy is a stalker.
The man must have a
spare key to the vacant flat next door,
and stays in that flat
every Friday night,
not just that one
time three nights ago.
He's then been ringing
your doorbell every following morning.
I see.
If he was staying next door,
he could ring your doorbell and quickly hide.
That explains why you were never able to find the dasher.
Say, how long has the flat next door been vacant?
I think it's probably been
about six months.
As I figured, it's locked.
If we could get in, I thought
we might find a clue about that man...
How about we call the management company,
and have them open it up for us?
But after what happened the last time,
I get the feeling they might not listen to me.
It's no use, huh?
Ki-mi-wa?
Ki-bi-wa...
What the heck is this?
What could this
ki-bi-wa mean...?
Bi?
Huh?
Why did I read it as mi?
Ki-bi-wa...
Thursday, a beautiful woman,
Japanese food.
Why...?
Rena-san, do these terms have anything to do with a show you host?
No...
Rather, maybe it could
be someone's name?
Someone's...
Someone's name?
Yes. Investigation Unit,
First Division.
Megure speaking...
Oh, it's Conan-kun?!
Yeah.
Uh... It looks like he's here.
Hold on a second, okay?
Let's see, the hold button...
In other words...
Takagi.
Your phone extension.
Right.
Yes, this is Takagi...
Takagi-kun!
Huh?
Inspector, didn't I give you my extension number?
Well, it's okay.
Oh...
More importantly, you have
a call from Conan-kun on line 1.
From Conan-kun?
What could it be about?
Conan-kun?
Yes, this is Takagi...
Ah, Detective Takagi?
I just wanted to
ask you something.
Three nights ago, did you enter
a flat numbered 305 in Haido City?
Y-Yes, I did...
Huh?
The reason?
Which means, this vehicle
was at the below-mentioned...
The reason is kinda... uh...
Detective Takagi,
could you have been...
...staking out a flat in the block across the street?
U-Uh...
What's wrong?
Oh, no, it's nothing...
What're you doing, then...?
Actually, that's right.
From that flat's window,
I could see the flat
where the ex-fiancée of a suspect in a case lives.
There was a possibility that the suspect might try to contact him,
so I called the management company,
and had them allow me to stake it out there.
I figured as much.
Figured?
Well, in the end, the suspect was apprehended in Toriya City,
and the stakeout was canceled halfway through the night.
But since the case
is still under investigation,
I could've sworn I asked
the management company to keep it quiet...
So how did you know
I was doing a stakeout there?
Detective Takagi...
While you were on stakeout,
you scribbled something on the glass door, didn't you?
Takagi Miwako.
高木美和子
What is it, Takagi-kun?
Takagi-kun...
What's with him?
I'm so sorry.
This guy's acting
really suspiciously...
Conan-kun...
Can you please not
tell her about this?
I'm begging you...
Sure!
That's fine, gotcha.
But I'm here with Ran-neechan and Uncle Kogoro right now.
Oh, no!
Takagi!
So basically, Detective Takagi was
staking out a suspect's ex-fiancée's place,
started thinking
about Detective Sato,
and wrote the name she'd have
if she married him on the glass door.
Right after that,
he got a call from Inspector Megure saying,
We've caught the suspect. Hurry on back.
He left in a hurry,
and forgot to erase the name he wrote on the glass.
I see.
So over the next three days,
the Taka in Takagi
and the ko in Miwako
faded away, right?
Seriously?
Honestly...
That guy always causes a scene!
S-Sorry about that...
But that's fine, because it's just
like Detective Takagi to do that!
Yeah. It kind of sounds like he gives off
a cute vibe that's unbefitting of a detective.
Right?
But now we're
right back to square one.
Yeah.
And the problem is
that tomorrow's Saturday...
At this point, the only thing we can do is catch the dasher red-handed.
Rena-san.
Y-Yes?
Please, let us stay here
for the night.
Tomorrow morning,
I, Kogoro Mouri,
will make sure
to catch that rascal!
Would you like a hand
with the cleaning?
Oh, don't worry about it.
Tomorrow's
the day for recyclables,
so I'm just bundling together any magazines and newspapers I don't need.
Because of my job, I have to go through a lot of magazines and newspapers.
Oh, doing some tidying up?
Dr Jekyll and Mr Hyde, eh?
That takes me back...
I read it in middle school.
It was really scary.
Do you know it, Conan-kun?
Yeah.
The mild-mannered Dr Henry Jekyll
drank a medicine
that he invented himself,
and became the evil,
villainous Edward Hyde.
It's a story about
split personalities, right?
Wow, you sure know your stuff.
Why, you!
He knows all kinds of weird stuff,
even though he's just a dumb brat...
There we go.
Thanks so much.
No, it's nothing.
Here.
Do you always leave them here?
Yeah.
If I put them here,
I won't forget to take
them to the rubbish pickup
when I leave in the morning.
Oh, I get it.
And since this flat is
in the corner of the building,
having them out here just for one night shouldn't bother anyone.
Is Tuesday a rubbish
collection day, too?
Yeah, it's the day for combustibles.
So I also leave that rubbish
out here the night before.
I see...
So that's why.
Say, if we find out who's doing this,
will you not get too mad at them?
They're probably a big fan of yours.
Well, duh, he's a stalker!
Wake up, Uncle!
Uncle!
Uncle, it's almost time...
H-He's here?
Rena-san, stay there!
Why, you...
Just you wait!
When I get my hands on you...
I'm gonna teach you—
Huh?
D-Dad?
T-There's nobody here.
N-No way!
This can't be!
How?
I can't believe this.
I can't... How?
How? Hey, Dad...
H-Heck if I know.
He's here.
Right here...
Here?
Aren't those just magazines?
C-Conan-kun...
Like I said, right back here!
You dummy. A big adult
couldn't possibly hide back here...
A-A kid?!
Why, you little...
Hey!
You were the ding-dong dasher!
I see...
You couldn't find him
because he was a kid.
I didn't think a person
could hide there...
I get it now.
You didn't ring the doorbell the Saturday before last
because there weren't any
bundles of magazines left out front.
She was out covering a story
and wasn't home all that week,
so she probably didn't have
many magazines to throw out!
Hey!
What's the meaning of this?!
Why did you do this?!
However I look at you,
you're a primary school student!
Well, if you won't talk,
you leave me no other option.
We'll talk about this at the police station with your parents.
I think he rang the doorbell
because he was trying to wake her up.
So that lady would make it in time for Morning Live 7.
When you stopped appearing on Morning Live 7,
this boy probably mistakenly thought
it was because you were oversleeping.
That's why he rang the doorbell at 6:30 on Saturdays.
School is off on Saturdays,
so if he could hurry home after ringing the doorbell,
he'd be able to check to see
whether you were on Morning Live 7.
But didn't she say there was
one time it happened on a Tuesday?
Don't tell me
you skipped school?!
I think it was a holiday.
There's a three-day weekend in October because the second Monday is Sports Day.
And if it had a sports festival
during the three-day weekend,
a primary school usually gives everyone the following Tuesday off as well.
Then you left the sleeping pills
so she'd have a good night's sleep,
and wake up
bright and early, right?
Yeah.
Because Mom always slept well after taking them.
I see...
But why?
Why'd you do that to me?
Because you looked like her...
You look like my mum...
My mum...
died in a car crash last year.
So... So I...
Little boy...
I understand how lonely you must feel without your mother...
But if you keep
clinging to her forever,
you'll only be
worrying her up in heaven.
You're a boy.
Toughen up so that
your mom can rest easy.
That's why you mustn't
ever come here again.
For your mom's sake,
and for your own sake too...
Got it?
Bye-bye, Miss!
Bye-bye...
Oh, it's just...
I used to have a
younger brother about his age...
Oh, right, I have to pay you
for your services!
Oh, there's no need!
Besides, you already made us
a delicious dinner.
B-But please,
as a way of thanking you...
Y-You sure?
Then, I'll send my bank details to your phone by e-mail,
so if I could have
your e-mail address...
Dude...
Geez.
What a boring, worthless case.
But aren't you glad
it wasn't a weird stalker?
R-Rain...
C-Crap!
I never retrieved the bug!
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
I-I think I forgot something
back at that lady's flat...
Oh, geez.
Dad, you go on ahead.
Conan-kun and I'll—
I-I'll go get it
and be right back!
What?!
Conan-kun?!
Well, then we'll be
waiting at the car park!
The sound of footsteps means...
Mizunashi-san must
have stepped on it...
Is that the sound of
a mobile phone being turned on?
N-Nanatsu no Ko!
Don't tell me...
She couldn't be...?!
Yes?
Oh, sorry.
I had some trouble,
so I had my phone turned off.
Don't worry.
It was nothing serious.
I just e-mailed
that person about it.
There's no way...
There's no way...!
No, that's not a problem.
I'll meet you at 10:00,
just as we planned...
Gin.
What?!
H-How?!
W-What did you say?!
Is that true, Shin'ichi?!
Yes...
No doubt about it!
I've found another
of those people in black,
after a scary amount
of coincidences.
This is bad!
The tracker's
started moving faster!
She must've got into a car!
Doc! For now, hurry and come pick me up in your Beetle!
And obviously,
don't let Haibara know!
O-Okay...
So, Shin'ichi...
Yeah.
Right now
I'm in Haido City, at...
You won't get away from me!
Conan-kun?
Did you find what you forgot?
Huh?
What's up?
Conan-kun says he happened
to run into the Doctor...
And now they're
going to Tropical Land.
Let him be.
It's raining, too...
What the heck
are they thinking?
Well, I'll call you again
when I start heading home.
Uh, wait—
I see.
You happened
to take a case request
from a news presenter acquaintance,
went to her flat,
and in order to investigate,
you stuck a tracker and a bug to the wall with chewing gum, but they fell off.
The bug happened to get stuck on the sole of her shoe,
and that woman happened
to be one of them.
Do I have that right?
Hey, Doc!
I told you not to
bring Haibara along!
E-Easier said than done...
So?
You say this news presenter,
Rena Mizunashi,
is working with them,
but are you sure?
Yeah.
She sent something to their boss's e-mail address.
And after that, she took a phone call,
and called the person on the other end...
Gin...
...so, yes.
But it sure was a lucky break.
To think that all those coincidences
would help you find a lead to one of them...
No, just the opposite.
It's the opposite.
This is the worst case scenario.
Think about it more carefully.
If they happen to find
the tracker and the bug...
They'll naturally try
to figure out who planted them.
And the first person
they'll suspect
is the detective who had just been
at that news presenter's flat:
Kogoro Mouri.
Oh, geez...
You don't mean...
Yeah.
Even if they believe the old man left it there
for the sake of an investigation she requested,
they cannot deny that there's a chance he may have heard their entire conversation.
And therefore,
they'd be sure to...
...come to silence him.
Kogoro Mouri...
And if need be,
every single person around him.
O-Oh, no...
Basically, the more information
we get about them from that bug,
the tighter the noose gets around
both our necks and the old man's.
Then...
Then you've got to hurry and
retrieve them before they notice!
But there's one thing
that baffles me.
That news presenter asked Detective Mouri
over to find the ding-dong dasher, right?
And the culprit was a child.
If she were one of them,
a case like that...
Yeah.
I was stumped about that, too.
The movement of
the tracker slowed down...
And the engine's
sound is echoing...
Which... means...
She went into an indoor
car park somewhere.
Then, she's meeting one of them somewhere in that building.
Something's getting closer.
A car?
This unique idling sound comes from an unequal-length header,
and this highly-responsive revving is that of a horizontally-opposed engine.
Hey, you don't mean...
Yeah.
A car with those features would generally be a Volkswagen, a Subaru,
or his favourite...
A Porsche!
What's the matter, Kir?
We agreed to meet at 10:00.
Gin!
Sorry. I felt uneasy about
a car that was following me,
so I was shaking it off,
just in case.
S-She's not talking
about our car, is she?
No, there was over
600 meters between us.
It couldn't be that.
I take it you
didn't have any problems?
Yeah...
I was just imagining things.
So can you put away that Beretta you've got cocked behind the door?
If you get weirdly
suspicious and shoot me,
won't you lose
your chance to kill DJ?
DJ...
Did she say DJ?
Well, no matter...
Everything within 500 meters of this building is under our surveillance.
If a suspicious car comes
this way, we'll know right away.
Doc.
I need you to slowly
pull over to the curb.
Once you've stopped,
pop the hood, get out,
and pretend you're
checking the car's engine.
Come on, hurry!
R-Right.
Okay, one final confirmation...
Recite it for me.
The time is 1 PM.
The place is Eddie P.
I, as his interviewer, have to lure DJ to the designated spot.
That's right.
I'll be waiting for you, Kir.
Thrust the prey straight
into my scope and get me all excited.
Oh, Chianti...
And you're with Korn, too.
What a reliable line-up...
Kir, Chianti, Korn...
Just how many of them are there?!
I'm counting on you.
Our successes are unheralded,
but our failures are trumpeted.
Whether we succeed or fail, the world will never know.
That's how
the Organization works.
Yeah, that's true.
Okay, it's almost time.
Let's get this over with.
And can you try
to do it without my help?
Vermouth!
Hey, hold on!
What's going on here?!
What's she doing here?!
You never told me about this!
This bitch went off on her own, dragging Calvados with her, only to watch him die!
How the hell could you
add her to our plan?!
Get back in the car, Chianti.
Vermouth is just here
as a last resort.
But...
This is an order
from that person.
At any rate,
it's going down at Eddie P?
I suppose that'd make
the perfect hunting ground...
What do you mean?
You need to brush up
on your history a bit, Vodka.
Anyway, the rain
outside is a problem.
Don't worry...ccording to the forecast...
stop raining...before...noon...
Damn!
The rain's too strong.
I can't hear them right...
Haibara,
do you know anything?
Who's DJ?!
And where the heck is Eddie P?!
That's what they were talking about...
It's some kind of code, right?!
Well...
I don't know DJ,
but if Eddie P is a place, maybe P means a parking lot or a park?
Then do you know anyone named Kir, Chianti, or Korn?!
I don't remember any Kir,
but I've heard of
Chianti and Korn.
They're both skilled snipers.
Then it sounds like they are planning to assassinate someone...
Hey!
What's going on?
Are those two there, too?!
Damn it!
I don't have enough info...
I need to get closer...
The tracker's location is
580 meters to the north-northwest...
So it's in that building's
underground car park...
Haibara, wait here with the Doc!
W-Wait, where are you—
Never mind, just wait here!
Hold it right there.
Kudo-kun?!
Shin'ichi?
Hi...
Cool Kid!
Bang!
M-Miss Jodie...
Hi!
W-What are you doing here?
We at the FBI have also
had our eyes on her.
Right after Vermouth started posing as Dr. Araide,
that news presenter, Rena Mizunashi, made frequent visits to his clinic.
But you surprised me!
I was staking her out
when you and Detective Mouri
went right into her flat.
Then...
I think someone was
watching me just now.
So that was...
Right!
That was me.
And that's how I knew about him being hired
to look into the case of the child's prank.
But just when I'd assumed she was clean and was about to stop my stakeout...
I saw you running back with a serious look on your face.
Cool Kid...
I figured something was up.
So I kept tailing her.
Well, I could tell she was
trying to shake my car off,
so I gave up before
I got in over my head.
I see...
So when she said...
Sorry. I felt uneasy about
a car that was following me,
so I was shaking it off,
just in case.
The car she felt uneasy
about was Miss Jodie's...
You lost sight of her car too, right?
You should leave this
to the FBI and go home.
You should...
Do you know where she's going?
I can't tell you the details,
but it seems she's going to
be interviewing three people today.
We suspect one of those people is in contact with them,
and they're going to make some kind of deal or exchange information.
No, it's not some sort of deal!
They're going to assassinate one of those three people this afternoon at 1:00!
H-How do you know that?
I accidentally got a tracker
stuck to the sole of her shoe...
So I've been using that, and the
audio receiver in my Tracking Glasses to...
Crap.
It's getting closer!
Get in!
You too, Doc! Hurry up!
Jodie here.
Target is southbound
on Toriya Road.
Follow her!
Gin's car went a different way...
Should we follow, too?
No, even if we blindly go after her,
we would just come up one step short.
And it'd be no laughing matter
if they realized that we're trailing her.
But won't someone be killed if we don't do something?
Simply put,
to stop this assassination,
you have to work out the identity of
this DJ person and the location of Eddie P,
plus get there first.
Right.
So can you tell us?
We need details about the three people that news presenter's going to interview today.
She's going to interview
three candidates running for the
House of Representatives for the first time.
The first is a professor in Teito University's
Department of Pharmaceutical Sciences:
Eisaku Tokiwa, who has researched and developed many kinds of medicines.
The second is a popular actor,
and a son of a wealthy family:
Junji Sendou, who'll be a second-generation politician if elected.
The third has a father who is a retired officer from the Ministry of Defence:
Yasuteru Domon,
a once high-ranking officer of the JSDF.
But I wasn't able to find out when and where she'll be interviewing each of them.
Apparently that was all up to her and the TV crew.
They might be
unscheduled interviews.
Which means it's possible that somebody
in the TV crew could also be one of them.
But none of those three
have the initials of DJ.
Eisaku Tokiwa, E and T.
Junji Sendou, J and S.
Yasuteru Domon, Y and D.
If only we could
figure out the location...
But there's tons of parks
and parking lots.
DJ usually refers
to a disc jockey, doesn't it?
The term stems from disc...
It refers to someone who swaps
records out to play one song after another,
comparing their
handling of the records
to the way a horse racing jockey handles their horse.
But I don't have info about any of the three being into music or gambling.
Gambling?
W-What do we do?
We should get moving...
Gambling...
If we don't go after her soon,
we really will lose sight of her car...
No. We're not going to follow her.
Let's contact
the candidate's office, and ask
what's on his schedule
for around 1 PM.
Y-You don't mean...
You figured it out?
Yeah.
One of those three
is their target, DJ.
The hint is Diamond Jack.
You mean
the jack of diamonds...?
That's what DJ means?
Yeah.
Those guys are using playing cards as a way
of referring to the person they're targeting.
Diamonds would mean someone
who has a lot of assets and money...
So that DJ must be
the son of a wealthy family...
Junji Sendou, who'll be
a second-generation politician if elected.
No.
The Jack in playing cards
is someone who serves the royal court,
someone who was appointed
to be a courtier or soldier.
It wouldn't mean
a prince or a son.
B-But he's the only rich guy...
It's certainly true that
a diamond represents wealth.
But in astrology,
it also signifies earth.
Therefore, it's the former high-ranking official of the JSDF
who also has an earth
character in his name.
土
Yasuteru Domon.
土門康輝
He's their target.
Yasuteru Domon.
He has a stronger sense
of justice than most.
On TV and in the newspapers, he makes radical remarks against violence and crime.
He's gained a strong following.
Because of this, there are many who hold grudges against him.
He had a hitman sent after him,
but that tough guy was able to defend himself admirably.
If that's who you mean, I think he'll be just fine without our protection.
No.
It's the men in black
who are after him.
Better safe than sorry.
Got it.
The phone number to the office of his election committee.
His home page says he's planning
to go golfing this afternoon,
but it doesn't say
where he's going.
So they're going
to snipe Domon-san
at the parking lot
of that golf course?
Either way, the fastest way to find out
is to call the office and ask.
Here.
Miss Jodie,
this is the number.
Okay!
Right, okay.
What?
Oh, nothing.
Was just thinking
that you'd changed a lot.
Because when we got caught up
with them in the past, you'd say...
Stop it!, It's too dangerous!,
You'd be better off running!,
or something of the sort.
Of course I'm helping!
This time, the tracker and the bug
you carelessly set up there
ended up stuck
to the sole of one of them.
If they find it,
you and everyone around you...
In other words,
all of us will be in hot water.
I guess so, but...
Plus...
Plus, I...
Yeah, I'm gonna go see them.
If I get closer and see them,
I might find out who the killer is.
Don't.
Didn't I tell you?
If they don't arrest the killer,
something terrible could happen.
B-But...
And not just to you.
The killer could get revenge on everyone who helped you accuse them.
I get that you want this evil person to be punished,
But you have to
control your feelings.
That, too, is a form of courage.
B-But...
But... I...
I don't wanna run away!
You'll never win if you
just keep running away!
Never!
Plus... what?
You don't know?
What do you mean?
He's not going
to the golf course?
Well, he canceled yesterday.
He said he suddenly had to meet someone today.
Then hurry and contact him!
His life is in danger,
so tell him not to meet that person!
We get calls like this a lot.
With youthful strength,
we can change Japan!
YASUTERU DOMON
But he'll be fine.
Domon-san's tough, and he's got two bodyguards with him.
Thanks, but don't worry.
If you'll excuse me,
I have work to do...
Wait!
I guess they figured
it was a prank call.
No way...
It's hardly surprising.
Damn!
Then I will have to
figure out the other clue,
the location of Eddie P, where they plan to shoot him!
This news presenter who's interviewing Domon-san, and who's one of them...
Where is she right now?
She's 18 km southeast of here,
at the Nichiuri TV station in Shiodome.
She's probably gone there
to meet with her crew, and—
A phone...
What's up?
Just to verify.
I have a cautious and
persistent personality, you know.
Don't worry.
I'm doing fine.
I'm about to head to Eddie P
with the crew in the TV news van.
The rain has stopped,
so it's a perfect hunting day.
Kir.
It was like this
this morning too,
but I'm wondering about
the noise from your phone.
Maybe it's because
I'm underground?
I was underground
this morning, too.
All right, Gin,
we'll go on ahead.
Hey, Chianti.
Good luck.
I'll kill her...
I swear I'll kill her!
I, too, hate Vermouth.
Calvados was smitten with her...
She used him.
So I hate her.
Yeah, I woulda iced
that bitch a long time ago,
if she hadn't been
that person's pet!
Damn...
Only 30 minutes until the time they
said the assassination will take place!
Eddie P... Eddie P...
Where the heck is Eddie P?
Say...
Maybe for now, we ought to head for that TV station?
Yes, good idea.
We won't get anywhere
if we just sit here all stumped.
Even if you figured out where this hunting ground is,
if we're too far behind
the TV news van in question,
We can't get there before they do.
Hunting ground...
Come to think of it,
Vermouth said...
I suppose that'd make
the perfect hunting ground...
What do you mean?
You need to brush up
on your history a bit, Vodka.
History...
Phone...
It's mine.
Let's see, this sound is...
...coming from
the Conan phone.
Uh, hello?
Don't uh, hello me!
Geez, you hung up on
me all of a sudden!
I-I'm sorry, Ran-neechan...
Whoa!
If this one wins,
I'll make a killing!
Put the Doctor
on for a minute!
We're just about to
get on the Ferris wheel!
So I'll call you back later!
H-Hey!
Oh, geez...
Oh, Cool Kid!
It's like you have
a split personality.
Split personality?
Wait a sec...
Hunting ground...
History... Park...
Split personality?
Oh, doing some tidying up?
Dr Jekyll and Mr Hyde, eh?
That takes me back...
That's it!
Doc!
Hang a left at the next light and get on the highway!
The highway?
But if we get on that now,
we'll be pretty far from Nichiuri TV.
Being far from it is just fine.
Because we'll get
there ahead of them.
Ahead?
Does that mean...
Yeah, I finally figured it out...
The place where they're planning to assassinate Domon-san,
Eddie P, is Haido Park.
Haido Park?
But why would Eddie P...
It clicked when you said the words
split personality earlier, Miss Jodie.
The nickname Eddie
is short for Edward.
I see...
Edward Hyde.
The first name
of the character Hyde
from Stevenson's horror novel Dr Jekyll and Mr Hyde.
Which is why Eddie P
is Haido Park!
But couldn't it be the parking lot at that park, too?
No, they said it would make
the perfect hunting ground.
Until the 16th century,
the original Hyde Park in London
was a place noblemen would hunt deer,
wild boar, and other animals that lived there.
Hence, it's a hunting ground.
I'm certain of it.
This is bad!
At this rate, the TV news
van will get there before us.
Doc! Hurry!
R-Right!
Hey, Gin... No Kir yet?
I'm seriously
dying of boredom here.
Wait. She's on the way
with DJ right now.
The sheep there aren't involved, so don't
you dare start hunting them down to kill time.
Same goes for you, Korn.
T-That kid...
And the FBI agent, too...
How?
Now listen...
Only she and I are going.
No matter what happens,
don't get out of the car.
R-Right.
Miss!
There's no time!
Where is she?
Thank you so much for agreeing to this exclusive interview.
Oh, it's nothing.
Anyhow, was this a good place?
Yes.
It's a really nice park, isn't it?
My usual jogging route
goes through here.
Of course, my bodyguards over there
end up having to run alongside me.
What's taking you so long, Kir?
By the way, about
what we discussed earlier...
Does this mean you accepted
my conditions for doing this interview?
Yes, of course.
I'm grateful.
All right, Kir...
Lure DJ to
the specified location.
Looks like this show
is gonna be heavy.
Shame it's not a live broadcast.
90 meters to go...
We've gotta make it!
Instead of standing here and talking,
why don't we go sit down somewhere?
Good idea.
Then, sit over on that bench.
Bench?
Sure, why not?
Yep.
Just like that...
Let's hurry and finish this up,
eh, Domon-sensei?
Huh?
Isn't that Domon-san?
Wow, it's really him!
Please shake my hand!
I don't mind.
I'm behind you all the way!
Please change Japan!
Ah, thanks.
Target sighted.
Okay to fire?
Not yet, Korn.
Too many sheep in the way.
Wait for DJ to
take a seat on the bench.
There he is!
Hey, isn't that Domon-san, the guy who's always on TV?
For real?
But where are the snipers?
They were worried about rain,
so maybe...
On the roof of that building,
over there!
And the other one must be
below the water supply tank!
Now, I'll take care of Domon-san.
You get everyone else
to somewhere safe.
No. If we just run out there, and
they start firing their rifles blindly,
they might hit the supporters gathered around him!
In order to prevent that...
And make them give up...
Umbrellas?
Now, now...
You can shake hands
after the interview.
This is really
getting on my nerves!
Don't be impatient.
Just wait.
There we go!
A sprinkler?
Say, Miss.
Do you carry a gun?
Thank you, thank you.
A gun?
Y-Yeah, I have one,
just in case...
And a silencer?
Y-Yeah, I got one.
Then can you shoot
at what I'm about to tell you,
in a way that
no one will notice?
Like I said,
handshakes afterwards.
Domon-san,
I'm rooting for you!
Please do your best!
Thank you.
Think footage like this
could help my campaign later on?
Yes, of course it will.
All right, Korn.
I've got the head.
You take his back.
I can do the head.
OK, whatever.
What's the matter, Kir? Hurry and get DJ seated.
Kir?
Domon-san,
we should start
the interview soon.
Yeah, you're right.
Excuse us, everyone.
Can I have you all move back a bit?
We're going to start
recording the interview.
The sprinklers?
Rain?
What? No way...
Seriously?
Come on, sit down...
Hurry!
Oh, thanks.
DJ, blue umbrella.
Can I shoot?
Wait.
Firing through the umbrella
will lower the likelihood of it hitting.
But that's funny...
It ain't raining over—
It started coming down here, too...
It started raining for real...
This rain sure is a blessing.
Chianti.
Kir, Korn.
Withdraw for now.
One hour from now,
wait at the designated place.
So will you tell me,
for the time being?
The synopsis of the
second assassination stage.
Oh, well.
Let's do the interview under the arbor over there.
Sure...
Now, shall we go?
Err...
Can we go, too?
Ah, sure!
Then, me too!
Me too!
Now's my chance!
H-Hey...
It's now or never...
I've got to get the tracker
and bug off her shoe!
All right, gotcha!
K-Kid...
She's seen him!
Were you... following me?
N-No...
I just happened to...
I see.
Thanks.
You picked up my shoe.
You're a lifesaver.
I mean it. Thanks.
Director!
Could you call in someone else to be the interviewer?
Sorry, but my throat's been
feeling awfully sore for a while...
Good grief.
Gin...
That news presenter saw you?
Don't tell me...
They found out we
were following her?!
No, I think I managed
to fool her somehow.
And she hasn't noticed
the tracker or the bug.
Then why didn't you
retrieve it back there?
You could've taken it off by saying you saw
something stuck on the bottom of her shoe.
Yeah...
I thought about doing that, too...
But I got a sort of...
I mean it. Thanks.
weird vibe from her...
Well, thanks to you,
we can keep tracking them.
There seems to be more to their assassination plan.
Yeah.
Rather, is it all right
to leave them be?
Isn't the TV crew she brought along
still clinging to Domon-san?
The crew isn't involved.
She made an excuse expressly
to leave the crew and go her own way.
So most likely, they're about to gather somewhere to discuss their next plan.
Now, just let the
FBI handle it from here.
The rest of you can
take the Beetle home,
but I'm going to borrow the kid.
How are you going to go after them without a car?
No problem.
My boss has personally
volunteered to chauffeur us.
Then, Doc.
You take care of the old man
and Ran-neechan.
Come up with a good excuse
for them to stay at your place.
Y-Yeah.
We'll have two or three of our people
keep an eye on you, just in case.
I'm counting on you.
Hey!
I'm sure you're aware of this,
but your first priority is to retrieve the tracker and the bug.
Don't let your foolish curiosity
and sense of justice distract you,
or you'll lose
absolutely everything.
Yeah, I know.
Shooting the sprinkler off to
make it seem like it was raining,
so that the target
and even the people around him
would naturally open their umbrellas and block the sniper...
You truly are quite
the impressive young lad.
So much so, that I'd like
to scout you for the Bureau.
This is James.
You've met him before,
haven't you, Conan-kun?
Not since that time
with the panda car, correct?
You really pulled me
out of the fire back then.
Panda?
That's right.
It's the code
James-san left us, P & A.
He was saying police car.
Huh?
How does P & A mean police car?
Spell out the & in P & A,
and it'll become clear.
Hm...
P & A...
P and AND and A...
PA-N-DA...
That's it! Panda!
So it is!
The coloring of a police car
is black and white.
Hey, get a move on!
We'll use the hostage
and escape!
H-H-Help!
W-What?
Officer!
Please help!
C'mon!
Excuse me!
I'm Takagi from the Police HQ!
Could you assist us
in apprehending that kidnapper?
Damn it...
How dare he go
and scare me like that?!
Okay.
Go along with him for now,
and turn off when you get the chance.
Good, they fell for it!
Okay, it's about time
to turn off onto a side street...
If you can't turn left,
then get in the right-hand lane!
B-But...
There's another
cop car on our right!
Then drop back!
Slow down and get behind them!
There's a cop car behind us too...
W-What?!
H-Hey!
We're completely...
surrounded by police cars!
So this old James guy
is with the FBI, too?
But why ever
are they after him?
Yasuteru Domon is not even a member
of the House of Representatives yet.
Most likely, because his father
is a well-known retired officer,
he holds influence in the political world,
is extremely charismatic,
and is almost the very
personification of justice.
There are already rumors of him being a future candidate for prime minister.
I see.
They want to nip the young sprout in the bud before he becomes a major obstacle for them.
That's their MO.
And if they kill him now,
they can make people believe
Kiriko Busujima did it.
Kiriko Busujima?
Yeah.
She's the head of the Deisankai, a group suspected of having hired a hitman to kill him.
I see.
Turn left at the next intersection.
So?
Can you hear them yet?
No, nothing.
They're still too far away.
Come to think of it,
do you know where Shu is?
No, and I'm looking
for Akai-kun as well.
You explained the situation
to him, didn't you?
Yes.
I also told him about the tracker
and the bug this kid planted.
But over the phone,
he just said...
I see.
...and hung up.
I haven't been able
to contact him since.
Ever since his sweetheart died,
he seems to have tendencies
to close himself off.
Not that he was ever
the open sort prior to that...
I can hear them.
That voice...
At around 4 PM, DJ will
pass over the bridge in his car.
That's where the
assassination will take place.
Gin...
This time, we'll have Chianti
and Korn around as support.
What? Support?!
I want to shoot.
Don't talk like that.
The guy has a custom-made
bulletproof car.
It ain't like the park job.
But...!
Plus, he'll be sitting between
two JSDF-trained bodyguards.
Even if your 7.62 mm rifle shot
through the thinnest side window,
the bullet
would never reach DJ.
Then how are we
supposed to kill him?
Are you saying we should stand
on the bridge buck naked and hitchhike,
in order to get into his car?
Ah, Chianti...
You're not far off.
Vermouth?
I'll crash this motorcycle
in front of DJ's car, forcing it to stop.
When he gets out to help me...
I'll come in from behind
and finish him off.
When that happens, the two of you take care of the bodyguards
who get out of the car with DJ.
But do you really think that cautious guy will get out of his car so easily?
Don't worry.
After seeing a woman
who's had her helmet thrown off,
and is lying on the pavement
with blood pouring down her head,
wouldn't a man with such a
deep sense of justice run over to help?
Cut the crap!
There'll be other cars
on the bridge, you know.
If a famous actress
like you exposes her face...
Don't be a fool.
The only thing exposed...
will be this face!
Kiriko Busujima
of the Deisankai!
Impressive as always, Vermouth.
You're a dead ringer.
Ah, so that's why
this bitch came along.
Where at, Gin?
We'll take DJ out... at Vain B.
Vain B...
That's the site of their
next assassination attempt?
Yes...
The time will be 4 PM.
It sounds like they plan to target Domon-san's
car as it's crossing a bridge somewhere.
So the B in Vain B
must stand for Bridge...
But we can't stop the assassination unless we figure out which bridge it is!
Quiet!
They're checking a map right now.
Maybe they'll give
the location's name away.
Korn will be here.
Chianti, you'll be here.
I'm really counting on you two.
Where might my motorcycle be?
Oh, it's behind that container.
Thanks.
Then, we'll meet up
in front of Vain B.
Say, Kir.
You're not...
...like that, are you?
Don't be silly.
Of course not.
What was that?
Well, I'll be leaving ahead of you.
Be ready to back me up
if anything goes wrong.
This assassination stage...
I've got a rather
bad feeling about it.
Leave it to me.
If things go wrong, and it looks like
you're gonna fall into their hands,
I'll jump at the chance
to put a bullet through you.
Good.
And if that happens, can you make sure to aim for my face?
If the world found out
I was involved in an assassination,
wouldn't that cause
a lot of problems?
Is something
on your mind, Vermouth?
No?
I just had a
weird feeling, that's all.
Nothing to worry about.
Well, we better get going, too.
Well, then...
I don't know
how much you know,
but will you be able to stop us?
My dear...
Silver Bullet-kun?
So we haven't the foggiest idea where they're going, then?
Nope...
And it's been getting harder
to hear them for a while now.
So the only thing we have to go on
is that it's on a bridge somewhere?
What if we call Domon-san's
electoral office and inquire?
Couldn't we find out that way?
We can ask where he's heading,
and what bridge he'll cross.
I've called them many times,
but they won't tell me anything.
Apparently I was too insistent before,
and now they think I have nefarious intentions.
Oh, dear.
It seems that until we identify the vain in Vain B,
this ill wind we're facing
won't change its direction.
Wind direction?
Vain, spelt V-A-I-N,
can mean futile, trifling,
or highly conceited.
I can't think of any place names
in Tokyo with those meanings...
No, that's not it.
It's not V-A-I-N.
It's V-A-N-E, vane!
Vane, as in the blades on
a windmill or weathercock?
Right.
At the same time, the word also means
the feather at the end of a arrow in archery.
One location around here with a name
connected to arrows and feathers is Toriya City.
In other words, Vane B is
Toriya—Bird Arrow—Bridge!
Perfect!
The assassination is at 4 PM, so we still have two hours left.
At last, we have
the upper hand against them!
There's a total of six people:
three women and three men.
Two of the women
are coming on motorcycles,
and the other four are coming in two different cars,
one of which is a Porsche 356A.
For the time being, we'll dispatch one of our cars to that bridge right away,
and take control of all roads leading to it.
That way, we can catch them
all in one fell swoop, right?
No. We'll hide all traces of our presence and approach them discretely from the shadows.
That way we can fish
them out, one by one.
Geez.
Why does the great
detective Kogoro Mouri
have to come to your house and play video games, Doc?
What's wrong with that?
You weren't doing
anything, were you?
And this detective game
is my magnum opus.
I wanted you to
be the first to play it!
A 3rd murder has taken place! You must arrive at the crime scene before the killer flees.
There sure are a lot of murders in this game...
This is the third one!
So what?
It's not like
anybody's dying for real.
But if it can convey that painful feeling to the player, I guess it has a tiny bit of meaning.
Well, I wish murders like that only happened in video games and TV shows.
The sorrow of
a person actually dying
isn't like a game or a TV show.
Anyway, where's Conan-kun?
Wasn't he with you?
A-Ah, he went
home ahead of me.
The rain started
getting really bad.
Then I guess I'll go home, too.
I'd feel bad for Conan-kun
if he's there, getting hungry.
U-Uh, no...
Don't go!
Edogawa-kun will be fine...
Don't worry.
So don't go!
Please!
Ai-kun...
Ai-chan...
All right.
If you say so, Ai-chan,
then I'll stay.
OK...
I've got a perfect line of sight.
What about you, Korn?
I can see well.
Yes.
I'm in position.
Good! All that's left now
is to wait for Kir.
Say, Vodka.
I've been hearing
a rasping noise when you talk...
No...
It's nothing.
Well, I'll probably be there
in about a few minutes.
Call me when you're there, Kir.
Roger.
Excuse me.
We need to ask you something.
Would you stop
your motorcycle?
How dreadful!
She's still breathing.
Rush her to the hospital!
OK!
R-Rena Mizunashi...
But why Rena Mizunashi?
From what you told me,
the woman on the bike
was supposed to be Vermouth, disguised as Busujima.
Yeah, I was sure, because she
was so far away from the tracker...
She changed into that leather jumpsuit and boots somewhere.
She must've left the loafer
with the tracker and the bug on it there.
But where did she...
Hey, not yet, Gin?
I hate it when
men keep me waiting!
Calm down, Chianti.
I haven't been
contacted by Kir yet.
And DJ's car hasn't
reached the bridge yet.
Yeah, whatever.
It's hard to hear you
over all this noise.
Noise?
What is it, Bro?
Pipe down.
H-Huh?
Ran-kun's playing the game...
Yeah.
But I don't see Mouri-kun?
Yeah, the main horse race
was about to start,
so he went home a bit ago.
What's up?
The signal from
the tracker disappeared.
Any sound?
Right now, I can
barely hear something,
but it's just been
muffled for a while.
Huh?!
Abort?!
You're saying to stop
when I've come this far?
Yes. I just got an OK
from that person.
We're changing the target.
Changing?
Changing the target?
So, where to?
Where's the next target?
The location is
Beika City, 5th district.
Mouri Detective Agency.
Mouri Detective Agency...
The horses have passed the fourth corner,
and the one that pulls ahead is...
Oh, what's this?
I'm getting
everything right today!
What?
Two black cars
are traveling together,
moving further and further away
from Toriya Bridge?
Are you sure
those are their cars?
Yes.
One of them
is a Porsche 356A,
and the other is a Viper.
We found an abandoned Harley,
so the woman on the bike
most likely got in one of the cars.
T-That can't be!
Because the car
of their target, Domon-san,
is still travelling
right in front of ours,
and we haven't
reached the bridge yet.
Say, where were
those two cars headed?
Which way are the cars going?
Huh? At an intersection
in Toriya City's 4th district,
they made a left, and are
now headed for Haido City?
How peculiar.
Are they going back to Haido Park,
where their shooting failed?
No!
I think they're heading for the next city over—Beika!
The tracker and the bug
have been discovered!
Leave Domon-san's car to the FBI car behind us.
Head for Beika City!
The old man's in danger!
What's with the car behind us?
I thought it was strange
that it's been following us all this time.
Leave it be.
If you get so nervous about that,
you won't be able to react
if something serious happens.
I'm extremely
thankful for your work,
so in order to become someone
worthy of your protection,
I myself need to be able to overcome this serious issue.
A serious issue?
I've just been contacted,
and it's pretty bad news.
But is it true?
What you said about Kogoro Mouri sticking
a tracker and a bug on the sole of Kir's shoe.
Yeah, I'm sure of it.
According to our reports,
he was the only person Kir came in contact with today before us.
But to suspect him just for that...
I don't know the reason,
but there's no question it was his doing.
And if someone else had planted it days earlier,
there's no way Kir wouldn't have noticed.
And if he's a great detective,
it's all the more likely he put it there.
Then, are you saying that detective's
got something to do with Kir going missing?
Keep your voice down.
The bug is still live.
I thought you crushed it
along with the tracker...
To muffle the sound,
I wrapped it in several layers of cloth
and have it hidden
in my coat pocket.
That ought to throw him off,
more or less.
I've got a few questions
to ask that detective,
while he's still
in the world of the living.
What?!
The old man went home?!
R-Right.
Ran-kun's still here, but as soon as I took my eyes off Mouri-kun...
Should I drop by the detective agency again
and convince him to come back?
No, that's a terrible idea!
Looks like he took off before our agents
could arrive at the Doctor's house.
Did something happen?
I'll explain later!
Until I contact you,
don't take a step outside your house!
Please, old man...
Be safe...
Please be safe!
S-Scary... Too scary...
Out of the first set of races,
I've won eleven in a row!
Could the god of horse racing be smiling on me?
Hey, c'mon!
Damn this
piece-of-junk TV!
This always happens
when it's important!
Ah, damn...
Hey! Old man! Old man!
Geez! This next race is about to make me 12 for 12!
The odds for the final race are...
I don't have time
to answer calls! Geez!
What a simpleton!
I took out his TV antenna,
and sure enough, he shows his face.
Something in his ear.
Good chance he's listening to that bug he planted.
Then, as he wishes,
let's let him hear our voices.
Are you listening, Kogoro Mouri?
Gin!
Don't move.
We have your back.
Before we send a bullet through that cheap suit
and into your back, I have a question for you.
It's about your
relationship with Sherry.
The tracker and the bug you planted match ones that that woman planted previously.
I won't accept it was a coincidence
as an explanation.
I'll give you ten seconds.
Should you feel like responding,
remove your left hand from
that earphone and raise it.
Earphone?
If I win this one,
I'm gonna win big!
So that's it!
The old man was listening
to the horse race on the radio.
There it is!
The Mouri Detective Agency!
10.
9.
8.
The car's roof! Hurry!
1...
Go!
A-A football?
Hey!
Who did that?!
Sorry!
I kicked it a little too hard.
W-Why, you little...!
Anyway,
how'd the horse race go?
You were listening to it
on that earphone, right?
Horse race?
I lost the last race!
You jinxed me!
Looks like he
wasn't connected, after all.
Get rid of him.
And the brat, too.
You got it.
Taking out any
potential threat, huh, Bro?
Wait!
If you kill a man with deep police connections,
despite having no proof he did anything...
You talk too much, Vermouth.
B-Bro...
Do you have...
something with that detective?
Oh, and what if I did?
Whatever.
Seems like whoever planted it
carelessly left prints on it.
After we've killed him,
and can search in his vicinity...
I'm certain we'll find
out whose work it was.
What?
Behind you at 8:00!
It's that building.
N-No way!
That's 700 yards away...
Give me that!
Shuuichi... Akai?
We meet at last...
My dear, sweet...
...nemesis.
The FBI...
Now I get it.
B-Bro...
Clear out!
But what about
the detective and that brat?
Never mind them!
Hurry!
Their cars are heading west
from Beika City, 5th district.
Tail them.
Though I imagine
they'll slip away en route...
That gunfire was from the FBI?
Yeah.
We got set up.
If he hadn't known that
we'd come there beforehand,
he couldn't have staked out
that spot on the building.
Then, Kogoro Mouri and the FBI were in this together?
I doubt it.
To the FBI, he was just bait
they could use to lure us out.
If he wasn't, would they endanger
someone they're working with like that?
They probably caught wind
that Kir was going to meet him,
and after they parted ways,
the FBI would plant the tracker
and the bug on Kir's shoe.
And even if we happened to find them,
they made it so we'd suspect him.
We'll leave it at that for now,
since this Kogoro Mouri seems
to be your favorite detective...
Thanks.
Rather, the problem is Kir.
Don't tell me the FBI...
Yeah.
I'm certain that
she's fallen into their hands.
I don't think Kir will talk so easily,
but I'll still pull out all the stops to find and retrieve her.
Oh? Do you have
something particular in mind?
I have any number of ideas.
And I still don't believe Kogoro Mouri
is completely in the clear.
Haido General Hospital
Did you see it?
This morning on TV.
I did indeed.
You mean the news that Domon-san
decided not to run as a candidate in the election this year, right?
Just because suspicion surfaced that his
father had an affair while he was in office...
Though that was twenty years ago.
It seems Domon-san agreed to that exclusive interview
under the condition that Nichiuri TV
keep that fact under wraps.
But he only made the deal
with Rena Mizunashi.
I take it she never
told the TV station.
If they had known he was such an honest man
that he'd step down over something like that,
they needn't
have tried to kill him.
Speaking of them,
I just wish we'd managed to capture two or three more of their agents.
I could've taken out
that guy's legs,
but I limited myself
to only shooting his bulletproof vest.
If I had rashly
immobilised his legs
and caused a gunfight
to break out in town,
innocent people
could have been injured.
In which case,
wasn't our top priority to make them think that we, the FBI, planted the tracker and the bug?
You're right, but...
And our lead to them
still hasn't been lost.
She's stable, but she has yet to regain consciousness.
Looks like we'll just have
to wait for her to recover.
We're having her hospitalisation
here kept under wraps.
But if a news presenter were to disappear all of a sudden,
the TV station
isn't going to keep quiet.
It'll be fine. Looks like...
Looks like that
kid's got it well in hand.
That boy again...
Just who is he?
A detective.
My favourite...
Hi, is this the HR Manager?
It's me, Rena Mizunashi.
I'm so sorry, but I need
to take some time off work...
You were lucky.
Detective Mouri, whom you were in concert with, fell under their suspicion.
But just when it seemed they
were going to assassinate him,
you got there in the
nick of time and saved him.
Well, since he predicted
that would happen,
waited in position to snipe them,
and made it look like the FBI
planted the tracker and the bug,
you should be grateful
to that Akai person.
Yeah, I am.
And to you for hiding Ran
at the Doc's place.
But that aside,
are you sure he'll be okay?
It doesn't seem like anyone's guarding Detective Mouri.
It's safer for him that way,
so I turned down the FBI's escort.
After all that work trying to make them think he and the FBI aren't connected...
So if I carelessly
let them guard him,
they would likely think
he's connected with the FBI,
which would put him
in needless danger.
Yeah, but...
Besides, we still have one card
that we managed to take from them.
That news presenter,
Rena Mizunashi-san, right?
It sounds like she's unconscious
in a hospital.
Yeah. The FBI apparently has her under 24-hour surveillance,
waiting for her
to regain consciousness.
But if they find out
she's in that hospital...
It'll be fine. I called the TV station with her voice,
and requested
an extended leave.
There's no way they'd think
she's actually hospitalized.
Anyway, don't let your guard down.
They're probably frantically
searching for her right now.
Yeah...
I figured they'd use any means
necessary to get what they want.
Dear Ran Mouri
Don't tell me, it's a...
Love letter?!
Maybe the culprit
felt the same way we do.
Hey, it was written
in your diary, right?
And this Nagai guy
was carrying a shinai, right?
Ran said she wanted
to tell him the truth, but...
Did she mean about me?
On the next Conan: