Victory, truth, and shocking evidence.
These all give you a strong impulse to move forward!
A cool, reserved, and smart girl.
She looks like Haibara and brings along an unexpected case!
Seeing through to the one and only truth...
I look like a child, but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
Yaiba Kick!
See?
Don't I sound like him?
You do! You do!
Genta-kun!
Stop talking and clean up!
Stop!
There you are, Mole Alien!
K-Kamen Yaiba!
Hey!
Kojima Genta!
Yes?
Genta-kun...
Stop fooling around and finish cleaning!
If you don't cut it out, I'm gonna tell the teacher!
Honestly, acting like an elementary schooler can be tiring...
But it kind of leaves me feeling less nervous.
Genta-kun, come on!
Well, being at peace is the best.
Let's hurry up and finish.
This is terrible!
Terrible, terrible!
Thise oss tewwibel...
It hurts...
Are you okay, Mitsuhiko?
Why are you in such a hurry?
It's a case!
A case!
A case?
A 4th grade girl vanished into thin air!
Vanished?
Actually, her older sister and my sister are classmates.
When I was younger, her sister would bring her along whenever she visited my house...
So we're acquaintances.
She called me up out of the blue last night...
And made me promise to walk home with her today.
Class 4-A
However, when I went to her classroom...
Everyone said she didn't come to school today.
She probably just caught a cold or something.
That can't be!
I called her house, but no one picked up.
Also, she...
She said she had a favor to ask...
And that I should invite the rest of the gang to walk home with us.
"The gang"?
You mean the Detective Boys?
She said she'd explain in detail on the way home.
She seemed really worried about something.
Hey, what's her name?
What's she like?
She's in class 4-A, and her name is Amemiya Shouko-san.
She has brown hair...
Brown hair?
Wavy...
Bob cut...
Yeah!
She's kind of like Haibara-san.
It can't be...
Super Secret of the Road to School
(Part 1)
Super Secret of the Road to School:
Part 1!
Okay, has everyone finished cleaning?
Kobayashi-sensei!
Jeez...
And?
What did the school say?
Did they get in touch with her?
About that...
Who are you talking about?
Amemiya Shouko-san in class 4-A.
Oh, Amemiya Shouko-san?
She was supposed to have the day off.
She had to go to her grandfather's funeral in Kyushu.
But, yesterday...
She said, "I'm not going to skip school tomorrow."
So we were all a bit worried.
She probably decided to go after all.
Her teacher, Hirayama-sensei, thought the same thing.
Hirayama-sensei?
Was there a teacher with that name?
I've never heard of him before.
It's no surprise that you kids don't know him.
He's a new teacher who started two days ago.
The previous teacher got into a car accident, so we needed a replacement.
Car accident?
Well, I think he'll introduce himself at the assembly on Monday morning.
Sensei!
When was that accident?
It was this past Monday.
Two days after the assassination attempt.
Um, can't you contact the girl's parents in Kyushu?
I think we'll be able to contact them soon.
When we called her grandfather's house in Kyushu...
We were told that they should return in the evening.
Anyway, I'm going to lock the classroom now.
You should all head home.
Okay, we will!
After we check out classroom 4-A.
Class 4-A
Even a hat as ugly as this...
Can look nice if an incredibly cute girl wears it, don't you think?
Give it back.
Let's see...
By putting together everyone's opinions...
Amemiya Shouko-san is smart, studious, quiet, and cool.
She speaks only when necessary...
And is popular among the girls, but at odds with the boys.
Just like Ai-chan!
B-But Haibara-san is liked by the boys too!
Thanks.
No, no!
Anyway, Haibara...
Why are you wearing a hat?
Isn't that Conan's?
I thought it'd be nice to look like this every once in a while.
Yeah, you look very boyish!
You look so cool!
But still, I'm asking why she's wearing Conan's hat.
Is there some rule that says she can't wear Conan-kun's hat?
Well...
If that girl is like Haibara...
The probability that she was tricked and kidnapped by some weirdo is low.
Either she really was involved in an accident, or...
That new teacher is one of them...
And mistook her for me when he kidnapped her.
No way.
It's only been a week since that time.
It's too soon for payback.
You think so? For them, this is rather slow...
If they realized you were the one who set up the tracker and bug...
Shouldn't you be worried?
As for this hat...
It's a precautionary move...
Right?
Yeah. But if that's the case...
Why is he in charge of the 4th graders?
It definitely doesn't make any sense.
If it were them...
They'd go directly for my classroom.
Also, the girl's strange behavior these past few days bothers me.
Yeah.
Like the way she'd avoid her friends and walk home by herself when school ended.
When we asked her friends about it, they said she wouldn't tell them why.
What if she sensed some sort of danger?
No, that's not it.
If she felt she was being targeted...
She'd only move about with her parents or friends around...
And she would've gone to Kyushu.
That's true.
But if she's the type who bottles up all of her fears and concerns inside herself...
Then it's a different story.
Just like someone I know.
Look who's talking.
Haibara-san!
Conan-kun!
It's over here! Over here!
Amemiya
This is Amemiya Shouko-san's house.
There weren't any traces of an accident on the way here.
I wonder where she went...
Maybe she just played hooky so she could stay and play games.
After all, she's by herself today, right?
Looks like no one's home.
I think we can probably go in for now.
I came here before, and I saw it during that time...
The key's hiding place.
Here it is.
Isn't that wrong?
Yeah, just barging into someone's house.
Please excuse me...
This is Mitsuhiko.
I'm not a robber.
Please excuse me!
I guess no one's home, huh...
Excuse me.
Is she the one on the right side of the picture?
Yeah, that's her.
You're right!
She does look like Ai-chan!
There's something else that's similar...
Something about her that's similar to Haibara-san...
Hey, are their voices similar at all?
Uh, no...
Her voice isn't similar...
She also doesn't speak with such biting words.
I'm so sorry to hear that.
Do you think she decided to come home?
W-Who are you guys?
Look who's talking, who are you?!
I'm Amemiya Shouko-san's teacher at Teitan Elementary School...
Hirayama Bungo.
A teacher?
Please don't scare us like that!
Huh? You have a bruise on your right eye!
I fell down the stairs this morning.
Your glasses are sliding off.
The nose rest on these glasses is broken.
What an irresponsible teacher.
But anyway, who are you guys?
Are you the neighbor's kids?
We're students at the school where you teach, Teitan Elementary.
From class 1-B.
But why are you all here?
The same reason as you.
We were worried and came to look for her...
For Amemiya Shouko-san from class 4-A.
I knew where the key was hidden...
So, we came into the house to look for her on our own.
We're sorry.
But there was no one home.
I see.
Maybe she went to Kyushu after all.
Hey, did Amemiya-san tell you she was going to be alone tonight?
But she told me she'd be eating breakfast and dinner at her neighbor Miike-san's house.
Then she's probably there!
All right, let's go check it out!
Let's go!
Wait, Genta-kun!
Please wait!
I'm going on ahead!
Original Broadcast Date:
January 23rd, 2006
Based on manga:
Vol. 49 Files 5-7
Amemiya Shouko-san isn't here?
No, she was supposed to come tonight...
I saw her rush to school with her backpack this morning.
This is definitely a case.
What should we do?
Did something happen to Shouko-chan?
She didn't come to school today.
Did the school call you?
Well...
I was out shopping with some of my neighbors earlier.
I just got home a little while ago.
On top of that, my husband is at work, so there hasn't been anyone at home.
I don't know if there was a phone call or not...
But it makes you wonder...
The rest of Shouko-san's family went to Kyushu for her grandfather's funeral.
Why did only she stay here...
To be taken care of by you, her neighbor?
I don't know the reason...
But, it seems that Shouko-chan begged her parents as she cried...
To let her stay.
C-Cried?
Even when I saw her this morning...
She looked like she hadn't slept a lot.
Maybe she had a fight with her parents?
At that time, did you notice anything strange about her behavior?
Something different from usual?
There was one thing.
When I asked why she was up so early...
She;'said she was going to a convenience store.
A convenience store?
So she did run away after fighting with her parents!
I see.
She went to the convenience store to stock up on food.
No way!
But she didn't seem like the type who would run away.
And, you are?
Forgive me.
I'm Amemiya Shouko-san's teacher, Hirayama.
Oh, the one who just started!
Yes, but I'm only substituting until the teacher who got into a car accident gets better.
Anyway, if you don't hear from me in 30 minutes, call the police!
We'll definitely find her by then!
W-Who exactly are you?
Edogawa Conan.
And...
The Detective Boys!
Let's go!
Yeah!
Elementary school student Amemiya Shouko-chan?
I don't know...
I just started working here, so I don't really know anyone by name.
We have a picture of her.
Yabatake
She looks like this!
Oh! That child came early this morning.
R-Really?!
But Mitsuhiko, when were you able to take her picture?
Earlier, when we went into her house...
I took a picture of the photo in the entrance with my cell phone.
So, do you remember what she bought?
Um, I think it was...
Fruit juice in a small plastic bottle...
Milk in a paper carton...
And an exacto knife you can strap onto a cell phone.
Juice, milk, and an exacto knife?
With only drinks, won't she get hungry?
Buying an exacto knife...
Was she trying to make a craft at school?
Well, now the possibility that she ran away is gone.
Was there any other strange behavior?
Lets see...
Oh yeah, she stayed in the kitchen goods aisle for a while.
When I asked her if I could help her find something...
She ran to a different section without answering.
I wonder what she wanted to buy...
Paper Plates
Toothpicks
Chopsticks
Ah! She probably wanted toothpicks!
My dad always tells me to go buy him toothpicks!
That's not something you would buy before school.
It's not like you would go to school while chewing one.
Oh, that girl; I just spoke with those kids about her.
Is that so?
Hey, that teacher...
We should be careful.
In front of us, he has a friendly face...
But as soon as our backs are turned, he's glaring at us.
Yeah...
Of course.
"Of course"?
Anyway, for now, we should search for Shouko.
Huh?
It's you guys!
Yumi-san!
It's the mini-patrol car lady!
What are you guys doing here?
Aren't your homes the other way?
I see.
Before this elementary school student, Amemiya Shouko, went missing...
The last place she was seen is this convenience store.
Wasn't there a call to the police?
About strange people lurking around, or a car accident...
There hasn't been a single call.
We did have a mountain of calls about illegal parking, but...
Illegal parking?
It's when you park a car or bike in a place you're not supposed to.
It's a bad thing!
I'm heading to one of those places right now.
Then, why did you stop at the convenience store?
Did you get hungry?
That's not it!
I came to buy this mask.
Yumi-san, do you have a cold?
I'm heading to three places in the neighborhood...
And I need masks in all of them.
Is there a strong odor or something?
Yes, in one of the places.
It's right next to the trash.
People have been throwing their trash out long before the collection date...
So it's become a feeding area for crows.
It got smelly once they started scattering trash around.
I guess it might be better to take care of illegal trash dumping first.
What about the other two places?
The second place is an unused garage.
I don't know if it's full of dust or something, but I can't stop sneezing whenever I go there.
Even when I was there yesterday, my nose wouldn't stop running.
Nothing like that used to happen when I went there.
And the last place?
To tell you the truth...
It's near my old college boyfriend's house.
I dumped him in a bad way, so I don't want him to recognize me.
That's why you want to hide your face with the mask?
Was he that bad of a man?
No. He was really handsome, but...
He was way too childish.
The story of me and my ex doesn't matter right now!
You're the one who brought it up...
Well, the third place is near a Pachinko game center.
Note: Pachinko is a Japanese game that's a cross between pinball and a video slot machine.
Customers who couldn't park their cars and bikes in the parking lot are parking illegally.
All right?
Yes, ma'am.
More importantly...
That missing girl has me worried.
Just in case, will you contact police headquarters...
And check if there have been any accidents around here?
I will.
It seems there weren't any accidents after all.
Then where did she go?
Hey, Ai-chan, do you know?
If you're really like that girl, maybe you know where she is.
I don't...
Oh, yeah!
Mitsuhiko, didn't you say there was something else that Haibara and that girl have in common?
I'm trying really hard to remember, but...
How can you eat at a time like this?!
What's the problem?
I get hungry when I think too hard.
Oh, that's right...
That girl opened her fruit juice outside the store right after she bought it...
And chugged it down all at once.
Was she that thirsty?
But her house is near here.
She bought fruit juice in a small plastic bottle, milk in a paper carton, and an exacto knife.
She stayed in the kitchen goods aisle.
Her personality is similar to Haibara's.
M-Maybe...
Conan-kun?
NEXT CONAN'S HINT
Allergies
Just as I thought.
Hey, is she really here?
C-Could it be that Shouko-san...
Was hit by a car?!
Super Secret of the Road to School
(Part 2)
Next Conan: Super Secret of the Road to School (Part 2).