Victory, truth, and shocking evidence.
These all give you a strong impulse to move forward!
A girl who suddenly disappeared...
And a dark shadow that looms over us while looking for her.
Seeing through to the one and only truth...
I look like a child, but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
The intense battle with the Black Organization is over.
Just as our school lives were returning to normal...
We found out-that Amemiya Shouko, a 4th grader from Teitan Elementary, had vanished into thin air.
Furthermore, the girl is a lot like Haibara.
Could the Black Organization be in our elementary school?
Elementary school student Amemiya Shouko-chan?
So, do you remember what she bought?
Um, I think it was...
Hey, that teacher...
We should be careful.
In front of us, he has a friendly face...
But as soon as our backs are turned, he's glaring at us.
That girl opened her fruit juice outside the store right after she bought it...
And chugged it all down at once.
She bought fruit juice in a small plastic bottle, milk in a paper carton, and an exacto knife.
She stayed in the kitchen goods aisle.
Her personality is similar to Haibara's.
M-Maybe...
Super Secret of the Road to School
(Part 2)
Super Secret of the Road to School:
Part 2!
Conan-kun?
Wait, what are you doing, Conan-kun?!
W-What the hell is he doing?
Conan-kun!
Just as I thought.
There's no mistake about it.
What are you doing, Conan?
If you want a plastic bottle, I'll give you mine.
Anyway, I'll contact police headquarters and tell them to locate the missing girl.
Wait!
Before you do that...
Can we go to the place I just thought of?
The place you thought of?
Then, you figured it out?
You know where the girl is?
Yeah.
I don't know if she'll really be there, but why don't we go anyway?
After we stop by the pharmacy.
Ph-Pharmacy?
Oh, and Manager-san...
Yes?
The hot water beside the register—can I have some?
Jeez...
Thanks to Conan, this is my second time cleaning today.
Hey, Genta-kun!
Stop fooling around and finish cleaning!
It's the second time I've heard that too...
Ayumi-chan...
Did you get it?
See?
Thanks.
Then, let's go!
Drugs—Cosmetics—General Goods
Beika Pharmacy
Your total is 470 yen.
Would you like it in a bag?
No, it's fine like this.
Thank you.
What did you buy?
Powdered milk in a stick for babies.
P-Powdered milk?
What are you going to do with that?
Ayumi-chan...
Can I have the plastic bottle Genta drank from?
The water from the convenience store is warm, just like you wanted.
Thanks.
Now, with this hot water...
Pour in the powdered milk...
Shake and mix it well...
Hey, Conan...
What are you going to do with that?
You're not planning on raising a baby, are you?
Yeah, that's it exactly.
But, it's not a regular baby.
Please wait a minute!
We're searching for the 4th grader...
Amemiya Shouko-san, who went missing on the way to school!
Can't you just forget about the baby?
That girl probably couldn't forget about it either.
Now, let's have Yumi-san lead the way!
To where she was planning to take care of illegal parking...
The unused garage.
O-Okay, that's fine...
Hey, would that girl really be in this kind of place?
This garage is really dirty, isn't it?
It's filled with dust.
Yeah, yeah. That's why...
You have quite a sensitive nose.
It wasn't always this bad...
Yeah.
Yumi-san...
Do you have any pets at home?
I do.
I have two dogs, Star and Hachi.
Do people you know only have dogs?
Y-Yeah...
Come to think of it, that's true.
Then, you haven't noticed...
That you have an allergy.
A-Allergy?
It's probably not dust that's making you sneeze.
Conan-kun, where are you going?
All right, let's follow him!
W-Wait!
I'm coming too!
Wait, you guys!
I'll go after them.
Miyamoto-san...
I-Is everyone okay?
Yumi-san!
Over here, over here!
Wait, my butt seems to be stuck...
They're so cute!
C-Cute?
I think these guys were the cause of your sneezing.
The cause of my sneezing was...
Cats?!
Yep.
Not dust...
But the hair these guys shed.
So, I'm allergic to cats?!
Probably.
But this place is pretty big, and I don't see any hair.
Cat hair is really tiny and light.
So, even if it's floating in the air for a long time, you wouldn't notice it.
I see!
That was the other thing Mitsuhiko-kun said Ai-chan and that girl have in common...
It's that they both love animals!
Yes, yes!
That's it!
That must be why the girl wanted to walk home with us today.
She wanted to show us the kittens and ask us to find owners for them.
Yeah.
Most likely, her parents hate cats or animals...
So she couldn't ask them.
She secretly took care of them by herself.
Look.
She made a milk dish by cutting off the bottom of the plastic bottle that she bought.
I see.
At the convenience store...
Paper plates and paper cups were sold out.
So, she used the bottom of the plastic bottle as a substitute.
Right.
Then, the reason that girl didn't go to Kyushu, but stayed in Tokyo...
Was because she had to give milk to these kittens.
In that case, her lack of sleep makes sense.
She was probably worrying about the cats to the point where she couldn't sleep.
Well, that's not the only reason for her lack of sleep.
Why the hell are you pouring it out?!
Shouko-san went through a lot of trouble to get that milk!
Because...
It was the milk that was the problem.
Cats don't have the enzyme that enables them to differentiate between types of milk.
Herbivorous cows and omnivorous cats have different minerals in their mothers' milk.
If you keep giving them cow milk...
They'll get sick and stop drinking altogether.
So, if you dilute powdered milk for human babies twice...
And warm it to body temperature, which is around 38° C...
Note: 38° Celsius is 100.4' Fahrenheit.
They're drinking, they're drinking!
She was also worried because the kittens wouldn't drink the milk.
But, that's because she didn't know the milk was making them sick.
And, of course...
She only did this because there are no pet shops nearby to buy cat milk.
And?
The girl, Amemiya Shouko-san...
Where is she?
That's right...
It's strange.
I thought she would be here with a worried look on her face.
Conan!
I don't know what's going on, but...
Let's go!
Again?
Jeez, not my butt again!
Where are we going?
Is it here?
My butt hurts...
There was another one, huh?
So, there were three of them!
But, why is he the only one outside?
What is it this time?
Where is it?
This is...
What're those?
They're the broken shards from a car's headlight.
Most likely, a car crashed into this pole, causing the headlight to shatter.
The cross section on the debris is still new so it's probably from a recent accident.
But, I don't think there have been any calls about an accident in this area.
Hey, look!
This...
Isn't it human blood?
There's a trail leading from the pole to the garage.
And here!
There are brake tracks...
C-Could it be that Shouko-san...
Was hit by a car?!
Well, there's no way to tell for sure...
But it's a definite possibility.
But the possibility that she was hit by a car is high.
She probably had an encounter with a car when she ran out into the road...
To chase after a kitten that...
jumped out of her arms when she was holding it.
Th-Then...
It was a hit-and-run?
If that was the case, he would have left the girl and drove away.
There still hasn't been anyone reporting an accident...
So there must not have been any eyewitnesses.
Then, where did Shouko-san go?
Where does this trail of blood lead to?
The blood...
It goes in both directions!
This must be the driver's blood.
If that's the case, then maybe...
Yumi-san...
Will you ask around hospitals in the area?
Thank you very much.
Oh yeah, wasn't Araide's place around here?
Isn't that you, Conan-kun?
Hello!
What happened?
Since you're together with everyone...
Hey, Sensei...
Do you know if the owner of the damaged car that's parked in front of the hospital is here?
About that man...
He has a slight concussion...
And he needed three stitches, so he's in bed resting.
Did he mention anything about a girl?
Well, he came in carrying her saying...
"I accidentally crashed into her, please help me!"
While covered in blood.
C-Covered in blood?
No, no.
It was the man who was covered in blood.
As for the girl...
She's sleeping in another bed...
With Hikaru-san to watch over her.
Is she injured?
No...
She's just exhausted due to her lack of sleep.
It seems she hadn't slept very well last night.
When she woke up earlier...
She said something about being hit by the car and losing consciousness...
But quickly fell back asleep.
You should've contacted the school!
I asked for her phone number just in case...
But, she didn't answer, and fell back asleep before I could even ask her name.
On top of that, her backpack was locked in the man's car.
So, I decided to ask questions after she woke up...
Since she was sleeping so comfortably.
But, I'm so glad...
That Amemiya-san is all right.
T-Truly...
W-What?
Since this morning...
I didn't know what I'd do if something had happened.
Hey, don't cry, Sensei.
Shouldn't you hurry and inform the school about this?
Th-That's right!
Uh, the phone...
Where's the phone...
Seriously, pull yourself together.
It seems the teacher isn't one of them.
Yeah. Looks like it.
Here it is!
Hello, this is Hirayama.
But, what was it?
That expression, as if he was glaring at us.
That's probably because he has bad eyesight.
He was squinting his eyes to try to see better.
Then, he's wearing glasses made from an old prescription?
Don't you remember what he said...
About falling down the stairs this morning?
A bruise above his eye means that, when he fell...
His contact lens fell out and either broke or got lost.
So, he decided to wear his old glasses in the meantime.
Remember?
When he tried to touch the bruise...
He accidentally hit his glasses with his finger, making them slip.
That's proof that he usually wears contacts.
You're saying that it seems like a really foolish thing to do...
But, if he was with them...
Isn't there a possibility that he did that so we would let our guard down?
Yeah, that's what I thought at first...
But, I became sure that he had nothing to do with them when he asked...
Who are you guys?
Are you the neighbor's kids?
It made my suspicions vanish.
But, how does that prove anything?
Usually, in that situation, an elementary school teacher would ask...
"Which school do you go to?"
Because, at that time...
We were all wearing backpacks.
Even if he was one of them, and pretending to be a teacher...
It's just too foolish.
That's how I understood.
He must've had bad eyesight and was missing his contacts, so he couldn't see clearly.
But, he might've just been acting like a careless person...
There's no need to pretend to be that complicated.
And if he slips on little things like that...
He can't be an enemy.
I'm more worried about the ones that sneak behind our backs without showing themselves.
The ones like Vermouth.
Something like that really happened today?
I'm so glad you were able to find that Shouko-san girl!
Uh, sure...
Ah, shoot.
So?
What happened to the cats?
The new teacher took one of them...
And Araide-sensei took the other two.
It seems he's going to try to find a patient who will take them in.
Hey, hey... Dad.
Why don't we take one of the cats?
Don't even think about it!
It would just claw everything apart and mess up the office!
Besides, if we got a pet cat...
We'd be just like that woman who thinks so highly of herself.
Are you talking about Mom?
I don't know, maybe...
Besides, I don't want to have even more freeloaders living here.
Honestly...
That's right.
Speaking of new things, today at my school...
Hey, Conan-kun.
Conan-kun, are you listening?
He fell asleep?
He's probably exhausted after all that happened today.
So?
A new teacher came to your school too?
No, it was a student.
He's a transfer student.
He looks a lot like that announcer, Mizunashi Rena-san.
He says it's just a coincidence, though.
He wants to come over to our house some time, so I'll invite him tomorrow!