Success! Integrity! Evidence and its impact!
An endless drive to become the best!
A girlfriend who stormed out after a fight over trivial matters,
and a sad reunion at the place where they first met.
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
So? When's he coming over?
He said he'd get changed before stopping by!
Who?
Didn't I tell you?
The new transfer student who wants to visit Dad's office!
Hey, Ran! Let's get going!
Ah... Right!
A transfer student?
Oh, right!
You were asleep when I was talking about him.
Hey...
Why would he want to come here?
Why not?
Ooh, you little brat!
You're jealous of Ran's new boyfriend!
Oh, Sonoko...
N-No, I'm not...
Then what?
I bet you're going to snitch to Shin'ichi-kun about it!
I am Shin'ichi.
Too bad!
He has no interest in me!
Hello, Ran, dear. You're home early.
I know you just got in, but could you kindly make me a cup of coffee?
My brain cells just won't wake up without the coffee you brew for me.
Is that an impression of someone?
Is Uncle all right?
Oh, it's just the spoiled rich girl!
S-Spoiled?!
Dad, the kid I told you about isn't stopping by until later!
Is he coming here to see Uncle?
That's right! He's a huge fan of Dad!
Does that make you feel better, four-eyes?
Damn you, Sonoko!
A big fan of the old man, is he?
My cool first impression was wasted on you philistines!
But...
Were you seriously trying to act cool for a high school boy?
Boy...
Boy?!
I thought you said this new student looked like Rena Mizunashi-san!
Rena Mizunashi?!
I told you, he's a guy!
But you kept calling him that cute kid, so I thought...
No, Uncle! Don't let him in!
Ah, looks like he's here!
Come in!
Uncle!
Ouch.
S-S-Sorry... I tripped over something...
N-Nice to meet you, Detective Mouri! It's an honor to be here!
Um...
That's Conan-kun, a kid who's staying with us.
Huh?
Like I said, he's a kid who's staying with us.
The four-eyed brat.
Your glasses!
Oh, thanks!
This is my dad.
E-Excuse me...
Nice to meet you, Detective Mouri!
Eisuke Hondo
Teitan High Class 2-B · Transfer Student
My name is Eisuke Hondo!
Howdy.
It's an honor to meet...you...
Ow!
Ouch...
What's with this guy?
I'm starting to understand why you keep calling him a kid, Ran.
He's just a little clumsy, that's all!
I'm not clumsy, I'm unlucky!
I drop my toast and the buttered side always lands on the floor!
I go camping with friends and the mosquitoes all go for me!
And in a group photo, I'm always the one with my eyes closed!
I can only conclude that God has it in for me!
If you were a girl, I bet the guys would be all over you.
That's why I wanted to meet you, Detective Mouri!
Huh? Why?
I wanted you to share some of your luck with me!
Luck?
You're so lucky you solve cases in your sleep!
God must be speaking through you!
Er... God?!
Hey! I know people call him Sleeping Kogoro,
but he's not really asleep when he solves those cases!
He gets relaxed, that's all!
But he always turns down interviews by saying he doesn't remember anything,
and tells reporters to talk to the police!
Come to think of it, me too...
He's just modest! Of course he remembers everything!
Right, Dad?
Y-Yeah, sure...
I want to see Sleeping Kogoro in action! Please?
I dunno.
This is a whole other form of trouble.
Er, excuse me.
Atsushi Misumi (32)
Client
Is this the Mouri Detective Agency?
Yes it is!
Aah! My breasts! He touched my breasts!
H-Have you come to ask Detective Mouri for help?
Yes...
Mouri-san! Looks like you got a client!
Awesome!
Again?
Not again...
M-My nose...
Is that natural?
Er... Please ignore him...
Oh... Sure.
You want me to find your missing girlfriend?
That's right.
We live together, and when I woke up this morning she was gone.
She must've left because of the fight we had last night...
If it's okay with you, could you tell me what that fight was about?
Sure, but...
Hey!
Leave us alone, will you?
That's okay! It was just a typical quarrel!
Was it?
Go on...
Right.
I've been busy with work lately and haven't been able to spend much time with her.
That was how the fight started.
But after the usual exchange of words...
The problem is, you've changed and I haven't!
We can't go back to the way we were when we first met!
After that, she went to bed without saying anything.
When I woke up this morning, she and the car were gone.
Typical quarrel, all right.
It doesn't sound like anything serious...
She just ran off.
I'm sure she'll come back after a couple of days!
I can't wait that long!
Tomorrow I have to turn in a major proposal at work, but I left my papers in the car she took!
I need to find her by the end of the day!
And I'm worried about her too, of course.
I see.
Well, I understand your situation, but I need more to go on.
Hey...
Did your girlfriend know you'd left your work in the car?
I think so...
Then maybe she's playing games with you!
Playing games?
Maybe she wants him to find her...
at a place where they played board games together!
B-Board games?
He said they can't go back, right?
That's like a board game!
We weren't allowed to go back any spaces
in the board game I played with Ran-neechan the other day!
You play board games with this four-eyed brat, Ran?
It's a video game called Pillage Street.
Conan-kun's good at it.
Are you stupid?
The man meant that they can't go back to the way they were when they fell in love...
Hey, maybe she went to the place where they first met!
Could be! She hoped he'd come looking for her and they'd rekindle the spark!
Anyway, Misumi-san...
What is it?
Where did you two meet?
Right...
It was at a ski resort in Gunma...
I told you not to tag along!
Are you all right, Eisuke-kun?
See? I'm always the first person to catch a cold!
Look at that snow. I think Sonoko made the right choice by not coming...
Gunma? It'll be covered in snow this time of the year.
Sorry, Ran. Do you mind if I don't come?
Good decision.
Hey! Don't spray your germs on Ran!
I'm fine! I feel warm and cozy!
Me too...
Did you two really meet on this freezing mountain?
Yes.
She was driving up here with three of her friends.
Her car stalled while she was taking a shortcut through here,
and I happened to pass by in my car.
What's going on?
Our car has broken down.
And there's next to no cars coming through here
so it's great you're here.
So the place where we met is right ahead of us, on this street.
Hey!
Behind those trees!
That's my car!
Whew.
Case closed.
Ami! Ami!
Hey, Ami! Are you all right?
Huh? What's wrong?
I'm gonna take a look!
Ah, wait...
Duct tape sealing the cracks of the doors on both sides...
and a charcoal stove on the front passenger seat.
Suicide?!
The key! Do you have a spare key?
I-I do!
Damn! The door's sealed with duct tape! I can't open it...
We'll have to call the police and have them pry open the door...
Move back.
W-Where'd you get the bat?!
I had some sports equipment in the trunk of my car.
Ami! Hang in there!
A-Ami!
Ami!
Tear off the duct tape that's keeping the door closed!
Oh, right!
The pieces are really stuck on.
I can't get them all off...
I know!
I should have something in the glove compartment...
Ami! Hang in there, Ami!
Ami!
I'm afraid she's already dead.
Oh, no...
Ami! Ami!
Ami... Hey! Ami!
I'll call for an ambulance and the Gunma police.
I already called them for you!
They said they'd send your greatest sidekick!
Oh, no, not...
...him again.
Since when are you my sidekick?!
Oh, please, Mouri-san!
Every case we've worked on together has been solved!
That's a perfect arrest record! 100%!
And your cases without me?
Oh, uh, well, um...
He's still not ready to fly solo.
Enough with the details! Let's start the investigation!
Today I'm going to get Sleeping Kogoro on tape!
Don't count on it.
Look at the car we pulled the deceased from.
The doors are lined with duct tape from the inside.
And there's a charcoal stove on the front passenger seat.
We had to break through the windshield with a baseball bat to get the woman out,
and that was the only way in or out of the car.
This is a case of carbon monoxide poisoning by burning charcoal inside an enclosed space.
It's clearly suicide.
You mean we won't get to see Sleeping Kogoro at work?
Who's the kid?
Just a teenage fan who tagged along with me today.
Your fan?
Yeah!
I'm Eisuke Hondo! Nice to meet you!
This is so exciting! I've never met a real police detective before!
Oh, er, I'm Yamamura of the Gunma Police.
Feel free to call me Yama-san.
A perfect pair.
Yamamura-san!
Y-Yes?
We found traces of a sleeping drug in this can of coffee inside the car.
Sleeping drug?
She must've taken it so she'd sleep while the carbon monoxide killed her.
I see!
In that case...
That lady must be a really restless sleeper!
She was found sleeping peacefully in the driver's seat!
That's not what I saw!
The waist of her jacket was all wrinkly, like it'd been twisted up!
That's very irritating while sitting, so she normally would have straightened it out.
Which means it got all wrinkly while she was asleep, doesn't it?
Come to think of it, that's true...
And look at the driver's seat!
Ran-neechan, come over here for a sec.
Oh, sure.
Can you bend down and pretend to drive?
Er, okay...
Like this?
See? That woman was about the same height as Ran-neechan.
Isn't the seat too far back?
She probably moved it back so she'd have more room to sleep.
The brat's right.
The seat's pretty far back for a woman that size to have been driving.
She probably moved it back so she could put the charcoal burner on the floor in front of her.
I see.
She had it in front of her at first,
but when it got too hot, she moved it to the passenger seat!
Hey... Who are you?
Oh... I'm Atsushi Misumi. I'm the boyfriend of the woman who killed herself in the car.
Oh, my. I'm so sorry...
Was she a restless sleeper?
She did toss and turn a lot...
I see...
Then it's suicide, no question!
Looks like it...
No.
This is a murder, skillfully set up to look like a suicide.
And the culprit is probably...
...that guy.
But I don't get it.
How could he exit a totally sealed car?
The car was completely sealed off with duct tape.
He drugged her and lit the charcoal stove...
What trick did he use?
But doesn't it strike you as odd?
Huh? What?
Next to Mouri-san...
Oh, you mean Conan-kun?
Next Conan: