Success! Integrity! Evidence and its impact!
An endless drive to become the best!
Even twisted love can’t get through this!
A locked room murder in a car sealed from the inside.
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Created by
Gosho Aoyama
“Detective Conan”
Serialized in Shogakukan’s
‘Weekly Shonen Sunday’
Planning
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Character Design
Mari Tominaga
Art Director
Yasutada Kato
Director of Photography
Takahisa Ogawa
Sound Directors
Yasuo Uragami
Motoi Izawa
Music
Katsuo Ono
Opening Theme
“Shoudou”
Performed by
Lyrics
Koshi Inaba
Music
Tak Matsumoto
Editor
Terumitsu Okada
Story Editor
Jun'ichi Iioka
Color Key
Fusako Nakao
Executive Producer
Makoto Moriwaki
Planning Support
Shin'ichiro Tsuzuki
Masato Hayashi
Toyohiko Okuyama
Masahiko Ishikawa
Producer
Hiroaki Kobayashi
Associate Producer
Mitome Asai
Chief Producers
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Masahito Yoshioka
(Tokyo Movie)
Director
Masato Sato
After the battle with the Black Organization,
we returned to a tranquil existence.
That’s when Eisuke Hondo, a student who looked just like Kir,
transferred to Ran’s High School.
Well, Eisuke turned out to be a clumsy boy who is a big fan of the old man.
But then a client came by, asking us to find his girlfriend who had driven off.
Did you two really meet on this freezing mountain?
Behind those trees! That’s my car!
Ami! Ami!
The doors are lined with duct tape from the inside.
And there’s a charcoal stove on the front passenger seat.
This is a case of carbon monoxide poisoning by burning charcoal inside an enclosed space.
It’s clearly suicide.
No.
This is a murder, skillfully set up to look like a suicide.
And the culprit is probably...
...that guy.
A suicide, you say?
In that case, we’d better wrap up here.
I’ll need you to come to the station for questioning later on, but that’s all for today—
Whoa!
You okay?
Oh... Yeah...
I just tripped.
Hey, there’s a depression in the snow.
Judging from the shape,
somebody parked their car here.
Who could have parked here?
It’s about the same size as the car we rode up in with the beardy man!
Say, when did you rent that car?
L-Last night...
Atsushi Misumi (32)
Client
After the fight, Ami said she wanted to use the car the next day,
but I needed a car too.
So I went out and rented one.
I never thought she’d use my car for something like this...
You’re such a silly man!
If you knew she was going to take your car, why’d you leave your work in it?
I-I was going to get it in the morning...
What work?
The project proposal he needs to present to his company tomorrow.
He hired me to find his girlfriend because he needed those papers back.
Say, did you get them?
Er, no, I haven’t looked yet...
But now that you mention it, the documents should be...
Excuse me, did you find some documents in the car?
We found some paperwork in the back seat of the car.
Ah, that’d be it!
Did you find them? That’s great.
We also found a purse that seems to have belonged to the deceased...
and found this inside.
That’s a cigarette lighter.
But what was it doing in her purse?
Who knows?
There was also a brand-new book, just published today, with a fresh burn mark.
So it looks like the lighter was placed in the purse recently.
For some reason we didn’t find any fingerprints on the book.
This gets weirder by the minute.
She hated cigarettes, but I’m a heavy smoker,
so sometimes she’d hide the cigarette lighter from me.
Maybe she put it in her bag out of habit.
You’re a heavy smoker?
Y-Yes.
Do you mind if I go smoke a cigarette in the rental car?
I held myself back today and barely smoked at all, you see.
Sure...
Cigarette...
Wait a minute.
Maybe...
Hey!
I knew it!
The killer has to be that Misumi-san!
Out you go.
The only question is how he did it...
Ow...
Are you okay, Eisuke-kun?
See? I’m always the one who slips and falls into the slush.
Hey, you’re bleeding!
I must’ve cut my finger on the broken windshield.
Wait! I have a bandage on me.
Stick your finger out.
Oh, okay...
It’s just a little scratch! He’s fine!
At least let me bandage it...
Do it yourself.
These bandages are so amazing.
What do you mean?
Look, it seals my finger perfectly!
It’s like the cut never existed!
Wait a minute. That duct tape...
Excuse me, Mr. Forensic Man!
You again...
I left something in the car when I went in!
Can I get it?
Hey!
I see...
So that’s how he did it!
It was suicide! Su-i-cide!
B-But...
Ami-san was inside this car,
and the doors were sealed with duct tape.
We found a charcoal stove with burnt charcoal beside her!
So forget about capturing Sleeping Kogoro on tape!
Er... Right...
What a pity...
What’s with you two? You should be glad this isn’t a murder!
But everybody at the station was hoping to see my video of Sleeping Kogoro!
Can’t you do something?
For the love of...
Hey, Uncle!
What is it?
I noticed something funny!
Over here!
W-What’s gotten into you?!
Look, the car door!
Isn’t it weird?
Not really...
Aside from the duct tape and the shattered window, it looks normal enough to me...
Sir? What’s the matter?
That proud pose and scornful attitude...
It’s Sleeping Kogoro!
I’m not scornful! I’m confident!
But sir, if you’re sitting down like that...
D-Does it mean...
That’s right! It’s time for Sleeping Kogoro to make a deduction!
Yay!
But first...
The most important figure in this case should be here...
...the victim’s boyfriend, Misumi-san.
Detective Mouri’s deduction show?
That’s silly.
Ami committed suicide, didn’t she?
What is there to deduce?
That’s what I thought...
Actually, there’s plenty to unravel.
After all, this was a murder made to look like a suicide!
M-Murder?
Yes. And the killer...
...is the person who entered the car under the pretence of rescuing Ami-san,
and then proceeded to cut the duct tape...
It was you, Atsushi Misumi-san!
Wow! Really? I never guessed!
See? That’s Sleeping Kogoro.
He’s just talking with his head down!
He’s not asleep or possessed!
I-I guess not...
But doesn’t it strike you as odd?
Huh? What?
That boy standing next to Mouri-san, behind the car.
Oh, you mean Conan-kun?
He often helps out with Dad’s deductions!
He’s standing by in case Dad needs something.
You’ve got to be joking, Mouri-san!
I’m the one who hired you to find her, remember?
So why...?
You set us up from the start.
You needed to trick us into believing this car was completely sealed!
Trick you?
I-I don’t mean to be rude, Mouri-san,
but the car was sealed.
The forensics team said they had a tough time pulling the duct tape off the doors.
That’s right.
But that was the door on the driver’s side.
What if the duct tape on the passenger side...
...had slits cut in it from the start?
What?
But you saw it yourself, didn’t you, Mouri-san?
You saw him cut through the duct tape with a utility knife.
Right. I was watching him.
He put his hand over a piece of duct tape that had been stuck lightly over the slits,
and cut neatly through them as he pushed down.
Then the car wasn’t sealed!
First Misumi-san brings his girlfriend here in his car.
He drugs her on the way over by spiking her coffee with sleeping pills.
Then he moves her into the driver’s seat,
and seals the edges of all the doors with duct tape.
Next, he cuts through the duct tape on the passenger side, so he can exit the car.
He hangs some strips of tape lightly over the slits to conceal them.
Then he lights the charcoal,
gets out of the car, and shuts the door.
All he needs to do after that...
is drive home in a rental car he’d parked at the scene earlier,
then get someone to come with him to “find” the body.
He has his patsy check the door on the driver’s side,
then quickly smashes through the windshield to get in.
He makes a show of cutting through the tape on the passenger side.
Voilà, a locked-room murder inside a car!
I see!
When we saw her slumped in the driver’s seat,
of course we tried to get in through the driver’s side.
We assumed the passenger side was sealed just as tightly!
Pressing down on the decoy strips of tape stuck them to the door,
so even if we checked later, we probably wouldn’t notice the gimmick!
Right.
Look at how the tape has been cut on the passenger side.
Cut?
The cuts on the horizontal and vertical strips of tape are slightly off.
That’s because Misumi cut through the horizontal strips first,
and the vertical strips later.
Oh... I see...
Then the driver’s seat was pulled back and her jacket was creased because...
Exactly. Misumi-san drove the car here,
and moved his girlfriend into the driver’s seat after she passed out.
Wait a minute!
I was desperately trying to save my girlfriend!
I can’t believe you’d suspect me of killing her!
It’s not like there’s any proof...
Proof?
Actually, there is.
In the car’s ash tray.
Remember that cigarette lighter in her bag?
She put it there not only to stop Misumi-san from smoking inside the car,
but also to prevent him from finding something before she left the car.
The thing she’d hidden in the ash tray:
A farewell letter!
Let’s see...
“I guess you want to take me to the place where we met,”
“so we can go back to the way we were in the past,”
“but it won’t work. I’ve changed. I’m sorry.”
It’s signed, “Ami”.
She was the one who’d changed...
And you were the one who wanted to come out here.
If this letter was written by the victim,
it proves...
I-It’s a trap!
Ami was trying to frame me!
She committed suicide and made it look like I killed her!
She could’ve cut the duct tape beforehand, putting the utility knife
into the glove compartment so I’d be likely to use it.
And she wrote that letter to pin the crime on me!
The letter isn’t the proof I was talking about.
The problem is the book cover it was written on.
You’ll know when you see it.
It’s one of those paper covers that bookstores use to wrap books for customers.
It probably came off the brand-new book we found in your girlfriend’s purse.
We didn’t find any fingerprints on the book because you wiped them off.
You bought it as a gift for her, so your prints were all over it.
But you forgot about the book cover.
She wrote that letter on it and hid it in the ash tray for you to find.
Maybe you’d like to explain how your fingerprints got on a cover that was just purchased today,
and was found inside a car you supposedly haven’t been in since sometime yesterday.
Y-You can’t tell if the cover came from that book...
Books are all different sizes, even if they belong to the same series.
A cover that fits the book so perfectly is rather uncommon.
Or should we take a trip to the bookstore?
I bet we’ll find a clerk who remembers...
That the man who bought the book this morning
had bloodshot eyes, haunted by the crime he was planning to commit.
Bloodshot eyes?
You’re wrong there, Mr. Detective.
I probably looked hopeless and defeated,
knowing it was the last favor I’d do for the woman I loved.
She asked you to buy the book?
That’s right. You’ll find my prints all over the cover.
After all, I did everything she wanted.
I fulfilled that woman’s every desire!
If she said she wanted to go somewhere on vacation,
I’d take time off work and make it happen.
If she said she wanted to see some popular singer in concert,
I’d stand in line all night to get tickets.
The same goes for this car.
I went into debt to buy the model she wanted.
That’s right... I felt like her Prince Charming.
But I finally realized I was wrong.
I was no prince to her...
...just a servant.
S-Servant?
I found a cigarette in her car.
A brand I don’t smoke.
I quit smoking for her too...
She was cheating on you?
That’s right!
When I confronted her, she admitted she’d gone out with another man.
She even laughed about it!
I felt like a fool!
Paying off the loan on that car,
so some other guy could drive around town with her!
And that’s why you killed her.
Yes.
But you have to believe me!
I loved her from the bottom of my heart!
I didn’t come here just to complete the crime!
It was partly for her!
I was filled with guilt!
I hoped maybe she was still alive!
That’s why I smashed through the windshield...
Cut the act.
I don’t know what went on between you two.
But I know your so-called love for her was long over.
W-What?
If you really wanted to save her,
you would have carefully broken the rear window or the window on the passenger side.
By smashing wildly at the windshield,
you sprayed her with broken glass and could have severely injured her.
You already knew she was dead.
You just wanted to destroy your past with her, along with the car.
Wow! You were amazing, Sleeping Kogoro!
Your deduction echoed through the snow-capped mountains of Gunma!
I’m gonna show this video to everybody at the station!
Yeah, whatever.
I don’t remember a thing...
On her lap again ...
Huh? I only got one shot of you...
Oh no! I kept pausing it so I wouldn’t waste the tape...
He forgot to take it off pause.
Can we go back and redo it?
Are you nuts?!
You really helped crack the case today, Eisuke-kun!
Huh?
Conan-kun noticed there was something suspicious about the duct tape in the car
because of what you said about the bandage!
Then he ran and told my dad!
Uh... Yeah...
Another sleuth beat you to it today!
What do you mean?
It’s his usual thing!
He always makes some funny comment that has nothing to do with the case,
but it gets people on track to the real solution!
D-Don’t tell me...
This kid does?
Is this guy on to me?
If you’re such a fan of Sleeping Kogoro, feel free to drop by anytime.
You mean it?
Yay!
Oww...
Nah, couldn’t be.
And perhaps if he couldn’t achieve his objective...
...the culprit’s next action would be...
...a kidnapping!
Next Conan: