Victory! Honesty! The shocking evidence!
The inexhaustible drive to aim for the top!
The popular series is finally here!
An unexpected meeting at a singles party!
The love of the police detectives hits the brakes!
Perceiving the one and only truth,
The body of a child and the brains of an adult,
His name is: Detective Conan!
I see, so you can't come.
That's too bad.
Sorry, some work that I can't just leave suddenly came in.
Well, if it's work I guess it can't be helped.
Oh right, tell that man not to drink too much.
If he gets drunk, becomes involved with the young
girls there and causes a problem, I won't be his lawyer.
Yeah, I got it.
Talk to you later, Mom.
What's with that sigh when
we're just about to eat a great meal?
Well...
Could it be that you asked Auntie Eri to come here too?
Well, maybe...
I figured that might be it.
When you suddenly said "A stylish cafe just opened,
let's go check it out," I knew there was something behind it.
Just as I thought, huh?
Liar. When you found out it was
good and cheap, you were crazy about it.
It was really difficult to get a
reservation at this place, you know.
Well, it's not such a bad place...
Except for all the annoying
young people and their group dates.
Eh? Isn't that Mouri-san?
Hey there.
Detective Chiba!
Ah, Detective Takagi's here too!
What's all this then?
Two men having dinner together at a place like this?
That's not it.
It's just a singles party.
Wha? You idiot! I knew it.
"Singles party?" Does Detective Sato know about this?
Ah, no! I'm only here to even out the numbers!
Ch-Chiba forced me to come!
Right, right, right? That's right, right?
Y-Yeah...
Even thought that's true, when you
say it that way it sounds like you're lying...
So please keep this a secret from Sato-san.
THE METROPOLITAN POLICE
DETECTIVE LOVE STORY
(PART ONE)
One more time, cheers.
Yo, Chiba. You're late you know.
The girls are really into it; they've already started.
Ah, sorry.
So, let me introduce you.
This is my friend from my middle school days
and the ringleader of our singles party, Emoto.
Emoto Masashi (26)
Sports Gym Trainer
Nice to meet you.
So, who's this?
This is Detective Mouri. We just bumped into him.
Oh, I know you! You're Sleeping Kogoro, right?
Hello.
So, is the "buddy" you mentioned here?
Ah, this is my coworker.
Ah, nice to meet you, I'm Takagi.
Well, he's a bit dull-looking,
but it's better than having no one.
Oh, this guy has a bad mouth, but he's good at heart.
Is that so...
Anyway, Chiba, we're really lucky today!
They're there among the woman
who came today. Two cute babes!
Is that so? That's great, right?
Your sister was planning to come
today. Could she be one of those two?
I didn't mean her.
One of them is one of my sister's old friends.
And the other is that girl's good friend or something.
Both of them do some kind of police related work.
Police related?
Oh yeah, Chiba, in the past you used to say
you wanted to become a policeman or something.
So what are you doing now?
I told you, I'm a police detective. A detective.
Then that dull-looking guy is a policeman too?
Ah, that's right.
Then maybe you've already met them somewhere before.
Those two policewomen in mini-skirts.
Mini-skirts?
Are you sure those two are really police officers?
Yeah, this isn't TV.
It's OK, isn't it? I do it 'cause I
can't wear showy stuff while on duty.
Y-Yumi-san?!
Eh? It's Takagi-kun and Chiba-kun! What're ya doin' here?
So you guys knew each other after all.
That means...
The other person...
...must be...
Hey, Yumi!
Hurry and get back here!
I can't handle all those guys by myself.
...Sato-san.
W-What's she doings here?
Takagi-kun? And Chiba-kun too?
Why are you here?
The mood's getting dangerous, don't you think?
Heh, it's starting to get interesting.
Hey, Uncle...
And so you see, the culprit came rushing at me like this...
Then I got his joint like this.
Can I be the culprit next?
Leave it to Detective Sato to monopolize all the men.
Well that's no big deal. The real problem is that man.
You figured out the trick in that last case too, didn't you?
Tell us about it, tell us about it!
It was so easy that I've forgotten how it was done.
Geez, you're so cruel.
I should be going soon I guess.
Hey hey, what are you saying, Sis?
Don't be silly, you're supposed to be relaxing.
Emoto Aya(28)
Illustrator
But I'm worried about Kouta
watching the house all by himself.
Uhm, is he your little brother?
No, he's my cousin who's just turning five.
His parents are both overseas on business.
So we're taking care of him at our house for the time being.
It'll be OK.
You fixed his dinner before we came.
You need to get out of that apartment once in a while.
But I still have work left to do.
Well, let's forget about work for today at least.
Not taking a breather every so
often can be bad for your health.
Yes.
Oh, I'm sorry!
Detective Takagi!
Ah, I'm sorry!
It's OK.
Ah, I really ought to be going home.
So many strange things happened before this.
Strange things?
Things to do with Kouta.
Like the Kamen Yaiba battle card.
Battle card?
Yeah. The other day Kouta
brought his friends over to show it off.
It was a super rare card that I hadn't seen before.
He said a nice man gave it to him or something.
It was a man with long bangs and a beard.
He'd dropped his wallet in front of Kouta.
When he picked it up for him,
he was given that card in thanks.
Moreover, that man took Kouta to his home, brought
out some cake for him and asked him a lot of questions.
What was he asked?
Kouta said the man was a fortune
teller and he asked about our apartment.
Things like where his bed was, where things were in the
entryway, and when my brother's and my birthdays were.
He even asked where we keep our mail.
Your mail?
Kouta told him I keep mine in a box inside the closet.
And that my brother leaves his out on top of his desk.
That guy said those were really
good spots and not to move them.
Is there anything important in your mail?
Well, nothing particularly.
Nothing in mine either.
Besides, that man is apparently one of my buddies.
Your friend?
He's probably just planning to surprise
me by doing something for my birthday
How do you know it was your friend?
Kouta said there was a phone
call while he was eating the cake.
The man happened to be in the
bathroom, so the machine picked up.
He said the voice he heard was my voice, so it can't be wrong.
Then, do you have any idea who that person is?
Dunno. I called all over trying to
gather members for this singles party.
Still, it has to be one of them, doesn't it?
It seems that after that guy heard the
message he sent Kouta home in a hurry.
He was probably afraid that I would
find out about it and ruin the surprise.
What did you say in the message?
Well, not much.
Just that my sister and I are having this
singles party here the Saturday after next.
What was that?
That means that person knows
the little boy is home alone tonight.
Call him right away!
I've tried a few times but he's not answering.
That's why I have to go home.
That's right, we have to go and check.
Yumi!
It's no good.
Hey, Chiba!
Dad!
What is it?
Kouta?!
Kouta-kun?
You're just being paranoid; the door was properly locked.
That man was just asking about
furniture placement and birthdays, right?
He's probably just some feng shui guy.
That's just the problem!
Even now there are a lot of people who use their
birthday as their safe's combination so they won't forget it.
And knowing the arrangement of the furniture
beforehand would make finding the safe easier.
Or possibly the letters and postcards might
provide a clue to help them infer the combination.
And perhaps if he couldn't achieve his objective...
The culprit's next action would be...
D-Detectives!
Come here!
Look at this.
Th-This is...
A kidnapping.
I have the boy; don't call the police.
But aren't you guys police detectives?
W-Well, yes.
Well, in some ways this makes it easier.
In any case, I'll contact the office.
Don't!
The culprit broke into this
apartment and kidnapped Kouta-kun!
He might still be nearby watching the place.
If police come trooping through this house, he'd find out.
It would be no good if he picked up the
electromagnetic waves from our cellphones either.
You can contact them after we confirm whether any
listening devices have been planted somewhere or not.
Don't you at least know that?
S-Sorry!
Sorry, I overstated that.
N-No...
Say, wasn't the culprit someone who met
Kouta-kun once, and might be one of this guy's friends?
Ah, yeah!
Then if you tell Uncle Kogoro about that
time in detail, maybe he'll know who the culprit is.
Uh, I guess so.
If I remember right, it was two
weeks ago on a Saturday, right Sis?
Yes, that day Kouta went out to play and
didn't come back until after 8 o'clock at night.
Eight o'clock?
That's pretty late, isn't it?
Yes, I was getting worried and
thinking about calling the police.
But he came home looking all innocent and said he was sorry.
He asked me to keep it a secret from his
mother and father, so I didn't scold him much.
I'd no idea he had met such a dangerous person.
Perhaps he had him pick up his wallet
on purpose and brought him to his house.
And by chance at the same time it arrived:
My message that said my sister
was joining the singles party tonight.
I see. Then the kidnapper must
definitely be one of Masashi-san's friends.
At that time he got Kouta-kun to tell him about
the arrangement of the furniture in this apartment.
He planned to break in tonight when they were both away.
Emoto-san, is there a safe in this house?
We don't have a silly thing like that.
We carry our credit cards and bankbooks and such with us,
so there's really nothing we worry about being taken, right?
Yeah.
In short, the culprit got into the house but
couldn't find anything of monetary value...
So he kidnapped Kouta-kun instead.
So, do you remember who you called
about the singles party that didn't come tonight?
Yeah. There were three of them.
The first one's name is Rokuda, a pal from when I was a kid.
The second was my junior in high school, Hikiya.
The third is a regular customer of
the gym where I work, Satsuka-san.
All three are good guys and I can't
imagine them kidnapping anyone.
Do you remember the times when you called those three?
I think I called Rokuda sometime after noon.
I called Hikiya in the evening.
And I called Satsuka-san later
that night, I think around 7 o'clock.
All three of them were during the time
Kouta-kun was out, from noon until 8 o'clock.
Nevertheless, he got cheated didn't he? After
the culprit went to such elaborate preparations...
He should have made sure there was
something of monetary value to steal.
Clearly, if he had wanted to kidnap
Kouta-kun, he could've done it those two weeks ago.
Then that man must have been interested in the mail, right?
Were there any important
letters or official documents in there?
Not really. Nothing that I know of anyway.
What about postcards?
That's it! The lottery numbers on
the new year's greetings postcards!
I think first prize this year was a trip to Hawaii. He
could sell that at a bargain ticket shop for a lot of money!
Maybe he made a note of the names and the
numbers of the people he sent new year's cards to...
Look. These are the three new
year's greetings cards we received.
They're all losers though.
Losers? Are you sure?
Yes, I checked all the new year's cards that were sent to us.
Right, right.
Unlike me, my sister is really into sweepstakes and lotteries.
What are you saying? You're the one who
collects cards at your age, like you were still a child.
Collects cards?
Just like Kouta, but I've been doing it since I was a kid
No matter how old I got, I just
couldn't stop collecting Kamen Yaiba cards.
I see, that's how he knew the
card Kouta-kun received was so rare.
Well, if you think my friends are so suspicious,
why don't we take a ride over and check on them.
All three of them said they had things to do at
home today so they couldn't come to the singles party.
Good idea. Since they're all suspects, let's go and check.
But, if they find out you're police detectives...
We'll stick to the pretense that were
stopping by on the way home from the singles party.
We'll keep that we came here a secret.
So, if they start behaving
strangely, it's an instant confirmation.
And if they happen to be absent, they must be the culprit.
They might know Detective Mouri's face...
So please remain here with Aya-san and
Ran-chan and wait for the culprit to contact you.
Ah, sure...
What about Conan-kun.
Yeah, we'll take him.
This kid notices a lot of things and he
might cause the culprit to lower his guard.
Ah, here it is. Number 203.
Is this the first time you've been here?
Yeah, at least to his apartment.
Who is it?
It's me, Emoto.
I'm on my way home from the
singles party. Can I come in for a bit?
What is it that brings you here so late?
Sorry, I was talking about you at the
singles party with these two people.
Rokuda Takuji (26)
Musician
Talking about me? What about?
Ah, you see, the two of us are in a band too.
But his lyrics and my melodies
haven't been meshing well recently.
Say, could you let me hear your songs?
Ah, this is Conan-kun. Nice to meet you.
Eh? Is this your child?
Uh, he's my little brother.
Hey, it's pretty good, isn't it?
You think so?
But what's this? You still have so many lottery tickets.
You do too. Those are from the
year-end lottery that I split and sent to you.
Have you checked yours properly like you should?
It's OK, they'd all be losers anyway.
How should I say it, Rokuda? If you have the money to
buy all these, you should move to a better neighborhood.
Maybe there's something good
in that bulging mailbox of yours.
Huh? Yeah...
Oh! Amazing, amazing!
It's just like Chiba's apartment...
Wow! Since I admire models so
much, this is super inspirational!
Hikika Kadonari (25)
Modeler
Being admired by a beautifully
designed character like you is a real thrill.
Character, eh?
I should have gone to the singles party too.
That's why I keep inviting you.
By the way, what was inside the limited edition event
pack of Yaiba cards you asked me to buy and send you?
Ah, all seven were worthless.
How about you?
Same with mine.
That illusory Potato Queen platinum card wasn't there.
What's the limited edition event pack?
It was a one day thing where you could only buy two packs.
There was a rumor that in among the 7 cards in each pack
there might be a super rare card that's not made anymore.
The price for those can go over
almost 800,000 yen on internet auctions.
800,000?
Well, cards and figures are fine and all.
But, Hikiya, you really should look
at some real live girls occasionally.
Wow.
Amazing, amazing!
Since I admire old-time money so
much, this is super inspirational!
That's overdoing it a little.
Satsuka Yoshikane (31)
Paper Money Collector
Oh? Then do you have some too? Like these?
Ah, no. Nothing special...
Translator's note: In Japanese, many syllables can matched to numbers based on similar sounds.
Just stuff like a 10,000 yen Taishi bill with a
number that ends with my name "Miwako" (385).
Translator note: Taishi (prince) in the previous sub refers to Prince Shotoku (573-621) imperial regent and one of the early supporters of Buddhism in Japan. His portrait graced the 10,000 yen bill from 1958-1986.
You should keep that safe without spending
it, even though it doesn't have any special value.
I guess I should.
The valuable ones are, look, these.
Wow, these are amazing!
The serial numbers are all the same!
At any rate, if you keep taking out loans to add more
rare bills to your collection, your wife will run out on you.
Ah, sorry about that time...
Did you get the 30,000 yen
repayment I sent you through registered mail?
Yeah, I think so.
More importantly, you should start
eating properly and come to our gym again.
You're really losing weight.
I suppose so.
So? There wasn't anyone suspicious among those three.
Well, there weren't any long-haired men with beards...
That was probably a disguise so that
Kouta-kun wouldn't see his real face.
Are you still suspecting them? Geez.
Kouta wasn't anywhere in any of the three guy's apartments.
Perhaps the voice on the answering machine
might just have been someone who sounded like me.
Oh, it's from my sister.
C-Could the culprit have contacted her?
Give me that.
Hello? Did something happen?
No, nothing yet.
But there's something Kouta said that's been on my mind.
Eh? What was it?
Was it some characteristic of the culprit?
No, it's just that when he was
eating cake at that person's house...
It seems there was a baseball game on TV.
He said...
It was a really boring game.
A boring game?
If it took place during this season, it would be either
high school baseball or a pre-season professional game.
For now, let's have investigators
stakeout those three people's homes.
We can check what baseball games were played on that day.
We might be able to narrow down the suspects.
H-Hey!
Stakeout?
Are you really going that far?
Maybe this is just someone's idea of a practical joke.
Maybe Kouta will show back up.
What kind of brain-dead things are you saying?
A child's been abducted!
Kidnapped!
A practical joke like that would be inexcusable.
Ah... I guess you're right...
Inspector, we've
identified the kidnapper!
If he refuses to come along voluntarily,
arrest him without a warrant.
Takagi-kun!
THE METROPOLITAN POLICE
DETECTIVE LOVE STORY
(PART TWO)