Victory! Honesty! The shocking evidence
The inexhaustible drive to aim for the top!
We forge ahead towards the solution!
Both the case and their love have a surprising development!
Can Detective Takagi decide it today for sure?
Perceiving the one and only truth,
The body of a child and the brains of an adult,
His name is: Detective Conan!
By coincidence we bumped into Detective Takagi and others who were attending a singles party.
However, sometime during the singles party, a cousin of one of the attendees, Kouta-kun, was kidnapped.
The culprit's demand was for one million yen.
I got the boy!
Prepare 1 million Yen!
I will contact you later!
Tell to the Police, I will kill him!
The Metropolitan Police Detective Love Story 7 (Part 2)
Hmm, so the ransom condition is 1 million yen?
That's aismall sum compared to the usual outrageous amount.
Yeah, since the culprit seems to know Masashi-san, he's probably taking his real financial situation into consideration.
All right, I understand. In the meantime, I'll have investigators stakeout those three people's homes.
Kouta-kun saw a live broadcast of a baseball game on March 26th.
According the season, it was either a high school baseball invitational or a pre-season professional game.
He said it was a boring game, so if we can find out which game it was, we might determine the culprit from the time.
Yes, sir. Later.
Ah, Sato-san, I found something.
There wasn't a pre-season professional game on that day, but..
There were three high school games.
So; which of those was it?
Well.. the first game was 7 to 6.
There was reversal after reversal, so it was a very close game.
It went to the 12th inning, lasting from10:00 until 2:00.
Hmm, can't imagine that one being boring.
I don't think so either.
After that, the second one ended at 4:30.
The result was 14 to 5. One team kept pounding away and scored a crushing victory.
Isn't it that one? Sounds like a one-sided and boring game.
Ah, but the losing school had a player who's gotten the attention of the professional leagues...
He hit 6 out of 6, including 2 home runs Quite an effort, eh?
And the last one?
Ah, it was 1 to 2 pitchers' battle.
Both of them got out of a pinch multiple times, The win was from a walk-off home run in the bottom of the 9th.
It ended precisely at 7:00.
That game would have been pretty interesting too.
Say, maybe he saw a regular TV program?
They might have shown baseball on one of those top.
You know, like on cable TV or satellite or something.
Uh, that's true.
Let's see, shown on satellite from 12:00 to 1:00, "Major League Digest" (Nice Game Selection)
From 3:00 to 5:00 was "Falcon's: The Track to Victory," a rebroadcast of last year's special on Nichiuri TV.
and on Cable TV, from 6:00 to 7:00 pm, there was a special show about the player, Kiyomatsu.
Hmm, there's no way the "Nice Game Selection" would be boring.
And "The Track to Victory" sounds like it should be interesting as it is.
Therefore, could it have been the special about Kiyomatsu?
Ah, mom said she saw it She said they showed all of Kiyomatsu's home runs since his debut and it was really good.
Well, instead... A video! Maybe a baseball video was playing.
I don't think that's the case.
Kouta said, he turn the TV himself with the remote.
Emoto Aya (28)
Illustrator
In that case, maybe anticipating that Kouta-kun would do that, the culprit setup an unrelated baseball video earlier...
In order to confuse the time.
Dummy.
Kouta-kun was using the remote, right?
If he changed the channel he'd realize right away.
Ah, that's right..
At any rate, are you sure Kouta-kun didn't tell you what time he went to the man's
Right, it seems that somehow that man really convinced him not to speak about it
It took some time to finally get him to admit to receiving that card and going to that man's home.
Umm...
if Kouta-kun received a rare Kamen Yaiba card...
Then isn't the guy who collects them, that modeler Hikiya-san, the suspicious one?
Hikiya Kadonari (25)
Modeler
No, even though I said it was rare, they sell things like that for around 3000 yen at shops.
Emoto Masashi (26)
Sports Gym Trainer
Any adult could have bought that card.
It's nothing like the illusory 800,000 yen premium card we were both hoping for.
By the way, back then Hikiya said he sentyou a pack of cards.
Are you sure that premium card wasn't inside?
I told you already. It wasn't there.
Satsuka Yoshikane (31)
Paper Money Collector
Speaking of premium, Satsuka-san said he sent 30 000 yen to you by registered mail.
Could one with all the same numbers have been mixed in or something?
Who knows.
I don't take notice of the number on each and every bill I get.
Musician
Rokuda Takuji (26)
For example, I'didn'teven check the lottery tickets Rokuda sent me.
I'm just not interested in that stuff.
Say, what about a movie?
Could that baseball game have been a scene from a movie or drama?
That's right.
Can you check on that possibility?
Yes.
For movies and dramas...
It's all romances.
"My Wonderful Affair."
One about an aristocratic group date, "The Lovers Who Passed by Each Other."
One about lovers separating/ "The Too-Brief Spring"
Eh, ah, those really were the programs shown that day...
I only went because of the food.
I didn't know it was a singles party.
Unlike someone else.
Ah, no, I was...
And what's with those clothes?
Were you trying to show off?
I could say the same for you, why would you be wearing make-up?
Eh? This? Yumi forced me!
Same here! Chiba forced me too!
Not that it matters anyway.
Exactly.
Doesn't matter at all.
Hey, what're you guys doing?
Yes?
It's Megure. How's it going there?
As for us, we haven't been able to find any game shown the day that looks boring.
Hey, hey... Everyone's staking out those three people's homes now and waiting to break in.
If this drags on much longer, the boy's life could be in danger.
I'm home.
Kouta!?
A-Are you alright?
You haven't be injured, have you?
No, I'm fine.
I was in the car of the man from before, but I got tired and fell asleep.
That guy, where does he live?
Where's his apartment?
Huh? Who's this lady?
She's a police1 officer.
Tell me, Kouta-kun!
But I already promised that man I will never say anything.
That man kidnapped you, so he's a bad person
Please tell me!
But...
It's all OK now, isn't it?
Since he's home safely.
It must have been one of my buddies.
Some practical joke, though I admit it was in bad taste.
How could this be a practical joke?
Hey, what's going on?
Did something happen?
Well, you see, the boy we thought had been kidnapped just came back.
What!? Did you give the 1 million yen?
No, the culprit hasn'teven contacted us yet
Masashi-san doesn't even intend to hand over the money.
In any case, it's already late for today, Kouta.
Well talk about this tomorrow, go on to bed.
Yes.
Kouta-kun.
What happened to your socks? They look like they're wet
Ah, this?
I remembered that Masashi-niichan said I mustn't take things from strange men.
So after saying bye-bye to the man with the beard, I went back to return the card he gave me.
But then he wasn't in the apartment Instead there was a man I didn't know irTtrfe bathroom.
An unknown man in the bathroom?
Well, as for us, let's leave the rest to the police.
Oh, it's time for the sports news.
I'd like to see the results of the World Cup preliminaries.
Excuse me, do you mind if I use the TV?
Ah, no. Go ahead.
And so it's 0 to 0. A scoreless draw, but still a great game!
What, 0 to 0?
Well, I guess that's not bad for an away game.
A scoreless draw?
I see, that's why Kouta-kun...
That person must be the culprit then.
Didn't I already tell you?
This was just a stupid practical joke by one of my friends.
He probably took Kouta just to see me freak out
Besides, Kouta came back safe and sound.
But, you see...
The kidnapper not only demanded one million yen...
He left a message saying he would kill Kouta-kun if you reported it to the police.
That was a clear threat, inexcusable for a practical joke.
Plus your voice was heard from the answering machine in the kidnapper's apartment
In other words, the culprit must be one of the three people you telephoned.
We can't just let this go.
Now, Kouta-kun. Let's go together, and visit their houses.
Even though the culprit was disguised at the time, if we go now, you'll know who's apartment it was, right?
Uh, but..,
Hey! I'm telling you that isn't necessary!
Wait a sec. Since Kouta-kun has come back home, you must haveTalready paid the ransom money-
If I'd done that, the officers would definitely have noticed!
But you might have given something else to the culprit
Maybe there was something of value in the things they sent you ancl you returned it or something.
Geez, didn't I just say-
A-re-re!
This picture was in Aya-oneesan's e-mail!
Hey! Conan-kun, what are you looking at!?
Ah! This? An illustrator friend of mine sends me these joke messages.
Geez, will you stop it, Conan-kun?
But, you see, it said "Click This" on the e-mail.
If I knew what was inside before I opened it, I wouldn't have done it
Idiot! First of all, you shouldn't open other people's mail no matter what the contents!
Wait a second.
The kidnapper picked the time when both Masashi-san and Aya-san would be out at the singles party to break in.
He wanted to steal something, right?
In that case, Hikiya-san who sent the Yaiba cards is in the clear.
He wouldn't go through all this trouble of this plan if he didn't know what was inside.
I see.
In that respect, there are the lottery tickets that Rokuda-san sent
If the winner was a number continuing from the tickets he had himself, then he would know the winning ticket.was'here.
Yeah.
And you could say the same thing for Satsuka-san.
If he'd lost one of the rare bills he'd bought..
It wouldn't be strange for him to think he'd accidentally sent it to Masashi-san.
Speaking of sending things, didn't a bottle wrapped in shiny paper arrive for Uncle Kogoro the other day?
Ah, that was champagne.
It was a thank you gift from one of dad's clients.
That's a kind of juice, right? I wanted to try some too.
It's alcohol, so children are not allowed.
Besides, Dad already drank it all.
Well, I guess I couldn't then.
Right, right
Since it was alcohol, Uncle opened it up as soon as it arrived and put it in his stomach, right?
Wait a minute...
When you receive money through registered mail, normally you put it in your wallet right away after you open it
That means if any rare bills had been mixed in, they'd be in Masashi-san's wallet
Even if he broke into the house, he couldn't get his hands on them.
In that case, the suspicious one...
Is the one who sent the lottery tickets, Rokuda-san!
That's not possible.
He knows don't care about lotteries and might have just thrown them away.
He also knows it possible you might have left them unopened on the desk.
Since you don't care about them, you might not notice if they were gone.
Naturally you might not even realize that they had been stolen.
Hold on a moment
Aren't you forgetting something?
Kouta said he watched a boring baseball game at that man's apartment
It was just past noon on that day when I called Rokuda's place.
,The only two games on TV at that time was the close high school baseball game with reversal after reversal,
AncTthe Major League "Nice Game Selection."
Hey, Kouta. That game you saw was boring, right?
Yeah, it was no fun at all.
See? Rokuda couldn't be the culprit
But, say, it says here that the "Nice Game , Selection" was an "anzenjiai" (safe game).
If it was safe, then wouldn't it be dull and unexciting?
Idiot!
That's read "kanzenjiai". It's what they call a ''perfect game".
It's when the pitcher doesn't let the opposing batters score even one hit It's as exciting a game as you can get!
Oh! Could it be?
It's true'a perfect game can be thrilling.
But for a child not familiar with the details of baseball, it might seem like a game where nothing happens.
Furthermore, if the broadcast window was only one hour long,
If could be almost cut to just that pitcher's plays, so it would only show scenes of the opposing batters getting out
It makes sense that he would call it boring.
So, Kouta-kun. Are we right?
The batters kept getting three strikes, so everyone was just getting outs.
With this it's clear that the kidnapper was Rokuda-san.
W-wait
Even if Rokuda is the culprit, it was only an attempt, right?
It's not like he got any money from me.
Besides, it seems he's hard up fonmoney. I'm sure he just unconsciously gave into'temptation.
You knew it, didn't you?
That one of those lottery tickets was a winner.-
You knew he was hard up for money, so you sent the tickets back to him still in the envelope.
But, not knowing that, Rokuda-san snuck into this house.
The lottery tickets weren't here and, in his impatience, he kidnapped Kouta-kun.
And, because of his situation, you suspected Rokuda-san from the beginning.
That's why you said we should go over to his apartment
When you saw the mail still in there in his mailbox...
Maybe there's something good in that bulging mailbox of yours.
That's what you said, right?
Did I get that wrong anywhere?
No, that's right It's just as you said.
But it's OK, isn't it?
He was the one who bought the lottery tickets originally.
Besides, he's the only one. He never gave up music, even now he still doing it
It was our dream.
Our group from long ago.
Everyone became bitter and quit
Except him.
So, please forgive him this time, Detective.
I can't
Kidnapping is a extremely vulgar crime, rigirt up there with murder.
I can't excuse it
Especially since it was just for money.
Well, a dream that needs to stab people in the heart to become true...
It's hard to sympathize with someone holding on to something so unfair.
That's..
That foolish guy.
Takagi-kun, we're going to raid Rokuda-san's house.
Geez, what's that guy up to at a time like this?
Inspector, we've identified the kidnapper!
It's Masashi-san's childhood friend, Rokuda Takuji.
There's a danger that he might flee.
If he refuses to come along voluntarily, arrest him without a warrant
No, we can't do that.
Eh?
Just now he came flying by with a strange look on his face.
W-Who did?
Ooh, Sato-kun!
Inspector.
It was him, there.
T-Takagi-kun!
How did you get covered with blood?
Don't tell me you went in and fought with the culprit to try to look good.
No, that's the kidnapper Rokuda's blood.
He saved him.
Takagi-kun broke into the apartment and saved Rokuda.
T-Takagi-kun!
What do you think you're doing?
Suicide?
He slit his wrists. The ambulance just left with him.
He was discovered soon enough, so it looks like he'll survive.
Also, it seems he's going to come in voluntarily afterwards.
But how did you know he was trying to commit suicide?
Kouta-kun's socks.
When I asked him why his socks were wet,
Kouta-kun said when he went back to Rokuda's place there was a stranger in the bathroom.
From that I figured after Rokuda let Kouta-kun go, he took off his disguise and was planning to kill himself in the bath.
Since his socks were wet, that meant Kouta-kun went into the bathroom.
Since he must have been right beside Rokuda,
If Rokuda was still conscious at the time, he should have reacted to Kouta-kun being in the room.
I see. Rokuda found the lottery tickets that had been returned in his mailbox.
He realized Emoto-san still cared for him, and was unable to endure the weight of the crime he had committed.
But how were you so sure that Rokuda Takuji was the culprit?
The thing that Masashi-san sent back and was in his mailbox...
It was the only thing who's value could be known beforehand and could be stolen by stealth.
It had to be the lottery tickets.
So why didn't you tell me?
Ah, well...
I wasn't confident about my deduction, and so I wanted to confirm it first. I'm Sorry.
Then, Inspector, I'll leave the rest to you.
Sato-san.
Ah, Sato-kun.
Can you write up the detailed report back at headquarters for me?
Uh, yes, sir.
Takagi-kun, you too.
I need to wait here for the search warrant
You can use my car. Have you been drinking?
I only had softdrinks.
I'm sorry.
For what?
You didn't do anything that requires an apology.
But aren't you angry?
Huh? Do I look like it?
Ah, if it's about the singles party...
It's OK. I bet Chiba-kun told you they were short on people and you couldn't refuse, right?
Well, I guess you were looking forward to some girls coming.
So you're mad about what I just did then?
Upon reflection, I know I should have shared my conclusions with you, as my superior.
But before bknew it, my body was moving on its own and I was running there.
I'm sorry, really.
Don't apologize.
What you did was far more important than arresting someone.
You did a really magnificent thing.
I'm upset that I wasn't thinking about what the suspect would be feeling.
And I'm mad at myself for fixating only on apprehending him.
And when at the same time some other person could see the big picture, I regret that
Ah, no. I only figured it out because I also buy lottery tickets frequently.
So, it's just like the chance you have with lottery.tickets...
Two people who are dating meet at a singles party they were invited to separately.
Ah, that's true. My tickets are never winners either.
Then I'm just another losing ticket, I guess?
Ah, no! You're a high-class big win
Watch where you're going
You really think so?
Yes! I'll swear upon my cherry blossom police badge.
Then will you make certain?
If I'm a win or not?
Yes, gladly.
Could it be you forgot we were back here?
Eh? Another singles party?
Right, we're short on people again.
Yumi... Sorry but I'm going to pass.
I've learned'mydesson before.
Eh? A smorgasbord of cake after dinner, all you can eat?
Plus its all paid by them?
I'll go, I'll go!
I'll catch the mugger in the third district right away and come running!
S-Sato-san?
Huh?
Gum
Mikami-san?
That's it! I understand now!
Conan - A Strange Child.