Victory, truth, and shocking evidence.
These all give you a strong impulse to move forward!
Today's episode title is a trick.
Once you know the story, you'll know the culprit!
The hidden message holds the answer!
Seeing through to the one and only truth...
I look like a child, but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
Get out!
What's with you, Dad?
Don't be so violent...
Never show your face here again!
Sensei, please calm down.
You've never visited since you moved out, yet you think you can just show up and ask me for money?
Umezu Osamu (60)
Famous Author
I never want to see you again!
Dad, wait!
Your blood pressure will rise if you get mad.
Shut up! Just get the hell out!
Umm...
Uncle!
I'm sorry.
Ah, Mouri-san!
Sensei, this is Mouri-san, whom I mentioned earlier.
H-Hello.
Conan: A Strange Child
Conan: A Strange Child!
I've heard stories about you?
Here you go.
Umezu-sensei, pardon me for intruding while you're unpacking...
Takashi, I have a guest. Go home.
Umezu Takashi (25)
Umezu's Son
Takashi, I have a guest. Go home.
I'm not done with you yet.
It'll be really unlucky for the both of us...
If you go to the police and tell them that I'm doing drugs.
If that happens, the bad publicity will ruin your reputation, and your life will go right down the drain.
You're a candidate for some famous prize, aren't you?
It'd be shameful for you if I got caught.
If you give me the money and just keep quiet, then we'll both be lucky.
So...
Shut up!
What happens to you is none of my business!
Go home!
Excuse me, but are you having problems with blackmail?
Don't pay any attention to him.
He's just lying because he wants money.
Little boy, do you want some gum?
It's good for your brain.
Thank you.
I'll have one.
Touru Mikami (30)
Umezu's Secretary
Who are they?
That's Detective Mouri Kogoro-san and Conan-kun.
I've read your book, "The Road to the Thirteenth Step".
If you signed it, it would become even more precious to me.
Dad's book is "precious", huh?
You sure are clueless.
Haven't you heard of a teacher publishing his student's book under his own name before?
Taka-san, you're saying too much!
Aren't you the real author, Araki-san?
Chika Araki (27)
Umezu's Student
Isn't that right?
Oh, Dad. I won't be needing your money.
I've decided to write a memoir.
I'll call it, The Son Talks: His Father's Bestselling Novel.
Takashi! What kind of person are you?!
Sensei! Please stop!
Sorry, Mouri-san. Can you wait in the café across the street?
Still, I don't understand people.
He has money and fame, and really shouldn't have any worries.
Please forgive me, Mouri-san.
Sensei's autograph is inside.
Thank you very much.
Say, why isn't he here?
He's been depressed recently.
He may seem like the confident type, but he does care what other people think.
Isn't that Araki-san
Yeah.
She's helping Sensei by going to ask the police a few questions.
Being an author isn't the easiest thing, I suppose.
Mikami-san, can you shed some light on this?
On what?
Was it really Araki Chika-san who wrote this masterpiece?
Mouri-san, do you really believe Taka-san's lies?
No, it's nothing like that...
Don't trust him.
What an interesting button!
This?
When the novel was published, Sensei gave these to everyone who worked on it.
It's a clay button with the design of a peony flower on it.
Note: The Japanese pronunciation of peony is "botan".
A button with a botan flower, eh?
Well, I have to be going.
Already?
I have a meeting at the TV station.
So, please excuse me.
Mikami-san is pretty busy too, huh?
Not bad...
I'm going to become a famous author!
I've decided on it!
I bought notepads and pens.
Now all you need is talent.
Yeah...
Huh?
Mikami-san...
Sensei won't answer his phone?
He's been feeling depressed lately, and...
No, I'm probably worrying too much.
I'll be okay on my own.
I'd like to come, since I haven't had a chance to thank him.
Sensei! Can you hear me, Sensei?
Here, here! Hurry!
Let's see, 503's spare key...
Sensei!
Sensei...
Mouri-san, call an ambulance!
What are you waiting for?!
Hurry!
No, even an ambulance won't save him now.
Most likely, this is a poison that attacks the nervous system.
Mouri-san, there's something on the screen.
My life as a writer is over.
Everything I've done has been in vain.
Mouri-san, there's something on the screen.
"My life as a writer is over. Everything I've done has been in vain."
It looks like a suicide note.
Sensei committed suicide?
It seems so.
He drank poisoned coffee...
Wrote a suicide note...
Also, he was the only one...
Who had a key to this locked room.
Hey, this window is open.
Could someone have snuck in through the win—
At this height...
It would be impossible.
What is it that he's holding, anyway?
That...
It's a wooden piece that priests hold.
It's a gift from his fans, given to him when he won an award for The Road to the Thirteenth Step.
They gave him a piece of wood—I don't understand.
It was hand-crafted from an Ichii tree.
Ichii can be written as "first place".
I see. He chose to die while grasping onto his former glory.
He must have died with regretful thoughts.
Hey, Uncle! There's something on the edge of this trash can!
Blood.
There's a wound on the back of his head.
Did he trip and fall on the trash can?
In that case, wouldn't it be knocked over?
He must've put it back, and...
No. With his intentions, he wouldn't bother.
However, if he was hit by someone...
He was attacked?
Hey, Mikami-san. What's this envelope?
It's Sensei's manuscript of "My Secret" for the Weekly Nichiuri.
Hey, weren't there three keys here before?
Where did the others go?
Araki-san or Taka-san could've moved them.
That means someone was here before the room was locked.
Mikami-san, please contact Inspector Megure at police headquarters.
His student, Araki-san, and his son, Takashi-san.
There's a good chance that one of them is our killer.
Also, they could have the missing keys.
There aren't any clues in the manuscript.
I'm not sure if this is supposed to be meaningful...
But, from someone else's point of view, it's a completely nonsensical phrase.
"Everyone can see it, but no one can recognize it. Only I may see the pleasures hidden in my works."
That's what it says.
"Pleasures hidden in my works"?
What does that mean?
I don't know, this is the first I've heard of such a thing.
Sensei...
Sensei!
Wait a minute. I can't let you go near the body.
When you left here, did you take one of the spare keys?
Yes, here it is.
I'll ask you this as directly as I can.
Ever since Umezu-sensei's book, The Road to the Thirteenth Step, became a big hit...
You've been pretty upset about its success, haven't you?
What are you talking about?
Please tell the truth.
Araki Ghika-san, you're the real author.
Isn't that right?
No, that's not true. I really didn't write it!
You were mortified after he stole credit for the work that was rightfully yours.
That isn't true!
Sensei really did write the entire novel himself!
If Araki-san is the culprit, why did she leave the window open?
This calendar...
The tape on it was recently replaced.
What's this?
A bubble?
Something like a string must have been pulled in through the window.
Araki-san, do you know what a dying message is?
Yes, I do.
There's a dying message in the wooden stick that Umezu-san is holding.
A dying message in a wooden stick?
This stick was made from an Ichii tree.
While waiting for you, I decided to look it up in a dictionary.
An Ichii tree is also known as an Araragi tree.
Araragi?
"Araki" and "Araragi". They're similar.
Isn't that just a coincidence?
Why is he holding the stick upside down?
It doesn't mean anything.
How can you tell?
He didn't bother to turn it over.
"A drowning man will clutch at a straw", as they say.
Note: This is an old proverb which means "When people are desperate they look for anything to help them, even if it won't do much."
Dad bit the bullet?
How lucky.
I guess this means his entire fortune is mine now.
Your father just died, and all you have to say is "lucky"?
Lucky...
This is one of the missing keys.
Ah, that's right. I snatched it while he wasn't looking.
I was going to break in when he wasn't around, but I guess that's no longer necessary.
Excuse me, but could we perform a quick body search?
Yeah, that's fine.
Today's my lucky day, so I don't care.
This is...
Drugs.
W-What?
Those aren't mine!
It wasn't me!
I didn't kill my dad!
M-Mikami-san, tell them I didn't do it!
I've figured it out.
Umezu Takashi...
Sensei's dying message was referring to you.
Huh... The message wasn't pointing to Araki Chika?
It may seem that way...
But you've overlooked the hidden meaning.
However, I, Mouri Kogoro-sama, have correctly deciphered the message.
There's another message?
Yeah.
This stick is made of wood from an Ichii tree.
Kiraku
Ichii
In kanji, "Ichii" would be written with "ki" and "raku".
You noticed that the stick was upside down.
That's because Umezu-san placed it that way on purpose, as a clue to reading his dying message.
Kiraku
Instead of "ki" and "raku", he meant "raku" and "ki".
Ki raku
"Raku" and "ki"?
"Raku" and "ki".
Doesn't it become "lucky"?
A word that his son frequently uses.
Now I see...
What are you talking about?!
I'm telling you, it wasn't me!
The stick was made from an Ichii tree.
Ichii?
Maybe...
I see...
I got it!
Somewhere around here...
Found it!
Let me go! It wasn't me!
I didn't do it!
You'll have to come with us for questioning.
I have to leave for a conference with some reporters and publishers.
Conan, where did you go?
I'm hungry, so let's go home.
Mouri-san? Is everything all right?
Wait a minute, Inspector.
Those two are innocent.
Mouri-kun...
Then, who did it?
Other than Umezu-san, they're the only two who could've gotten into this room.
Indeed, they're the only ones who had a key.
But, for someone like Mikami-san...
All he had to do was knock, and Umezu-san would have opened the door for him.
Mikami-san...
If you don't mind me asking, where did you go after you left the café this evening?
I walked to the TV station while trying to call Sensei, but got no answer...
So, I came here with you.
Isn't that the wrong order?
After leaving the café, you went to the roof of this building.
On the guardrail, you tied a string long enough to reach this room.
Then, you had Umezu-san open the door for you, and went inside.
While his attention was diverted, you poisoned his coffee.
First, you typed a a fake suicide note on a word processor.
Second, you pulled the hanging string through the window.
Then you left, carefully locked the door behind you, and went back up to the roof.
Finally, you gathered people who genuinely believed that this was suicide...
To back you up in case the police suspected it was murder.
This was Takashi-san's role.
In other words, he was just protecting himself?
Mikami-san took the bag of drugs he used to poison Umezu-san...
And put them in Takashi-san's pocket while they were fighting.
Mouri-san!
Please, stop this!
These are only guesses!
You have no proof!
That's true.
Fortunately, Umezu-san left us a dying message.
Again with the dying message?
This is the third time.
Umezu-san placed the stick upside down on purpose.
It's an important part of the hidden message.
Don't you remember?
It's that nonsensical phrase from Umezu-san's manuscript.
"Everyone can see it, but no one can recognize it. Only I may see the pleasures hidden in my works."
If you look carefully at the bookshelf, you'll understand his secret.
A Chicken, a Bird, and a Crocodile
Niwatori to Kotori to Wani.
A God? A Wolf?
Kami Ka? Okami Ka?
Honey and Sin
Mitsu to Tsumi.
My Mama's Selfishness Towards Me
Mama ga Watashi ni Shita Wagamama.
Newspaper
These are all like "shinbunshi", words that are the same forwards and backwards, also called palindromes.
Among his many works...
Don't Cry, Papa Don't Cry and Oh No, I'm Doomed
Nakuna Papa Nakuna and Dameda Sadameda and many other palindrome titles come to mind.
In other words, the secret of his writing that only he could recognize was the use of palindromes.
Mouri-san...
Could it be that you suspect me only because the name "Mikami" is a palindrome?
That's exactly it.
That's ridiculous.
When I realized this, I started to watch you more closely.
That's when I noticed...
That a button on your blazer is missing.
One of the bottom buttons has disappeared.
How did that happen?
Please excuse me.
After we parted ways at the café, you returned to this apartment.
You used the method that I just revealed to kill him.
While rushing to the TV station to make your alibi, you realized that your button was missing.
If it was found on Umezu-san's body, all of your work would've been futile.
You started to run back to find the button...
But you ran into me on the way back.
You had hoped to break away from us long enough to retrieve it, but never got a chance.
You still haven't found it.
Along with the gum...
The gum that Umezu-san had been chewing is gone.
Detective Takagi...
I'd like you to search in the area around Umezu-san's body.
Most likely, the button and gum are still there.
They're here.
Chiba.
Yes, sir.
Inspector.
Mikami-san, this button belongs to you.
Do you want to confess?
The novel I wrote was published in his name.
He wouldn't even allow me to talk about the book in public...
Since everyone would find out that it was in my style of writing.
That's why you killed my dad?
Sounds like something out of a bad murder-mystery novel.
I guess that's your mistake, Mikami-san.
You really are lucky, Takashi-san.
Your father's estate and all his fortune now belongs to you.
Takashi-san, that's great news!
But first, you should have a chat with Inspector Megure about those illegal drugs you mentioned earlier.
Illegal drugs?
Ah, no...
I'd like to hear all about it.
Takagi-kun, why don't we bring him along?
No, just a second...
How's it going, Uncle?
Are you still writing?
I'm-experiencing a bit of writer's block...
I'm on a roll at-the beginning, but when I get to the conclusion...
I can't remember anything.
That makes sense—you're asleep by then.
You sure are strange, Uncle.
Why can't I remember this?
Oh, by the way, Conan...
I thought of something interesting.
What do you think of Conan: A Strange Child?
"Conan: A Strange Child"?
Right!
Conan: A Strange Child...
Conan: A Strange Child
"Konan Hen na Ko".
It's a palindrome!
What's that supposed to mean?