Victory! Honesty! The shocking evidence!
The impulse takes it to the limit!
Pets make up a big part of our world.
Dogs may wag their tails for their owners,
but they'll bare their teeth at the bad guys!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
THE GREAT DOG COEUR'S TRIUMPH
Yeah.
Looks like Coeur lost this round, too!
Musashi, you've got to lose to a girl once in a while.
Wow, they're so cute!
They play fetch and everything too, huh?
Yeah.
Tsutsumi Eisuke (35)
Musashi's Owner
Both golden retrievers and Irish setters were
originally used for hunting wild game.
They're specialized breeds.
Yagisawa Hiroshi (34)
Coeur's Owner
That's why they're so good at search and retrieval.
Yagisawa manami (30)
Hiroshi's Wife
They usually play together in the
Tsutsumi family's yard, but...
When we heard that Beika Park had
opened a "Dog Land" section...
Tatsumi Misato (33)
Eisuke's Wife
We came to check it out.
There's so much more space than we expected,
and Coeur and Musashi were both so excited.
You're right.
It's nice and wide out here.
Say, do you mean the Tsutsumi-san that
lives in the big house on the fourth block?
Right.
He's a company president and the
one who lives in that huge house.
We met each other while out walking one day.
That was a good five months ago.
You know, Coeur and Musashi
are actually childhood friends.
Is that right?
Childhood friends, huh?
I wonder where my Musashi ran off to?
Hey...
When did I become a dog?
Coeur!
What are you chewing on?
She's always doing stuff like this!
Musashi's the same way.
He eats grass, leaves, and even dirt!
The last time we brushed his teeth, he even
had clay stuck between them, didn't he?
Yep.
So you brush your dog's teeth, too?
We sure do.
Right after every meal.
Every meal?
He's better than Uncle Kogorou!
Coeur!
Musashi!
All right, go and get it!
Musashi (2)
Irısh Setter (Male)
Coeur (2)
Golden Retriever (Female)
Wow, that was so much fun!
Next time, we should take Dad with us too.
Right?
But don't you think Uncle's more
interested in horses than in dogs?
That's true.
The ones wearing number bibs.
Yeah!
Hey, would you two be quiet?
I'm with a client.
Oh, we're sorry.
Now, what was the name of your neighbor's dog?
Nakatani Yoriko (41)
Client
It's Musashi.
An Irish setter named Musashi.
Musashi?
So this Musashi barks and growls whenever he sees you?
Yes.
And he's such a large dog, I'm always afraid
that one day he'll end up attacking me.
I'm so scared.
Mouri-san, please do something.
I'm not really sure what I can do...
We moved into our current house three years
ago when my husband was transferred here.
The couple next door moved in around the same time.
Both houses were originally owned by the same person.
They had wished for their parents to live
comfortably in the house we do now...
So they made the hedge, the only boundary
separating the two properties, quite low.
That's why I'm afraid...
The hedge is low enough for Musashi
to jump over if he really wanted to.
So why don't you just raise the hedge?
That's what I thought, too!
But my husband keeps saying that it's fine the way it is.
So does his mother, and she doesn't even live with us.
By Musashi, do you mean the dog
owned by the Tsutsumi family?
What, you know them?
Yeah, we just met.
It's true that Musashi's a large dog, but...
I really can't see him as a dog who barks
and growls at people without a reason.
Let alone attacking someone...
Miss, could you have maybe done
something to make Musashi angry at you?
I didn't do anything!
How rude!
Fine, your services are not required.
If anything should happen to me...
Mouri-san...
It will be your fault!
No, I...
Look what you did now.
Sorry...
But to place all the blame on Musashi is wrong.
Right?
Yeah.
But soon after that, an unexpected case occurred...
You all right?
Yes.
I'll just go on inside.
All right.
What was that?
Dear, that's Musashi's bark!
Yeah.
Get away!
Get away from me!
That's our neighbor!
Musashi!
Cut it out, Musashi!
Are you all right, ma'am?
My mother...
My mother's...
It can't be...
Dear?
Yeah...
Hello, Mouri here.
What now, Musashi did?
Understood, I'm on my way.
What's happened to Musashi, Dad?
It seems he attacked Nakatani-san's
mother, and caused her death.
All right, all finished.
How long will it take for me to walk again?
Let's see...
It's a pretty bad sprain, so it could
take up to four or five days.
Four or five days...
I'll be off now.
Thanks for your help.
Now, if you could please explain in further detail.
Yes.
This evening while my husband was out
on an errand, his mother came to visit.
I set out some coffee for us, but, because I
was in a hurry, I spilled some on her clothing.
So I had her wear my cardigan instead.
Soon after that, I remembered that I had left the
laundry hanging outside and went to bring it in.
But I was careless and ended up dropping one
of my husband's shirts in the yard next door.
Unfortunately, my neighbors appeared to be out.
And though I wanted to go get the shirt,
I was just too frightened of Musashi.
That's when my mother-in-law
said that she'd go get it instead.
I told her not to because it was too dangerous, but...
She said, "It'll be fine, I've known
him since he was a puppy."
Musashi-chan?
You're such a good boy.
Mother!
Get away!
Get away from me!
That's when the Tsutsumi couple came to my rescue.
Yes.
We were supposed to be out late at a party, but...
On the way there my wife became ill, and
we came home earlier than expected.
But thanks to that, you saved my life.
Uhm...
May I ask you a question?
Why do you have that cane?
We bought this for my mother-in-law,
who always uses a cane.
And the firecrackers?
I've taken to carrying them around recently
just in case Musashi did attack me.
I heard dogs don't like the sound of firecrackers.
I'll take those.
Inspector...
I believe Musashi mistook my mother-in-law for me...
And attacked her because she was wearing my cardigan!
That's why I came to you and asked for your help!
But, even so...
This is where Kinue-san was attacked.
And Yoriko-san fell down...
Over there.
Blood?
Yoriko-san didn't have a wound that
would have had excessive bleeding.
Which means that...
This blood must be Kinue-san's.
But what's it doing over here?
From the autopsy report, we've learned that Nakatani
Kinue-san's death was caused by a blood hemorrhage.
She died instantly.
Instantly?
The teeth marks on her throat appear
to match those of Musashi.
Traces of Musashi's saliva were
also found on the entry wound.
Say, why did Musashi attack Kinue-san?
He mistook her for Yoriko-san.
Kinue-san was wearing Yoriko-san's cardigan, after all.
Weren't you listening to what she said last night?
A dog's sense of smell varies in
relation to the type of scent, but...
It's said to be one hundred million
times stronger than a human's.
The cardigan had Yoriko-san's scent on it, so...
Then, shouldn't he have smelled Kinue san, too?
If his sense of smell really is that strong.
That's right.
Even if he smelled both scents and got confused...
It's hard to believe he'd completely
mistake her for Yoriko-san.
And, why do you think Musashi went
directly for Kinue-san's throat?
Wouldn't he go for her hand or leg first?
And those bloodstains are kind of strange, too.
Bloodstains?
Around the area where Yoriko-san fell, there
were a few splatters going towards the hedge.
Oh, it's been confirmed that those stains
are the same blood type as Kinue-san's.
Most likely, when Yoriko-san held Kinue san in her arms...
Blood got on her hands and rubbed off
on the cane when she touched it.
If that's the case, then isn't it weird that none
of that blood came off near Musashi?
Come to think of it, that is strange.
This is just another of his jokes.
Don't let him lead you around.
Hey, aren't there other points that concern you?
Yeah, there actually are.
First, the fact that we've discovered that Yoriko-san and
Kinue-san didn't get along very well from the start.
According to testimony from the husband's sister...
The cause is that even though he's over forty,
he still caters to his mother as much as possible.
And the shirt that Yoriko-san dropped
was one that Kinue-san had purchased.
So that's why Kinue-san went to get it herself.
The next piece of information we learned
is that Kinue-san had a weak heart.
She did?
The third point we heard from the Tsutsumi couple is that,
even though Yoriko-san was originally pleasant to them...
Over time she's refused to speak
even when they met face-to-face.
Musashi even used to stick to Yoriko-san like glue.
And then all of a sudden, he began
to bark whenever he saw her.
By the way, it seems Yoriko-san was a junior
high school art teacher before she married.
The couple doesn't have any children.
Even so, no matter how you look at the circumstances,
I still think Musashi was the one responsible.
No way!
It wasn't Musashi, was it, Conan kun?
Speaking of dogs attacking humans...
There was that one incident with John.
Hey, it's your owner on the phone.
The owner made it so that whenever John heard
a combination of a certain phrase and sound...
He was programmed to attack a person.
But this time...
Neither the Tsusumi couple nor Yoriko-san appear to
have been training Musashi for attacking people.
I've got it!
I've got it, Inspector!
This was a thoroughly researched, carefully planned murder.
A planned murder?
The murderer is none other than Nakatani Yoriko.
She's continuously been on bad
terms with her mother-in-law.
So much so that she ultimately wanted to kill her.
And she also resented her neighbors
the Tsutsumis and their pet dog.
The Tsutsumi couple, too?
The reason is most likely envy.
Even though the couple is much
younger than she and her husband...
They're much more successful and get
to live in a more expensive residence.
I see.
And based on that, she thought up a way
to use Musashi to murder Kinue-san.
She first got a hold of a cane that's
similar in shape to Kinue-san's...
And when the Tsutsumis were gone from the house she
used the cane to antagonize Musashi over the hedge.
She also made sure to use a few
firecrackers and startle Musashi.
And then last night, she waited for an evening
when the Tsutsumis were out, called Kinue-san...
Spilled coffee on her clothing on purpose,
then had Kinue-san wear her own cardigan.
Once it got dark, she went to bring in the laundry and
dropped her husband's favorite shirt over the hedge.
She arranged everything so that Kinue-san
would most likely go to retrieve it.
Musashi noticed that someone had come into his
territory, and then saw the cane he hated so much.
On top of that, he smelled someone he hated
on the clothing Kinue-san was wearing.
Doing his best to indicate that he didn't want her to
come any closer, he most likely began to growl louder.
And that's when you came up from behind and...
You derived an ingenious method of killing her,
using the dog's senses of sight, smell, and hearing.
Since Kinue-san already had a heart condition...
It was possible that she'd go into cardiac
arrest merely by Musashi attacking her.
But, Musashi got a hold of Kinue-san's
throat, and he caused her to hemorrhage.
That was even better than you'd hoped for.
Is this true, Yoriko?
And you're supposed to be a great detective?
Since you've gone this far, I assume you have evidence?
You'll see for yourself shortly.
But before that, would you mind letting
us borrow the clothes you're wearing?
And that cane as well.
Listen up.
After Satou-kun throws the firecrackers, as soon as Musashi
reaches for her, pull on that leash as hard as you can, got it?
Yes, sir, I understand.
Takagi-kun, I'm counting on you.
Satou-san, I'll protect you even if it costs me my life.
If he gets agitated after hearing the
firecrackers, Musashi's likely the one.
But more likely...
All right.
Let him loose!
All right, come here.
Good boy!
That's impossible!
See?
Didn't I tell you?
Is that so?
We heard about the incident on the news.
We've been really worried.
So is Musashi still with the police?
Yes.
Since Kinue-san was technically
trespassing on the property...
Good girl!
The Tsutsumis and Musashi won't be
punished for any wrongdoing, but...
Go get it!
We've got to hurry and work out the truth behind all this.
Got to get more information.
Hey, why don't we go see the Tsutsumis?
Yeah.
Good idea.
You're moving away?
Yeah.
Even though no one's blaming us, the fact that Musashi
attacked Kinue-san and caused her death still stands.
We just can't live here anymore.
I see...
That did you find this time?
What's this?
That's...
Musashi's toothbrush.
Toothbrush?
The last time we brushed his teeth, he even
had clay stuck between them, didn't he?
By the way, it seems Yoriko-san was a junior
high school art teacher before she married.
Don't tell me...
When you think of clay and art...
Our deduction that you deliberately provoked
Musashi into attacking Kinue-san was flawed.
Musashi did nothing wrong.
You're the one who killed Kinue-san.
"I'm the one"?
Just what are you saying, Inspector?
You had Musashi bite into some clay, then made
a plaster mold out of his teeth indentations.
You used your previous experience as an
art teacher to work out the logistics.
That night, when Kinue-san went next door to retrieve the
shirt you'd purposely dropped, you pushed her from behind.
Musashi was severely agitated by the violence
he'd witnessed and began to bark loudly.
You used the firecrackers to startle Musashi and
buy some time to get back to your house, but...
On the way there you slipped and twisted your ankle.
That's when the Tsutsumi couple arrived, and you
told them that Kinue-san had been attacked.
And, while the couple remained focused
on checking Kinue-san's condition...
You took the teeth mold and threw it
over the hedge onto your property.
This plaster mold of yours helped resolve
all of the loose ends in this case.
And the one who found it was Conan-kun here.
It wasn't me.
Coeur's the one who found it.
There's a reason why Musashi's saliva
was found on Kinue-san's wound.
When someone in their group is injured, dogs naturally
lick the wounded spot to help ease its healing.
You took advantage of that trait, didn't you?
Well, anything you'd like to say?
That woman...
Every time she came here, she'd look over at
our neighbors' house and say with a sigh...
"I should have chosen his wife myself."
Just because of that you...
That's right!
No matter how much older you got, you still clung to
your mother and did absolutely everything she said!
You'd never understand.
If only I hadn't sprained my ankle...
Your ankle will eventually heal itself!
But before you worry about that, don't you have
something more important you need to heal?
Say, I've been wondering about this for a while, but...
The name "Coeur" doesn't really seem
like something you'd call a girl.
Could it be that it's not the English meaning?
You're right!
It comes from the French "Coeur.''
I had no idea...
In French it means, ''Heart."
Heart...
I'll bet that her heart was filled with wanting to help
her childhood friend when he was in trouble.
I wonder if my Musashi has a spirit like that.
Oh, I'm sure he does...
Nope, I don't think so.
Because when there's a case, his heart's nowhere near here.
You've got me there.
Conan-kun, did you say something?