Success! Integrity!
Evidence and its impact!
An endless drive
to become the best!
Somebody wants to
interview the Detective Boys!
But while we're anticipating
the public's attention...
An unexpected case arises!
He sees the single
truth for what it is...
And looks like a kid,
but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Sorry I kept you waiting.
I apologize for coming at a time when you're so busy.
No, it's no trouble at all.
I'm...
As you can see
here on my card...
I'm Kobayashi Sumiko,
the homeroom teacher of class 1-B.
Please, have a seat.
You're a freelance writer?
Oh...
Yes, I am.
I thought I'd made a name for myself lately with my articles in women's magazines...
But it seems I may have
been making too much of it.
Oh! No, I just don't
read magazines very often...
Sorry about that.
Please, don't worry about it.
I'm not the least bit upset.
So, um...
What did you
want to see me about?
If you're here for a story
about bullying or something...
I'll let you know that my class
doesn't have any problems like that.
No, no...
Nothing like that.
I want to do a story on...
The "Detective Boys"
who are in your class!
What?
T-The Detective Boys?
You mean that club Kojima-kun
and his friends formed?
Yeah!
Yes. I heard a lot about
those children's activities.
But they just randomly decided to
call themselves the "Detective Boys"...
In reality, they simply
look for lost cats and so on...
Hey...
Minami! Megumi! Ai!
Haven't we heard those
names somewhere before...?
It says they're three fierce ones!
But members of
the police told me...
That they also contribute their
services with murder cases and such.
Particularly a boy by the
name of Edogawa Conan...
What? Conan-kun?
I see...
So, the title of
this article will be...
"The 21st Century Revival
of the Boy Detectives Club!"
I'm absolutely certain that
will grab everyone's attention.
Um, well...
I don't know what to say...
Interview with the
Detective Boys, Part I!
What...?!
An interview?
With us, the Detective Boys?
Wow!
That's right!
You see, a writer named Sugimori-san visited me after school yesterday.
He told me he really wants to write a
human interest story about your activities...
And asked me to
cooperate with him.
That sounds fun!
I'm getting so excited!
S-So...
Do you have a cold,
Kobayashi-sensei?
That's certainly not good.
It seems like it.
Though it doesn't seem
like I have a fever yet...
But I have a runny nose
and can't stop sneezing.
Are you okay,
Kobayashi-sensei?
Did you take any medicine?
By any chance, do your eyes itch?
Yes, they do.
I was up late last
night grading tests...
So my eyes must be tired.
That's hay fever!
What? No way!
That can't be it.
I've been strong against that kind of thing ever since I was a child.
So, you see...
Hay fever is
caused when antigens...
In other words, the substances that cause allergies, enter one's body.
Antibodies are created to fight off those antigens...
And once those have accumulated
inside the body beyond a certain level...
The antigens and the
antibodies react to each other...
And get converted into substances that cause allergy symptoms.
But because the antigen-carrying pollen is limited to being formed only one time a year...
It takes many months and
years for them to build up.
That's why, even if
they were fine as a child...
There are often cases of people
developing hay fever in their 20's and 30's.
Oh, so that's it!
And?
What about the interview?
Well, of course...
We, the Detective Boys,
have obviously gotta do it!
Don't we?!
Yes!
Looks like a
rain shower's coming.
But those guys sure are late...
They're the ones who said we'd
meet up 30 minutes beforehand, too.
Now, listen!
30 minutes before!
We're gonna meet
up 30 minutes before!
Don't be late!
You got that, Conan?!
What, you're asking me?!
Yeah, I got it...
Oh?
But are you okay
with that, Kojima-kun?
Huh?
Of course I am!
Anyway...
Dress normally
tomorrow, you guys.
Yes, because we want to have him see
the Detective Boys just as we really are!
You sure are smart!
Yeah, let's do our best!
Hey, Conan!
Thanks for waiting up!
We're sorry
we kept you waiting!
Sorry, Conan-kun!
Were you waiting long?
Hey!
You guys are late!
What've you been doing?!
But that was 'cause
Ayumi was taking forever...
Well, I wanted
to do a bunch of stuff.
That's fine, isn't it?
After all, she is a girl.
Please let this slide.
Man, I guess
I've got no choice.
By the way,
where's Haibara?
I'm right here.
When did she...?
More importantly, you guys...
What's with those clothes?
This isn't what
we talked about!
Ta-da!
What do you think?
After all, we are
getting interviewed.
Isn't that right, Mitsuhiko?!
Yes.
We must not let ourselves be interviewed in anything but our very best attire!
Because so many
people will be looking at us!
Yeah, exactly!
Aw...
Why did this have to happen?
It starts raining right when
we're going to be interviewed.
God's so mean...
He sure is.
It was sunny
all day yesterday, too...
What's the big idea?
Mitsuhiko, this is your fault
for telling us to dress normally!
Huh...?
What are you talking about?!
Wasn't that you, Genta-kun?
My formal clothes are getting drenched in this rain, making them a complete mess!
My shoes are soaked...
And my parents just
bought them for me last night!
These guys are
getting way too into this.
We'll be fine.
As long as we have him let us use his
dryer or something before the interview.
Isn't it at the writer's place?
But TVs nowadays all
display in high definition.
If we're filmed going into the home
with wet spots from the rain on our clothes...
What?!
There's gonna be
TV cameras coming, too?!
Oh, brother. Of course not.
Maybe they're gonna
do a special about us!
In that case, I'm sure a beautiful
female TV reporter will be there, too!
Then I hope it's
Mizunashi Rena-san!
Me too!
She couldn't possibly come.
After all, she's currently
lying in a hospital bed.
Yeah...
That anchorwoman who's part of the men in black...
Apparently hasn't
regained consciousness yet.
Hey...
This interview couldn't be
related to them, could it?
No way.
No matter how you think about it, inviting five kids to your house is bound to attract attention.
It's hard to picture them doing something that could leave a trail to them if someone saw.
Don't they operate in the shadows, where no one will sense them?
Yes, that's right.
Besides, if they were planning to target either of us...
They wouldn't have called
on an adult to come with us.
Sorry, kids!
Did I keep you all waiting?
K-Kobayashi-sensei?
She looks just
like Detective Sato...
What's the matter?
H-Hey...
Y-You forgot your glasses!
Oh, this?
I decided to wear
contacts for a change!
What do you think?
Is this no good?
Maybe I look funny like this?
You don't look funny at all!
Your clothes are feminine,
and look really nice!
You look even
prettier than normal, Miss!
Thanks!
I'm happy you think so.
This writer was a
real looker, wasn't he?
No, not at all!
That's not it at all.
But it'd be better to
give up on the contacts!
Your eyes are itchy from your hay fever, so
being irritated by the contacts isn't good for them!
Okay, okay...
My glasses...
I'll be fine if I wear my glasses, right?
Yeah, doing that's
much better for you!
It looks like there isn't much pollen in
the air right now because it started raining...
But there could be a lot of pollen
accumulated in the writer's home!
And I think you should dust off that fancy
trim really well before entering the house...
So you don't bring
any pollen inside, either.
You're right. I'll do that.
Well, Miss?
Was the writer handsome?
W-Well, he
wasn't bad-looking...
He's friendly and
very easy to talk to...
So I'm sure you'll be able to get along with him pretty quickly!
And he said he's famous for his experience in writing for women's magazines...
So I'm sure he knows
how to handle children, too!
He said he's famous?!
He's a star?
Then he must live in an
unbelievably huge mansion!
Maybe he'll have his own chef... and even a pastry chef, too!
He must be gonna treat us to an awesome feast for dinner!
No, I know he will!
Oh, um...
That's expecting
a bit too much...
Is this it?
S-Sure looks that way...
This isn't a mansion...
Isn't this just
a regular apartment?
With this, don't
expect a TV camera crew...
Or a beautiful
female TV reporter, either!
Well, that's okay!
Now you all can talk more freely, without feeling nervous, right?
Hey...
Did that writer really say he
wanted to interview us in his home?
These look to have no more than
single, nine square-meter rooms.
No, the interview will
be at a nearby restaurant.
Oh, no!
I was supposed to call him when we got to the bus stop down the street!
I knew it.
I have to call him right away!
That's okay!
Since we're already here...
We can get this over with more quickly if we have him interview us in his home.
Yes, let's.
You need to get it together.
I wonder if he'll be surprised
when we all suddenly show up.
Yes, he might be.
Don't make too
much noise in there, now!
Oh? Is he out?
No, the morning paper is still stuck in the mail slot.
So maybe he's still asleep.
H-Hey!
It's unlocked...
Wait, Genta-kun!
S-Sugimori-san?!
Stay out of the room, Miss!
What?
If you, who's acquainted with him, had a
strand of your hair happen to fall in this room...
Wouldn't it only
cast suspicion on you?
For now, please call for an
ambulance and the police, Miss!
Because they might think it's a prank if we called, 'cause we're kids!
Oh, okay...
No, there's no
need for an ambulance.
His body's completely stiff.
He's been dead
for at least half a day!
S-Stiff?
Dead for half a day?
And this could be...
What are you waiting for?!
Hurry!
A-All right!
The victim is
Sugimori Masato-san, age 32.
He was a
freelance writer, correct?
Y-Yes, that's right...
We had an appointment to meet with him today.
He said he wanted
to interview the children.
So this is how you found him when you got here, huh?
Yes, sir.
Incidentally, when did he
approach you about that interview?
It was in the early evening the day before yesterday.
He stopped by the school.
So that means he was
alive until at least then...
Hey, Miss...
Didn't you tell Sugimori-san
that we accepted the interview?
Yes, I did...
I called Sugimori-san before
noon yesterday and told him.
Do you remember the exact time?
Oh, just a second...
I'm pretty sure I called him from this
phone between third and fourth period...
So I might know if
I check the call log!
It was 11:22 AM.
Which means that the murder took place after that time...
Inspector!
Oh, what is it?
This camera tripod seems
to be the murder weapon!
Hmm...
The killer made it this far into
the room before bludgeoning him...
So that means there's a strong chance
that they were someone he knew.
Yes.
Since the victim was a writer...
We could consider someone he interviewed as the perpetrator.
That's right...
It's also possible it was someone who held a grudge against him for a scandalous article.
Oh, but if he wrote an article about a celebrity or such...
It might be a fan who
resented him over what he wrote.
So the suspects are countless...
I think there are four
people who are suspicious.
What?
C-Conan-kun...?!
See? Take a look at the button for
the answering machine on this phone!
Oh?
T-The light's blinking.
It seems to have
four new messages.
But Conan-kun, why do you think
these four messages are suspicious?
Look closer!
At the edge of that button!
Can't you tell?
The blood on it
has been rubbed off.
What?!
Oh!
You're right...
So that means...
Somebody pushed the answering machine button after the blood spattered on it, huh?
I wonder who did
something like that?
W-Well...
It was after the
victim was attacked...
If the victim pushed it while barely
remaining conscious after the murderer fled...
He would have called 110 for help,
instead of checking the answering machine.
Besides, Inspector...
There's no blood
on the victim's fingers!
So that means that the
murderer pushed the button?
Right.
I can only think that the murderer turned the answering machine on after striking the victim.
In that case,
why'd they do that?
I'm sure that was because they didn't want
the deceased Sugimori-san to be discovered.
That way,
even if someone called...
It would make them think he was out, so they wouldn't drop by.
But the key to this
room is on the table...
And the door was unlocked!
Oh? The key...?
I think they would lock the door if they
didn't want Sugimori-san to be found dead.
Y-Yes, you're right.
Then the remaining possibility is...
The killer...
Left a message on
the answering machine...
To create an alibi!
That explains why they
didn't bother to lock the door!
Exactly!
If the discovery of
the body was delayed...
And the estimated time of death became uncertain...
Wouldn't the alibi
they made go to waste?
What?
Okay!
Let's listen to these right now!
What is going on?
Who is  this boy?
Okay, let's hear the
voices of the four suspects!
Oh!
W-Wait a minute, Inspector!
Oh?
What's wrong?
Shouldn't we listen while recording it, just in case?
That way, we can listen to them
again as many times as we need.
And if we accidentally
delete them while listening...
It would cause a
lot of problems, you know?
R-Right.
May I ask the forensics team
to bring recording equipment?
Please do.
Um, excuse me!
Hey, Conan!
Is the killer's voice really
on that answering machine?!
Yeah.
The blood that splattered on the machine's "on" button was partially smeared off.
After the murderer bludgeoned Sugimori-san to death...
They intentionally turned it on...
And left a message on the
answering machine to create an alibi.
But couldn't the murderer have done that on purpose in order to throw off the investigation?
Then, take a look
at that over there!
What...?
There's blood on
the front doorknob.
That's proof that the
murderer left in a hurry...
Without noticing there
was blood on his or her fingers.
Oh! You're right!
There certainly is blood on it.
The way the blood is smeared on the
answering machine button wasn't intentional.
It doesn't seem like they had a
sudden bright idea to try to trick us...
But since there are no
fingerprints on the bloody doorknob...
It does look like the
murderer was wearing gloves.
Hold on, there!
Huh?
Aren't you going a little
too fast from the get-go?
Oh?
This is fine for Detective Takagi and Inspector Megure, because they're used to you.
But this is the first time Kobayashi-sensei has seen your deductive reasoning skills!
So she's belittled!
What?
Hold yourself back a little!
What do you mean,
"hold myself back?"
She's looking at me, too...
This isn't good...
Oh?
Aren't you always doing that?
Huh?
Doing what?
Your "Oh, hey!" or
your "Isn't that funny?"
Put on your somewhat
absent-minded child act.
Why, you...
I'm sure you know this...
But if the public learns about your detective work...
They'll eventually
get wind of it too.
Yeah, I know!
That's why I wasn't planning
on talking much at this interview.
I'm not so sure about that.
But is it true?
Is Sugimori-san, the victim, really a famous writer...?
Well, yes.
Sugimori-san told me so himself
when he visited the school the other day.
He said he'd made
quite a name for himself lately...
In that case, isn't it strange that he's
not living somewhere better than this?
There's always the chance that
Sugimori-san was lying through his teeth.
No! He...
I know, I know...!
It's kind of embarrassing,
now that she's mentioned it...
Oh, hey!
Look at that!
There's a funny key hanging from Sugimori-san's waist!
Huh?
Oh?
See!
It's got a silver horsie on it!
I bet he liked animals!
H-Hey!
Oh, excuse me.
This is the key to a Ferrari.
The super-car?
I-Is that a super-car?
But if that's true...
Sugimori-san may have been a man
who spent everything he had on his car.
Sometimes, people will make huge cuts
to their living expenses to maintain a luxury car.
Hmm...
And the fact that he kept the keys to this room on a different chain...
Means he was
probably showing off.
H-Hey, Conan.
What's up with that...
"Oh, hey! Look at that!"
Just now?!
It's that kind of behavior that
makes adults look down on us kids!
It's cute, but you might
be acting a bit too childish.
Yeah, Conan!
Please stop
doing things like that.
O-Oh, come on!
But...
No matter how
I go about doing this...
It's not gonna be easy...
Isn't this...
Your voice, Miss?
Whoa!
So our teacher
might be the killer?!
No...
There's only one person
who has a solid alibi...
Hey, slow down...
Oh, right...
Kobayashi-sensei
was suspicious of me.
Hay fever?
Now that you mention it, weren't all
three of them involved with hay fever?
Hey, there's
something I want to ask you...
Here it comes...!
On the next Conan:
Interview with the Detective Boys, Part II!
Next
Conan's
Hint!
Railroad crossing sound.
The movie's finally opened!
The Private Eyes' Éclair!
It's 'Requiem'!