Success! Integrity!
Evidence and its impact!
An endless drive
to become the best!
In a surprising case
at the interview location...
The Detective Boys
all band together...
With deductive reasoning that
puts the police detectives to shame!
He sees the single
truth for what it is...
And looks like a kid,
but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Sugimori Masato-san,
a popular freelance writer...
Came to Teitan Elementary, saying he
wanted to interview the Detective Boys...
About our activities.
The following day, we
went with Kobayashi-sensei...
To pay a visit to
Sugimori-san's home.
But there, we discovered
Sugimori-san's deceased body!
After analyzing
the scene of the crime...
I determined that the four messages left
on the answering machine were suspicious.
Interview with the
Detective Boys, Part II!
Oh, Inspector!
The recording equipment's here!
Ah, right!
Now, let's start
with the first message.
Isn't that the sound of a
nearby railroad crossing?
Oh man, it sure is long...
The warning bell's been
going off for over two minutes...
It—
It stopped.
So let's start
with the first message.
You have four new messages.
Oh, Sugimori-kun?
This is Haruka.
It seems I had too
much to drink last night.
I'm sorry.
I'm not angry with you anymore.
Speaking of hay fever, it looks like a
significant amount of pollen is in the air...
You never take me
back to your place...
So has everyone watching taken some kind of precautions against hay fever?
So I just thought you might
have a girl besides me on the side.
That's right!
The "All-Around Special Info" for April 22nd is on hay fever!
Anyway, call me
when you get this.
Received Friday at 11:25 AM.
Inspector...
Could you hear the sound of a
TV playing in the background, too?
Yes.
That was "Full-Blast TV",
the program Nichiuri TV airs at 11 AM.
April 22nd was just yesterday...
So if we asked the TV station,
they should know what time this was on air.
This is Higaki...
I wanted to see you
and apologize in person...
The next station is Okuho. Okuho.
Please watch your step as you leave—
So I'm on my way there now.
But if you're out,
I'll drop by some other day.
I'm real sorry about your car.
Later.
Received Friday at 11:27 AM.
So now we could hear a train's on-board announcements in the background?
Okuho Station
is quite far from here...
So it would take over
30 minutes, even on a train.
Um...
This is Inaba from Koeikan.
I wanted to ask you about your
progress on the article we requested.
Editor-in-chief, sir,
what's today's date again?
It's April 22nd, 11:28 AM!
As you heard, you have one week until the deadline, so please give it your all!
Chief, are we still going
to the game tonight?
Oh, and if this is about
the scoop we discussed...
I'm not upset
about it anymore.
Don't worry!
It's at the Tohto Dome tonight.
I look forward to working with you in the future!
Received Friday at 11:29 AM.
This time,
I heard people's voices.
Sounds like he called
from the company office.
It sounded like there was the editor-in-chief
and one other person besides the caller.
Isn't Koeikan also
pretty far from here?
Yes...
One would have to transfer trains, or travel about an hour by car.
Now for the last message...
Hi again.
I called you earlier, too...
Oh?
But this is K-Kobayashi, homeroom teacher for Teitan Elementary Class 1-B—
Oh, I'm sorry!
It looks like I've
come down with hay fever...
There was something I wanted to ask you,
but I'll bring it up when we meet tomorrow.
W-Well, I'll see you tomorrow...
Received Friday at 11:30 AM.
Isn't this...
Your voice, Miss?
Y-Yes...
Whoa!
So our teacher
might be the killer?!
What...?!
No, hardly.
If our teacher
was the murderer...
She would have forced her way into
the room and rushed over to the body.
That way, when
the police investigate later...
She could easily mislead them, even if they
found a strand of her hair or her fingerprints.
Hey...
You need to hold
yourself back a little, too!
Oh, sorry.
Incidentally, what was it you mentioned wanting to ask him in the message?
Ah, yes... It was about the
interview with the children.
Then, you can confirm that you left
that message yesterday at 11:30 AM?
Yes.
You can also hear the bell
ringing for the start of fourth period.
When third period ended at 11:22 AM yesterday...
I called Sugimori-san to tell him
that they accepted the interview.
But right afterwards, I remembered my question and called him back.
But that time, I only
got his answering machine.
Which means the the murder occurred between 11:22 AM and 11:30 AM.
But Inspector...
The clock on this phone is accurate,
according to the teacher's testimony.
Which means it occurred in
the three minutes between 11:22...
And when the first
message was left at 11:25.
Three minutes...?
That was awfully well-executed.
Yes, it was.
Come to think of it, when I called to accept the interview...
He said something about how someone would be coming to visit him soon.
Oh?
What was their name?
I don't know.
T-The police?!
If this is about the fines for my
parking tickets, I already paid those!
Ah, no...
This is about Sugimori-san...
You left a message on his answering
machine before noon yesterday, correct?
Y-Yes, I did...
I got awfully drunk the night before...
And it seems I started a fight with him...
Do you remember
where you called him from?
I called on my cell phone
from this apartment.
Do you have anyone
who can verify that?
No, not really.
Why?
Ah, no.
We'll give you the details later.
We'll send a car to pick you up,
so could I have your address, please?
Okay.
Rizen-cho, 1...
Rizen-cho, huh?
That's quite far from here, too...
What?
Did I call Sugimori?
Yeah, I did yesterday...
From a train on
the Tohto Loop Line.
But all I got was
his answering machine.
Were you with
anyone at the time?
Nope, I was alone.
Oh, don't tell me...
Did he storm into the police about the
scratch I got on the bumper of his Ferrari?
I borrowed his car, and only
grazed it on a telephone pole.
But he was pissed.
I'm sorry, but
Inaba just stepped out.
Though I think
he'll be back soon.
Oh...
I'm Hayashi,
the editor-in-chief.
What do the
police want with him?
Do you know where he went around 11:30 AM yesterday?
I don't know...
Our editors come
and go all the time.
He left a message on a
certain person's answering machine...
And we could hear your
voice in the background.
You said,
"It's April 22nd, 11:28 AM!"
Oh, then he must have been
here at the editorial department!
His cell phone's been acting up,
so he often asks me the date and time.
I've been telling him for the past
year to hurry and buy a new one, but...
Chief, are you going
to the game tonight?
Are you okay?
I'm worried about that, since
it's not at the Tohto Dome today.
No, not the game...
I'm talking about your health!
Oh, I got over that cold
after a good night's sleep.
My eyes aren't that
inflamed anymore, either...
So I'm sure I
must have been tired.
Oh, Inaba-kun!
There's a call from the police for you!
Huh?
The police?
What could they want?
Okay, Inaba-san.
We'll send someone out to get you shortly...
So please remain at
the editorial department.
Yeah, it's weird!
What's the matter?
In the second message...
The on-board
announcement is strange.
Normally, it should say
"Please watch your step as you leave the train."
Please watch your
step as you leave—
But if you're out,
I'll drop by some other day.
They're right.
The announcement
stops at "as you leave".
I'm real sorry about your car.
For now, why don't
we call and verify this?
Later.
What?!
The conductor
making the announcements...
Had hay fever?
Yes...
It was me.
I suddenly came down
with hay fever yesterday...
And I couldn't make it around the loop line even once...
So I ended up having someone
fill in for me just past noon.
I-I see...
It sounds like he stopped at "as you leave" because he was trying not to sneeze.
So that's it.
And when my wife checked about
"Full-Blast TV" that was in the first message...
It seems that information about hay fever really did start around 11:25 AM.
Which means that all three of them seem to have alibis.
No...
There's only one person
who has a solid alibi...
Is that the railroad
crossing sound again?
Come to think of it, doesn't the
Tohto Loop Line run on the tracks outside?
The Tohto Loop Line takes an
hour to go around the loop once...
And I think the arrival and departure times are all the same from 11 AM to 5 PM on weekdays.
Well, for the time being...
Let's hear what the three who
left those messages have to say.
Yes.
Then, I'll go pick them up.
No...
I think you only need to...
Bring one person here.
What?!
Only one?
After the murderer
killed Sugimori-san...
They took the trouble to turn on
the answering machine in the room...
And left a message on it
to create an alibi, right?
So from those three messages...
And the calls Detective Takagi just made to the three who left them...
Can't you tell who's
suspicious, and who's not?
Here's a hint: hay fever.
Oh, right...
Kobayashi-sensei
was suspicious of me.
But I'm just a kid,
so I might be wrong!
Hay fever, huh?
Come to think of it, weren't all three of them involved with hay fever?
They're not listening to me...
At 11:25 AM...
In the background
of Haruka-san's message...
That's right!
The "All-Around Special Info" for April 22nd is on hay fever!
There was the sound of a TV program giving information on hay fever that had just started.
In Higaki-san's message,
left at 11:27 AM...
There was a peculiar on-board
announcement on the Tohto Loop Line...
Please watch your step as you leave—
That was because the conductor
making the announcements had hay fever.
And due to him needing
to try not to sneeze...
Someone filled in for him just past noon,
before the loop line had gone around once.
But in the message
Inaba-san left at 11:29 AM...
When asked for
the date and time...
It's April 22nd, 11:28 AM!
There was only the voice of the
editor-in-chief answering as such.
Nothing related to
hay fever was in it!
Right...
Hey...
When Detective Takagi just called the editor-in-chief, didn't he say...
That he got over his cold after a good night's sleep, and his eyes weren't inflamed anymore?
Kobayashi-sensei, isn't
that what happened to you?
Y-Yes...
But I had hay fever, not a cold.
Slow down.
That's it! The
editor-in-chief had hay fever!
But does that have
anything to do with this case?
It might be best to call
all of them here, after all...
It's a little over an hour!
No, it's not!
It's exactly an hour!
What was that?!
What's wrong, you two?
What was what?
It's the time it takes the Tohto Loop Line to go around the loop once...
Those two are
quibbling over how long it is.
One time, my mom and I fell asleep on the train while on the way home.
Since it would be a pain to change trains, we just rode around the loop.
We got home a
little over an hour late!
But I believe the time schedule
says it's exactly one hour!
The inbound and outbound
trains are slightly different...
But they both
take about an hour.
Come to think of it...
That conductor with hay fever
was announcing Okuho Station...
Isn't that 30 minutes away, no matter
if you take the inbound or outbound train?
Y-Yeah...
Because Okuho Station is on the opposite end of the loop.
If that conductor got off just past noon,
before the loop line went around once...
Wouldn't that mean he got on
just after 11 AM, at the earliest?
Y-Yes, it would.
A-And so...?
Hey, Ayumi-chan...
Oh, right!
Hey!
What if Higaki-san only
said he called from the train...
But he actually recorded the announcement and played it back while he made the call?!
I-I get it!
If he did that, it would sound
like he was calling from the train!
I don't think that's it.
The conductor said he suddenly
came down with hay fever just yesterday.
If the conductor boarded
the train around 11:00 AM...
That means the announcement
could only be recorded after 11:00 AM.
Higaki-san left his
message at 11:27 AM.
So if he was close to Okuho Station,
which is over 30 minutes away from here...
Leaving a message with the
train's on-board announcement is...
He had to come here, and turn the answering machine on after killing Sugimori-san...
So that isn't possible.
I guess Higaki-san is innocent.
Right.
B-But you know...
Wait, Genta.
Huh?
Not yet.
Okay, go ahead!
B-But you know the sound of the
TV in that Haruka lady's message...
Would be easy to have in a
message left right from this room!
There.
I get it!
She used that TV, didn't she?
Oh?
If she turned the answering
machine on after killing him...
And called here while that TV
was playing in the background...
Wouldn't it seem as though she called from somewhere else?
That would mean Haruka-san is the most suspicious.
Oh, what's that?
There's people making noise outside!
You're right.
"Hurry!
I've gotta get through!"
"Again?!
This takes forever!"
Do you think this is...
The railroad crossing?
Speaking of which...
Didn't it go off before we started
listening to the messages earlier, too?
This seems this railroad crossing goes off for over two minutes.
And if you use your phone
to look up the time schedule...
It looks like a train comes
through here around 11:24 AM.
And Haruka-san's message was left on the answering machine at 11:25 AM.
According to
Kobayashi-sensei's statement...
The murder took place in the three minutes between 11:22 AM and 11:25 AM.
If it was Haruka-san...
Coming here, looking for
Sugimori-san to have an opening...
Clubbing him to death
with the camera's tripod...
Pushing the answering
machine's on button...
And leaving the room would use up almost all that time!
It's just as Conan-kun
and the others said.
Since she left a message on the answering machine with the TV in the background...
It would have had to be
from this room or close to it.
But the fact that the sound of the
railroad crossing wasn't in the message...
Means she left the message
somewhere considerably far from here.
So Haruka-san couldn't have
committed the murder, either.
Then that leaves only Inaba-san.
Isn't that right, Conan-kun?
Yep!
You're probably right!
What?!
Sugimori-san was killed?!
The murder took place between
11:22 AM and 11:25 AM yesterday.
Where were
you during that time?
I-I was at the
editorial department!
Didn't you hear
the message I left?
Um...
This is Inaba from Koeikan.
I wanted to ask you about your
progress on the article we requested.
Editor-in-chief, sir,
what's today's date again?
It's April 22nd, 11:28 AM!
See?
The chief's voice is on there!
So there's no
doubt about it, is there?
Okay, Mitsuhiko...
Oh, oww...!
What's wrong,
Mitsuhiko-kun?
My stomach suddenly...
It might have been the mini cup of
creamer I put in my tea this morning!
The bag that had the expiration date written on it was torn...
So I knew it said "April",
but I couldn't read the rest...
You know, you'll be fine if it was only two or three days...
But you'll have major problems
if that was from a year ago.
"If that was from a year ago?"
Um...
Shouldn't Genta-kun
have taken this role?
That's it! A year ago!
He was able to record that
message a year ago, on April 22nd!
The editor-in-chief never says April 22nd of which year...
And he never specified which article
was requested during the phone call!
I see.
So yesterday, one year
after he recorded that tape...
He used it to leave an message on the
answering machine after committing the murder...
In order to create an alibi.
U-Um...
What gives you that idea?
I really did call from the
company office yesterday!
Miss...
You don't really want to go outside when you have hay fever, do you?
N-No...
That reminds me...
Didn't the editor-in-chief
guy have hay fever, too?
What?
All day long today, he was
saying, "It's a cold, it's a cold".
If he thought he had a cold, that's all
the more reason he wouldn't say this:
"Chief, are we still going
to the game tonight?"
"Don't worry!
It's at the Tohto Dome tonight."
Sounded like he was quite enthusiastic about going to the night game.
The chief's a huge fan of pro baseball, so he'd go even if he caught a cold!
I don't know if he
went yesterday, though.
But, you know...
When Detective Takagi first called and talked to the editor-in-chief, he said...
"I'm worried about that, since
it's not at the Tohto Dome today."
T-The chief
must've been mistaken...
Then was he "worried"
about the weather?
Y-Yeah...
With the weather was like it was today,
it might get rained out if there wasn't a roof!
Then what about the "Don't worry! It's at the Tohto Dome tonight"...
On the answering machine?
That was about
the weather, too.
But...
It was sunny all day yesterday!
So that's it.
A year ago, it was
raining on April 22...
And it seems there wasn't
much pollen in the air, either.
N-No, that's...
All just speculation!
It's not like you could
hear raindrops in the message!
Besides, you don't have
any proof that I did it!
Hey...
Your motorcycle out
front was awfully muddy.
You don't wash
it very often, do you?
N-No...
And your boots are
dirty and worn out!
Why didn't you
buy new ones, too?
"T-Too?"
After all, didn't you
just buy your gloves, Mister?
The price tag's still on them!
So that's it!
While committing the murder, you
were wearing the gloves you always use.
And you must have bought a replacement set when you realized blood had gotten on them.
What's more, the fact that the price tag is still on them...
Means you probably only
realized that on your way here.
Well, then...
Why don't we test for blood on
places you're likely to have touched?
We'll start with the handlebars of the
motorcycle you said you haven't washed.
As suspected, traces of blood
from the victim, Sugimori-san...
Was found on the
handlebars of the motorcycle.
The motive for the murder was the
"scoop" he had mentioned in the message.
For three years, the two of them...
Had been working on a story about certain
major politicians suspected of being corrupt.
But Sugimori-san sold it to another
magazine that offered a higher price for it.
Inaba-san stated in a trembling voice, that he didn't care about the money.
He had only wanted to publish
the story in his own magazine.
In the end, his interview
with the Detective Boys...
Was just a trick to
make his story seem coherent.
I'm tired...
That's 'cause
we had to talk a lot.
I was so nervous!
They say "the best place
to hide a leaf is in a forest."
So by dividing your
lines among the children...
You made it so
you wouldn't stand out.
Pretty much.
Now our teacher won't...
Hey, kids...
There's something
I want to ask you...
Here it comes...!
Have you heard
of Edogawa Ranpo?
Yes.
Isn't he the guy who wrote the book with
Akechi Kogoro and the Fiend with Twenty Faces?
Yeah!
You five are just like the
"Boy Detectives Club" that's in those!
I'm a huge fan!
That's why I have
a favor to ask you!
What?
You're just gonna tell us not to do dangerous stuff, aren't you?
We'll be fine.
We always
think before we act!
Actually, I want you to let
me join the Detective Boys!
Can I?
What...?!
No grown-ups allowed!
Please act your age!
She references her name to Kobayashi Yoshio, the
leader of the Boy Detectives Club in Edogawa Ranpo's novels.
But my name is Kobayashi!
So there's no reason
not to let me join, is there?
Looks like I'll still be okay.
Yes, it does.
What?!
Another interview?!
That's right!
And of course, I'll be going with you as the advisor of the Detective Boys!
So this one will go fine!
When did she
become our advisor?
And the interviewer is
none other than the famous—
We've had
enough of interviews.
Sounds tiring...
Oh, really?
That's what they said, so
I'm deeply sorry for the trouble.
No trouble at all.
I'm sorry for the sudden request.
Oh...
I thought Conan-kun
would accept it for sure...
It's a golden special
with Yoko-chan, and all...
I think their homeroom teacher must be a real tough one!
The Fiend with
Twenty Faces
Did you want him to
investigate something for you?
Damn it!
You have to make it, please!
On the next Conan:
Ueto Aya and Shin'ichi:
The Promise from 4 Years Ago!
Ready... Go!
Next Conan's Hint!
TV Drama.
This year's movie is incredible!
Yeah, it's the best!
What?!
You've seen it already?!