Victory! Honesty! The shocking evidence!
The impulse takes it to the limit!
Ueto Aya-san shares the spotlight for the first time.
Due to a case, Shinichi's promise comes up once again!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Really?
Yeah, Suba-kun and Kobayashi-kun!
I can't believe it!
It's true!
Yuki!
The tennis club's...
Kitada-kun?
Yuki...
Hey!
Kitada!
Kitada-kun?
Kitada...
Female High School Detective - Yuki's Casebook
Oshibana High School
The formula of deduction...
Must be applied to the equation of this mystery.
The solution is obvious from there.
As I thought...
As I thought, Sensei is the culprit!
This is the answer, isn't it?
UETO AYA & SHINICHI
THE PROMISE FROM 4 YEARS AGO
What's a pretty girl like me doing
here on a bright and sunny day...
Dusting things and tiring herself out?
It's that demon, I tell you! That demon!
I can't believe she got her daughter-in-law
to clean up an empty house.
Your mother-in-law really is a demon! A demon!
Hey, hey.
Don't bring up "daughter-in-law" or
"mother in-law" or anything like that.
I wanted to do this anyway.
I didn't even ask you to help, Sonoko.
I guess that's true.
But this really is something, isn't it?
The sheer number of books.
"Yami no Danshaku: Night Baron."
Books by Kudou Yuusaku are all over here, huh?
"Female High School Detective - Yuki's Casebook."
This...
They made a TV version of this a while ago, right?
Right, right!
It was a two-hour drama.
It's one of Dad's earlier works.
When I read it now, though, the story seems a bit childish.
Isn't this Ueto Aya-chan?
Yeah.
She had just received her first starring role...
And visited Shinichi's parents with her
manager when this picture was taken.
Now that you mention it, I think I've heard of it before.
It happened a few years ago...
It was in my first year of junior high,
so about four years ago, I think.
I was a really big fan of Aya-chan's back then, so...
After Shinichi told me...
I was so excited that I brought along.
something for her to sign, but...
Shinichi didn't seem too interested in Aya-chan.
He just played with his soccer ball by himself.
But I saw Aya-chan's expression...
And remember her looking especially serious.
Afterwards, I asked Shinichi what they were talking about.
What did he say?
Nothing.
That.
Really, I wonder what was said then...
Shinichi...
Maybe they were arranging some kind of date?
Sonoko, you...
How is that even possible?
Someone's at the door.
Yes?
Uhm...
Is Kudou Shinichi-san there?
Me?
Sounds like a young woman...
Sony, Shinichi isn't home right now...
May I ask who this is?
A young woman...
Ueto...
This is Ueto Aya.
Ueto Aya-chan?
It's really her!
It's really Ueto Aya-chan!
Do you remember me?
Yes.
You're Mouri Ran-san, right?
Shinichi-san's childhood friend.
Yes.
This is my classmate...
Suzuki Sonoko-chan here!
Nice to meet you!
Nice to meet you.
This is Conan-kun.
Good afternoon.
Ah, good afternoon...
You're embarrassed, aren't you, you little four-eyed brat?
Shut up.
Do you know when Shinichi-san will be back?
I don't know either.
Ever since he started investigating a certain case, he...
Miss, are you looking for Shinichi-niichan?
Did you want him to investigate something for you?
That's right.
Is there a way for me to contact Shinichi-san?
About that...
Even if you call his cell, most of the
time you have to leave a message.
But I can try calling him for you.
Sorry to trouble you.
That's useless, given I'm right here.
Well, if you want to have something
looked into, Mouri Kogorou can...
Uncle probably won't be able to do it.
Why's that?
He got drunk last night and didn't get up this morning.
No point getting him, then...
Just his answering machine again.
Is that so?
How frustrating...
Say, even if you have to leave a message...
If you tell him about the case in it,
Shinichi-niichan might come back.
That's true.
If it isn't too much trouble, could you tell us about it?
Next to my apartment building, there's
an old woman named Koda Fumie-san.
She's about 80 years old and lives alone.
Grandma and I are on good terms, so I visit
her house often while on vacation, but...
When I went to see her again today...
Grandma?
It's Aya.
I'm coming in now.
Grandma, I came to visit.
Grandma?
That's strange.
Where did she go?
Grandma usually leaves the door unlocked
whenever she goes to buy groceries nearby.
I thought today was no different...
So I waited at her house, but...
She didn't come home, did she?
Right.
I grew a little worried and decided to go
to the vegetable market to ask around.
In the end...
Ah, that old woman you're talking about just passed by.
When I asked her where she was
headed, she replied "Beika District."
Beika District?
Yeah.
That's all she said before hurrying on her way.
She definitely looked more flustered than usual.
I'm a little worried, myself.
And then, I called a taxi and got
to Beika as quickly as possible.
But I didn't know why Grandma would come here, so...
I had no idea where to start.
At that moment, Shinichi-san's name came to mind.
Although I only saw him that once, four years ago...
I've heard he became a very active high school detective...
And that he lives around here.
So that's why you came here to find him?
Yes.
But he and I...
Never mind that.
Does that old lady know anyone in Beika District?
I don't know.
Then, I should send Shinichi a mail with all this information.
Is there anything else you know about that old lady?
Shinichi-niichan has always said that the
more information you get, the better!
That's right.
What else...
When Grandma was younger, her
daughter died of some illness.
Her daughter?
Half a year ago, I found out about
it from one of Grandma's friends.
It was when Fumie-chan was about 40.
Her only daughter, A ako-chan, was only 17 years old.
Fumie-chan was an unwed mother,
raising Ayako-chan on her own.
That day, she went to work as usual...
While she was away, Ayako-chan suddenly became ill.
By the time Fumie-chan came back,
Ayako-chan was already, well...
Fumie-chan felt guilty for not being able
to see Ayako-chan one last time...
She kept thinking that she caused her daughter's death.
I never knew about that...
Fumie-chan won't tell anyone about it.
Now that I think about it...
You really look like Ayako-chan.
Even your name is Aya-chan.
That must be why she took a special liking to you.
I'm home.
I bought so much that it's made me late.
Welcome home.
You can't tell anyone what I just said.
Grandma was always smiling.
Never in my wildest dreams did I
think that she lived with such pain.
17 years old—that's around our age, huh?
It must have been hard...
For that old lady and her daughter.
If I remember correctly, her daughter really loved
classical music—particularly any of Mozart's works.
Is what she just said related to the situation?
I still don't know...
Maybe I can look at this another way?
Say, when Aya-san entered the living room...
The TV was already off, right?
Before Grandma went out, she
may have been watching it, right?
That's possible.
I saw that the newspaper on the table was
turned to a page with TV listings on it.
Was the tea cup half empty?
That means the old lady was watching TV...
And only left the house because
something came to mind, right?
Do you remember what channel it was on?
I remember.
While I was waiting for Grandma...
Nichiuri TV!
Nichiuri TV...
Nichiuri TV, right?
Yeah.
Conan-kun?
I just want to look into the types of shows she watches.
Shinichi-niichan doesn't subscribe
to any newspapers, does he?
That must be why you want to call someone.
No.
"No" what?
You can actually do that?
Isn't this the show we were talking about?
It's this one!
"Female High School Detective - Yuki's Casebook."
They're airing a rerun of it.
It's true!
I didn't know.
Even the star of the show herself didn't know...
Wait a second.
The drama was filmed in Beika District, right?
Beika Station, Beika Park...
And the Shitara Shunichi Memorial Hall.
That's that old western-style house!
Although his wife later turned it into a memorial hall...
Before that, it was the home to a
pianist that died ten years ago.
In the drama, after Aya-san was
knocked unconscious by the criminal...
She was locked in the hall's basement, right?
Right, right.
But the exterior there was only filmed as a backdrop.
The indoor scenes were shot on a set elsewhere.
Is that so?
I understand!
I understand now why that old lady ventured to Beika.
Really, Sonoko?
Yes.
Female high school detective Suzuki Sonoko's deductions...
Are never wrong!
Is she all right?
Listen.
That old lady must have trouble
differentiating between dramas and reality.
What do you mean?
It's likely that, once she looked at the
TV listings in the newspaper...
And saw Aya-san's name...
She made sure to watch the drama once it began.
She watched half of it but then fell asleep.
And, by the time she woke up, the
second half was already airing.
She saw Aya-san be attacked in surprise and end up
being held in that western-style house's basement.
The old lady, who had only just woken up...
Perceived the action in the drama as reality, and...
Left her home and set out on her own to rescue Aya-san.
Afterward, she came straight over to Beika.
But doesn't that mean the TV had to be on the whole time?
Since the TV was off later...
She must have recognized it was
just something that was on TV.
Don't bother me!
No one needs to be concerned with such small details!
Here!
Therefore, she must be at the memorial hall.
It can't be wrong!
What do you think, Aya-san?
Jeez, Sonoko's deduction...
But that old lady must have watched that drama.
Her coming to Beika should have
something to do with the drama.
But what is it?
Say, instead of just standing here listening to my
deduction, why not go there and have a look?
Good idea.
Let's go.
I just saw this woman you're looking for.
Just as I thought, my deduction was correct!
Is she still inside?
No.
She must have left here 10 minutes ago.
She left?
Could she be mistaken?
Maybe she left because Aya-san wasn't here.
Say, how did she look then?
When she came here, she kept looking
at the windows on the second floor.
Afterward, she asked if she could go in, so I said she could.
It didn't seem like she came to rescue Aya-san.
That means...
Seeing as she just went back ten minutes ago...
She should still be somewhere around here.
Do you know where she went?
Yes, she went over there.
I'll look for her.
Wait, we'll come along too.
And how did she look when she left?
She looked like she couldn't believe what she was seeing.
When I tried speaking to her, she
didn't respond and just left like that.
Thank you.
Wait a second...
Perhaps something inside is the key to this mystery.
May I come in?
Please do.
Isn't that...
The old Beika Hospital?
Particularly any of Mozart's works.
Could it be?
Ayako...
I'm sorry...
Mom is coming to you...
This is bad!
Lady!
Damn it!
Maybe Fumie-san is on her way home.
Yeah...
It's Shinichi.
Hello?
Ran, I saw your message.
Where are you right now?
In front of the Shitara Memorial Hall.
Ask the woman to play something by Mozart right now!
Mozart?
Yeah, hurry!
I'll go.
Sonoko is going now.
Can I speak with Aya san?
Shinichi wants to talk to you.
Excuse me.
Hello, this is Aya.
Aya-san?
Fumie-san is at the old Beika Hospital right now.
Beika Hospital?
Please hurry!
Fumie-san is going to commit suicide
in order to be with her daughter!
You have to make it, please!
Aya-san...
Fumie-san's daughter was once a
patient at the old Beika Hospital.
She likely stayed in one of the rooms on the second floor.
The sound of Mozart's piano pieces
coming from the Shitara residence...
Would bring comfort to her daughter's spirit.
From the window in that patient room,
she could see the Shitara residence.
That was what Fumie-san saw on the TV drama.
She was so surprised that she couldn't sit still...
And immediately left for Beika.
Afterward, from the windows of the Shitara
Memorial Hall, she could see the old Beika Hospital.
She probably couldn't believe what she saw...
That building had remained intact for the last forty years.
This way!
Fumie-san left for the hospital from there.
And, the moment she stopped in
front of the old hospital building...
Unforgettable memories came rushing back.
Fumie-san always held herself
responsible for her daughter's death...
And now...
She's planning to go be with her.
The only one who can stop her, Aya san...
It's you.
Me?
Grandma!
Ayako...
The only one who an stop her Aya-san.
It's you.
Mom...
I've only been alive for 17 years, but...
I feel very lucky...
To be my mother's daughter.
Really lucky.
I've always wanted to tell you that.
Ayako...
That's why you have to keep on living, Mom!
Live my life through yours, all right?
I will...
I will, Ayako.
Thank you.
Grandma?
Aya-chan...
Grandma...
Just then, Ayako came here...
That child...
She...
Forgave me...
That's great, Grandma...
That's great...
Ran!
You found her!
Shinichi-kun...
I guess I fulfilled the promise we made four years ago.
Yeah.
Looks like I did, too.
You're pretty good at soccer.
Are you going to be a professional soccer player someday?
No.
I want to be a detective.
Detective?
Like Holmes.
Sherlock Holmes?
Before I do that, I'll first become a high school detective.
And not just a kid playing around.
A real detective!
How about we make a deal, then?
The next time we meet...
Right, four or five years from now...
I will become a real actress...
And you will become a real detective.
All right.
Deal.
And as I was saying...
I'm impressed you could solve it with just a message.
It was nothing.
Just a matter of applying the formula of
deduction to the equation of the mystery.
Later, then.
Later.
Ran-neechan!
Conan-kun!
Is everyone over there?
Oh, and you found the old lady, too!
And what are you doing over there?
You can't get across, can you?
That's hilarious!
Why you...
Ran-san, Sonoko-san...
Thank you.
Conan-kun, thank you, too!
I'm glad!
Let's go home now, Grandma.
Well...
Come back when you have time.
Bye.
Conan-kun!
Bye-bye!
That really was some acting.
In the end, the case had a happy ending.
But, from that day onward...
Hey, hey, here she goes again...
That promise you made 4 years ago...
What was it, Shinichi!?
Looks like I won't be able to call her for a while...