From a different perspective...
An imposing wall is just a large door.
Today we're thinking outside the box.
Find the missing boy from a series of random e-mail!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
A tsunami-induced shipwreck incident...
Forest fires due to abnormal drought...
And frequently occurring earthquakes?
I bet a large meteorite will crash down in the near future or something.
Feels like Earth is in deep trouble.
Well, even I, the great detective Mouri Kogorou...
Can't stop these natural disasters.
Well, I'll go ahead and say you normally aren't even capable of stopping a fight among children.
Thank you, Azusa-chan.
Female High School Detective - Yuki's Casebook
You're taking it slow to be with your family today?
Oshibana High School
Nah...
Let's see, after this I need to go investigate the pinball payout rate of the new pachinko parlor nearby...
And then a drinking party with the neighborhood association this evening...
Followed by mahjong at night...
See, I'm so busy!
Is that so...
Oh, no, please don't worry about me.
Azusa-chan, what is it?
You can tell!?
That I'm worried about something!?
More like you said so yourself...
What is it you're worried about?
Well, actually...
It's about this...
THE PURSUIT OF THE FISH E-MAIL
A cell phone?
Hey, hey, don't tell me some customer dropped this in your shop again!
Oh, no, this is mine.
Then, could...
It be that you've been getting suspicious prank e-mails?
It's about e-mails all right, but they are not prank ones.
The sender is Osabe Mitsuru-kun, a five-year old boy.
A kid?
Starting about two or three months ago...
Welcome!
He and his father became loyal customers and frequently came to my shop.
How do you do, Miss?
Apparently the boy's mother went back to her hometown and hadn't come back since...
Since then, he often sent me e-mails via his father's cell phone.
Things like, "I finished all my cucumbers"...
"I took a bath all by myself"...
Each day he would report to me his everyday trivial matters like clockwork.
In that case, why not tell his dad to make the kid stop sending e-mails?
It's not like I'm troubled by his e-mails.
It's because I got as many as four e-mails from him today...
Four—that many?
Yeah, and I'm concerned about the contents.
The first one goes, "Miss, how are you?
"I'm going out with Papa today.
"He bought me a chair and a hat!
"Since everyone's wearing one, I'll wear it too."
The second one goes, "Since they're getting sweaty and uncomfy, I took off my shoes."
I wonder if he was doing things that would cause him to sweat?
"I can see the sign of a restaurant.
"I want to eat a hamburger at your place, Miss."
The third one...
"A man with black glasses and a woman wearing blue are looking at me, but I'm not scared.
"I'm not gonna cry."
Not gonna cry?
Is he in some sort of scary situation?
And the fourth one...
"Will I get caught in the net like that fish and die too?"
He'll die!?
Well, did you e-mail him back, Azusa-chan?
I asked things like "Where are you?" and "What are you doing?"...
But all the e-mails I got from him didn't seem to be like an answer.
Maybe he doesn't know how to open incoming e-mails.
So that kid knows how to send e-mails, but not receive one?
I think he was taught how to send me messages by hitting "reply" which was shown on my e-mail subjects, but...
It's always his dad who checked the inbox.
In short, in order to prevent him from opening suspicious e-mails, his dad didn't teach him how.
So that means, that child's dad...
Is not around him?
Come to think of it, he did mention he was hungry in his second e-mail.
Don't tell me he's been left alone for that long...
When were the e-mails sent?
Yes, let's see, the first one came...
At 9:07 AM.
The second one came at 10:16 AM.
The third one at 11:54 AM.
The fourth one came just now, at 3:02 PM.
Each e-mail came at longer intervals.
Does that mean Mitsuru-kun is getting tired?
Geez, speaking of that dad...
What's he doing neglecting his kid like this?
I don't know about his father, but...
Don't you think Mitsuru-kun's family went out on a fishing trip?
Idiot!
Although he did say "the fish got caught in the net" in his e-mail...
No one in their right mind would fish around where fishermen are trying to collect their net!
I've thought about it too, but the first two messages were both about fishing!
It seems Mitsuru-kun and the people around him are all wearing hats.
He also said his feet were all sweaty.
Since kids don't usually wear boots in the first place, I bet he was told to put on rubber boots.
So what situation requires wearing a hat, putting on rubber boots, and sitting on a chair?
However, if that was the case, the anglers around him...
You're right.
If they did see a kid waiting all by himself for a long time, they should have done something.
I bet that's because...
What is it, Conan-kun?
What?
Everyone's so caught up in their fishing...
That they didn't pay attention to that kid...
We're telling you that situation seems odd!
But then again, I bet that kid has a stiff neck, don't you think?
Huh?
What're you talking about?
Because, the first e-mail was about how everyone around him are wearing hats...
The second e-mail mentioned a restaurant sign.
Upon sending the third e-mail, Mitsuru-kun saw a man with sunglasses and a woman in blue clothes.
Wasn't he looking up all this time?
You'd understand if you put yourself in a child's shoes.
Its really a pain, you know?
Speaking as if you were an adult trapped in a kid's body!
I'm just giving an example...
Hey, could it be that kid's sitting in a car?
A car?
In other words, it's not that the kid wanted to look up all the time...
It's just that he couldn't see what's below.
I see, inside the car!
If he was sending e-mails from his seat...
He wouldn't be able to see below the waists of the people passing by because the door blocked them.
In other words, the "people are looking at me" in his third e-mail...
Were indeed anglers who were concerned about Mitsuru-kun being left alone?
They couldn't talk to him from outside the car.
I see.
So after they arrived at the fishing spot by car, his dad left and disappeared for whatever reason.
And the kid who had to wait in the car for a long time started sending Azusa-chan e-mails to fight boredom...
But eventually became tired.
But why hadn't Mitsuru-kun's dad...
Come back, huh?
This is it!
But, this is yesterday's news...
4 Anglers Currently Missing
Since the sea is still rough, it's likely accidents are to happen again.
Did you call him?
Have you tried to dial his cell phone?
Yes just in case.
But it never went through even though I tried several times.
I wonder if he's at a place with no signal?
Maybe he's been told by his dad to turn the power off after sending e-mails...
To conserve battery power.
Hey Azusa-neechan, have you heard anything about any fishing spot the two of them usually go to?
Well, not specifically...
Come to think of it!
The other day, while reading some leisure magazines in my shop...
His dad suggested that "they should go there".
I remember that he dog-eared the page.
Hurry and bring it!
This is bad.
Six hours have already passed.
What on earth happened?
Beyond that, I still don't get the meaning of the fourth e-mail.
"I'd get caught in the net like the fish and die"?
Would a fisherman wander around while keeping a fish in a net?
No, normally they'd put it in a cooler.
In that case, why did Mitsuru-kun use that expression?
What?
You found three dog-eared pages!?
Yes, I'm sure it was this magazine, but...
Some of my other customers also have the habit of folding a page...
The first spot is Nakaarai...
The second is Kusarazu...
And the third is Komaezaki?
They're all very far away from each other.
There's information on recommended inns written here.
Since it's Saturday, they might have planned to stay for a night.
Nakaarai
There are no reservations made under that name.
Is that so?
By the way, are there many anglers over there today?
Yeah.
Although the winds are blowing, it's still a good day for fishing since it's cloudy.
Is it possible the sea got really rough and swallowed some anglers!?
Don't you go and jinx it!
Is this a prank call, knock it off!
Kusarazu
Well, Osabe-san...
Osabe-san, right?
No one with that name is staying here.
The weather?
It's raining here.
On a day like this you can catch lots offish, so many anglers are here.
Do you know of any accidents because of the rain?
Nothing of the sort.
It's raining on and off and there isn't any wind.
Komaezaki
Osabe?
I don't know of any guest like that!
Is something the matter?
Sounds like you're quite upset.
Yeah, some guests are making a fuss about catching nothing.
On a bright sunny day like this...
Your bait will be too obvious to the fish especially since we have shallow waters.
But there's no wind, so it's easy to use the rod.
If you want to catch some fish, hone your goddamn skills!
Right?
I guess you're right...
Mitsuru-kun sent me another e-mail!
Hurry up and call him!
His phone is probably still on right now.
Right!
The number you have dialed is temporarily
not in service or has been powered off...
No luck...
Oh dear...
And, what does the e-mail say?
Well...
Let's see...
"I thought there was only one fish, but there were actually three...
"I envy those fish..."
What does that mean?
Dunno...
He thought there was one?
I see...
It has three fish indeed!
Mama...
Mama, why did you leave?
When will you come back?
Papa, have you also left me and gone somewhere?
You still haven't come back no matter how long I waited...
How I envy those fish...
"I envy those fish"?
Can't make heads or tails of it.
The only thing we know is that this kid is probably somewhere in one of the three fishing spots.
Nakaarai, said to be a good day to fish since it's cloudy, though the winds are blowing.
Kusarazu, a little bit of drizzle and no wind.
And the third spot is Komaezaki, sunny and without wind.
Then isn't it Nakaarai?
Where you can catch many?
Nah, you can still catch some in Kusarazu.
Only Komaezaki is no good.
But when Mitsuru-kun and his dad dog-eared the magazine and decided where they should go...
It was last week.
So the weather is...
Irrelevant, huh...
Say, even if they say there's no wind, is it possible for them to get no wind at all the entire day?
Well, you will if it's sunny and the temperature rises...
Come to think of it, before we hung up, the man in the last inn said...
But there's no wind, so it's easy to use the rod.
...Just as I say that, the freaking wind starts blowing though.
Say.
If we assume Mitsuru-kun is in the car and keeps looking up all this time...
Then perhaps he's in a daze or something?
Because, there's no way for fish to swim up there, like in the sky!
Fish swimming in the sky?
He didn't mention anything like that!
But look, he e-mailed about seeing three fish instead of one like he originally thought!
You're right about that, but...
If he's envious after looking at them, doesn't it mean the three fish were swimming together happily?
That reminds me, Mitsuru-kun seemed pretty lonely ever since his mom went back to her hometown...
Perhaps he was comparing the three fish to himself.
However, where in the world can we find fish swimming in the sky?
Then, maybe he had seen a surreal movie like that with his dad, don't you think?
Remember, not long ago it was Boys' Day.
Boys' Day?
May 5th...
Speaking of the Boys' Festival...
The carp streamers!
Could it be that Mitsuru-kun can see some carp streamers from where is?
Since carp streamers will hang down and appear as if they were dead when there's no wind?
Then, is it Kusarazu where there's no wind?
No, since he e-mailed about thinking there was one but in fact there were three...
It means there was no wind but it started blowing later.
Komaezaki!
That must be the place!
Papa...
I somehow don't feel well...
It's so hot, and I feel sick...
Papa...
Hyperthermia?
You mean Mitsuru-kun?
Yeah.
Inside a sealed car under the scorching sun...
If he stayed still for six hours, it would more than likely happen.
He's probably already dehydrated by now.
Beyond that, Ran.
Did you already ask the Komaezaki police for help?
Yeah, but since there are many fishing spots, it might take long to find him.
It's all my fault...
If only... if only I had consulted with Mouri-san much sooner...
Don't worry, we'll find him.
Plus, with the sun setting, it might actually be easier to find him.
At any rate, we can get the whole view of the city from here.
The problem is the carp streamers.
Not to mention three carps.
Many people still keep those hanging even though Boys' Day already passed.
It's an iconic sight in this season.
It'd be a big hassle trying to narrow it down to the ones we want.
Awesome, I've spotted a huge net!
I bet you can catch a whale using that net!
Look, over there.
Idiot!
That's a golf practice course.
It's just surrounded by a huge net so the balls won't fly off.
No one would try and catch a whale with that thing!
Don't tell me...
Mitsuru-kun happened to see that net and the carp streamers overlap?
That's why he wrote that e-mail...
I see, so we're looking for a golf course that has carp streamers next to it.
Where is it, where is it, where is it?
Got it, right over there!
Mitsuru-kun!
Where are you?
Answer us!
The only parking lot where you can see those two overlap is here.
However, this is quite spacious.
But I bet he's here somewhere.
Search carefully inside every car!
Mitsuru-kun?
Mitsuru-kun!
That reminds me, that was written in his e-mail.
So he's at a place where the carp streamers overlapping with the golf course net...
And that signboard can be seen.
Found him!
He's over here—Mitsuru-kun!
No good, it's locked...
It won't open.
Mitsuru-kun, Mitsuru-kun!
Step aside.
The miss from Poirot!
Mitsuru-kun!
Miss, why?
What's wrong?
Hurry and open it!
But papa said I can't leave the car...
It's fine, it's fine!
Just listen to what I say!
Please!
Mitsuru-kun 1
It sure feels nice out here!
Judging from his looks...
Seems he's all right!
They're going sea-fishing, but the rods are for a river...
I also don't see any coolers.
Could it be Mitsuru-kun's father came here for a different purpose?
That reminds me, how was that guy doing?
The guy who got caught in the middle of a fight?
Hey, where did that man who got caught in a fight go?
Who the hell are you?
Just answer the question!
We don't know.
Although it seems his head was bleeding.
We heard an ambulance, so he's probably at a hospital.
Hospital?
Hey, Mitsuru!
Mitsuru!
Thank goodness, are you all right?
Where did you go?
I was all by myself until this miss and the others came!
I see, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Huh, you're from Poirot...
Yes, we saw Mitsuru-kun's e-mails.
I was worried so I came with Mouri-san.
Hello.
Oh, my...
Sorry for all the trouble.
Actually, this morning...
The hell was that, you bastard!
Wanna take this somewhere!?
Hey, stop it!
Stop it, you guys!
Screw you!
Shut up!
Shit!
You bastard!
Just like that, I was knocked out cold and was in a hospital until now.
But, Mitsuru...
As a reward for having to wait, I brought you an amazing present!
Mama...
Mama!
I'm back, Mitsuru.
I see, his mom looks a lot like Azusa-san.
That's why he e-mailed me.
So your wife was hospitalized for three months due to tuberculosis?
Yeah.
I didn't want Mitsuru to worry, so I told him she went back to her hometown.
Because her TB also made it hard for me to take him for a visit.
And since today was when they would determine whether she could be discharged or not...
I thought I would let him see her soon...
So I lied about going fishing and brought him.
Boy, was I surprised.
Since when I came to, I saw my wife looking at me with a worried face.
And her test results?
Satisfactory.
I won't go anywhere else.
I'll always be with you!
Really?
Great!
How nice!
Looks like they're back to three as well.
I wish we could also get back to three soon!
I'll settle for being the decorative banner then...