From a different perspective...
An imposing wall is just a large door.
The red "shadow" left behind at the scene, unfolding according to the plot of a novel...
The mysterious unseen suspect!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Sasamoto Yasutarou (32)
Company Employee
What the...
That thing...
Could it be...
Shadow...
Hikage...
Yeah, it's Kamio...
It's Sasamoto—are you still sleeping?
I was up with Sensei all night...
I didn't get home until dawn...
What's wrong?
Hikage...
Hikage appeared!
Were you ambushed?
I'm heading to the train station.
I'll head there too—don't leave...
I'll take a taxi and be there in 30 minutes.
I'm counting on you.
Kamio Toshiyuki (32)
Mystery Magazine Editor
There's no doubt...
It's just as you predicted...
Let's call the police.
Kamio...
But will they believe us?
If that's the case...
That's it!
We can ask a detective.
You were almost killed?
Please help us.
We already know the culprit.
He was a member of our mystery investigation club in college.
A man called Hikage Taeichi.
What makes you so sure he's the culprit?
Half a month ago...
I received a script sent by Hikage.
Script?
For a novel...
Saying that he will kill all of his old partners, one by one.
It's a murder prophecy novel.
Murder prophecy novel?
AND IT'D BE NICE IF EVERYBODY DISAPPEARED
It would've been bad if you had been hit.
It could definitely kill you...
But using red paint to write the words...
He's got some vulgar tastes.
He's been like that since our college days.
Even the novel he wrote on a computer had a title in bright red letters.
Also...
He always wore sunglasses.
It's definitely Hikage—there's no doubt about it.
You received the novel from Hikage-san about half a month ago, right?
The Mystery Investigation Club had 18 members, but only 4 were active.
Those people were...
Sasamoto and myself...
Nesu Takeshi...
And Hikage.
We've barely seen each other since graduation.
Then, half a month ago...
I got a script at the mystery magazine company where I work.
For work named "And It'd Be Nice If Everybody Disappeared"...
There weren't any mysteries.
There weren't any tricks, either.
It's a story of revenge...
Where the main character's hatred causes him to kill his three friends from college...
One after another.
There's something other than the content that you won't believe.
The names of those three murdered people are...
Nesu Takeshi...
Kamio Toshiyuki...
And Sasamoto Yasutaro.
In other words, our names!
I finally figured out the meaning of this strange novel...
Only two days ago.
Two days ago?
Two nights ago, at Beika Park...
Someone discovered a male corpse that had been impaled by a dagger...
The victim was one of our members, Nesu Takeshi.
In the novel sent by Hikage...
Nesu Takeshi... was murdered in a park at night.
Would you mind letting me take a look at the novel?
I see...
The murder method is the same...
That means this isn't a coincidence.
It's certainly not a coincidence...
This novel is a murder prophecy.
But something's off.
Even though he specified the murder method for Nesu Takeshi-san...
The murders of both Sasamoto-san and Kamio-san are not explained in detail.
Oh...
That's right.
That's why I'm worried...
When and where does he plan to kill us?
The motive for murder seems to be the hatred caused by everyone's harsh criticisms of the novel he wrote.
Now that you mention it, there was an incident like that...
That's right.
The setting process no longer works.
The trick isn't inventive.
There are no surprising twists in the plot.
The emotions are too dramatic.
That means that there's no basic reality.
But it's not like that never happened before.
Kamio, your novel was criticized by Hikage, right?
What's so interesting about your novel, Kamio?
This was my most confident work.
You need a smack on the head to wake that brain up.
This kind of crap can't pass for a story at all.
Everyone was the same.
It's been 10 years—why seek revenge after all this time?
That's true...
Have you seen Hikage-san recently?
Not recently...
Speaking of which...
We thought that he was already dead.
Dead?
Hikage left home three years ago...
He said that he was going to the mountains.
After that, he never returned.
That's why everyone thought that he died in an accident.
But that guy is still alive.
A man who has been presumed dead for three years...
Setting his plan for revenge into action after all this time.
Kamio-san!
There's a package for you.
Package?
Is it royalties for your script?
I never turn in any scripts.
Could this be...
Wait, don't open it!
Man, that was dangerous.
You got pretty lucky.
It seems that there wasn't enough gunpowder...
Maybe he miscalculated how much he needed.
A mistake?
Or...
We've determined that it was sent by Hikage Taeichi.
The package had this inside.
It's definitely Hikage.
There's another thing that the public hasn't yet been made aware of...
We found the same thing under the corpse of Nasu Takeshi-san.
At any rate...
Kamio-san, you should remain inside the hospital for now.
Don't worry, I'll be protecting you.
Your work can be done from the hospital.
Your head editor has already agreed.
Sasamoto-san is a salesman...
That won't work for him.
Mouri-san and I will protect you, then.
Sorry to bother you.
Now then, you...
I will...
Go home immediately!
How did I know...
Well, I'm counting on you.
I'm going home now.
We need to figure out Hikage Taeichi's whereabouts.
It would be best to find his hideout.
I cannot leave here no matter what.
Ma'am!
It hurts...
Are you all right?
My waist...
Watch out!
Stop!
Hikage...
That's Hikage!
You're all right.
You won't be hurt while we're around.
The bomb failed, so he tried a hit-and-run.
What's with this guy?
This is...
That car hit the brakes when it rushed through here.
The bomb sent to Kamio-san didn't have enough gunpowder.
Was it supposed to be a threat?
But...
Nesu Takeshi-san was actually murdered.
Nesu-san, Kamio-san, and Sasamoto-san were all handled differently.
Why is there no consistency in the culprit's actions?
Good morning.
Sorry to bother you again today.
It was unfortunate that I didn't catch that car yesterday.
The next time he appears, I will definitely...
Excuse me.
CALLING
Who...
Yes?
Long time no see.
It's me.
It's Hikage!
Since you're under the protection of the police and a detective, you don't need to worry...
I'll let you go this time.
He's retreating?
However, I will not give up.
I will definitely kill you if there is an opportunity.
Why, Hikage?
Hikage!
Excuse us.
Kamio-san?
Hikage just called.
He called me too. /
He seems to be giving up.
I can finally relax.
But we can't just let him go.
Of course not...
Hikage Taeichi committed a crime...
We have to catch him no matter what!
Yes, this is Takagi.
Is that true?
Understood, thanks.
What happened?
They weren't able to find Hikage Taeichi's hideout.
After his disappearance three years ago, he didn't contact anyone around him.
Damn it!
He should've at least written about his hideout in here!
If past hatred is the motive...
There may be clues in the novels he wrote in college.
Novels from college...
Are they still here?
I have a magazine at my house...
It was issued by the members of the Mystery Investigation Club.
Is there anything in that magazine?
There aren't any clues.
There's nothing here, either.
This style of writing is like...
But...
Why would he do that?
Why?
What's his purpose?
This case...
This seems like a wasted trip.
He probably intended for us to drop our guard as a result of that phone call.
If we don't catch Hikage Taeichi soon...
Uhm...
I'm going to Sensei's place today.
I understand.
I will go with you.
Hey, Detective Takagi...
Conan-kun!
What kind of person was the deceased Nesu Takeshi?
Now's not the time to talk about that, but...
His reputation wasn't very good.
One person was angry at him because he never paid a debt that he owed.
Money...
Nesu did?
Asked me?
Yeah...
Did he ask you anything about money?
If I remember correctly...
He claimed he would get the money, but it was still suspicious...
He said he'd use the incident from three years ago.
Three years ago.
Is it the disappearance of Hikage-san?
Hikage-san was a very hard-working person.
He said he wanted to become a famous writer.
He worked toward that goal every day.
But I guess he failed in the end.
Failed?
It was two or three days before he left...
He burned the novel he wrote in the backyard.
He burned it and cried in front of his friend.
Friend?
Is he among these people?
This person...
Are you burning this masterpiece?
That person said it was awful...
And that it had absolutely no value.
I've wasted seven years working on this.
Shortly after that, he disappeared.
"I think that's why he went to the mountains...
In order to commit his suicide in despair.
Now I understand.
It was me who called everyone here?
That's right.
You said that you solved all the mysteries.
I didn't say anything like that.
The mystery in this case is far from—
Mouri-san?
It started already?
Sleeping Kogorou!
Feelings of hatred, stemming from college...
That is the true motive behind all of this.
We've known that the entire time.
That was stated in the novel that the culprit, Hikage Taeichi, wrote.
This case has nothing to do with Hikage-san.
Has nothing to do with...
What do you mean by that, Mouri-san?
Hikage-san wanted to become a famous writer...
Trying to realize his dream, he worked hard writing mystery novels even after graduating.
We already knew that.
However, he was stressed because he couldn't write any satisfactory works.
But Hikage-san finally finished a masterpiece three years ago.
And, regarding that piece of work...
Hikage-san took it to his past partner, who is now an editor of a mystery magazine...
Kamio-san...
He brought it to your place, didn't he?
Is this true, Kamio?
After reading it, you immediately realized that it was a true masterpiece.
However, you...
What do you think, Kamio?
This is really awful.
You probably did this because your confident work from your college years had been rejected by Hikage-san.
As a result, he believed your words and committed suicide in his despair.
That's impossible!
We're being attacked by Hikage right now, aren't we?
Right?
When Hikage-san disappeared...
Kamio-san was already aware...
That it was because he planned to commit suicide out of despair.
You must have felt guilty for your actions three years ago.
At the same time, you tried very hard to forget that incident.
But, half a month ago...
Your past partner, Nesu Takeshi-san...
Started to blackmail you.
Hikage died three years ago because of you, right?
Did I guess right?
He also showed me his work.
In truth, I really need money right now.
To you, money probably wasn't the issue.
But you couldn't sit with the fact that someone else knew of the painful past you wanted to forget.
As a result, you decided to eliminate Nesu Takeshi-san from this world.
But, if you killed him straightforwardly, you would become a suspect.
So you made up a culprit...
Making it seem like Hikage Taeichi-san had committed the crime.
You crafted the scenario to make the motive appear to be hatred out of slandered work from college.
However, Nesu-san was not the only one who criticized Hikage-san's work.
If Sasamoto-san and yourself weren't being targeted as well, then it would be suspicious.
In order to make people believe that Hikage-san was trying to exact his revenge...
You wrote the novel, "And It'd Be Nice If Everybody Disappeared."
Did you really write that?
Then, in the park...
You killed Nesu-san as illustrated in the novel.
You also disguised as Hikage-san and ambushed Sasamoto-san.
Hikage appeared!
I'll head there too—don't leave...
I'll take a taxi and be there in 30 minutes.
You pretended as if you had answered the phone at home.
Then, 30 minutes later...
You acted as though you had just rushed from your house.
You then led us to believe that you were being targeted by Hikage-san as well.
You also found an opportunity to sneak out of the hospital.
You disguised as Hikage-san and targeted Sasamoto-san.
Then, you used his voice to deceive us.
It's Hikage!
If we think about it this way, we can understand why the culprit's actions lack consistency.
The only one you wanted to kill from the beginning was Nesu Takeshi-san.
Am I right, Kamio-san?
No way...
Aren't these just deductions?
Mouri-san, you don't have any proof.
Sasamoto-san still remembers...
The company of the taxi that you rode in yesterday morning.
The taxi driver will probably remember that there was a strange customer...
Who got off near the crime scene after riding only 800 meters.
You call that a testimony?
It's possible that he could have mixed you up with someone else, but...
It's not the only piece of evidence.
This man...
Darn it...
This thing won't wash off no matter what.
When you were using the red paint...
You probably got some on the bottom of your shoes.
Kamio-san, may we take a look at them?
The soles of your shoes.
Kamio...
How and when did you realize I was the culprit, Mouri-san?
That novel...
"And It'd Be Nice If Everybody Disappeared."
I realized that the author couldn't have been Hikage Taeichi-san—it was you.
It had your writing style.
Writing style?
The writing style for that novel is different from the novel that Hikage-san wrote.
Hikage-san's novel employed much more emotional punctuations.
However, there weren't any in that particular novel.
In addition, there isn't any punctuation for space; it was directly expressed.
It was a very repressed writing style.
It was written in the same style as your past novels.
Writing habits are hard to change, no matter how many years have passed.
Especially after an author is able to thrive on them.
This is unavoidable, Kamio-san.
Humans are animals that cannot change their habits.
Kamio...
Animals who cannot change their habits, huh?
Gonna go wash my face.
Murder prophecy!
In here...
The red "shadow!"
Look, right here...
Help me, Conan!
Call the police!
Do something!
Isn't that just a trace of your saliva?