From a different perspective...
An imposing wall is just a large door.
Stuntmen are so cool!
Behind the flashy scenes, we catch a glimpse of a tragic case.
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Kamen Yaiba!
You shall not get away!
Shoot!
Curses!
Like I'd let you escape!
Yaiba...
Curse you!
What?
THE CAR STUNT'S UTMOST LIMIT
No way!
We can't execute a plan like that.
It's way too dangerous!
Fukamachi Shinji (30)
Director
Nakasato Hidehiko (28)
Assistant Director
I think so as well.
Who the hell was talking to you?
Keep your mouth shut, newbie.
It's definitely dangerous...
Rikiishi Kengo (38)
Stuntman
For any other stuntman but me.
But I can nail this one.
I've lost count of how many of these I've done before.
Right, Kijima-chan?
Kijima Daisaku (40)
Cameraman
Yeah, sure.
But...
Let's run through it without stopping.
Forget the trick photography.
From the time I drive up the ramp until the car falls, one cut is all we need.
Well, if I'm filming from below, the camera won't record you jumping out of the car to safety.
But you know...
Rikiishi-san...
You're just not the stuntman that you...
Thanks a lot for letting us come today...
But having the chance to see a Kamen Yaiba show filming is so awesome.
That's our Professor!
He sure is well-shown!
I think you're looking for, "well-known."
Check it out!
Look at all these Kamen Yaiba stickers they gave me.
I've almost got the whole set.
Wow, really?
What was that?
If you think I've lost my touch, just say it to my face!
What's going on?
They sure sound angry.
A fight?
But, with the technology we have now...
We're able to increase the intensity and quality of the shot much better than with only an actual stunt.
That's why...
You don't think old-school stunts are necessary anymore?
No...
That's not what I meant...
The car the monster drives reaches the roof.
He parks the first car, now called Car A.
The camera switches to the remote-controlled Car B.
In place of Car A the monster was driving, Car B turns and speeds ahead toward the edge.
Of course, the edited shot with the explosion doesn't show the car falling to the pavement.
Then, once we add some digital enhancements...
The stunt for that scene will be more than enough.
Damn it...
Nishiwaki Masao (45)
Mechanical Technician
Steering wheel, check.
Brake, check.
Well, looks like that's that.
Hurry up and decide already.
I've got work to do.
How the mighty have fallen, Kijima-chan.
Taking orders from a kid like that.
What'd you say!?
Please stop!
This is the plan we've decided on.
I've already got the producers' permission.
Thank you in advance!
You sure about this?
You're gonna regret it.
The scenes where Kamen Yaiba appears are so cool!
Let go of me!
You know, with the swooshes!
Yeah, the part with all the flashes!
I love that part.
Once we finish our meals, we'll be doing the next take.
We're now on standby, thanks!
He kinda has an attitude problem, that man.
Doesn't matter, he's gonna get beaten by Yaiba anyway.
That's just what he gets, huh?
Hey, hey...
That's what happening during the show, not real life.
But this is kinda boring.
We came all this way, and they're not even filming anything.
It's their lunch break so there's no helping that, Genta-kun.
Well, how about we have our lunch now, too?
Now that you mention it...
Did everyone receive a lunch?
My stomach's growling.
Oh, Genta-kun!
Your stomach reacts quickly.
Kamen Yaiba
To Ayumi-chan
Here you are.
You sure my signature's good enough?
Of course!
Thank you so much!
Where did Genta-kun and Mitsuhiko-kun go?
Wow, they have the same license plate number and everything.
Once on the roof, these two cars will switch places...
And the remote-controlled one will be driven over the side, right?
This is so exciting!
All right, here's a little souvenir.
Ta-da!
Stop that, Genta-kun!
What are you doing?
What's going on, kids?
Nothing at all.
Nope.
Nothing!
Excuse us!
Ta-da!
Check this out!
I'm counting on you.
Got a sec?
You've gotta be kidding me!
I can't believe you're still meddling!
I'm not meddling!
Those two are arguing again.
I was just trying to say that... Rikiishi-san!
I hope they can start filming without too many problems...
Looks like it won't be so easy.
Rikiishi-san!
Huh?
Did it start already?
Somebody stop him!
He plans to do his version of the stunt!
Rikiishi-san!
No way...
I told you...
I told you it was too dangerous.
What in the world is going on?
The seatbelt's a bit loose.
On the roof, he was on the verge of unfastening the belt...
But didn't get out of the car in time and got caught in the accident.
What is it?
This is...
Hey, Mr. Cameraman?
You were filming just a minute ago, right?
Could you play it back for me?
I knew it.
Almost forgot.
Better check up there, too.
Hey, Conan!
Where are you going?
He's working ahead of us again!
Let's follow him!
Hey, hey, guys!
This is...
Just what are you doing, Conan?
This wasn't an accident.
It was a very carefully planned murder.
What'd you say?
The deceased was a stuntman named Rikiishi Kengo-san, age 38.
Was the cause of death found to be from the fall?
Once the car crashed into the ground, the impact from the collision ran through his entire body.
He died instantly.
Which reminds me...
Having a person in a car that's dropped from such a high place...
That's quite a dangerous way to film something.
That's not how it was.
We'd never be allowed to do a stunt like that!
What do you mean by that?
I mean, Rikiishi-san's the one who decided to do the stunt like that.
It backfired on him...
To be more precise, it wasn't a stunt.
It was a performance before the real shooting.
Why would Rikiishi-san do something like that?
He was feeling the pressure.
Feeling the pressure?
I can understand how he felt.
Younger guys just keep getting hired.
And if I ever asked to do anything else other than film, they'd fire me as soon as possible.
I'm not saying that we don't need stunts.
They're especially important for this kind of story?
But, with the digital technology we have now...
We're able to create some great scenes without using old-school methods.
Truth is, there are plenty who think using CG alone is more than enough.
So what can I do about it?
The producers are the ones with the final say...
I heard that the producers planned to fire Rikiishi-san, but you convinced them not to.
You sure about this?
You're gonna regret it.
Let go of me!
Well, no matter how you look at it, he was in a rush to keep the job he was barely holding onto.
That must have been it.
I can't believe what I'm hearing, Kijima-chan.
Weren't you the one who talked to the producers and made it hard for him to keep his job in the first place?
I don't know how he did it, but...
Rikiishi-san somehow knew all about it.
You just shut your mouth!
Is that why you think I had it in for that bastard?
Once he found out about your crappy maintenance habits, you're the one he ended up punching!
Come, now.
This isn't the place to be fighting.
That's right, you got slapped around by that bastard quite a few times, too, didn't you?
And you yelled, "I'll kill him" at more than one of the drinking parties.
What, are you saying I did something more than that?
Officer, please just set the record straight.
This was an accident, right?
Let's see...
To see if there was some failure in the car itself, well have the maintenance staff thoroughly check over the vehicle.
There's no way that was the problem!
The mechanics were flawless!
But you still have a motive.
Look who's talking!
But under the circumstances, it's probable that it was ultimately an accident.
See, I told you.
Wait a minute.
Uhm... Uh... That's...
This was a murder crafted to appear like an accident.
What'd you say?
What makes you say that?
Please, calm yourselves.
There's something I'd like to confirm about the deceased Rikiishi-san's personality.
His personality?
For instance, whether or not he'd want to perform a stunt even more because of the risk involved.
Most definitely.
He was someone who rushed to try something a little more dangerous.
Always had been.
It was always "survival of the fittest" for him.
Of course, when someone does a stunt like that, they have to go through intense training.
But the guys who can do the stunt are ultimately the best ones.
How about Rikiishi-san?
He was the best.
No doubt.
Especially when he was younger.
Lately, he'd probably been afraid of losing that title.
What if the murderer latched on to that weakness of his?
Could you explain further?
Fukamachi-san...
What were you talking about with Rikiishi-san before he jumped in the car?
He told me, "I'll show you what a real stunt looks like."
Then he ignored my protests and leapt into the car.
You've got it backwards.
Backwards?
Meaning that it wasn't Rikiishi-san, but you, Fukamachi-san.
You're the one who brought it up.
Maybe by saying something like, "We might be on different sides, but depending on your performance..."
"You might convince everyone to change their minds."
That's all you'd need to say to prompt him into action.
That's crazy!
What, are you trying to say that I killed him?
That's right.
You're the murderer, Fukamachi-san!
Agasa-san!
Even if Fukamachi-san did provoke him...
Rikiishi-san is the one who drove the car and misjudged the actual stunt.
There's no way that can count as murder.
Right.
That's why Fukamachi-san said this to take advantage of him...
"There's no air bomb in the back of Car A."
"It's pointless to perform the stunt using only Car A."
"Don't even think about it"
Phrasing it like that only made Rikiishi-san more determined.
Once he reached the roof, he quickly changed to Car B where the explosive was installed.
Then, on the verge of dropping off the roof, he'd perform the most dangerous part of the stunt.
He thought, "I'll show them how good I am."
So that means that the car that fell from the roof is Car B?
He's wrong.
This one doesn't have an explosive inside.
It's Car A!
Now I'm all confused.
Me too.
No, wait a second.
If I remember correctly...
Takagi-kun...
Just in case, go check the car on the roof.
Inspector, it's here.
This has to be Car B.
Which means that Rikiishi-san didn't switch from Car A to Car B.
He performed the stunt in the original car, made a mistake, and fell over the side.
Like we thought, an accident.
Now, don't be so quick to decide on that.
Remember how Rikiishi-san looked immediately following the crash.
If we could see the photos the forensics investigator took of the scene...
Conan-kun!
Right!
I knew it.
There it is, right there!
The Kamen Yaiba sticker that Genta-kun put on the car.
He stuck it on the car the vehicle specialist guy drove up to the roof.
Right, Genta-kun?
Uhm...
There's no doubt about it.
He must have changed cars on the roof.
I put stickers on both cars.
No way...
Which means that we can't prove whether or not he switched cars.
That's not it.
This is what you're meant to see.
Hey, Mr. Cameraman.
Can you show me the video again?
Stop!
His cape isn't caught in the door.
This means...
And it doesn't appear as if he opened or closed the door of the vehicle on the way up the ramp.
But what about the explosive?
All the culprit had to do is stash it somewhere.
But that alone isn't enough to prove that he switched cars.
Conan-kun!
I went up to the roof right after the accident, and...
Found that the hood of the car was hot.
As if the car had just been shut off.
Oh, so that indicates...
That's crazy!
Well then, how about this?
For example, just for example, if I'd convinced him to do it, and he switched cars on the roof...
If he didn't get clear of the car before it fell...
I don't want to be cruel, but it's his own fault!
You mean he "lost his touch"?
Instead of trying to tear off his seatbelt, he should have put on the emergency brake.
That's true.
It was impossible for him to use the brake.
I just don't get it.
Try to remember...
Just what kind of vehicle Car B was.
Something in addition to being the base for the air explosive.
It was remote-controlled!
And where is that remote control now?
It's...
This, right?
He said that he wanted to check on it, so I lent it to him.
If we use this, we'll definitely find out which car was which, won't we?
This is...
Kinda sounds like it's crying, huh?
I was in debt.
And I used the production money to pay it off.
If anyone found out, I'd be fired!
So that's why you used Rikiishi-san's weakness against him and contrived a plan to murder him?
Once Rikiishi-san reached the roof in Car A, you waited until he changed vehicles...
And then operated the remote control, directing its every move.
Since the brake wouldn't work and the door wouldn't open, you made him fall over the edge.
And afterwards, Rikiishi-san's death would be deemed an accident he caused himself.
So long as everyone thought that he died in Car A...
You could return the remote to the vehicle specialist Nishiwaki-san with everyone being none the wiser.
Isn't that what you thought?
Oh, I can't eat another bite...
Yaiba's so cool!
It's no good, Genta-kun.
Put as many stickers on me as you want.
I'm beyond repair.
Got that right.