By looking at what's blocking our way with an open mind,
a wall can be turned into a wide-open door.
When you open your mouth up wide and say "ahh,"
an unthinkable act occurs, just like in today's case.
Seeing through to the one and only truth,
I look like a child, but have the intellect of an adult.
My name is Detective Conan!
The Final "Ahh"
The Final "Ahh"!
Mouri-san, please hurry.
Can't you run any faster?
This is my limit.
Nitta-san, how about you lose some weight?
Eh? Did you say something?
I wonder if my hearing aid is going bad?
Top floor! It's the room at the very end!
A remodeled gun, huh?
Nitta Hideko (70)
Suzuki Yumi's neighbor
He's a really famous detective so,
he'll solve it right away.
A cold?
Suzuki Yumi (40)
Dentist's Assistant
No, I'm fine.
Even doctors can neglect their own health, be careful.
Oh no, I'm not a doctor.
I'm just a dentist's assistant, that's all.
Then, continuing along in your story...
Nitta-san, you said you heard a gunshot-like noise sometime before 3:00 PM?
To be exact, it was 2:45 PM.
When I awoke from my daily afternoon nap,
Suzuki-san had arrived.
Yes. I made sandwiches for lunch today.
Then, I remembered that you like feeding the carp in the pond, so...
Thanks.
I was just about to go, so this will be a great help.
Aren't you going to the dentist today?
I took the day off.
Well then, how about we have tea when I return?
I'll be back before 3:00 PM.
That sound just now...
It came from Yamamoto-san's room.
Wasn't that the sound of a pistol?
It can't be...
It can't be, right? At this kind of place in the middle of the day...
The carp are waiting for me to feed them, so I'll see you later.
Afterwards, I returned a little bit before 3:00 PM, and...
Has anything happened since then?
No, nothing...
Oh my, Nakanishi-san, good afternoon.
He used to live in your room.
Huh?
What's he doing, leaving it open like that?
It looks like a will.
I've heard that Nakanishi-san and Yamamoto-san were good friends.
Even if Yamamoto-san had committed suicide,
Isn't it strange for his best friend to just leave without calling the police or an ambulance?
He left like he was running away, right?
That right, there's definitely something up.
No matter how you look at it, he's the only one who could be the murderer, right?
His actions are suspicious enough, no doubt about that.
I should alert Inspector Megure just in case.
I was on my way back from buying a cake as requested by Ran,
when I met Nitta-san, who was running to the police and wound up here.
He couldn't repay his debts to Nakanishi-san, so he died to avoid having them looming over his head.
However, that will was written in a word processor.
We can't be sure it was written by Yamamoto-san himself.
But, what's bothering me more than anything else...
...is that he discovered the body of his childhood friend, then he left without alerting anyone.
Yeah.
That's right.
At the time, I thought nothing like this could have happened in the middle of the day.
According to my former-policeman instincts,
The culprit is the childhood friend, Nakanishi.
The motive is the hardships of his debt.
Mouri-san...
Going by the autopsy results,
It doesn't look like murder.
Hotoke-san's body doesn't show any signs of resistance.
He didn't resist?
Assuming the gun was forced in his mouth,
his lips would've closed around it, and there'd be a wound showing signs of resistance.
Since there isn't one there,
it could only mean he opened his mouth on his own.
Inspector, please take a look.
It's true, there are no signs of resistance.
But still, with everything else...
Hey, it says here these butterflies are called red admirals.
The vegetation here is...
We're not talking about that right now!
You're bothering us, so just goof off somewhere else.
Inspector, the results from our investigation,
Yamamoto-san has a criminal record involving guns.
According to his neighbor, Suzuki-san...
If you asked him to turn down the volume on his TV or such, he'd just get angry at you.
He was a guy who only lived for his butterfly collection.
Inspector,
It seems very unlikely that such an unsociable person would commit suicide over a debt.
Mouri-san,
you don't understand the situation.
Suzuki-san and Nitta-san heard the gunshot around 2:45 PM.
Nitta-san saw Nakanishi-san just a little before 3:00 PM.
If we assume Nakanishi to be the culprit,
then what was he doing during those fifteen minutes in between?
If he were the culprit, wouldn't he have fled from the crime scene the first chance he got?
Inspector,
it's Nakanishi-san.
Nakanishi Saburou (30)
Yamamoto Nabuo's childhood friend
Like I said, I came at 3:00 PM as I promised.
When I entered the apartment, he was already dead on the sofa.
You discovered the body, but aren't you his childhood friend?
Why didn't you alert the police right away?
I had lent Yamamoto money!
I ran because I didn't want people to think I did it because of the money.
No, you can't lie.
You wrapped a towel around the gun so that your fingerprints would be erased.
Somewhere around 2:45 PM, you put the gun into his mouth,
and murdered him, all while making it seem like a suicide.
There are two people who heard the gunshot.
Wait a minute!
Then, explain how I put the gun into Yamamoto's mouth!
Was he just zoned out with his mouth open waiting for it?
Y-You must have waited for him to yawn or something like that.
I came because he owed me money!
Of course he opened his mouth wide and yawned... We're good friends, aren't we?
Well, that's true, but...
That's true, it's exactly like Nakanishi-san said.
There are too many inconsistencies for him to be the culprit.
I'd like to ask you one more thing...
At 2:45 PM, the assumed time of Yamamoto-san's death,
Where were you and what were you doing?
I was inside a taxi, on my way here.
What's the name of the taxi company?
I don't remember.
If I'm not mistaken, it was a blue car.
There was a picture of a mouse or some kind of animal.
I'll try to match it.
He's trying to buy time.
That man's a tough opponent too.
If he'd faced Mouri-san he wouldn't be able to run away though.
Mouri-san, I'm going to have tea with Nitta-san,
so if you'd like, let's go together.
Then, let's eat that cake I bought.
Geez.
I don't even get my money back.
If Yamamoto-san's death was suicide,
What did he plan on doing with his butterfly collection after he died?
Those butterflies were so important to him...
There's still something missing.
Something I haven't noticed.
However, what is it?
Original Broadcast Date:
June 5th, 2006
Based on manga:
None (Anime Original)
Thanks for waiting.
Now, I can't wait to dig in to that cake!
It's strawberry!
Conan-kun, open up your mouth.
Okay, say ahh...
Mouri-san, forget about work already.
Just for Mouri-san...
Here, a strawberry!
Ah, no, I'm an adult...
Well, since you insist...
Conan, don't tell Ran.
Okay, say "ahh"...
Ahh!
Jeez... he's an old man who just can't keep his mouth shut...
Should I get some brandy to go with it?
That'd be great!
"Just a little bit more, a little bit more..."
How much longer will I have to wait?
My men are searching their hardest as we speak.
This should be it, Yamamoto-san's patient registration card.
I wonder what Mouri-san needs this for.
I think he wants to know,
if Yamamoto-san has visited a dentist or not,
and if he did, which dentist he used.
Thank you very much.
That's right, Yamamoto Nobuo-sari
He's one of your patients...
Yes, right.
It was cancelled?
A kid named Conan, my assistant, will be coming over.
So, please explain everything to him.
Tokyo City Taxi
West Japan Taxi
Tokyo Taxi
Kouhoku Taxi
Yonehana ---
Imperial Transport
Yonehana Taxi
Shinjuku Wireless
Taisho Taxi
Tokyo City Taxi
West Japan Taxi
Tokyo Taxi
Kouhoku Taxi
Yonehana ---
Imperial Transport
Yonehana Taxi
Shinjuku Wireless
Taisho Taxi
Officer Chiba, did you figure out which taxi Nakanishi rode?
Not yet.
Nakanishi might have been lying for all we know.
Hey...
Uncle Mouri has something he needs you to check for him.
Uncle, wake up!
Uncle!
Another one? Ahh...
He seemed to really like it, so I told him to drink more.
Uncle, wake up!
Hey, can you help me?
No more! No more strawberries!
Geez, Inspector, I feel bad for you. You're unfortunate.
What are you talking about?
We're going to leave soon.
Okay then, stand up.
What are you doing?!
Where are you taking me?
Until we find the taxi you rode in,
you're a suspect.
Stop kidding around! I'm not involved in this!
You're a man with a really bad attitude.
If you're a bad guy, then act like a bad guy,
and admit to your crimes!
That's what I'd like to say, but...
Inspector, Yamamoto-san's death was indeed murder, but that man has nothing to do with it.
Yamamoto-san was murdered,
Disguised? By whom?
Well, what makes you think it was disguised?
As you can see, Yamamoto-san exceedingly loved butterflies.
He's sure to have thought about what to do for his butterflies if he were to die.
Before he died, he'd have probably let them go.
Also, there's the place Yamamoto-san was sitting.
If he shot the gun there,
the exiting bullet would have hit the glass case.
If his aim was bad, he might have harmed the butterflies.
Therefore, it's not possible for him to commit suicide in such a place.
That's true...
At 2:30 PM, Yamamoto-san was making a phone call to the dentist to cancel an appointment.
In other words, he was murdered in the half-hour between 2:30 PM and 3:00 PM, when Nakanishi-san discovered him.
That would be at 2:45 PM.
We have witnesses who heard the shot, so it's without a doubt at that time, but...
The other problem is the murder method.
How did the culprit put a gun into Yamamoto-san's mouth?
The culprit told Yamamoto-san to open his mouth, and he did just as he was told.
He opened his mouth just by being asked to?
I suppose that's possible for a kid, but this is an adult we're talking about.
There was someone who could control
Yamamoto-san to that extent.
Who is that person?
Inspector, "Please open up your mouth wide."
Who would have to say that to make you open up obediently?
Obediently?
God... My grandma...
Okay now, let's have a big "ahh"...
A big "ahh"...?
A doctor!?
That's right, it's a doctor.
Specifically, dentists are the ones who say that the most.
Then, the culprit is a dentist?
A dentist came into this room?
No, the one who came works for a dentist.
Furthermore, they're an acquaintance of Yamamoto-san,
and they also knew of his debt.
Who is that person?
Suzuki Yumi-san,
You're the assistant to the dentist that Yamamoto-san visits at the Beika Dental Clinic, aren't you?
There's a slim line behind your ears,
a mark which comes from wearing a mask for many years.
You also admitted you took the day off from working at the clinic.
By eavesdropping,
you knew Nakanishi was coming to collect the debt at 3:00 PM,
and so you set in motion your previously devised plan.
Previously devised plan?
You moved into this apartment about two months ago.
That was immediately following Yamamoto-san's visit to your clinic.
Your goal was to coincidently meet and befriend Yamamoto-san.
And then, as you were aiming for, to be able to speak with him.
Furthermore, you knew Yamamoto-san had been driven into debt.
You used this and crafted a scenario where he had killed himself due to his debts.
Today is a weekday,
At 2:30 PM, there aren't many people in the apartments.
Also, you knew Nitta-san takes her hearing aids out so she can take her daily afternoon nap.
Today's your appointment, right?
I'll do it for you. I'll even do it for free since we're friends and neighbors.
Hurry up and let me in.
I've made other arrangements, so please cancel today's appointment.
The drinks are for later, okay? It'll be over quickly.
Okay then, shall we begin?
It'll be bright, so close your eyes.
Okay now, open wide and say "ahh"...
It'll all be over soon.
You, who had murdered Yamamoto-san,
setup a tape with a recording of a gunshot on it,
and visited Nitta-san with bread crusts.
Having done that, when Yamamoto-san "died" at 2:45 PM, you'd be with Nitta-san.
In other words, you created an alibi for yourself.
Then, after that, Nitta-san left to feed the carp.
You saw her off.
By doing this, the time of Yamamoto-san's death was set at 2:45 PM.
Furthermore, you made sure that Nitta-san would discover it at 3:00 PM.
In other words, you disguised it as a suicide.
You're wrong! It's wasn't me.
I don't have a reason to murder Yamamoto-san.
You have one.
I've checked it, Suzuki-san.
Ten years ago, your husband was in an traffic accident at a tunnel in Kokyou.
He currently remains unconscious and hospitalized.
Butterflies!
The assailant was Yamamoto Nobuo,
careless from being distracted by the butterflies, on top of having been drinking.
That same Yamamoto coincidently appeared out of the blue.
Meeting him again, you thought of taking revenge for your husband.
Am I wrong?
You are!
No, that man did steal my husband's ability to be a dentist and forever ruined his future.
But, I didn't kill him.
I've never even been in this room before.
It seems I've caught a cold, so please excuse me.
I'd like to say, "Please take care," but, Yumi-san...
That isn't a cold.
Most likely, it's a pollen allergy.
Pollen allergy?
Yes, and it probably came from mugworts.
Note: Mugwort is a type of plant, also known as wormwood.
A mugwort-induced pollen allergy?
It was written in one of the books in this room.
It seems mugwort is a food for the red admiral butterfly.
Even though it's a favorite food for the red admiral butterfly,
it's a vegetation that can cause pollen allergies in humans.
Also, one more thing,
You hair is sparkling a little, isn't it?
Most likely, those are butterfly scales.
Mouri-san,
I live next door.
It's possible that the pollen may have blown into my room.
Without me knowing, a runaway butterfly may have stayed in my apartment.
Conan, bring that thing over.
Yumi-san, you must know what that is.
Yes, it's a dental mirror to look-at-the back of teeth.
I tried very hard to borrow that from Beika Dental Clinic.
It's a custom made product, and has the initials "B.D.C." engraved on it.
Amongst the patients, was there anyone who was given one of these,
or anyone who wanted to take one home?
No, there wasn't.
Inspector, under that table, there should be a coffee cup.
Please take a look.
It just looks like coffee.
What about it?
Inside there's a stirrer, isn't there?
Try taking it out slowly.
Why is it here? Why?
The one who brought that dental mirror to this room,
it could've only been you.
Am I right?
Yamamoto-san came for an appointment.
Of course, he'd forgotten my face and my name.
But, the reason I couldn't forgive him was even though he'd promised he would never drink and drive again,
he came driving to the clinic drunk.
This person didn't regret anything they'd done.
And when I thought that, I felt sorry for my husband, and then...
I deeply regret what I have done.
Like I said, I did get the cake, but various things happened on the way back!
I'm not lying, Ran-chan!
Open up please...
She turned off the light switch!
Ran must have turned off her switch towards us too...
Is this the punishment for "ahh"?
I've grown tired of living.
It can't be...
Even if you lie, there's always some evidence left behind.
I found the evidence!
However, the problem is proving his plan.
What should I do?
I can't let anything like this happen!
The Man Obstructed by the Steel Frame
Next Conan: The Man Obstructed by the Steel Frame.
Amnesia
Next Conan's Hint!
Amnesia.
Officer Chiba, about today's murderer...
Today's almond jelly?
No, murderer.
Did I eat it?
Eh...?