From a different perspective...
An imposing wall is just a large door.
Stopping life will lead to death.
That means you have to stop the case
you've stumbled upon, Detective Boys!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Look at that Unajuu!
Genta-kun, stop staring and let's go!
I wanna eat it...
Look out!
Are you all right!?
Did he get hit?
No, he must have dodged it — he seems to have passed out
Mitsuhiko!
I know, the ambulance.
How was it, Detective Takagi?
Looks like it was just a simple mistake while manning the crane.
So this is an accident, not a case, right?
And according to the nurse's station, he tripped and broke one of his legs, but
There's nothing abnormal with his head or brain waves.
It's just that he's still unconscious, so we can't confirm who he is or where he's from.
I forgot! -
This is that person's bag.
Oh, it might have something that would reveal his identity.
What's with this rope?
This is...
A rope...
Gloves...
A wallet...
And an envelope?
I'm tired of living."
"I'm tired of living."
This is...
A suicide note.
So, that person...
He tried to commit suicide with that rope?
Manaka Daijirou, 27 years old.
Even though he's in his 20's, he says that he's tired of living...
That's something a far older person would say.
And...
THE MAN OBSTRUCTED BY THE STEEL FRAME
You finally woke up, Manaka-san.
I'm with the police.
What in the world is this?
Please, explain your circumstances.
Manaka-san!
My name — it's Manaka?
Yes?
I can't — I can't remember anything!
How sad, he doesn't know who he is.
All right, I'll give him a punch!
No, you can't, Genta-kun!
Why're you stopping me?
He may not remember now, but if he does remember...
He might try to commit suicide again.
That's true...
This means that I have to keep watching him, or else...
You never know when he'll get his memory back.
I want to help him regain his memory, but, if he does, he might commit suicide...
What should we do?
We must solve it!
We must solve the problem before he regains his memory!
What problem?
He wants to commit suicide, because he has a problem!
If we solve it for him...
Then he won't want to die anymore!
All right, this is a job for the Detective Boys!
Yeah!
That person...
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
Did he really lose his memory?
You think he's lying?
He's lying!?
When people lie, it shows on their face.
They'll blink more, and their eyes will wander.
That person's eyes' were wandering.
That's because he was worried, since he couldn't remember his own name.
Besides, why would he have to lie about losing his memory?
How would I know?
I don't think it's good to doubt without knowing why!
But something's off about that person...
And when you think about it, back then...
Back then?
At that time, he was headed south of Beika.
The residential area is in that direction.
Wouldn't you do the opposite if you were committing suicide?
Wouldn't you rather go to a mountain or something, where there aren't many people?
The residential area has places where there aren't many people.
Maybe...
That's fine.
Since Conan-kun doesn't want to go, we can go by ourselves.
First, let's investigate the problem that Manaka-san has!
Yeah!
No matter what, we're going to prevent his suicide!
Yeah, prevent his suicide! Prevent his suicide!
Fine, I'll go!
Manaka-san's an artist?
He's not famous or anything, though.
But these are beautiful!
They're all relaxing and well done.
He's a serious person, so he'll easily spend half a year finishing a piece.
Because of that, he can't pay his bills.
He has trouble with money?
Hey, Manaka Daijirou-san...
I think you should return it to us today.
The two million yen, that is.
Manaka-san's not here.
We'll come back later, then.
The only problem Manaka-san has is his debt
Those two come and ask every day.
If the problem is debt, then the Detective Boys can't solve it, can we?
But we can't give up now!
Doesn't Manaka-san have anyone who's willing to lend him money?
He doesn't have any family, though he has an uncle...
But apparently he won't even lend wisdom, no matter what he goes to ask him for.
So that uncle doesn't have any money, either?
No, he's loaded!
His name is Ginbayashi-san – he has a mansion in Beika's South District
Beika's South District...
Oh yeah, there is one, isn't there?
A mansion belonging to someone named Ginbayashi!
The uncle's a family-less loner, too.
You'd think that he'd be a little more kind to his only blood relative...
His only blood relative...
So that's what's going on!
What's up, Mitsuhiko?
I figured it out!
A way to solve Manaka-san's debt?
Oh, not that – not yet
Then what did you figure out?
I figured out why Manaka-san was walking there at that time!
You figured it out, Mitsuhiko?
Manaka-san wanted to go to his uncle's house in Beika's South District!
His goal, of course, was to take revenge for never being loaned any money.
He wanted... to commit suicide there!
I see!
Sorry Mitsuhiko, but that doesn't explain everything.
What he really wanted to do was probably...
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
Hey, not again!
Huh? I thought you went home?
No, this bugged me after all.
Does your foot hurt?
The anesthesia's wearing off, so yeah...
But it's good that you broke your leg.
If it was your hand, you wouldn't be able to draw until you healed!
That's true.
This person knows that he's an artist
He faked his amnesia.
' If he was interrogated by Detective Takagi, he might spill something.
So he faked his amnesia on the spot
Manaka-san was probably heading towards his uncle Ginbayashi-san's house...
It's likely just as Mitsuhiko deduced.
But he wasn't trying to commit suicide...
He was trying to fake Ginbayashi-san's suicide.
The gloves were to hide his fingerprints.
The suicide note's words make sense, if this was the case.
"I'm tired of living."
That's something a far older person would say.
If Ginbayashi-san dies, then his inheritance starts flowing to his only blood relative, Manaka-san.
That's probably the motive.
But the problem is how to explain this plot to others...
Conan-kun!
We had to look for you, since you disappeared so suddenly!
Hey, Mitsuhiko...
Yes?
Let's say that there's a plan for a crime here - one that involves a person's life.
But nothing's happened yet – it's going to happen in the future...
Giving us no evidence.
How would you catch the criminal?
There's no need to catch the criminal.
If it hasn't happened yet, then you prevent it from happening!
That's true.
There you are, Conan...
We looked all over for you.
Let's all go and ask.
At Ginbayashi-san's place.
If that person would help with the money...
Then Manaka-san wouldn't think about doing anything stupid.
The crime that involves a person's life – you meant a suicide!
What're you talking about?
About preventing a crime before it happens!
Daijirou-san tried to commit suicide?
For now, he happens to have amnesia...
But if his memory returns...
His problem is his debt!
If you would lend money to him...
I have no intention of helping him.
President!
But you still have time!
I doubt that you children will understand...
But when Daijirou graduated from college, he went to work at a bank.
I was happy.
I was planning to have him inherit my company.
But half a year ago, he quit!
Just to follow an old dream to become an artist
He completely trampled all over my kindness.
Why would I support him!?
But...
He came to visit last month...
He wanted money.
Are you a man or not? You're pathetic.
Promise me that you'll quit something as stupid as painting!
I'll give you this, as much as you want
Forget it! Why would I depend on someone as disgusting as you?
Now you've said it, never show your face here again!
I said I'd help him, but the idiot declined.
Maybe the motive wasn't just money.
Manaka-san thought about killing this person...
Because of his hatred from not being understood...
It's time to go to my company.
Hinuma, prepare to go.
But, President...
He decided to tie himself to his dream.
Then let him get tied up—I don't care if he struggles or commits suicide!
Ginbayashi-san!
This person's eyes are wandering too.
What a horrible person.
Conan-kun!
We can't do anything more for him!
I can't let such a strange case happen!
Are you sure you don't want to go see Daijirou-san in the hospital?
It's better to leave that idiot alone.
You're saying something you don't mean again.
As I thought, he lied.
You can't leave him alone, that's why every time he has an exhibition...
You have me buy his work.
That's enough!
You're persistent, but I'm not loaning the money!
You were secretly buying his work, right?
You eavesdropped.
But if you do it secretly, Manaka-san can't know that you support him.
Because he doesn't know, Manaka-san probably...
Loathes you from the bottom of his heart.
I think so as well.
Please, be honest to Daijirou-san.
Don't misunderstand me, Hinuma. I'm not buying his paintings to support him.
I buy them to burn them! ♦
Where do you see those paintings I bought? There isn't even one here or at the mansion!
Of course there isn't, because I burned them, to illustrate how he trampled all over my kindness.
No way...
You guys are definitely related.
What do you mean?
You're exactly like Manaka-san.
Your eyes wander when you lie.
This kid... I'll kick you out!
Give me a hand, Hinuma!
No, I also want to know why the president would lie!
What lie are you talking about? Stop, you insolent brat!
You brat – what have you done!?
Ah, I'm sorry!
Even if you lie, there's always some evidence left behind.
I found the evidence!
No way...
Say, mister, how about we go see Manaka-san?
Tell him that, in truth, you've always supported him.
If you don't...
This case will never come to an end!
It seems that, for now, they think that I'm trying to commit suicide, but...
If I let something slip...
You can't pretend to have amnesia anymore!
You tried to kill your uncle, Ginbayashi-san, with this!
You're under arrest!
This is the end for you!
This isn't good; if I keep this up...
I see, you all were trying to solve that problem for him.
But, in the end, there was only so much we could do...
I understand. Now, it's my turn.
When he gets his memories back, I'll persuade him.
"No matter how bad of a financial problem you have, you can't ever think of suicide," I'll say.
It's these people – they're the debt collectors!
That amnesia's gotta be a lie.
Don't think that I'll let you off the hook...
Stop!
Takagi-san!
He heard our voices and fled!
He won't get away!
He disappeared!
From here...
No way! His leg's still broken.
But where else did he...
He has amnesia, but he recognized the debt collector's voice?
No, it's the opposite! He heard the debt collector's voice...
And his memories came back.
Then he's in the dining hall!
If his memories came back...
Does he intend to commit suicide?
Manaka-san disappeared?
We're searching for him, but...
No one's seen him over there!
Same here.
Which means that he might still be in the hospital...
Either way, please come here, Conan-kun!
Yeah, I will.
His memories seems to have come back, so we need to hurry and find him.
He really might commit suicide this time!
You're actually worried about him, aren't you!? Ginbayashi-san!
Hinuma, the car.
He's not here.
I found him!
Ah, he stopped!
Is he going to jump?
We need to hurry!
I can't walk anymore.
I haven't eaten since yesterday—I'm starving...
I, too, wanted to become an artist
But, I couldn't make a living and, in the end, I gave up on that dream.
So that's why.
Then you should understand Daijirou-san's hardship more than anyone else...
Perhaps you mean to continue supporting him?
It's the opposite.
Yeah, it's because he understands...
That this person has been deserting Manaka-san.
Don't die, Daijirou.
Don't do it!
Don't die!
Killing yourself-you absolutely can't do it!
Your memories returned!
Please, we'll listen to your story!
If they listened to my story, I might let something slip!
Stop! I'll jump!
Found you, at last!
Return our two million!
Stay away! Neither of you come any closer!
If you do, I'll really jump!
I'll die!
I'll really, really die!
You're pathetic, saying "I'll die" over and over.
Why are you here?
When you started saying that you wanted to be an artist, I opposed!
I said that you couldn't make a living with paintings.
Yet, you didn't listen – you chose to live your dream.
How idiotic.
How could someone like you understand my feelings!?
And then, you started to depend on me.
But, Daijirou...
If you naively think that you can keep falling back on someone whenever you're not doing well...
Then you won't be able to follow through with your dream!
That's why I chose to harden my heart
No matter what you requested of me, I would never support you.
Don't say something so convenient!
But you couldn't leave him alone.
You secretly supported him.
He was buying your paintings.
My paintings?
Apparently, he's been buying and sending them to an elementary school.
See?
I graduated from that elementary school.
It seems to be a student's thank you card.
Thank you for all the beautiful paintings!
Beautiful paintings always put children's hearts at peace.
I continued to send them while holding onto that belief.
You bought my paintings...
You've secretly been supporting me.
Why didn't you tell me?
It's not support!
They were good paintings – they just happened to be yours.
Geez, he's really overdoing it
He's actually a good, loving uncle.
Yeah!
His eyes are wandering again.
Here's the two million.
Thanks.
This isn't support, either.
This is pre-payment for the paintings that the children are looking forward to.
Uncle...
I'm sorry, in truth, I was...
You don't have to say anything.
Don't ever think of suicide again.
I'm sorry – I'm sorry, Uncle!
The crime that involved a person's life...
We managed to prevent it!
Yeah.
I wanna eat it...
He's staring again.
It might drop, Genta-kun.
A steel frame, I mean.
Watch out!
That was close, the saliva was about to soil my shirt
Conan-kun?
What are you doing?
I wonder?