From a different perspective...
An imposing wall is just a large door.
We Detective Boys are going clam digging.
And the elite police detective and
younger brother takes the stage!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Are we there yet?
Just wait a little more.
That's why I said we should've arrived earlier!
I couldn't help it, there was a major traffic jam.
Ta-da!
We did it!
Finished!
Well, Professor?
Isn't this great?
What an amazing sand castle!
I know, right?
It's a masterpiece if I do say so myself!
I made it happen too!
I did what little I could and pitched in too!
I see, so all of you joined forces.
Hey, you guys.
Have you forgotten that we're here to gather clams?
Stop monkeying around already.
But...
To be frank, we've grown tired of it
No matter how hard we dig, all we got was sand.
Well, isn't this better?
They don't have to force themselves to search for clams.
It doesn't seem like there's a lot around here.
Is that so?
I beg to differ, though.
So many clams!
Really...
There's at least 20 or 30 of them!
Did you buy them at a fish market or something?
It so happens that many cheaters will do this!
Idiot!
Why would I do that?
There's a trick to this.
A trick.
So there's a trick?
Please teach me how!
Listen up.
Lightly rake over the beach where waves wash over and soften the sand beforehand.
And when the waves hit later...
See?
The clams come floating up since they're lighter than the sand.
Awesome!
You're the man, Conan!
Where'd you learn that from?
Just like magic!
Then, will we only find clams near the beach shore?
No, that's not true.
When clams stick out their siphons...
They create tiny holes that people nickname the "clam's eyes".
And since clams often aggregate in one place...
You just look for the spot with a bunch of small holes...
And start digging down 10 to 15 centimeters gently so as not to hurt their shells, then...
See?
Aren't there plenty of them?
CLAM DIGGING WITH A SIGH
(PART ONE)
See?
Huh?
Where'd they...
Those kids are...
Over there.
Awesome!
They keep popping up!
A huge haul, Genta-kun!
I found more "clam's eyes"!
If we had a bigger rake, wouldn't we be able to get a whole bunch and sell them?
Maybe we can even open a seafood store!
Clam Palace
A huge profit right there!
This is our chance!
Yes!
You can't do that.
The width of the rake needs to be under 15 centimeters...
And each person shouldn't take more than two kilograms, per proper manners.
Follow them and be as happy as a clam!
But still, does everyone really follow the rules?
It's imperative that each individual keeps the rules in mind.
Do you understand?
Genta-kun, if people were to catch too many eels and reduce their amount...
Preventing you from eating eel rice anymore, wouldn't you hate it too?
Oh, no!
I will never allow something like that!
Genta-kun...
See, nobody's in a rush to catch as much as they can, right?
Since the original purpose of shellfish gathering is to just have fun finding clams while getting showered in sand.
I see!
You're right!
Understood!
Looks like someone's not having fun, though.
See?
Maybe he can't find any clams.
Should we teach him?
How to find them.
Yeah,yeah!
Hey there!
Do you know what "clam's eyes" are?
If you dig up those tiny holes...
You will find this many clams!
Ushigome Tsuguo (21)
College Student
I've already gotten plenty of clams.
See?
Then, why were you sighing?
Why, why?
It's just...
A lot has been going on...
Hey, Ushigome!
We bought our lunch!
And snacks too!
Who are these brats?
Your acquaintances?
I just happened to bump into these kids.
Who are you guys then?
Hisazu Shouko (21)
College Student
Yashima Mitsue (20)
We are...
From the same club in our college, called...
Mitsuse Takashi (21)
College Student
"The Clam Clan," yo!
I don't get it, what kind of clan is that?
The four of you are wearing matching hoodies!
Are you guys aiming to become a comedy group?
Nah, that's not it.
Here, it's written on the back of our hoodies, right?
"The Clam Clan".
"The Clam Clan"?
In short, we are in the same group who love to gather and eat clams...
A clan of four people!
Well, today's the first time we're wearing these hoodies since they were made not long ago.
I see...
They're punning "clam" and "clan"...
Well, anyway, let's break for lunch, Ushigome.
Let's do that
Here!
We didn't forget to buy this.
Ushigome-kun, your favorite...
Hey, Ushigome!
Green tea!
Thanks.
Well...
This one?
Rice balls with salmon, pollack roe, and plum stuffings.
Thank you.
And then...
Potato chips as a snack.
Here, please enjoy.
Well?
How's our catch?
I've gathered quite a lot
Wow, isn't this amazing!
Let me take a look.
As expected of Ushigome-kun!
Somehow I'm getting hungry...
Already?
Didn't you just eat your boxed lunch, Genta-kun?
Then, to the convenience store...
Why don't we buy some snacks?
Yes!
In that case, I'll go then!
Mitsuhiko!
You're planning to sneakily buy some Yaiba chocolates, aren't you?
That's not true, Genta-kun...
Ayumi will go too!
Here.
In that case, all three of you go together as friends'.
But don't buy unnecessary things.
Got it?
And pay attention to the ears.
I heard there was recently a hit-and-run incident in this area!
You guys really need to be careful!
Yeah, yeah!
Loud and clear!
I'm gonna get some eel rice-flavored potato chips!
I wonder if they'll be all right?
They don't sell such a thing, Genta-kun!
Maybe we should head out soon.
That's right
We've dug up enough clams, after all.
We'll have a clam party at Ushigome-kun's place!
Then, Ushigome.
Well stay here and clean up our mess.
Why don't you carry the clams to the car and clean out their sand?
Hey, Ushigome?
Oh, that's right!
I happened to run into a restaurant with good shellfish cooking the other day.
So why don't we all go there?
Sounds good!
We'll go, well go!
So let's have lots of drinks at that restaurant tonight...
Then, crash at Ushigome's place...
And have the clams we got today for tomorrow's breakfast in some miso soup or something.
All right?
Sounds like a plan?
Ushigome?
Ushigome-kun...
Yeah...
Let's do that...
Uhm...
What happened to him?
He doesn't look too good.
Nothing...
Not a big deal...
Now, let's clean up, clean up!
Right!
All right then...
Don't forget to sort the trash.
Yeah, yeah.
This bag is for...
The plastic bottles.
Say...
What?
Just now...
The atmosphere changed.
Yeah.
Yaiba chocolates...
Yaiba gummies...
And Yaiba chips?
What the heck are these?
You bought these snacks just because you guys are after the Masked Yaiba freebies?
What's so wrong about it?
Genta-kun just wanted them so bad...
Mitsuhiko, that's low!
But those taste good.
That reminds me, those four who were here...
Did they go home?
Yeah, just now.
Right after they finished cleaning up after themselves.
My hats off to them for acting properly in contrast to young people these days.
Looks like they forgot one of their important tools.
A rake?
But, how do you know it belongs to them?
I don't see any name written on it
Look, you can see a fresh, blackened stain on this wooden handle, right?
This is probably a bloodstain.
Blood!?
I see.
That man who let out a sigh...
When we first saw him, he was sucking on his index finger.
So probably he cut his finger on a broken shell or something while digging for clams...
And the blood got on the rake handle, is that what you're saying?
Yeah, about right
Then, they might be looking for it right now...
Hey, Professor.
When exactly did those four leave?
Like I said, just now.
In that case, they might still be in the parking lot.
Then let's take it to them!
You're right.
Let's go together!
Yeah!
Conan-kun, I'll take this.
Hey!
By "just now," it's already been four or five minutes!
I'm sure they already left...
This is pretty spacious for a parking lot!
I'm sure they're still here!
Where are they?
Where?
There they are!
There they are.
You dropped something!
Hey!
Clam digging?
And then this happened?
After you finished digging, and while the three of you were cleaning up your trash on the beach...
He went ahead and carried the buckets full of clams to your car—I mean Ushigome-san.
And when you guys returned to the car, he was already in this state?
That's right
An almond scent from his mouth.
And since next to his body was this...
Green tea plastic bottle, what I can surmise is...
Presumably Ushigome-san died from drinking a mixture of green tea and cyanide derivatives.
Then...
As we thought...
A suicide?
As you thought?
Care to shed any light on this?
No, it's not like that.
He seemed to be distraught over something recently...
Since he wasn't cheerful.
I don't know what was troubling him, though.
Shouko, any idea?
No, I don't know.
But, judging from his state of mind...
I think it's possible that he committed suicide.
That's right...
Or maybe...
Taking advantage of Ushigome-san's suicidal mood as a convenient pretext...
One of you doctored this green tea...
By mixing poison into it, which is another valid possibility!
What are you insinuating?
We didn't do such a thing...
And?
Which of you bought the green tea?
All three of us bought it at the convenience store.
Since he said he hadn't eaten anything since breakfast
We also got some rice balls and snacks.
Then, did Ushigome-san take the green tea out of the plastic bag himself?
I did.
I handed it to him.
But soon after that, he was gulping it down as if nothing was wrong.
What about it?
Did any of you touch the plastic bottle while he was drinking from it?
The only time we may have touched it was when we bought it
Ushigome-kun held onto it the entire time.
It's unlikely that anyone else touched it
And I merely passed the rice balls over to Ushigome by throwing it
Rice balls with salmon, pollack roe, and plum stuffings.
Thank you.
I did open the bag of potato chips and place it next to him, but...
I never touched the green tea.
Here, please enjoy.
Thank you, thank you.
However...
One could've done it when the others weren't looking.
No way!
What those people are saying is all true!
I was watching the entire time.
And after Ushigome-san unscrewed the cap, no one other than Ushigome-san touched it.
Runt...
Weren't you with that Smoking Kogorou before or something?
"Smoking"?
Sleeping!
If that's the case, is that private detective with a small mustache here also?
Where?
He's not here.
Is that so?
In his stead, my friends tagged along.
Conan-kun!
We brought the professor here!
Professor, you tell him.
That Ushigome-san was holding his green tea bottle the entire time.
Understood.
I don't think he let anyone else handle his tea while he was drinking it
Are you sure you didn't take your eyes off him?
It's true.
Although today was the first time the children and I came across him at this beach...
We saw him let out a deep sigh, so we were concerned a little bit
A deep sigh?
Inspector!
Near the feet of the body...
I found this small jar lying around!
Is that so?
Let's see.
Judging from the fact that someone replaced the pills with powder...
Looks like this is the cyanide substance in question.
That's...
The jar Ushigome-kun used to hold his supplement pills!
Are you telling the truth?
There's no doubt about it
Since I often saw him taking those.
That so?
Forensics!
Examine this jar along with the plastic bottle and the lid if you will.
Roger.
What I mean is...
Then, I'm counting on you.
But at that time...
At that time...
What is it, you runts?
Did you recall anything else that might help?
Oh, no...
It's just...
Could you laugh a bit for us?
COME AGAIN!?
Because you looked just like that person...
Just like a certain coral-haired police officer we know!
Howdy!
Doing all right?
It's no surprise he looks like him.
Since this person is the younger brother of that Inspector Yokomizo.
Are you really!?
I do recall my brother telling me...
About how that Smoking Kogorou...
It's Sleeping, you know?
And a brat with glasses...
"A brat with glasses"!?
And some runts who like to play detective...
Used to hang out together!
What was that?
We're not playing!
We're the Detective Boys!
That's right!
Although their faces and voices are similar...
Their ways of speech and tempers are complete opposites.
Yeah, looks that way.
I hate to tell you this, but looks like well have no further use of your little detective group this time.
What do you mean?
No one else touched the plastic bottle in question.
And the container with a substance resembling poison was found inside the car.
Not to mention he was so depressed that he kept sighing.
We have no choice but to deem it a suicide.
So,shoo!
You brats go home, go!
You're in the way!
Why the rush, "younger brother"?
Don't be so stingy!
Does that cap really belong to that plastic bottle?
Yeah...
Since only this little guy was in the car...
Moreover, the tea residue on the inside of the cap hasn't dried yet
And the brand is a match.
But isn't that strange?
There's blood around the mouth of the bottle.
But I see nothing of that sort on the cap.
You're right...
What?
Hey, hey, why is there blood on this?
Well...
I guess it's because...
Ushigome-kun...
Ushigome-kun injured his finger, right?
An injury?
If that's the case, he probably cut himself on a broken shell or something while picking up clams.
I bet he was picking those up while having a lot on his mind.
It's most likely true that he was injured.
Since when we first met him, he was sucking on his finger.
That's why we realized the rake with blood that was forgotten on the beach belonged to that chubby mister.
And when we came to return it...
We encountered this scene.
I see.
He does have a cut on his right index finger.
But the blood already clotted.
So basically, when he first unscrewed the cap...
The fact that his wound hadn't closed resulted in his blood getting on it
But when he brought the bottle with him here...
He noticed the blood on the cap just as he was about to open it again.
So he wiped off the blood before opening it, and that's what transpired.
But...
Would a person who's about to commit suicide do such a thing?
"It's an ill bird that fouls its own nest".
Maybe he wanted to keep it clean before he died.
Anyway, I'm waiting for the forensics report
Until then, I'll have to ask you guys to be on standby!
Understood.
We have no choice.