From a different perspective...
An imposing wall is just a large door.
We Detective Boys are going clam digging.
And the elite police detective and
younger brother takes the stage!
Are we there yet?
Just wait a little more.
That's why I said we should've arrived earlier!
I couldn't help it, there was a major traffic jam.
Ta-da!
We did it!
Finished!
Well, Professor?
Isn't this great?
What an amazing sand castle!
I know, right?
It's a masterpiece if I do say so myself!
I made it happen too!
I did what little I could and pitched in too!
I see, so all of you joined forces.
Hey, you guys.
Have you forgotten that we're here to gather clams?
Stop monkeying around already.
But...
To be frank, we've grown tired of it
No matter how hard we dig, all we got was sand.
Well, isn't this better?
They don't have to force themselves to search for clams.
It doesn't seem like there's a lot around here.
Is that so?
I beg to differ, though.
So many clams!
Really...
There's at least 20 or 30 of them!
Did you buy them at a fish market or something?
It so happens that many cheaters will do this!
Idiot!
Why would I do that?
There's a trick to this.
A trick.
So there's a trick?
Please teach me how!
Listen up.
Lightly rake over the beach where waves wash over and soften the sand beforehand.
And when the waves hit later...
See?
The clams come floating up since they're lighter than the sand.
Awesome!
You're the man, Conan!
Where'd you learn that from?
Just like magic!
Then, will we only find clams near the beach shore?
No, that's not true.
When clams stick out their siphons...
They create tiny holes that people nickname the "clam's eyes".
And since clams often aggregate in one place...
You just look for the spot with a bunch of small holes...
And start digging down 10 to 15 centimeters gently so as not to hurt their shells, then...
See?
Aren't there plenty of them?
CLAM DIGGING WITH A SIGH
(PART ONE)
See?
Huh?
Where'd they...
Those kids are...
Over there.
Awesome!
They keep popping up!
A huge haul, Genta-kun!
I found more "clam's eyes"!
If we had a bigger rake, wouldn't we be able to get a whole bunch and sell them?
Maybe we can even open a seafood store!
Clam Palace
A huge profit right there!
This is our chance!
Yes!
You can't do that.
The width of the rake needs to be under 15 centimeters...
And each person shouldn't take more than two kilograms, per proper manners.
Follow them and be as happy as a clam!
But still, does everyone really follow the rules?
It's imperative that each individual keeps the rules in mind.
Do you understand?
Genta-kun, if people were to catch too many eels and reduce their amount...
Preventing you from eating eel rice anymore, wouldn't you hate it too?
Oh, no!
I will never allow something like that!
Genta-kun...
See, nobody's in a rush to catch as much as they can, right?
Since the original purpose of shellfish gathering is to just have fun finding clams while getting showered in sand.
I see!
You're right!
Understood!
Looks like someone's not having fun, though.
See?
Maybe he can't find any clams.
Should we teach him?
How to find them.
Yeah,yeah!
Hey there!
Do you know what "clam's eyes" are?
If you dig up those tiny holes...
You will find this many clams!
Ushigome Tsuguo (21)
College Student
I've already gotten plenty of clams.
See?
Then, why were you sighing?
Why, why?
It's just...
A lot has been going on...
Hey, Ushigome!
We bought our lunch!
And snacks too!
Who are these brats?
Your acquaintances?
I just happened to bump into these kids.
Who are you guys then?
Hisazu Shouko (21)
College Student
Yashima Mitsue (20)
We are...
From the same club in our college, called...
Mitsuse Takashi (21)
College Student
"The Clam Clan," yo!
I don't get it, what kind of clan is that?
The four of you are wearing matching hoodies!
Are you guys aiming to become a comedy group?
Nah, that's not it.
Here, it's written on the back of our hoodies, right?
"The Clam Clan".
"The Clam Clan"?
In short, we are in the same group who love to gather and eat clams...
A clan of four people!
Well, today's the first time we're wearing these hoodies since they were made not long ago.
I see...
They're punning "clam" and "clan"...
Well, anyway, let's break for lunch, Ushigome.
Let's do that
Here!
We didn't forget to buy this.
Ushigome-kun, your favorite...
Hey, Ushigome!
Green tea!
Thanks.
Well...
This one?
Rice balls with salmon, pollack roe, and plum stuffings.
Thank you.
And then...
Potato chips as a snack.
Here, please enjoy.
Well?
How's our catch?
I've gathered quite a lot
Wow, isn't this amazing!
Let me take a look.
As expected of Ushigome-kun!
Somehow I'm getting hungry...
Already?
Didn't you just eat your boxed lunch, Genta-kun?
Then, to the convenience store...
Why don't we buy some snacks?
Yes!
In that case, I'll go then!
Mitsuhiko!
You're planning to sneakily buy some Yaiba chocolates, aren't you?
That's not true, Genta-kun...
Ayumi will go too!
Here.
In that case, all three of you go together as friends'.
But don't buy unnecessary things.
Got it?
And pay attention to the ears.
I heard there was recently a hit-and-run incident in this area!
You guys really need to be careful!
Yeah, yeah!
Loud and clear!
I'm gonna get some eel rice-flavored potato chips!
I wonder if they'll be all right?
They don't sell such a thing, Genta-kun!
Maybe we should head out soon.
That's right
We've dug up enough clams, after all.
We'll have a clam party at Ushigome-kun's place!
Then, Ushigome.
Well stay here and clean up our mess.
Why don't you carry the clams to the car and clean out their sand?
Hey, Ushigome?
Oh, that's right!
I happened to run into a restaurant with good shellfish cooking the other day.
So why don't we all go there?
Sounds good!
We'll go, well go!
So let's have lots of drinks at that restaurant tonight...
Then, crash at Ushigome's place...
And have the clams we got today for tomorrow's breakfast in some miso soup or something.
All right?
Sounds like a plan?
Ushigome?
Ushigome-kun...
Yeah...
Let's do that...
Uhm...
What happened to him?
He doesn't look too good.
Nothing...
Not a big deal...
Now, let's clean up, clean up!
Right!
All right then...
Don't forget to sort the trash.
Yeah, yeah.
This bag is for...
The plastic bottles.
Say...
What?
Just now...
The atmosphere changed.
Yeah.
Yaiba chocolates...
Yaiba gummies...
And Yaiba chips?
What the heck are these?
You bought these snacks just because you guys are after the Masked Yaiba freebies?
What's so wrong about it?
Genta-kun just wanted them so bad...
Mitsuhiko, that's low!
But those taste good.
That reminds me, those four who were here...
Did they go home?
Yeah, just now.
Right after they finished cleaning up after themselves.
My hats off to them for acting properly in contrast to young people these days.
Looks like they forgot one of their important tools.
A rake?
But, how do you know it belongs to them?
I don't see any name written on it
Look, you can see a fresh, blackened stain on this wooden handle, right?
This is probably a bloodstain.
Blood!?
I see.
That man who let out a sigh...
When we first saw him, he was sucking on his index finger.
So probably he cut his finger on a broken shell or something while digging for clams...
And the blood got on the rake handle, is that what you're saying?
Yeah, about right
Then, they might be looking for it right now...
Hey, Professor.
When exactly did those four leave?
Like I said, just now.
In that case, they might still be in the parking lot.
Then let's take it to them!
You're right.
Let's go together!
Yeah!
Conan-kun, I'll take this.
Hey!
By "just now," it's already been four or five minutes!
I'm sure they already left...
This is pretty spacious for a parking lot!
I'm sure they're still here!
Where are they?
Where?
There they are!
There they are.
You dropped something!
Hey!
Clam digging?
And then this happened?
After you finished digging, and while the three of you were cleaning up your trash on the beach...
He went ahead and carried the buckets full of clams to your car—I mean Ushigome-san.
And when you guys returned to the car, he was already in this state?
That's right
An almond scent from his mouth.
And since next to his body was this...
Green tea plastic bottle, what I can surmise is...
Presumably Ushigome-san died from drinking a mixture of green tea and cyanide derivatives.
Then...
As we thought...
A suicide?
As you thought?
Care to shed any light on this?
No, it's not like that.
He seemed to be distraught over something recently...
Since he wasn't cheerful.
I don't know what was troubling him, though.
Shouko, any idea?
No, I don't know.
But, judging from his state of mind...
I think it's possible that he committed suicide.
That's right...
Or maybe...
Taking advantage of Ushigome-san's suicidal mood as a convenient pretext...
One of you doctored this green tea...
By mixing poison into it, which is another valid possibility!
What are you insinuating?
We didn't do such a thing...
And?
Which of you bought the green tea?
All three of us bought it at the convenience store.
Since he said he hadn't eaten anything since breakfast
We also got some rice balls and snacks.
Then, did Ushigome-san take the green tea out of the plastic bag himself?
I did.
I handed it to him.
But soon after that, he was gulping it down as if nothing was wrong.
What about it?
Did any of you touch the plastic bottle while he was drinking from it?
The only time we may have touched it was when we bought it
Ushigome-kun held onto it the entire time.
It's unlikely that anyone else touched it
And I merely passed the rice balls over to Ushigome by throwing it
Rice balls with salmon, pollack roe, and plum stuffings.
Thank you.
I did open the bag of potato chips and place it next to him, but...
I never touched the green tea.
Here, please enjoy.
Thank you, thank you.
However...
One could've done it when the others weren't looking.
No way!
What those people are saying is all true!
I was watching the entire time.
And after Ushigome-san unscrewed the cap, no one other than Ushigome-san touched it.
Runt...
Weren't you with that Smoking Kogorou before or something?
"Smoking"?
Sleeping!
If that's the case, is that private detective with a small mustache here also?
Where?
He's not here.
Is that so?
In his stead, my friends tagged along.
Conan-kun!
We brought the professor here!
Professor, you tell him.
That Ushigome-san was holding his green tea bottle the entire time.
Understood.
I don't think he let anyone else handle his tea while he was drinking it
Are you sure you didn't take your eyes off him?
It's true.
Although today was the first time the children and I came across him at this beach...
We saw him let out a deep sigh, so we were concerned a little bit
A deep sigh?
Inspector!
Near the feet of the body...
I found this small jar lying around!
Is that so?
Let's see.
Judging from the fact that someone replaced the pills with powder...
Looks like this is the cyanide substance in question.
That's...
The jar Ushigome-kun used to hold his supplement pills!
Are you telling the truth?
There's no doubt about it
Since I often saw him taking those.
That so?
Forensics!
Examine this jar along with the plastic bottle and the lid if you will.
Roger.
What I mean is...
Then, I'm counting on you.
But at that time...
At that time...
What is it, you runts?
Did you recall anything else that might help?
Oh, no...
It's just...
Could you laugh a bit for us?
COME AGAIN!?
Because you looked just like that person...
Just like a certain coral-haired police officer we know!
Howdy!
Doing all right?
It's no surprise he looks like him.
Since this person is the younger brother of that Inspector Yokomizo.
Are you really!?
I do recall my brother telling me...
About how that Smoking Kogorou...
It's Sleeping, you know?
And a brat with glasses...
"A brat with glasses"!?
And some runts who like to play detective...
Used to hang out together!
What was that?
We're not playing!
We're the Detective Boys!
That's right!
Although their faces and voices are similar...
Their ways of speech and tempers are complete opposites.
Yeah, looks that way.
I hate to tell you this, but looks like well have no further use of your little detective group this time.
What do you mean?
No one else touched the plastic bottle in question.
And the container with a substance resembling poison was found inside the car.
Not to mention he was so depressed that he kept sighing.
We have no choice but to deem it a suicide.
So,shoo!
You brats go home, go!
You're in the way!
Why the rush, "younger brother"?
Don't be so stingy!
Does that cap really belong to that plastic bottle?
Yeah...
Since only this little guy was in the car...
Moreover, the tea residue on the inside of the cap hasn't dried yet
And the brand is a match.
But isn't that strange?
There's blood around the mouth of the bottle.
But I see nothing of that sort on the cap.
You're right...
What?
Hey, hey, why is there blood on this?
Well...
I guess it's because...
Ushigome-kun...
Ushigome-kun injured his finger, right?
An injury?
If that's the case, he probably cut himself on a broken shell or something while picking up clams.
I bet he was picking those up while having a lot on his mind.
It's most likely true that he was injured.
Since when we first met him, he was sucking on his finger.
That's why we realized the rake with blood that was forgotten on the beach belonged to that chubby mister.
And when we came to return it...
We encountered this scene.
I see.
He does have a cut on his right index finger.
But the blood already clotted.
So basically, when he first unscrewed the cap...
The fact that his wound hadn't closed resulted in his blood getting on it
But when he brought the bottle with him here...
He noticed the blood on the cap just as he was about to open it again.
So he wiped off the blood before opening it, and that's what transpired.
But...
Would a person who's about to commit suicide do such a thing?
"It's an ill bird that fouls its own nest".
Maybe he wanted to keep it clean before he died.
Anyway, I'm waiting for the forensics report
Until then, I'll have to ask you guys to be on standby!
Understood.
We have no choice.
CLAM DIGGING WITH A SIGH
(PART TWO)
Hold on, Genta-kun!
Please don't eat the snacks in a place like this!
Want a bite?
You opened up everything!
Geez, how much longer is that younger brother Yokomizo gonna keep us waiting?
Thanks.
Looks like an update's coming.
Let's check it out!
Wait for me!
Well, according to the forensics report...
The substance found inside the green tea was poisonous cyanide derivatives.
Yashima Mitsue (20)
College Student
It was also detected from the cap of the plastic bottle.
Mitsuse Takashi (21)
College Student
Adding to the fact that the jar found in the car also contained the same poison...
Hisazu Shouko (21)
College Student
Looks like we can conclude Ushigome-san's incident as a suicide.
Is that so...
By the way, whose car is this?
It's a rental car Ushigome paid for.
Because he's always the driver whenever we go clam digging.
So do you guys come to this beach often?
No, this is our first time here.
We actually planned to come last week, but...
Things came up...
So we prolonged it until this week.
Well, you can fill me in while at the station.
Say...
Did they find any traces of blood on the plastic bottle cap?
Although a minute amount, they did find some.
Along with Ushigome-san's fingerprints.
"Minute amount"?
Most likely when he first unscrewed the cap...
His wound didn't come into much contact with the cap.
Well, now that everything's clear, go home already!
All you kids!
Suicide...
Is this really a suicide?
Surely Ushigome-san had opened the plastic bottle lid and started drinking green tea...
And nobody else touched it afterwards.
The one who carried the plastic bottle to this car was also Ushigome-san himself.
I don't see any windows of opportunity for anyone to lace the poison...
But it's bugging me...
What that person said earlier.
At that time, why did that person...
Hold on, Genta-kun!
What kind of weird look is that?
I don't have a choice!
Because both my hands are tied!
Then, why not wrap up your chocolate in that silver foil...
And put it inside the bag along with the chips?
Once I got my hands on the food, I don't want to let go!
Say, everyone.
Do you still have the garbage bags with you?
Yeah...
You're going to the police station now, right?
How about I throw them away for you?
If you insist...
But we also drank and ate a lot in the car, so there's quite an amount of trash.
These are the recyclable plastic bottles.
Here's the combustible trash.
And this is non-combustible trash.
Well, we're counting on you.
Conan-kun!
What's with all those?
What are you planning to do, bringing their trash here?
Hey now!
But they had everything sorted out...
Are you going to do some crafts?
What're you gonna make out of plastic bottles?
I see.
Well, you're wearing a smug grin on your face...
So you figured out something?
Yeah.
That it wasn't a suicide at all.
Then, who's the culprit?
Before I reveal that, I have something for you guys to help out with.
What is it?
Just a little more digging.
Geez, Conan...
If you already figured out the culprit, why do we have to keep digging like this?
Not to mention since we're so far away from the water, are we even going to find any clams here?
If I recall correctly, this place is where those students had spread out their sheets earlier.
Yeah.
To say nothing of clams, even the trash was picked clean and there's absolutely nothing here.
Like I said, we're not looking for clams, but the plastic bottle...
Found it!
I found the plastic bottle cap!
You can't touch it, Ayumi-chan!
It says "green tea" on top.
If I recall, that guy named Ushigome was also drinking green tea, right?
What's more, isn't that blood on the lid?
It's blackened a little, but...
It's likely blood.
Then, could it be that cap is...
Right.
This should make everything clear.
Not only the fact that Ushigome-san did not commit suicide but was murdered...
And also the culprit who did this!
Well, we're headed to the station for questioning.
So give those three a ride in my car—
Younger bro, younger bro, younger bro!
Please wait up!
Wait for us!
Can you hear us out first before you take those three to questioning?
Hear you out?
Because we just figured it out!
Just figured out what?
We're telling you—the culprit who killed Ushigome-san.
And that culprit was...
Someone who came clam digging with Ushigome-san...
In other words, one of you three!
Hey, hey, the hell are you yappin' about?
This was a suicide!
A suicide!
Ushigome-san was headed to this stationary car in the parking lot all by himself.
And by the time these three returned from cleaning the trash on the beach...
He already passed away, right?
Not to mention the green tea bottle laced with poison was lying nearby the vic...
And next to his feet, we found the same poison jar rolling around.
Based on the testimony that Ushigome-san was drinking the green tea at the beach just fine...
One could only conclude that he mixed poison in his green tea and drank it himself.
There's no other way to look at it!
But about that green tea...
Ushigome-san didn't purchase it himself, did he?
Yeah.
It was these three people who bought it? but...
Yashima-san only handed the plastic green tea bottle to him.
Mitsuse-san just tossed him a pack of rice balls.
Hisazu-san merely opened up the chips and put it next to him.
Ever since Ushigome-san unscrewed the green tea lid at the beach...
None of those three had touched the plastic bottle.
Not to mention Ushigome-san was carrying the plastic bottle the entire time, no?
So tell me who, when, and how did anyone manage to poison him?
Have you forgotten something?
What do you mean?
It's something that always comes with plastic bottles, you know?
Something that comes with plastic bottles would be...
The labels that carry the product names?
What are you talking about, younger bro?
The cap, the bottle cap!
If one applies poison on the inside of a plastic bottle cap...
And without touching the plastic bottle, swaps the old cap with this new, poisoned one...
The poison would be easily mixed in!
I see, what an amazing deduction.
However, as much as I want to say that...
That's impracticable, kids.
It might've worked out if the plastic bottle were still completely filled with green tea.
But Ushigome-san already opened the screw cap and gulped down a large amount, hadn't he?
Assuming that's the case, even if the cap was swapped with the poisonous one later...
The poison on the closed cap wouldn't have reached the green tea at all.
However, suppose that you apply it on the spiral part inside the cap?
That's right!
In that case, it will go on the mouth of the plastic bottle when he screws the cap back on.
Yeah, it's true that his lips will contract poison when he takes a sip that way.
But the toxic substance in question...
Was found in lethal amounts in the green tea contained in the plastic bottle.
If the poison only got on the mouth of the plastic bottle...
There wouldn't have been much poison in the green tea.
That's true.
Well, if you wanted to mix the poison on the inside of the cap into the green tea...
You'd have to put the plastic bottle upside down or...
Shake the bottle with a splashing sound for it to get mixed in.
Did Ushigome-san have a habit like that?
No...
He'd shake it only if it's tomato juice or something.
Perhaps he laid it sideways?
Sideways?
If I recall, Ushigome-san...
Returned to the car while carrying two buckets, right?
Yeah, that's right
Hey.
How come Ushigome-san had to carry the buckets himself and none of you helped out?
Because Ushigome was the one who knew the most about clams.
And he's always in charge of picking up the clams and cleaning the sand out of them.
Although we were the ones who had to cook it
Was it always two buckets?
Yeah, about right
I don't care about that trivial stuff.
I'm asking you to answer why you said "sideways"
Because...
Ushigome-san had to hold the two buckets and both of his hands were occupied!
I'm asking...
In that case, he'd either have to put the plastic bottle in the bucket, under his arms...
Or inside the kangaroo pocket of his hoodie like the ones you're wearing...
Placing it sideways, wouldn't he?
Come to think of it, Ushigome-san did keep the plastic bottle sideways inside his pocket like that
I see.
If it were sideways, the green tea inside would shake whenever he walks.
This trick guarantees that by the time he reached the parking lot, the poison on the inside of the cap...
Would have been completely mixed into the green tea.
Yeah, that's exactly right.
But, still...
What if he didn't conveniently happen to put on a hoodie with a pocket like that?
I think he didn't just "happen to" wear it.
What these people are wearing is the matching hoodies they made for their Clam Clan.
And since it was made not long ago, if someone suggested that they wear it for today's clam digging...
Wouldn't Ushigome-san also comply and wear it?
Plus, since Ushigome-san had always carried two buckets and returned to the car before you guys...
Someone could have easily predicted that he would put the plastic bottle in his hoodie pocket sideways.
I have to agree it's possible to mix poison that way, but...
The problem is, who was able to swap the poisonous cap and how?
Normally, when you unscrew a cap, you would likely put it near you, right?
That's right
I believe Ushigome-san had also placed it somewhere on the sheet he was sitting on.
If that's the case, since all that Yashima lady did...
Was hand him the plastic bottle...
It's impossible for her to have swapped it
And still, that Mitsuse mister...
Did nothing other than tossing him the pack of rice balls.
And if he were to stretch his arm and attempt to switch the cap sitting on the sheet, he would've been seen.
In that case, that leaves us with the person who placed the bag of chips next to Ushigome-san.
Hisazu-san...
Apparently you had the best chance to swap out the cap sitting on the sheet
What the...
Hold on, what are you saying?
How could she if all she did was to put down a bag of chips?
That bag of chips is the perfect camouflage for the deed.
Hisazu-san placed the bag of chips immediately next to Ushigome-san.
You simply had to hold the poisoned cap between your fingers beforehand...
And swapped the caps with the bag obstructing the view.
Having done so, Ushigome-san would mistake the cap as the one he put
So how come there's blood on the mouth of the plastic bottle and none on the cap?
The answer is because the vic touched the swapped poisonous cap after his finger wound began to heal.
Of course, even if his wound was closing, he still used the same finger to unscrew and screw the cap.
That's why we detected a minute amount of blood even on the poisonous cap.
Isn't that how it played out?
Isn't that right, Professor?
Yeah...
Which means the original cap with Ushigome-san's blood should be around somewhere.
Didn't you guys have some bags of trash?
We gave them to the brat with glasses.
Hey, hey...
Don't tell me you've examined the caps?
But even though there were six plastic bottles...
I only found five caps.
Only the cap of the empty green tea bottle was missing.
So is this what transpired?
First she had Ushigome-san drink up a whole bottle of green tea that she bought in advance...
And filched the cap.
Then she laced poison on it somewhere else, and replaced the newly bought green tea bottle cap with it
Now, all she had to do is to suggest going home at the right time.
Ushigome-san would return to the car and likely drink up the remaining poisoned tea.
Later on, if the police discovered the jar with toxicant she had left in the car beforehand...
It would make it ostensibly a suicide.
Perhaps that jar was also...
Swiped from Ushigome-san without his permission in order to use it as a staged suicide prop.
But, your calculations were thrown off when you were swapping the caps.
The cap had already been smeared in Ushigome-san's blood.
That's why you didn't throw it in the trash bag, right?
If we had collected that, we would have figured out it was swapped out
Although you may have already tossed away that bloody cap somewhere...
We could always try searching the beach where you were.
I already thought of that and found it
Here.
The green tea bottle cap with blood.
But, how could that be proof?
If you're talking about fingerprints, she had already touched it during the convenience store purchase!
-Nah, I'm not talking about fingerprints.
By coming into contact with the cap...
Hisazu-san's fingers would likely test positive for this.
The evidence that you touched Ushigome-san's blood...
A luminol reaction.
Come on, Shouko, are you all right with him accusing you all he wants?
Why don't you retort him!?
Tell him he can search all he wants and get nothing!
I can't retort him.
Because what that officer just said...
Every bit of it was the truth.
Hey, don't tell me it's because of that accident...
Accident?
Hey, what is it?
What accident?
Well, do you recall?
The hit-and-run incident here last week.
Maybe it has something to do with that?
Since they showed a gloomy look . when that topic was brought up.
Hit-and-run?
The one that involved hitting a drunkard?
So that was you guys?
But we didn't know!
Not until we saw the newspaper the next day!
Besides...
Hey!
Besides?
What?
Besides...
Since Ushigome-kun said we might have hit something...
We all got out of the car and checked around immediately, but didn't see anyone.
There was.
There was someone at that time.
In the patch of grass where I checked...
A man was lying on the ground, drenched in blood...
Then, why didn't you say anything!?
I couldn't!
That man wasn't breathing...
And Ushigome-kun had been drinking.
If we were found out, we'd lose our new jobs that are so hard to come by!
That's right...
If only Ushigome-kun would've kept his mouth shut...
If he didn't start talking about turning himself in...
You're just like a clam.
No matter how well you think you've hidden...
You'll always leave behind a trace somewhere.
That troublesome something will become more apparent the more you try to hide.
Even if Ushigome-san didn't own up, we police would've still tracked you down.
By sniffing out that rotten hole in your heart
We've finally cleaned these all up.
We can't just leave them here after all.
But to think that you ascertained the culprit's identity just by seeing the bag of chips placed next to victim...
That's not the only thing.
When I mentioned the mouth of the plastic bottle had blood on it...
She blurted out that Ushigome-kun injured his finger.
What about it?
I just happened to know that he had cut his finger, but...
Normally if there's blood on the mouth of a plastic bottle...
Shouldn't people assume that it was either because his lips cracked, or there's a wound in his mouth?
Especially since there was no blood on the cap found next to Ushigome-san.
That's how I figured out
The reason why Hisazu-san said that was because she saw the cap with blood when she did the switch.
Isn't it just like you said, Professor?
Just like that
That's right.
I'll need you to come to the station later as well.
Bring the brats too...
Some of the brats are gone?
Huh?
You're right...
If you're looking for them...
They went back to the beach in a big rush just now.
Saying they lost some very important thing.
Geez!
And it was a Yaiba figure we had never seen before!
Geez, and you really don't remember where you dropped it?
If I did, I would've found it by now!
It was super rare!
It's the kind we'll never get if we don't buy a truckload.
You guys love it, don't you?
Digging in the sand...