From a different perspective...
An imposing wall is just a large door.
The stubbord detective, Yokomizo's younger brother
and the great deduction that amazed him!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Together with Professor Agassa, we came to collect clams.
By chance, we met students from the Clam Clan.
However, one of them, Ushigome Tsuguo, died
after drinking a poisoned cyanide drink.
An examination of the scene
showed a high probability of suicide, but...
But that's strange.
There's blood on the neck of the bottle,
but there's no blood on the lid.
Ushigome must have scratched his finger.
Scratched it?
So when he was picking up the clams,
he cut himself on a broken shell or something.
He must have been picking them while he was deep in thought.
I see.
Indeed, there's a cut on his index finger.
The blood clotted.
So when he opened the cap the first time, the scratch was still bleeding,
and the blood got on the bottle.
He brought it here and when he opened it a second time, he noticed the blood on the cap.
After wiping off the cap, he opened the bottle.
CLAM DIGGING WITH A SIGH
(PART TWO)
Hold on, Genta-kun!
Please don't eat the snacks in a place like this!
Want a bite?
You opened up everything!
Geez, how much longer is that younger brother Yokomizo gonna keep us waiting?
Thanks.
Looks like an update's coming.
Let's check it out!
Wait for me!
Well, according to the forensics report...
The substance found inside the green tea was poisonous cyanide derivatives.
Yashima Mitsue (20)
College Student
It was also detected from the cap of the plastic bottle.
Mitsuse Takashi (21)
College Student
Adding to the fact that the jar found in the car also contained the same poison...
Hisazu Shouko (21)
College Student
Looks like we can conclude Ushigome-san's incident as a suicide.
Is that so...
By the way, whose car is this?
It's a rental car Ushigome paid for.
Because he's always the driver whenever we go clam digging.
So do you guys come to this beach often?
No, this is our first time here.
We actually planned to come last week, but...
Things came up...
So we prolonged it until this week.
Well, you can fill me in while at the station.
Say...
Did they find any traces of blood on the plastic bottle cap?
Although a minute amount, they did find some.
Along with Ushigome-san's fingerprints.
"Minute amount"?
Most likely when he first unscrewed the cap...
His wound didn't come into much contact with the cap.
Well, now that everything's clear, go home already!
All you kids!
Suicide...
Is this really a suicide?
Surely Ushigome-san had opened the plastic bottle lid and started drinking green tea...
And nobody else touched it afterwards.
The one who carried the plastic bottle to this car was also Ushigome-san himself.
I don't see any windows of opportunity for anyone to lace the poison...
But it's bugging me...
What that person said earlier.
At that time, why did that person...
Hold on, Genta-kun!
What kind of weird look is that?
I don't have a choice!
Because both my hands are tied!
Then, why not wrap up your chocolate in that silver foil...
And put it inside the bag along with the chips?
Once I got my hands on the food, I don't want to let go!
Say, everyone.
Do you still have the garbage bags with you?
Yeah...
You're going to the police station now, right?
How about I throw them away for you?
If you insist...
But we also drank and ate a lot in the car, so there's quite an amount of trash.
These are the recyclable plastic bottles.
Here's the combustible trash.
And this is non-combustible trash.
Well, we're counting on you.
Conan-kun!
What's with all those?
What are you planning to do, bringing their trash here?
Hey now!
But they had everything sorted out...
Are you going to do some crafts?
What're you gonna make out of plastic bottles?
I see.
Well, you're wearing a smug grin on your face...
So you figured out something?
Yeah.
That it wasn't a suicide at all.
Then, who's the culprit?
Before I reveal that, I have something for you guys to help out with.
What is it?
Just a little more digging.
Geez, Conan...
If you already figured out the culprit, why do we have to keep digging like this?
Not to mention since we're so far away from the water, are we even going to find any clams here?
If I recall correctly, this place is where those students had spread out their sheets earlier.
Yeah.
To say nothing of clams, even the trash was picked clean and there's absolutely nothing here.
Like I said, we're not looking for clams, but the plastic bottle...
Found it!
I found the plastic bottle cap!
You can't touch it, Ayumi-chan!
It says "green tea" on top.
If I recall, that guy named Ushigome was also drinking green tea, right?
What's more, isn't that blood on the lid?
It's blackened a little, but...
It's likely blood.
Then, could it be that cap is...
Right.
This should make everything clear.
Not only the fact that Ushigome-san did not commit suicide but was murdered...
And also the culprit who did this!
Well, we're headed to the station for questioning.
So give those three a ride in my car—
Younger bro, younger bro, younger bro!
Please wait up!
Wait for us!
Can you hear us out first before you take those three to questioning?
Hear you out?
Because we just figured it out!
Just figured out what?
We're telling you—the culprit who killed Ushigome-san.
And that culprit was...
Someone who came clam digging with Ushigome-san...
In other words, one of you three!
Hey, hey, the hell are you yappin' about?
This was a suicide!
A suicide!
Ushigome-san was headed to this stationary car in the parking lot all by himself.
And by the time these three returned from cleaning the trash on the beach...
He already passed away, right?
Not to mention the green tea bottle laced with poison was lying nearby the vic...
And next to his feet, we found the same poison jar rolling around.
Based on the testimony that Ushigome-san was drinking the green tea at the beach just fine...
One could only conclude that he mixed poison in his green tea and drank it himself.
There's no other way to look at it!
But about that green tea...
Ushigome-san didn't purchase it himself, did he?
Yeah.
It was these three people who bought it? but...
Yashima-san only handed the plastic green tea bottle to him.
Mitsuse-san just tossed him a pack of rice balls.
Hisazu-san merely opened up the chips and put it next to him.
Ever since Ushigome-san unscrewed the green tea lid at the beach...
None of those three had touched the plastic bottle.
Not to mention Ushigome-san was carrying the plastic bottle the entire time, no?
So tell me who, when, and how did anyone manage to poison him?
Have you forgotten something?
What do you mean?
It's something that always comes with plastic bottles, you know?
Something that comes with plastic bottles would be...
The labels that carry the product names?
What are you talking about, younger bro?
The cap, the bottle cap!
If one applies poison on the inside of a plastic bottle cap...
And without touching the plastic bottle, swaps the old cap with this new, poisoned one...
The poison would be easily mixed in!
I see, what an amazing deduction.
However, as much as I want to say that...
That's impracticable, kids.
It might've worked out if the plastic bottle were still completely filled with green tea.
But Ushigome-san already opened the screw cap and gulped down a large amount, hadn't he?
Assuming that's the case, even if the cap was swapped with the poisonous one later...
The poison on the closed cap wouldn't have reached the green tea at all.
However, suppose that you apply it on the spiral part inside the cap?
That's right!
In that case, it will go on the mouth of the plastic bottle when he screws the cap back on.
Yeah, it's true that his lips will contract poison when he takes a sip that way.
But the toxic substance in question...
Was found in lethal amounts in the green tea contained in the plastic bottle.
If the poison only got on the mouth of the plastic bottle...
There wouldn't have been much poison in the green tea.
That's true.
Well, if you wanted to mix the poison on the inside of the cap into the green tea...
You'd have to put the plastic bottle upside down or...
Shake the bottle with a splashing sound for it to get mixed in.
Did Ushigome-san have a habit like that?
No...
He'd shake it only if it's tomato juice or something.
Perhaps he laid it sideways?
Sideways?
If I recall, Ushigome-san...
Returned to the car while carrying two buckets, right?
Yeah, that's right
Hey.
How come Ushigome-san had to carry the buckets himself and none of you helped out?
Because Ushigome was the one who knew the most about clams.
And he's always in charge of picking up the clams and cleaning the sand out of them.
Although we were the ones who had to cook it
Was it always two buckets?
Yeah, about right
I don't care about that trivial stuff.
I'm asking you to answer why you said "sideways"
Because...
Ushigome-san had to hold the two buckets and both of his hands were occupied!
I'm asking...
In that case, he'd either have to put the plastic bottle in the bucket, under his arms...
Or inside the kangaroo pocket of his hoodie like the ones you're wearing...
Placing it sideways, wouldn't he?
Come to think of it, Ushigome-san did keep the plastic bottle sideways inside his pocket like that
I see.
If it were sideways, the green tea inside would shake whenever he walks.
This trick guarantees that by the time he reached the parking lot, the poison on the inside of the cap...
Would have been completely mixed into the green tea.
Yeah, that's exactly right.
But, still...
What if he didn't conveniently happen to put on a hoodie with a pocket like that?
I think he didn't just "happen to" wear it.
What these people are wearing is the matching hoodies they made for their Clam Clan.
And since it was made not long ago, if someone suggested that they wear it for today's clam digging...
Wouldn't Ushigome-san also comply and wear it?
Plus, since Ushigome-san had always carried two buckets and returned to the car before you guys...
Someone could have easily predicted that he would put the plastic bottle in his hoodie pocket sideways.
I have to agree it's possible to mix poison that way, but...
The problem is, who was able to swap the poisonous cap and how?
Normally, when you unscrew a cap, you would likely put it near you, right?
That's right
I believe Ushigome-san had also placed it somewhere on the sheet he was sitting on.
If that's the case, since all that Yashima lady did...
Was hand him the plastic bottle...
It's impossible for her to have swapped it
And still, that Mitsuse mister...
Did nothing other than tossing him the pack of rice balls.
And if he were to stretch his arm and attempt to switch the cap sitting on the sheet, he would've been seen.
In that case, that leaves us with the person who placed the bag of chips next to Ushigome-san.
Hisazu-san...
Apparently you had the best chance to swap out the cap sitting on the sheet
What the...
Hold on, what are you saying?
How could she if all she did was to put down a bag of chips?
That bag of chips is the perfect camouflage for the deed.
Hisazu-san placed the bag of chips immediately next to Ushigome-san.
You simply had to hold the poisoned cap between your fingers beforehand...
And swapped the caps with the bag obstructing the view.
Having done so, Ushigome-san would mistake the cap as the one he put
So how come there's blood on the mouth of the plastic bottle and none on the cap?
The answer is because the vic touched the swapped poisonous cap after his finger wound began to heal.
Of course, even if his wound was closing, he still used the same finger to unscrew and screw the cap.
That's why we detected a minute amount of blood even on the poisonous cap.
Isn't that how it played out?
Isn't that right, Professor?
Yeah...
Which means the original cap with Ushigome-san's blood should be around somewhere.
Didn't you guys have some bags of trash?
We gave them to the brat with glasses.
Hey, hey...
Don't tell me you've examined the caps?
But even though there were six plastic bottles...
I only found five caps.
Only the cap of the empty green tea bottle was missing.
So is this what transpired?
First she had Ushigome-san drink up a whole bottle of green tea that she bought in advance...
And filched the cap.
Then she laced poison on it somewhere else, and replaced the newly bought green tea bottle cap with it
Now, all she had to do is to suggest going home at the right time.
Ushigome-san would return to the car and likely drink up the remaining poisoned tea.
Later on, if the police discovered the jar with toxicant she had left in the car beforehand...
It would make it ostensibly a suicide.
Perhaps that jar was also...
Swiped from Ushigome-san without his permission in order to use it as a staged suicide prop.
But, your calculations were thrown off when you were swapping the caps.
The cap had already been smeared in Ushigome-san's blood.
That's why you didn't throw it in the trash bag, right?
If we had collected that, we would have figured out it was swapped out
Although you may have already tossed away that bloody cap somewhere...
We could always try searching the beach where you were.
I already thought of that and found it
Here.
The green tea bottle cap with blood.
But, how could that be proof?
If you're talking about fingerprints, she had already touched it during the convenience store purchase!
-Nah, I'm not talking about fingerprints.
By coming into contact with the cap...
Hisazu-san's fingers would likely test positive for this.
The evidence that you touched Ushigome-san's blood...
A luminol reaction.
Come on, Shouko, are you all right with him accusing you all he wants?
Why don't you retort him!?
Tell him he can search all he wants and get nothing!
I can't retort him.
Because what that officer just said...
Every bit of it was the truth.
Hey, don't tell me it's because of that accident...
Accident?
Hey, what is it?
What accident?
Well, do you recall?
The hit-and-run incident here last week.
Maybe it has something to do with that?
Since they showed a gloomy look, when that topic was brought up.
Hit-and-run?
The one that involved hitting a drunkard?
So that was you guys?
But we didn't know!
Not until we saw the newspaper the next day!
Besides...
Hey!
Besides?
What?
Besides...
Since Ushigome-kun said we might have hit something...
We all got out of the car and checked around immediately, but didn't see anyone.
There was.
There was someone at that time.
In the patch of grass where I checked...
A man was lying on the ground, drenched in blood...
Then, why didn't you say anything!?
I couldn't!
That man wasn't breathing...
And Ushigome-kun had been drinking.
If we were found out, we'd lose our new jobs that are so hard to come by!
That's right...
If only Ushigome-kun would've kept his mouth shut...
If he didn't start talking about turning himself in...
You're just like a clam.
No matter how well you think you've hidden...
You'll always leave behind a trace somewhere.
That troublesome something will become more apparent the more you try to hide.
Even if Ushigome-san didn't own up, we police would've still tracked you down.
By sniffing out that rotten hole in your heart
We've finally cleaned these all up.
We can't just leave them here after all.
But to think that you ascertained the culprit's identity just by seeing the bag of chips placed next to victim...
That's not the only thing.
When I mentioned the mouth of the plastic bottle had blood on it...
She blurted out that Ushigome-kun injured his finger.
What about it?
I just happened to know that he had cut his finger, but...
Normally if there's blood on the mouth of a plastic bottle...
Shouldn't people assume that it was either because his lips cracked, or there's a wound in his mouth?
Especially since there was no blood on the cap found next to Ushigome-san.
That's how I figured out
The reason why Hisazu-san said that was because she saw the cap with blood when she did the switch.
Isn't it just like you said, Professor?
Just like that
That's right.
I'll need you to come to the station later as well.
Bring the brats too...
Some of the brats are gone?
Huh?
You're right...
If you're looking for them...
They went back to the beach in a big rush just now.
Saying they lost some very important thing.
Geez!
And it was a Yaiba figure we had never seen before!
Geez, and you really don't remember where you dropped it?
If I did, I would've found it by now!
It was super rare!
It's the kind we'll never get if we don't buy a truckload.
You guys love it, don't you?
Digging in the sand...