From a different perspective...
An imposing wall is just a large door.
A text message that resembles a code.
Just as Uncle Kogorou is stumped,
it's a kitty to the rescue!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
First, meet with the client at 9:00 AM...
Then from 10:00 AM to 1:00 PM, eat lunch at Poirot and enjoy a relaxing coffee time...
And from 2:00 PM, watch Okino Yoko-chan's soap opera that I've been waiting for so long while videotaping it...
At which point I thoroughly theorize on future developments...
No, wait.
I should skim through the previous five episodes before the client comes...
Not bad a plan since I can review the storyline.
Wow, I'm so busy!
Living my life to the fullest!
Wait, hey!
What're you guys doing?
Isn't it already time to go to school?
Sort of...
What is it?
What are you hiding from me?
Well, it's not anything weird...
What the, it's just a cat...
What!?
A cat
A cat!
THE SECRET OF THE RUSSIAN BLUE
Hey, hey.
Did you pick it up off the streets?
No...
It's Aunt Eri's cat!
I thought her cat was brown-colored with black spots.
Not this weird grayish color like a rat!
This cat is called a Russian Blue, which has blue-gray fur and green eyes as unique characteristics.
She said that her old cat died last month, and she got this one from a friend.
It died of old age.
However, why is this freaking cat in my agency?
Because Mom just dropped by earlier and...
Sorry, Ran.
Gan you watch this cat for three days?
What happened?
I have to take the afternoon flight to Okinawa where my client awaits...
But Kuriyama-san who was supposed to take care of this kid is bedridden with the flu.
Even so...
I don't have anyone else to turn to except you, Ran!
'Kay?
Hold it, Mom!
Take care of Goro-chan then, Ran!
That's what she said.
Watch the cat?
But when you guys go to school, I'm the one who's gotta take care of it!
Good morning, Ran!
Sonoko!
We're gonna be late, Ran.
Am I interrupting something?
Sorry, I'm coming.
I'm on my way!
Hey!
Then please take care of Goro-chan, Dad!
I see.
But Ran, wasn't her previous cat also named "Goro"?
My mom seems to really like that name, so she used it again.
Note: roll around = gorogoro
She used to say it's because cats always roll around, but...
Maybe the truth is...
Geez!
Why must a great detective like me take care of some freaking cat?
It's already housebroken, so it's quite easy since all you have to do is make sure it doesn't run outside.
Then you go ahead and take care of it
It's fine if you skip class.
You have my permission!
Permission, you...
I'm pretty busy for the rest of the day!
Um, excuse me...
I'm Kirishita, the one who called yesterday.
Huh?
I thought over the phone we agreed to meet at 9:00 AM, and that it was your wife who was coming...
Actually, my wife is not feeling well.
So before I go to work, I've brought it here in her stead.
My daughter's code.
Indeed...
It's a code.
Yes.
This is a message my daughter accidentally sent to my cell phone.
I have no idea what it says, and my daughter has asked me numerous times to delete it
So I thought it might be an alarming message, and decided to seek your advice.
What is it?
Oh, no...
I was reminded of the novel,
The Deductions of Holmes the Calico Cat...
You know, the series penned by Akagawa Jirou-san.
That's right.
In the first story of Holmes the Calico Cat, Holmes was also sitting on someone's shoulder.
And they say that Russian Blues can be trained to perch upon people's shoulders.
I see...
Hey!
A brat like you should hurry up and get to school already!
Okay.
Just a while ago, you told me not to go!
Well, it does seem true that this message gives out a dangerous vibe.
Mouri-san, you think so too?
Yeah.
What can be vaguely read is in the second row...
"Boyfriend"...
And the last part in the third row, "plz come with me".
That tells us something.
That's right.
My daughter is a second year in high school, but...
It seems she recently got a part-time job without telling us.
So I'm afraid that maybe some bad guy sweet-talked her into handing over her money...
In fact, my wife fell ill precisely because she's worried.
I see.
Second year in high school, huh?
A dangerous age indeed.
It so happens that my daughter is also in her second year.
And she's been getting butterflies whenever she thinks of some flashy detective brat
Hey, didn't I tell you to hurry up and go?
I forgot something!
Geez...
Maybe this is some sort of code-speak that's popular with teenage girls.
Actually, I've also thought of that...
And asked my co-worker's daughter about it.
And, what'd she say?
About that...
As soon as she read the message, she let out a smile...
Why not let your daughter do as she likes?
She said that.
With an impish smile.
I knew this was a dubious message...
For the time being, please forward this message to my cell phone.
Sure.
I'll contact you soon as I break the code.
Then, I'm counting on you.
Bye then, Goro.
Take care of Uncle, will you?
Can't make heads or tails of it no matter how many times I look.
I should go wash my face and freshen up.
Did this cat go in the washroom?
Geez, what a hot potato that landed in my lap...
Well, if only it were as clever as the calico cat in that novel...
It'd be a different story.
What the hell is this!?
Don't tell me that cat was sleeping on this towel!?
Hey, you!
The hell are you doing!?
These are videotapes of Yoko-chan's soap opera!
If you dare leave as much as a tiny scratch, you'll be sorry!
The tape for the second episode is missing!
Don't tell me you freaking hid it somewhere...
Hey, hey, playing with a shoe this time?
Isn't this Conan's shoe?
Where the hell did you get it from?
Listen up!
You need two shoes to form a pair!
It won't be of any use if you separate them!
Keep that in your tiny brain!
Man...
Sneaking up on me and stealing things from me...
Instead of Holmes, it's looking more like Lupin!
I see, I see...
This character that looks like an o with a protruding horn is the small Greek letter sigma...
And the crooked v is the small Greek alphabet nu.
The symbol that resembles a hiragana te is the small Greek letter tau.
Note: tsukiatte
Then, what appears to be "plz come with me" at the end of the message should read...
Tsukiattau
"Please come witauh me".
I don't even...
Speaking of the Greek alphabet, it's used in star names.
Maybe it has something to do with astronomy.
Let's see, I recall an astronomy book was right over here...
Damn you, playing pranks again!
English-Japanese dictionary?
By "English-Japanese", it means it translates from English to Japanese.
In this message, the only letter of the English alphabet used is W.
If I force myself into thinking of this W as a Japanese character...
It's the hiragana n!
I see!
So she's playing around with foreign symbols that resemble certain hiragana and katakana?
That's why instead of "tsukiatte" she used "tsukiatau".
With this, I guess I'm starting to get the hang of it!
Great work, Goro!
Wait...
Don't tell me this cat...
Was trying to tell me all this?
Could it be like in the novel?
Hey!
This is not a toy!
Cats always will be cats after all, huh...
At any rate, she had purposely substituted foreign characters for hiragana and katakana...
And it's obvious that our young lady wrote this message in a playful way.
If I think of it along these lines.
W will be the hiragana n...
Nu will be the katakana re...
Tau will be the hiragana te...
In that case, the equal sign will be the katakana ni...
And the postal mark must mean the katakana te.
However...
"Niteteku"?
What the hell does that mean?
Unless I decipher the meaning of the sigma letters which are after W...
And before the hiragana tsu, it seems I can't read it
But that character does not resemble any hiragana nor katakana.
Anyway, I'll use a circle to mark the unknown symbols and go from there.
Yo n gen en re ka re ni te te ku tsu ki a t te...
So is this some kind of code after all?
Hey!
Geez...
Hey, not there again!
I said you can't go there!
It's already past noon!
Less than two hours until Yoko-chan's drama!
But if I don't solve the meaning of this mysterious message before then...
I can't relax and watch Yoko-chan's drama, now can I?
Hold on...
That reminds me, this little thing also snooped around these tapes earlier, didn't it?
Could it really be trying to tell me something?
The only discrepancy that comes to mind is the missing videotape of episode two.
Missing...
Wait, wait
Before that, this runt slept on my towel in the washroom...
And the fur it shed got on my face.
"Dropped" and "missing"!
Is it possible that the symbols are not only just look-alikes of hiragana and katakana...
But are also meant to represent corrupted forms of characters on purpose...
Giving the sense of "Don't you think it's like, cute to use corrupted writings?"
In that case, the sigma must mean a certain hiragana or katakana but with missing or dropped parts.
If so, the only character I can think of is...
The hiragana...
Then this plus-minus sign is...
Chi!
Which means the plus-minus, W and sigma are...
Chi n no?
What the hell?
Nah, the right side of the plus-minus sign...
If I add a stroke there it'll be the hiragana chi, but...
If it's on the left...
It'll become sa instead!
If this is sa...
Then plus-minus, W, and sigma will be...
Sa n no.
Could it be that someone's name should go before "-san's"?
Now my problem is the arrow before the plus-minus.
But I've seen this arrow before, in a certain rich young miss's New Year card.
What does that arrow mean?
This is...
(Happy New Year)
"Akemashite omedeto"!
I see!
The arrow is the elongation mark.
The bar that extends a sound!
In that case, the name that goes before the plus-minus...
Should be Satou or Tarou, a name with an -ou ending that sounds like a "long o"!
All right, I'll solve it in a jiffy!
Damn...
Yo sa n no gen en re ka re...
Ni te te ku no tsu ki a t te...
Looks readable but it's actually not.
The names that start with Yo and ends in a long o...
Would be Yonjou or Youichirou, but...
No matter how I look, they don't fit in at all.
Hey!
Don't play-bite my shoe!
That reminds me, this cat...
Was play-biting Conan's shoe earlier.
And it was only one shoe.
I seemed to have said something...
Listen up!
You need two shoes to form a pair!
It won't be of any use if you separate them!
Need two to form a pair?
So she used two characters to represent a single character!
In that case...
The koto meaning "words" and the en meaning "extend" in the first row...
Combine to form tan or "birth"...
And the two postal marks in the third row form gyou or "to go".
Hold on, hold on...
In that case, the first hiragana I thought was yo...
If I added the missing stroke back...
And paired it with the following iteration mark that looks like the symbol >...
I would actually get the hiragana o!
And for the following character, if I pair the L with the mathematic subset symbol resembling a flattened C...
I shall get the hiragana to!
And pairing the symbol resembling a flattened katakana fu with the tiny circle makes the katakana pu!
If I read the second row using this method...
I get pu re ka i ni.
It means "buy birthday present"!
All right, if I keep reading...
"I'nn 9onna 9σ buy D@d's |3day prsnt so plz come wiτh me."
That's some surprisingly easy to understand "gal-speak"
Gal-speak?
Hold on, Dad...
Don't you dare tell me you're flirting with some young girl!
Oh, no...
My client entrusted me with this message.
Hey wait...
Why the hell are you girls here!?
What happened to school!?
We did go, so what?
What are you talking about, Uncle?
It's already evening.
Then hurry up and prepare dinner at once!
Fine.
Let's go, Ran.
I'm back!
Welcome back.
Hey there, glasses brat.
Sheesh...
Stealing my spotlight!
Despite the fact it was the two of us who solved it, right?
I shall give my client a call right now!
Note: katsuobushi = dried bonito flakes
My katsuobushi plan was a huge success!
I secretly scattered katsuobushi at places where hints could be found...
So that the cat would poke around, giving Uncle some hints to solving it.
Looks like my plan worked quite well.
Is this Kirishita-san?
This is Detective Mouri Kogorou who met with you this morning.
So, have you already...
Figured out the meaning of my daughter's message?
Yeah, indeed I have...
Hey!
That's dangerous, you might fall off!
Dangerous?
So it was a dangerous message after all!?
No...
Your daughter is not dangerous at all, but rather well brought-up...
Well brought-up?
Hey, idiot, stop pulling!
You're the one who's pulling at random topics, Mouri-san!
No...
Please hurry and tell me!
What kind of message was it!?
I promise not to be shocked by the contents.
I'm ready for the worst scenario!
And if I give my daughter the third degree about it...
I bet my daughter will cough up what she's been secretly doing!
Now, please tell me!
Mouri-san, Mouri-san!
Well, in fact I don't understand it at all.
What do you mean?
What's more, I just happened to land myself a huge case earlier...
And it looks like I'll be tied up with it for a while.
So I actually called you to decline your case.
How come!
However, since she's a fabulous daughter, I think it's best if you support her and let her be without worrying.
How can you be so sure of that?
It's not like you've met my daughter...
It's the Great Detective's...
Intuition, so to speak.
Then, say hello to your daughter!
It's best that we keep his birthday present a surprise!
That cat...
Perhaps it didn't require my help at all to begin with.
Are you hungry?
Then I shall tell Ran to get your dinner prepared.
Dinner...
Evening...
Yoko-chan's drama!
Not only did I miss it but I forgot to record it!
It's all because of you fooling around that made me forget!
And you even freaking hid my videotape!
Hold it.
What do you think you're doing to my Goro-chan?
You.
Eri!
Aren't you supposed to be in Okinawa?
I was worried about my baby, so I flew back early and plan to finish the rest of my work via phone and fax.
Now, Goro-chan.
Let's say bye-bye to this scary man's place!
Same Goro, but big difference...
Wasn't the other black-spotted brown Goro you had also attached to you?
Very different from a certain dimwit too.
Don't tell me "Goro" is...
The "Goro" from "Kogorou"?