While seeking an exit,
An impossible barrier can become a door.
The legend of a villa,
How can a window be the root of all evil?
Recognizing that single truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is Detective Conan!
Sonoko...
Jan, ken, pon!
Janken is the Japanese version of Rock, Paper, Scissors.
It's a tie!
"Aiko desho" means "it's a tie", so players present a new sing on desho.
I lost again?
Sorry.
Yep, good luck carrying the bags for the next ten minutes.
Could it be you guys know I'm not good
at Janken, but make me play anyway?
Alright then, I'll treat you to a meal
when we reach the Suzuki Villa.
V-Villa!?
Didn't you say we were going to your sister's
friend's mansion to escape this summer heat?
Huh?
Did I say that?
Then, that means...
See episodes 34-35, released by Anime-Conan.
We're going to the same villa as the Bandaged
Man and moving corpse murder case, aren't we!?
I think it may be...
No way!
I'm going home!
You can't.
You would get lost.
But...
So that's why she made us abandon the car midway...
Forcing us to walk the rest of the way to the villa.
This way, Ran wouldn't be able
to leave after getting scared.
That fool...
Um, did someone already solve that murder?
Of course! By the Queen of Deduction, me!
That's right, ever since that case...
You've been solving cases like my
dad, as if you were sleeping.
And, when that bandaged man attacked me,
The one who saved me was none other than Conan-kun.
This kid was there, too?
Well,
Save that discussion for when we get there.
No way!
The bridge!
Perhaps this is a part of a grand scheme...
No, that's not likely, as it's broken from the base.
It's just a poorly built bridge.
I see...
But, this is a problem.
How can we get to the villa?
The car that brought us is gone,
And my sister and her friends
won't be back until late tonight.
Then, let's call their cell phones.
We can have them pick us up.
We can't do that.
There's no service here.
No way...
Well, then...
Let's use a phone in that villa there.
There may be someone inside.
THE SEALED WESTERN-STYLE WINDOW
(PART ONE)
The Sealed Western-Style Window, Part One!
Looks like no one's home.
What are you guys doing?
Ah, the bridge to that other villa?
It had already fallen when we left earlier.
Yes.
Could we use your phone to call for help?
Makino June (29)
Musican
Of course,
And feel free to wait here until your ride comes
Thank you very much.
But really, this is a beautiful villa.
Our agent said an unknown rich guy built it.
Tendou Tooru (30)
Musican
We just bought it at a bargained price.
We're just ordinary people, after all.
Bargained price?
Yeah, after we formed this band of musicians,
We began searching for a place to
write, compose, and practice.
That was when we found this rarity.
But if it's so rare, shouldn't it have been expensive?
No, it was really cheap.
Kuramoto Youji (28)
Musician
This villa has a strange history it seems.
They would have demolished it if we hadn't of bought it.
Strange history?
Yeah.
They say that two rich brothers built this originally.
Every summer, they would bring their wives here,
To escape the summer heat.
But on a rainy night...
The older brother told them something strange...
He said a demon came through
the window and attacked him.
A-A demon?
After that, the brother decided to seal
the window with nails and keep it out.
It's no use...
I can still sense it!
They told us that this villa was later remodeled.
Everything down to the beds and wallpaper were changed.
But two years after the remodeling,
There was another incident.
Incident?
It involved the older brother's wife.
While she was gardening...
She saw something.
From the window that was supposed to
be sealed, something was staring at her.
T-That...
Was the demon?
Maybe.
And some days later...
Acting as if she were possessed,
She hung herself with a rope in her room.
Three months later, acting as if he were possessed,
The older brother leapt from the third floor to his death.
After that,
Only the younger brother and his wife were at this villa.
This is why it was so cheap.
Well?
Isn't this place great for writing songs?
Yeah...
Hey, hey...
What kind of music?
But is that window really unable to be opened?
Well, if you don't believe us, let's go check.
Alright?
It's true...
The window has been nailed shut.
It won't move at all.
See?
They advised us to have this window
repaired when we bought this place,
But we considered it a waste of time and money.
You should definitely fix it...
You guys want to stay here tonight?
You may see the demon.
We'll pass!
We're about to leave.
I'm glad you all came back as we were leaving.
Oh?
We were just out buying groceries.
There should've been someone home, Rinko.
Rinko-san?
Rinko Honami (28)
Musician
Hey.
Can't you all be quiet around here?
How can I write songs like this!?
That's Rinko.
She writes for us.
She's been acting strange ever since we moved in.
But we all depend on Rinko to write
songs for our band, Dorcus.
So we let her be.
Ah, you said Dorcus?
I know them!
People adore your CD production.
I even have one of your CDs!
Oh?
Thanks.
Where'd they go?
Ah, I found you all.
I just finished talking with my sister.
She said she'll be here to get us in two hours.
Thank goodness!
But wait...
While we're waiting, let's visit the garden.
From there, we'd be able to see where the
demon was staring at that woman from.
Let's see, the weird one is the fourth
one from the right on the 2nd floor...
Ah, there it is.
You can't tell it's weird from the outside.
You can't even tell that it's sealed from out here.
Was there really a demon looking out from there?
Yeah.
Look, there's birdhouse up there.
It's true.
Ah, Conan-kun, be careful.
But there's nothing inside,
Not even a bird's nest.
But there is a white plate in here.
It's weird to put a plate in a birdhouse, isn't it?
Oh?
Let me look.
Ah, Eisuke-kun, you shouldn't...
He really is unlucky.
Are you alright?
I'm fine...
Well,
Let's have them take us to see the other rooms.
What is it now?
What's that!?
Huh?
What was that?
I saw something...
Looking at us from the sealed window!
Jeez, did you hit your head when you fell?
No, I really did!
Conan-kun!
What's wrong, boy?
It's sealed shut...
And the nails haven't been removed.
Rinko!
Hey, Rinko.
Hurry and open up!
Rinko!
What's going on?
Before we went out,
Rinko asked me to get this CD for her.
I haven't been able to get her to answer.
Oh, maybe she's asleep?
It's not unusual for her.
Hey!
Rinko!
Hey...
Rinko, why aren't you answering?
Rinko?
Rinko!
I've got that CD you wanted.
Open up, hey!
Could it be, earlier she was mad...
Rinko, what's with you?
How can I write songs like this!?
Well, I guess...
She may have left...
I dunno, I can't see.
Boy, mind taking a look?
Sure.
Lady, do you have a hand mirror?
Yeah.
T-This is...
W-What is it, Tooru?
What's wrong?
I can see her feet...
Suspended.
Hey, does that mean...
On three...
Rinko!
It can't be, Rinko!
What the—
Hurry and get her down first,
And then we'll call for an ambulance and the police!
The lock is still engaged.
Then it's likely...
That the key is still on her key-holder.
Those...
Those are keys for a car and a bicycle.
The black one is likely for an electronic lock.
Must be for this villa.
Then, this room's...
Where?
There.
Aside from that, the door was locked...
And so were all of the windows.
This room is completely sealed.
Did she commit suicide?
It's no good.
She stopped breathing.
That means the one staring at us...
From this sealed window...
It must be the demon!
What?
You mean you saw it?
Yes...
We didn't, Eisuke-kun did...
Right...
It was from the garden...
Hey, you!
You must've been imagining!
It's true!
It was a little dark...
But something was watching us, I'm sure!
Are you glasses broken!?
No!
But...
What if he's right?
What if there is something else in here with us?
Because this room...
The villa owner's wife committed suicide here.
W-Well, let's put Reiko on the sofa for now...
We shouldn't leave her on the floor.
Hey, you're on her key-holder...
I'm sorry, Rinko.
I see.
I'm on the case.
You all came into this room to give Rinko-san
the CD that she asked you to buy for her.
Everyone called out for her,
But when she didn't reply, you looked
under the door and saw her feet.
You then saw the door was locked
and forced your way inside...
Where you found Rinko-san, hanging from this rope?
Y-Yes...
And the key to the room...
Is it on Rinko-san's key-holder?
The key to this room is on that keyboard.
This is the right key.
There's no copy of this key, right?
Yeah, that's the only copy.
But couldn't someone have made a copy?
That's not possible.
After we bought this villa,
Only Rinko had the key to this room.
Actually, she had all of the keys,
And handed them out.
Then, after you two forced the door open,
Did anyone get near this window?
Why does that matter?
The only one moving around after the door was opened...
Was that little boy.
All of the windows were locked then.
You didn't mess with the windows, right?
Since the key was found inside of the room
and all of the windows were locked...
There's only one conclusion, and that's suicide.
Um, excuse me...
What I'm, actually trying to say is...
It wasn't a suicide.
I'm saying that this is a locked room murder!
And the killer is one of these three!
Isn't that right, Mouri-san?
Huh?
Where's Mouri-san?
He isn't with us.
Huh?
W-What the...
Ran-san, Conan-kun, and that
guy with the glasses are here?
Why?
Why ask me?
Hey...
Why are you saying this is a locked room murder, Officer?
Well, we police can see things about
this chair that ordinary people cannot.
When someone hangs themselves on a rope,
They usually kick the chair away.
But not this time.
The chair's under the rope.
So, this tells me Rinko-san...
Was murdered and then put up there.
Um, that chair was put there by us...
When we came into the room.
W-Why?
We did it to get Rinko-san down.
We thought she was still alive.
It's because when we came into the room...
The chair was already on the floor.
Oh? I see.
It's a suicide as I thought.
Isn't he decisive...
Ah-le-le! What's this?
I can stretch it!
Conan-kun, what are you doing?
Stop that!
Doesn't this look like measuring tape?
Hey, stop that!
Oh, hey...
That key-holder can be stretched pretty far, huh?
Well, Rinko used that as a ruler in the past.
She once said it could measure up to four meters.
Oh? That's simple.
Simple? It's not just that...
Hey, if the key to this room was on that key-holder,
Couldn't you open it even from far away?
You're not so smart, Conan-kun.
Your arms aren't even long enough
to reach the door, are they?
That's not the point.
Hold on a second.
If the key was on the key-holder...
That's right.
You could make this a locked room case.
Look, Rinko-san and the rope are in line with the door.
If it were stretched,
The room key on Rinko-san's key-holder...
Could go under the door,
And into the keyhole.
And after it's locked...
You can release the key, automatically
returning it to Rinko-san's key-holder.
But why was the key found in a location
separate from that of the key-holder?
Maybe, right before Rinko-san was to commit suicide,
she thought her friends may be accused of killing her.
Or maybe...
Someone killed her, made it look like suicide,
And then destroyed the evidence
pointing to it being a murder?
I see.
Hold on!
Are you saying one of us is the criminal?
What're you saying? You must be joking.