While seeking an exit,
An impossible barrier can become a door.
Today, we'll resolve the mystery.
It's up to Officer Yamamura and his big surprise.
Recognizing that single truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is Detective Conan!
Before we made it to Sonoko's villa,
There had been an accident.
We went to a nearby villa for help.
There, we met the members of the band Dorcus.
They told us about a ghastly legend.
And...
One of their members...
Honami Rinko-san, was dead.
But I began to doubt it was a suicide.
There's only one conclusion, and that's suicide.
What I'm actually trying to say is...
It wasn't a suicide.
I'm saying that this is a locked room murder!
And the killer is one of these three!
THE SEALED WESTERN-STYLE WINDOW
(PART TWO)
The Sealed Western-Style Window, Part Two!
Wait, are you saying that the killer...
That the killer is one of us?
Are you joking?
Then, do explain...
How this became a locked room case.
I'm only giving my opinion.
Alright, do you mind if I ask some questions?
When did you three see Rinko-san for the last time?
Before her body was discovered,
Ran-neechan, can you let me down?
Where were you and what were you doing?
The last time I saw her...
Was when she came in shouting at us about all the noise.
Afterwards, I went upstairs to my
room to practice with my guitar.
I was there until Tooru was outside of Rinko's room.
Kuramoto Youji (28)
Musician
When Rinko stormed off to her room,
I was with you guys, right?
Yeah.
Tendou Tooru (30)
Musician
Afterwards, I went upstairs to listen to a CD.
And that was when I remembered about Rinko's CD.
So I took it down to her room.
Makino June (29)
Musician
I was arranging books in the room
where Rinko shouted at us earlier.
The last owner asked us to tidy up the room,
So I decided to pick out some books to sell.
Even though they are well organized,
It's still hard to decide.
But...
Why did the original owner leave this stuff here?
They were most likely trying to leave
their life at this villa behind them.
The owner's brother and his brother's
wife did commit suicide here.
They say there's a demon here near a certain window.
D-Demon?
Do you want to see it?
It's in a room up here.
It's true...
A demon can come through this?
That's why it was nailed shut...
By the older brother of the two
that were residing in this villa.
But why would anyone sleep in this room?
Is this your room?
No, my room belonged to the younger
brother's wife downstairs.
This is the maid's room,
Which is why it doesn't look as furnished.
But, isn't it strange?
The maid's room is up here while the wife's is downstairs.
The wife had trouble with her feet,
so she stayed on the lower floor.
Well, it's ironic that the older brother jumped from upstairs.
I'm just fine in his room.
This has to be the older brother's.
It certainly looks nice.
With four windows in just this room...
Does that mean Rinko-san...
This is very well furnished, huh?
It's because rich people lived here.
Well,
Rumor has it the younger brother forced the
older brother and his wife to kill themselves.
When we bought this villa, we were told...
The older brother's wife committed suicide because
she had an affair with the younger brother.
They said the older brother found out
and committed suicide himself.
An affair?
Yeah.
We were told the younger brother was having
an affair with his brother's wife.
And would meet up at night.
Anyway, let me consult with a senior officer about the case.
You all wait here for now.
It's as I thought.
With this tree here, you can only
see it from the second floor...
And in this bird house...
As I thought,
There's no doubt.
The one who killed Rinko-san and
made it look like a suicide...
Is that person.
All by utilizing the story...
Of this villa's demon.
Let's see, from what a senior officer has told me...
Two years ago, a similar case occurred at this villa.
Those who died at this villa were
an older brother and his wife.
First, the older brother's wife hung
herself on the second floor.
Three days later, from his room's window,
The older brother committed suicide from the third floor.
Afterwards, the older brother's wife hung
herself with a rope as Rinko-san did.
Exactly in the same manner.
This incident occurred after the older brother...
First mentioned the villa's demon.
He then proceeded to nail the
window in the maid's room shut,
Forcing the locals to claim it as a haunted villa.
Due to this, we've gotta go to the police station.
Huh? We're leaving?
Shouldn't you investigate more?
Back then,
I saw something looking at me from that sealed window.
You saw something?
Yes, something at the window that was supposedly sealed.
I'll be leaving then.
Why?
Because we're facing a demon here, a demon!
We police can't apprehend a demon!
Hey...
Besides, the room where Rinko-san
hung herself was completely sealed,
With the key found in the room!
That means Rinko-san only committed
suicide because she was possessed!
Oh, then the mess in the room
was also done by the demon?
M-Mess?
Because the encyclopedias are arranged 6, 3, 4, 1.
But all of the others are arranged correctly.
Are you talking about what happened?
Ignore him.
Ignore the brat.
Anyway, can we get back to work?
We did just lose a member...
We want to do something about it.
Go ahead, but I think it'd be best
for you guys to leave this place.
When Rinko-san committed suicide,
Makino June-san was in the maid's room.
That's the room with the sealed window.
At that time, Kuramoto Youji was
in his room on the third floor.
It's the same room where the older brother
committed suicide from two years ago.
And also at that time, Tendou Tooru was in his
room, which doesn't have a scary history, but...
His room is beside Youji's...
And above Rinko-san's!
If Rinko-san's soul is still here...
Does that mean you three have been possessed!?
Ah, we actually plan to stay here
tonight and leave tomorrow.
We need time to pack up Rinko's things.
We've brought a lot of things to this villa already.
That must be my sister!
You want to come home with us?
I guess so.
Hey, Officer.
I think it's actually...
What?
What is it?
Ah, no, it's nothing.
Ah, that's right, I'll need your home addresses.
Could you three wait in your rooms?
I think we'll close this case then.
Ah, alright.
Sure.
That's no problem.
They're finally gone.
Well, let's go pack our things.
Yeah.
Right.
Well then, I'll pack my things and then get Rinko's.
You alright to get both?
I can help you pack her stuff.
No, no.
Let June do it.
Being a woman's room, there are only
things another woman should see.
That's right.
Well, let's pack so we can leave tomorrow.
Yeah.
Your plot has been revealed,
Kuramoto Youji-san.
No, actually...
The one who is responsible for murdering Rinko-san!
Youji, I can't believe it.
Rinko...
Hey, what do you mean? I couldn't do that.
Besides, what are you doing in my
room? Didn't I just lock the door?
It was me who opened the door from in here.
What?
That officer asked me to pretend I left the villa,
And then had me hide here in your room...
Just like how the older brother found his way into Rinko's
room through the secret passage, so he could hide here.
Secret passage?
Don't try to deny it.
We saw it all in Rinko-san's room.
Youji-san opened the door behind the bookshelf...
And rearranged the books before putting them back, right?
And we saw you come out of that closet...
From the peephole on that door.
I also know how you did it.
You went to Rinko-san's room to talk about something.
Later, you killed Rinko-san.
You used a rope to hang her and locked the doors and
windows to make the room appear completely sealed.
Then, you exited through the passage...
And replaced the books...
Making it seem like she hung herself.
But your plan wasn't perfect.
Because the books weren't in the correct order.
And there's only one way that happened.
You heard Conan-kun mention the order of the books.
You were afraid the police would find the secret passage,
So you decided to fix it while everyone was asleep.
Well, it's alright for you not to have noticed,
Because you can't see the order from outside.
But how did you know...
About the secret passage?
I found it easily, because...
Because...
Because, well...
Let's see...
What was it?
Ah, I see, I see.
When I saw the windows at this villa,
Something suddenly hit me.
Rinko-san's room is on the 2nd floor,
Youji-san's is on the 3rd floor,
And...
Tooru-san's rooms don't match.
I noticed that only the maid's room with the sealed
window has narrow spaces between the windows.
Not to mention the fact that the
window is too close to the wall.
And then Conan-kun mentioned...
The strange order of the books in Rinko-san's room.
I decided then.
The window couldn't be opened
not because it was nailed shut...
But because only half of it was nailed.
The left side of the window is inside of the secret
passage, which is why it can't be opened.
The narrow space exists due to the narrow passage, which
is why Rinko-san's bookcase is the door the passage.
To make the nailed window stand out less,
A bookcase was put between the next two windows.
This way, no one would notice the
amount of space between them.
A part of the window was hidden,
So that the secret passage could be used for observation.
I see.
When I saw someone looking at me from the window,
They were actually only using the right side.
But who built the secret passage?
It was made by the older brother.
From the four rooms, the windows all
give a similar view of the backyard.
That room is smaller due to the secret passage,
Because the entrance to the passage is directly above it.
The brother pretended he saw a demon
so he could build this secret passage,
And modify the villa.
The maid's room became smaller due
to this, and even if someone noticed...
No one would complain about it.
Then, why did he build it?
He did it to look into whether his wife
was having an affair with his brother.
Conan-kun told me there was a plate in that birdhouse.
Inside was a white plate by itself.
If it were in place,
The younger brother was telling the others wife...
To unlock her door that night.
But wouldn't the older brother
know if he saw the birdhouse?
After realizing his brother and wife would notice
any drastic changes, he came up with another idea.
Also, due to the trees outside, you
can only see it from the 2nd floor.
He couldn't see it from his wife's or the maid's rooms...
Which is why he built the secret passage.
That way, no one would notice him looking for the sign.
Allowing him to see when they would meet.
Well, even if we can't prove it now...
Let's say the older brother killed his
wife, made it look like a suicide,
And then committed suicide himself, not
being able to live with what he'd done.
And that means, Youji-san...
Killed Rinko-san the same way.
I see now.
You two wouldn't let me into Rinko's room, because you
knew I would return later in the night to fix the books.
Meaning you two were with the
police the whole time, right?
Yeah...
The officer told us when he came for our addresses.
He told us not to let you into Rinko's room.
Well? Aren't you going to ask why I killed her?
Yeah, it's about the guitar, isn't it?
But, didn't you two plan to help each other?
Yeah.
I kept trying to work with her.
I kept going to Rinko's room to practice...
But, she...
No, no, that just won't do
Don't you listen to the latest music?
Your guitar skill is obsolete!
You should learn over from the beginning.
And...
Rinko never stopped after that,
And started degrading my favorite artists.
Then...
Then, Rinko, before I knew it..
She couldn't say anything at all.
Then, you mean you didn't mean to kill her?
No, well, somewhat.
I never told anyone about the secret passage.
I don't know how, but somehow, I already
had a rope ready for Rinko.
Well, then, I didn't believe I had killed her.
I hurried and hung her on the chandelier near the door,
Took the room key off of the keyholder,
And left through the secret passage.
To make sure no one saw me, I looked outside.
Which is when that guy with glasses saw me.
Well...
Maybe it's me who was possessed by this villa's demon.
That rope I found in the secret passage...
The older brother may have used
it to murder his wife, huh?
Alright, get him to the station.
Wow, your deductions were amazing, Officer.
Officer Yamamura, you were great.
Well, I'll admit you're worthy of being my rival.
No, actually, that reasoning was done by Mouri...
P.S., P.S...
P.S.?
P.S.:
"If people knew such a petty case was solved
by me, my reputation would be ruined.
"Keep my involvement a secret ."
Mouri Kogoro.
Well, when I solve a case,
I get gratification from using my own wits.
Well, let's go home.
That's right.
But to be able to solve this villa case by just cell phone...
Detective Mouri's amazing, huh?
But, he did only use a cell phone to
send a very detailed message...
Couldn't he just have come as Sleeping Kogoro?
Yeah.
I would have you or Sonoko do the sleeping...
But I can't...
Not around that guy.