From a different perspective...
An imposing wall is just a large door.
Master and disciple.
An unthinkable occurrence in the world of rakugo.
The gleam of saury is the key.
He sees the single truth.
He may look like a child but he thinks like an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
"Countless as the pebbles and fish native to the waters,
enigmatic as the fate of water and clouds, of..."
Well... "of places to eat and sleep..."
"of places to eat and sleep..."
"and places to live."
Beika, block 5, house 39!
Do you have to say where you live?
And the rest?
Have you already forgotten?
He's been at it for a week.
Just memorize it already.
"Blessed marlberry tree..."
"From Paipo, from Paipo..."
Ah, "From Paipo, from Paipo I am!
From the Ponpokorin, from the country of Paipo I come,
from Asperger's Ponpokorin."
"From the frightened Asperger's—
"From the Shuringan King of Paipo I come,
from the Shuringan of Queen Gurindai,
from Ponpokopi and Ponkokona of Gurindai I come,
blessed and long-lived I am and that is my name."
Uncle.
Listen, Mouri-kun, maybe you should let it go.
I don't think you have any memorization skills.
Don't say that, Inspector.
No, I know what you want.
A free drink, isn't it?
Third Amateur Theater Arts Festival
Winner drinks himself to death at Bake's bar
When: 12.08 (Saturday) from 3:00 p.m.
Where: Yonehana-cho Community Center
Guest: Rakugo performer, Manrakutei Ichimatsu
Sponsor: Yonehana-cho Shopping Street
But is it worth the humiliation in front of an audience?
No, I hadn't even thought of that at all.
Mouri-san, are you already on your way to the theater?
I see you're enthusiastic.
It raises expectations.
Uwajima Nagaro (50)
Security equipment shop owner
The rumor that the famous detective Mouri would tell a rakugo has spread like wildfire.
This is the organizer, Uwajima-san.
Inspector, did you hear that?
Do you still want me to quit after that?
All right, all right.
I'll teach you something shorter, so you'll remember it right away.
And on that vacant lot, they built a fence!
Hence?
A fence joke?
That's his level.
THE MEGURO SAURY CASE
Here comes the master Manrakutei Ichimatsu.
Master Ichimatsu.
Thank you for doing this.
Manrakutei Ichimatsu (55)
Rakugo story teller
Nagaro.
Thank you for inviting me.
We're childhood friends.
Who is that boy?
He asked to be an apprentice,
but I told him to come back when he graduated school.
Master, tea's ready.
Ah, Uwajima-san.
Nagaro, come and have some with us.
Join us, gentlemen.
What's a rakugo master doing here?
He's helping to prepare meals.
Helping?
And that woman?
Spring has come to the master's heart.
It's time to say goodbye to the bachelor life.
Meguro Mia (30)
Meguro cafeteria owner
What kind of fish is it?
Knife fish.
That's a lot.
Oh! I get it, master.
Your fable today will be about Meguro's saury?
Isn't that right?
Yes.
Master's "Meguro's saury" is a masterpiece.
Those who hear the rumors immediately get the urge to eat saury, and they come running.
That's why there's so much saury.
And what is "Meguro's saury?"
"Meguro's saury" is a rakugo.
There once was a lord who didn't know how to live outside the palace.
One day it occurred to him to go hunting with his falcon in Meguro.
There, in one of the farmers' houses, he tasted saury for the first time.
He was amazed by the taste and, when he returned,
ordered to make him saury again.
But, concerned for the nobleman's health,
the servants heavily steamed and defatted the saury,
and had even torn the fish apart to remove the bones.
The nobleman found such a great difference that he asked them where they had caught that fish.
The servants replied that it was freshly caught live fish.
And then the king said:
"The saury must be from Meguro."
Master!
Ouch...
Looks like I cut myself with a broken cup.
You're bleeding!
Hey, wait. It's all right.
People are watching.
What are you talking about?!
You're about to go on stage and you have to take care of yourself!
Miya-san, thank you very much for the tea.
Master, we will celebrate at 7 p.m. at Cafe Märchen.
Okay, got it.
7 o'clock at the Märchen.
Right, we're going to the stage before you.
That was the wife of one of Master Ichimatsu's apprentices, wasn't it?
Yes, his name is Manrakutei Kisaburo.
He's a storyteller with a promising future.
So, she was his wife?
She divorced that man,
and since then, Master Ichimatsu has been looking after her.
I get the impression that master helps her financially, too.
He's a good man, isn't he?
I'm worried that she may be cheating on him.
What do you mean?
Do girls just get close to old men like that?
Rumor has it that Master Ichimatsu has some small savings.
I suspect that she has only approached him for the money.
You shouldn't judge a person by their appearance.
Is the rakugo world the only one left with the concept of humanity?
Okay, one more time.
From the Shuringan King of Paipo I come,
From the Shuringan... from the...
Short story, switch to the short story.
Got it.
They put a fence on that vacant lot.
Hence?
Oh, man...
He said "hence" right away.
Fence, fence!
Fresh?
I see.
And they put a fence on that vacant lot.
Fresh!
Master Ichimatsu, you're up.
Yes.
How did it go?
My goodness, I didn't think
I had such overwhelming talent.
The audience couldn't stop laughing!
Those people weren't laughing with you,
they were laughing at you.
I see, I would like to see you another time to learn from you.
Is that saury?
Where did you get that saury?
Sir, I picked the most delicious and freshest fish at Nihonbashi Market.
Unacceptable!
The saury must be from Meguro.
Master,
I'll keep you company tonight.
Next time, victory will be mine.
Hey, hey, you're gonna do this again?
Excuse me. I may have someone coming to see me.
I'll join you later.
I also have some unfinished business to settle.
Can you wait for me for a moment at the entrance?
Office
No Trespassing
Uwajima-san is working very hard.
Oh, looks like his work is over.
Master, I'm going.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Where is Master Ichimatsu?
His guest hasn't arrived yet,
so he said to go without him.
I see.
This is Megure.
What? Someone stabbed Master Ichimatsu?
An anonymous call?
It was a man.
They said Master Ichimatsu was stabbed in the dressing room.
He lost a lot of blood.
The victim was found lying unconscious.
Is he going to make it?
We don't know yet.
What's this?
Me-gu-ro...
Maybe it's about "Meguro's saury"?
He wanted to write "Maguro's saury",
...but only had the strength for one word.
By the way, about Meguro.
Look at this.
On the handle of this knife,
...even if it's almost illegible...
it says "Meguro".
Meguro?
"Meguro's saury."
"A saury dinner."
Inspector, I got it.
The perpetrator...
The girl from Meguro Cafeteria?
Excuse me, please.
It's me...
I stabbed Master Ichimatsu.
So, this kitchen knife is yours?
Yes.
Why did you do it?
I'll explain in her place.
It was about money.
You owe money to Master Ichimatsu.
If the master is gone,
...there's no need to repay him.
That's all.
Please forgive me.
Chiba.
Yes, sir.
Let's go to the station.
Wait a moment!
She didn't do anything!
Who are you?!
You're...
Manrakutei Kisaburo.
A disciple of Master Ichimatsu...
Manrakutei Kisaburo (30)
Rakugo story teller
I'm the one who stabbed him!
I, Manrakutei Kisaburo, who was expelled as a disciple a year ago.
I stole from Miya, or rather,
from the owner of the restaurant, this very knife...
and stabbed him with it.
Why did you do that?
We're talking about someone who used to be your mentor.
Inspector!
This man is lying to cover for me.
I'm the one who stabbed him!
After gaining some popularity, I turned my nose up and skipped a few classes.
Gambled away my debts.
And even cheated on my wife.
But that doesn't mean I can be kicked out of the class.
So that's the motive.
That's a lie!
He loves rakugo more than anything.
He must want with all his heart to get back on the stage.
Why would such a man...
The words the master left behind prove everything.
"Meguro's saury"
That's my crowning glory.
There you have it.
Mouri-san, it's not true!
He didn't do anything!
It's me, it's me!
Shut up. What does this have to do with you?
These two think they're criminals, so they're covering for each other.
It's got nothing to do with you, get out!
What the hell do you know?
But what's the meaning of this message?
What did you say?
Stop it, both of you!
By the way, master...
Excuse me. I may have someone coming to see me.
I'll join you later.
Who was master Ichimatsu expecting?
A meeting...
Seven o'clock...
Märchen.
Hold it!
I see!
It's all clear.
Very well.
We'll talk in detail at the station.
Let's go, Chiba.
Yes, sir.
What the hell were you doing up there?
We're leaving!
Inspector, wait a minute.
These two have nothing to do with our case.
Kisaburo-san, you came to this room to see Master Ichimatsu.
After we left for Melchen.
I believe it was just before 7 o'clock.
Master Ichimatsu was already on the floor unconscious.
And there was a knife with a familiar name next to him.
You immediately assumed that Miya had committed the crime.
Is that why you...?
On the other hand, Miya...
saw Kisaburo enter this room...
Kisaburo immediately ran out of the room after seeing Master Ichimatsu lying there.
Miya immediately decided that Kisaburo was the culprit.
So that's it.
You saw me?
That's right...
Naturally.
Besides, I'm your biggest fan.
If the police got their hands on you...
So I...
Right.
But, you know... How in the world did you think I'd try to stab my mentor?
I have the same question for you.
I wouldn't lay a finger on the master.
Okay, stop it.
If that's the case, Mouri,
then who attacked Master Ichimatsu?
Mentor Ichimatsu left the perpetrator's name on this board.
You mean the inscription "Meguro?"
That doesn't sound like much of a name.
Detective Chiba,
Under the white board is Master Ichimatsu's bag.
Take a look at the notebook inside.
And please read his plans for this evening.
Celebration at seven... at "Naruheso"?
"Naruheso"?
What the hell is "Naruheso"?
Indeed, here, it says "Naruheso".
Please try to remember.
Master Ichimatsu has a cut finger on his right hand.
He probably wrote it with his left hand.
He wanted to write "Märchen"...
"Märchen"...
"Naruheso"?
Inspector, look at the board with your head slightly tilted.
If you look sideways at the "ME" you will see that it says "NA",
the "GU" looks like a "GA".
And the "RO" remains the same, and there is a sign of elongation.
What do you get now?
NA
Na-ga-ro...?
NAGA
NAGARO
Uwajima-san, where are you going?
Just business...
Stay with us a little longer.
Master Ichimatsu wrote your name, Nagaro.
That is to say, he indicated that you were his aggressor.
That's ridiculous.
When could I have done it?
Mouri-san, you are more than aware
that I didn't have the material time to do it!
Detective Chiba.
Look through the hole in the suspended ceiling.
All right.
There's a bag in there.
I tracked it down with Conan's help.
This allowed me to find out that the suspended ceiling connects the office and this room.
Please examine the contents of the bag.
All right.
It's a doll that's for sale in your shop.
It allows a girl to make it look like there's a man in the house.
A burglar-proof doll.
You left it at the window,
making it look like you stayed to work.
Then you broke into that dressing room through the ceiling.
Using the knife you prepared,
you stabbed the master.
Uwajima!
Then he came back as if nothing had happened and went to Märchen with us.
No, no!
It wasn't me!
And the proof?
Do you have proof that I am the culprit?
Detective Chiba.
There's a loudspeaker on the wall.
A loudspeaker?
Yes.
Look around that loudspeaker.
There should be a tape recorder.
A tape recorder?
Look closely.
The loudspeaker is on, allowing you to hear what's going on in the hall.
Some time ago, Master Ichimatsu asked me:
How did it go?
That is, Master Ichimatsu wasn't listening to my rakugo.
The loudspeaker was off.
And now...
It's on.
Who turned it on?
Probably someone who wanted to secretly record Ichimatsu's "Meguro's saury".
It was on top of the loudspeaker.
Detective Chiba,
rewind a bit and play it back.
No, you can't do that.
The saury must be from Meguro.
Uwajima-san,
unlike the tape recorders of yesteryear,
modern ones can store hours of recordings.
Detective Chiba,
the moment of the crime must be recorded.
Rewind to that moment.
Okay.
Nagaro!
What are you doing?
Shut up!
Because of your visits to the restaurant, Master Ichimatsu.
Miya doesn't pay any attention to me anymore!
Don't be silly!
Miya's waiting for Kisaburo to come back!
Damn it!
Stop it!
It's me.
I stole the knife from Miya's restaurant
and attacked him.
Hey, kid.
A gift.
It's the master's tape.
It's got "Maguro's saury" on it, too,
so forget your tape recorder.
I get that you love the master's stories,
but don't you dare eavesdrop again.
Okay, thank you very much!
Miya-san, Kisaburo-san.
The hospital just called.
The master will live.
You can't be forgiven for thinking I'd stabbed him
just because you saw me leave the room!
But...
I saw you were carrying a knife.
A knife?
Conan,
maybe they're talking about that "knife".
Yes, it could be.
Kisaburo-san, that's what you were carrying, right?
Ah, there it is.
I wanted to give it to the master,
so I picked the best one this morning.
You mistook it for a knife?
But it was dark,
and you looked determined.
That's why I'm calling you a slacker!
How can you confuse a knife with saury?
Come on, knock it off.
"Saury" is written as "fall+knife+fish".
It's not that hard to make a mistake.
Master Ichimatsu's life is no longer in danger,
so why don't the two of you nibble
on this fish together like you used to?
I'd like that.
I'd like that, too.
But first I have to go see the Master.
I'll insist, too, with all my heart.
So ask to be his apprentice again.
Will he forgive me?
He will.
After all, the master was waiting for you to return.
...or it'll all be a dream again.
Conan...
...were you moved to tears by my story?
Usually children get bored and fall asleep,
...but the fact that I didn't let you is a testament to my artistic talent.
I'm awake because you've taken my place.
They had sent a threatening note just before a wedding ceremony!
Six months ago, this same couple had been assaulted by a burglar,
and now this man is threatening them again.
Surprisingly, this couple
is a perfect match for Inspector Takagi and Traffic Officer Yumi!
Posing as the couple that was supposed to get married,
they will work together in a police operation to catch their suspect!
And the next Conan, a special.
Metropolitan Police Detective Love Story
Fake Wedding!
Next Conan's Hint!
Ominous message
Huh? Next week, those two detectives are doing a one-hour special?