While seeking an exit,
An impossible barrier can become a door.
In this one-hour special,
Can the police stop the culprit from committing his crime?
Recognizing that single truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is Detective Conan!
You did it.
My body, my body can't move...
After beating out so many rivals...
I'll finally have the girl of my dreams.
Sa... Sato-san!
Takagi-kun.
Y-Yumi-san? Yumi-san!?
Takagi-kun...
No, didn't mean Yumi! Not you, Yumi-san!
Congratulations, Yumi!
About time, Yumi!
W-Wait a second!
H-How did this come about? What's going on?
Save me, Chiba!
H-Hey Chiba, how can you eat a hamburger now!?
Inspector Megure!?
Right, left, right... It's no good...
Takagi-kun!
Congratulations, Takagi-kun.
It's not like this, Shiratori-san!
Oh no, if she thinks it's like this...
S-Sato-san?
Congratulations...
Takagi-kun!
Ouch...
Yumi? Thank goodness it was only a dream.
METROPOLITAN POLICE OFFICER LOVE STORY
THE FAKE WEDDING
The Metropolitan Police Officer Love Story - The Fake Wedding!
Here.
Such a great wedding.
Yeah, but it would have been better if I had caught the bouquet.
Jeez, you're too young for that.
Or have you already promised some guy?
It's not that. It's wearing the wedding dress.
Then, I'll rent you a cheap one so we can take a picture.
Nevermind.
They aren't that cheap.
We can't yet!
Just for a bit, Takagi.
What's going on?
Come on!
What're you...
Officer Takagi!?
Y-You're getting married!?
Congratulations!
No...
This is bad, the worst people to be caught by...
Well, who is it?
Don't be foolish, Dad. It must be Officer Sato.
I'm sorry to disappoint...
But I'm the bride!
Yumi-san...
Aren't you the female officer Miyamoto Yumi!?
Eh, Officer Sato...
What about Officer Sato?
Actually, it's not what it looks like.
No, no, you two are a perfect match.
Shiratori-san...
How about it? Why don't you two get serious?
Oh, do you like that idea, darling?
Hey, Yumi...
Oh, Miwako...
Don't you get it, Yumi? You two are in a serious position.
Yes, I understand!
Not to mention, Yumi, you're enjoying this a bit much.
Yeah, I get you.
U-Um...
I think we've missed something...
The truth is...
Inspector!?
What? A deadly burglar is threatening you?
You mean these two?
No, these two are stand-ins.
The criminal is actually threatening the bride and groom who reported this to the police.
Six months ago, there was an incident involving a masked burglar who broke into the bride's house.
The groom was able to rescue the bride and fight him off...
But he said, as he was leaving:
You... I'll make sure you pay for this.
But why would you prepare the stand-ins? It doesn't seem like they're needed.
If he were an ordinary burglar, it wouldn't be, but we found fingerprints on the weapon he used.
The burglar's fingerprints match that of a serial killer that was involved in four other murder intrusion cases.
The murderer took six lives during that time.
In every case, the criminal entered while the owners were sleeping,
And murdered them by slashing their throats.
After looting the house of its valuables,
He would set the residence on fire.
And the day before yesterday, the bride found a piece of paper in her mailbox.
"Congratulations... I'll be sure to throw a fantastic celebration for your wedding."
I see. I guess it may be necessary to use stand-ins while dealing with such a dangerous guy.
But why Officer Takagi and Yumi-san?
Oh? You don't think I look good with Takagi-kun?
Ah, no...
We had no choice.
The bride, Masudo Rei-san, and the groom, Taira Masateru-san...
Look like this.
I see. They do look like Takagi and the patrol woman.
Really?
So, is the actual ceremony on hold?
No, the groom insisted it go on.
So, we put officers at the entrance to the building to make sure those without invitations didn't get in.
Note: For western style weddings in Japan, as the couple leaves the chapel, there are often either flower or rice showers.
The time he should strike is while those two are having their rice shower.
So, that's when they'll come into play.
Of course, those two will be wearing protective vests,
And all of the others in the wedding will be switched with officers.
But will you all be alright? You don't even know how you'll be attacked.
Don't worry, if anything goes wrong, Miwako will come to our rescue.
Yeah, for Takagi-kun.
I'm shocked! You would choose love over our friendship?
I have no choice. The burglar seems more angry with the groom than the bride.
Besides, you're getting close.
Miwako!
Ah, excuse me. You just look like someone I know.
Could you be here for Taira-san and Masudo-san's wedding?
Ah, yes. You, as well?
That's right.
The ceremony is at 5:00 in Ceremonial Hall 3?
I guess I'll see you all there.
Good luck, Rei-chan.
Let's see, Ceremonial Hall 3...
Hey, Masudo-san. I'm Karube.
Thanks for the invitation. This is our first time meeting in person, right?
Seeya, can't wait for the ceremony.
Even they can't tell you all apart.
Do they really look that much alike?
That just shows how good of a couple you all are.
Shiratori-san...
Only because you like her...
Well, at any rate, we don't want to cause any trouble.
I'd like for Takagi-kun and Yumi-kun to wait in the back for now.
We'll send along instructions later.
Yes.
It's time to relay our plans to the true bride and groom.
Alright, excuse us, Mouri-kun.
Good luck.
Hey Uncle, why don't you go with them?
You're a renowned detective, right?
The inspector and the others could use you.
That's true.
Inspector!
I'm going, too!
Conan-kun!
Um...
Do we know you?
Ah, excuse me, you just look like someone I know.
Hey, hey...
What do you mean, Rei?
Isn't this our special day?
We can't back down now.
But Masuteru-san, someone is threatening us.
What if one of the guests gets hurt?
Don't worry. Everything will be fine.
I promise you.
B-But...
Sorry to intrude.
Inspector!
How are things?
Everything looks great at the moment.
Our colleagues are stationed around the building.
No matter what happens, they'll protect you.
See? Everything will be fine.
But who is that with you, Inspector?
Ah, this is a detective named Mouri Kogoro. We met up with him by coincidence.
That great detective?
You're "Sleeping Kogoro"?
I'll do everything I can to help.
Firstly, about the incident six months ago,
Could you give me the details?
Yes, it was snowing that night.
It all happened around midnight.
I awoke to some strange noises and couldn't turn the lights on.
I found a flash light and wondered down the hall...
I found a man trying to break into my safe.
He chased me down the hall,
And caught me just as I got to the exit I knew he would have killed me.
That's when he arrived and saved me.
I had a bad feeling.
Her parents were on vacation that day,
And she was alone there with her two elderly servants.
And that was when he fought him.
Hurry, the police!
I hurried and called the police.
As I got back, I saw the intruder leaving...
Oh, so that's when he said, "I'll make sure you pay for this."
But through all of that, neither of you were hurt.
I was fine and unhurt, but his left hand...
The criminal ended up slamming me down, breaking my thumb and wrist.
Until a week ago, I was in a cast.
But, we should have waited to go to that place when he recovered.
That place?
Her father wanted us to get out of Japan for our safety.
Her father even bought us a home in Hawaii.
Wow, impressive.
That home has a sophisticated security system,
So no one should be able to break in while we're away again.
Someone broke in while you were away?
Yes, into his apartment.
It was while we were out for the evening.
What was taken?
Nothing, but my computer, which was off, was on.
Ah, hold on a moment.
Yes, this is Megure.
Oh, Chiba-kun?
What!? A burned corpse with its neck sliced!?
Yes, at a warehouse near the Teimuzu river.
The body is that of a thirty or forty year old man.
He's wearing a black suit and a white necktie.
And, according to the evidence the lab just tested,
Under his left fingernails...
You found fingerprints from the burglar and serial killer!?
A white necktie, usually for formal wear...
Hey, did your computer have the guest list on it?
Yeah, we were making it in his bedroom.
Then, the victim could be someone on the list!
The burglar must have been after the invitation.
Does that mean the burglar is already here!?
Cancel it, cancel it.
Cancel all the weddings and evacuate everyone.
I don't want so many people here with a murderer in the middle.
It's-best to get everyone out now.
Hold on a second. Inspector.
Even without proof that he's here,
You all are going to ruin our ceremony?
But Taira-san...
When you drove the burglar away six months ago from...
Masudo Rei-san's home, the burglar vowed he would have his revenge.
Also, what about the threatening letter found in her mailbox?
And the burned body, found in a warehouse near the Teimuzu river,
With the throat sliced.
Even with the burglar's fingerprints being under the left fingernail of the victim.
You still don't believe the burglar is here?
Not to mention that the victim was dressed in formal wear, and after someone broke into your apartment...
Your computer that was off was on when you returned.
If the same burglar broke in and looked at the computer,
He almost certainly saw the guest list.
He must have killed someone on the list, stole their invitation letter...
And is now blending in here as a normal guest.
Right, all just to take revenge out on you.
But, we don't even know the guy who was burned...
Inspector Megure, I have something for the bride and groom.
It was requested they open it now.
Who sent it?
I'm not sure, a staff member handed it to me.
Hey, hey, why bring something potentially dangerous here?
Oh, but I already...
I already checked it.
Ah... I see...
Ah, it's from Shimizu-san,
Our chat buddy.
Oh, could that be the video?
Chat buddy?
We got involved in this hot springs site on the internet.
For our party tonight, we invited the site's members so we could meet them for the first time in person.
This is the video we're playing at the party, so I guess she finally finished editing it.
We're supposed to check it one last time.
May I see it?
Taira-san and Rei-chan's Lovely Day.
After the burglar incident,
This couple became closer...
Oh, you're already here?
Where's this?
The entrance to my apartment.
And this Shimizu-san was recording?
Yes, after chatting, we found out we were neighbors and became close friends.
Sorry about that.
We're going to Tropical Land today, right?
You put your keys on the light Do you always do that?
Yeah, it's a habit.
That means Shimizu-san could sneak in anytime, right?
She isn't that way!
She was the one who suggested we report the break-in to the police.
You mean to say, you didn't report this to the police?
No, since there was nothing missing.
But, we did move the date of the wedding to one day later than what was on the computer.
So, even if the criminal saw the date, he would come on the wrong day.
But still, if the computer had the names and addresses of all the guests,
He could have easily got in contact with one of the guests to confirm the date.
If that's so, why not have the bride and groom meet the guests?
The bad man may be pretending to know you two, right?
Y-Yeah.
But wait, what if they get attacked in the process?
We can have them observe the guest room from an adjacent one.
Why not do that? It's the safest way.
We don't know what the burglar will do if we cancel the wedding.
Will you please confirm the guests?
Alright...
That's alright.
Sato-kun, tell Takagi-kun and Yumi-kun:
The burglar may be hiding in this building.
Tell them to stay alert in case he comes after them.
I got it.
Ah, also, Sato-kun.
I'd like you to guard them as well.
Masudo-san, this is scary...
■Don't worry, I'm here-with you.
Hey, hey! Look at this!
How do I look? Well?
Hey, Yumi! You're getting married!?
Stupid, why would I get married? It's a police assignment.
Um, Yumi-san... I don't think you should be telling that to outsiders.
I know that! Be quiet while I'm on the phone!
Sorry!
Eh, a man's voice? No, nothing, just the T.V.
Jeez, wasn't she the one into it earlier?
never understand women...
Yes, we're getting married!
Oh well, won't be too much longer, right?
This is what I'd expect from Yumi-san...
I'm sure it was.
I'm sure it was heart-breaking to see him with another girl even in a dream, right?
Eh? What're you saying? It wasn't real.
But, you know what they say, sometimes the bad things from dreams come true.
Sometimes... The bad things...
Could it be-!?
Sato-san, it's not like that!
Not everything that happens in dreams comes true!
See what I mean?
What're you talking about?
Didn't the inspector tell you to wait in the room?
Yes...
What's this? Listening in on us on your wedding day?
You shouldn't do that.
That's right.
Alright, let's go, Sato-san.
Hey, don't walk away.
Jeez, you need help with everything.
Sato-san?
Is there something with them?
Anyone?
Yes...
Tell us everyone you don't recognize.
Which ones?
Yes...
That dark-skinned man with the sunglasses...
That thin man with dark hair...
And, that bearded man with glasses who just came in.
Especially number three.
The third one has been taking pictures the whole time.
What do you mean, Ran-kun?
Because earlier, I saw him,
Doing what he is now and taking pictures of the couples.
He's taking pictures of the couples? It may be Uncle Gunji, the photographer.
But you don't recognize him?
I knew him when I was little...
But he was thin back then, and had no beard.
I haven't seen him since he became a photographer and began travelling.
hen, what about the other two?
Especially the man wearing sunglasses in here.
It's possible that he's Shimabukuro-san...
The instructor of my snowboarding class.
I invited him because I met Masuteru-san at his class.
Is that right?
I don't snowboard any longer, however.
I didn't recognize him because he's usually wearing a hat and goggles.
I see.
Well, what about the other man?
He could be the administrator of the hot springs site, Karube-san.
A hot springs site...
Inspector, internet sites have administrators.
Of course I know that.
He agreed to come to the wedding,
But I've never met him before.
This would be our first time.
But he must know your face at least vaguely,
As he came up and talked to Yumi-san earlier.
The truth is we've sent him pictures before, so he should recognize us.
Inspector...
Our only option is to take those three's fingerprints and compare them to the burglar.
N-No way. That's too disrespectful for our guests.
But, what other way is there?
Hey, how do you know that those fingerprints are the bad guy's?
Well, in the break-in before Rei-san's, we found fingerprints at the scene,
From when the burglar murdered the owner...
The criminal left their fingerprints on the victim's earring.
Since bits of the killer's glove were recovered from the victim's teeth,
It's likely that the victim bit his hand, pulling off his glove in the process.
And as he held her down again, he touched her earring.
This fingerprint matched those found on the knife at Rei-san's home.
We determined that it must have been from the culprit's left ring finger,
As the fingerprint on the knife completed the one from the earring.
Inspector, does that mean the criminal wasn't wearing gloves?
No, he was wearing gloves then, so it was probably from before the incident.
It's likely that he didn't wipe them beforehand because he took the weapon with him the last four times.
It's probable that he didn't expect to be fought away by Taira-san.
Not to mention, there were no other fingerprints on the scene.
Right, Taira-san, was the door locked when you came to save her during the blackout?
No, it was open.
That's because when I found the entrance during the blackout, and just when I got to the door...
Is there something wrong?
No, it's just, I feel like I saw something then...
What was it?
Remember!
Hey, don't force her!
What is it, Ran?
Look, those three...
The thin man has a bandage around his left ring finger and,small finger...
The guy with the glasses has a bandage on his left ring finger...
And the guy with the sunglasses has had his left hand in his pocket the whole time...
They may be trying to avoid leaving their fingerprints anywhere.
That's it, go ahead and get those three's fingerprints.
That'll show you that the burglar isn't here.
I know I didn't invite anyone like that!
But look, Conan-kun is already asking around.
That brat's at it again...
Mouri-kun...
Well?
What did you find out from those three?
The guy with the bandage sprained his finger playing baseball,
The one with the small bandage says he caught it in a door,
And the one with his hand in his pocket says it's a habit.
Note: A stye is an inflammation of a gland in the eyelid.
That's right, he's wearing sunglasses indoors to hide a stye on his eye.
That's it! I remember!
It was when Masuteru-san came...
I saw it when Masuteru-san saved me!
The criminal...
The criminal had a stye on his right eye!
What?
A stye?
T-Then, the criminal is the man wearing sunglasses!
But those heal after a week...
That means he's here after all...
The serial killer burglar.
Y-You said the serial killer burglar is already here?
He's already inside this building?
He met with one of the guests, and killed them...
Likely for his invitation.
So, as the bride and groom's stand-ins, you all must be careful.
Then again, there's another possibility.
Another? What do you mean by another possibility?
I need a favor.
What?
Actually, could you step outside, Takagi-kun?
his is girl talk.
Ah, alright...
Then I guess I'll go to the toilet, unless they're still there... I'll be right back.
Of course.
I thought this may happen...
So I brought it.
Thanks, Yumi.
Since we can't recognize this serial murdering burglar...
Since Rei-san can't identify him, we'll have to take everyone's fingerprints,
And match them up with the burglar's.
Please don't do that.
What if you're wrong?
But aside from the burglar's fingerprints,
All you told us was that he had a stye on his eye.
And that won't help us now, as it must have healed.
Don't you remember the burglar's voice?
You heard him say, "I'll make sure you pay for this," right?
But his voice was muffled due to the mask he was wearing.
Not to mention, if it were identifiable, we would have reported it to the police.
Inspector Megure, we have to begin the ceremony soon.
Is that alright?
I understand.
Let's begin the ceremony.
Hey, hey...
We're on our way now.
Listen up.
Taira-san.
Taira-san!
This wedding is happening.
If you police are so worried, you can be on alert...
While watching the ceremony.
I really don't expect the burglar to show anyway.
W-Wait, Taira-san!
Let them go.
Let him do as he wishes.
I don't see why I should.
By my deduction, the one who controls this ceremony...
Inspector Megure...
It's you.
Huh?
Why's there no one guarding the door?
This is Takagi, I'm coming in.
I'm coming in now...
No way!
No one's here?
W-Why?
There you are, Takagi.
I just received instructions from Inspector Megure.
You're supposed to stay here until further notice.
Where's Yumi-san?
The inspector gave her instructions and she left.
Oh, right...
But... Where?
The bride, Masudo Rei-san, will now be escorted by her father.
Everyone, please welcome them.
Hold on.
We meet again...
My two friends!
That's him!
Arrest him!
Stop! Don't try anything.
I knew the police were here.
Fear not...
As I'll leave as soon as I slice these two up.
That's enough fooling around...
Officer.
Fool!
It was me who broke into this woman's house.
You should stop joking, as you're not too I mg us.
You simply can't be the burglar.
Oh, then...
How?
How do you know this isn't the burglar?
Six months ago, it was pitch dark in the house...
When the burglar broke in.
You couldn't have seen him well.
You obviously couldn't know by just looking at him,<right?
Really?
I thought you said the burglar's voice wasn't distinct enough to identify.
I met an officer earlier who had this exact voice.
Oh? Where did you meet this officer?
Dunno, it-was somewhere in this building.
Aren't I correct?
I have to be right.
No one would play such a joke here.
You're right in saying it's an officer.
But...
He was by the Teimuzu river,
And only got here just now...
It's Chiba-kun.
I'll ask you again.
How did you know he wasn't the burglar?
Ah, no... Well...
Tell us why you opened the package earlier...
Without even knowing who it was from.
In this situation, unless they knew what could be in it,
They wouldn't open it.
But you already knew.
You already knew that nothing dangerous would come,
Because you made sure.
Naturally, you had nothing to fear.
Because you already...
Murdered the serial killer burglar, right?
At a warehouse near the Teimuzu river...
You murdered him.
What's going on out there?
Why am I the only one waiting in this room?
We're really busy out here.
Well, at least tell me where Yumi-san and Sato-san went.
Just tell me anything.
You mean Sato isn't there with you?
She isn't here...
What do you mean?
Why isn't she with you all?
Hey, this isn't the time to be messing around, Sato-san...
Huh? I killed the serial killer burglar?
All I meant was that the burglar wouldn't dare come here with so many officers here.
Why would this suggest I killed him?
Besides, those three men Rei didn't recognize are the most suspicious.
No, those three are innocent.
Those three walked up to Yumi-kun, thinking she was the true bride.
Ah, excuse me. You just look like someone I know.
Hey, Masudo-san.
If someone intended to murder another guest for their invitation,
They would have avoided the bride until their scheme played out.
Yeah, he wouldn't know how the person he was coming as acted around the bride.
Also, his voice was heard before.
The burglar has no way of knowing how well his voice was remembered.
So, if the burglar did come here,
He wouldn't want to talk with her too early.
We didn't notice this until Mouri-san pointed it out.
But what about their left ring fingers?.
All three of them were hiding it.
That was a coincidence.
If the fingerprints of the burglar, who was wearing gloves, were on the weapon, it must have been from before.
No one would remember which hand it was.
If someone didn't remember which hand, wouldn't they have hidden both of them?
You had to cover up.
You didn't know for sure.
After reading the case report, you pretended to have a broken left wrist and thumb.
With it in a cast,
The police couldn't get that hand's fingerprints.
That's because the fingerprints on the weapon...
Were placed when you were fighting the burglar.
They were yours.
The only reason you left fingerprints on it was because your right hand was occupied.
That's what Rei-san said, right?
She was running through the dark for the entrance, but the burglar caught her.
When you saved her.
She saw the stye on the burglar's right eye.
If she could see a stye on the criminal's eye when you came to save her,
You must have had a flashlight with you at the time.
That means that you...
Must have known beforehand that the electricity had been cut.
He must be a colleague of the burglar.
Lucky for you that you all were fighting on a rug.
This way, your fingerprints would only be found on the knife.
Otherwise, your fingerprints may have been on the floor.
It's likely that you betrayed your partner because you began to have feelings for Rei-san.
So, your partner that you had betrayed waited to take out his revenge.
And you let him break in to your apartment...
So that when he checked your computer's data,
He would see a fake date for the wedding.
So, when you saw him around this building yesterday,
You led him away...
To an abandoned warehouse near the Teimuzu river to murder him.
Well, am I wrong?
Yeah, that's almost right.
But the reason I saved this woman was because I could get more money by marrying her.
Damn you.
I tried to explain it to that fool.
He didn't get it, so I killed him.
That fool could do nothing but break safes anyway.
Yes, that's right.
Just like the police!
Don't present a knife to a serial killer burglar!
Conan-kun?
You're surrounded by police!
There's no escape.
Escape?
I'm done after you get my fingerprints.
So, I may as well...
Take a few with me to the other side!
Y-Yumi-kun!
Yumi-kun!
Yumi-san!?
Sorry to disappoint.
But I'm not Miwako.
Aren't those Sato-san's clothes.
That's right, we switched places.
We used wax to change our hairstyles.
Your hairstyles?
The reason I was clinging to you earlier,
Was to make Miwako want to wear a wedding dress.
Miwako tried her best to be your lovely bride,
But she couldn't fit the safety vest under the dress due to her muscles.
Then... Sato-san is...
When the Inspector told me to get to the ceremony hall,
I took her.
Yu... Yumi-kun!
That's one!
No way!
Corset wires are pretty tough.
Miwako-san!
Sato-kun?
Move!
I can't do anything in this dress!
Alright!
That's embarrassing...
Conan-kun!
Ran-chan, stop him.
Stop!
Sato-san!
You're not escaping!
Takagi-kun!?
Takagi-kun, what the-
I was just coming...
How did this happen?
Wow, Officer Sato...
Oh? You had already realized that the groom was suspicious?
It wasn't hard to piece together.
I noticed the second I saw the video.
Even with his wrist and thumb broken, he was able to change fast.
Then it occurred to me he must have been faking it to hide his fingerprints.
Also, he didn't report the break-in at his own apartment.
I see, because if the police knew, they would test the fingerprints and match his with the burglar's.
Right, I knew I couldn't let our lovely bride near such a dangerous man,
So I switched places with Yumi.
You seemed glad to be wearing a wedding dress.
It meant nothing, those don't suit me anyway.
Is that right?
But it was surprising, wasn't it?
Who would have thought that that man was a famous photographer hired to make a poster of the wedding?
Hey, just hurry past it! It's so embarrassing! Hurry, hurry!
Go Yumi. Go on, Takagi-kun.
Go, go.
It's not how I pictured it.
It's already been a month since then.
It's a good picture though, isn't it?
It's vandalism if you tear it down.
I know that.
What were you thinking, Chiba?