From a different point of view, even an imposing
wall blocking your path is just a large door.
An illusion show leads into a case!
An enigmatic scenario,
and a double-trick mystery!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid
but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Gen'yo Fuyuki's
Magic Show
Wow, this is incredible!
It's as if the ghosts you love so much
are about to come out of the poster.
Don't say that, Conan-kun!
Unlike the cheerful vibe you get
from Kazumi Sanada's magic,
Gen'yo Fuyuki's magic show
gives out a dark, creepy vibe.
It's weird that Fuyuki-san asked
for you so urgently.
Either way,
let's see what he wants.
Trick vs. Magic
(Part I)
Gen'yo
Fuyuki
Come in.
If you'll excuse me.
It's you, Mouri-san!
My apologies for calling a great
detective such as yourself so urgently.
Gen'yo Fuyuki (35)
Magician
My name's Fuyuki.
I'm Mouri.
This is my daughter...
Good afternoon.
My name's Ran Mouri.
And this is Conan, a mooch.
Mooch?
Don't call me that.
Good afternoon.
Oh, sorry.
Since you mentioned over the phone
that you wanted to meet me at all costs,
I came as fast as I could.
It's no bother.
Do you two like magic?
Yeah, I love it!
We watch magic shows
every once in a while.
If we didn't say yes, he probably
wouldn't let us come with him.
Then...
I can't believe I have to
put up with this.
Amazing!
Though admittedly,
his technique is impeccable.
Anyway, there's a reason I asked you
to come to this theater specifically.
To be honest, I believe somebody
in the group wants to kill me.
I want you to catch whoever it is.
Did you get any threats?
Recently, on two
separate occasions,
equipment fell from the ceiling during our rehearsals, and I barely made it out alive.
The first time, I figured
it was just an accident,
but then it happened again.
Was anyone around
you at the time?
No, I was all alone.
Besides you, how many people
are in your group?
Hey! Let me do the questioning!
Sorry. How many are you?
There's five of us, besides me.
First off, there's
Misa Uehara, an assistant.
Misa Uehara (26)
Assistant
She's my ex-fiancée,
and she holds a grudge against me because
I broke up with her three years ago,
unilaterally.
Unilaterally?
Yes.
Another assistant,
Chiaki Nakagawa.
Chiaki Nakagawa (24)
Assistant
She's my ex-wife, and we
finalised our divorce last year.
But she still hasn't forgiven me
for all the times I've cheated on her.
After that, there's Kazuma Ishida,
the video operator.
Kazuma Ishida (19)
Video Operator
He's my disciple, and he took it upon himself to record all our shows,
in an attempt to study magic.
Video operator...
He has the makings of a good magician,
plus he's obedient and good-tempered.
He's the only one I trust.
Next to him, we have
Shingo Shoji, the director.
Shingo Shoji (37)
Director
He was my disciple long ago,
but he wasn't any good at magic,
and I ended up hiring
him as a director.
The two of us have
different opinions
on which direction
the show should turn to.
This is the last time
I'll be counting on him.
You're going to fire him?
Yes.
Finally, we have Minoru Hasegawa,
the crane operator.
He gambles a lot,
and owes me a lot of money.
Minoru Hasegawa (45)
Crane Operator
If I were to die,
he'd be free of his debt.
Basically, the people with
a motive to have me killed are...
...four, all except
Kazuma Ishida-san, right?
Right.
Mouri-san.
Yes?
Here. Tickets for tonight's show.
Right.
I don't think anything will happen,
but throughout the show,
I'll perform certain tricks
where I risk my life.
Therefore, I'd like to agree on an emergency signal with you, just in case.
A signal?
If I perform this gesture,
I would like you to run towards
the stage and save me,
even if we're
in the middle of the show.
But then, can't you
just cancel the show?
That's not an option.
I'm a professional magician,
so my pride won't allow it.
Roger. I'll do my best, too,
as a professional detective.
Please do.
And make sure nobody else
in the group knows about this.
Very well.
We still have a lot of time
before the show starts.
Where do you guys want to-
What's wrong, Ran?
Ran-neechan, Fuyuki-san
let you down, didn't he?
He broke up with his
fiancée unilaterally,
cheated on his wife multiple times, and ended up divorcing her...
And he was talking
about it like it was no big deal.
An adult's world
is really complicated.
Uncle, your world's
pretty complicated, too.
Conan-kun!
Ow...
Mind your own business!
Either way,
I have work to do.
You two go ahead
and do whatever you want, okay?
Conan-kun, are you okay?
Huh?
If something were
to happen during the show,
it'd be something involving his magic equipment.
And what are you doing here?
So this is how it works?
Hey, don't ignore me!
Somebody's here.
What?
Oh, crap! Hide, Conan!
Over here!
Right!
Lie down over there,
I'll cover you up.
Oh, right!
Hey, Conan, isn't this the box from
the trick where they cut a girl in pieces?
Yeah, but it's fine. They put
her back together afterwards.
No, that's not the point!
Squeeze your legs tighter.
Right.
Quiet, they're here.
Kogoro Mouri?
The detective?
Yeah, apparently he hired him.
I overheard him over the phone.
Who do you think
dropped that equipment?
No idea.
But if somebody wants to kill him,
they'll have to be a lot smarter than that.
Yeah, if the two of us
could see eye-to-eye...
Yeah, it'd be easy.
Hey!
How can you say
something like that?
He might have a pretty bad
temper for a group director,
but it's thanks to him
that we're making a living!
Yeah! You should
be thankful to him!
What are you on about?
The only reason you put up
with him is money.
Shut up.
You too, Kazuma.
You actually hate Fuyuki, because
you've been with us for ages,
and he still won't let you come
on stage as a real magician.
No, I don't hate him.
So, should we go?
Yes.
I don't really care, but
why don't you shave your beard?
You look like a bum.
Hey, wait!
Who do you think you are?
Damn it!
Uncle, are you okay?
Of course not!
Man, that sucked.
Uncle, you'd have
to stretch upwards
and grab your knees with
your hands to pull that off.
Stretch upwards and grab
my knees with my hands?
Because then you'd be fine, even
after the box is cut in half, right?
Oh, right.
But now, we know for sure that everyone in the group has a motive to kill Fuyuki-san.
I'll have to be extra-careful
with this case.
All right!
Aren't you gonna check
the magic equipment?
Looking at all of that isn't
gonna do us any good. Come on!
Okay...
Gen'yo Fuyuki's
Magic Show
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to Gen'yo Fuyuki's magic show!
Tonight, we present you a strange
and fantastic world of magic.
Please enjoy it
to your heart's content!
Look at her, she's having a blast.
Oh, no!
Oh, no...
No way!
Oh, thank goodness...
It's incredible, isn't it, Dad?
Fuyuki-san's an expert
at throwing knives.
Fuyuki-san only made it look
like he was throwing them.
What?
But we saw the knives strike!
You think you saw that.
There's a special mechanism.
I saw it a while ago,
back in the storage room.
When I was hiding
there with Uncle.
With Dad?
The next trick's about to start.
Those spikes are for real!
If those spikes go through him,
he's got no chance.
Those straps are only holding him
down with a very weak adhesive.
After the curtain drops,
he'll escape through a small
space on the side of the table.
Wait, wasn't that the signal?
What?
I saw it, too!
Wait!
Wait, wasn't that the signal?
What?
I saw it, too!
Wait!
Fuyuki-san!
Conan-kun!
What an honor!
Aren't you the great
detective, Kogoro Mouri-san?
Is there a case in here?
No, I...
Apparently, Mouri-san thought
that these two beauties
wanted to murder me,
and came running
here to help me.
But you can relax.
As you can see,
I'm safe and sound.
So it seems.
But don't let your guard down,
because during the second act, there's
a trick where I put my life on the line.
I hope you'll look after my safety.
Will do.
Ladies and gentlemen, please
give Mouri-san a big applause!
Thank you, thank you.
I apologize.
I just wanted to make sure if you
could see me making the signal or not.
Everything has a limit.
Thanks to your joke,
I went through major ridicule.
I truly apologize.
But what I said on stage is true.
During the second act,
I'll perform a truly dangerous trick.
Huh?
Fuyuki-kun!
What was with that trick?
In the scene I directed,
you weren't supposed to scream like that,
nor was blood supposed to come out!
It was my idea.
Thanks to it, we were even
able to fool a great detective.
That wasn't what we agreed on!
I was aiming
for a splendid, elegant image,
in the middle of that dark mystery.
Kazuma!
Yes?
Shoji-san.
From now on, this show isn't
going to be splendid nor elegant.
Instead, I'm going to
make it even more exciting.
Then have it your way.
But that's not making
the show exciting,
it's just grotesque!
I'm sorry you had to witness that.
Did you want something?
No, it's nothing.
Where's Conan-kun?
He went to use the toilet,
and he still hasn't returned.
Never mind him.
Just don't take your
eyes off Fuyuki-san.
I have a bad feeling about this.
From here, I'll be able to tell
right away if something goes wrong.
Kid, you can't watch
the show from here.
Go back to your seat.
Yeah, but...
Come on.
All right.
Dad...
No, it's fine.
He didn't do the signal.
It's been a long time.
Don't worry. The trick's
probably supposed to be like this.
Once they pull
the curtain back up,
Fuyuki-san will be right
on top of the water tank.
Oh, no!
Damn it!
Fuyuki-san! Fuyuki-san!
What are you doing?
Open the water tank, quickly!
Lower the curtain!
Hasegawa!
Open the lid, right away!
Did something happen?
An ambulance!
Call an ambulance!
Right!
Fuyuki-san!
Mouri-san! Give him CPR!
Right.
Fuyuki-san!
Fuyuki-san! Fuyuki-san!
Boss!
Boss! Boss!
Fuyuki-san!
Boss!
Fuyuki-san! Fuyuki-san!
Hang in there, Fuyuki!
Gen'yo Fuyuki's
Magic Show
Beika
Theater
Gen'yo Fuyuki's
Magic Show
Even if it's for the sake
of the investigation,
we can't reveal the secret
behind a magic trick.
That's... you know...
We can't tell you, you know?
I have to remember that trick...
This latch...
Got it! Now I just need evidence!
On the next Conan:
Trick vs. Magic
(Part II)
Next Conan's Hint: Latch
Next time, the trick
will be made clear!
The case, or the magic trick?
I'm not telling you...