From a different perspective...
An imposing wall is just a large door.
The truth about the case with a trick.
A dodgy trick?
Or an eye-diverting trick?
He sees a single truth.
He looks like a child, but thinks like an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
Uncle received a call from a famous magician, Fuyuki Genyo, requesting an urgent meeting.
Fuyuki Genyo (35)
Illusionist
Fuyuki-san thought,
that someone on his team was trying to kill him,
so he asked his uncle to find out who it was.
There are five people in the team.
Uehara Misa (26)
Assistant
Assistants, Uehara Misa.
Nakagawa Chiaki (24)
Assistant
and Nakagawa Chiaki.
Ishida Kazuma (19)
Responsible for the video
Responsible for the video, Ishida Kazuma.
Shoji Shingo (37)
Director
Director, Shoji Shingo.
Hasegawa Minoru (45)
Responsible for Mechanics
In charge of mechanics, Hasegawa Minoru.
Then, shortly after the investigation began,
it was time for the magic show.
And suddenly.
What?
What the hell!
Fuyuki-san! Fuyuki-san!
TRICK VS MAGIC
(PART TWO)
Mr. Fuyuki! Mr. Fuyuki!
What are you waiting for?
Remove the locks quickly!
The curtain! Lower the curtain!
Hasegawa! Lift the lid!
Is something wrong?
Ambulance! Ambulance!
Okay.
Fuyuki!
Mori-san, CPR.
Mr. Fuyuki!
Chief!
Fuyuki!
Leader!
Come to your senses, Fuyuki!
Fuyuki!
This is the end.
Leader!
I've filmed up to this point.
You can't help but look at it.
But it's precious footage.
It's good that you were filming.
No, it's not.
Thanks to the two tapes,
we were able to recreate the situation.
How was the trick supposed to end?
When the curtains went up,
he should have been standing on the tank. Fuyuki.
And how would he have gotten out?
Well, that's...
Yes...
We can't tell you that.
Why not?
It's necessary for the investigation.
Inspector.
Even if it is for the investigation,
we can't reveal the secret of the trick.
I've got it all figured out!
The tank lid for this trick has a secret.
That's what I thought.
What were you thinking?
Here, look at this.
This hinge doesn't have a pin.
Yes.
When the girls shackled Mr. Fuyuki's legs,
they secured the hinges with padlocks.
At that moment, they discreetly pulled the pins out of the hinges.
The lid could then be easily opened.
When Mr. Fuyuki was placed in the tank
and hidden behind the curtains,
he would lift himself up with his abs,
grasp the handle on the inside,
emerging from the water to take a breath.
That's right, there's a handle.
That's how it works.
Mr. Fuyuki would dive back into the water,
and when the curtains were raised,
he twitched and twirled defiantly.
Dad.
This is also an act.
No signal.
When the curtains came down again,
he would remove the special, easy-to-open handcuffs,
and lifted his torso back up to his feet,
climb up, hold on to the handle on the door,
and climb out of the water tank.
Now I get it.
You're really something, Conan.
I've seen it on TV.
I hope you're right about that.
Well, basically.
According to the forensic report,
it seems that Fuyuki-san drowned.
The question is,
whether it was an accident or whether someone was behind it.
I understand, Inspector.
This is murder.
There are two perpetrators: Uehara Misa and Nakagawa Chiaki!
What?
Wait a minute!
What makes you think that?
The two of you conspired to kill Mr. Fuyuki,
pretending to pull the pins out of the hinges,
and left them there!
Don't you dare joke like that!
I definitely pulled out the pins.
Here.
Look!
And the lid is actually open!
Here.
The other day,
when we were dragging Mr. Fuyuki,
you could've removed...
What are you talking about?
Chiaki and I held Fuyuki by the sides.
You were holding the lid!
Was I?
Uncle.
Was the lid open then?
I don't know...
I was busy with other things, too...
But when I took Fuyuki's legs out,
the lid opened easily.
So the pins were removed?
Shall we watch the video Kazuma made again?
It's coming up.
Why did you pan away?
Because the secret...
It won't reveal itself if you film it.
Okay, okay.
Then show me the moment
when Shoji-san released Fuyuki-san's legs.
Got it.
Fuyuki!
It's coming.
Mori-san, CPR.
Mr. Fuyuki! Mr. Fuyuki!
Chief! Chief!
Fuyuki!
Director!
Come to your senses, Fuyuki!
Stop it.
Okay.
Why do you keep panning away?
You missed the important part again.
I'm sorry.
That's a shame, isn't it, inspector?
But still.
It's unlikely that Misa-san and Chiaki-san did it.
Kazuma.
Yes.
By the way, Kazuma-san.
You gave something to Fuyuki-san during the break.
It was a drug.
A drug?
What kind of drug?
A beta-blocker. An adrenaline regulator.
Beta-blocker?
An adrenaline regulator.
When you take it, your heart rate goes down.
To perform the trick and get out of the tank, you need to hold your breath for a long time,
so he always took it 15 minutes before the start.
So this is Fuyuki-san's order?
Of course it is.
I got it!
You switched the pills with muscle relaxants.
"Prohibited harassment"?
What were you thinking, Takagi?
Muscle relaxants.
When you take them, your muscles weaken
and you can't get up because of weakness in your abs.
But when the curtain went up the first time,
Fuyuki-san twitched painfully,
but did not give a signal.
At that moment, the drug had not yet taken effect.
But when he tried to rise a second time, it did.
Wait!
I respect my mentor! Why?
Don't you really resent Fuyuki?
He still won't let you go on stage as a magician.
No way.
To prove it, only you, when everyone was trying to save Fuyuki-san,
continued to shoot the video.
If you really respected the teacher,
you wouldn't have kept filming
when he was between life and death.
It's just that...
The teacher kept saying,
that I should keep filming no matter what.
That I would become a professional, worthy of Fuyuki Genyo.
Forensic scientist!
Yes.
I'm listening.
So you didn't change...
Of course not!
The deceased's blood test?
It will be done.
I'm waiting for the results.
The blood test will take some time.
I'll ask you all to wait in the dressing room.
What is it, Conan?
I'm going to the bathroom.
Oh, man.
Remember that trick.
Somewhere in there,
somewhere in there must be the criminal's hidden trick.
After that, the chains were permanently down.
By the way, then too.
What if...
Let's go over the video again.
Okay!
What's wrong, Takagi?
What's gotten into you, Takagi?
Sorry, it was an accident.
What's gotten into him?
By the way, after the curtain came down a second time,
the lights went out for a while.
That hinge...
Oh, did you notice something again?
Isn't that hinge weird?
Because usually the center part is the longest.
That's right.
I'm surprised you noticed.
And what is that hole?
I've been thinking about that, too.
It looks like it was handmade.
After the fact.
Conan.
That was a long time in the bathroom.
My stomach ached a little.
Oh, man.
Did you always have those hinges on the tank lid?
Hinges?
Oh, no.
The old ones wore out, so they were replaced recently.
Who replaced them?
I'm going to the bathroom again!
I got it.
There's still evidence.
Take a good look.
Maybe we're missing something.
Ambulance!
Okay.
Fuyuki!
Mr. Mori...
I found the proof.
I knew it. That's who the culprit is.
You didn't find it?
Yes. According to the forensics report,
no muscle relaxants were found in Mr. Fuyuki's blood.
And then there's Kazuma.
The video review didn't yield much either.
We can't hold them any longer.
I apologize for the wait.
Damn. I was absolutely sure.
Hey, uncle.
What do you want, kid?
This way.
What's so strange about this place?
There's nothing strange in here.
Hey, kid.
Mouri?
Uh-huh, he asked everyone to gather on the stage.
Inspector, what if this...
It's here! That's it.
Hey, Detective Chiba.
Uncle, everyone's here.
Dear friends, this case is truly extraordinary.
I say this because there was a device for the trick shown on stage.
The perpetrator added his own contraption to it,
making it a double trick.
At the same time, I made a mistake by not preventing it.
Albeit with a delay, I will allow myself to point out the culprit.
With this clever trick,
he took the life of Mr. Fuyuki.
The director, Shoji Shingo, it was you.
W-What are you...
You were supposed to be watching the magic trick through the monitor backstage
but you weren't actually there.
You were on the ceiling beam just above the tank.
But if someone had been there,
wouldn't the audience and Misa and Chiaki have noticed?
No, you couldn't see the top from the audience.
It was dark above the tank,
the light doesn't reach up there.
For both Misa and Chiaki,
and for Hasegawa-san backstage.
Yes, you couldn't see it.
Indeed.
The perpetrator may have been on the beam,
but how did he kill Fuyuki-san?
The audience's tape shows that no one approached the tank.
Right! The audience would have noticed.
It's impossible to go near the tank without being caught on camera.
You can't? Not at all.
When you were on the beam,
you waited for the curtain to go up,
and while Mr. Fuyuki pretended he couldn't get out,
you climbed down the crane cable
directly onto the lid of the tank.
Possessing the dexterity of a former magician, this is a technique only Shoji-san can pull off.
Once down on the lid, did he
insert pins in those hinges?
But how did he get back on the beam?
Shoji-san did not return to the beam.
He got out from under the tank.
From under the tank?
When the curtain came down,
he jumped off the tank.
As the stage fell into darkness, he quickly climbed out from under the curtain
and ran backstage.
When everyone sensed something was amiss, he ordered to pull out Fuyuki-san,
and distracted everyone from the video.
And quickly took out the pins?
Takagi, search Shoji-san.
Yes, sir. Excuse me.
Go ahead.
Check it carefully.
I'm sick of being looked at like a criminal.
Inspector, he doesn't have them.
Search again, but more carefully.
But the pins are small, he could have thrown them away anywhere.
Forensics didn't find anything like that on the scene.
So somewhere in the hallway or the dressing room.
Chiba was in the dressing room with him the whole time.
Even if we find the pins, there's no evidence he threw them away.
There is proof.
The point is that Shoji-san didn't use pins, but a ring.
A ring?
Inspector.
Look at the hinges on the lid of the tank.
The hinges on the lid?
There is an unusual hole in the hinges.
This?
By taking a ring that can be separated and sliding it through the hole in the hinge,
he locked the lid.
And this ring, Shoji-san,
is on the middle finger of your left hand.
Excuse me.
There it is. A double ring.
There is a slit on this ring.
It can be split in two.
Each of the resulting rings can be twisted.
Indeed. What does that mean?
Every magician has a few magic tricks with him.
And you have no proof that I used that ring.
You don't know when to give up.
Then, let's take another look at the Kazuma's video.
Detective Chiba!
Mr. Fuyuki!
Fuyuki-san!
Stop!
It's the ring.
So...
The ring was on my finger the whole time.
Rewind it a bit.
Ambulance!
No ring.
Then, after I walked away from the lid,
you removed the rings from the hinges
and freed Mr. Fuyuki's legs.
Mr. Shoji. Do you admit your guilt?
I have no regrets.
After all, didn't you get to see the greatest magic trick of your life?
What?!
Shoji-san, magic is meant to entertain.
And you used it for murder.
You're not just worthless as a magician,
but also as a human being!
It's so late.
And once again you were on top of it, Dad.
I guess so. Except I don't remember a thing.
Wait, what if it's beyond magic?
What happened?
Ran, it's not "Sleeping Kogoro" anymore,
it's "Wizard Kogoro".
Shall I put him to sleep again?