Even when encountering a huge wall, with friends it will soon become a large door.
Today is a one hour special. A long awaited travelling play. A showdown at the Konpira theatre.
Seeing the one truth, while looking like a child, having the brains of an adult. His name is Detective Conan.
Oh, father. After we finally came to Shikoku.
Shikoku = Smallest of the four main islands of Japan.
It's better to eat rather than to drink.
"Sanuki" is the region name of Kagawa prefecture where udon noodles were first brought from China to Japan.
Sanuki Udon!
Okay, okay... But before that, let me wet my lips a bit.
Udon = Thick wheat noodles, usually served in a hot broth.
If you do that, I won't be responsible if you fall asleep during the play.
That's right. After we finally get to meet Tamanousuke-sama!
I get it already...
Hey, the Kanemaruza theatre where Tamandusuke and others are doing the play is really famous, isn't it?
Kanemaruza = The oldest kabuki theatre still in use in Japan, was built at Konpira in the early 19th century.
Kabuki = Japanese classical drama.
That's right. Every spring they perform the Konpira kabuki play...
...and people around the nation come to see it.
Oh, look, look!
You're right. Amazing!
I'm looking forward to this!
The phantom of the theatre
The phantom of the theatre.
This is an udon restaurant?! It's just someone's home.
Welcome!
Ohhh! Well, well! There seem to be snacks to go with the beer.
They are toppings for udon, father.
Piping hot:
Hot udon and hot fish soup
Hot and cold:
Hot udon and cold fish soup
Cold and hot:
Cold udon and hot fish soup
Lukewarm:
Thank you for waiting.
Oh, here they are.
Tempura = Deep-fried fish and vegetables in a light batter.
Tempura is over there, you may choose how much you want.
Delicious!
They just take your tongue with them! This is really the real taste.
This has really opened my eyes! It's come to this, so I'll do it.
I mean that. That.
"Sanuki Udon roaming eating contest?"
Sanuki-Udon
eating contest by trying the food at various restaurants
Start of the Temple road
You two young ladies. Here, use these canes.
Return them on your way down, okay?
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
A cane? I'm not that old...
Exactly, how many are there?!
Let's see... To the Main Sanctuary there are 785 steps in total.
Seven hundred...
And eighty-five.
This is easy.
I should have used this from the beginning. Since there is something this useful!
Huh? Where is father?
Over there.
Delicious!
As expected, local sake is on a different level.
Father.
What about the shrine visit?
Sorry. Pray for me too.
Besides, Kanemaruza is right over there. I'll wait here. Obachan, one more!
Obachan = Cuter version of obasan (an endearing term for an unrelated older woman)
What happened to tasting udon at different restaurants?
I'm finally here. Carrying me only half-way is unfair.
You're slow, Sonoko-neechan.
You could've stayed down and rest with my father.
Wait a minute! Don't compare me with him!
Konpira-sama is a Sea's Guardian Deity, right-?
It's true. The people who work at sea receive courteous blessings; this says...
It's almost time. Shall we go to the Kanemaruza?
I've been waiting for this! I wonder if Tamanousuke-sama is doing good?
And Renge-san, right?
That's right. That's the problem.
Are they like "love-love" yet, those two?
Target or not... Ah, Tamanousuke-sama!
Oh, Sonoko...
Haha... Every single person...
Originally aired on: September 11th, 2006
Story based on manga: TV Original
Welcome, all.
You had a long way to walk. We can't thank you enough.
This is hopeless.
Those two.
Kataoka Renge (17)
Actress
Itou Tamanosuke (17)
Chairman
Just look at them, all love-love.
Conan-kun!
Megumi-chan!
Hello.
What's the matter?
Itou Megumi (7)
Child actor and Tamanosuke's little sister
There are no little kids today.
Ah, you mean them.
They had some things to do, so...
That's good. Megumi is so happy!
H-Hey, Megumi-chan...
This, this... Isn't the kid with glasses popular?
Conan-kun.
Here you go?
The entry way is low, so be careful with your head.
What's this about a low entrance...?
Father!
Are you alright?
I thought he would do that.
We are still in the middle of preparations and a bit busy, but...
Woah, how wonderful!
Ah, right now, at the stage, they are checking if the Seri is working.
Seri
Seri?
Several people push it up from the basement.
The actor comes out from there and takes a pose.
Rotating Stage
The stage is moving!
That's a Rotating-Stage. Again, there are many people in the basement rotating it.
Using the same method as in the olden days.
About the basement, it's called "Naraku".
Naraku = Theatre basement, also means Hell
Naraku
In the olden days the drainage was bad, so the people in the basement had a hard time, hence that name.
This road is called Hanamichi, the audience to stage passage!
Hanamichi
Hanamichi = The passage through audience to stage
After a signal, the actor-goes through the audience to the stage.
On the way, there is "Suppon". Just like Seri, it's lifted from below.
And then, right above the Hanamichi, there is a crane like "Kakesuji".
Kakesuji
Once connected, the actor can fly all over the place.
Amazing...
Sakura = Cherry blossom
The ceiling is patterned with bamboo and from up there they make Sakura snow storms, like they used to do.
Grape rack
Uwaa! It's like a time trip to 100 years ago.
Balcony seats
It's true.
Far from 100 years.
The Edo (or Tokugawa), period ran from 1603 to 1867.
The Tenpou period was from around 1830 to 1843.
Firstly, this Kanemaruza was built as a Shogun forte and office at the end of the Edo era at the Tenpou period.
Shogun = Supreme general of the samurai, equivalent to a "general": A high officer in an army.
Becoming a partial payment of a debt, it became the best Japanese theatre there is.
To be able to do a play here... It really makes me feel like an actress.
Plus, you two are all love-love...
Sonoko! Ah, I heard that you are performing the Phantom of the Opera today, but in a different era.
That's right. A showy play in stage, an ugly face poorly hidden, a mysterious phantom and a sweet songstress.
And their love story develops to love and hatred, a fearful play.
But instead of Opera... The Phantom of the Konpira!
Beloved daughter, sing! For your loved one, me, the angel of song, sing! Sing, I say!
Ah, noble angel! Shining angel! Carry my soul to the heavens!
You cannot sing!
Open your eyes! That is a devil! A revengeful ghost!
Fantastic...
Hey, hey. Who is that person?
The one who is supporting the play this time, Rausu Tatsuhiko-san.
A sponsor, huh?
"Rausu..."
From Rausu Companies, Kansai, huh?
I think I read about it in a newspaper...
Rausu Tatsuhiko (27)
Sponsor
His father passed away and the young son was just recently appointed as the successor, or something.
No, way. Oh, no. Why so suddenly...
Pleased to meet you, I'm Suzuki Sonoko!
Do your best, Renge.
Yes! Renge!
Because this Rausu Tatsuhiko is with you.
Thank you. But I have a small role in this play, so...
About that... The heroine songstress is Renge. If we negotiate about a change...
Rausu-san!
That's decided by the chairman, me.
Not you, the sponsor.
Not to mention, I'm not the phantom either.
That's right.
Phantom?
Not because the request isn't firm enough, right?
Obviously not!
Well, I only wanted to see my child-hood friend's hour of triumph.
Request. A change of heroine. A child-hood friend and a phantom. This is almost like...
The Phantom of the Opera. Opera-za no kaijin, there's no way.
A child-hood friend of Renge-chan, huh... But isn't this...
Wouldn't it be better if you would be a little more honest, Tamanousuke-kun?
Huh?
Why don't you confess your feelings to Renge? You like her, don't you?
R-Rausu-san...
If you stay hesitating, I'll steal her.
Love triangle!
Sonoko!
I don't really mind, chairman.
Changing roles with Renge-chan...
What are you saying? Stop joking.
Don't you understand why you are in this?
That's right. And as a long time fan of Romi-san... Just sharing the stage with you will make me happy.
Karube Romi (22)
Actress
Thank you.
Wow, what a beauty! I feel like I've seen her somewhere...
Karube Romi-san. A famous young actress.
She gladly accepted the heroines' role...
...my-brother said. He was sure that she would refuse, but she quickly said okay. That surprised him.
Well, well. Excuse me for my rudeness... Please, do your best.
My, my. Seems that I'm hated.
Oops. It's so dark in here, I can't see well.
Someone! Collect the performance piece by the sponsor-san.
Performance piece?
A filthy tape.
It's luminous tape. Look! It's put on there as well.
You're an intelligent boy, aren't you? That's right.
At the theatrical blackout, it's put here so that the actors don't get their positions wrong.
Neither of them seems to be within your reach, Sonoko.
That's totally fine. I found a different target.
A different target?
Kawatake Otoya (25)
Actor
Finally some rehearsal, huh? It's a stage of friendship. Well, I have no interest except for my own play.
Somehow he's so cool.
Move, move! You're in the way.
Ah! We're sorry.
Who let these in? It's not time for guests yet!
I get the creeps from him.
Sonoko...
Ah, I'm sorry, Nabe-san. I forgot to introduce them.
Nabeshima Katsuo (40)
Chief of stage setting
Here is the detective Mouri Kogoro-san, and...
Detective?
Mouri Kogoro?
That famous...
Yes, I'm that famous Mouri Kogoro.
And then, the daughter, Ran-san.
Nice to meet you.
And then...
My dear Edogawa Conan-kun!
H-Hello...
And then...
I'm Suzuki Sonoko-chan! Nice to meet you.
Whoever you are, I don't want you to get in the way. The predecessor was stricter.
Dad is dad. I'm me.
Well, if I didn't have this job, I'd be neck deep in debts.
I should be thankful as well, for the chairman. Ok! Let's go!
Don't get in the way now!
Okay, let's start.
Renge-chan, could you bring my mouth wash from the back?
The requested mouth wash is to keep her throat clear, not to freshen up her breath.
Alright.
Conan and the rest, go to the seats.
Yeees!
Romi-san! Are you alright? Romi-san!
Originally aired on: September 11th, 2006
Story based on manga: TV Original
Romi-san...
What is this?
Someone... an ambulance... Call an ambulance!
Stop that, chairman.
You're exaggerating. It wasn't anything serious.
Romi-san...
It's just a scratch. But this is quite close to the audience. It won't be good publicity if this gets out.
Shit. Messing with me.
Who did this? Clear up and fast.
If I don't fix this soon, it won't make it to the show.
He's the worst. He's got to be the criminal.
Sonoko...
But first, treatment...
Let's go to backstage first, Romi-san.
That rope, it seems like it's been severed with a sharp object.
The phantom's doings?
That's rubbish.
That was just someone's prank.
Then what is this?
If it had worked, we actually might've had to change the heroine.
That won't happen. Somehow I want to fight this now.
The phantoms or something are trying to make us wet our pants? I won't take it. Right, chairman?
Excuse me... You're in the middle of something, but... A phantom?
It's the phantom of the Konpira theatre!
As I said, that's...
If I remember correctly, it's the title of this play, right?
The phantom of the Konpira.
Yes... That's why...
I see. It's the chandelier. Chandelier.
That would be it.
Huh? Chandelier?
In the play that will come to this stage as well, the Phantom of the Opera...
A chandelier falls right on the first heroine.
That's not all. It's very similar to your situation! The setup of the people in the Phantom of the Opera.
That reminds me, just now Tamanousuke-san said that the phantom's request isn't enough.
That's the same as well. In the Phantom of the Opera, the phantom requests the change of the heroine.
What could this mean? It seems like everyone is hiding something big from us...
No, no. What to expect from a famous detective.
Tamanousuke-kun. I think it would be better to discuss this matter with Mouri-san after all.
I understand.
First, we thought they were just pranks, by someone.
Doing really nothing, only showing up to scare people, that was...
To deliver these letters.
Hmm... They are all... very alike.
What exactly does this mean?
"Wide participation, I have interest! To be stabbed and die a glorious death! Sanuki Konpira's Phantom".
Sanuki = An area in northern Shikoku.
"Wide participation, I have interest." It's obviously about the play, isn't it...?
To say, "To be stabbed and die a glorious death" does sound very play like...
Isn't it a code? About the "Sanuki" word.
Nicely figured out, boy.
Sanuki?
This was so easy, it on the contrary bothers me.
Sanuki... Ah! I see! Reading Sanuki without-SA.
Removing SA syllables and then read it, right? Let's see...
Hiragana = One of the Japanese syllabaries.
Change them all temporarily in hiragana, and it's easy to figure out.
And... take out the SA syllables, right? Doing that...
Oh, cool!
"Change the heroine! To Renge!
T-This is... Clearly a threatening letter.
But if we would always listen to each one, we couldn't make a play!
Exactly. But, if we ignore it, what happened just now...
Meaning, it wasn't a simple mistake, huh?
That means, I don't think this is over yet.
Chairman. I'm doing it.
If it's okay with Romi-san.
Well, you might just be a real actress.
Hey, hey.
Is it really okay, Mouri-san?
Considering the situation and the threatening letter, it doesn't seem to be personal...
Even if the rope's cut, we don't know if it was really on purpose until we check into it more closely.
He's right. At this stage, if the police would make a move...
Regarding to the play, we have to leave the decision to the chairman, Tamanousuke-san.
Then, it's decided. We go with these roles.
Today's premiere... I feel the same way for tomorrow's show.
I want you all to do your best.
Earnestly, beloved daughter!
Believe in me and sing! Who believes in me, shall not die!
Who is there?
Please wait! Are you a god? Or else... a devil?
That is a devil. Here is your punishment! The dweller of the world without light... of the world of darkness!
You foolish and rude youngster. Being cursed, you shall be!
My love, my spirit, if you desire to bind them, you shall become revengeful to the world of darkness!
I'm so touched...
I knew it... It's because father drank so much again.
For a while now, what is that woman looking at?
That's...
Hm? What is that?
Hey, over there!
Who is it, screwing around?
What?
What's the matter? That voice...
It's almost like...
A frog?
What happened?
This too is alike, with the Phantom of the Opera.
No way!
Shit... Where did it go?
The curtain. Close the curtain. Romi-san, come back here.
What is it?
This is the only path, but... None of the guests seem to have seen a phantom going through here.
Why, exactly...?
Hey, brat! What are you doing?
Ehh, umm... It was so high, it seemed interesting...
This isn't an amusement park! Only staff personal are allowed here!
Ah, I'm sorry!
Karube Romi
Someone changed Romi-san's mouth wash?
She thought it was the same wash, then the curtain opened, and she went to the stage like that. And then...
That's mean. Who would do such a thing?
You, you can't think...!
That doesn't matter. Right now I have to think what to do with this play.
You rehearsed with Romi-san, didn't you?
The lines, you should know them, right?
Y-You don't mean I...
There's no time to grumble about trivial things. The customers are waiting.
The curtain is down. In fifteen minutes, I'm raising the curtain.
Hurry!
A phantom? Obviously just someone spiteful...
The other customers seem to think so too.
Where is Conan-kun?
A dead end, huh? This is almost like a maze.
Anxious, loved daughter.
This is not too good... Where am I?
...if I can. Be Romi-san's substitute actor.
Don't worry.
I am... in luck with the angel of song.
No one is here. What was that...?
No one is here. What was that...
To have met that person, my heart has been filled with joy!
But that person is a dweller of darkness. I wish to be taken by that darkness...!
Stop this talk about the world of darkness. I shall guide you to the world where there's light!
Wherever, as your friend...
Conan-kun! Where did you go?
To the toilet.
Please, swear. You will only love me!
I shall swear. I will only love you!
You cannot go back anymore!
You shall die on this road!
Everything will end, everything will vanish in the darkness! Like this oath!
I shall not fear your true appearance. What I fear is that warped heart of yours!
Amazing, Renge-san.
You wouldn't think she was a substitute.
Huge success, Renge-chan.
That substitute's acting was magnificent, wasn't it?
I'm looking forward to tomorrow's play.
This place gives me the creeps...
This is...! What on earth...?
Nabe-san!
Don't move! Don't move from there.
N-No! You're wrong! It wasn't me! It wasn't me!
What did you say? Tamanosuke-san was apprehended by the police?
Yes.
Save... Conan... My brother...
Calm down, Megumi-chan.
Why on earth was he taken in for?
That is... The stage setter, Nabeshima-san... They say he killed him!
No way Tamanosuke-sama would do something like that.
But, they said that he was found unconscious next to Nabeshima-san, holding a knife.
You mean he had fainted?
And he was also wearing the phantom's mask, which was covered in blood...
So they are saying that every phantom incident until now was the chairman's doing!
Oh, no... Father. Let's go to the police immediately.
Right.
Interrogation Room 1
You were asked to come with a letter?
"Be gone!
I want to put flowers to the small dying village. Stone monument's morning, at the base I will wait. Rausu"
Could this also be a part of the Sanuki code?
It's alike with that threatening letter from that phantom of the Konpira theatre.
That's right.
If you put it in normal hiragana...
"I want to talk about Renge. I will wait near the stone monument,"
Then, when you went to the crime scene...
Exactly!
But, why would someone do something like that?
That's because he's the phantom of the Konpira.
To get the heroine changed, sending threatening letters, dropping the paper lanterns on Romi-san...
...and changing her mouth wash... That's the only thing you can think of!
About that... Rausu-san is saying the exact same thing. That you called him there.
No, no! I'm not saying that Tamanosuke-kun is the phantom! Just... that he did call me there.
With this, night?
Be gone! I want to put flowers to the small dying village
Public park's morning, at the base I will wait
Tamanosuke
A same kind of letter with the exact same content was delivered to Tamanosuke-san, he says.
Only difference is, is that the park was a stone monument. And the sender, was you.
And so, did you go?
I went, alright. But Tamanosuke-kun didn't come.
Obviously. Because at that time he was at the crime scene.
Then, did you meet or see anyone at the park?
If that's the ease...
Romi-san?
So, you didn't notice Rausu-san, but you were at the park, right?
What were you doing?
I see...
Criminal affairs section
Konpira murder affair and searching investigations.
T-This is an honour, Mouri-san! To be able to investigate with you...!
You have evidence to suspect Itou Tamanosuke-kun, because he was holding a knife in his hand...
But Tamanosuke-san was unconscious, wasn't he?
It's possible that someone else made him hold it, right?
That's right.
That's it, that's it.
So, regarding about that...
Indeed there was a bump at the back of his head...
But he could've also fought with the victim, slipped and hit his head to the different level.
Different level?
Please.
Ah, yes. Right behind the fallen victim was a big memorial stone. The pedestal was the different level.
And the motive for the crime...?
It's obviously money.
They were staff for the previous chairman, and he wanted the chairman pay off his loan...
...and the victim was pushing it a bit too much. And then, finally...
Oh, no...
That's a lie, right?
One more thing. This is important.
Framing Rausu-san as the phantom of the Konpira and thus getting Renge-san's feelings toward himself.
That's exactly weird. Because, from the beginning, those two were...
All love-love. Even though it's mortifying. He has no need to do such a thing.
As I'm saying... Isn't that exactly the reason Rausu-san appeared?
You can't tell from a woman and a man by just looking the surface.
The manuscript is impossible now.
The chairman is a suspect...
It's such a shame.
She .wasn't,half-bad, Kataoka Renge.
You believe in Tamanousuke-kun, don't you?
The chairman believed in me too. That's why I was Romi-san's substitute.
That was wonderful.
But, I was scared. I thought I definitely couldn't do it!
Then, the angel of song... the phantom encouraged me!
What?
It isn't you, right?
Are you doubting me?
I don't know! What or who should I believe? I don't know.
If you are in this much anguish, you should just quit this play!
Renge. I want you to live with me.
No way.
I apologize. I am now only worried about chairman and only that...
Is that so? I understand. Then tell this to that chairman.
As a sponsor, the damage, is too great. It's regrettable, but as it is, I have to withdraw my hands from this.
Oh, no!
But, you are another stony. I will definitely not give up.
I'm sorry. We had no intention to eavesdrop, but...
Say, is it really true? That the phantom encouraged you?
That's why I can't be honestly happy. Because of the encouragement, I did well with the play.
That's not true. It's your true talent.
But changing the heroine to the new one, it's the same again, isn't it? With the Phantom of the Opera.
That's right. I'm afraid of that too.
Who exactly is it?
If it's not Tamanosuke-sama Then of course, Rausu-san!
Or rather a real phantom? A ghost? A monster!
No. That can't be.
This is it!
What is it, Conan-kun?
What is that?
That's right. A wireless one. Probably with this...
To tell you the truth, I heard the phantom as well that day.
Which means... In other words...
It means that the phantom of the Konpira is not a ghost or a monster.
I'm going to ask my father again.
I'll come too.
I have to hurry too.
There are things that were bothering me from the beginning.
The threatening Sanuki letters. Imitating the Phantom of the Opera to the phantom of the Konpira's behaviour.
If it either wanted to be found or someone witnessing it, I can understand the reasoning.
But a murder is going one step too far. Maybe there's a hint there...
A difference in level, huh?
This is the ideal place for the criminal to hide...
Father! Can't you do something?
After coming all this way... At this rate, Tamanosuke-sama's stage will be forever gone!
You don't have to worry about that.
Just now I got a call from Oonishi officer. Itou Tamanosuke was released as innocent.
In exchange, Rausu Tatsuhiko was apprehended with circumstantial evidence, it seems.
This time there is no mistake.
On the cane that is used to climb the stone steps to the crime scene...
...they found not only the victim's fingerprints, but Rausu Tatsuhiko's as well.
We think that they fought and his fingerprints got on the cane. Moreover, from his car...
Don't joke around! I don't know about any cane! And I don't remember putting those things in my car!
At yesterday's premiere a certain phantom made an appearance and caused a huge uproar.
Most of the guests thought it was part of the play, though...
Projector! Didn't you use that at that time, huh?
I see... It was done like that! D-Don't joke! I wouldn't do that!
If you use a remote control, even from your seat you can control the projector, you see.
Ridiculous.
And then, a tape-recorder and a transmitter. By hiding these, you did the phantoms voice to Renge-san?
To get her moved. We even found the speaker near the ceiling.
It was all to get her feelings to yourself! That's why you framed Tamanosuke-san. That's the way it is, right?
Don't joke!
Brother! Brother!
Onii-chan! = Honourable big brother, with a cute suffix.
I made you worry. And the others?
At the hotel.
Let's go. In any case, we have to think what to do with the show.
Yeah, Conan-kun, thank you!
The problem is, after all, that pedestal.
If the criminal attacked Nabeshima-san from up there...
Originally aired on: September 11th, 2006
Story based on manga: TV Original
That's right! Alibi... I have an alibi!
Too bad, but that also...
The speak practice in that park was a lie?
She had been scared of being dropped from the role.
"If I would be an important witness for the sponsor, Rausu..." she thought.
That's what she's saying.
What? Why would she do such a thing...?
Hm? What's the matter?
Excuse me. Could I go to the restroom?
One more thing. The projector that played the phantom.
Controlling it with a remote controller... That's possible from somewhere else too.
That's right. Like above the stage!
Ah, officer.
Ah, you are Mouri-san's...
That Mouri-san told me to ask you something...
Mouri-san did? What?
Where were Rausu-san's fingerprints on the cane?
Ah, that. They were on the tape.
Right. A different coloured and shining like daylight. Well, it was a mark after all.
From which store did it come?
About that... There hasn't been a store to claim it as theirs...
Because it was performance tape, I thought we would find it immediately, but...
Performance tape!
I see... I figured it out. I figured out the real culprit!
Rausu Tatsuhiko has escaped!
I'm deeply sorry. When I looked away for a little moment...
Call an alarm! Hurry.
You do not love me! Don't love me, don't love me!
Let me go! Let me go!
Then you shall have a destiny with never leaving my side! Destiny of never leaving my side!
Leaving these on purpose is also the same. But why purposely tell their whereabouts...?
But there's nothing but to go.
Conan-kun. You haven't seen Renge?
Tamanosuke-san.
These are...! Don't tell me that Rausu...
You were here! We looked for-you, Conan-kun.
Is something the matter, you two?
Renge! Where are you?
Renge-san!
Over there!
Rausu! Where is Renge? Wait, Rausu!
Let us die together, loved daughter. Together fall to the world of darkness!
Let me go! Let me go!
Wait, phantom!
Let her go!
Renge-chan!
Stop this immediately.
Sonoko...?
The phantom of the Konpira theatre... I know that you are not Rausu-san.
And that from the start your intention wasn't a murder.
Isn't that right? Let's finish this already, Romi-san.
What did you say?
No way!
That's right. From the beginning your behaviour was strange.
Because it was all your own charade!
That was acting? Why would you...?
Of course, to ensnare Rausu-san, right?
Romi-san... Why.
For revenge. To that man's father.
The deceased Rausu Companies' predecessor, right?
Because of that predecessor my father's business was taken...
An illness that destroyed his body... Mother following him soon after...
What did you say?
Being alone, the only thing I could do was to act!
First, I didn't think about a revenge... Then the offer for this play came.
Even now... Even now! I feel like my parents are shouting from the other side!
So then, my framing...
But at first, I had no intention to commit a murder.
At least, I wanted to destroy this play...
...and drag the name of the sponsor, the Rausu Companies, to the mud. That would've sufficed!
Then to put pressure on Renge-chan...
"This child can't do it. She will surely make a huge mistake at the stage", I thought.
But it was a huge success. I had forgotten...
...that Renge-chan is an actress. Like me, this child should have crumbled under the pressure...
On top of that, that man found me out.
With this my loan is cleared, right? Your thoughts?
That's right... I couldn't forgive the wrongdoers about my mother and father.
I should kill this one and make him take the blame! That's what I decided to do.
Then you called Nabeshima-san to the trap, hiding yourself behind the memorial stone and waited.
If the criminal would hit Nabeshima-san from that pedestal... A short person...
Yes. For example, even a woman it would be possible to hit Nabeshima-san with a deadly blow to his neck.
That performance tape that was on the cane, is something Rausu-san touched by coincidence.
You thought that the police would think...
...that Rausu-san was trying to steal Renge-san from Tamanosuke-san by framing him, right?
And then, you showed yourself to Rausu-san.
By taking back your testimony later, you made the suspicion on Rausu-san worse.
Plus, at the park while he was waiting for Tamanosuke-san, you put the projector into his trunk.
Yes...'But as expected, Rausu noticed it.
Come out! I know the real culprit!
If it's come to this, there is only one way for me, I thought.
Escaping the police, Rausu and Renge-chan were forced to commit a double suicide.
But to have that little lady to see through it all...
Don't! Romi-san!
You poor, misfortune man...
Damn it! Tamanosuke-san!
Conan-kun!
Romi-san. To take someone's life... Then even your own! Is that also because of your parents again?
Whatever the circumstances, you've done something that a human should never do!
You can't just close your eyes on that. Dying is unforgivable!
And by leaving such an easy clue, the pamphlet of this place, didn't you want someone to stop you?
To stop yourself from doing anything else...
What a relief. All thanks to Sonoko.
Did I do it again?
While you were sleeping, yes.
I'm sorry. I will continue with acting. With the chairman, forever.
Renge...
I understand.
This is fun!
This needs some serious kneading.
But somehow it feels good.
Koshi = Hip; the body of a noodle (Wordplay)
My hip is more tired than this udon dough. At least give me some beer, please!
He never changes.