[Simultaneous worldwide release on 30th October!]
[Witness the conclusion of the legend!]
*charcard* Bungo Tatei
(on-screen: Bungo Tatei, freelance photographer)
Charcard: Jōji Narukawa
*eyecatch*
*ED*
*NEP*
From a different point of view, even an enormous
wall obstructing you can become a large door.
An unexpected twist at
a movie's preview screening!
A false start to a case thanks to the Detective Boys!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
The game is over - You have no way out!
You are out, Dark Sasim!
What are you saying...
Can you catch a bigshot...
...like me?!
Don't think...
Feel, like water...
Simultaneous worldwide release on October 30th!
Witness the conclusion of the legend!
Witness this event of the century!
Yet another huge line...
It can't be helped.
It's the conclusion of a popular movie series that's been going for 20 years, after all.
But we were lucky to get tickets to a preview screening of a movie like that, weren't we?
You got them from Yōko Okino-chan, right?
Yeah. Be thankful!
I'm the one who got the old man to ask her, since I had nothing to lose.
Well—
Now, feel the power of Dark Sasim, master swordsman of the dark!
The master fencer of light, Bey Jū, won't allow such power!
I'll finish you off with the sun-sword of Kisasa, the female warrior of fire!
They're not exactly thanking me...
Come on! Line up properly!
So what? We have tickets, don't we?
We can just get in when the time comes without having to get in line.
But the seats are first-come-first-serve.
If you don't line up you won't get good seats.
Even so, when we think about how we're going to watch the movie before our friends...
We get excited!
We can't sit still!
Then you've gotta get into the parts well.
Bungo Tatei
Dark Sasim's two-sword style is wielded
with the large sword in the right hand, and the short sword in the left.
Also, Bey Jū's eyepatch is on the left eye.
And Kisasa's sun-sword is long, so
you have to stretch it like this!
So cool! It extends!
You're quite knowledgable.
Yeah...
Actually, I have the same goods as them...
Hmph, a fanboy.
So you like Star Blade too, mister?
You bet... Ever since I watched the first part when I was your age, I've been a big fan.
Also, I met my girlfriend at a preview screening of this series.
Did she not come today?
Ah, no... Some things happened.
Did you two have a fight?
Could you only get one ticket?!
No, it's not like that...
Though my friend Narukawa, who's also a fan of Star Blade,
kept calling me last night trying to convince me to give him this one.
Hey, mister!
Be careful holding it!
It's a very important ticket!
Sorry...
It's not long until the opening now!
Look, it's Dark Takio, the dark swordsman!
It's true!
Oh, right!
Then how about I take a photo of you with him?
Yeah!
Okay, now give me a big smile!
Thanks, mister.
You're welcome.
Sorry for the bother.
Not at all, in fact...
this is what I do.
Bungo Tatei-san?
A photographer, huh?
Yeah...
So I can assure you they'll come out good.
In return, want us to take a photo of you?
Really?
Then I'll do it with that camera...
Okay, cheese!
Thanks.
Then so I can send you the photo,
write your name and address in this notebook.
Ah, yeah, sure...
Er...
Did you write it down?
Y-Yeah...
Then, I'll send it to you once it's been developed and printed.
To this address, okay?
It's free, of course, so don't worry about it.
I can't wait to watch Dark Takio!
Yeah! How will this movie end?
He's so strong that I get excited when I see him!
Relax!
I'm sure Bey Jū and Kisasa will take care of Dark Takio!
Evil never triumphs, after all!
Eh?
Oh. Somebody's calling me.
Hello? Tatei here.
Ah, Narukawa?
What?!
Come to the Okuho II Building straight away?!
Yeah... Okay... Right. I'll go right away.
I apologise, but would you mind holding my place in the line?
I'll leave my things here.
No problem.
I'll be right back.
Hey you.
What'd that guy ask you?
Huh? What do you mean?
He didn't take your money or anything?
No, he just took a picture of us.
Before, he kept insisting on taking one of us, too.
Really annoying.
We thought he must've been some new type of swindler...
I guess we were wrong...
Jōji Narukawa
Hey, Narukawa!
Sorry I'm late!
Geez. What was that call before about?
You're the one who told me to call when I got here!
Sorry, it was a little misunderstanding.
If it's nothing important, I'll be going.
I don't have enough free time to waste it!
Relax, I'm sure you'll like this.
It's a present...
...that I've put my heart into, my friend.
That guy from before really said something odd.
Yeah.
Saying that Kisasa and Bey Jū would take out Dark Takio...
He said something like "evil will fall".
Hm? Isn't it usual for evil to be punished by allies of justice?
But Dark Takio turned good in the last movie!
He rebelled against Dark Sasim!
When he took off his skull mask, he was really handsome, so he has to be a good guy!
So why did he say that?
Maybe he'll betray them in this movie?
What?!
He probably didn't watch Star Blade V.
Hey! Don't search through other people's stuff!
See, two tickets for the preview screening from three years ago.
They were wedged in his notebook, unused.
What's that stain on one of the tickets?
Probably blood.
Though it looks like it's been there a while.
Blood?
What if... What if he had a bloody fight to get them?
I don't know about that.
But the owners of the tickets...
...were that Tatei guy, and the woman in this photo.
No doubt about it.
It's a photo taken inside a car.
The date on it is the same as the one on the tickets from three years ago.
Then why didn't they go to the preview screening?
No idea.
The lift?
It's at the end of the hallway, on the left.
Thanks.
Hey, Narukawa! The lift's on the left side of the hallway!
What?
We would've found it easily.
Sorry, I'm terrible with directions.
How odd...
What's odd?
They're just notes, aren't they?
Earlier, Tatei tore out the page where the Doc wrote his address on,
and put it in the case with the film, right?
I thought he did it to make sure he didn't forget what's on the film, but...
...all the films are numbered,
and it seems he details in this notebook what's on each film.
There's no remnants of other pages having been torn out of the notebook.
And all the finished films are inside this bag.
So why just that film?
Hey, show it to me already! What's this present you were talking about?
Don't be so impatient. I'll give it to you in a bit.
In just the right place.
Talking about the film, I remember something odd about it too...
After I took his photo, he rewound it straight away,
even though there was still enough film for 15 photos.
Isn't that odd?
A film taken out half-way...
Deliberately tearing out the Doc's address and putting it in his pocket.
And a pair of tickets for the preview screening from three years ago, tainted with blood.
A friend, also a fan of Star Blade, who called him away.
It can't be! He...
Hey, Tatei...
Is it okay to be here? This is the roof...
Do you remember, Narukawa?
Huh?
It was sunny, like today.
On the day of that preview screening,
when we met Ami.
I got it! I understand it now!
He must've come to the preview screening as part of his job!
So he took out the film to keep his professional photos separate!
Dummy.
If he was here on a job, he wouldn't have been lining up.
Oh, you're right.
Perhaps...
he no longer intends to come back.
What?
Hey, don't tell me you forgot. It was only six years ago.
Of course I remember. We met Ami at the preview screening for Star Blade IV.
We found her lost nearby, clenching her ticket, and escorted her to the cinema.
Six years ago, it was the same cinema as today...
and the same cinema as three years ago.
Wait. Are you...?
Are you still angry about the accident that killed Ami three years ago?!
True, I was the one driving.
But even the police said the truck driver was at fault!
He fell asleep and wasn't obeying the traffic lights!
Damn it!
Sure, I did oversleep that day and was in a hurry,
but I wasn't going too fast!
Why are you bringing up that again now, and in a place like this?
Here. It's the present I promised you.
Whoa! A ticket to the Star Blade preview screening!
You called me asking if I had any spare, right?
But you said you didn't last night...
Well, I got a job at the last minute so I can't go.
So I called you this morning.
Plus, I figured Ami'd be happy if I gave it to you here.
After all, the accident happened right near the base of this building.
Ah, yeah, that's right.
Ever since the accident, things've been tense between us.
So take it, as proof of our reconciliation!
Hey, also, there's only five minutes until the opening!
If you don't hurry, you won't make it to the pre-screening event!
Really?!
Well then, thank you, Tatei!
You're welcome! Make sure you watch it instead of me!
You betcha!
I'll burn the role of your favourite character, Dark Takio, into my eyes!
Though whatever happens, I'm sure Bey Jū and Kisasa will finish him off in the end!
I guess...
Next time we meet, I'll treat you to something for this!
Okay...
Ami...
Sorry for leaving you alone for three years...
Wait for me...
Now I too... can be with you...
It's useless...
Even if you jump now, it'll just be seen as suicide.
Because I'll testify...
That I saw you climb over the fence by yourself!
You...?
You're one of the kids who were in the line, right?
I think you're misunderstanding.
I just climbed up to take a look at the scenery.
The plot you wrote went like this...
First, you planned to pick a suitable group from the line
and make friends with them, saying you were a big Star Blade fan.
Take a picture of them with your camera...
Have them write their name and address in your notebook, saying you'd send them their picture...
Tear out that page, and place it in your pocket with the film.
You'd previously called a friend out,
telling him "Call me when you get there".
And once he did, you'd say his name and the place out loud, so those friends would remember.
After that, you'd leave the line,
telling them you'd be back soon...
You'd meet with your friend, make him come up to this roof,
then after handing him the ticket you would just have to jump off.
Well, the ones you picked for the role of your friends were us...
So when our address and photo were discovered on your corpse,
of course the police would contact us...
And hearing us testify that you were surely a movie fan,
and your friend who called you wanted your ticket...
Once they confirmed that your friend attended the preview screening with a ticket with your fingerprints on...
The police would conclude...
That your friend called you here right before the preview screening, pushed you off the roof of this building, and stole your ticket!
Incidentally, you deliberately asked where the lift was
to make sure that they'd remember you were with a friend.
And you deliberately dropped the ticket so my friend's fingerprints would get on it.
After the preview screening,
when the police recover the tickets,
if a ticket shows up with your, your friend's, and my friend's fingerprints on it...
it'll prove that you had the ticket today when you met us.
You're smart, boy.
But will the police really believe the testimony and deductions of a single boy?!
It'll be fine!
Even if they don't believe one of us,
there's five of us!
We'll make them believe!
Also, we passed by someone who looks like they might be a friend of yours.
By now, he'll have left the building and be on his way to the cinema.
Even if you were to jump now, time-wise it'd be impossible, so your trick won't work.
Too bad for you.
Damn...
You don't understand how I feel...
We know!
Three years ago, he was driving the car your girlfriend was in.
There was an accident, and she died. That's your motive, right?
How do you know that?!
Your notebook had tickets and a photo.
The tickets were for the preview screening of Star Blade V, from three years ago.
The photo shows you and a girl as a couple, riding in a car's back seat.
Most likely, the photo was taken by the driver, a friend who'd push the shutter for you.
Furthermore, there was blood on one of the tickets
and the photo had the same date as the preview screening, so I got a general idea.
That day, you couldn't attend the preview screening because of an accident,
and it's likely that the cause was the driver,
the friend you tried to make out to be a killer!
Yeah, that's right...
If he hadn't overslept that day...
If only he'd come at the time we'd arranged...
We'd never have crossed paths with that damn truck...
But that resentment's unjustified.
I know! I've been telling myself that over and over again to restrain my heart!
But then he called me for the first time in 3 years!
Just to ask me if I happened to have an extra ticket to Star Blade VI!
And then he happily took that ticket and headed off to the cinema...
As if he forgot what happened three years ago.
His mind full of Dark Takio and Bey Jū's confrontation...
Those two aren't gonna fight!
Dark Takio's on Bey Jū's side now!
I see...
Neither he nor his friend got to watch Star Blade V...
Then, if he wanted the ticket, that means...
Hey, was the accident three years ago close by?
Yeah... That's why I was gonna jump from this building...
Take me there!
Eh?
That's the guy we passed by leaving the building.
But that's not the way to the cinema...
Narukawa...
Well? Where was the accident?
Over there.
The truck hit us and threw us against this guard rail.
Huh? There's something there.
I knew it.
What is it?
The ticket to the preview screening of Star Blade VI!
There's another ticket here, from three years ago.
This one's weathered from wind and rain though.
But... why did he...?
Dummy!
He wanted that woman to see it!
By leaving them as an offering where she died, they might make it to heaven!
Furthermore, the fact that he didn't mention it to you...
...indicates he was probably in love with her too.
He loved your girlfriend... just as much as you did.
I don't mind myself, but the event before the screening ends in three minutes.
Hey, come with us to the preview screening!
You can watch the movie and tell Ami about it!
We happen to have a spare ticket!
Since the old man passed on watching it...
Thanks.
But I'll leave it.
I haven't watched V yet.
And well...
I'll buy Star Blade V and VI's DVDs,
and watch them at his place.
They're late.
The mini-cars, figures and books lined up on the shelves...
...they're almost all upside down.
Why?
The Upside-Down Conclusion
(Part I)
On the next Conan: The Upside-Down Conclusion (Part I)
Next Conan's Hint: Collection!
Next time, a strange collector shows up!
Hey, Haibara, what do you collect?
That's a secret.