From a different point of view, even an imposing
wall blocking your path is just a large door.
A baseball came flying in, and a house
becomes a case flipped on its head!
Something's not right about this room!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but
has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Sensei!
Toshihisa Manda (53)
Novelist
Well, if it isn't the editor, Shimaki-kun.
Geez, don't Well, if it isn't Shimaki-kun me!
So, what are you here about?
W-What are you saying, Sensei?!
I'm just joking, don't worry.
Don't scare me like that...
It's about the manuscript, right?
Yes, that's right, Manda-sensei...
I'm begging you, don't play jokes on me...
This is a real problem!
The printers can only wait two more hours!
Two hours will be more than enough!
Two hours?
I just have one hurdle left to jump,
and after that, it just leaves the epilogue.
Really?
Of course.
Please trust me. We've known each other so long.
Hey, Novel-kun!
I'm counting on you to keep an eye on Sensei!
Don't let him make a run for it!
If he tries to get away, bite him!
I'll be waiting in the lobby by the lifts.
Please call me when you're done!
Sure, will do.
Yes... Two more hours...
Yes.
Seems like he can pull it off.
Yeah, that's what he said.
It'll probably be all right...
Yeah, don't worry.
Here's what he wrote...
The Ace of Teitan Primary School's Class 1-B,
the prince of pitchers, Genta Kojima,
aims to remain undefeated!
Two outs, bases loaded.
Mitsuhiko Tsubaraya's in full form!
And here's the first pitch!
Got it!
I did it!
I'm counting on you, Edogawa-kun.
Counting... for what?
The ball, the ball!
A-All right!
Leave it to me!
You got it!
That was awesome, Conan-kun!
Yes... if we were playing football.
You have to catch the ball in your glove!
This isn't football!
You got something against baseball, Conan?
That's right, Conan-kun!
Take this seriously, geez!
My bad, my bad...
What am I supposed to do?
After years of playing football, I'm used to doing everything with my legs...
Sensei...
I've been waiting for you...
They got my neck on the line now...
Manda-sensei...
Those clothes...
Kohei Haramoto (28)
Manda's protegé
Did you sneak out of a hotel again...
...disguised as a valet?
You really like doing that, don't you?
Yeah, they tried to lock me up.
This was the quickest way to get away.
This way, nobody noticed me.
Hey, you brought Novel-kun with you!
Novel, Novel!
That's a kitty... It's me...
I couldn't leave him. Novel
panics if one of us isn't around.
More importantly...
...have you finished the manuscript?
Yeah, I polished it off...
...six hours ago!
Six hours ago?!
But when I called you from the hotel, you said you just needed a bit more time!
I was just messing with you. Your voice sounds hilarious when you're desperate.
Come on, Haramoto-kun...
Can't I at least have a little fun?
Being your ghostwriter can get stressful, you know.
But as long as you pay me the big bucks...
I've got no complaints!
Here!
Your latest novel!
With a happy ending, just as you requested!
Ah, thank you!
So, er... Did you talk to your editor about me?
Once I hand this off to him, we're going to have a meeting at my place to discuss the next piece.
I'll bring him across the street to meet you after that.
Really? Thank you so much! I'm so glad!
But once you've had your début,
I'll probably have to retire.
Don't worry, I can keep ghosting for you!
I'll be writing detective novels, which is nothing like what you write!
I'll even use a different writing style.
A different...
To be honest, I'm almost done...
with my début novel!
Want to give it a lookover? You'll see, it really feels like it was written by somebody else.
Soon I'll be a real novelist!
And if my work sells, I'll have more
money for my collections...
Oh, yeah. You are quite the collector, aren't you?
Yeah.
I've loved collecting stuff since I was a kid.
But the item I want now...
...is the Akutayama Award for New Writers!
You're one of the judges, so I'm a shoo-in, right?
If I win that one, collecting other
awards will be a piece of cake!
Speaking of collections, I finally got something else I've been missing!
Oh?
It feels so good...
...to complete the set!
That's nice to hear...
Working —
Do Not Enter!
Come on, Novel! Time to head back to the hotel...
Novel?
Novel? Novel?
Where are you, Novel?
Come out!
Novel? Novel!
Novel? Novel?
Novel! Novel!
Where are you, Novel?!
Shoot!
I've got to hurry... To hurry back to the hotel...
Sensei? Manda-sensei?
If I don't get back to the hotel,
Sensei! Sensei!
my alibi...
Sensei! Manda-sensei!
What now?
Sensei! It's been two hours!
What do I do now?
Sensei! Manda-sensei!
Sensei?
Geez, what a nuisance.
I was just going over my last revision!
Oh... I see! Sorry about that.
Frankly, I've impressed even myself this time!
Here.
Thank you so much!
And thanks for the hard work!
Say, is Novel-kun okay?
He always comes out to greet me.
He's awfully quiet...
Oh...
He's sleeping in his carrier.
In his carrier...
Seems that way.
Well, I'd better get back to the office to look this over!
Why don't you read it in my room and e-mail it to the printer from here?
That'll save you some time.
Afterwards, we can go to my place
and talk about my next novel.
I didn't think you had anything planned after this...
I'm sure you'll enjoy it.
It's an entirely new genre for me.
A mystery?
But you specialize in period fiction!
You're not pulling my leg, are you?
Nah.
But I've always wanted to challenge
myself with a mystery novel.
You have?
I'm looking forward to it.
I can't wait to read it!
Right, right?
Sensei, please, tell me more about it!
I've already thought up a detective character.
I'll tell you all about it at the house.
Oh, no, tell me! Don't leave me hanging.
Well... well...
Novel-kun is awfully quiet today...
Did something happen?
U-Uh, well...
He was running around all day...
...so he must be tired.
No need to worry.
You're right...
Okay, hold on a minute.
I need to tidy up a bit...
Oh, sure. I'll wait.
Novel!
Novel! Novel!
Ah, Novel, you're back! Good boy!
Now it's all in place.
I've completed the perfect crime...
Right, Novel?
What?
W-What was that sound?
I think a window broke in the house across the street.
Looks like some kids were playing baseball and hit a ball into a window.
What?!
Geez...
You swing too hard, Genta-kun!
I didn't do it on purpose! It bounced away!
You can't tell the ball where it can go.
Nobody's answering the door.
But it looks like somebody's at home...
Maybe the ball hit the person inside the house and knocked them out!
There's no way to know without going inside.
Huh?
Huh? Err...
Haibara-san?
I had a feeling it was unlocked.
Excuse us...
Well, it's a good excuse to go in, but...
The room the ball entered must be...
H-Hey, Conan!
Should we go in?
Conan-kun, this is a home invasion.
Conan-kun!
Haibara-san?!
Looks like we've got no other choice, don't you think?
Excuse us!
Excuse me...
Is anyone home?
Excuse me!
We're not suspicious people...
Huh? Something's weird about this room...
Yes, but I can't put my finger on it...
Isn't it obvious?
Over there.
The toy cars on the shelves...
The figures...
...and the books...
...are almost all upside-down.
But why?
Did my ball do this?
Maybe your ball warped the space inside the house, causing a supernatural phenomenon...
Mitsuhiko, something is off,
but don't get too carried away.
The ball Genta hit...
I won't lose this time!
Here it comes, Genta-kun! Hit it if you can!
I can hit anything!
Edogawa-kun!
Conan-kun!
Oh, crap!
That was a pretty strong one!
Oh, geez, Genta hit it really hard!
Genta's ball just happened to
go in through an open window.
But we heard something smash!
The ball must've hit a vase or something.
A-Are you serious?
What if it's really expensive?
And I've already blown my allowance this week...
To know how much whatever we broke costs,
we'll have to ask whoever lives here.
The ball should be in this room...
Of course...
That's just if the guy who lives here...
...can still talk.
Well?
It's no use.
Given the rigor mortis, he's probably been dead for an hour or two.
I see fragments from a vase
scattered around the body.
I bet he was hit on the back of the head.
You don't mean...
The ball I hit bumped into the vase...
...and knocked it onto the guy's head?
G-Genta-kun...
I'm doomed!
What do I do? What do I do?!
What now?!
Don't be an idiot!
You hit that ball just a few minutes ago!
Not an hour ago, right?
What now? What... now?
Looks like your ball hit that vase over there.
That's good, right, Genta?
What a relief...
Then this means someone struck him from behind...
Yeah. He was hit with this vase
while he was looking through this drawer.
How do you know that he
was looking through that drawer?
Look at the edge of the drawer. It's dented!
The body collapsed on it after he was hit from behind!
He'd probably opened the drawer to either put something in or to take something out!
I see...
You're so smart, Conan-kun!
It's the room next door that confuses me.
Yeah. Most of the toys, models and books on the shelves are turned upside-down.
If the killer did that, then what was it for?
H-Hey!
What are you kids doing here?
H-Haramoto-kun?!
Is that Haramoto-kun on the floor?!
Hey, Haramoto-kun!
Haramoto-kun!
What are you doing?
Call the police and an ambulance!
S-Sure, right away!
You kids need to clear out!
Uh... Understood.
Kitty!
How'd you get in here?
Kitty...
Don't touch my cat!
C'mon, out! Out!
You'll have to give a report when the police arrive.
What's his problem?
He didn't have to be that rude to us.
Tell me about it.
Got it?
Uh, yeah...
Never mind that.
Didn't you notice yet?
Yes.
There's something even stranger about this room!
Look at the shelves!
The dolls, the miniature cars and the books...
They're all upside-down!
But why?
I get it!
Haramoto-san didn't turn
them upside down, the killer did!
On the next Conan:
Next Conan's Hint: An unfinished manuscript!
Look, an unfinished manuscript!
Genta-kun, it's completely blank!
That's why it's unfinished.