From a different point of view, even an imposing
wall blocking your path is just a large door.
We finally figured out the upside-down trick!
An incomplete novel, and a cornered killer!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but
has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
My name is Toshihisa Manda, and I’m a novelist who was locked in a hotel in order to finish a novel.
I sneaked out of the hotel
and murdered my disciple
and ghostwriter, Kohei Haramoto.
After that, I snuck back to the hotel
in order to forge an alibi.
While we were playing baseball,
we lost control of the ball, which went flying into Haramoto-san’s house.
Then, we went to his room…
…where we found him murdered.
An Upside-Down Conclusion
Part II
I see…
You guys came to get your ball,
and when you reached this room,
you found this man on the floor
with blood around his head.
He was probably murdered
during an attempted theft.
But the room doesn’t look particularly messy.
I think it was somebody he knew!
What?
See?
There’s a sign on the door outside saying “Do not enter!”
Right. So?
This means somebody’s on the other side of the door writing.
Yeah! And if you open the door, you’ll get spotted right away!
There’d be no way to get behind him without him noticing!
If it was me, I’d start making some noise on purpose, and once the victim came out of the room,
I’d be waiting for him with the weapon ready to strike.
You’re scary, Ai-chan…
The point is, Haramoto-san must’ve let the killer in himself!
It was someone he knew… Like this man here!
What did the forensics say was the estimated time of death?
Roughly two hours ago, around 3pm.
Where were you at that time?
I was locked up in a room at the New Beika Hotel so I could finish my latest novel.
The New Beika Hotel isn’t far from here.
It’d only take a couple of minutes by car or less than ten minutes by bike.
Shimaki-san, were you with him?
No, I was sitting in front of the lifts next to the room where Sensei was.
But he’d have to pass through there to leave the hotel.
And I don’t think Sensei’s
that good at sneaking out.
When did he finish the novel?
Oh, geez! Don’t tell me you suspect me of murder!
No, no! Just following procedure, sir!
Well?
Yes. Well, he finished the novel around 4pm.
After that, I looked over it in his hotel room, and took a taxi with him to his home, to talk about his next novel.
I see.
Do you know if Haramoto-san might have any friends with grudges against him?
Beats me. He was a private person.
He told me he wanted to be a novelist,
so I gave him jobs like revising my manuscripts and the like.
That’s why you’ll find many of my manuscripts on his computer,
including ones I never finished.
A while ago, you mentioned that you’re the one who let him live here.
Yes. I used to live here with my family.
But it got too small for us, so we built a new house across the street.
Well, my sons have all grown up and my wife has passed on, so I live alone now.
I didn’t want to demolish this house, so I let him live here.
This place is pretty clean for a bachelor pad.
A housekeeper comes in once a week…
But…
I think Haramoto-san likes to keep things tidy!
Look, there’s nothing in this drawer but a mirror!
Hey, Conan-kun!
Oh, that’s funny!
There’s blood and broken pieces of vase on the mirror…
…but the middle of the drawer is clean!
Almost like there was something here…
What?
Maybe the murderer was after the contents of this drawer!
Do you have any idea what it might be, Manda-san?
Er… No…
Hey…
Anyway, isn’t it about time you noticed something really odd?
That’s right! There’s something even stranger about this room!
Stranger?
Look around this room!
Look at the shelves!
The miniature cars…
…the dolls…
…the books…
They’re all upside-down!
The kids are right…
But why?
What?
A cat!
Is that your cat?
You can’t let your cat run around a crime scene!
Sorry… I was so focused on this that I forgot all about him.
I-Inspector! The back door!
Hey! Who are you?
This is a private residence!
Ichimura-san!
Oh… You’re here too?
What?! Haramoto-san was…?!
I-It wasn’t me! I’m just the housekeeper!
Oh, you’re the one.
Then, do you have any idea…
Yes?
Oh… It’s probably one of Haramoto-san’s pranks.
Pranks?
Yes. He was always pulling ridiculous pranks.
Like piling his slippers in a tower…
…or loosening all the light bulbs in the house so they wouldn’t turn on…
…or leaving video tapes in a row in the hall causing a domino effect.
Then he’d spy on my reaction with a creepy grin.
Then he’d just look at me with an innocent face while I have to clean everything up.
That’s why I’m sure this is just more of the same. Because he knew I’d be arriving at this time.
What, it’s just a prank?
But it makes sense it’s a prank.
Yes. Apparently he was pretty childish.
Sheesh, we thought it was some kind of trick.
No.
Haramoto-san didn’t turn them upside-down.
The killer did!
What?
Look at those books!
The covers are crumpled up, see?
Whoever turned them over did it in a hurry!
There are toy cars with their side mirrors broken off
and figurines that have fallen out of their boxes…
This was apparently a very important
collection to Haramoto-san.
Even if he wanted to prank the housekeeper, I’m sure he’d be more careful.
I see. The housekeeper arrived roughly two hours after the estimated time of death.
He knew when to expect her, so there wouldn’t be any rush to set this up.
Yeah.
But why would the killer do this?
Most likely, it was to hide something.
Yeah.
It’d stand out if one thing was turned upside-down…
…so the murderer turned everything over to hide it.
Er, may I leave?
It’s time I got back to the editorial office.
You can come back once you’ve finished proofreading, right?
I still want to talk about my next book!
Sensei, I really don’t think it’s appropriate to discuss a mystery novel on a day like this!
Mystery?
I thought you wrote period novels…
At my age, it’s time to try something new.
In fact, I don’t have much left to do on this one.
Come to think of it, even what’s on the shelf seems rather well lined-up…
Yeah… More than half of them are mystery novels.
That’s right. Haramoto-san loved detective novels.
He always said his debut would be with one!
He had such an interesting idea for the detective…
Say, Ichimura-san! Did he ask you to bring anything today?
You know…
He used to send you out to shop for things for his collections.
Especially when he didn’t have time to get out of the house.
Well, today…
He wanted me to call him in the morning.
Oh, right! He wanted me to set up a dental appointment for him.
I see…
It’s just that when I called him from the hotel earlier…
…he was telling me how excited he was to complete some set.
But don’t worry. He was probably talking about one of his absurd collections.
You called him today?
Yeah.
I often call him when I’m stuck in work… for a change of pace…
How did he sound?
Like his usual self.
I see…
What do you see?
Have you figured out who the killer is?
Yeah…
The murderer didn’t hide something by turning things upside-down.
He thought he could hide it
by turning them upside-down!
The killer didn’t hide something by turning stuff upside-down…
…but he thought he’d hide it by turning stuff upside-down?
To be more exact, he thought it’d be hidden.
Hidden…
What was it?
As proof, we have what the killer said to interrupt just before it could come out.
Wait, you mean…
He’s the killer?
I think so.
I’ll come back after proofing this manuscript at the office.
Then, may I go too?
I want to start preparing for a meeting, and want to drop off my cat.
Fine…
Feel free to call me if anything comes up, I live right across the street.
He’s making a run for it!
Should we let him?
Hey! Your next book will be your first detective novel, right?
Right.
I can’t wait to read it! I just love mysteries!
I wonder if it’s on Haramoto-san’s PC.
I don’t know…
Why are you cheering him on?
Aren’t you gonna corner him?
Knowing you, I’m sure you’re up to something.
But isn’t it time you wiped that smug grin off your face?
Okay, okay! I’ll tell you the plan.
But only if you agree to help!
Yeah!
Of course!
His protegé’s murdered,
and he has the nerve to set up a meeting to talk about a mystery novel.
Yeah.
Say, what about me?
Oh, right.
This toy car is broken!
Yes, the side mirror has snapped off.
I didn’t do it!
Looks like the person who moved the items was in a hurry.
But that doesn’t make sense.
Haramoto-san did this to play a prank on the housekeeper, right?
Right. Because he knew she’d be arriving at 5 PM.
This collection probably wasn’t all that important to him.
But that novel writer told us…
…how excited Haramoto-san was about getting a complete set!
The question is, what collection did he complete?
Yeah, but from those words alone, there’s no way to know…
He could be talking about cars or figurines or sets of books…
“Complete set”?
“In a hurry”?
Huh? You got a cold?
Nah, it’s the cat hair! It’s all over this room…
Cat hair?
That’s right. Manda-san
let his cat run around this room
even while the police were searching the area.
No wonder there’s so much cat hair!
I think Manda-san is mean…
What makes you say that?
He came here because he heard something break,
and then saw us entering here,
so he followed us in case we were dangerous.
I’d never bring my kitty into danger like that!
Even if I did, I’d keep him in his carrier!
He could step on something sharp and hurt himself!
Yeah.
It’s like he let his cat run around on purpose.
Let his cat run around on purpose?
“Meanwhile, Detective Yako Hyakki allowed a smile to paint itself upon his harshly closed lips.”
“Naturally, accepting the investigator’s word…”
This is as far as it goes…
You took longer than expected.
Er, yes, sorry…
I ran into some trouble.
W-Well, Sensei, why don’t you tell me about this detective novel?
You say you’ve already started work on it?
Yeah. In fact, I’m almost to the end.
I’m just wondering how to wrap it up.
After all, in this murder case,
the detective is the victim.
What?
You see, the story is about an attorney who’s murdered at the beginning of the novel.
She possesses the body of a friend of hers, a police detective, to solve her own murder.
Ah… That sounds interesting.
Our attorney/detective’s
name is Yako Hyakki.
Has a ring to it, don’t you think?
Who could it be at this hour?
I-Inspector…
I’m sorry, but could this wait until after my meeting?
We think you can spare us the time.
You see, we’ve solved the case.
S-Solved the case?
You know who did it?
Yes.
The person who murdered Haramoto-san…
…was you, Manda-san.
I can’t believe it!
Manda-san, the famous novelist, is a murderer?
But wasn’t Manda-san locked in his hotel room working since the previous night,
and thus would still be there at 3pm,
the time of the crime?
The editor, Shimaki-san, probably wasn’t watching the door the whole time,
so he probably snuck out in disguise as a bellhop or something like that.
Then he probably took a bicycle or something similar he’d prepared in advance to Haramoto-san’s house.
In a careless moment, he beat him to death with a vase,
and rushed back to the hotel to create a perfect alibi.
But there was a problem.
Right. The cat you had with you.
It ran away from the room where the crime took place to the adjacent room.
You searched the house, but the cat was hiding somewhere.
That’s when you remembered something.
That before you killed Haramoto-san,
he’d mentioned finally having a “complete set” of something.
You live across the street from Haramoto-san.
You knew that if you left the back door open, the cat would come back to your house when it got hungry.
But before that, he’d walk all around the house, all over the collection that Haramoto-san had just finished today.
If we found those cat hairs, we’d have proof you’d come to this house today.
After all, you and your cat
were supposed to have been locked up working in that hotel room since the night before!
That’s when you came up with an idea.
If you turned all of his collectibles upside-down,
then when the housekeeper came in two hours and set everything right,
she’d knock the cat hair off the items!
Yeah… But what if the cat hair stayed on anyway?
It wouldn’t need to fall off!
He just needed Ichimura-san to tell the police she’d touched the items!
The cat hair on the floor could’ve got stuck on the toy cars while she was flipping them back.
But why bother to turn
everything upside-down?
Why not just knock things to the floor?
But that wouldn’t look like a prank.
If she thought it was the work of a thief,
she might call the police without touching the crime scene, ruining the plan.
But we went into the room before the housekeeper got there!
That’s right! That’s why
Manda-san was so nervous.
So he had to use his brain a bit.
Manda-san saw us entering that house,
so he hurried over with his cat…
…and let it run around the house so it could get hair on everything!
So that’s why he got upset when we tried to pick the cat up!
If we held the cat until the police came, his plan wouldn’t have worked.
But he still managed to cover up the evidence.
With no proof, he can say you’re just making everything up.
Yeah, but I left a perfect bait.
Wonderful deduction, Inspector!
I advise you to become a mystery novelist!
But where’s the proof? If you don’t have any proof, you can’t arrest me!
Of course, I’m not the killer.
But I think I’ll use that deduction in my next novel.
Speaking of mystery novels, we found one on Haramoto-san’s computer.
An unfinished manuscript
starring a ghost detective…
…named Yako Hyakki!
What?
We asked Shimaki-san, your editor, to cooperate with us and wired his clothing.
We heard you’re working on a novel…
…about a ghost detective with the same name!
I-I told you, didn’t I?
Haramoto kept copies of all my rough drafts!
So you wrote that manuscript?
O-Of course!
To be honest, the children were playing on the computer when they stumbled upon the novel.
My men and I read it along with them, hoping it might contain some clue to Haramoto’s murder.
But I have to admit I wasn’t sharp enough to guess the ending.
Maybe you’d be kind enough to tell me who the murderer in the story is, and the trick that was used.
Ah, that…
Of course, you wouldn’t let us see the CD case with the CD you stole from Haramoto-san’s drawer,
as that case should still have his blood on it.
You were reading it just now, weren’t you?
As after returning from the hotel,
you found Haramoto-san’s body and didn’t come back home until now,
as you were with your editor since then, leaving you with no time to read it beforehand.
And despite that, you were telling Shimaki-san the entire story just now.
Don’t tell me that boy…
I can’t wait to read it!
I wonder if it’s on Haramoto-san’s PC.
Did he push me to read the manuscript right away so I wouldn’t have time to hide the disc?
That CD and its case…
They’re in your house, aren’t they?
Sensei!
I’m no sensei anymore.
Just an old man whose fire went out after his wife’s passing.
The truth is, my work over the last two to three years was written by Haramoto-kun!
At first I heavily revised his drafts
before publishing them.
But then he started complaining
about my revisions.
And lately, I couldn’t find anything
wrong with his work.
And finally…
Please… Just stay in the bleachers and let me do my stuff.
You’ve already passed the torch.
Those words were so depressing and humiliating…
I couldn’t forgive him for that.
Then why did you steal his mystery novel?
I was overcome with the idea that
I could write it better than he could.
But I lost.
No matter how much I think,
I have no idea who the killer was, or what trick he used.
I guess I never was cut out to be a mystery writer…
akogare ga deai ni kawatta hi yume to yume ga tsunagatta
obienagara utsumuki aruita hi
furimukeba kimi ga ita
nagareboshi hitotsu mitsuketa yo
tachidomatta toki ni wa ichi-ban ni dakishimete hoshii
hoshizora ni
mô kimi dake o hanashitari wa shinai
namida wa yesterday
kimi ga kureta kotoba de
egao de nemuri ni tsuku made
mô kimi dake o hanashitari wa shinai
kanashimi wa yesterday
kimi ga kureta kotoba de
egao de nemuri ni tsuku made
So it was the housekeeper’s comments who gave you the clue?
Yeah.
Yeah, when she was trying to tell us about the detective that Haramoto-san came up with,
Manda-san interrupted her.
That's when I realised he was trying
to steal Haramoto-san’s work!
That just leaves one mystery.
You mean the murderer in the novel?
No! The “complete set”
Haramoto-san was talking about!
Oh, that.
He was probably talking about his teeth!
Teeth?
The housekeeper, Ichimura-san, said she’d made a dental appointment for him.
And there was a mirror inside the drawer Haramoto-san was looking into when Manda-san killed him.
Besides, among the vase’s fragments inside the drawer, there was a dental piece.
Why didn’t you tell Inspector Megure about something this important?
Because he already knew who the killer was.
Besides, forensics will tell him that.
ha
Yes, teeth.
A death threat?
The writer was murdered
by a character from her novel?
The killer must be trying
to confuse the investigators.
But was that the only objective?
The Mystery Novel I Loved
On the next Conan:
Next Conan’s Hint: Sushi ginger.
Look forward to the next episode!
What kind of fish is that?
It’s ginger, you dummy.
shôga
You really are hopeless.
shô ga nai