From a different point of view, even an imposing
wall blocking your path is just a large door.
A character from a mystery novel
threatens the life of its author.
Is this fiction, or non-fiction?
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but
has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
“Pro Football, 2006”
“How to Win at Horse Racing”
I’m being called!
Uncle?
Excuse me! Coming through!
Inspector!
Seems it’s my turn. Let’s go!
- Wait! Inspector!
- Uncle!
You sure seem to have a lot of free time…
Well, since we’re here anyway, please let us help with the investigation.
Otherwise, this brat might cry.
Well, Inspector, what kind of case is this?
A murder.
The victim is the person who lived in this flat.
Murako Saikawa-san, age 65.
She lived alone.
Apparently she was a novelist.
Does the name sound familiar, Mouri-kun?
Murako Saikawa?
I seem to recall that long ago, there was a novelist by that name.
Murako Saikawa…
An incredible mystery novelist,
famous for years.
Death was instantaneous, caused by
a blow to the head with a decorative object.
From what was determined
during the investigation,
she was murdered last night,
approximately between 7 and 9pm.
We might get a more accurate estimated time of death once the autopsy is concluded.
Who’d want to murder a famous mystery novelist, and why?
Inspector, the body was found by two people.
My name’s Tono.
Shun’ichi Tono (26)
Editor at Labyrinth Publications
I work at Labyrinth Publications,
and I was Saikawa-sensei’s editor.
And this is the block of flats’ manager.
Keiso Murata (55)
Pearl Block of Flats Manager
My name’s Murata.
Please tell us again exactly
how you found the body.
This morning, I went over
to pick up some documents.
When I met up with her yesterday, we’d agreed I’d come by to pick them up.
However, no matter how often I kept ringing the intercom, nobody came to the door.
I felt that was kind of strange,
so I asked the manager to use his key to open the door for me, and…
Sensei!
And then…
Sensei was…
I see.
Tono-san, you were at Saikawa-san’s home yesterday, too?
Yes. I was there from early in the evening until around 8pm.
The estimated time of death was between 7 and 9.
Hey, you’ve got really great instincts!
It’s odd that you knew something was up
just because nobody answered the intercom.
It really does sound strange.
Oh, that’s because a couple of days ago,
Sensei received this.
A postcard…
“Dear Murako Saikawa-sensei,
the next piece I will be adding to my collection will be your life.
I will come to take it soon.”
A death threat?
It was sent by a… “Taniyoshi Ohebi”.
It’s read “Ryo Orochiya”.
Ryo Orochiya? That’s insane!
Who’s this “Ryo Orochiya”?
He’s a criminal mastermind,
from Saikawa-sensei’s biggest novel.
A character from her novel?
The novelist was murdered by a character from her novel?
Of course not!
That’s ridiculous!
Right.
But that does seem to be the case.
This is a trick by the killer.
He did it to confuse the investigators.
To confuse the investigators?
But was that the only objective?
Murata-san,
if you have an empty flat, we’d appreciate it.
We’d like to use it as a base of operations for our investigation.
Of course.
Chiba.
Yes, sir.
Tono-san, you may have been the last person to see the victim alive.
Could you stay with
us for a little longer?
Of course.
Inspector!
They said the flat was locked, right?
I suppose the killer left it locked last night, before escaping.
That way, they could delay the time it took to find the body.
But from what I understand, in this block, each tenant gets two keys.
And Saikawa-san’s two keys were found inside the flat, weren’t they?
Did the killer have a copy of the key?
Right. That means there’s a limited number of people who could’ve used such a key.
The editor who came to meet her might have one.
Yes, he could’ve had one made.
And the manager has one, too.
This is Megure.
Understood.
What was it?
That was Kawanaka-kun, he just finished interrogating all the neighbours.
Apparently, a few days ago, the victim
and the manager had a very heated row.
They seem to be our main suspects.
Tono-san, who was visiting the victim up until the estimated time of death.
And Murata-san,
who had a potential motive.
Furthermore, either of them could’ve had a copy of the key made.
Besides, if either of them is the killer,
then it’s no coincidence that they were the ones who found the victim.
By being the first to arrive,
the killer could’ve come inside
and got rid of any evidence he might’ve left the previous night.
Yes, it’s likely.
What is it?
It’s just remnants of ginger.
Saikawa-sensei hated fresh ginger.
She always said she couldn’t
stand its bittersweet taste.
I suppose she took all of the ginger from the sushi she ordered last night, and threw it away.
She ordered sushi for dinner last night?
Yes, she asked me for it,
and I ordered it over the phone.
Inspector, we have the entire floor available for us.
I see, good job.
Well then, Tono-san, please tell us everything that happened last night, in detail.
Of course.
If she threw it away last night,
then it’s been over half a day since.
In that case, most likely…
Saikawa-san was killed
between 7 and 9pm yesterday.
I arrived to see her at around 6:30pm.
Though she wasn’t doing it
professionally anymore,
she still kept writing a lot of mystery novels.
We were together for about an hour, talking about the possibility of publishing them all as a collection.
Yes, Saikawa.
At the Pearl block of flats.
The usual order, for one person.
The order arrived at around 8pm.
Since I had other business
to deal with, I left afterwards.
I’ll come to pick up the documents
tomorrow morning.
Thank you.
If you’ll excuse me…
Around a quarter to 9, I met up with some friends in front of the station,
and stayed with them
until deep into the night.
Until deep into the night.
We’ll confirm this with your friends.
I’m perfectly aware that I’m a suspect.
But why would I do it?
She was a treasure
among mystery novelists.
I didn’t have a row with Saikawa-san!
People must’ve misunderstood.
That may be the case.
Either way, tell me about last night.
I was in the manager’s quarters the whole time.
I was alone, so I don’t have any witness to confirm it for me.
The manager’s hiding something.
The key point is at 8pm.
From 7 to 8, Tono-san could’ve committed the crime.
And after 8, it could’ve been Murata-san.
Either way, split up and investigate.
Right!
Saikawa-sensei?
We were told she ordered
sushi from here last night.
Oh, no! How could I screw up this bad?
E-Excuse me…
I’ll pay for this for my entire life!
Can you explain what you mean?
The squid and the octopus!
Huh?
The squid and the octopus?
Usually, in our restaurant, we don’t include squid or octopus in our orders.
But when Saikawa-sensei
ordered them, we always did,
because they were her favourite.
But last night, I was careless and forgot.
Oh, was that it?
I thought it was something serious.
Of course it was serious!
It was her last order!
Sensei, I’m so sorry…
We just came to ask when
you took the order to her.
He didn’t see her?
Right.
He took the order to her flat at 8,
but he didn’t see Saikawa-san anywhere, and didn’t hear her talk, either.
At that time, she was already in the afterlife.
It’s possible.
Excuse me.
Who are you?
Please don’t, editor-in-chief!
Let me go!
I’m the editor-in-chief of Labyrinth Publications.
Yasunobu Shimazaki (50)
Labyrinth Productions Editor-in-Chief
My name’s Shimazaki.
I was told Tono is one of your suspects.
Well, that’s…
He came to work for us,
specialising in mystery novels,
because he admired
Saikawa-sensei’s work so much.
Even today, he was planning the
publication of a collection of her works!
R-Right…
A true fan of Murako Saikawa?
Were you familiar with Murako Saikawa’s works?
No, not until this case came up.
Of course, because
she’s been forgotten.
But that’s precisely why he insisted her works should be published.
There’s tons of people who don’t know the greatness of Saikawa-sensei!
Original tricks, perfect composition.
I want everyone in Japan to know of her!
Honestly, I didn’t think it’d sell well.
Our publisher is in a precarious situation.
And publishing something with low sales expectations would only make it worse.
But I think we’d do it anyway.
I was moved by his passionate desire
to make her happy during her final days.
Her final days?
The doctor said she had an incurable illness.
She had, at most, half a year to live.
Tono is the one who’d regret Saikawa-sensei’s passing the most!
Excuse me.
Megure.
Ah, Beika Medical University.
Understood. Thank you.
We’ve got the autopsy results back.
The victim’s stomach contained rice and raw fish.
Probably the sushi.
Yes. And apparently she was killed an hour later.
If the order was taken to her at 8pm…
Then the estimated time of death would be around 9pm.
And as far as Tono-san goes,
we’ve confirmed that he was with his friends the whole night, starting at a quarter to nine.
His alibi checks out?
My apologies for having suspected you.
You can leave now, if you want.
I’m glad, Tono.
Yeah…
If you’ll excuse me, then…
Then, the killer is…
W-What? You saw him last night?
R-Really?
Yes, I had to make a delivery at a specific time,
and that’s when I saw him.
It was around 9pm.
9pm?
I like to drink a lot.
But one day, old Saikawa saw me sipping a bit in the morning.
She said she’d inform
the management company.
You’ve gotta be joking, I’d get fired for sure if that happened.
That’s why I went to visit her last night, to ask her to reconsider.
But no matter how much I kept ringing the intercom, that old lady wouldn’t answer.
If you suspect me, show me the evidence!
Murata-san!
He stinks of alcohol.
I’ll open the window, to bring in some fresh air.
Of course! There’s another one!
And there’s also that ginger…
Proof… Proof…
I figured out the killer’s trick!
I figured out the trick.
But what was the motive?
Inspector!
Among the things found at the crime scene, there’s nothing that indicates Mr Murata as the killer.
Nothing, huh?
It’s on the news now.
It’s super-sensational.
They probably made a ton of cash off it.
“Famous Novelist Gets a Death Threat from a Character in Her Novel”?
I guess Tono-san couldn’t keep quiet.
He even revealed all the info about the postcard.
The contents of an ongoing investigation are supposed to be a secret.
Of course, that’s it!
Mouri-kun?
Is it the usual?
M-Mouri-kun!
Inspector Megure.
Please call Murata-san and Tono-san back here.
I’ve solved everything.
Takagi! Chiba!
Yes, sir!
Inspector, the killer used an alibi trick.
An alibi trick?
Let’s put the case’s facts in order.
Saikawa-san was killed
between 7 and 9pm yesterday.
And it happened approximately one hour after she ate the sushi.
Yes. Therefore, the approximate time of death is 9pm.
That’s where the problem lies.
How was that determined?
Because the sushi order
was taken to her at 8pm.
Yes, but the sushi inside Saikawa-san’s
stomach wasn’t necessarily that specific sushi.
What does that mean?
There was another.
Another?
In addition to the order of sushi that was sent to her at 8pm,
when Tono-san visited her,
he also brought some sushi.
Saikawa-san actually ate the sushi that Tono-san brought.
And it wasn’t after 8, but at 6:30.
An hour later, Tono-san killed Saikawa-san.
At that point, digestion
stopped in the victim’s stomach.
This would prove that she was killed an hour after she ate the sushi.
Afterwards, Tono-san called the sushi restaurant.
The usual order, for one person.
Thank you for your patronage!
He stored the sushi that arrived
at 8 inside a plastic bag,
locked the door with a copy of the key,
in order to ensure the body
wasn’t found immediately,
and halfway through, he threw away the bag with the sushi and the key.
This way, he was able to set up
an alibi for 8:45 onwards.
He knew that sooner or later, an autopsy would reveal that she died an hour after eating sushi.
And given the call to the sushi restaurant at 8pm…
Naturally, we thought the time of death was 9pm.
As a result of that, Tono-san, who had an alibi for that time, would no longer be a suspect.
That’s what he predicted.
That is to say, he used the autopsy that was intended to help solve the case, in order to set up an alibi.
It was you?!
Hold on, Mouri-san!
Still, you made a mistake. The ginger.
If that ginger was from last night,
it would’ve dried up long ago.
But somehow, the ginger we found was still soft...
Because last night, when you disposed of the sushi you ordered, you also disposed of the ginger.
This morning, you realised your mistake,
asked Murata-san to open the door for you,
and when the manager wasn’t looking,
you slipped that ginger into the kitchen.
Please stop this! Where are you getting that?
I gave her sushi?
It’s obvious that Sensei ate the same sushi that was taken to her at eight!
Inspector, according to the autopsy,
what did they find in Saikawa-san’s stomach?
It was sushi, wasn’t it?
Yes, but more specifically?
Oh, let’s see…
Rice, tuna, sea urchin,
flounder, squid, octopus…?
Squid and octopus?
Yes, certainly.
Detective Takagi, doesn’t it sound strange?
Strange?
Yes, it does!
Oh, no! How could I screw up this bad?
The squid and the octopus!
He forgot them?
You knew exactly the kind of sushi she would like, and therefore, didn’t forget…
The squid and octopus that she loved so much.
You were shocked that the restaurant owner forgot them?
The autopsy you manipulated,
ended up turning against you, and brought you to your doom.
Tono, you…
This is the end of the line for you, Tono-san.
Beginning with Ryo Orochiya, every criminal that Murako Saikawa-san created
accepted their guilt when
they were caught, did they not?
Why did you do it, Tono?
Sensei was ill, and had very little time left.
And if she died from an illness,
she would’ve done so as a forgotten novelist,
and nobody would have
paid any attention to it.
But if she was murdered,
and by a character from the novels she herself wrote at that,
the media would make a big deal out of it.
You wanted the world to know who Murako Saikawa-san was.
Therefore, you came up with that strange death threat, and caused all of this.
Whatever the motive, there’s never a justification for murder!
But for her sake, it was better…
Tono!
Did you really do this just for Saikawa-san?
If this came out in the media, the collection of her works would sell a lot more,
and the publisher would profit greatly.
Didn’t you consider that, too?
I wanted Labyrinth Publications to continue working on mystery novels…
Tono… God damn you!
Shimazaki-san!
A person who truly loves mystery novels would never commit murder.
akogare ga deai ni kawatta hi yume to yume ga tsunagatta
obienagara utsumuki aruita hi
furimukeba kimi ga ita
nagareboshi hitotsu mitsuketa yo
tachidomatta toki ni wa ichi-ban ni dakishimete hoshii
hoshizora ni
mô kimi dake o hanashitari wa shinai
namida wa yesterday
kimi ga kureta kotoba de
egao de nemuri ni tsuku made
mô kimi dake o hanashitari wa shinai
kanashimi wa yesterday
kimi ga kureta kotoba de
egao de nemuri ni tsuku made
Oh, they changed to a different manager.
That’s obvious.
A manager who spends the entire day drinking is in no condition to work properly!
Down it goes!
What about a detective?
Sonoko-neechan, if everybody
has a red handkerchief,
there’s no way to tell
which one’s yours, right?
Huh? A notebook?
This notebook…
There’s a bloodstain on the planner.
On the next Conan:
Next Conan’s Hint:
Names in Katakana
Look forward to the next episode!
What does your name mean
in kanji, Conan-kun?
kochôran
murinandai
The “ko” from “moth orchid”,
and the “nan” from “unreasonable demand”…
Huh?!