It's hard to prosper while so far apart.
By following a drama's fable,
We get thrown into a red-tainted case.
Recognizing that single truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is Detective Conan!
Conan-kun, be careful up there.
Make sure you don't fall.
Alright.
Hey, brat with the glasses, how's it look?
Jeez, is this how you thank me?
I mean really...
Is this alright?
Of course, that brat needs to grow up sometime.
Don't say that.
Hey, hey...
Is it really up here?
Well, Conan-kun?
Is Sonoko's red handkerchief up there?
It's the red one, the red one!
My red handkerchief blew into that tree, I know it!
Isn't that why I'm up here?
I don't see it.
It's not here.
That's strange...
After the wind blew it away, I'm
pretty sure it got stuck in that tree.
Huh? You found it?
Y-Yeah...
But there's a problem.
It's true that the wind blew it away...
But I don't think it tied it to this branch.
Hey! Did you find it or not? Answer me!
Sonoko...
Hey, glasses-wearing brat!
Could it be the thing you're standing on?
Hey, answer me!
Huh? What?
Standing on?
O-Oh...
Sonoko...
Looks like... We found it.
Conan-kun!
Edogawa Conan-kun!
Um...
Come down.
Sonoko's Red Handkerchief, Part One!
Hey...
You gonna tell us?
Jeez... Sonoko...
Why did you want to?
What made you want to visit this maple forest?
Well?
Interesting.
Oh, see this red handkerchief?
You should know just by seeing this.
The handkerchief?
Red?
No idea.
Well, you at least recognize the title, right?
Title?
"The Maple Leaves of Winter."
It's, "The Maple Leaves of Winter."
Oh, I remember!
Last year's most popular romantic drama?
Right, right!
Wait, you didn't watch it?
Aren't you into those?
Yeah...
But it came on during a show in which Okino Youko
was singing, so dad was watching and taping that.
Uncle and Okino Youko...
So, about the drama and the red handkerchief.
Are they related?
A kid like you wouldn't understand,
But Sonoko-sama will explain anyway.
Hey, hey...
It involves an army officer and a wealthy daughter.
Love and romance!
They met for the first time when he retrieved her handkerchief...
From a maple tree.
The two fell in love.
But there was a senior officer who was jealous of their love.
So he filed an unjustified charge against him,
Forcing him to flee abroad.
And when the war was over, she received a telegram from him.
"On Hatsuzora, wait under the the maple leaves."
Right?
But, doesn't "hatsuzora" refer to the first sky?
All of the maple leaves are gone during winter.
Right.
She knew he meant the forest where they first met.
She couldn't remember exactly where,
so she walked all over the mountain.
But she only found dead trees.
She found out that there were no
maple leaves during hatsuzora.
She was about to give up and go home.
She was sure he wasn't there.
And then it happened!
Amidst the snow, tied to a branch, was...
A red handkerchief...
A bright red handkerchief!
And so, they reunited under that tree on that day.
They decided to elope...
And lived happily ever after!
That's great!
Also, the officer is dark skinned, speaks
simply, and is just all around cool.
Like Kyougoku-san?
Right, right, that's just it!
I watched it again on DVD and it reminded me.
A fable with so much love and romance...
It was just like me and Makato-san, right?
Right, the reason I came up here to where the drama was shot...
This!
I'm gonna put up my own red handkerchief!
I see, so you can meet Kyougoku-san.
But is it okay to do that without permission?
Don't worry, I'm only gonna put up one.
No one will know.
No, someone will notice.
Why? Something we don't know?
W...
Wait...
What's this!?
There are red handerkerchiefs everywhere!
Sonoko, is this where they shot that drama scene?
In the last scene, the officer was
waiting with his back to a big rock.
So probably...
In other words: You weren't the only one that thought of this.
This isn't good...
I already mailed Makato-san!
"I'll be waiting under the maple leaves on the eve."
What will I do?
There you go again, Sonoko,
With your puzzling messages.
But don't worry.
Since there are so many handkerchiefs here,
You two will have to meet.
S-Sonoko?
It has to be my handkerchief or there's no point!
That's right, I found something earlier.
What was it?
On that tree I just climbed,
There was a red handkerchief tied to a branch.
No way!
That was pretty far from here!
What if they are tied to trees all over this mountain?
Makato-san...
Where will I wait for Makato-san!?
I think, before that,
You should consider whether a martial arts type
of guy like him could get this maple leaves hint.
Alright, I have no choice.
Here, glasses-wearing brat, hold this.
Y-Yes.
Ran, help me out.
We're taking down all of these red handkerchiefs!
Huh!?
S-Sonoko...
Makato-san and I must have our destined meeting!
Is this really alright?
Makato-san!
Sonoko, you shouldn't...
Sonoko...
Sorry, sorry.
It's my fault this happened.
Oh?
Aren't you taking down the handkerchief's
because you can't see the maple leaves?
Yeah...
Right.
By saying it's your fault, you mean...
Could you be...
The writer of "The Maple Leaves of Winter?"
I'm a big fan!
Ah, no, I'm just on the drama's staff.
Assistant Director.
He's just an assistant?
Well, I'm sorry for ruining your view.
Ah, no, it's nothing, right?
But one of the writers asked me if knew of a
maple leaf forest to be used in a drama series.
So I suggested we use this range.
Since this is near my hometown, I played here as a child.
And while I was scouting out the area,
I saw a red handkerchief tied to a maple tree.
When I reported this to the writer,
He decided to include it in the script, creating a powerful story.
Really?
And then, it became popular.
People began camping here,
And even began tieing red handkerchiefs up here.
This made the owner of this mountain angry.
"Are you trying to cover my mountain in handkerchiefs!?"
Right?
Is that right?
Guess so.
But, then again, the inn and shop owners
are satisfied with all of the customers.
Not many came here unless it was maple season.
So, I'm the one who handles requests about which
mountain it was from the TV reporters and fans.
"Where is the mountain you filmed on?"
"Where did you film the last scene?"
Actually, just today,
A fan offered to pay me,
Just to find the tree which the original handkerchief was tied to.
So, I set out to find it,
And here I am.
That's nice.
Really.
Oh, that's right...
Hey, could you pass on a message for me?
I forgot the fan's phone number.
In front of the train station, you'll find
Akagi Inn, which has a guest notebook.
"I found the tree you seek. Meet me at the
rock used for the drama's last scene."
I need you to write that there.
The original plan was for me to meet the
fan at the inn and escort them to the tree...
But it'd be hard on me to walk down there
for our meeting and then escort them...
All the way back up here, you know?
Well, we should leave your name with the message.
Ah, right.
My name is...
"Hozumi."
Write it in katakana and I'm sure they'll get it.
You want it written in katakana?
Yeah, I've only spoken with that person over the phone,
But I can tell they are a big fan of
the drama and come here often.
Aside from that, the mail I got earlier
indicated they're already there waiting.
Anyway, I told them I'd write in the
notebook if something went wrong.
I guess I'll see you all later.
Yes.
Let's see
"I found the tree you seek.
"Meet me at the rock used for the drama's last scene."
And then...
"Hozumi."
That should do it.
Yeah, looks fine.
Say, Sonoko, want to eat here?
C'mon, I'm starving.
Alright then.
Coming, Conan-kun?
Yep!
Huh? You, too?
Of course I am.
So, what're you in the mood for?
I knew it'd be good.
I really did.
What's wrong, Sonoko?
You've barely moved your chopsticks.
Is something wrong?
S-Sonoko...
Maybe I should go...
Go where?
To that place...
To tie this handkerchief.
Right now?
This is nothing new.
Her sudden impulses as usual.
Would you like it, Ran?
For example...
Ran, you planned to wear your favorite color, red,
To meet up with Shinichi-kun.
But he saw a cute girl wearing red go by and followed her.
You got to meet him,
But you forgot to wear red.
It's just like that.
Isn't this the exact same scenario?
What the hell is she talking about?
Let's go, Sonoko!
Let's go now!
Oh...
Doesn't take much to get her going, huh?
But, see...
Since there are red handkerchiefs tied up everywhere,
Doesn't that mean...
He wouldn't know which was Sonoko-neechan's?
Don't worry!
Look!
I added my name to it and made it look like a flag.
Now there's no way Makato-san can miss it!
There goes "The Maple Leaves of Winter" plan.
S-Sonoko?
What?
It's getting dark...
Ghosts might come out.
Really?
Let's hurry, then.
We're almost there.
A notebook?
Is it...
Hey, this...
Doesn't this belong to that assistant director?
It does.
Must've dropped it.
Yeah.
There's blood on the calendar section.
Looks like he smeared it with his finger...
But why April 1st?
Also...
It's kind of wet...
Well, we can just put it in the lost box later.
T-That's right.
Let's go, Conan-kun.
Y-Yeah...
Blood...
It's not dry...
Could it be...
W-What?
C-Conan-kun...
Get back here, glasses-wearing brat!
See!
It's because you were running!
What is it, Ran?
This guy...
Is he dead?
I think so...
How could this have happened?
He was fine earlier...
The body's still warm.
He was killed under thirty minutes ago.
There's dirt under his nails.
But what's dirt doing here?
H-Hey...
Shouldn't we call the police?
Hello?
Is this the police?
Dirt under his nails...
Blood on the calendar section...
Specifically on April 1st...
What is Hozumi-san trying to say?
Yes.
We found a man who's been stabbed.
Here...
Someone's here...
And...
It's not just one or two...
What the...