It's hard to prosper while so far apart.
As their numbers multiply,
Sonoko calls out for her special someone!
Recognizing that single truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is Detective Conan!
Sonoko's Red Handkerchief, Part Two!
Let's see...
Oh? It was you guys?
The ones who found the body?
Have you all done something which caused
a curse to be placed upon your souls?
Of course we haven't.
Maybe it's the kind you don't know about yet!
We're not cursed!
Ah, excuse me. Did you all know that guy?
No, we just met him earlier today.
He asked us to deliver a message to
the Akagi Inn by the train station.
Next time we saw him was here, stabbed in the chest.
What kind of message?
He said he was the Assistant Director on a TV drama
called "The Maple Leaves of Winter," then...
I know "The Maple Leaves of Winter"! I know it well!
It's a romance drama that's being reaired
on a local Gunma station now, right?
My grandmother suggested it to me.
"The Maple Leaves of Winter!" "The Maple Leaves of Winter!"
I started watching and I'm totally hooked!
Every Saturday night from 9:00 to 10:00, I always watch.
And, with today being Saturday,
That means...
I had to bring my portable TV so I could watch some of it!
I'm recording it from home, too, but
I just couldn't wait that long!
Oh, and his message?
Ah, yeah, he said there was a fan who wanted to see the
original maple tree where the red handkerchief was tied.
He then told us to leave a message at the Akagi Inn,
where the fan was staying, saying he found the tree.
How lazy of him, he could have done it himself.
Well, did you meet the fan?
No.
Sonoko left a message in the guest book.
"I found the tree you seek. Meet me
at the rock used for the last scene."
And you signed it as "Hozumi" in katakana, right?
Huh? Why in katakana?
Dunno, just what he said to do.
Yeah.
Hey.
Maybe it was because he used katakana often?
Look, this is the planner we found on the way here.
"Hozumi" is written in katakana here, too.
We found it about 100 meters away.
We saw the blood on it and ran here.
Blood? On it?
And when we made it, he was lying there.
Let's see, nothing in the planner...
April 1st is marked with blood...
April 1st... April 1st is April Fools... April Fool...
Um...
Yes?
Could that be a dying message?
Yeah, there was blood on his finger, after all.
Yamamura-san.
The estimated time of death is 5:00 this evening.
His wounds indicate he was stabbed
in the abdomen and then the chest.
We can't find any ID on him, so the culprit probably took it.
That's no problem.
All we have to do is contact the staff
of "The Maple Leaves of Winter"
and ask about the Assistant Director, Hozumi.
Yeah, one officer just reported that
he found an empty tent near by.
An empty tent? That sounds suspicious.
Look into that immediately!
Y-Yes, sir.
Hey, did that officer mention anything else?
Like seeing lots of suspicious people.
No, all he mentioned was the tent.
Forget about that tent, why aren't you at the Akagi Inn?
This is where the last scene was filmed,
So the fan he planned to meet should be suspected.
Oh, this is where they filmed the last scene of the drama?
Yep, that's right.
In the final scene, the officer was
leaning against that rock and she...
Stop stop! Stop now!
I'm still in the middle of the drama.
Don't spoil it for me!
Fifty-three people? All staying here?
Yes, we're fortunate.
And, what about those who came this morning?
If you don't mind.
Remember what he said?
He told us the fan sent him a message
that they'd already checked in.
Right.
Well, did someone?
Let's see...
These are the three who checked in this morning.
Then, is it possible to bring them here?
All three of them.
This is an annoyance...
Ohkuma Isamu (25)
Guest
The police here this late? Something wrong?
Watanuki Tatsuzou (63)
Guest
Hans Burkly (41)
Do you all have business here?
Ah, no, I was just wondering where you
three where at 5:00 this afternoon.
I was asleep in my room.
I was in the bath.
I was walking outside.
Is there anyone who can confirm those?
No.
I was using the bath in my room.
I didn't meet anyone.
A young guy with a rough personality,
an old man with glasses,
and a foreigner who wrote his name in katakana.
Hey, Ran, isn't that guy with the nose ring suspicious?
He probably can't read kanji and
requested he write in katakana.
What about that old man?
Kanji may be hard on his eyes, so
he could have requested katakana.
Wait.
Then, it could be the foreigner.
A lot of foreigners likely can't read kanji, but
some recognize hiragana or katakana.
So, among you three, who has heard of a drama
titled "The Maple Leaves of Winter"?
The hell's that?
It's not familiar.
Don't maple leaves dry up in winter?
Oh, I see! You all are just pretending!
But don't worry, if you're a big fan, you'll
react in some way to the opening.
Now, behold!
"The Maple Leaves of Winter"!
Alright, here we go: The European Karate Championship!
Tonight's airing of episode eight from "The
Maple Leaves of Winter" will be postponed.
Huh? No way.
A special!?
We're supposed to watch karate?
But, naturally, the spotlight is
on him tonight: Kyougoku Mokato.
Oh, no...
That's true.
Let's check out his intro video.
Let me see that!
At just 18 years old,
He's from Japan, Kyougoku Mokato.
Makoto-san!
But Sonoko, didn't Makoto-san tell you about this?
He said: "I would rather commit seppuku
than lose a match in front of you."
Isn't he so sweet?
S-Seppuku?
Not like he'd lose anyway.
Yamamura-san...
We contacted the drama's production company.
They said there was no Assistant Director named Hozumi.
This is a copy of the staff list I got from a part-time employee.
A copy of the staff list...
Is this list right?
The dates are mixed up.
Look, here at the bottom.
That's true.
I see! The dates!
But if we consider the part-time employee told the truth,
it means the victim was lying.
A lie?
That's true, April Fools' is the day you can lie.
That means the culprit is lying!
Ah, no, Yamamura-san, it could mean the victim was lying.
Hey Sonoko, would you listen to me?
Well, Conan—Huh?
Conan-kun? Conan-kun?
If my reasoning is correct...
The culprit hasn't found it yet.
Here! This is it!
The ground's still soft.
As I thought, Hozumi-san was digging here...
Until the culprit found him.
I see.
The maple leaf of winter...
Was simply to mark this grave.
Hey Conan-kun, where are you!?
Go home now.
Go home?
Yeah, I was having trouble finding
a gift for Genta and the others.
I'm having Professor Agasa come get me, so don't worry.
Hey, how can I not be worried!?
By the way, are those three guests who
checked in this morning still there?
Yeah, they're still here.
But it's getting late, so Officer Yamamura said they would be
called in for questioning later.
Is that so?
Hey, could you put Sonoko-neechan on?
It's Conan-kun.
He said he wants to talk with me?
Hello?
Yeah, I remember that.
You mean the tree we first thought
my handerkerchief was caught on?
It was close to the rock used for the drama's final scene.
It was about ten minutes away.
That tree may have been used for the drama as well?
Yeah, there's a red handkerchief tied
there, and the branch looks well.
You idiot, that red handkerchief was tied there by a fan.
The tree used for the drama is right next to the rock.
It'd be too confusing with multiple trees to be like that.
Is that so? Thanks, Sonoko-neechan.
Hey, wait!
Huh? It cut off.
No way, did the connection die?
Ah, Ran-kun?
Ah, that's right, I'm coming to pick up Conan-kun.
We just talked to Conan-kun and decided that Sonoko
and I are going to ride home with you as well.
No way, I just called for the car to pick us up.
Shhhh.
So, Professor, can you tell us where you're meeting Conan-kun?
We were talking to him when his
cell phone battery suddenly died.
That's strange, I thought I was just picking up Shinichi.
I'm supposed to meet him at the entrance to the mountain
where "The Maple Leaves of Winter" was filmed.
Oh? Thank you, Professor.
Yeah.
You should at least smile.
Isn't this the reunion you've longed for...
Watanuki Tatsuzou-san?
I don't know who it is that's buried there,
but I do know you're the one who killed him.
And you marked the location with a red handkerchief, right?
This way, if something happened, you could easily move the body.
You chose the color red because it's harder to see.
Not many people came here unless it was autumn, right?
But because of that handkerchief,
A drama was created and became very popular.
Fans began coming here often,
And re-enacted the last scene with their own handkerchiefs.
Because of this, you were unable to find your own.
You were afraid someone would find the body sooner or later,
so you later found Hozumi-san, who was a
member of the drama's production staff.
You decided to pay him in order to seek out your tree.
Just as you asked, Hozumi-san found the tree.
As such, you two decided to meet at
the rock used for the last scene.
You two agreed that after you paid
him, he'd take you to the tree.
But, before he met with you, he came across the bones.
He dug at the base of the tree, just like you did.
And after you two met, he tried to blackmail you.
But you didn't comply.
Instead, you killed him.
You forgot to ask him where the tree was...
So you looked near that tree.
Because you figured it would be near the rock
used in "The Maple Leaves of Winter."
But, it wasn't near the last scene.
You should have expected that since the tree you
were searching for was over 500 meters away.
Actually, the staff would never shoot near the original
tree, since two red handkerchiefs may be in view.
Of course, they had to avoid that.
And with the drama's staff being so appreciative to the
original handkerchief, they would never take it down.
Boy, you're a little clever one.
But what would you have done if I hadn't showed?
I would have just told the police.
After all, it's already stated clearly in Hozumi-san's planner.
That's foolish, it's just April 1st marked with blood in there.
Right, April 1st.
In the old days, people used to remove
cotton from their kimono's on that day.
April 1st
This is how the kanji for April 1 st is read as an
unusual surname in katakana: "Watanuki."
Watanuki (kanji)
Watanuki (katanaka)
You see, April 1st is "Watanuki-san".
That means...
He was referring to you.
Furthermore, the reason Hozumi-san
wrote his name in katakana:
In kanji it's "August 1st," which is Hozumi in katakana.
The name comes from when farmers used to pick
ears of rice on August 1st and offer it to God.
August 1st
We usually don't read the kanji for "August 1st" as Hozumi,
Hozumi
So he was likely used ti using katakana.
Beyond that, Hozumi-san's planner
was found far away from the body.
You thought Hozumi-san died from his abdomen wound,
but then you saw him doing something with his planner.
You stabbed him again, took the planner with you,
Saw no significance in April 1st, and tossed it aside, right?
What the- What the hell are you?
Edogawa Conan.
A detective.
Oh, but you little detective brat, do you
know why I ran away from the body?
Noticing that it was beginning to get dark, you
figured no one else would come by there today.
Yeah, that was the plan.
That was our plan.
Forty, no, fifty... Who are they!?
These are my colleagues I called upon to find the tree,
but I think we have more than enough to take on a little boy.
Conan-kun!
Geez, don't worry about that glasses-wearing brat.
I have no choice.
He's probably getting into something dangerous again.
Kyougoku Makoto's match up is coming!
Geez, he's so curious.
Oh, he hasn't shown up yet?
Nope, it looks like he just got seeded.
What? Who's that?
Dunno.
Ran! Sonoko!
Conan-kun?
The glasses brat?
H-Hey...
Who are all of these people?
No idea...
Conan-kun?
Brat with the glasses, who are these people!!
Who are they!?
They're not your friends, right?
My, my, it seems we have three extra graves to dig.
Who's he?
He's not friendly, for sure.
Ran!
There are too many...
Ran's...
At this rate, we're not gonna make it...
Damn!
Makoto-san, please save me!
Makoto-san!!
What's going on?
Something's...
Over there.
Kyougoku Makoto hasn't made it?!
He's been missing for thee days?!
Then, where could he be?
Makoto-san?
Why are you-?
Well, actually...
The front, the front!
So, you see...
Behind you!
Damn it, I'll make you pay for this...
And so, by the time Officer Yamamura
arrived ten minutes later, it was over.
Later, we found out those guys,
and the older guy, who was a leader,
were members of a dangerous gang.
And the buried body was that of one of their former leaders.
Apparently, the old man and the victim couldn't decide
who would become leader, so the old man killed him.
So, even if he manages to get out of prison,
he would have to face the gang.
Well, that's if he can get out.
Wow, you're a hero!
So you flew here after sensing Sonoko-kun was in danger?
Well, I just went to the place she mentioned in her mail.
Oh, you figured out that it was "The Maple Leaves of Winter"?
Actually, my sister asked me to record it for her,
And I ended up getting hooked.
But I thought I put on the "eve of the eve"?
That's the part I couldn't get.
It's the day before Christmas Eve.
I was going to ask even if it were embarassing,
but it would depreciate my manhood.
So I set up a tent and waited...
Because I had to be there.
Was it too much?
Not at all!
What a thoughtful guy.
But it's so great that you gave up your win streak for Sonoko.
I'm so touched!
The "Best 4" have all gathered here
at the Europa Karate Championship.
It's unfortunate that Kyougoku Makoto isn't here.
Excuse me, can we go to the Narita Airport?
Don't tell me you're going back!
Yes. I plan to fight the winner to see who's strongest.
Geez, he still wants to fight.