Friends!
No matter what, I'll always be your partner.
A man of strict rules and an easygoing woman.
A tragedy happens between them.
Seeing nothing but the truth,
while having the body of a child:
This is Detective Conan.
Are we really going to see him?
Yes, it's for you, Genta!
Well, that's one way to put it.
We learned about that man yesterday...
Ah, it doesn't go in there, Kojima-kun.
Eh? Oops... Non-combustible waste goes to...
Learn how to separate the trash better, Genta!
l-Idiot, I was just a little careless.
You're always a little careless, Genta!
Ah.. Is that so?
If Iwata-san saw you, he'd give a thirty minutes lecture.
Who is Iwata-san?
A man that lives in our apartment complex.
Ah, Chiharu-chan lives in an apartment?
Yea. His name is Iwata Iwao-san.
He moved in about three months ago.
He's very strict about taking out trash.
When the trash truck isn't coming, he's taking the trash back to the owner to tell them they should follow the rules.
Isn't he going a little bit overboard?
He's just serious about the rules.
Yes, he's a very admirable person.
I see, I wouldn't go that far...
That's it! Why don't we all take a school trip
to this Iwata Iwao-san tomorrow morning?
A school trip?
So you can take this strict person as your role model, Genta-kun!
Uh..?
Hehe... Hey...
And so, we came to see him.
Goodmorning!
That's Iwata Iwao-san...
This is yours, isn't it?
There was some of your mail inside...
Don't peep in other people's trash!
Iwato Iwao (30)
Machine brand research
establishment employee
It's wet from the rain, so that indicates you put it outside last night.
The trash is to be brought in the morning!
Why won't you follow the rules?
That person is just like Chiharu-chan said.
The mysterious overly-serious rule-follower.
On top of that, trash and empty cans were mixed and matched!
Please separate them properly!
This seems like a big spectacle, somehow...
Even though people are watching...
It just means that he's serious about it!
What do you want?
I understand, OK?
Be careful you, acting so great will bring you to your end someday.
These are my classmates.
Goodmorning!
Morning.
I've learned a lot from watching you,
it's good to be strict with the rules.
No... Someone just has to do it.
Well, then...
But he could have just quietly said it to him in person.
There was no real reason to make an uproar in front of everyone.
Actually, there is a reason why Iwata-san is so strict with the rules...
A reason?
Not too soon after Iwata-san had moved in,
there was an arson attempt!
Arson?
Someone hadn't followed the rules and their garbage was set on fire!
It was a good thing that Iwata-san coincidentally
went by and extinguished the fire.
So what you're saying is that that's the reason
why he became strict with garbage?
But you know, if you nag people about it too much, they
will just want you to shut up and won't like you.
That's called unjustified resentment through
misunderstanding, right Conan-kun?
Conan-kun?
Huh? Ye.. Yeah.
And so, three days later, a case occurred.
A murder?
Yea, Iwata-san was...
That's what I said about grudges!
But I would have thought... Oh no!
Poor guy... And he was so diligent...
No, it's the opposite!
Iwata-san was the aggressor!
That man was?!
Officer Takagi!
Oh, everyone. What is it?
Actually about Iwata Iwao-san... Is it really true?
Do you guys know about him?
Yes, that's why... Please tell us more, in detail.
It's true. He really did murder someone.
A female, because she didn't deliver her trash right.
For trash misdelivery?
Last night, I mean, around 5:30 in the morning...
...I woke up thirsty and while drinking
I incidentally looked out the window.
There was a person taking out her trash. I couldn't believe it.
You again! I told you not to take it out at night! Like previously!
As I warned her, she...
Oh shut up, you're always complaining...
Don't be so stuck up!
She suddenly tried to hit me with an iron pipe that was there.
Even before I couldn't stand you!
"Like this I will get killed, I have to
take that iron pipe" is what i thought.
A-Are you alright?
He- Hey... Hey!!
No way...
And so, he soon came to give a confession to the police.
So, instead of a case...
Hmm.. That's right...
I admit that I have done something unforgivable... But
officer! Even though it's evil, it was in self-defence!
That's right. It was self-defence!
If Iwata-san told the truth, that is...
Self-centered, err... defence? What will happen to that guy?
The murder isn't his fault, right?
Isn't his fault?
But for it to happen in the late night...
We are searching for a witness, but we really can't seem to find one.
Therefor, it will be hard to prove if the victim
attacked him with an iron pipe or not.
Are you doubting him?
We can't just take his word for it, can we?
That's only one side of the story.
That man is a very serious person!
He isn't someone who tells lies!
That's right!
But if he really felt threatened by her, why didn't he run?
That bothers me too...
If you're getting misunderstood or mistaken,
then running away would be more strange!
Well, logically thinking, yes, but...
It seems that the victim was always loose about taking out her trash.
The woman who passed away?
That's right.
She lived by herself in that mansion;
Katayama Misa-san was her name.
She was a slack hostess, so that's why
she always came home late at night.
From our quick search, it seems that
she always took out her trash at night.
The head of the neighbourhood association
also gave her a warning, but...
Katayama-san. If you can't follow the rules, it will be a problem.
Rules, rules, that's so annoying!
I'm only taking out the trash at night.
If it's such a problem, call the police to get me arrested. Humph!
It seems that was all the head of the neighbourhood association did.
About that time, Iwata moved in and warned
her numerous times about the garbage...
...but Katayama Misa-san seemed very disagreeable towards Iwata.
And then happened what Iwata told us, huh...
For an easygoing woman and a rule-abiding man to be living
in the same neighbourhood and for this to happen...
That's a scary coincidence, isn't it?
But is it...?
For now we can only rely on his testimony.
So let's check out if Iwata is a reliable man.
It has only been three months since he moved here.
Let's find out what happened before that.
I'll continue searching eyewitnesses.
If we clearly tell them how diligent Iwata-san is...
...then we should be able to prove it was self-defence!
If it really was self-defence, that is...
Even if I tell you not to, you will still follow me, won't you?
Iwata-san's characteristics?
For example, did he usually make up lies?
No, no! For Iwata-san to tell lies? It's the opposite!
He was a very honest person.
See? This is a waste of time, Officer Takagi.
Yea...
So, if there was a rule-breaker here,
he would likely confront him, right?
Confront him? Nothing like that! He was a nice man.
Sounds a little different, doesn't it?
Because last time we saw him, he was making a huge spectacle.
Yea...
After he moved into that apartment, did his personality change?
Ah... I was surprised of his moving, because it came so suddenly.
Suddenly?
He made a contract for two years for this mansion,
but in the end didn't keep it, since he moved out.
Huh?
So are you saying that he had plans continuing living here...
...but he suddenly changed his mind and moved
to that apartment in the Beika area?
Huh? Iwata-san moved to the Beika area?
Yes.. What about it?
Nothing... But moving to a smaller apartment...
He didn't have any money problems and
his company was quite close from here.
This was much more convenient, don't you think?
Three months ago, there might have been some sudden
reason for him to necessarily move to that apartment.
Yea..
I can't think of anything else.
And because he moved, the case occurred.
Hey, what does that mean?!
Well, what does that mean?
Hey! Well?
Even if you ask me...
As I thought, this case wasn't coincidental!
More likely...
Three months ago, you ask?
Yes, did something different happen to Iwata-san?
Three months ago...
Ah! For such a bright guy, he was unexpectedly
wearing a very cold expression about that time.
Was it after his grave visit...?
Grave visit?
Yes... It was the second anniversary of his benefactor's
death who took care of him when he was in school.
The grave visit, was it before he moved to the apartment?
Yes, I think it was soon after he moved.
That grave visit might have something to do with this.
School-time benefactors...
Ikami Lawyer Office
Better than good law-office
Ah, you must mean Yasaka-san, right?
Iwata and I were both broke and schooling,...
...with part-time jobs, we made it.
His part-time job was with Yasaka-san, who had a workshop.
Yasaka-san's wife threated the parentless
Iwata-san like their own son.
Even when he got in an accident near the
workplace and was injured badly...
If a blood transfusion is necassary, please use my blood!
Mine too.
It seemed the couple became his lifeline.
So that couple were life donors, so to speak.
Iwata said the same thing, but...
...two years ago, the poor couple was deceived by a money-lender
and their house and even the workshop were taken.
They commited suicide.
About that grave visit, it must have been
exactly 2 years ago since that happened.
If I remember correctly, the grave was in
Henryuuji, somewhere in the Beika area.
Henryuuji is...
It's close to Chiharu-chan s apartment, right?
Yeah.
Wait... From Beika Station to those apartments.
It's right after them, right?
So that moneylender who deceived the couple
and drove them to suicide is now...?
He should be in prison already, he was guilty on many things.
But the woman...
The woman?
There was a woman involved in it.
When I researched a bit, I leared that the Fujikura
lender was introduced by this woman.
I found out that she knew from the beginning that it was all a sceam.
Is there any way for that woman to take responsability as well?
But she only introduced them.
Unfortunatly, she can't be punished by law.
Can't be punished by law... That woman!
Iwata was in agony.
And that woman's name was...?
I haven't heard, but she was working
in some bar or club as a hostess.
Hey! Could it be?
What about that woman?
So that's it!
I would like to quickly confirm
something about a convicted Fujikura...
What is that?
He died of an illness last month?
Fujikura?
Fujikura Eiji. Have you heard from the name Katayama Misa-san?
I wouldn't know with what kind of men that
unpleasant woman would go out with.
Ah, but they worked together.
I wouldn't know.
Takagi here.
Ah! About the previous... You made sure?
Thank you very much.
That was the prison guard.
He's heard about the person working with Fujikura.
Fujikura said himself, that once we would be out, he was going
to meet a hostess named Misa to hurt people again.
They're connected. The victim and the assailant.
Mutsuhiko...
But, there isn't any decisive evidence yet!
Evidence...
Co- Conan-kun...?
What's with this kid?
Conan!
This person is Katayama Misa-san, right?
That's right. What about it?
Is this a recent picture?
About six months ago...
Six months ago...
Is there something wrong with this picture?
She's injured.
Oh, right. She left it between a car door, they were almost
torn off. It was a big mess. They were all fine but one.
All but one...?
I have one thing I want to confirm.
Yes. The weapon we have as evidence,
about that particular iron pipe...
We left to find the evidence to help Iwata-san,
but only confirmed an unbelievable thing.
Mitsuhiko...
The result is clear, because there is only one truth.
You do know why we asked you here, don't you, Iwata-san?
From this point, three months ago, you came here to visit this grave.
This grave is Yasaka-san's who commited suicide two years ago after
being deceived by an evil-mannered money-loaner named Fujikura Eiji.
You came to see them then.
Yasaka-san...
After that grave visit, as you were heading back
to the train station, you accidently saw her.
She was the woman who worked with Fujikura
Eiji in deceiving the Yasaka couple.
Rules, rules! That's so annoying!
I'm only taking the trash out at night.
If you have a problem, call the cops to have me arrested!
Even if she had driven the virtuous couple
to suicide, she wasn't regretting it at all.
That time, you thought about it, didn't you?
For you to have met her again was certainly fate, a chance
to seek revenge for the generous Yasaka-san's.
You rent a room for a place right across hers and moved in.
Even if you were seeking revenge, you didn't want to be caught.
Since she hadn't gotten any punishment by law, the revenge wasn't
your sin. So you thought of a way to kill her in self-defence.
You innitiated your plan immediatly.
You started the arson fear, which became your excuse of becoming
a very strict man about disposal and warning people about it.
Then, you only had to wait for your chance.
You continued to wait for that woman, Katayama
Misa-san, to bring her garbage.
Moreover, you were waiting for the ideal chance
when nobody would be passing by.
And so, last night, that chance finally came.
You pressed her fingerprints on the iron pipe
you had prepared and reported to the police.
Isn't that so, Iwata-san?
To make a planned murder look like an accident...
So it would look only like some neighbourhood problems.
You thought that the police wouldn't search
too much about the participants' past, right?
That woman... picked up an iron pipe that was
left behind and suddenly tried to hit me.
I was only protecting myself! That was only self-defence!
That's enough...
Yeah...
Give up already.
We have proof. Katayama Misa-san's fingerprints.
Fingerprints?
Are you saying that woman's fingerprints weren't on the iron pipe?
On the contrary, we found both of her hands. All ten fingerprints.
Six months ago, Katayama-san injured her right index
finger badly. After that she couldn't bend it anymore.
Someone must've forcefully pressed her fingers to the iron
pipe, otherwise that finger's fingerprint wouldn't be there.
I couldn't forgive her! That woman!
If it wasn't for the blood, I wouldn't have survived.
Hey, if you look away, you will get hurt!
Right! I was thinking that maybe you would let me
work here after I graduate from High School.
Don't say stupid things.
That's right, Iwata-kun. You will become
the ruler in Japan, won't you?
Idiot! Not only of Japan, but of the whole world!
That's true. Hahaha!
To deceive such a nice couple... I couldn't rest
with it, even if I had to commit a murder.
But what you did is still a crime. No matter
how unforgivable of an opponent.
There's no way to fix it with an apology!
Yasaka-san!
What's the matter, Genta-kun?
Listen! A really strange guy moved in our
apartment. That person was really...
What's wrong?
He just doesn't learn...
It seems that those five numbers aren't the only hints.
Next on Conan:
Class-1-B's Great Plan!
Next Conan's Hint
Dices' eyes.
Look forward to the next episode!
Are there eyes on dice?
Yes, six of them!
Really?!
Are you alright, Genta-kun?