Friends!
No matter what, I'II be there!
Everyone in grade 1 B goes for a great search!
Is Kobayashi sensei missing?
Seeing the one truth, while looking like a kid, having
the brains of an adult, this is Detective Conan!
It has really hit the rain season, hasn't it?
Geez... Damn rain.
We were even supposed to play dodge-ball in the fifth
period's class activity... This seems to be a free period...
Oh, no... I was so looking forward to it.
Then what are we going to do for class activity?
Who knows...
We just did the fun imitations...
Then, aren't we going to the library?
Ehh? That's boring...
Alright...
Done.
Perfect!
Grade 1 Class B's Great Operation!
Everyone...
You all have your pencils with you?
And your stroke order is correct, right?
Honestly...
I can't do this seriously.
Oh no, Conan kun.
Listen, Conan-kun. Woman's kanji is...
Ku - no - ichi. That's how you write it!
Yes, yes.
Oh, no! I forgot to bring my eraser!
Here.
Please use mine.
Thank you, Ai-chan.
So it's "please use"...
Conan-kun. Quietly!
I'm sorry!
Haibara, you bastard...
Oh? Did you say something, Edogawa-kun?
Teacher!
Yes?
There's a person who hasn't written anything yet!
What is it, Sakamoto-kun?
Are you not feeling well?
That's not it.
All my pencils have broken led.
Even if I wanted to, I can't write with them...
Didn't you bring a pencil sharpener?
I forgot it.
Then you can just lend one from someone.
Someone, but from who?
What?!
Ah, well. Here.
I'll lend you my pencil, so...
Thank you...
Next time you feel troubled, don't mull
it over by yourself and tell us, okay?
Okay.
Huh?
Alright! Next is the long awaited lunch!
You are always the most full of spirit
at this time, aren't you Genta-kun?
Ah, everybody...
What? No lunch?
Genta-kun...
At lunch break, please don't come to the class room, okay?
Sensei has to meet someone here at that time.
We can't enter, no matter what?
I'm sorry.
But he's a very shy person, so...
Okay, let's go to the cafeteria...
Yes!
I wonder what that was
Kobayashi-sensei's... that wink.
She's surely hiding something.
What's this?
That's our classroom there, isn't it?
Something seems to have happened.
Did something happen?
It's terrible!
Sensei is... Sensei is...
I will be taking care of Kobayashi-sensei. Can you
figure out where she is? The fiend with 200 faces.
Th-The fiend...
...Of 200 faces?!
I see. This was the wink's meaning.
Isn't it cute?
That Ranpo-maniac.
The-then, the person that teacher was meeting with, was...
The fiend?!
First, we have to report this to the headmaster!
Wait a moment!
This paper was in my desk.
Is it from the fiend...?
No. More likely this is a deduction game
that Kobayashi-sensei has made for us.
Deduction game?
In other words, sensei's hiding-place
is hinted for us to look for.
By saying that we can't come here
during lunch break means,...
...that there must be hints still hidden, right?
Let's search for them!
There's one in my desk...
A paper with the number '2'.
Mine has the '1'.
I'm '5'!
Three.
Two.
One.
Five.
Number '4' is missing.
Then, it's hidden somewhere in the class room, right?
Alright...! Let's all search for it!
Yeah!
U - Uhmm...
Also in my desk, there was a paper...
Alright! Number '4'.
Now we have them all!
Hey, wait a second...
Who are you...?
That's mean, Genta-kun. She transferred
here earlier. She's Higashio Maria.
Higashio Maria?
That's right, Genta-kun. Don't you remember?
No way...
Well, it's not his fault for not remembering.
Because you were resting at home
with a cold when she transferred.
Well, of course then.
Anyway, let's gather all the hints we found.
You're right.
The number '1' paper was in my desk,
in Tsuburaya Mitsuhiko's.
The '2' was Yoshida Ayumi-chan.
'3' was Edogawa Conan-kun's.
'4' was Higashio Maria-chan.
And finally, '5' was Kojima Genta-kun.
But, I wonder why Genta-kun's the only red one.
Have you had nosebleeds lately?
No, I haven't!
Maybe it has something to do with grade orders?
See, in Japan there's a 5 scaled grade
system for our records, right?
For example, if the numbers match with the lectures...
...then sensei is in that lecture room, right?
Five scaled grade system?
The number two is about me?
Teitan elementary school only has two:
"Good" and "work harder".
Oh, is that so?
I just heard that in my sister's time there was a
five scaled grade system, so I messed up a bit.
If I recall, it was quite a long time ago...
Haibara-san, how much do you differ in age with your sister?
Haibara, do you have a sister?
Maybe it was my mother...
Hey. It seems like those five numbers aren't the only hints.
Look. The back of the paper on the blackboard.
Dices?!
mi i mu.
Ni shi go?
sa hi ro.
fu yo go.
This doesn't seem to be a play with sound.
But what is this? Six dices?
We have only found five, so it doesn't
seem to have a connection...
No, it connects greatly.
Somewhere in this class,...
...there should still be a number '6' hidden somewhere.
A number '6' ?
It wasn't in my desk.
Neither in mine.
Or mine...
So, where is number '6' ?
Yeah, it's here.
The paper you're looking for.
Geez, couldn't you have told us earlier?
Well, that's for me to descide!
Wait a second... I haven't seen you around that much.
Who are you?
Geez, Genta-kun! Have you already forgotten?
He was hurt soon after school started and was finally
able to come back in October, Sakamoto--!
It was something with Sakamoto...
Surely it was Sakamoto... Sakamoto...
Takuma-kun.
Your name is Sakamoto Takuma-kun, right?
Yes.
Oh, I see...
That's Conan for you!
So you remembered, right?
No. I'm sorry for Takuma-kun, but I forgot as well.
Then, how did you know his name?
Thanks to sensei's code.
After solving it, the name "Takuma" will surface, you see.
Then...
You know it? Where the teacher is hidden?
Yes, of course.
Where? Where? Tell us, Conan-kun!
Yea... You're a bit cocky, aren't you?
This Haibara...
Firstly, why Genta's number was red...
First grade's class B's Edowaga Conan-kun...
...please come to the teacher's staff room.
Someone's calling you, Conan.
Y-Yes...
Well, it seems I really have to go.
Hey, Conan...?
Then please tell us the answer to the code!
Don't worry.
If it's you guys, you'll solve it right away.
Any kid would know this easy game.
Well then... I'll leave the rest to you!
Leave it to us...?
Conan-kun?
Yoro?
Yon - roku - shiku.
So that's it, huh?
Hey, hey. Do we have to solve
Kobayashi-sensei's code without Conan?
I guess we'll wait for Conan-kun to come back.
That's stupid.
He figured it out. Is there some reason why we can't?
But, you know...
Moreover, this is an elementary school teacher
who made the code for children.
It's not some incomprehensible dying message
left in a crime scene or a treasure map.
It must have been made for us to solve, right?
There's no reason for us to back down.
Tha-That's right...
I somehow feel like we can solve it now!
Let's do our best!
Then, firstly, let's insert the names of our numbers
to match these dice numbers, why don't we?
Le's see... First is '3', so it's Conan-kun,...
...and then '1' was Mitsuhiko-kun, then '6' is Takuma-kun!
'2' is Ayumi...
...'4' is Maria-chan and '5' is me!
Conan, Mitsuhiko, Takuma, Ayumi, Maria, Genta.
Conan
Mitsuhiko
Takuma
Ayumi
Maria
Genta
If we take just the first syllables.
Komita amage...?
Edogawa
Tsuburaya
Sakamoto
Yoshida
Higashio
Kojima
Let's try by surname...
That makes...
E tsu sa yo hi ko...
Maybe the numbers in our drawers and these
dices don't have a connection, huh?
It bothers me that only Genta-kun's number was red.
What is it, Ai-chan?
Did you figure something out?
Well, you know... Of the six numbers, only one is red...
I have a feeling there is something like that.
Of the six, only one is red...?
In traffic lights one of three is red...
And in a card-deck there are 52 cards, meaning 26 red ones...
U-Uhmm...
Th-That.
Ah! I see!
It's the dices, right?
Incredible, Maria-chan! You realized it quickly!
Yeah! We really like sugoroku at home!
Kansai dialect...
Really like?
No need to be embarrassed
Dialects are a language's accessories.
You can take it off, that's fine, but don't throw it away.
Furthermore, it conveys the,
important message of your origin...
Yea! That's right!
But hey... What do my red number
and the dice's number have in common?
The dice's red number is '1', right?
In other words, it means that the paper
your desk makes the number '5' first.
So, me being first means...
Normally, it would be your height or weight,...
...but in our last health check, I and Yoshida-san
were almost the same height and weight.
And kids grow up so fast this age,...
...so it probably isn't that.
By the way...
Is Takuma-kun somehow good with games or sports?
Why are you asking?
Well, Conan-kun said it, right?
A game that any kid could play is a hint.
Therefore, it could be someone good with games and sports!
Then... Genta-kun was first, so...
All right! It's baseball, obviously.
If it's baseball! I can do it too.
I've done a lot of throwing and catching with my dad.
Then, are you saying you're better than me?
Wait a moment.
You're not playing as professionals in baseball...
For elementary school kids, isn't it a little too
hard to decide who's better than the other?
You're right.
There must be another game as a hint.
Kobayashi sensei, right?
You've been here, listening to their conversation.
And when it looked like I was about to solve the code easily,...
...you called with your cell phone for
another teacher to call me away, right?
I can't help it! If it's too easy, it's no fun!
It isn't just for fun, is it?
This grown-up kid...
But, ... I wonder if it will work...
Hide and seek.
TV-game!
Playing house!
They don't exactly fit...
I'm good with history games!
Because Genta-kun knows so much.
History... Knows...
Hey, Ai-chan, do you remember any?
You're right.
Maybe it's not a physical game.
Like... For example...
Shiritori!
Our six names make Shiritori.
Huh? Shiritori?
Certainly!
Ge-N-Ta
Ta-Ku-Ma
Ma-Ri-A
A-Yu-Mi
Mi-Tsu-Hi-Ko
Co-Na-N
That's true! If it's Shiritori then Genta-kun is the first!
Nicely noticed, Takuma-kun!
J-Just a coincidence.
I see...
The teacher is hiding in that classroom.
But Mitsuhiko... So what if it's Shiritori?
Well, if we put our names of the
Shiritori in the order of these dice...
...it will line up our six numbers that were in our desks.
Maria-chan was third in Shiritori, that's why she's number 4.
First was Genta-kun, so '5'.
The sixth was Conan-kun, so '3'.
Second was Takuma-kun, '6'.
Fourth was Ayumi, so '2'.
And the fifth was me, '1'.
Continuing from here... 4, 5, 3, 6, 2, 1.
Yo-ko-sa-mu-ni-i?
It's nonsense, isn't it?
Is it really Shiritori?
That can't be! They fit too perfectly to be a coincidence!
That reminds me, after Edogawa-kun had solved this code,...
...he knew that Sakamoto's name was Takuma, right?
That's right. In Shiritori, a name between Genta-kun and
Maria-chan would begin with a TA and end with a MA.
So it can't be anything else but 'Takuma'.
But hey, we have a 'Tachima' in our neighbourhood.
And there's 'Tanuma' too!
But those are surnames, right?
Maybe Edogawa-kun knew Takuma's KU from somewhere.
Ah, that's it! Right! That's true!
Is there something wrong?
Well, because Takuma-kun's surname is Sakamoto...
Counting from the beginning, the
sixth syllable in his name is KU.
Everyone is saying that Takuma's number
6, that was in his desk, fits perfectly!
I got it!
So, when I, Tsuburaya, was first, it's TSU, right?
Then I'm... Kojima Genta, so... I think it's GE...
It's N!
I'm Yoshida, so the second is SHI, right?
I'm Higashio, the fourth, so O.
Edogawa-kun was third, so he's GA.
Now... Let's read them in the order of the dices'!
Umm... The first dice was my 3, so...
O!
Next is Kojima-kun, so...
N!
The next, Edogawa-kun is...
Ga!
Next, Sakamoto-kun.
Ku!
Yoshida-san.
Shi!
And then, Tsuburaya-kun.
Tsu!
It's ongakushitsu!
I think I'm beginning to understand Kudo-kun a bit.
Then, let's all go check the music classroom!
Let's go, Maria-chan!
Hey! You're comming too!
Because if the answer is wrong we
all have to think about it again.
I-I know that...
Well... Is Kobayashi-sensei there?
No.
It looks like nobody's here...
No way!
Could it be that we went wrong with the code somewhere?
Maybe it wasn't the dice, like I said...
Maybe it was the Shiritori that went wrong.
There's no way!
Geez, before you complain, we have to search first.
Surely she's here somewhere!
More like, this is a bit too much...
Kobayashi-sensei!
That's it! Our deduction was...
Yes. Of course, a big success!
Be grateful. I had a hard time.
Sorry about that.
Then, sensei. Give us some sort of reward.
There's no such thing!
Oh, there isn't?
It was sensei's lost. I admit defeat.
Isn't that good enough?
Not good enough!
No, it was your win, Kobayashi-sensei.
A girl who just transferred to a new environment
who couldn't make friends...
...and a boy who had been injured and absent for a
long time from school and seperated from class..
Taking those two's names in the code,
made everyone remember them.
Creating a situation where they had
to participate to solving the code,...
...and magnificently making them a part of the class?
Hey, listen to this! For the next class activity, let's go to that
mysterious western house in Nichioume and explore!
That 'Eto' house next to Professor's.
Rumour says that everyone has left
that house and only ghosts live in there!
I'm telling, hey. That's my house.
Oh? That sounds interesting!
It does!
Nichioume street's mystery house!
'Eto' It's 'Eto'!
It's read 'Kudo'.
Tsukasa-kun is definitely gone to that ocean.
Please! Let me find you!
Next on Conan: The missing page.
Next Conan's hint: Photo frame.
Look forward to the next episode!
Next Time it's a line from an opening page!
kantou = opening page of a book/ eastern half of Japan, rose = route, line, alignment
Where has that train run off to?
I can't break it to you.