No matter what, I'll always be your partner.
The missing final page of a book and a missing stone.
Where will our deductions lead?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Man, how many years has it been
since I've had to write a book report?
Come on, Conan-kun.
Are you even trying?
Uh, yeah...
Don't you "uh, yeah" me.
Haibara-san went home ages ago.
And Ayumi-chan and Genta-kun are both taking this very seriously!
I can see how Ayumi-chan would be working hard, but Genta?
What are you talking about?
Conan-kun, you're the only one who isn't making an effort.
See, even Genta-kun is...
This looks so yummy!
Uhm, Genta-kun...
Hey, hey.
All right.
This book's the one for me.
Wait, Genta-kun!
Are you sure you know what "book report" really means?
He's hopeless.
Huh?
What's wrong?
It's just strange.
Conan-kun, look at this.
See?
Isn't it just a prank by somebody?
Why would they do this...
Just choose another book.
No way.
This has to be the book!
But still...
Conan-kun...
You'll help me look around, won't you?
I found a clue.
Maybe if we ask this kid, we'll find out something.
I have to go too?
There's just no excuse for tearing a page out of a school library book.
Here we go again.
The missing page.
What does it matter?
It looks yummy.
Like I've told you, and more than once.
Are you listening, Genta-kun?
A book report means that...
Ouch!
Ow!
Hey, hold it, buddy!
Are you all right, Genta-kun?
What a rude person!
Who knocks someone down and doesn't apologize?
I've never seen him around here before.
Me neither.
What's going on over there?
Let's check it out.
I wonder which one he is.
He's probably already gone home.
Is there a Naitou Tsukasa-kun here?
Tsukasa-kun is absent today.
There's nothing we can do about that.
Let's head home, too.
He didn't call in sick or anything, so Sensei was worried about him.
No one from his house called the school?
I'm not sure.
Tsukasa-kun just transferred here in the fall, so...
Oh, I see.
I thought that he'd been looking kinda down recently...
I wonder if something happened to him.
Does it have something to do with this book?
That's the book!
You know it?
Tsukasa-kun told me about it.
He did?
Even though school was over, he was still reading it.
So I got curious and asked him...
"What kind of story is that?"
It's about Alec...
Well, Alec's the main character of the story.
One day, he loses this important harmonica.
So he goes to ask a wise turtle what to do.
The turtle says that if he can find the "Again Stone,"
something that's been lost will return to him again.
To find the stone, he needs both a kind heart and courage.
Alec keeps searching until he finally finds the stone
And when Alec flashes the stone at the sky, the
harmonica he lost comes floating down to him!
So I said, "If only there were a stone like that in real life."
And Tsukasa-kun laughed a little and said, "Yeah."
Hey, let's go there.
Go where?
Where else?
To Tsukasa-kun's house, of course.
Sorry, excuse us!
Is there a case?
I really doubt that.
Hey, hey, did something happen?
A precious stone that was on display in that room got stolen.
Hey, Mitsuhiko...
That man just now...
Don't you get it?
He's the stone thief!
Are you sure about that?
That's why he ran away like that!
All right, it's time for the Detective Boys to get to work!
Genta-kun!
Let's go!
Wait, Genta-kun!
Since she drew us a map, we'll find it in no time.
Yeah.
What's wrong, Kobayashi-sensei?
Oh, Conan-kun.
Actually, something troublesome happened.
Troublesome?
Yeah, the truth is...
I borrowed a stone sample from Beika Museum for a week.
And now it's been stolen!
It's a really valuable stone.
I promised to return it later today.
Sensei...
May we take a look around the science room?
I know it was here after class yesterday.
They were pretty reckless.
It's hard to think of this as the work of a professional.
"Returnolith"?
That's right, we just...
Ayumi-chan, can you show me that book again?
Here you go.
Thanks.
I'm pretty sure a stone was mentioned here, too...
The Again Stone and the Returnolith...
I see.
It's possible that the person who stole the stone also read this book.
Tsukasa-kun returned this book yesterday.
The stone was taken sometime between
yesterday after school and today.
What is it, Conan-kun?
All right.
Lets go, Ayumi-chan.
To look for the stone thief?
To Tsukasa-kun's house.
I'm starving...
We've completely lost sight of him.
He was just in front of us a second ago...
What is it?
There he is, the stone thief.
Let's go, Mitsuhiko!
Got it!
We lost him again!
No, I'm almost certain he went this way.
Maybe this is the place.
All right!
Hey!
What do you kids want?
I'm so sorry!
Please spare our lives!
So you think Tsukasa-kun was the one who took the stone?
If Tsukasa-kun was the one who ripped out the page,
it's highly possible that he took the stone, too.
If that's true, then Tsukasa-kun's a bad kid, huh?
I told you, we don't know that just yet.
Here it is.
Excuse us!
What're you two doing here?
Conan-kun?
If you're hungry, there's plenty more to eat.
Mister...
You heard from Tsukasa-kun's teacher that he
never showed up for class today, didn't you?
Do you have any idea where he could have gone?
Aren't you worried about Tsukasa-kun?
I am, but I'm still gonna eat.
It's true that we came here on a misunderstanding,
and ended up eating some exquisite food, but...
Now that we've heard what's happened, it changes everything.
Look, I'm busy getting the restaurant ready to open.
Doesn't your wife help?
That's none of your business!
Hey, mister.
Could you show us Tsukasa-kun's room?
We might learn something new.
What do you wanna do that for?
Because we're worried about Tsukasa-kun.
What are you doing, Tsukasa?
Nothing.
Boys like you ought to be playing
soccer with their friends or something.
I don't have any friends.
So you kids are Tsukasa's...
We're his friends.
If my deductions are correct...
After Tsukasa read that book, he found
the stone in the science room.
He then became convinced that it was the
"Again Stone" mentioned in the story.
Then this morning he came to school,
took the stone, and disappeared.
But what's his motive?
What is Tsukasa-kun trying to get back?
Conan-kun.
About this, could it be...
Tsukasa-kun's mother?
So she passed away...
She looks so kind.
But now she's gone...
Could it be...
How'd it go?
His dad doesn't know what beach it is, but it appears
to be a secret spot shared between him and his mom.
I see...
Could this beach be where Tsukasa-kun is now?
We still can't know for sure.
Hey, Conan!
You find something?
All kinds of things.
Ayumi-chan, bring the book over here.
Flip to the page that's torn.
Here.
All right.
Tsukasa-kun's definitely the one who tore the page out of the book.
He brought the page home with him,
and cut off the edge he didn't need.
That means, we can look at Tsukasa-kun
as the person who took the stone, right?
Right.
Great work, Genta!
The stopper on the back is loose.
Let's see what's inside.
It's some kind of note.
With some strange words.
What does it say?
Crab-san is scissors scissors...
The orange is paper.
The caterpillar is rock...
Paper scissors.
What do you think it is?
Sounds like a code to me.
Sure does.
Genta-kun, you need to be thinking, too!
This could be a clue!
Crab-san, scissors scissors...
What could it mean?
What is it, Mitsuhiko?
Genta-kun, stay just like that.
Please don't move.
So I should stay just like... this?
Crab-san, scissors scissors.
I figured it out!
I know what that code means!
That sea is supposed to be a secret place
for Tsukasa-kun and his mom, right?
And behind their picture was the code.
This code is like a map, which means it tells us how to get there.
That's right, Mitsuhiko.
Which means, which means...
Let's see...
They rode a crab to get there?
That's right!
Crabs are red, you know.
And that stands for the TR Touto Line.
Keep going.
"Scissors scissors" means four fingers are up.
So that means...
Stations...
And maybe that equals the number of stations!
Right!
Now what do we do?
Let's get going before it gets dark.
Four stops away from Beika Station on the Touto Line...
Hey, that could work for either inbound or outbound.
Next, it's the "orange" part.
Orange-colored!
But the Sakaimachi and Minato Lines are both orange.
Wait, why is Crab-san the only one with the honorific "-san"?
Because he's more important?
It's Platform 3.
1 & 2 are for limited-express trains.
And which way is Platform 3 for?
Inbound, right?
Right.
At the next station, we transfer to the Minato Line...
Then we'll get off five stops later because
of the five fingers in "paper".
The problem is, what do we do from there?
Yeah.
Yes.
Yes—right.
Thank you for your help.
We're back!
We had so much fun, Dad!
Yeah?
And Mom was so funny.
When the waves rushed up, she—
I told you to always come in through the back door!
Sorry...
Here, it's a souvenir
Next time, come with us, Dad.
We're in trouble, Conan-kun.
There's no other train that we can transfer to from this station.
Rock means zero, I'm sure.
But there's no such thing as a Platform 0 for a train.
That's true.
And what does the caterpillar stand for?
The bus terminal.
There's a Bus Number 0!
Try thinking of the caterpillar as a bus instead.
I get it!
Let's go!
So it wasn't a real caterpillar... wait up!
Doesn't that look like a caterpillar?
This has to be it.
I'll go ask the bus driver.
Hey, are you really sure, Conan?
If Tsukasa-kun's not there...
Don't worry about it.
How'd it go?
There's no mistake.
"Paper scissors" makes seven, and the seventh
stop from that bus is indeed Ohama Beach!
That settles it, then.
Tsukasa-kun has to be at that beach.
There's the sea!
Great, just a little further.
The sea, the sea!
We didn't come here to play, you know.
Let's split up and search.
If you find him, contact us immediately.
Right!
Let's get going too.
Please...
Please let us find him.
Tsukasa-kun...
So we finally made it...
To the last page.
Tsukasa-kun?
Naitou Tsukasa kun from 1st grade, class A, right?
Who are you two?
We both go to Teitan Elementary, and I'm Edogawa Conan.
My name is Yoshida Ayumi.
The truth is..
Wow, the sea, the sea!
So this is where you were, Tsukasa-kun!
Let's have some fun since we're at the beach!
That's right.
You, too, Tsukasa-kun!
Come on, come on—it'll be great.
All right, sumo.
Let's do sumo!
You're not gonna get me!
He's fired up!
Bring it!
Tsukasa-kun sure looks like he's having fun.
Looks that way.
But, how did you know he'd be here?
Because the sea in that photo looked just like the one in the book.
That's all?
There had to be a reason he tore the page
out of the book and took the stone.
Something Tsukasa-kun wanted to get back
even if he had to break the rules to do it.
And that is...
His mother?
Right.
Tsukasa-kun wanted to use the stone's
power to bring his deceased mother back.
And the rest was all thanks to Mitsuhiko's deduction.
Hey!
Tsukasa!
Dad!
What about the restaurant?
Don't worry about that.
How?
How'd you know where I was?
This led me here.
I'm sorry, Dad.
I thought if I came here, I'd be able to see Mom.
I'm so sorry.
Tsukasa...
It took so long to get here, I'm hungry all over again.
Mister, feed us some more yakitori!
No more, Genta-kun!
No problem.
Keep taking care of Tsukasa for me, all right?
You got it, just leave it to us!
So you found the stone, Naitou-kun?
Sensei, uhm...
Thank you.
We looked for it, too, but didn't have any luck.
Sensei, I'm the one who took the stone.
I'm glad that you're being honest with me.
But you can't do things like that any more.
I'm so sorry!
Sensei, check out my homework!
Wow, you sure finished up quickly.
This is your report?
Looks yummy, huh?
Come on, Genta kun!
The assignment was to write a book report.
That looks more like a picture diary!
That's so like you, Genta-kun!
Geez, is eating the only thing ever on your mind?