It's hard to prosper while so far apart.
Exactly who is Hondou Eisuke?
A case on the Teimuzu River!
Something new is beginning!
Recognizing that single truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is Detective Conan!
Did it return yet?
Mizunashi Rena's conciousness.
No.
She's suffered from blunt force trauma.
The doctor first said one month.
He also said if it took two, it could take longer...
Assuming her condition worsened.
This is bad.
The longer she takes, the higher the
chance we'll make a mistake.
Then we really should move her to a
different hospital, preferably in America.
No.
That's exactly what they're expecting.
B-But...
Well, if that's the case, let's catch them.
Don't you think she's perfect bait?
B-Bait?
By the way...
Do we know anything about Mizunashi Rena's past?
Actually, everything she said on and to Nichiuri TV was fabricated.
That includes her birthplace and her hometown.
I guess that means we don't even know about her family.
Then, a strange name like "Mizunashi
Rena" must be a joke as well.
A joke?
Mizunashi is 0,
"Mizu" is water, "nashi" is without: "without water" which equals 0.
Rena can be pronounced Reina. "Rei" is 0, "na(na)" is 7.
Rena is 07.
007.
Right?
Shadow of the Black Organization:
The Young Witness.
Ah, no.
Even if I did say that,
it was only because you asked me to do it.
I'm home.
You should talk to your husband about it.
Oh, really?
YOU INSENSITIVE BASTARD!!!
Who was that on the phone?
Some woman who asked me to follow her cheating husband.
"It's because of you that he left me and that I'm miserable!"
That's what she said, but she isn't exactly loyal either.
Geez, I'd like to be James Bond right now.
Huh? Why?
What do you mean?
He only wears expensive brand name clothes,
drives super cars, has all that high tech stuff.
He can follow someone easily.
And me, I've got normal clothes, a beat up rental car...
And a partially working camcorder for following spouses.
Not to mention, he gets all the hot chicks.
I get a middle aged woman yelling at me over the phone.
What went wrong?
This coffee's great!
Is this a brand?
Nope, it's not It's a new filtered coffee that
was on sample sale at the supermarket.
The ad had something about collecting
points to win a really cute coffee pot.
Well, just instant from now on.
You...
If you're gonna complain, you won't be drinking any!
Ow!
Hot, hot, hot...
Y-﻿You are...
Hondou Eisuke!
H-Hello...
Oh, I'm so sorry! Are you alright?
No, I'm fine.
I think I stood up on the wrong leg as a child.
So, how'd you get in here?
We met at the supermarket by chance so I brought him along.
Detective Mouri, you said I could come over whenever I wanted!
Is that right?
I'm here to help! I'll answer the phone, or anything, really!
Yes, this is the Mouri Detective Agency!
Hello? Hello?
H-Hey...
That's odd, they hung up.
You hung it up yourself!
You're best at not touching anything!
Y-Yes.
I didn't sense him...
I'll get you a towel, Eisuke-kun.
When he came in.
Excuse me.
Maybe I just wasn't paying attention.
Or maybe...
I got it, Eisuke-kun.
Oh, alright.
Oh, I'm sorry, I didn't see you!
No...
Or maybe his shadow's just too bright...
Detectives sure have a lot of free time.
Eh?
Might be different if somebody hadn't hung up on a client.
Oh, this manga's taking a break next week.
Man, I want to know what happens next.
The break's for the author to collect information.
But this could require investigation as well, right?
Huh? Why?
See, the only reason they ever give is that the
author is collecting information, right?
He could have just quit because he didn't like the work.
He could have caught the flu and is now unable to continue.
Or maybe he was kidnapped and is being held somewhere?
I don't think so...
But, it's like that actor who disappeared half a
year ago when they said he was taking a break.
But he was actually sick, right?
There was someone recently, too.
Let's see...
Right, they were on TV a lot...
They were there one minute and gone the next!
Oh, right! You mean Itakagi Roku?
You know, the musician who had his
breakthrough and debut last year!
Are you sure you haven't heard of him?
Y-Yeah, maybe.
I thought so, but Sonoko told me...
He's only been performing for one year,
But he already needs a break? Something's wrong.
Right?
Is Sonoko-neechan a fan of his?
Yeah, because he plays indie music.
The girls only go after him because he has money.
He's almost 007.
That guy is dead.
I saw him get dumped over a bridge.
Ah, I see.
Ever since he saw an ad for Itakagi Roku's latest CD on TV,
Takumi-kun has been telling you that, right?
Y-Yeah.
He's always saying "Papa, the saw guy is dead."
The saw guy?
It's because he looks like a saw!
Album Cover "Silver Sky, Volume 1"
It's probably because of his silver haircut.
But since there weren't any news reports on TV or on the radio,
At first I did not believe my son...
But when I heard he had taken a break...
I wasn't sure, so I told him we'd visit you, Detective Mouri.
We tried to call earlier, but someone
answered and hung up immediately.
Uh oh...
Hey!
Hey, Takumi-kun, do you know where this bridge is?
It seems like such a long time ago.
I can't remember exactly where, but...
I did hear fireworks there!
Then it could have been New Year's fireworks.
Hashiratani-san, do you remember where Takumi-kun was then?
No, but it must be on the way to the
temple we visited on New Year's.
We were in a traffic jam at the time, So I actually got pretty tired.
I guess I was too tired then to notice the fireworks.
Can you tell me exactly what happened there?
Let's see...
There was a man standing over the
bridge with a big bag beside him.
He then just picked up the bag and threw it over!
Then, Itakagi-san was in that bag?
But, how do you know he was in there?
Before he dropped it, I saw him!
There was a lot of blood...
But I also saw that guy's head!
I really seen it!
Don't be foolish, if someone were walking
around with that, someone would notice.
But, it was dark and hard to see.
So what? If it was actually that dark,
how did a little boy like you see him?
It just happened. His head just popped out of the bag.
What did the man do after dropping the bag?
He took out stuff from his clothes and dropped them.
I couldn't see because his body was blocking the way,
but he was feeling around his clothes for something.
Feeling around his clothes?
Did this guy have something in his mouth before that?
Yeah, there was something.
I see, a cigarette!
He had a cigarette in his mouth!
That means he was searching for his lighter!
And? Did he find his lighter?
Yeah, but he discarded it after lighting his cigarette.
And then, did he stick around?
Nope, he got in a car and left right after that.
Would you be able to recognize his car or face?
The car was in the dark, and all I could see was his hat.
But the person did have a strange picture on his arm!
Huh? A strange picture?
It was a strange nail.
A strange nail?
Oh, that's right!
I could see one more thing from the car's window.
There was this really big, glowing hammer!
A big glowing hammer?
A saw,
a nail,
and a hammer.
Do you think we believe this crap, you little punk!?
M... Mouri-san!
Ah, no... You were just joking with us, right, boy?
Takumi-kun, it's true, right?
Yeah.
You aren't...
Really lying, are you?
It's not a lie! I'm really not lying!
My chance!
If I remove the transmitter and listening device now...
Alright I've got it!
B-Boy?
Don't tell me, you... followed me here?
Of course not...
Just a coincidence.
I see...
Thank you.
You saved me, by getting my shoe...
Really, thank you.
Takumi-kun...
What this boy has said isn't a lie.
Huh? What're you saying?
It's been four days since New Year's.
If this were true, there would be something
on the news about a discovered body.
This is the evening news.
The male body found floating in
the Teimuzu river has been identified.
His family has confirmed that the body belongs to Itagaki Roku-san.
Itagaki Roku (22)
The body was found stuffed into a bag.
Because of the existence of wounds to
his head likely caused by a blunt weapon,
the police are treating this as a murder investigation.
It's... It's really true.
Then, Itagaki-san was really placed into a bag, as my son said...
It really happened, didn't it?
Of course! I don't lie!
Well, that means we should hurry and tell the police, right?
That's right. This kid's an eye witness.
But if you go in talking about Itakagi Roku's saw head,
About the nail on the criminal's arm,
And at the very least...
If you tell them you saw a giant glowing hammer from your car,
I doubt the police will trust what you say.
Besides, you can't remember which
bridge the body was thrown from.
Then, let's take Takumi-kun in a car...
And retrace everything they did that day.
We already know it was the Teimuzu river.
That's true, and I believe you said
it was on your way to a temple?
Hashiratani-san, do you remember at least
some of the route you took that day?
Well, yeah.
But, Eisuke-kun, it was great how you knew
he wasn't lying by touching his face.
Oh, no, it's nothing.
I was just doing what my father did when I was a child.
I just got lucky this time.
Well...
Which way'd you go at this intersection?
The right'll take us to the Big Haido Bridge.
Straight ahead takes us to Haido Central Bridge.
The left takes us to the New Haido Bridge.
Y-Yeah, going straight is the fastest way.
Then, let's take Haido Central Bridge.
But...
They always have sobriety checkpoints that way...
And since I was avoiding them...
Big Haido Bridge then?
Ah, no. There are too many traffic lights that way.
But the other's the longest way...
You think you can decide soon?
Sorry.
I always take this road to work.
What bridge I choose depends on my mood.
Unfortunately, I don't remember my mood that day...
Really...
You said you remembered the way!
I-I'm sorry...
Dad! It's alright.
We can check each bridge one by one.
If you're at this intersection, only those
three bridges cover the Teimuzu.
That's it, right, Conan-kun?
Conan-kun?
Yeah.
What's wrong? Don't you feel well?
It's not that.
Not at all.
Oh? I see then.
I was just doing what my father did when I was a child.
I just got lucky this time.
No, it wasn't any sort of luck.
This wasn't by chance.
He did just what that woman did to me.
Sudden irregularities in someone's breathing, their pulse, or
a widening in their pupils, can tell you if someone's lying.
Furthermore, their demeanors and behaviors...
They're almost identical.
As I thought, this guy...
And that woman...
Hondou... Eisuke...
You...
And her...
Are they somehow connected!?
Mizunashi Rena...
Known as "Kir" to them...
To the Black Organization!
Look, one of the buttons with which the
poster is attached to the wall is missing.
That's it!
That's the design I saw!
Are you sure boy?
Have you already done such a tattoo to anyone?
Right, look!
Clearly, this is what he had in mind!
Next Conan.
Shadow of the Black Organization.
The Strange Illumination!
Next Conan's Hint:
Nail & Snake.
Look forward to the next episode
Is it really how it seems?
That's how it is!