No matter what happens, I'm still your partner.
The Black Shadow lingers...
So does the mystery of the glowing hammer.
Now it's time to close the case!
Recognizing that single truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
At the Mouri Detective Agency, we were
visited by a father and his son,
The son, Takumi-kun, claimed he saw a
body dumped into the Teimuzu River.
But, he also said he saw a nail and a
glowing hammer around the same time.
Then, we saw a news report saying that the body of
popular musician Itagaki Roku-san had been found...
Shadow of the Black Organization.
The Strange Illumination!
This is the New Haido Bridge,
the next one over is Haido Central Bridge,
and the one beyond that is the Big Haido Bridge.
How about it, Takumi-kun?
Remember anything?
Nope.
Well, which side of the bridge was the
guy on when he dumped the bag?
I don't remember.
Then, did you see the fireworks behind him?
Just think about it...
Since the fireworks must have went off on this side,
you might be able to remember which side you were on.
Well, Takumi?
Fireworks?
I've got it!
Maybe...
That the hammer you saw was a firework reflecting in the water?
See...
When a firework first goes off, it looks like
a hammer. That's probably what he saw.
But still, that would have just been the end of the hammer.
When a firework goes off, it starts out shaped like a tadpole,
and eventually ends up looking like a frying pan, not a hammer.
Oh...
Hey...
I didn't see any fireworks.
I just heard something that sounded like them.
Oh, so that means there were no
fireworks on this side of the bridge?
Even if there were any, I doubt he would have seen them.
That night, Takumi was in the back, and
the lanes on both sides of us were full.
We were in the center lane, so the view from
the windows was probably blocked.
Okay, let's just go on to the next bridge.
Now we're on Haido Central Bridge, same side as last time.
Anything that comes to mind is a clue.
Okay, okay.
Hello?
Sonoko? What is it?
Didn't you hear!?
What?
"What"!? What do you mean by "what"!?
Roku! Roku's dead!
Yeah, I just saw it on the news.
Since you haven't remembered anything yet, how
about we forget about your "glowing hammer"?
I know, I know.
Maybe it'd be easier to search for a guy with a nail tattoo.
We used to ID people by their tattoos, but
now they're just a fashion statement.
Hey, Sonoko...
Did Itagaki Roku by any chance like nails or something?
Yeah. Something like a weird picture of a nail.
Sonoko, are you sure?
Like I just told you, it's the logo for
his old indies band "Nail Snake."
It's a snake with, a nail through its head.
Do you know anyone who does tattoos of that logo?
Yeah, they're all over.
I think there's a fan shop that doubles as a tattoo parlor.
Most fans have their tattoos done there.
I think it was somewhere near Haido Central Bridge...
Huh, Ran?
Ran?
Hey...
No! This isn't the picture I saw!
You sure about that?
It's definitely a snake with weird nails.
Couldn't the band's logo have changed?
Look, one of the pins used to stick it to the wall is missing.
Someone replaced it with scotch tape, right?
Another banner was placed behind this one at one point,
because you can see around the edges that the wall's discolored.
This means that something else was
there and was removed not long ago.
You're sharp, kid.
You're right, though.
This is the new logo.
It won't be official until next week.
That's the design!
That's the design that was on his arm!
Have you given this tattoo to anyone yet?
Eh? Yeah...
Some hardcore fans heard about it the logo change early.
They came here to get the design done.
Alright, here they are.
It was these three.
From right to left, Kiritani-san,
Yasui-san,
and Kannai-san.
A lot of people I do tattoos for send me photos later.
Takumi, do you recognize any of those three?
It was dark and he was wearing a hat so I'm not sure.
But I did see the nail as he was getting
into his car, which was nearby.
Car?
The man in the middle leaning against
the foreign car, does he own it?
Yeah, he's been driving it for ten years.
Hey, isn't this the car you saw?
It's black.
I don't know...
Well, what about the guy on the right with the hat?
That's not the hat.
Hey, why was the logo changed?
It's because Roku, who left the band
for his solo debut, designed the logo.
Most fans wanted to change it after he left.
With all that's happened with Roku and all...
Nail Snake's performing a live memorial here tonight.
Stuff was round between them, but Roku
and the band leader were best friends.
Behind this guy in the picture is...
OKINO YOKO-CHAN!?
Well, it looks like that coffee pot you can
win with the filter coffee I told you about.
I see. Yoko-chan must be doing their commercial.
You "see"? How'd you know about the
promotion without seeing it on TV?
Well...
It's because of this:
An advertising vehicle.
I thought it was cute, so I took a picture with my cell phone.
Wait! If they do advertising vehicles
for coffee pots, maybe they do...
Oh, never mind...
Can I see it, too?
Sure.
But it really is a cute coffee pot.
S-Sorry! I pressed the wrong button!
It's okay. Don't worry about it.
Alright, our last stop: Big Haido Bridge.
I know you still don't remember anything.
Where did you see that suspicious guy at?
Let's just call the police.
Takumi's telling the truth, right?
And he really did see it.
But, the police are gonna question that.
Especially that "glowing hammer" business.
I see! So that's how it is?
I've got it.
I know who packed Itagaki Roku-san
into that bag and dumped him.
But I really did see it!
It was this huge glowing hammer!
Look, kid...
It was probably a dream.
A dream?
N-No, it wasn't!
The part about Itagaki-san being stuffed
into a bag was probably a coincidence.
You probably dreamed up his face coming
out of the bag and the snake tattoo, too.
Since it was New Year's Eve and dark and stuff,
You wouldn't be able to see a tattoo.
That's true.
Wait a second...
Could it be... Fireworks?
Fireworks would light up everything
around, at least for a moment.
There would be fireworks then, right?
Then the suspect was on the other side,
where you could see the fireworks.
If he was over there when the fireworks went off,
you wouldn't be able to see his tattoo.
I... I see.
But, if the guy was on the other side and he
could see the head coming out of the bag,
how did he identify the tattoo?
Even if Takumi-kun's car was in the middle
lane, it'd still be hard to see the handrail.
So how could he see the driver's arm?
Stupid. I could see his arm because the
car's driver side window was down!
Still, if it was so dark out, I don't see
how you could see his tattoo.
But if he was the driver, how could you see it anyway?
But, I did...
Maybe...
He had his arm hanging outside the window?
Wait, that means the tattoo was on his right arm,
because we can only see the car's right
side from here and not his left arm.
Alright! Let's get back to that tattoo shop
for one last look at those pictures!
We can't.
They're closing at 6:00 for the live memorial service.
Um...
Maybe...
Maybe there's a snapshot of them on your cell phone.
Right, Eisuke-niichan?
Found it! It's here!
But I don't remember taking this picture.
Um...
I think it happened when I pressed that button by accident...
Well, going by their pictures, we can eliminate the
guy on the left who has a tattoo on his left arm.
That means the criminal must be one of the other two, right?
The criminal had a car, right?
The guy with a car in his picture must be the one!
Stupid!
The guy on the right probably has a car, too.
But that guy said he'd been driving foreign cars for ten years.
That just means he likes foreign cars. It doesn't mean he's the...
Foreign cars?
Their steering wheel's position is reversed.
That means if he had a foreign car,
the wheel would be on the left.
Ran, let me see that.
But, maybe he rented a Japanese car that day?
No.
If he rented a car, it'd have to be a foreign one.
He wouldn't want to end up in a car accident with
a dead body because he wasn't used to the wheel.
Then, the criminal is...
Yeah, the guy on the right with the hat.
I think his name was Kiritani.
Then let's hurry and report this to the police...
No, it's to early for that.
All we have is circumstanial evidence.
We need some solid proof.
But the police could take him to the station and interrogate him.
They could make him confess.
Just as long as we have Takumi-kun's testimony.
Just remember.
Don't mention anything about a glowing hammer.
Ah, I understand.
But I really... I really did see it!
Takumi...
Hey...
Maybe it's that building?
Look! When both sides of the elevator are lit
up, it looks like the handle of a hammer.
Hey, it can't be a hammer without the "hammer" end of it.
What does the top of a hammer usually look like?
There are lots of types.
You've got your straight ones,
the ones that look like upside-down boats,
the ones where the middle is rounded and looks like a pot...
Pot!?
That's it!
I knew it! Look!
The coffee pot's lit up!
The hammer was upside down, right?
What Takumi-kun saw was the lights on the
advertising vehicle and the elevator overlapping,
making the shape of a glowing hammer!
So it wasn't a dream, huh?
Sorry, Takumi-kun.
It's okay.
You should have told us that earlier...
But didn't the fireworks go up on this side?
If he was on the side opposite the fireworks,
Takumi couldn't have seen the building.
Although you can't see it from here...
You can easily see it from Haido Central Bridge.
So the criminal dumped the body from
the bag from Haido Central Bridge?
Yeah, most likely.
We'll probably be able to find some evidence over there.
"Over there"?
The elevator of that building sticks out a bit.
To see both rows of lights completely,
You have to be at a certain angle.
The rest of the time, the coffee pot won't
align and it won't resemble a hammer.
So, you have to be at a specific place
to see perfect glowing hammer.
With this knowledge,
we'll be able to find where the criminal dumped the body.
But what kind of evidence can be there?
Probably...
If the criminal threw away the lighter,
the criminal must of had a reason for getting rid of it.
Even if he wore gloves when dumping the bag,
he probably took them off when he used the lighter.
Since his tattoo is on his wrist, Takumi-kun
couldn't have seen the tattoo otherwise.
Do you think he's going to Roku-san's memorial concert?
It's possible, but we need more evidence
before approaching him.
You know what...
I have an idea about how to make the bad guy confess.
And, last of all...
Our dear Roku's favorite song.
Hey, what're you doing? This is the parking lot!
We'll get in trouble if a car catches on fire!
Oh, just some kid...
Excuse me, I'm with the police.
Would you come with us for questioning?
Huh? Why?
Someone fitting your description was
seen on Haido Central Bridge...
Dumping a dead body from a bag into the river.
They're pretty sure it's you. We've got
them watching from over there.
They saw my face?
No, not your face. It was...
Your tattoo.
Oh, that's right.
I think they heard your voice, too.
Oh, they must have made that up. No
way they could have heard my voice.
Because there were fireworks...
Oh?
They couldn't have heard your voice because of the fireworks?
Did you get that, Takagi-kun?
Yes, sir. Loud and clear.
Only the killer and the witness would
have known about the fireworks.
So, could you tell us why...
You phrased it like that?
Then, those fireworks just now...
That's right.
We set this up and had these officers pretend to question you.
Actually, we just wanted to jog your memory
of the incident with the fireworks.
Well, it's best to leave such childish tricks to kids.
Afterwards, Kiritani-san was taken into custody.
He confessed to the crime.
He was angry that Itagaki Roku-san
left the band for his solo debut.
He'd planned to bury the body in the mountains, but...
After seeing the sobriety checkpoints at
the end of the Haido Central Bridge...
He decided to dump him into the river.
What he threw in afterwards was Roku-san's lighter.
After killing Roku-san by hitting him in the head,
he wore a jumper he found in the room to hide the blood on him.
He realized that he'd accidentally used
Roku's lighter from the jumper.
The lighter was recovered from the Teimuzu River,
and it looks like Kiritani-san will be charged with murder.
After we finished telling our story
to the police, we headed home...
Man, today was really exciting!
I got to work on a case where a famous person died.
No, no.
There must be more, right?
More cases with famous people.
Or at least cases about them, right?
Of course.
A few for Okino Yoko-chan.
Eh!? For that top idol!?
You're really a great detective!
Really?
I bet there've been cases with famous
people that didn't go public.
You know, like if a famous person asked you to do it in secret...
And before it made the news,
you solved it.
Has there even been a case like that?
Oh, c'mon!
Don't be embarassed to tell me, Detective Mouri!
Hey, why don't we talk about it over dinner?
Ohh, I'm feeling pretty sleepy.
Sorry Eisuke-kun, we'll have to do it some other time.
Conan-kun's tired it seems.
That's okay.
There's no doubt.
There was someone recently, too.
Let's see...
Right, they were on TV a lot...
They were there one minute and gone the next!
This guy's digging for information...
Mizunashi Rena...
I won't show you my hand that easily...
Especially since...
You're hiding your hand so well.
What? Case?!
Toria Street?
The boy from then...
There's no doubt!
Is he really...
brought us here knowing this?
Next Conan:
Shadow of the Black Organization:
The Mystery of the Big Reward!
Next Conan's Hint:
The Red-Headed League.
Look Forward to the next episode
I love Holmes!
You're just like that other Holmes freak.
Ah- that's true.