No matter what happens, I'm still your partner.
After reasoning through the darkness,
we've finally came to a case that involves the Organization!
Recognizing that single truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
After a boy and his father visited the Mouri
Detective Agency, we began an investigation...
Which got us involved in a murder case.
But something Hondou Eisuke did...
The way he could tell if that boy was lying...
It was the same thing Mizunashi Rena had done to me.
There's no doubt.
This guy's digging for information on...
Mizunashi Rena.
Shadow of the Black Organization.
The Mystery of the Big Reward!
Kir...
Nothing has turned up despite our
Organization's relentless search.
The FBI's gotten pretty good.
Kir's dead.
No doubt about it.
Let's hope you're right.
They could force her to betray us...
That won't happen.
Even after being shot, infected with truth serum, and
beaten until her ribs cracked, she didn't give it up.
There's nothing to worry about, Chianti.
You mean that incident where Anokata
deemed Kir worthy of joining us?
Yeah.
I heard about that.
Kir smoked out a rat who snuck into
the organization and cornered him.
Naturally, he reversed the situation and tortured
her, almost killing her before you guys showed up.
But there's something I still don't get.
What could Kir have used to make Anokata let her join us?
Her teeth.
Kir used her last remaining weapon and bit down
on that guy's wrist until she reached bone.
On top of that,
She took the gun he'd dropped in the struggle...
And blew his head off.
That's proof that she snapped.
But the rat did die, right?
How do we know Kir didn't leak anything?
Because of what the rat had in his pocket.
He had an MD that was recording the interrogation.
An MD?
I get it...
Kir's voice wasn't recorded on it.
But, Partner, we never did found out who that rat was, did we?
No.
With his disguised face on all of those fake passports
and licenses, he definitely wasn't an ordinary rat.
But at least we found out his real name.
Oh yeah...
One of his colleagues came after us and started
talking to him without noticing us, right?
Yeah. Right into that dead rat's ear...
He kept saying a name we didn't recognize
from any of the licenses or passports.
Over and over...
He eventually noticed us and decided to kill himself.
What was his name, anyway?
I was too far away to hear.
Well, damn.
I always seem to forget the names and faces of dead people.
Still, I have an idea of who the rat is.
I'll ask Kir when she comes back.
I'm sure she heard the name, too.
I hope we find her soon.
We will.
There's already a lead that's being investigated.
Geez, what're you thinking?
It's Sunday. I just wanna sit back, relax,
and enjoy some coffee here at Poirot.
So, what're you doing here,
Hondou Eisuke?
Oh, come on now. Don't be mean.
Wasn't it you who said he could come
over whenever he wanted, Dad?
But it's 7:00 in the morning...
Why so early?
Well, I actually brought some information on an interesting case.
W-What!? A case!?
Is the client rich?
No, um...
It's just something I saw on someone's internet homepage...
So there isn't a client.
Hey, Dad!
You idiot! You think we're running some type of charity here?
At least hear him out. He came all the way here to tell you.
I don't have time...
Nope, you don't!
Uncle, you're organizing your Okino Yoko-chan videos today.
Right?
Oh! That's right!
Oh, that's weird. Conan-kun's usually
really interested in new cases...
Yeah, normally I am...
Just not his cases.
Sorry, Eisuke-kun.
No, it's nothing.
It's just something that hit me...
After I read "The Red-Headed League", it peaked my interest.
"The Red-Headed League"!?
Oh, I know that one!
That's a famous case from a Sherlock Holmes story, right?
A red-headed man was paid a very high salary
for staying in a room to copy an encyclopedia.
All the while, from his store's basement,
people were digging a tunnel to a bank.
Hey, what about that case?
Well? What kind is it?
But the case's not really...
Just spill it!
Geez, Dad!
I found it last night.
It was someone's journal on their homepage.
Hey, why were you reading someone else's journal?
Ah, no...
Some people make their homepages open to everyone.
Oh. You kids and your weird habits.
So, the owner of that home page has red hair?
No, the only thing it has in common with
"The Red-Headed League" is the high salary.
One of the journal entries said:
"Finally, a job! Hurray for the economy!
Got some good luck this year!"
He said the employer is from an organization trying to
reduce garbage burning since it hurts the environment.
All the job involves is collecting the garbage
the day before it's picked up...
And switching it with the garbage
taken out on the next garbage day.
He loads the van and returns it to the parking lot.
That afternoon, some money gets deposited into his account...
50,000 yen.
50,000 yen?
But wait...
50,000 yen each trip, two days a week...
450,000 per month, right?
450,000?
450,000!?
C'mon, Dad. This could be a crime.
But it's true. The high wages do make it
a lot like "The Red-Headed League."
Right?
He said he found the job on the net and
that everything else was done by email.
Three days after agreeing to the job, the car key arrived.
He's had the job for two weeks now.
Is that so?
I'd say some famous person live near there, and there's
some rich stalker going through their garbage.
The writer thought the same thing at first,
but he later wrote that no one famous lived near there.
Oh... I see.
Another strange thing is that no one goes through the garbage.
He took a picture of the garbage in the trunk
with his digital camera after loading it.
He came back the next day and compared the
garbage with his picture, but nothing had changed.
So, what's the job for?
Dunno...
Well then, maybe it's like the plot of the story, where the
employer is doing something in the worker's house.
Well, you know his address?
No, that wasn't on the homepage.
But the place where the garbage's collected was.
I think it was 3rd Street Park in Toriya City?
Toriya City?
What is it, Dad? Is something happening there?
Actually, Ran...
I heard a new pachinko parlor opened
there, so I can go and test it out!
Then, why don't we go there now?
It's not yet 9:00, so that person might be there now!
Alright, let's go!
Toriya City, huh?
Hold on a second...
Today's February 5th, a Sunday.
In this area, they collect garbage on Mondays
and again four days later, on Thursdays.
I guess so.
You "guess"!? You...
Garbage isn't picked up on Sundays anywhere.
Oh, that's right.
One of the journal entries said the employer wanted the
trash collected very early since he wasn't sure of it all yet.
Idiot! You should've told me that earlier!
Whatever! I'm going to walk around
until the pachinko parlor opens.
You guys take the train home.
What!?
Geez...
Um, excuse me, sir.
The day before yesterday around 9 or 10 in the
evening, did you see a tall, suspicious...
That you, Takagi?
M-Mouri-san!
The hell are you doing?
That's what I wanna know.
Hey, hey! Mouri-kun! You again?
Inspector!
You aren't involved in this case, are you?
What?
A murder. Don't you watch the news?
A murder case?
It's this house.
Well, it's nice.
I have the information right here.
Let's see...
The victim was the wife of this house's
owner, Funemoto Tatsuhito-san.
Kaneyosan, 39 years old.
Around noon yesterday, the housekeeper went to check on her.
She found the wife leaning against the veranda
of her room, shot in the back of the head.
Based on the angle of the bullet's entry point,
the shooter was at least 180cm tall.
The estimated time of death is the
day before yesterday between...
9:00 and 10:00 in the evening.
It happened just after she came back from a friend's home party.
I see. A home party, huh?
Some of the things she had with her at the
party are missing, so we're looking around...
But nothing has come up yet.
Any word on the motive?
It was most likely burglary.
The pearl necklace and bracelet she
wore to the party are missing.
We believe that's where the crime started.
How about witnesses?
Well...
Since she didn't come back from the party until late,
no one was awake to hear anything from her room.
I see.
Judging from the lack of evidence,
the criminal must've been a pro.
Yeah, that's what I think--
What is it, Inspector?
You idiot!
Why are we telling him about the case!?
He has nothing to do with it at all!
Now, now, Inspector...
Force of habit, I guess.
Sorry.
Toriya City...
A murder case...
Could it be...
That this guy bringing us here was a coincidence?
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
Ah, did you figure something out?
No...
Oh no, not this again.
You all shouldn't be involved.
Leave this case to the police.
You all should go.
Look at the time!
Mouri-san?
Excuse me, Inspector!
Please forgive me.
The rest is up to you!
What, you're leaving?
Wait, Dad!
Why did Mouri-san run off in such a hurry?
Well, you see...
He's investigating... something.
Investigating? Something?
Mouri-san?
Yes?
You're that famous detective Mouri...
Mouri Kogorou-san, am I right?
Yes, I'm Mouri Kogorou.
Shigeno Takami (48)
Housekeeper
Please help us find the criminal who killed the missis!
Well, actually...
You can count on the police for that.
I can't rely on them!
Please, Mouri-san!
I understand how you feel.
But I've really got to be somewhere...
Please help us.
Uh...
Dad...
All right.
It would be an honor for me, Mouri Kogorou,
to find the one who killed the missis.
Thank you very much!
What's going on out there?
Keep it down, Kaneyo's wake is tonight.
Oh, sir. Please forgive me.
This is the great detective, Mouri-san.
Funemoto Tatsuhito (43)
Owner of the Funemoto Estate
Mouri...
Ah, then you're that famous...
Yes.
I'm the famous Mouri Kogorou.
But what're you doing here?
I actually came here by chance.
Mouri-kun...
I've got this.
I'm going to take the case.
I'm going to find the one who killed her.
Sir, he has solved many cases!
Well, I wouldn't say that...
Mouri...
It's alright, Inspector.
Mouri-san has helped us out on a lot of cases.
Takagi!
Oh, Dad...
Well, this is still a good thing, right?
Sorry, Eisuke-kun.
It's okay. We'll get to it later.
Well, he isn't very anxious.
One of them would be.
Meitantei Man!
I know who the criminal is!
Hey! Touji!
Who are you, kid?
This is my son, Touji.
Funemoto Touji (8)
Tatsuhito's Son
So you're the little man, eh?
The one who killed my mom was a
foreign lady dressed all in black!
Hey, cut that out.
Why, Papa?
Why won't you believe me?
Son, let's go this way.
No! Let me go!
A woman dressed in all black...
A foreign woman?
Wait, that boy...
Ah, son!
Touji!
Believe me! I really saw her. Believe me, Uncle!
I know that suspicious foreign lady killed my mom!
Where have I seen this boy?
I really saw her, Uncle!
Believe me! Please, Uncle!
Hey, you.
What made that foreign woman suspicious?
It's because of her weird questions!
Weird questions?
About the accident!
"Did you see really the accident?"
"Did you see the face of the one in the accident?"
"Did you tell your papa and mama about it?"
Accident!?
Could it be...
And? How did you answer.
After I said I kinda told my mom...
She started smiling.
That means she must have killed her!
That's right! This boy!
At that time...
That accident...
Where that Black Organization member...
Kir, also known as Mizunashi Rena...
That accident where she was taken unconscious to the hospital.
He was at the scene of the accident...
This boy.
There's no doubt!
Does that mean...
This guy knew, and brought us here?
What is he conspiring...
With this boy?
No, with the only witness of the accident...
The accident where he saw the FBI confront her.
It seems there's no way out...
That accident...
And...
Mizunashi Rena.
If I'm right, the Black Organization must know about it.
They know the FBI has Mizunashi Rena, no, Kir.
You're an amusing character.
I don't know what's coming, but...
Alright.
I'll take it.
This case...
I'll follow through with it until the end.
This is recent...
Or maybe they are in the trash?
In the trash?
There's something here...
An onion?
Is it really?
Falling star.
Next Conan:
Shadow of the Black Organization:
The Pearl Shooting Star!
Next Conan's Hint:
Setsubun no Mamemaki.
Look forward to the next episode
Throw them!
It's time to shock the ones in black!
Are you listening to me, Conan-kun?