No matter what happens, I'm still your partner.
The Black Organization and a little boy.
We came across it by accident,
but we have to solve this case!
Recognizing that single truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Hondou Eisuke came to Uncle with
a case about a weird part time job.
When we went to Toriya City to check out garbage exchange
for ourselves, we found out it wasn't done on Sundays.
With no luck, we met up with the police...
Who introduced us to a murder case.
And, by chance, we met the boy who
witnessed Mizunashi Rena's accident.
Funemoto Touji (8)
Tatsuhito's Son
There's no doubt.
Which means...
This guy knew, and brought us here?
It's finally getting interesting.
Shadow of the Black Organization.
The Pearl Shooting Star!
Well?
What kind of accident was it?
Well, see...
Someone riding a motorcycle suddenly flew over me.
Then their helmet came off.
And then...
That's a scene from Masked Yaiba!
Masked Yaiba?
Yep.
From when Masked Yaiba was being chased.
These guys were attacking him while he was riding,
and his helmet fell off and almost gave away his identity!
You're wrong!
I really did...
Hey... Have we met before?
I don't think so.
Then, what the boy's telling us...
Yeah...
To cope with the shock of losing his mother, he's probably
confusing reality with something he saw in a movie or on TV.
If the murderer wanted to cover up that accident,
this boy would have been killed as well.
The wife went jogging four times a week,
after taking out the garbage.
It makes more sense to use a gun and kill her then.
Especially compared to breaking into the
second floor and waiting for her, right?
That's true.
Then, let's visit her room.
Uncle Kogoro might be able to figure something out.
Uh, Inspector?
What is it?
Funemoto Tatsuhito (43)
Owner of the Funemoto Estate
May I wait down here?
Sure. I don't mind.
Has he been in the wheelchair long?
Shigeno Takami (48)
Housekeeper
No, only for about a month now.
On a fishing trip with some friends from work,
he fell on the rocks and broke his leg.
The doctor said that the cast can come off in a couple of weeks.
So, his room's on the first floor?
No, it's here on the second floor beside of the mistress's.
When he wants to go upstairs, he leans against
me. I carry up the wheelchair afterwards.
This is the mistress's room.
Is this the veranda...
Where she was found with the gunshot wound to the head?
But, how did the culprit get in?
Our man used a hook and rope on the handrail, climbed
up onto the veranda, broke the window, and snuck in.
This spot overlooks a drainage bank, so not
many people were around at the time.
But isn't it weird?
The glass near the bottom lock is broken,
but the glass at the top isn't.
It'd be hard to open the door this way, right?
Yeah, we noticed that earlier.
Stop running around, Conan-kun.
The mistress liked stargazing,
so she'd often stand out on the veranda and look at the sky.
She probably just forgot to lock it.
She was shot between 9:00 and 10:00 at night after
coming back from a friend's home party, is that right?
Yes. When she came back, she said she
was going straight to her room to sleep.
That means the culprit had already
snuck in and was hiding somewhere.
Allowing him to step out and shoot her
when she went out to the veranda.
He probably left after getting the pearl necklace and bracelet.
I knew it. It was a pro.
But, that guy was somewhat careless.
He left the hook and rope along with the
gun and its silencer down on the ground.
Well, even pro's make mistakes.
But his guy was kinda dumb, don't you think?
Look, there's a pearl earring on the table.
It's loaded with stones and looks really expensive.
Shouldn't he have taken it, too?
Stupid! She probably wore the earrings to the
party and took it off when she came in.
She was killed right after that,
so the criminal probably didn't even notice it.
Oh, she was wearing those earrings that day.
But why is there only one?
She was wearing the other, right?
Yeah, it was on her right ear.
He probably missed it because of how
she was leaning against the veranda.
Well, she sure was in a hurry, huh?
W-What?
Well, usually, you wouldn't step out onto the veranda
after taking off only one earring, would you?
That is unless someone called her out to the veranda...
While she was taking them off.
Excuse me, but where were you two days ago,
between 9:00 and 10:00 in the evening?
You mean me?
I was with a couple of friends in the living room downstairs.
Then, those friends saw her alive?
Yeah, after coming home, she peeked into the
living room to tell me she was going to bed.
And the boy?
I think he was asleep already.
He'd been running around the house the whole afternoon.
After my friends left, I cleaned up after him
and went to sleep around midnight.
And what was the man of the house doing from 9:00 to 10:00?
Like Touji, he ate dinner and got to bed
before the mistress returned home.
His room is next to her's though, right?
Yeah.
He kept saying how tired he was
from playing with his son all day.
Inspector...
Does that mean the husband is the murderer?
That's impossible.
Didn't I tell you?
Judging from the angle of the bullet's
entry and exit points on her head...
The culprit must be at least 180cm tall.
The husband is only 150cm...
And is even shorter in a wheelchair.
But what if his leg already healed and he shot
her after standing on the wheelchair?
What about that?
We considered that at first,
but his doctor said the latest X-Ray indicated it
was impossible for him to stand on his own.
So, that probably isn't the case.
Maybe he had her kneel over so he could shoot her from above?
It's not that either.
If that were true, there would be
a bullet in this room somewhere.
We haven't found a bullet in this house,
much less this room.
I-I guess you're right.
Also, we've been looking for the pearl necklace and
the bracelet and haven't come up with anything.
Maybe it's in the garbage.
Garbage?
That's right.
It could be related to the case Eisuke-kun discovered.
A case...?
What're they talking about?
There's a group researching the burning
of garbage's effect on the environment.
They hired someone to collect garbage
around here at a very high salary.
Even after doing it for two weeks, there've been
no signs that anyone has touched the garbage.
I see.
That means the husband killed his wife,
threw away the necklace and bracelet
to make it look like a robbery,
and had already hired someone to dispose
of the garbage beforehand?
That can't be.
No, that's impossible as well.
We checked all of the garbage,
both what was ready to be taken out and what
was already out, and still found nothing.
I see.
So, how much was the necklace and the bracelet worth?
About one million yen for the pair.
My employer bought them for his wife as a birthday present,
and even had her name engraved on the clasp.
Hey, Takami-san!
Could you turn on the air conditioner?
Yes, sir.
Why can't he do it?
He's not good with technology.
Sorry.
It's nothing.
Oh, the police are still here?
Did you find anything?
No, not exactly.
Hey, Papa. I'm hungry.
It is past lunch...
Then I'll order some take-out.
Come on, now. That's all we've had since yesterday.
All right. I'll go make something.
What's that?
What is this?
An onion?
Let's see, what do we have...
Is there anything I can do?
It looks like you have a lot of dishes to do.
I just haven't had time, with everything that's happened.
I'd love the extra help.
Alright.
The expiration date for these eggs is February 4th...
That's yesterday, so maybe you shouldn't use them.
Wait, if February 4th was yesterday...
Two days ago was...
The 3rd!?
Wait, Ran-neechan!
Hey, what'd you make for dinner two days ago?
Two days ago?
Let's see...
Teriyaki fish, boiled vegetables, miso
soup, and some cold tofu, I think.
Oh?
That sounds great.
Takami-san, is it ready?
Ah, no.
I think we need new ingredients.
Can you hurry it up, then? I'm starving.
Yes, sir.
Let's leave for now and come back tomorrow.
Then, I...
I'm...
I'm done here?
Yep.
Hold on!
Don't you think this case could be related to that guy's job?
You again?
But if we stay a bit longer, we may be able to connect them!
Geez...
W-What're you doing?
I just figured out...
The trick the criminal used to get rid of the wife's jewelry.
It's a blind spot we carelessly missed.
Wait a second...
Don't tell me they were flushed down the toilet?
You know when we checked the sewage
pipes, we didn't find anything!
If they could be flushed down the toilet,
there'd be no reason to spend so much money.
I'm going out.
No, let's have...
Ran,
Eisuke-kun,
and Funemoto-san's son, Touji-kun, go.
Is that alright with you?
Yeah, I have no issue with that.
Hey...
What the hell're you doing, Mouri-kun?
You keep changing your mind every minute.
Well, changing his mind is something he does often...
He's too young to know the truth.
Imagine him knowing his mother was killed by his own father...
Tatsuhito-san.
I thought it'd be best if he didn't find out this way.
I know that he was in the room next to her's
on the second floor when she was killed...
But he's only 150cm and in a wheelchair.
He wouldn't have been able to hide the jewelry like this.
Keep in mind, along with the missing
pearl bracelet and necklace,
she also had pearl earrings.
Yeah, I remember Conan-kun said...
"Unless someone called her out to the veranda."
Inspector, doesn't it bother you?
How he was able to get his wife...
To suddenly go out onto the veranda...
With words.
Words?
Most likely, Funemoto-san said:
"A shooting star!"
"Look, up there!"
Right?
"A shooting star"?
"Up there"?
I see!
That would make her rush out to the veranda...
Since she loved stars!
And "up there"?
If he made her look up, he could shoot her from the wheelchair,
making the bullet go through the back of her head.
This would make us think the culprit was really tall.
That way, the gun will be facing upward,
so the bullet will fly out into the drainage bank.
So, the glass at the bottom was broken...
Because he was in a wheelchair and
couldn't reach the glass at the top.
But what about the pearls?
If he's the murderer, where did her pearls go?
Funemoto-san can't move about with a broken leg.
Did you really check everywhere in the house?
Yeah, we checked every place they could be.
What about the vacuum cleaner?
The vacuum cleaner?
We actually didn't look there...
But he couldn't use it since he's bad with technology anyway.
And if he did use it, it'd make a lot of noise.
I agree that if he used it, someone would have noticed...
But what about Shigeno-san?
Try to remember the day after the case...
He was playing with Touji-kun, who made a mess,
which was cleaned up by Shigeno-san.
What're you getting at?
It's normal for a kid to make a mess while playing around.
Yeah, but it was February 3rd.
February?
3rd?
February 3rd?
You mean...
Right, a traditional event from ancient times...
Setsubun, right?
Conan-kun?
Setsubun?
Touji-kun probably had his dad wear a mask
and throw beans around with him, saying:
"Demons out, good luck in!"
And since Shigeno-san cleaned up the mess...
Hey, you don't mean...
He took the pearl jewelry apart!?
Since they're similar in size and with so many there...
He knew she wouldn't notice the pearls
there since she was rushing to finish.
It would be hard for her to tell, after all, since
the beans and pearls look so much alike.
In other words, he planned it all.
Funemoto-san played setsubun no mamemaki with Touji-kun in
order to make sure the murder on the veranda was covered up.
He then set up the hook and rope and broke the bottom
glass of the door to make it look a break-in.
And afterwards, he removed the pearls from her bracelet
and necklace and hid them until the next day.
After playing with his son, he tossed the pearls over
the railing to the first floor to mix in with the beans.
Leaving Shigeno-san to vacuum them up.
Check the vacuum cleaner!
Yes, sir!
So, he planned to throw away the vacuum's
bag that his collector would get, right?
Yeah, he was likely going to cancel the job soon
and collect the pearls when his leg healed.
I would assume he planned to have them pawned after that.
I see. Since her name's on the bracelet...
It'd seem like an outsider really did steal the pearls.
But what about evidence? There's no evidence, right?
Fingerprints.
Even if his fingerprints are on the pearls, that won't mean...
It's not the pearls.
I figured it all out when I saw a piece of an
onion on the wheel of his wheelchair.
Since it was on his wheels, it must have been on his hands.
Onion?
So onions must have been on whatever he touched.
Whatever he touched that had a piece of an onion on it was...
Most likely a rubber glove from the kitchen.
He took them from the kitchen after
dinner and used them to shoot her.
The next morning, he put them back while
Shigeno-san went to check on her.
Inspector! We found the pearls in the bag!
Look for onions on the kitchen's rubber gloves!
Yes, sir!
Something Funemoto-san didn't expect was that Shigeno-san
would be discouraged from cooking after finding the body.
That's why you wanted her to make a meal earlier, right?
So that she'd have to use the rubber gloves to wash the dishes.
After she used them, your fingerprints
inside the gloves would be gone.
Funemoto-san...
If I missed anything, please correct me.
S-Sir, it isn't true! Say it isn't true!
Did you know?
She was addicted to partying.
I didn't even notice...
Until I had to stay home more because of my injury.
My wife had been sponsoring extravogent
parties, week after week.
I knew she was fond of that lifestyle...
But I had no idea.
Money, money! There's no money!
I know! We can take out a second mortgage!
Hey...
Oh, is something wrong? You want a divorce instead?
You can't make me shine anymore anyway.
I've got plenty of other sponsors to go to.
Hey...
You can take over with Touji.
I'm tired of raising him.
A star like me can't be dragging a kid around, right?
It was those words...
Coming from a wife and mother...
I'm home!
Papa!
What's wrong?
Are you crying?
Do you want to throw beans again?
If we do, it'll make Mama happy up in Heaven!
That's right, Touji.
But Papa needs to go out of the house for a while.
Since a demon like me took something special from you.
Huh? He's already gone?
After showering Touji-kun with questions,
he suddenly said he had something to do.
Showering him with questions?
He kept asking him about the accident and the foreign woman.
Touji-kun said that when he asked the woman who
she was, all she said was "uma, uma" in English.
Uma, uma?
That's weird, isn't it?
Umaa... Uuma... Uman...
A secret makes a Woman Woman...
V... Vermouth!
Hondou.
The name of the rat we were talking about.
The guy that Kir killed?
Yeah.
His partner kept chanting his name like a
monk into that rat's ear. He kept saying...
Hondou, Hondou, Hondou!
Right?
Let's split up and look for her.
Damn!
Wait, Genta! There is a cliff!
There! It's her!
She's down there!
If this is a murder, the offender is probably among them.
Next Conan.
The Unsmashable Snowman,
Part One!
Next Conan's Hint:
Snowman Gloves!
Look forward to the next episode
Officer Takagi likes gloves, doesn't he?
What're you doing!?