No matter what happens, I'm still your partner.
With a chilling event coming,
the Detective Boys build a snowman,
forging the tracks of the case!
Recognizing that single truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Nicely done, Shinichi.
Yeah, yeah... So great, so great.
The Unsmashable Snowman, Part One!
Huh? Where is everybody?
Look, they're over there.
Geez, they said they'd let me teach them to snowboard earlier...
Now all they wanna do is build a snowman.
So, regardless, is everything alright?
With that boy who saw Mizunashi Rena's motorcycle accident.
I was thinking that the foreign woman helmet may have been...
Yeah, that woman from the Black Organization...
Vermouth, I believe.
W-What'd you say!?
Doesn't that mean...
Don't you get it!?
That means they already know about her accident!
Yeah, they almost definitely know...
About Mizunashi Rena's injuries and hospitalization.
Hey, Shinichi...
But that's all they know.
They definitely don't know where.
Furthermore, I already told Jodie-sensei
from the FBI about that case.
The FBI won't let her be found easily.
But, is the boy alright?
The FBI is protecting and watching over him as of now,
but I don't believe the organization's interested in him anymore.
If they wanted to kill him, they would've done it earlier.
But isn't it strange?
That the house where a murder occurred...
Is also Where the boy who met that woman lived?
It's no coincidence.
I was concerned as well...
So I looked Mizunashi Rena up on the
net and found something interesting.
A big fan's homepage dedicated to
the announcer Mizunashi Rena.
Then it hit me:
This was the guy who was hired for that strange
job and was an indirect cause of that case.
One day, he was wearing his custom
jacket with her picture on it...
When something strange happened...
"When I finished the job and was on my way home,
some kid pointed at my jacket saying,
'I saw her fly off her motorcycle!'
His said his name was Touji."
But that means that guy read it.
That guy?
Yeah...
The guy who connected that murder
case, the boy, and the strange job...
The guy who lead Uncle Kogoro and myself
to a case which took us to the boy's house...
The guy who had me meet that boy again...
Hondou Eisuke.
Hondou Eisuke?
He's a transfer student at Ran's school.
His eyes are identical to Mizunashi Rena's.
Hey, hey, hey, don't tell me that transfer student...
They could have sent him to locate Mizunashi Rena.
That's just one possibility, but, that guy...
I just don't think so.
I can't really describe it, he just doesn't seem evil.
You idiot! What if that's their plan,
to make you lower your guard!?
But that guy...
Cried.
Didn't I mention it?
The saw, nails, and hammer case?
He cried at that time.
It may have been that he was angry he couldn't solve the case...
Or maybe it was because he knew the answer,
but couldn't think of a way to show it.
But then, he did cry...
It just looks like its crying!
Hey, come on!
It looks more like an alien, doesn't it, Mitsuhiko?
Yeah.
It was a great idea to buy fruit on the way here, huh?
Yeah!
Hey, you kids! Don't touch that!
Kokura Sakuko (22)
University Student
That's our graduation project.
That's only the outline, though.
Kiyama Tanji (22)
University Student
It's a graduation project?
Is this a snow model?
That's right.
We re students at a sculpturing art college.
Onoue Asaka (22)
University Student
We four love snow.
So much what we begged our professor to let us do this.
But it looks like this guy's the only one working on it.
Well, it isn't like that.
Itabashi Kazuya (22)
University Student
I make the starting form before we discuss the figure.
When we're done, we take a picture with it,
and call it our final snow sculpture.
At first, everyone does their own part,
which helps me do the frame.
We named it "The Grieving Snowman. "
The head's basically finished,
but the body isn't.
Well, take your time.
Don't say that.
We're leaving the day after tomorrow.
If you don't hurry and finish the frame...
You shouldn't say that, Sakuko.
Itabashi stayed just for us.
You can put it that way, but doing a four
person project was you three's idea.
I never agreed to it.
Now, now, this is our last winter vacation as university students.
Yeah, that's right, this may be our last time together.
We four may never be together again after graduation.
Right, Asaka-chan?
Yep.
Is that so?
Why don't the four of us go night-skiing to celebrate?
Oh, that's right, not all of us can.
Hey, Sakuko! Wait a second!
Oh, Asaka-chan...
Oh, don't worry.
She's already decided.
Well, bye for now, we'll be inside.
Let us know then you're done.
Got it.
That brunette's foot...
She's dragging it on the ground.
I really don't like that woman with the almond-shaped eyes.
Well then, let's surprise them with our snowman.
How?
First of all...
Sakuko here.
Huh? Talk with me?
Right now?
I knew we'd get curry.
Especially after all the work we did on the snowman.
Yep.
All you guys did was make a snowman...
She here?
No.
Maybe she went skiing by herself and can't
find her way back due to the snow...
Hey, hey, Asaka-chan...
Um, is something wrong?
It's the old man who was with those kids...
Sakuko, the one who was with us earlier,
wasn't in her room when we went to get her.
We've already checked the shops.
Maybe she really is out there...
Let's split up and look anyway.
We'll search around the lodge, you guys look in here.
Hey, Sakuko-san!
Are you out here?
Where are you, woman with the almond-shaped eyes?
Hey!
Guys... Where are you all?
Guys!
Stupid, stop crying.
Hold onto my jacket and don't let go.
You guys staying together?
Yes, Haibara-san is holding onto my hand!
What the---!?
It's my hand...
So, you sure it's my hand?
Hey, isn't searching during a whiteout like this useless?
Yeah, we should continue after the storm settles.
Our snowman's head fell off!
No way!
The wind must have blown it off...
The glove!
Damn!
Wait, Genta!
That glove!
There's a cliff there!
That was close...
I told you.
But, at least the storm has let up, huh?
Yeah.
Is something wrong, Conan-kun?
In the lake down there...
What's that floating?
Then, could it be...
Use the magnifying function of your glasses.
Alright.
I can see someone down there...
That is...
Sakuko-san!?
The deceased is Kokura Sakuko-san, 22 years old,
a fourth year art student.
The cause of death looks like drowning.
Should I schedule an autopsy regardless, Yamamura-san?
Yeah, but also...
Well, was she traveling alone?
No, she came with her three classmates from their art school.
From the right: Kiyama Tanji-san,
Onoue Asaka-san,
and Itabashi Kazuya-san.
So, those three found the body?
No, it was found by...
Us, the Detective Boys.
We were going through the snowstorm to find her...
And spotted her body from up there.
She was floating in the lake.
You're that boy that's always with Mouri-san...
Then, of course, Detective Mouri is...
He's not here.
Sorry, it's just us.
Oh... Is that so?
That means we won't be able to see
Sleeping Kogorou solve this cursed case.
Cursed?
Yeah.
On her feet: snowboarding boots.
In the lake: a snowboard.
You see, to get to the lake below the cliff, you
have to get across the bridge by car, but...
The bridge was blocked until we got here.
Then she fell while riding her snowboard?
Right, it's natural to assume she rode off accidentally...
Then fell into the lake and drowned.
But it's strange...
This lake, I mean!
The lake?
You haven't noticed? There's so much
snow, but the lake hasn't frozen.
There must be a creature lurking under the surface doing this...
Which is what sucked Sakuko san into the lake!
It's the hot springs.
The water from the hot springs flows
into this lake, keeping it warm.
Though, it isn't a safe temperature for people.
I've heard it never freezes over.
Is that so?
Yeah, it's stated in the guidebook.
Shouldn't a local police officer know this?
Well then, I guess it was an accident.
But still, I wonder if she was really snowboarding.
Because this woman isn't wearing a hat or goggles.
That's true, I don't think anyone would go snowboarding
during a snowstorm without something on their head.
It probably came off when she fell in the lake.
That could be for the hat or the goggles...
But gloves wouldn't come off, right?
That's true...
So, that means Kokura-san...
Must sweat a lot!
Hey...
Hey, you know, right?
Some people don't wear gloves because their hands get sweaty.
But still, you need gloves for snow boarding.
Maybe someone put boots on her because she
wasn't originally dressed for snowboarding.
Someone may have murdered Sakuko-san and made it look like...
A snowboarding accident.
No way!
Then, it's one of those three?
I believe it's possible.
Um, can you tell me about Sakuko san's
day up until her body was found?
S-Sure.
We last saw her just before noon, right?
Yeah, Sakuko went to her room immediately.
The four of us were going to meet at
1:00 for lunch, but she didn't show.
We went to her room and knocked, but she didn't answer.
So, we asked the lodge staff to unlock the door,
and discovered she was gone.
We three split up to look for her inside the lodge...
But found nothing.
That's when we came along.
Maybe she went skiing by herself and can't
find her way back due to the snow...
Hey, hey, Asaka-chan...
Um, is something wrong?
It's the old man who was with those kids...
Sakuko, the one who was with us earlier,
wasn't in her room when we went to get her.
We've already checked the shops.
Maybe she really is out there...
Let's split up and look anyway.
We'll search around the lodge, you guys look in here.
And then we split into two search groups,
which is when Conan-kun spotted her body from above.
And you guys, where were you all from when you
left her until you realized she was missing?
I was in my room at the lodge.
I was in my room as well.
I was making a snowman behind the lodge.
A snowman?
Yeah.
It's a working version for our graduation project.
It looks like Sakuko-san rented a snowboard and boots.
Did you all as well?
Yeah, I rented one.
I rented a pair of skiis, but...
But?
Kiyama-kun hasn't skiied in awhile...
Ever since I injured my leg last year and couldn't ski anymore.
But, you could still push someone over without skiing, right?
See, any of you three could have called her
to the top after you all split up earlier...
Arid pushed her right into the lake, making it look like she fell in.
That's impossible.
It'd make sense if she rode off on a speeding snowboard...
But if she were just pushed off, she would
have landed right about there.
Not to mention, it's still about five meters to the lake.
I see, so it's impossible for her to have just been pushed off.
But if you ski with her on your back...
I don't think that's possible, either.
During a snowstorm, it'd be pretty difficult
to get back up there so quickly...
Even with a rope.
If you still suspect me, you can go check
my skiis and ski boots in lodge locker.
They would be wet if I used them, right?
You three are using the same locker?
Y-Yeah.
Then, the one who took her boots and snowboard
could have been any one of you three, right?
Hey, what're you getting at?
So, if you tied her to the snowboard
and pushed her over the cliff...
She would hit the lake, making a big splash!
Are you feeling okay, Officer?
The slope is too bumpy.
It would flip over if you tried that.
But what about our snowboarder, Itabashi-san?
You could angle it easily.
Then, where's the rope used to tie her to the board?
That's right!
Even if it did make it there,
wouldn't the body still be tied to the board?
And besides, she may not have her gloves on because...
She may have been trying to use her cell phone to call us for help.
But why would she take off both gloves to use the phone?
Maybe it was a text message.
She used both hands to do text messages.
A text message?
Ah, yeah.
She always used to text people before calling them to
make sure they could talk, saying, "Is now alright?"
While she was text messaging, the wind
probably blew the gloves away.
She may have been chasing them...
And accidentally fell off.
Was the snowstorm really that bad?
Yeah, it definitely was!
It was so bad that all you could see was white!
Guys... Where are you all?
I guess this was an accident after all.
Right?
Would you please stop accusing us now, Officer?
Well, anyway, let's head up there where she probably fell from.
We may find some traces of the accident there.
"Accident"? It can't be...
Someone about to meet their friends for lunch in an hour...
Wouldn't drag a snowboard out in a snowstorm.
If this is a murder, the criminal is likely among those three.
What's left...
Is how they got Sakuko-san from the lodge...
All the way down here...
To throw her in the lake.
Snowman?
Yes, why?
Genta-kun!
Chance of killing - 0%!
I'm 120% sure it was an accident!
Sakuko-san's life was taken not by an accident, but by a murderer.
Besides the criminal, it seems...
The evidence is the tracks the criminal left behind.
Next Conan.
The Unsmashable Snowman, Part Two!
Next Conan's Hint:
The Taste of Snow.
Look forward to the next episode
What does snow taste like?
It's pretty salty.
Yes, yes.