No matter what happens, I'm still your partner.
I suspect it wasn't an accident.
We have to uncover the snowman trick!
Recognizing that single truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Last time, Professor Agasa took us
on a trip a snowy mountain.
While Genta and the others were making a snowman,
they met a group from a nearby art college,
who were doing their graduation project.
Sakuko here.
Talk with me?
Right now?
But, when we went looking for Kokura
Sakuko-san outside of the lodge...
We found her floating in the lake.
Well, anyway, let's head up there where she probably fell from.
We may find some traces of the accident there.
"Accident"? It can't be...
Someone about to meet their friends for lunch in an hour...
Wouldn't drag a snowboard out in a snowstorm.
If this is a murder, the criminal is likely among those three.
What's left...
Is how they got Sakuko-san from the lodge...
All the way down here...
To throw her in the lake.
The Unsmashable Snowman, Part Two!
This is probably where she fell from.
But even though the fence is broken, all that's left is the sign.
I was told it broke last week and was scheduled to be fixed soon.
I don't see any snowboard tracks here...
It probably got covered by the snow.
A snowman?
Could this be the one you were talking
about, your graduation project?
Itabashi Kazuya (22)
University Student
Y-Yeah...
That's the one.
So, while you were making this, Itabashi-san,
did you hear her voice or anything?
You were pretty close to where she fell from.
No, I was up here until 1:00, right before lunch.
I didn't hear her.
I was focusing on finishing this, and the snowstorm...
It was pretty loud.
So... What exactly is this thing?
It's pretty unusual.
Onoue Asaka (22)
University Student
Kiyama Tanji (22)
It's a snow model.
Itabashi-san is the only one who knows
how close it is to being finished.
He keeps it all in his head.
A snow model, huh?
Even I can tell it's unfinished.
Because, over there, you have an apple, bananas, and tangerines.
You guys were gonna use these later, right?
That's wrong.
Those were parts to our snowman.
Its head fell off due to the snowstorm.
Oh... Right.
I see...
Hey, hold up!
Don't be stomping around, our Detective
Badges are buried down there!
Oh, sorry.
This brings back memories.
I used to put gloves on sticks as well.
Not again!
Hey, you alright?
Genta-kun?
Genta-kun!
G...Genta-kun...
Your nose... Your nose is bleeding!
This should do it...
Now listen:
Lie face down and stay still.
Got it?
Y-Yes...
Ai-chan, so amazing! You're like a nurse!
Geez, this is embarrassing...
No, I'm jealous of you, Genta-kun.
But I can't believe you got a nosebleed from falling on snow.
A scoop must have been buried under there, I guess.
It definitely wasn't a scoop.
I did taste something funny though.
Taste?
A funny taste?
From the snow?
Yeah.
Hey, Genta! What'd it taste like?
The snow! What'd it taste like?
It was a bit salty...
That means...
Professor...
Did you get anything?
Yeah. The autopsy revealed that the water
from the lake was found in her stomach.
So, it really was an accident?
No.
This is actually more proof to the contrary...
These tracks the criminal left behind.
Yes, there are some things left unclarified...
But it looks like an accident.
We're just about ready to wrap up and head back.
What? The chief invited you over for dinner tonight?
That's great!
Of course, it'd be great if I were invited...
But if there's any doubt, be sure to investigate thoroughly?
No, the chance of this being deliberate is zero!
I'm 120% sure this was an accident!
No...
So, if you'll...
It may not have been an accident after all.
Hey, hey, what's up, Officer?
You just called us out here suddenly.
We already told you everything.
Sakuko's death was an accident, right?
Yeah, but, this guy has something strange to say.
No, no, nothing strange about it.
It's that old man...
Sakuko wasn't in an accident; she was murdered.
And the criminal is one of you three.
That's what I mean.
Hey now, I only got everyone out here because
I thought you had a clue about the case...
Not so you could call people murderers like a detective.
Ah, no...
If we look at everything...
We can only conclude Sakuko-san snowboarded
through the place where the fence should be.
Due to the snowstorm, I know she
drowned after falling in the lake.
I say this because l known no one else came toward the lake,
since the bridge was blocked until we police arrived.
Yeah... And then?
Regardless, there are about ten meters
from the lake to the bottom of the cliff.
Even if she were pushed from the cliff,
she wouldn't make it to the lake.
And then, there's one last thing...
One hour after she parted with those
three, she failed to show up for lunch.
So, they searched for her until...
-Until- her body was found.
Even with the use of a rope, one of them couldn't get
her body down there and make it back in an hour.
You can't be telling me that any of them could possibly...
H-Hey...
Sorry, this is quicker.
Officer?
Hey, are you alright?
It looks like he's sleeping...
It really does.
No, I'm not sleeping.
I'm just too upset with myself to stand.
Oh, I guess that's how it is.
I can't believe so simple a trick fooled me this long.
A trick, you say?
Yeah, the criminal pushed Sakuko-san off the cliff...
After putting her in something.
P-Put her in something?
Hey you're not gonna say she was put in a sled, are you?
Even if you put her in a sled...
It'd flip over, just like a snowboard would.
Even if someone rode down in the sled with her,
they would still have to climb back up.
A sled? It's nothing so unusable as that.
I speak of something that will definitely arrive
at the lake and will disappear with time.
Arrive there?
Disappear?
There's no way, nothing's that convenient.
I see now.
But instead of using misleading words
such as "arrive" and "disappear,"
I suggest using "roll to" and "melt".
It's more straight to the point, right?
That's it!
What is?
Look, it's something we've assembled.
Assembled?
I see!
Something we've assembled?
Yeah, of course it's a...
Snowman!
If you put that woman in a giant snowball, put it at the edge...
And roll it off...
It'll roll down and make a huge splash when it hits the lake!
It wouldn't take long for the snow to melt, which
would leave Sakuko-san floating in the lake.
That does make sense, since the hot
springs make the water unusually hot.
A snowman? Quit joking around.
I know Sakuko was pretty small, but..
I doubt you'd be able to fit a normal sized person in a snowball.
It would break apart before making it to the bottom.
That's true, it would have to be at least two meters to work.
And even if someone did get so much snow together,
I don't think they could push it off alone.
But see, a lot of snow isn't needed.
Right, it just has to be as big as...
As big as what?
The snowman I'm leaning against.
Didn't I tell you already?
If it were only that big...
It'd break apart before reaching the lake.
That sounds right, but...
Hey, say something!
H-Hey!
Ah, shit!
What's wrong with him?
What're you doing?
Hey, is this supposed to be funny?
No.
I was just reminding you...
Of when Genta-kun fell near the snowman earlier...
And ended up with a nosebleed.
Genta-kun!
G...Genta-kun!
Your nose... Your nose is bleeding!
What does that have to do with this?
Genta-kun, do you remember what the snow was like then?
I think...
It was salty.
Right, the crucial point of the trick is...
Salt.
Well, am I right?
I see. He used the chemical reaction
of the salt to harden the snowman.
The chemical reaction?
When salt comes in contact with snow, the freezing
point is lowered, making that part of the snow melt.
But before it melts, it absorbs the nearby heat,
causing the snow around it to freeze and harden.
When freezing is needed for skiing
courses and igloos, the do this.
But for ski courses, ammonium sulfate is used
to prevent damage after the snow melts.
Ammonium sulfate?
Ammonium... sulfate?
Well, you'll learn about it in your future science classes.
Hey, hey, all of this means nothing.
Where was this supposed snowball hardened at?
Are you saying you saw it?
I didn't see it, but it probably was done here.
Right at this snowman near me.
The hardening of the snowball was done here,
leaving the snow around it hardened as well.
That's why Genta-kun got a nosebleed after falling here.
"Was" done there? Isn't it still there?
The culprit made this snowman quickly
after committing the crime.
To prevent us from realizing this snowman was used for the trick,
the culprit made another body.
And the proof is this.
See, the head is hardened with salt, too.
As long as you recreate the shape, you
can place the head on the body again.
Wait a second...
That means the one who put Sakuko in the snowball was...
Right, the person who was making a
snowman the entire time: Itabashi-san.
It was you!
You're the only one who could've pulled this off!
Even to just putting the head on a
new body requires concise work,
which is something only the creator, Itabashi-san, could do.
Most likely, you took advantage of the
snowstorm and called her outside.
Just before, you told her to wear her skiing gear.
You probably said,
"Since the snowstorm's getting bad, let's talk in the room."
And after luring her to your room...
You forced her head into the sink...
Effectively drowning her.
You then put her boots on her,
went out into the snowstorm...
And put her into the space you had prepared earlier.
You then put her snowboard inside,
and then put on a lid made of snow.
You then rolled it up to the edge...
And finally...
Pushed it over.
And with that, she was floating in the lake.
But hold on, can all of that be done in an hour?
After he supposedly rolled Sakuko and the snowball off the cliff,
he made another snowball for the body, right?
When he came to meet with us, he
wasn't breathing hard or anything.
It's true, he'd be tired if he made another, but
if he uses one that's already half finished...
Half?
You all probably had no idea...
But the kids did something to their
snowman in order to surprise you all.
Isn't that right, you guys?
Y-Yeah, we did it to order to surprise them later on.
In the body of our snowman, we planted...
Our Detective Badges.
Huh? That's the sound of our Detective Badges...
It's coming from their snowman's stomach...
Then, our snowman's head didn't fall off during the snowstorm...
Itabashi-san just removed the fruits and used its parts,
allowing him to use it to make another one.
B-But that's not proof Itabashi's the criminal.
The evidence centers around Itabashi-san's sink.
According to the autopsy results, the water
from the lake was found in her stomach.
So, in his room, you should find containers
or traces of water he prepared before.
You may even find a sample of her hair as well.
Naturally, her sink could've been used,
but Itabashi-san's is more likely.
If it had happened in her room, he would have put on her
goggles, gloves, and her hat before putting her in the snowball.
B-But...
Itabashi had no reason to kill Sakuko!
Yeah.
I didn't think I had it in me...
But because of Asaka-chan, I just somehow did it.
What do you mean?
Itabashi!
You know, right? That Sakuko loved you.
But you always loved Asaka.
The girl who gracefully scaled the slopes with her skis.
To make you forget about Asaka, that woman...
Made Asaka go snowboarding.
She knew she was too inexperienced.
She stole Asaka's legs that way.
All for such a stupid reason.
Hey, are you serious?
Yeah, she was muttering about it when she was drunk once.
Hey, is something wrong, Sakuko?
I broke Asaka's leg.
Hey, what do you mean by that?
I've done everything I can,
but she just won't go away.
What's her deal?
Asaka, that bitch...
What'd you say?
Oh, I'm sorry.
I didn't know you'd care that much.
N-No way...
Itabashi, why...
Why didn't you tell me about this!?
Itabashi!
Only because I didn't want to give my enemy salt.
S-Salt?
Yeah.
Knowing you, I couldn't be sure what you
would have done to her if you had known.
I couldn't let you...
Avenge Asaka and get covered in mud.
I couldn't let you have that role.
But that was surprising.
To think putting salt on snow makes it harden.
Right?
No, it's not just for hardening.
If you put salt on snow and mix them, the salt disperses...
Until it's all gone.
They use this same method for melting snow
on the road, using calcium chloride.
Right, that guy used salt wrong...
The wrong way...
The worst way.
Instead of melting his murderous desire...
He hardened it.
A biting turtle?
Biting turtle and 1,000,000 yen...
What happened, Conan-kun?
Perhaps these two cases have a connection.
I won't let you go!
Next Conan:
Mysterious Case Near the Pond
Next Conan's Hint:
X-ray
Look forward to the next episode