Snap!
I’ll always be your partner!
A ferocious alien species!
Something unexpected between the pond’s troublesome
new resident and the man who wishes to raise it!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Created by
Gosho Aoyama
“Detective Conan”
Serialized in Shogakukan’s
‘Weekly Shonen Sunday’
Planning
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Character Design
Mari Tominaga
Art Director
Yasutada Kato
Director of Photography
Takahisa Ogawa
Sound Directors
Yasuo Urakami
Motoi Izawa
Music
Katsuo Ono
Opening Theme
“Kumo ni notte”
Performed by
Lyrics & Music
Arrangement
Yuka Saegusa IN db
Yuka Saegusa
Masazumi Ozawa
Editor
Terumitsu Okada
Story Editor
Jun'ichi Iioka
Color Key
Fusako Nakao
Executive Producer
Toru Okahata
Planning Support
Shin'ichiro Tsuzuki
Masato Hayashi
Toyohiko Okuyama
Shuho Kondo
Producers
Shuichi Kitada
Hiroaki Kobayashi
Associate Producer
Mitome Asai
Chief Producers
Michihiko Suwa
(Yomiuri TV)
Masahito Yoshioka
(Tokyo Movie)
Director
Masato Sato
Presented by
“Beika Central Park — Beika City”
W-What’s going on?
D-Detective Takagi!
Oh, it’s you guys.
Is there another case?
Yeah.
At Fukurokoji-san’s house just over there.
Late last night...
Thief!
Just like that, he let the thief get away.
He was robbed of about 3 million yen in cash.
The culprit wore gloves, giving us nothing
to cross-reference as far as fingerprints.
He was also wearing a ski mask, so we don’t
have much of an idea as to what he looks like.
All we know is that he’s a tall, thin male.
We’re scouting for witnesses now.
I guess you won’t be needing the Detective Boys’ help, then.
Yeah, interrogating suspects and searching
for evidence is the job of a police officer.
Let’s go!
We still have to go to Central Park, right?
Speaking of Central Park...
It’s there.
This morning, City Hall received news about that...
Please stand back, it’s dangerous here.
Please move away from the pond.
Where? Is it true?
Don’t push me, Genta!
Conan-kun’s actually scared, huh?
Found it!
Over here!
There!
There’s no doubt.
That was definitely a snapping turtle.
S-Snapping turtle?
Did someone raise it as a pet?
Or did Japan have this kind of turtle to begin with?
It may have been abandoned by its owner after
they discovered they could no longer raise it.
It’s called a snapping turtle.
Its habitat stretches from North America to Mexico.
It’s highly aggressive, and the power of its jaws is astonishing.
Without much effort, they can snap a human finger in half.
What a scary creature...
How could anybody keep it as a pet?
There are all types of people in this world.
Maybe raising a pet like that filled a void in their life.
Must be quite a lonely person.
There are more and more lonely people like that, aren’t there?
No wonder reptiles are so popular.
Well, I don’t really care about reptiles, but...
We maybe able to understand those that raise them.
Raising a pet can be pretty liberating, but to
toss one away is just being irresponsible.
That’s right!
Yeah.
Not to mention that animals like those are not
native to Japan, and could disrupt our ecosystem.
It’s unforgivable.
What’s wrong with having more animals around?
That’s not the problem.
But still, we can’t just leave that snapping turtle here!
Let’s find the person who left their frightened turtle here!
Right?
This is a job for the Detective Boys!
But, where do we start?
The Detective Boys: Defenders of Justice, huh...
Then, how about this?
Let’s find the pet shop that the turtle’s owner would usually go to.
Snapping turtles eat a lot, so...
They must’ve gone out a lot to buy small fish
and prawns to make turtle food, right?
Figure it out yet?
I see.
Let’s get moving, then!
You’re really clever, aren’t you?
What’s wrong, Conan-kun?
You’re the one who abandoned that snapping turtle, aren’t you?
I finally found a boyfriend...
But...
He didn’t like reptiles very much, did he?
No...
After that, things just got complicated.
Isn’t that good though?
To have found someone who can cure your loneliness?
But, no matter how you explain it,
abandoning an animal like this...
H-Haibara-san?
I just remembered that I have something to do, so I’m leaving.
Where is it?
It got away!
There’s no mistake.
That’s Kamejiro, the turtle that I raised.
You’re the owner of that snapping turtle?
Excuse me.
My name is Nihonmatsu.
I live in an apartment in the third district.
Yesterday, I turned away for a second, and it ran off.
I never thought that it would come all the way here.
I beg you.
Hurry up and give me the snapping turtle.
W-What is he talking about?
The turtle is mine!
A turtle with more than one owner.
How interesting.
Say.
Is that turtle really yours?
There’s no mistaking it.
Turtles like these are rarely seen.
But that’s weird.
That lady said that she left it here yesterday.
I never thought that the real owner would show up.
Why are you claiming that that turtle is yours?
Er, well, actually...
To atone for my wrongdoings.
Atone?
When I was little, I bought a green turtle at the local fair to raise as a pet.
But I got tired of raising it, and it became more and more of a hassle.
In the end, I released it into a nearby pond.
Afterwards, I kept regretting what I did.
When I heard this morning that a snapping turtle was found at this pond...
I thought that it had to be one that someone else abandoned.
The turtle never did anything wrong.
I felt sorry for it.
So I wanted to take it home to raise it again.
To make up for abandoning that green turtle long ago.
So that’s what it was.
Such a good person.
Kimata-san...
Please give me that turtle.
I’ll take good care of it.
I beg you.
I should be the one begging you.
Please continue to raise it.
T-Thank you.
I will, I will.
That’s great, Nihonmatsu-san.
For that snapping turtle, it’s probably the best case scenario, right?
It really found the best possible owner, right, Conan?
C-Could it be—
Excuse me, excuse me.
Did you get it?
No, that’s not it.
Look.
There are two—
Snapping turtles!
There’s one over here too!
There’s another over here, too!
With all of them, there’s a total of...
Four...
What’s going on in this pond?
Nihonmatsu-san, which turtle is yours?
That’s...
It’s fine.
Just give me all of the snapping turtles in the pond.
A-All of them?
Well, these turtles must’ve been mating. It’d be cruel to separate them.
Nihonmatsu-san!
You’re such a nice person!
Don’t cry.
Say, that finger...
What happened to it?
Oh, this is nothing.
All right!
Got one!
Be careful, that’s how they are.
Suddenly springing up out of the water
and biting people, the little punks.
How scary...
But, if you look closely, it’s still pretty cute.
I guess I still really like turtles, eh?
It must be because you raised
a green turtle a long time ago, right?
Yeah, that’s probably it.
That turtle is cute and beautiful, isn’t it?
The green on its shell gets brighter as it grows, doesn’t it?
This guy...
You’re talking about that guy, right?
What don’t you believe about him, Conan-kun?
Everything.
Take this type of green turtle, for example.
Only when the turtle is in its infancy is its shell a bright green color.
Over time, it becomes black.
Beautiful, isn’t it?
The green on its shell gets brighter as it grows, doesn’t it?
It just isn’t possible.
If he really raised one before, he’d definitely know.
Wasn’t that a lie, then?
The part about abandoning the turtle too?
Of course.
That so-called admission of guilt was a total fraud.
Furthermore...
That person doesn’t think turtles are cute.
On the contrary, it seems that he doesn’t like them at all.
That’s how they are.
Suddenly springing up out of the water
and biting people, the little punks.
That whole thing was just a lie.
Then why did he want to take all
four of the snapping turtles away?
Do you think he’s bringing them to the Dragon Palace
so that the turtles have to repay him for saving them?
Oh, geez.
Understood!
Whatever his motive is, I’m going to figure it out!
Mitsuhiko!
Genta, keep an eye on that guy.
Conan-kun!
Conan!
What kind of person is he?
He doesn’t seem too bad, but...
It seems like he has a lot of debt,
in addition to all of the rent he owes.
To us, he’s a pretty bothersome tenant.
It seems as if he has money troubles.
And there doesn’t seem to be any unusual
purchases of snapping-turtle food.
So he wants to sell them rather than raise them?
No, snapping turtles only cost about
seven or eight thousand yen each.
Even if he sold all four of them, it still
wouldn’t be enough to cover his rent.
If he doesn’t intend to sell them...
Then there has to be some other reason...
Got the second one!
But to raise four turtles...
What about your sink?
That’s true, I should get ready.
Once you catch all four of them, let me know.
All right, I’ll see you then.
Everything’s gone well, so far.
But originally, there was only supposed to be one.
And now there are four...
He’s sighing.
Looks like he really only wanted one of the
four snapping turtles specifically.
But they got mixed up, and he can’t tell them apart.
It’d be better to just take them all back.
The one he wants is among the four, anyway.
There must be something special about that turtle.
I got it.
With interest, the total is 1 million yen, right?
I have the money ready, but something came up.
1 million yen?
I’ll definitely pay off all of my debts today.
The consequences of eating one’s words...
You should be aware of them, right?
Hurry up and get that turtle for me!
What did he mean by that just now?
Once he gets that snapping turtle,
he can pay off his debts...
What does that turtle have to do with 1 million yen?
I’ve got it!
Is it because there’s some kind of map on its shell
that leads you to some kind of treasure?
Genta-kun, who would have the time to draw a map like that?
Well...
Granny, let me give you a hand.
Good timing, Genta-kun...
Got the third one!
There’s only one left...
The snapping turtle and 1 million yen...
What is it?
This is...
Detective Takagi mentioned it earlier this morning, didn’t he?
About a thief who struck last night,
wearing gloves and this kind of mask.
I’m gonna go find Detective Takagi!
Ayumi-chan!
We haven’t confirmed that this belongs to the burglar yet!
But the time matches.
It was raining a bit last night.
Yet this isn’t wet at all.
Which also means...
It was burnt some time after the rain
stopped last night and this morning.
I see.
In other words, this is likely what happened last night, right?
The thief escaped to here after stealing
the 3 million yen from that house.
So the stuff he used last night was also disposed of here.
It’s possible that the two events are somehow related.
Which two events?
Last night’s burglary, and Nihonmatsu-san wanting
to find out the snapping turtle in the pond.
In that case, doesn’t that mean the man named
Nihonmatsu was actually last night’s burglar?
Didn’t you say that the culprit was a tall, skinny male?
Well, we did say that...
He’s a tall and skinny person, too!
And he also said this:
I’ll definitely pay off all of my debts today.
Furthermore, there’s also a bandage around his finger.
I’d guess that he hurt his finger when
he was trying to burn the evidence...
That’s how they are.
Suddenly springing up out of the water
and biting people, the little punks.
Or possibly by being bitten by a snapping turtle.
But there’s one thing I don’t quite understand.
I see, like why he even raised snapping turtles to begin with, right?
I already know why.
Listen up.
For whatever reason, after he ran off with
the money and escaped here last night...
He took off his ski mask,
took off his gloves...
And he planned on burning the evidence here.
But at that moment,
his finger was bitten by a turtle,
who must’ve seen his face.
But in this pond, there are a total of four turtles.
Because he couldn’t recognize which turtle
it was, he had to get rid of all of them.
Conan-kun, if that guy’s the culprit and
he already got the 3 million yen,
why can’t he pay off his debt?
Yeah, that’s the question.
The fourth and last one!
Hey, wait for me!
You want to find the guy from this morning
who told us about the snapping turtles?
I don’t think he gave us his name, but he was male.
And his voice sounded pretty young on the phone.
Maybe he thought that he couldn’t catch
them all, so he asked City Hall for help.
But why would he want the snapping turtles so badly?
I have the money ready, but something came up.
What was the “something” that came up?
Last night, one of these snapping turtles bit his finger...
But that doesn’t explain everything.
Wow, so big!
Something looks hidden there!
Shu-chan, no!
It’s dangerous!
Let’s go home, all right?
Does that mean...
But it isn’t impossible....
Say, it’s best if we investigate these four snapping turtles.
What would we be looking for?
I knew it.
You can’t let me raise them?
Well, we need to deal with all the paperwork first.
So please give us about a week.
T-That’s so long...
I really have to wait an entire week?
Oh, right.
I think we’ve got him.
Let’s see...
I think it was 304, 304...
Found it.
That’s strange.
It won’t work no matter how many times you try.
You wanted to pay a one-week rental fee, right?
If you leave it there for more than three days,
management will confiscate the contents inside.
No, actually, I just wanted to...
Unfortunately, the coin locker was made
so that you can’t open it without a key.
I-Is that so?
Mind if we open the locker?
Police?!
Nihonmatsu-san, what’s the meaning behind this money?
Damn it...
Because you were in debt to someone,
you stole 3 million yen from
Fukurokoji-san last night, didn’t you?
But once you put the money in
the coin locker, you failed, right?
I thought I was in luck, until...
I’m exhausted...
Hey now, are you all right?
Let’s find a place to rest before we continue.
Damn, I’m screwed if they see me.
Are you all right?
Lucky!
This is bad, I have to hide this!
Oh, Minami-chan, Megumi-chan...
But I was out of 100 yen coins...
So that’s why you ran to the park. To burn the evidence.
You’d only need to retrieve the money once dawn broke.
It was a foolproof plan.
However, something happened then that
you couldn’t have possibly imagined.
N-No way...
Why is this happening?
Hey, spit it out!
Give me back the key!
No way...
That’s what happened.
Your precious key ended up being swallowed.
I never thought that something like that could happen.
But these are the results of our X-ray tests.
So you decided to report this to City Hall
so they’d let you capture the turtle.
However, you could have decided not to bother with that,
and just reported the loss of your locker key
to the company that deals with it, couldn’t you?
It wouldn’t work.
Even if he had done that, they’d check to make sure the stuff
in his locker belonged to him after helping him open it.
If they found out about the 3 million yen inside,
they’d be able to link it to the robbery from last night.
Is that so?
So he was left with no choice other than
to capture all the snapping turtles.
He’s running away!
You won’t get away!
Take this!
Geez, why are you letting them go like that?
Letting dangerous animals roam
in a park that belongs to everyone.
That’s right.
But you’re in no position to criticize them.
You’re under arrest for breaking and
entering, and the theft of 3 million yen.
Oh, that’s good, isn’t it?
All four turtles have new owners now.
Well, he’s still pretty scary, but it’d
be pretty cruel to abandon him.
Hey!
S-Something happened!
This time, I heard a crane was spotted up ahead.
And, there’s more than one!
Let’s go!
Hey! We’re going to be late!
After a turtle comes a crane.
That’s just great.
Kaitō Kid?!
Five riot officers just under the window...
It looks hard to enter from here.
A blackout!
Look, the painting’s gone!
Right, it disappeared as if it were an illusion...
I’m going to rip your mask off once more, Kaitō Kid...
Next Conan:
Next Conan’s Hint:
Illustration on an advance notice
A certain snobby Kid might show up
for the new school term in April.
What a kidder...