No matter what happens, I'm still your partner.
Today, one thing that's stolen is a life,
is that guy really responsible?
Recognizing that single truth,
a child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Mouri Kogoro?
Yeah.
Why have you invited that famous detective here?
I have to, you see.
I'm being targeted, Father.
Targeted? Why?
Of course, it's because of what the art
world has been anticipating for so long...
Guren, Konjiki, Junbaku...
And now, Seiran.
The one who plans to soar to it through the darkness to take it is...
A notorious burglar known as "The Magician Under the Moonlight."
They call him Kaitou Kid.
W-What'd you say!?
I received a notice earlier.
"Tomorrow at 20:00, I'll come to collect my beloved
Seiran from the cover of a full moon's glow."
O-Oh no, we have to do something!
Of course, I've called the police.
With him being an elusive magician with the ability to transform,
I'm not so sure they're qualified.
N-No, that's not what I'm worried about.
What if this ordeal leads them to... And the painting...
No one will find out...
Ever.
Takeyori-kun, you mean you...
Yeah, I was out of ideas.
Stop it, Takeyori-kun.
Whatever you're planning, stop it!
What gives you the right to tell me that?
The way this has come together makes it your fault, Father.
If you must do it... I may have an idea...
I'm joking!
I was just messing around.
I'm a world famous artist, after all.
How could I do something like that?
Then, the notice was a joke as well?
No, I actually did get it.
Don't worry, though.
Whenever that famous detective Mouri
faces him, Kaitou Kid never wins.
Especially since he began bringing that active little boy with him.
He'll be able to protect this treasure, too...
That boy named Edogawa Conan.
Kaitou Kid & the Four Masterpieces, Part One!
Well now, Conan-kun.
This is your third bout with Kid. Will you beat him?
I won't know until after it's over, but I don't think I'll lose.
Besides, this isn't just the third time.
Oh, so you've faced him more than what's been in the news.
So, what's the trick to beating Kid?
Actually, I don't always beat him...
Of course, it's all due to the daily training
sessions taught by me, Mouri Kogoro!
Oh, the famous detective!
He's a lucky kid!
So, Detective, will you win?
You mean, against the world's greatest burglar?
I can't say.
But, despite the chances involved...
He'll suffer!
Chances and suffering, great, great...
Why the hell're you here with your terrible puns!?
I-Inspector Nakamori...
This is where Kaitou Kid said he'd show.
Why don't you grab that old fox Megure
and hunt down some murderers?
I'm afraid you're mistaken, Inspector Nakamori.
I was asked to come to this villa by Oikawa-san,
the one who received the notice from Kid.
Inspector, are the police fully prepared?
Why has Kid switched from precious
stones to paintings all of a sudden?
One rumor claims that the notice itself was a hoax!
No comment!
How many times have I told you all not to get near the scene?
But Oikawa's newest work is supposed
to be unveiled live on TV tonight.
Right?
Yeah.
I heard the painting itself is done, but he's
just waiting until the revealing to sign it.
Well, that's if Kid doesn't steal it first.
What's this? You make it seem like he'll get it no matter what.
Oh, no...
Regardless, don't enter the house until the warning time
of 8:00 PM has passed and we've secured the painting.
Understood?
I've been expecting you, Mouri-san.
Oikawa Takeyori (59)
Artist
I'm Oikawa Takeyori.
Nice to meet you.
But I had to bring my daughter along, I hope you don't mind?
Um, if you want, Conan-kun and I can wait in the car.
No, no. It's fine. I trust Detective Mouri.
That's great to hear.
Not to mention, I've heard this little boy is that thief's counterpoint.
Alright, let me show you where Seiran is.
Please, this way.
Takeyori-kun...
I need to speak with you.
I'm sorry, can it wait a moment, Father?
That's your father?
Kanbara Haruhito (82)
Takeyori's Father-in-law
Yeah, he's my wife's father and my teacher, Kanbara Haruhito.
You may recognize his name if I pronounce it as "Seijin" instead.
Oh, the famous scenery painter.
Unfortunately, he hasn't held a brush
in ten years due to his hand injury.
Welcome to my workshop.
This is such a great atelier!
As you'd expect in Okutama, the only
scenery out here are mountains.
Five riot officers just under the window...
I doubt he'll come this way.
He could use his hang glider, but the
windows seem like they're locked.
All this over this painting, huh?
Yeah, this is Seiran.
Well, let's take a peek...
You can't do that, Mouri-san.
I don't like people seeing my work before its done.
But isn't your signature the final touch?
Oh, no, there are some small touch-ups I want to make.
I see...
All of these plaster models make this look like a school's art room.
I teach art classes here once a week.
Is that a security camera?
Yeah, I had it installed immediately after I received the notice.
We can check the videos if you want.
This way.
Looks like both entrances have two guards each.
All four of them have pinch marks on their cheeks, too.
I guess that means Inspector Nakamori
has already checked them out.
Alright, we've only got thirty minutes until
the announced time of 8:00 PM.
Everyone, be at your best and protect this painting!
So, this is the feed...
I mean, the picture is very clear, but why's there only one camera?
When he told me he already had surveillance
equipment, I didn't expect a single camera either.
I'm sorry, I wasn't clear about it.
Hey, why aren't there any guards in the atelier?
I won't allow anyone in there.
It's possible one of them could peek at
my painting like Mouri-san almost did.
My men aren't like that at all...
But I guess having one is better than none.
Oh, that's right.
Sorry, but could you turn the camera off?
I need about ten minutes to do my final check.
But there's only thirty minutes until the announced time...
I'll borrow this transceiver until then.
I'll contact you when I'm finished checking.
Understood.
You're free to enter.
Thanks.
Takeyori-kun...
Father?
Can I have a moment?
I'm about to do my final check.
But I have something to tell you!
Don't worry, I'll handle it.
Could you wait just a few minutes?
Too long, just too long.
The hell's he doing? It's been well over ten minutes.
I'm finished, Inspector.
You can turn the camera back on.
Alright, do it.
How is it? Is it working?
Yeah. Now hurry and leave the room.
Alright.
We can talk now, Father.
Actually, I wanna get a look at this painting even Kid wants to steal.
It's part of a four piece set.
A four piece set?
The first, Guren, was a flower,
the second, Konjiki, was of the moon,
the third, Junbaku, was a bird,
and the fourth that Kid's after Seiran, should be of the wind.
I get it! The four beauties of nature!
I see, he's trying to convey the four
beauties through the four paintings.
Hey, I can see he used a flower, the moon,
and the wind, but why is Junbaku a bird?
It's a crone.
The pointing is of on exotic, pure white
crane in the middle of a snowfield.
Well, his last two works both fetched
high prices, so I'd say this one...
A blackout!
The lights are out!
It's the circuit breaker!
You guys go check it out and get it back in order!
Yes, sir!
Is it Kid?
But there's still ten minutes left before the announced time...
Father! Are you alright?
What is it?
What happened?
Answer me!
The old man was inside when the blackout occurred.
Why'd you let him go in?
He went in just as I was going out.
He said he didn't trust the police or some detective
to protect the painting and that he'd do it himself.
I was on my way to get you, and the lights suddenly went out.
Where's the key?
I was hurrying to get in and dropped it...
Damn...
Let's break it down!
1,2, 3...
What the...
Shit!
You all below the window, have you seen anything!?
We saw something fall from the window, which
looks like some cups and some paint brushes.
Look, the painting's gone!
Right, it disappeared as if it were an illusion...
Father!
Hang in there, Father!
Tainted with blood the color of a crimson lotus flower...
The old man's life faded away.
Father!
Kaitou Kid killed someone!?
But, I heard he's never hurt anyone...
I'm not sure.
Since Kid killed someone, the report's going to run awhile.
Yeah, it may even go well into tomorrow.
Hey, you, over there!
If you're not doing anything, get us
some drinks from the station car!
Oh, sure.
Got it.
They're here!
Inspector Megure!
We heard that someone was murdered, is Kid responsible?
Was it really the police's fault?
No comment, no comment.
But it's true that Oikawa's newest
artwork, Seiran, was stolen, right?
You all are assuming Kid would never kill, right?
I said no comment!
Can you comment on the investigation so far?
Hey, let us through already!
The weapons used were a knife and a stun gun.
There's a wound from the stun gun on the victim's neck.
Kanbara-san probably caught the culprit stealing the painting.
Figuring he'd been caught, the culprit used the
stun gun and then the knife to finish him off.
Any fingerprints?
None on the stun gun, but Oikawa-san's
was found on the handle of the knife.
Then, could he have...
No, with it being that dark, he wouldn't be able
to find him immediately without a light source.
I would say it's more likely he heard Kanbara-san's yelping
and then felt around on the ground until he found him.
That's probably when he touched the knife.
Also, when we broke the door down, we
heard the culprit exiting via the window.
So the culprit was in the room before the blackout?
Yeah, he was probably hiding in the ceiling and
came out by the air conditioner after the blackout.
But why'd the blackout occur?
Several high-voltage devices were programmed with timers
to activate at the same time, causing the breaker to trip.
If we'd been more cautious, we would have found them earlier.
Unfortunately, Oikawo-san only just
got the notice yesterday morning.
We weren't contacted with the information until last night.
That would mean he sent the notice only after
he was done with the preparations, right?
And then? Did anyone see the criminal escape out the window?
No, we were prepared for him to come through
that window, so we didn't spotlight it.
That would've told everyone where the pointing was.
All we recovered were these two brush stands and some
brushes that fell when he went out the window.
Well then, Megure, I'll leave the rest to you.
You can use the security camera video to identify the suspect.
Hey, hey, isn't the criminal Kid?
Aren't you the one who deals with him?
This guy isn't Kid.
The only thing he'd never steal is a life.
Inspector Megure, the video from the atelier's
security camera is ready to be played back.
This is an hour before the crime...
This is right after the painting was checked...
And this is the first image from after the power was restored.
I know why there's a segment missing before and after the blackout,
but why is there a cut before and after he checked the painting?
They turned the camera off at my request.
If anyone sees my paintings before they're
complete, I can no longer appreciate them.
It's been my policy for the longest time.
According to Inspector Nakamori, Konbara-son went
into the room after you finished your check, correct?
Yeah.
He said he couldn't trust a detective
or the police to protect the painting.
My father-in-law was being stubborn and refused
to leave, so I went to get Inspector Nakamori.
I left, locking the door just to be safe,
and then the blackout happened.
After I called out to him and he didn't reply,
I tried to get in but dropped my keys.
I see. That's why Inspector Nakamori broke
the door down after he made it here.
But isn't it weird?
After you finished checking the painting,
you were talking into the transceiver.
The video doesn't have sound, but you were telling
Inspector Nakamori that your check was done, right?
Yeah.
Since Kanbara-san came in just after that,
why didn't you use the transceiver to call for the inspector?
That's because my father-in-law took the transceiver from me.
He said he wouldn't let anyone stop him.
I did hear that the transceiver was
found on Kanbara-san afterwards.
But can't we think of it this way?
After the blackout, Kanbara-san decided
to protect the painting by hiding it.
There must be cupboards in the atelier
that're used to store canvases.
No, that's impossible.
I wanted to be sure that if Kid did get
inside, he'd have nowhere to hide.
So, before checking the painting, I
locked all of the canvas cupboards.
And the keys?
They're with the atelier keys I lost during the blackout.
I think they were found in the hallway earlier.
Then, we should assume someone
snuck into the atelier in the dark?
That's impossible.
Before the blackout, the police officers guarding the doors
would have checked to make sure they were locked.
But Kid wouldn't really need a key...
Actually, I overheard Inspector Nakamori tell his men that
if there was a blackout, to grab the knobs and not let go.
That means, someone was hiding in the ceiling and
appeared in the atelier during the blackout.
After appearing, he killed Kanbara-san, who was inside the
room, stole the painting, and escaped out the window.
But is that something Kid would really do?
We can't really say yet.
It would seem he's never killed before.
But he may have finally given in.
You sound anti-Kid to me.
Of course! Kaitou Kid is the archnemesis of the police!
Do you have a reason to side with Kid, Sato-san?
And what if I do?
How do you know that the notice was real?
It's the picture Kid always draws on his notices.
He always draws a new one for each notice.
If someone were to copy one of them from a newspaper or from TV,
they would be caught instantly.
But according to Inspector Nakamori, they checked and
are sure it's really him since the lines are different.
But you know, someone that's good at
drawing could be pretending to be Kid.
Like a mangaka, an illustrator, or...
Maybe a painter?
Hold on, Conan-kun!
I did say "maybe."
I can't draw anything silly like that.
Speaking as a professional artist, I would say it's authentic.
I think so, too!
I bet it's Kid.
He's a bad guy!
Well then, let's use your wits to capture the bad guy.
Oh, a phone call.
It's this one.
You have two phones?
Why's that?
Yeah, one's for work and the other's for private use.
One of them seems to have blood on it.
After rushing to my bleeding father-in-law's aid, I called
some relatives to inform them of the bad news.
It probably happened then.
It's me.
Could you call me back later?
I'm sorry. May I go change?
I'm uncomfortable with all this blood on me.
Let us search you first, please.
Inspector Nakamori already saw to that, but if you must.
I've come to steal the truth.
Kaitou... Kid.
Hey man,
any idea what's in this bag? It seems heavy.
Don't touch it, don't touch it.
You'll get fired for touching things without permission.
Oh, boy!
I just noticed something.
What?
I think there's something in your back pocket.
I wonder what it is?
Look at this!
What?
It's a card!
Kaitou Kid!?
What a great find, boy!
He must have put this in your pocket before all of this happened.
Yep! I'll give it to the inspector right now!
I told you Kid did it!
Or at least that's what you wanted to hear, right?
I see now.
He figured a child would be excited
about anything that involved Kid.
That's why he invited us here.
If this guy had prepared this card, he
would have just left it at the scene.
This means it's geniuine and he only just found it.
Inspector Nakamori would've never
missed it if he had it on him back then.
That means that card was definitely put on him after that time.
I'm going to rip your mask off once more, Kaitou Kid...
Here tonight, under this full moon.
We cannot say this yet, but everything points to this option.
Well, I guess there's no doubt that Kid's the murderer.
A thought came to me that could serve as a clue.
Will you let me demonstrate?
Where is it?
Here!
Next Conan:
Kaitou Kid & the Four Masterpieces, Part Two!
Next Conan's Hint:
Things you can't see, but still exist.
Did Kid really do it?
He is a thief, after all.
It is Kid.
Well done!