No matter what happens, I'm still your partner.
The mystery and truth behind the masterpiece are now solved.
Was Kaitou Kid really not involved?
Recognizing that single truth,
a child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
The last of the four masterpieces by Oikawa Takeyori-san, Seiran,
was targeted by Kaitou Kid.
Oikawa took action after he received the notice.
He had a single security camera installed in the atelier.
And, despite Oikawa-san's security measures, it wasn't enough.
His father-in-law, Kanbara Haruhito-san, was found dead inside.
Kaitou Kid & the Four Masterpieces, Part Two!
Was Kanbara-sensei's murder done by Kaitou Kid?
We're currently investigating all possibilities and
should be able to make an announcement soon.
Oikawa-san, will you paint it again?
The last of Nature's beauties, Seiran!
Oikawa Takeyori (59)
Artist
Of course...
I won't.
Never.
This is why I must beg Kaitou Kid...
For my father-in-law's life and Seiran...
Please give them back to me!
Hey...
Huh?
When Inspector Megure come, did anything seem different?
Was anything different?
Now that you mention it, I remember a man from
Nichiuri TV's staff being taken from the crowd.
He was probably just exhausted.
I see.
He must have switched with one of those four, then.
Well then, was there a suspicious bag or anything?
Maybe one big enough to hold a person?
Not that I've seen.
If you see one, could you call me in secret?
I guess, but why you, boy?
It's because Uncle Kogorou thinks
Kid is disguised as a police officer.
Are you serious?
If I answer my phone and whisper to Uncle
Kogorou, Kid won't suspect anything, right?
I see.
Kanbara-san's appearance before he went into the atelier?
Detective Mouri wants to know that?
He's wondering if he was really protecting the
painting alone or if someone else went in.
No, Kanbara-san was standing in front of the door
quietly while Oikawa-son was doing his check.
He walked in when Oikawa-san opened the door after his check.
Those two were in the atelier for one or two minutes.
Maybe he said he'd protect it then?
Of course, we tried to stop Kanbara-san.
Oikawa-san said they'd be quick.
We had no idea Kanbara-san didn't plan to leave the atelier.
Right after the blackout, the criminal who was hiding
in the ceiling jumped down and killed Kanbara-san.
So, was anything different after Kanbara-san
went in and after Oikawa-san came back out?
Like, did he have blood on his clothes then?
No, there wasn't any blood on him then.
But still, couldn't his clothes have been turned inside out?
They definitely weren't.
Inspector Nakamori thought that at
first, so he checked out his clothes.
Although there was blood on the outside of the jacket,
there was none inside or on the inside of his undershirt.
But also, that blood got on him after he
come in with the inspector and his men.
He found Kanbara-san by chance when he was feeling around.
That must be when he got the blood on him.
But was it really by chance?
You came in with the inspector, didn't you, boy?
Since he was in the dark, cutting Kanbara-san's throat
so quickly while we were looking for a light source...
That would be pretty much impossible.
Hey, now that you mention it, the door Oikawa-san
knocked on during the blackout was that one, right?
Since Kanbara-san went in from this side,
why did he knock on that door?
He was probably on his way to get the inspector to help
get Kanbara-san out when the blackout occurred.
If you mean that room, the inspector asked the guards something.
He asked them while Oikawa-san was
still inside checking the painting.
Yeah, I remember.
He told me to make sure the police really turned off the camera.
He told me to knock once if it was still on.
I knocked twice, the signal for it being off.
A signal? Why didn't he come speak with you at the door again?
He probably thought I'd be able to see
the incomplete pointing from the door.
Did you hear anything about the victim?
Yeah, two strange things.
There was a strangely shaped mark in the blood on his sweater...
And on his left thumb, there was a strange, round mark.
The odd mark in the blood is probably from his
wrist being in the way when his neck was cut.
I have no idea about the weird circle mark on his thumb, though.
Then maybe, he...
Hey! Stop running around!
We're going home.
Ah, but Kid hasn't been caught yet!
That's a job for the police.
Isn't it your bed time?
Since he would have used his hang glider
to get away, there's no escape line, right?
Right.
We can eliminate escape routes through the witnesses.
But isn't it strange?
Even with the riot squads all around the
villa, no one found a single hiding place.
It's because we didn't spotlight any of the windows.
But, see...
But isn't Kid's hang glider white?
He couldn't have used some sort of magic to disappear completely.
Right, right. He's a magician.
This isn't just a simple hand trick, right, Conan-kun?
But...
Hold it! I'm sorry for the interruption.
Sure...
Whether he used a trick or not, if we can't prove it...
If that's so, can't we investigate it...
Using this as a hint?
For this, we'll need a newspaper and an empty cup.
First, I'll take the cup and cover it with the newspaper.
Next, I'll lift it...
and move it to the middle.
And...
How miraculous! The cup's gone.
You can say whatever, but that isn't magic.
When you moved the cup, you let it fall into your lap so you
could pound on the shape of the newspaper later, right?
Someone did that at the 1st division's
end of the year party back in the day.
Oh, my Dad mentioned that once.
I wonder who did it then...
I see...
Besides, what does this prove!?
How does this relate to the trick used in this case?
Well, see, I think Kid disappeared using this.
I'm so sorry!
Don't worry about it.
It was a cheap gift from my mother for my wedding forty years ago.
I had no idea...
Don't be so careless!
There may be sharp fragments you can't see down there!
Yes, ma'am...
Excuse my asking, but about your wife...
She died five years ago.
I painted the the third of the beauties, Junbaku, just afterwards.
Fifteen years ago, she was travelling overseas
when she was wounded in a tornado incident.
She had been in a coma ever since.
Speaking of fifteen years ago, isn't that when
your first painting, Guren, was announced?
Yeah, it was within a year of her accident.
I painted it to cover my wife's hospital
bills, but it was a great success.
I became a popular artist afterwards.
I did what I could, opening this place as an art classroom.
Excuse me.
I'm sorry, my younger brother's calling.
It's fine.
Keep looking, there must be more.
I don't see any more...
Then let's use light.
They'll reflect the light and be easy to see.
Huh?
Detective Mouri?
Yep. He told me to ask you all if anything fell from the window.
But still, all we found were two brush stands and some brushes.
That reminds me, I found some fishing line.
Since there's a lake you can fish in
nearby, I'd say a fisherman dropped it.
It's about 7 meters long...
One end is tied in a loop and the other's a bent fishing hook.
There's no doubt, this is what the criminal used.
That means the other thing should be here somewhere...
Here!
There's a hole in this rock.
Hey, is this that boy?
We found the big, suspicious bag you mentioned.
Really!?
Yeah, the bag was near one of the Nichiuri TV trucks...
with Officer Chiba inside.
Officer Chiba? Did you try to wake him?
Yeah, but when we tried to open the bag,
the zipper broke, not letting us get past his neck.
I see. I'll tell Uncle Kogorou right now.
Conan-kun, did you find out something?
Officer Takagi...
The Chiba in the villa is Kaitou Kid.
They just found the real Chiba.
I have to tell everyone!
Wait, just a second.
Could you look for something, Officer Takagi?
Somewhere in this villa...
is Seiran!
Seiran is still in the villa?
Then, you're saying Kid didn't steal it?
I'm asking you to help because it wasn't.
I think you, out of everyone, can find it.
OK...
Uncle, over here!
Jeez...
What're you up to? Kid escaped a long time ago.
Hey, hold on!
Conan-kun, leave the rest to the police!
No, that won't be necessary since I've solved it.
Ran, call for Inspector Megure.
And now...
This is what  Seiran really looks like.
Fishing line?
It's just a piece of cloth hung over a fishing line.
It's just like Officer Takagi's trick.
Just like the shape of the cup under the newspaper,
the cloth over the fishing line makes it look like the real thing.
This is a simple trick used to fool spectators.
First, you make a loop in the end of the line.
You then put it around the bolt and dose the
door, making it stretch across the room.
You let the other end go between the two brush holders.
You do this to keep the height between
the window and the bolt even.
And then, you put the other end of the string through a
hole in a rock you prepare earlier and hang it outside.
This puts pressure on the fishing line.
Then, after placing the cloth over the
line, you get your incomplete Seiran.
Now all that's left is for the door to be broken down.
Do it.
Yes, sir.
1, 2, 3!
When the door opens, the fishing line on the
door slips off due to the weight of the rock.
The other side of the string is pulled due to the
other side's weight, pulling it to the outside.
The knotted loop forces the brush holders
outside, also opening the window.
The brush holders and the rock will fall out the window at the
same time, right beside of the riot squad stationed outside.
So, by placing brush holders by the window,
it makes it seem the criminal was
inside and escaped out the window.
But who would do all of this?
It was all done when Oikawa-san had
the camera shut off for his check.
What?
Then, you mean...
Right.
The one who made us think the painting was stolen...
And the one who killed Kanbora-san during the blackout...
Oikawa-san, you're responsible for all of it.
Your problems began then.
When you opened the door and talked with the guards,
you told them not to look into the studio at any cost.
You took this opportunity to hook it around the bolt, didn't you?
What are you trying to infer, Mouri-san?
I simply didn't want anyone to see an incomplete version of my art.
Besides, my father-in-low entered
the atelier after my check anyway.
Why would I want to kill someone protecting my painting?
No, you made up the bit about him protecting the painting.
You refused to talk with Kanbara-san
every time he approached you,
forcing him to enter the atelier.
He knew you would talk with him if
you two were alone in the atelier.
You had planned for Kanbara-san to enter and
immediately stunned him with a stun gun.
You then waited for the black out timers.
Your timing was perfect for going to "ask"
Inspector Nakamori to help with him.
And when Inspector Nakamori forced
his way inside, you followed him...
Right to the unconscious Kanbara-san.
You then slit his throat.
That's how it happened.
That isn't possible.
I didn't have a flashlight on me.
It's possible...
Even without a flashlight.
All that's required is a cell phone.
Back then, you placed a cell phone by the unconscious Kanbara-san.
If you called the phone, its light would show you were he was.
You knew that after the inspector
and his men broke down the door,
they would be worried about the pointing
and the brush holders above everything.
Oikawa-san...
You said you had two cell phones, right?
The white one being for private use and the black one for business.
After the incident, you used the white one
to call relatives, it being a private call.
Later, when your brother called, the
call came in on the black phone.
The blood-stained white cell phone... Is it really yours?
Naturally, you could've deleted the data,
but the police con find out easily.
Whose phone is that? The phone company
can tell us who called during the blackout.
You're right, it's my father-in-law's cell phone.
I used its light to find that old meddler.
Meddler?
He was always was one.
He forced me to make the last of the four the
same thing that claimed my wife's livelihood.
That's right, she was hurt by a tornado.
Then, why did you decide to make the four piece set with it in it?
How else could I express the true beauty of nature?
The first, Guren, is of a crimson red lotus flower...
The second, Konjiki, is of the moon...
And the red-crowned crane on a snowy plane in
Junbaku is set around the snow, not the bird.
Those three alone are a complete set.
But my father-in-law...
He told the buyer of Guren and Konjiki that...
If he paid more for Junbaku, he could promise him Seiran as well.
That's when he turned it into a four-piece set.
I started pointing to pay for her treatment.
I didn't like him cheating that investor.
I couldn't bring myself to point Seiran after she died.
I was able to think of a trick to make the painting disappear...
But he said he would go through with his own plan if I did.
Plan?
He was going to spill everything!
That Seiran didn't really exist, that the
Kaitou Kid's letter was faked by me!
He didn't stop to think that all of that
would ruin my life and my career!
That's not it.
When Kanbara-san said he had his own plan, he meant this.
Takagi-kun?
That painting there...
It couldn't be...
The wind blowing through Summer's leaves: Seiran.
But the one who painted this isn't who you think...
It's Master Kanbara.
Impossible!
His hand is injured! He can't paint!
You never noticed, then.
Kanbara-san had an oval marking from
a color pallette on his left thumb.
He kept his brushes in his storage box, each
one of them having bite marks on them.
He had learned to paint with his mouth.
He tried his best to copy your style.
Why didn't he say something?
No matter how good the painting was,
it was still only a copy of your style.
If it being a fake were found out, your career would be over.
Why...?
Why didn't he...?
Oikawa-san...
Even though it is somewhat rough as a whole,
I actually really like this Seiran.
This one is like the others in that the intention
of helping someone was kept in mind.
Officer Takagi?
Oh, hey.
I guess you're about to grow wings and fly away.
Am I wrong?
How'd you know?
Elimination.
Inspector Megure mentioned that trick from the police party.
You couldn't have known about that, right?
Inspector Megure was there and Officer
Satou learned it from her father.
You weren't Officer Chiba, since he
was already inside of a bag earlier.
Is that really a good place to hide a body?
Since the zipper on the bag doesn't go past the neck,
that means all they can see is a sleeping
Chiba, but it's really Officer Takagi.
This is a trap you set to help you escape.
But I would like to thank you for showing me the trick he used.
Don't mention it. I'm a professional with tricks, after all.
I mean...
I hope you'll let me go this time.
I only came to clear my name. I'm innocent.
Just like her underwear.
Conan-kun!
Hey, the hell are you...
Oh...
Take this!
Bastard!
Kaitou Kid?
So he was disguised as Officer Takagi?
How strange, I aimed the ball at the smoke.
It should have hit him.
What the hell?
Dad! Your pants are...!
That brat...