Speed!
I'll always be your partner!
The car the three of us are riding in
is rigged to explode if we lower our speed!
What do we do, old man?
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid
but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
♪ Chasing after rabbits… ♪
♪ in Kano Mountain… ♪
♪ Fishing for little fish… ♪
♪ in Kano River… ♪
Ran.
How many more kilometers
until we get to the hot springs?
Still about 100 kilometers, I guess.
What? We've only traveled for 10?
Dad!
Why do you keep asking every five minutes?
I get that you're excited, but...
Shouldn't you be paying
attention to our speed?
I know that.
But today's going to be a great day.
First is the hot springs...
Then a delicious meal, and some good booze.
And I'll enjoy it even more
since it's half price!
Put me through to Inspector Megure, with the
MPD's First Criminal Investigation Division, Section 3.
Ran, get that for me.
Who's it from?
Let's see...
Inspector Megure?
Did you say Inspector Megure?
Hello—
Mouri-kun! Where are you?
I-In Takaoka.
This is Ran...
I'm in a car right now
with my dad and Conan-kun.
Ran-kun?
In Takaoka?
Their current location is Takaoka!
What'd the inspector say?
Well...
Listen up, Ran-kun.
Yes?
Remain calm and listen.
That car you're in...
There's a bomb wired to it!
A bomb?
What'd you say?
Ran-neechan!
Once you've driven more than 10 kilometers,
the bomb in that car will switch on.
10 kilometers?
That means, the switch is already...
That car...
Do not stop that car!
You have to keep moving forward!
As soon as your speed falls below 20 km/h...
It'll explode!
It seems that's how the criminal wired it.
But, Inspector, couldn't this be a prank?
The criminal claimed he would blow up
the water tower first.
Since we can't confirm
if the threat is true or not...
We should assume that
there really is a bomb attached.
An explosion...
A bomb.
Since it exploded just as
the old man happened to pass it...
The bomb must have been
equipped with a timer.
That was a demonstration
to prove this wasn't a trick or a prank.
There really is a bomb in this car.
Mouri-kun?
Mouri-kun!
Keep calm.
Just drive calmly.
I've engaged emergency measures.
Let's get going.
We'll try to catch up with you.
Say, Inspector...
Do you have any intel on the bomber?
All right, I'll tell you on the way.
Earlier, a man called me,
giving the name Sugiyama.
While that's likely an alias,
he said that the car Kogoro Mouri rented
from Beika Rental Cars
had been fitted with a bomb.
Does someone named Sugiyama
bring anything to mind?
Sugiyama...
The clerk from the rental service
was named Sugiyama.
Beika Rental Cars
Jiro Sugiyama
He's the one who referred us
to that 50% off hot spring deal today.
But why me?
He said that if he was able to
kill a famous detective...
He said he'd become famous as well.
I thought it was a joke initially,
but he knew about your plans.
And after his display,
with that water tower explosion...
We have no choice
but to follow his instructions.
Instructions?
Sugiyama...
Wants you to get on the highway.
The highway?
What for?
No idea.
But until we have a better grasp of the situation,
we should follow his instructions.
I understand.
The criminal called, and requested us by name to get on the highway...
Did he choose today for a specific reason?
Please report on the status of the blockade near the Takaoka entrance to the expressway.
The entrance to the Gosho Highway from Takaoka,
towards Araimachi, has now been closed.
Also, it has been sealed
in the Takaokamachi direction.
Route 8 has been sealed in the Takaoka entry direction, and detoured.
Footpaths adjacent to each road have also been sealed.
Confirming sealing of all roads.
Alternative routes have been ensured.
Roger.
Mouri-kun!
We located your car.
Keep your car in the open lane.
Understood.
Ran, Conan...
The inspector is already here.
The police will help however they can.
Don't worry.
Kogoro Mouri...
Writhe in terror!
I'll enjoy it, ever so slowly...
Until you're dead.
It can't be!
What's wrong, Dad?
The gasoline...
It's half gone!
When I got the car, it was full!
Damn!
The bomber must've waited for us to check, then emptied the tank just before we left.
It's fine!
Before we run out of gasoline,
I'll get the two of you out of here.
Mouri-kun, let the two of them out first.
Open the windows!
They won't open!
Same with the door!
Ran-neechan, what about your side?
This side's no good either.
Damn! They must have been sabotaged!
There's less than half a tank of gasoline left.
At 20 km/h, we have one more hour at most.
Once the gasoline runs out,
the car will stop and explode.
Since the windows and doors
won't open from the inside...
What can we do?
Megure here.
Takagi-kun, where are you right now?
I'm almost there!
Inspector Megure, sorry for the delay!
We're depending on you, Takagi.
All right!
Maintain this height!
Roger!
I'm counting on you...
Takagi.
Conan-kun.
Get back from the window.
While Ran and I can get out once
the window glass is broken,
what about the old man?
He'll have to take his foot off
the accelerator to get out,
which will cause the car to slow down.
What should I do?
We can't let the car go below 20 km/h.
Will anything work?
Slow down!
Back up!
Move the car back just a bit!
Good!
The tires...
The tires?
The tires' spinning...
Stop without stopping them...
We can do it!
I have no other choice. I'll have to do it!
Ran-san!
Conan-kun!
Detective Takagi, hurry up
and save me! I'm scared!
Just hold on, Conan-kun.
All right!
I'm going to pull you over now!
Damn!
Conan-kun!
Are you all right, Conan-kun?
All right, once more!
It'll be OK. Don't worry.
They rescued one person.
No matter.
In another ten minutes,
the gasoline will be all used up.
When that happens, Mouri will die.
Conan-kun is safe and sound!
Next, we'll get Ran-san!
No!
Inspector Megure!
Bad news!
We're only few kilometers away
from a traffic jam.
There's enough space
for one car to make it, but...
No more than that, even side-by-side.
Abort the rescue efforts!
Let's get on it!
Ran! Hurry!
Ran-neechan!
Hurry!
Ran-san!
It won't work!
O-Oh no!
Takagi! Back up now!
Hurry!
Ran...
M-Mouri-kun...
Inspector!
Uncle Kogoro, he...
Ran...
Take my jacket and put it over your head.
Roll after you jump.
You may get hurt...
But you won't die.
You can do this.
But, what about you, Dad?
Saving you comes first.
Just do this, for me.
Mouri-kun?
Can you hear me, Mouri-kun?
Almost there...
We're almost there, Brother!
Ichiro Matsumiya?
Right.
It's a case that we worked on together.
The culprit murdered his ex-lover, and when trying to escape arrest,
he drove his bike onto the highway.
He crashed into the safety railing and died, three years ago today.
But, I thought that was suicide.
Matsumiya had a younger brother
who was studying in the US at the time.
He didn't know the circumstances.
No matter how much we explained,
he wouldn't believe it was an accident.
No way...
So this is revenge over a misunderstanding?
Right now, we're looking for his brother.
We'll arrest him as soon as possible.
So?
How much gasoline is left?
It's almost empty.
I don't know how long we have...
Ran...
It's my fault.
Sorry for getting you in this situation.
But you can do it.
Hurry and jump!
Dad...
Idiot!
Get out of the way!
Watch where you're going!
Kogoro Mouri...
It's almost time to say goodbye.
This tunnel...
Will become your grave!
All right!
I did it!
I got Kogoro Mouri...
I've avenged you...
Brother!
Where are you going, if I may ask?
I'm Megure, from the MPD.
Jiro Matsumiya-san, I believe?
It was three years ago today.
We looked into cases involving
Kogoro Mouri and the highway,
and found the death of your brother,
Ichiro Matsumiya-san.
And that he had a brother, Jiro Matsumiya...
That's how we got to you.
So what about it?
We suspect you used the computer in your house
today to hack into the highway department's security.
And, we suspect it's
somehow related to our case.
Would you mind coming with us?
Is something wrong?
Sugiyama...
No, Matsumiya-san.
You look like you just saw a ghost.
How?
How... How are you still alive?
I simply used the clues you left behind.
When the car stopped,
it should've exploded!
We refueled the car, so it's still running.
It's only a matter of time
until the bomb is disarmed.
B-But how?
I wired it to the body!
T-There's no way you could get to it!
The car kept moving without stopping.
The experts are disarming it as we speak...
While keeping the speed at 20 km/h.
But, when...
What about the explosion?
About that.
Inside the tunnel...
The bomb squad was hidden
in a large truck's cargo bed.
They set up a slope and a net...
We're all set.
Once I reached the truck,
they signaled me to drive the car inside it.
Once the car made it onto
the truck bed, the net stopped it,
while tire rollers kept the tires spinning.
Afterwards, they were able to
move in and rescue Ran...
Fill up the gas tank...
Pry my door open...
And hold the accelerator in place.
This way, the tires kept spinning,
even though the car wasn't moving.
So they could take their time to disarm it.
And using a smoke flare and fireworks...
Fire in the hole!
We made it seem like the car had exploded.
That...
Can't be...
Damn!
If you all hadn't followed so closely...
My brother wouldn't have died...
What are you saying?
Your brother wanted to commit suicide.
You're wrong!
You're the reason my brother is dead!
My brother wasn't some suicidal coward!
At the scene of your brother's accident...
There was no evidence
of the brakes being applied.
Moreover, just before he crashed into the fence...
He took off his helmet.
It was intentional suicide.
No...
Matsumiya...
You're the one who won't listen.
Do you really think what you've done
would make your late brother happy?
Shut up!
Matsumiya...
You're lucky, compared to your brother.
In the end, no one died today...
Which means you didn't become
a murderer, right?
Mouri...
Well, you're a lucky guy.
I'm glad.
Mouri-san...
You know, I was really surprised
when I saw that the person driving that enormous truck was actually Detective Sato.
Yes, it's me!
Why would you be surprised?
Conan-kun said you were
the one who came up with the plan.
What's wrong, Dad?
We should hurry to the hot springs!
There's no reason to do that now, is there?
But the half-price special was for today only!
Unless he just made that up
to get us to take the car.
No way!
Well, it's possible that it just might be true.
And therefore, Inspector...
Let me borrow a police car.
Are you daft?
How could I do that?
I knew it.
Always trying to find
a bright side, eh, old man?
All right, let's head for the library.
Wait up!
Shin'ichi!
Huh? It won't open!
What?!
On the next Conan:
Young Shin'ichi Kudo's Adventure
(Part I)
Next Conan's Hint:
Shin'ichi Kudo's Younger Brother
Next week, it's a story about ten years ago!
So it's a story without Conan-kun?
But Shin'ichi was there.
Oh, really?