No matter what happens, I'm still your partner.
Today, we go back 10 years, to when Ran and I...
embarked on a dangerous adventure!
Recognizing that single truth,
a child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Library
Book The Adventures of Sherlock Holmes by Conan Doyle
Conan-kun, you can't do that!
Don't be so loud!
Ah, sorry.
Besides, if you keep yawning while reading his work,
the one you love so much, Conan Doyle, will roll over in his grave.
What do you expect?
I read all of the mysteries in here while I was in elementary school.
There's nothing left.
Is that so?
This world is full and brimming with mysteries.
What he... That voice just now...
The deal back then...
Right, it was that guy...
What with that scared look?
Oh, it's nothing.
Hey!
Kojima-kun, what're you doing?
Don't stand on books!
But if I don't, I can't reach the books up here...
Sensei, help!
Sensei!
I don't feel sorry for you!
Are you all right, Genta-kun?
Which book do you want?
I'll get it for you.
Ah, let's see...
Let me put this one back first.
There's something in the back of the bookshelf.
What is it?
Maybe it's a dead snake?
I don't know, not all the way out here.
Young Kudo Shinichi's Adventure, Part One!
Jeez, don't say things like that,
I really thought that it was a snake!
It looks like a wallet.
Yeah, it looks like leather.
But, why would someone put this in the back of this book shelf?
Hey, let's look inside!
There may be money in it!
Jeez...
It looks like there's just a piece of paper.
What the...
There's something written on it, though.
What's it say?
Thank you...
Class 1-A, Mouri Ran.
How'd you know that?
It really say that?
Um, let's look...
T-That's really what it says, but...
Of course I'd know, Ran and I were...
No, I mean... Ran-neechan told me about
something that happened a long time ago.
Something happened?
Yeah, something strange, suspicious, and mysterious.
It all started 10 years ago...
10 years ago
Wait up, Shinichi!
I don't think we should be going to the school this late...
That's why I told you to go home.
You'll get in trouble for sneaking out.
I'll expose the monster on my own.
But, if you go by yourself, you'll get eaten!
Stupid! There's no such thing as a monster.
But Sonoko-chan heard about it!
It appears in the library when there's a full moon!
It's a ghost with a creepy voice and a strange hat!
There's a full moon out tonight.
This'll be interesting.
Shinichi!
Stop slowing me down.
But...
I knew everything would be locked, we can't get in.
No, we can.
Huh? Why's it unlocked?
I unlocked it before I left today, since the
security guard doesn't check carefully.
All right, let's head for the library.
Wait up!
Someone's in the library!
It's the ghost!
What? It's just the security guy?
That was scary...
Looks like he's been drinking again.
Great. Since he just checked, he won't be back for awhile.
See? No ghosts here.
But there's that sound...
There's a ghost with a hat on near the window!
Shinichi!
Stupid, look closer.
The curtain has slipped off some of its hooks.
It only appears on a full moon because the
moonlight makes the shadow form.
That weird "laughing" sound is the wind
that's coming through the window.
All most ghost stories lack is on explanation.
Is that so?
Well then, that resolves everything.
Is that really so?
Shinichi!
What you're doing is reading the preview on the cover of the book,
simply pretending you can see everything at its finest.
Book Arséne Lupin: Gentleman Burglar by Maurice LeBlanc
This world is deep...
and brimming with mysteries.
Who are you!?
Me?
I am your...
Sibling.
What?
No, I should be more specific.
I'm your younger brother.
My younger brother?
What do you mean?
Run, go get the security guard.
All right!
What? It won't open!
What!?
It's no use.
I've cast a spell on that door
It'll only listen to me.
What'd you say!?
Careful, I didn't come to fight you.
I've actually come to challenge you.
Try to find the treasure that's in here.
The treasure?
If you can find it, you win.
You can then have the treasure.
And...
I'll even tell you who I am.
Whether you accept my challenge is up to you.
If you do accept, I'll lift the spell on the door and let you go home.
If you do not, you'll spend the rest of your lives in this cold, dark room.
Oh, by the way...
I really love seeing blood...
And anything red.
We're not scared of you!
We're not gonna listen to a bad man like you!
Oh my, what a fiery little girl.
I accept.
I said I accept.
I'll play your game.
That's you all right, Kudo Shinichi...
My older brother.
Shinichi!
You! What're you...
He's gone...
He disappeared?
Hey Shinichi, are you really going to accept?
Yeah.
Dad has always told me to never back down from a fight.
But that man just then was like a demon!
I don't care if it was the devil or some demon.
I just wanna know who he is...
And what this code means.
But, Shinichi, if that guy uses his magic around us again, he may kill us!
Magic?
Remember, he casted a spell on the door so it wouldn't open!
Stupid, take o closer look.
You see the map next to the door, right?
There's fishing line that goes through the
hook attached to the top of the wall.
When we came in, he used the fishing line to push
the map against the door so it wouldn't open.
All of this was done from where he was sitting originally.
That guy said a lot to try and scare us,
but all he is...
is some clumsy magician that forgot to hide his trick.
Amazing, Shinichi! You're just like Holmes!
You think so?
All right then, Holmes-san!
Do you know what the code says?
I don't know what it means yet,
but it says...
Note: Kanji characters are the last you learn when learning
Japanese, As they're the most complicated.
FIND HAIDO'S STRANGE BEGINNINGS
"Haido no... Okori wo... Chinmeyo."
I think.
Note Some kanji characters are rare, so it's likely that
some 1st graders would not be able to read them.
"Okori wo chinemeyo"? Is that really how it's read?
Yeah, I see "okuru" in a lot of novels.
"Chinkon" means "requiem" and is written with two kanji.
As for "chin", I saw "chin-kon-ka" on one of my mom's CD's.
I asked her about it so I'm sure.
I'm sure on adult will know.
Let's ask our dads!
Stupid!
Don't tell any of the adults.
This is a battle between me and him.
That boy read...
"Ikori wo shizumeyo" as "Okori wo chinmeyo"!?
How cute!
That Shinichi guy's such an idiot!
I was really young then.
It's not like you could have then.
Hey...
What do you expect? He was in first grade.
But that Shinichi boy reminds me of Conan-kun!
Is that so?
And then?
What happened next?
Hurry and finish!
Those two got home safe, right?
Ran-neechan said that next...
Come on, Ran!
Where have you been this whole time!?
Um, I forgot something at school, so I had to...
Don't lie to me!
It's that Shinichi-kun again, isn't it?
Yeah...
I knew it!
I haven't seen him much lately.
What kind of kid is Yukiko raising over there?
Maybe Yuki-chan is trying the hands-off approach.
Oh, dear, you're going to work now?
Yeah, there was a murder at a warehouse in the Haido Port.
Lieutenant Inspector Megure and I are going to check it out.
Be careful out there.
It could be dangerous.
You too, make sure the doors are locked.
That thief hos been taking things everywhere.
Of course, I'm the wife of a police officer.
Take care.
All right, take care of Ran for me, Eri.
I get it.
I'll take care of him.
I'm sorry, Eri-chan.
Good night.
Hold it! I'm not letting you go to bed until you spill it, Shinichi.
I wonder what you were doing taking a girl to school after dark.
I told you already, didn't?
I forgot something there.
What kind of answer is that?
Oh, it's fine.
They both got home safe.
But still, Yuusaku...
Besides, this isn't o police interrogation.
He's not going to say anything with you being so angry.
First, quell your anger and remain calm.
Yuusaku says, "Ikari wo shizumete" here, as the "quell your anger"
part, as compared to shinichi's "okori wo chinmeyo" from earlier.
QUELL - ANGER
"Ikari wo shizumeru"?
Hey, how do you write that?
QUELL - ANGER
"Ikari wo shizumeru"!
Is it written like this?
What is this?
It's a code that my teacher mode.
What a mean teacher, giving such hard kanji to first graders.
It must be an interesting teacher who is fond of riddles.
Riddles?
I'm not sure what they want to get across by mentioning Haido.
Oh, say,
why don't we go to the beach?
That'd be great!
Haido Port?
The code says to go to Haido Port, Shinichi?
Yeah.
QUELL THE ANGER OF HAIDO
"Haido no ikari wo shizumeyo" refers to Haido Port and...
Note "Drop the anchor" can be pronounced the same
as "quell the anger" just written differently.
"Dropping the anchor."
But Shinichi, didn't you say it was "Okori wo chinmeyo" last night?
D-Did I now?
But is this all right?
The guy that gave you the code snuck into
the school and waited for you, right?
We should just tell the police.
It's not too late to call them.
Let's just wait until we've solved it.
Oh, and I'm sorry for making you come out so early, Professor.
No, no, I'm actually glad.
It's been awhile since I saw you two getting along.
You guys used to always come by and play before school.
I hadn't seen you all together in awhile, so I was worried.
I thought you'd gotten into a fight.
I-It's nothing like that...
Right?
Y-Yeah...
Look at all the police cars...
Did something happen-here?
That's right, my Dad mentioned something last night!
A murder at Haido Port!
Then, that guy could'be the criminal?
No, he couldn't be.
This happened around the time you all were at the school.
I heard the criminal was caught before daybreak, anyway.
Besides, what we really need to find out is why
that guy wanted you guys to come here.
Maybe he'll come by if we wait for him?
No...
And anything red.
Look, look.
It's gotta be red.
Maybe it's that.
The lights flash red!
The professor already told us, didn't he?
The case has nothing to do with him.
He couldn't have known the police cars would be parked here.
That means it must be something that's always here...
Something that's red.
The fire hydrant!
But it doesn't look like anyone's here...
It's peeling!
It's a piece of paper!
It's another one that's hard to read.
Let me see it.
"Clear the allegations against Toriya, and demolish the liver of Goroukou."
We know "Toriya" is referring to the Toriya District, but...
We can't be sure what "clear the allegations" means.
It's probably another riddle.
Note Mito Koumon was historical figure later featured
in a famous TV drama with the same name.
Is the Goroukou mentioned referring to Koumon-sama?
Maybe.
Hey Professor, "clear the allegations" would mean
to prove that someone wasn't the criminal, right?
Yeah.
Note In japan, black means guilty while white means innocent.
The criminal must be the black one.
My Dad says it a lot.
He says: "The criminal is the black one!"
Black?
The criminal is the black one?
The opposite is white...
White, white, white...
Toriya Castle!
Note "Shiro" in Japanese means both "castle" and the color "white".
Then let's head to where the castle was once!
No, we need to head to the floodgates near the castle!
The floodgates?
Not to the castle?
NOTE "Goroukou" was the name he assumed as he travelled about
the countryside writing wrong, disguised as an old man.
"Goroukou" comes from Mito Koumon, while
"liver" points us to the internal organs.
To "demolish" his "liver" means to remove the middle...
So, by removing the middle kanji, "to" and "kou", from Mito Koumon...
I see!
MIZU MON
That leaves you with the two kanji for "water" and "gate".
Since it's near Toriya Castle, it has to be the Toriya Floodgates!
Well, these are the floodgates...
I don't see any weird red things...
I knew we should gone to the castle first
But if that were so, "clear the allegations against
Toriya" is all he would have had to write on the paper.
That means there must be something here, near he floodgates...
Or maybe something between where the
castle once was and the floodgates...
Something red...
The railroad crossing!
Do you see anything?
No, nothing at all.
Wait...
If it were something you could find before the
lights turned red, it'd defeat the purpose.
That means it has to be something that only shows after it turns red...
Shinichi?
Did you find something?
"Okuho's"...
"Erase his mark and..."
With o raspy voice, endure loneliness.
This is the third one, huh?