No otter what happens, I'm still your partner.
Today, we go back ten years...
As we try to find the truth behind the red clues!
Recognizing that single truth,
a child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Kobayashi-sensei uncovered a wallet from the back of a bookshelf.
And inside, was a message from Ran as a first grader.
Ten years ago...
After going into the school at night.
Shinichi met his "younger brother, who gave him a riddle...
Saying that a treasure awaited him at the end.
"Erase his mark, and..."
With a raspy voice, endure loneliness.
Young Kudo Shinichi's Adventure
(Part Two)
Young Kudo Shinichi's Adventure, Part Two!
Even if it's talking about the Okuho District,
we don't know what the rest means.
Maybe it's about a dentist?
Note: "Kamishimeru" can mean endure in some cases and the action of "biting" in others.
It does say "bite".
No, there aren't any around.
Then, where's it pointing to?
Hurry up and tell us, Conan-kun!
Now, now, start with he "Erase Okuho's mark part.
I got it!
Maybe it's the supermarket?
The supermarket?
Why would you think that?
W-Why?
Dad always says, "With some management, Mom could erase our deficit."
That's why Mom always gets worried when she goes shopping.
That's not it.
It's not "akaji, it's "akashi'.
It's some kind of mark that can prove a person innocent.
Finding the "mark" could refer to scratch-offs...
Then, erasing it would be...
A postmark?
Then, the place it mentioned...
Yeah, that's what Ran-neechan said next.
Ten years ago, that guy named Shinichi noticed that, too.
10 Years Ago
We need to go to Okuho post office?
Oh, does that mean you've solved it, Shinichi?
Yeah, half of it.
This "akashi" it's talking about should be a mark, right?
So, erasing the mark would be...
A postmark!
The mark that tells when a stamp was issued.
That's why it's the post office.
But, but...
The post office workers don't hove raspy voices, do they?
Right.
I'm not sure about that part,
but if it is the post office, we have to go.
Why?
Because these codes are about going somewhere, finding another code on something red, and doing it again, right?
The first red thing was a fire hydrant.
Then e railroad crossing's warning lights.
And if the third code is about the post office, it's gotta be...
I really love red things.
I got it!
A mailbox!
There should be a red mailbox, right?
Exactly.
He took Ran with him!?
Shinichi-kun did?
Yeah, they went somewhere with Agasa-san.
I think it was... Haido Port.
H-Haido Port?
There was a murder there!
Oh, that won't be a problem.
I heard that murder was solved this morning.
It's a holiday, too.
It's better than staying inside and watching TV or playing games.
I think they should be able to go beyond the doors on a grand adventure.
Lately, my son has been staying inside reading books all day.
I should be thanking your daughter for taking him outside.
But wasn't it Shinichi-kun who took her?
Now, now, don't worry!
Jeez...
You're always so carefree, Yuki-chan.
Oh, right!
I got a call from the Police HQ for you, Yuusaku-san.
They said, "Thank you for your assistance in helping protect be jewels."
Oh, that.
That must be from when you beat that eccentric thief, right?
No, actually...
I should say his escape was he clever part.
But, why'd hey call your house?
They tried to call you all, but the line was out.
Oh, I get it, Yuu-chan.
You unplugged the phone again, didn't you?
Oh, well, I have to be able to concentrate when my deadlines come up.
Well, if those kids coll, tell my daughter to come home immediately.
Oh? You're leaving already?
I don't have time to relax right now.
My first trial is coming up next week, so I have to finish preparing for it.
I see.
You'll become a great lawyer, I know it.
Good luck!
Thanks, but I'll probably lose since it's my first case.
I'll let you cheer me up afterwards, all right?
All right!
Oh, that's right, aren't you supposed to meet with someone?
You know, that magician that's training you.
I completely forgot!
I made plans to hand over my latest essay.
I'm gonna be late!
Okuho Post Office
Hey Shinichi, here's the mailbox...
But there's nothing on it.
How weird, I was sure it was here.
I guess we need to figure out the "with a raspy voice, endure loneliness" part first then, huh?
Hello, evening paper!
How's business?
As you can see, the cuckoo is singing.
A singing "kakko"?
What's "kakko"?
It's cuckoo.
It's referring to the "school"!
Lets go, Mouri!
Mouri?
Hey, Shinichi!
I said "Shinichi"!
Jeez, didn't I tell you?
Don't call me by my first name at school!
It's embarrassing.
But Shinichi is Shinichi, right?
Call me "Kudo-kun".
And in turn, I'll call you "Mouri-san".
Well, we don't be kids forever.
I'll see you later, Mouri-san.
This is the only red thing near the school.
I can't find anything up here.
Look closer! It has to be there!
It's just not up here.
There's something on the pole!
Right, since this code was made for kids,
it'd have to be somewhere we can reach.
What's his?
You can't read it either, Professor?
If you try to make something of it, it tries to say "Beika", which is probably the district, but...
Maybe it's in Chinese?
Note: Chuugoku = China
The bit after Beika is read "Chuugoku", right?
That's true, but that doesn't make it Chinese.
Beika Middle...
Beika Middle School...
Is there one?
No, Beika just has a college and a high school.
But why is the last character the only one with a square around it?
Well...
I've seen this somewhere before...
Dad!
What're you all doing here out here?
Ah, actually I...
T-The Professor mode us a code and we're trying to solve it.
Right, Professor?
Yeah, pretty much.
A code?
Dad, why're you here?
Oh, see, the killer we caught this morning used to work at that post office,
so the Lieutenant Inspector and I came for statements.
You know, seeing hem solving codes brings back memories.
When I was a child, my friends and I used to make codes and pretend to be spies.
But this one's too hard to get.
Well, let me see it.
All right, bu it's really hard.
What're you trying to say!? We're police officers!
A little, simple riddle made for children is nothing to us.
Hey, Mouri-kun, do you get it?
No, not at all...
Well, now! It's a clever code.
But it may be too hard for kids.
What? Couldn't get it either?
Hey, Lieutenant Inspector, how about some Mahjong tonight?
Oh! 1 was thinking the exact same thing!
I dunno why, but seeing that code mode me wanna play Mahjong.
What? You, too?
Mahjong?
Bye Ran, be sure to get home soon!
Yes!
Shinichi, this is a game from China called "Mahjong".
Just like in Seven Bridge, in order to win, you hove to draw the last waiting tile or use another player's.
But, what makes it different from Seven Bridge is...
In Mahjong, like Poker, you earn have a complete hand.
This, which is either "tonba" or "nanba",
is the rule that allows "ba" to control the game.
Mahjong?
You think this code has something to do with Mahjong?
I think we can solve it with Mahjong.
I know the third character, "chuu" and the last one "higashi" are on Mahjong tiles.
The others aren't on Mahjong tiles.
For the first two, we can just assume they refer to the Beika District.
The last character, "higashi", surrounded by a square is "ba" in Mahjong.
See, that means it's either "tanba" or "nanba", right?
The two characters on top are read "kokushi".
It's one of the complete hands, called "kokushimusou", which is when you can get 1, 9, and the other character tiles.
But what about the "chuu" on top of that?
Well, I guess the Mahjong tile "dora" may do it.
Note: machi = waiting
Oh, wait, since it's a kokushi, it'd probably be a "machi" tile.
And? When you read all three together?
Machi... yaku... ba?
I see! It's City Hall!
I see, and without a city hall in Beika, it must mean the branch office.
Yep, let's go!
It isn't here.
It's not here, Shinichi.
There's nothing red here.
Oh, it's already late in the evening...
Shinichi, why don't we go home and continue tomorrow?
Since you're out of school for Golden Week, it'll be fine.
Golden Week?
I see, it's a holiday!
It is, but what's that mean?
Since it's the ward office, it should be up...
"The End"?
Is this English?
Well, those are just "W" and "S" from the alphabet.
I don't know what the arrow means, though.
But since it says "the end", this should be the last one.
Do "W and "S" mean anything by themselves?
That's right! They're directions!
"S" stands for South, while "W" stands for West!
So it's telling us o go from South to West?
Maybe the arrow is meant to tell us to look in those directions?
South is that way...
West is...
This way.
It's beautiful!
I see.
So that's it.
I know now.
I know who made the code.
Who is it?
My Dad.
He asked a friend to give us the code to get us here...
To view the sunset.
It was probably because I've been inside reading a lot lately.
But the only reason you went to the school last night was because of a ghost story you heard by chance, right?
Sonoko-chan said she heard it from a man who delivered books to the library.
He told her about the ghost.
That was probably the guy who was there last night.
I see.
All he had to do was mention it to Ran-kun's friend, which would mean it would get back to you, who loves mysteries.
Exactly.
To put it simply, we were manipulated by my Dad this entire time.
But aren't you glad?
We got to see such a pretty sunset.
Yeah, I'd rather not admit it, but I feel the same, Ran.
Oh, I mean... Mouri.
I like Ran!
I wanna hear Ran!
Is that...
If you want...
I guess it's OK.
Really!?
That's great, Shinichi!
Lemme go!
I need to thank your dad!
Stupid, if anyone, thank my Dad's friend who gave us the code and is watching us now.
That guy's around here watching?
Yeah.
To be able to show us the sunset, he'd have to keep an eye on us the whole time, right?
Otherwise, he wouldn't know how long it'd take us to finish each one.
He had to watch us so that-when we had solved one message,
he'd be able to control the timing by switching the next one out.
guess that's how he was able to time when we got here.
But couldn't that have been your dad?
No, he would have stepped out and said:
"Took you long enough."
Hey, guy from lost night!
You're listening, right?
We're going to put a message for you in the wallet!
Come get it later!
We'll put it behind that gentleman thief book you were reading!
Please come get it!
So, that's why there's a piece of paper with "Thank you, Class 1-A Mouri Ran" written on it in this wallet.
That was such a wonderful story!
But the book in front of the wallet...
Wasn't one about a gentleman thief.
That's probably because...
The arrangement of the books has changed over the last ten years.
But still, whoever that was never came to pick up the message.
Even if the arrangement changed, he'd know where it was.
That's true.
But the one who came up with the codes...
I think he ran out of ideas near the end.
Why?
Because, at the beginning, the riddles were very interesting,
but the last one was just "S" and "W", saying "look west".
That's what I mean.
My reasoning back then was wrong!
If he wanted to show us the sun, the "W" would've sufficed.
The arrow and "S" wouldn't have been needed!
Then, what were they for...
The "S, "W" and the arrow?
Why was the last one just a direction?
The first was a port...
The second was the shape of a castle...
The third was floodgates...
A middle school...
He looks sunk in thought.
Actually, the post office code started with erasing a "mark', with "mark being encircled...
So, if you "erased" the circle...
Then, if you wrote down the symbols vertically as I asked before...
And if "S" to "W" meant to turn it 90 degrees...
That means it would be...
Oxhide...
Leather!?
It's the wallet!
We were wrong!
He wasn't watching then!
We'll put it behind that gentlemen thief book you were reading!
Please come get it!
Conan-kun?
Hey!
What's wrong?
I see, that's it!
This code, there's no way a kid could solve it.
This code was meant for Dad!
He thought that I'd go to Dad after I got stuck.
That means, ten years ago...
The one who gave it to us was...
10 Years Ago
Well then, thank you very much.
No, it's likely just someone spreading a rumor.
After all, we magic-ions are con artists that play tricks when people aren't looking.
Oh, now, a con artist?
It's such a shame that Mr. Kudo couldn't make it.
Actually, I should say I'm relieved.
My tricks are nothing but a house built of sand in his eyes.
I feel as if he can see through them all.
Don't be modest.
You're one of my "Seven Knights that I've met".
You really are, Kuroba Toichi.
Those essays, I love reading them.
I'm quite a fan.
You can have this!
You're such a pretty old lady!
Hey, Kaitou, don't be so bothersome.
What an energetic child you have!
But, did you know...
You aren't supposed to use "pretty" and "old lady" together!?
Since Mr. Kudo couldn't make it...
A letter from my friend will arrive for him later, so if you could have him reply to this address...
Oh, that's for the fan letter to Yuusaku, right?
When I told him about it, he wrote you a reply and had me bring it.
But, I wouldn't really call it a "reply"...
Wait!
It's just a simple exclamation mark.
Am I right?
Yeah...
But, how'd you...
As should be expected from the one who named me.
My friend's letter was the same.
It was just one symbol.
Dear Yuusaku Kudo...
Kaitou No. 1412.
That's right, she said...
Yuusoku is the parent of the name Kid!
A reporter jotted down "1412", which Yuusoku read as "K.I.D."
I'm your sibling.
Well, maybe I should say, your younger brother.
So that's what he meant then.
Are you gonna be able to stop me next time?
Yeah...
Of course!
But, what's this supposed to mean?
This question mark...