Anniversary!
I'll always be your partner!
When she sees her mother removed her ring,
Ran's about to explode with rage like never before!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
Could you get the door, Kuriyama-san?
Kuriyama-san?
Kuriyam—
Oh, that's right...
I sent her out to run some errands for me.
Coming!
But who could it be, so early in the morning?
Congratulations, Mom!
Ran?
And Conan-kun?
So, congratulations for what?
Don't tell me you've forgotten
such an important anniversary!
Anniversary?
It's not my birthday...
Not that!
Today's the day you and Dad...
went out on a date for the first time!
It's your first date anniversary!
What's with the excitement?
I found an old photo album while I was
organizing the bookshelves last night.
All the photos had little
notes in your handwriting.
There was the first
dinner at home anniversary...
The first married spat anniversary...
Dad's first arrest anniversary...
Right, Conan-kun?
Uh, yeah...
Well, even she was young and foolish once...
So, as your daughter, I decided
to throw a celebration for you!
Sorry.
I'm in no mood today for dealing with
jokes about moldy old tales like that.
Sheesh.
Oh, and...
Please don't bring me flowers again.
This little guy might chew on them...
And some flowers are poisonous to cats.
Oh, sorry! I'll put them in the bathroom
where he can't get them.
Let's see... A vase...
A vase...
Conan-kun, could you get that vase for me?
Sure.
Not this one!
Use the vase on the shelf.
Say...
Are you mad at me?
N-No, of course not.
But you've seemed irritated
ever since I got here.
Hello?
Kisaki Law Office...
What? Right now?
Sure, that's fine with me...
That's so kind of you! I'll be there right away.
All right... Sure.
Sorry, Ran.
I need to go out for a while.
Can you look after Goro-chan for me?
It's just about time for him
to visit the litterbox.
Kuriyama-san should be back soon.
Who do you think she was
talking to just now?
I don't know...
Maybe it's another lawyer she knows?
Oh! Hey!
Bad kitty! Get out of there!
Sheesh...
Look, a photo!
It must've been inside this vase.
Who's this guy in the photo with Mom?
Looks like he's the person
who just called a minute ago.
How do you know?
See the number written
on the back of the photo?
The same number is on
the phone's call history.
The guy sure doesn't look like a lawyer...
Y-Yeah...
M-Maybe Mom hid the picture in this vase
because she didn't want me to see it?
You're probably overthinking this...
But there's nothing but waste papers in here...
She set it up so if I looked in here
she could claim it was a waste paper basket!
H-Her wedding ring!
Come to think it, she didn't have her ring on...
Could... that... mean...
She's cheating?!
Let's go, Conan-kun!
We can still catch up with her!
I'm back...
Oh?
Kisaki-sensei? Kisaki-sensei!
A toppled vase...
Trash strewn on the floor, and...
A mysterious bouquet of flowers...
I smell a case!
Oh, it's just you!
All right...
Conan-kun!
R-Right, I'm coming...
Found her!
There's no doubt about it...
It's him...it's him!
Ran-neechan?
Welcome! Can I help you?
O-Oh, right...
But why?
Why, Mom?
It's time for action!
I'm gonna ask them myself!
Why don't you wait and see?
We don't know if he's a bad guy!
Y-Yeah, but...
Megu-chan!
What a pwetty little cutie-pie you are as always.
Thanks!
C-Cutie-pie?
What's with the baby talk?
I don't think she's cheating with this guy.
He doesn't seem like her type.
B-But when Dad's drunk...
He's like, "Ran-chan! Can you get
me more sake? Pwetty pwease!"
And everyone knows Dad's a womanizer.
Maybe he's Mom's type after all.
Look, Conan-kun!
His arm...
It's all scratched up!
Looks like he's not such
a nice guy after all...
Oh! Wait...
Mom...
She's shivering.
The...
The shaking...
won't stop...
S-She's crying...
Mom's crying?
But Mom never cries like that!
So... why...
would she cry over a
baby-talking womanizer like him?!
Wait.
A photo, trash, and a ring hidden in a vase...
The way he was using baby talk...
Scratch marks all over his arms...
And the words she uttered
with tears in her eyes...
"The shaking won't stop"?
What should I do?
Don't worry.
Think of it as a dream. It's all just a dream...
This creep seduced Mom, broke her heart,
and now he's brushing off
their affair as just a fantasy!
This guy is scum!
He'll pay for this!
I see. That's what's going on.
If I've correctly deduced who that guy is,
it explains why she's meeting a man who
speaks in baby talk and has scars on his arms,
in a place like this.
And when she said, "The shaking
won't stop", with tears in her eyes,
he answered, "Don't worry.
It's all just a dream."
That explains all of that too.
And the reason the wedding ring was in the
waste paper-filled vase in Kisaki-sensei's office is...
Ran-neechan, you're making a mistake!
Auntie isn't cheating with him...
He'll pay...
This guy's gonna pay!
U-Uh-oh!
Y-You've got it all wrong!!
R-Ran!
That guy is...
He's her veterinarian!
He's a vet?
This womanizer? This baby-talking guy?
I don't think he's a womanizer...
But I heard the way he talked
to the girl just now!
Calling her a little cutie-pie!
He wasn't talking to the girl.
He was talking to the
dog she was carrying!
Lots of vets use baby talk when they
talk to the animals they work with.
It must be force of habit.
Right, mister?
Well, yeah...
The marks on his arm
are animal scratches.
He has to hold them still
while he examines them.
And on top of that, he lifted the dog's ear.
Ear?
Yeah.
He was checking the dog's health
from the condition of its ears!
That's how I knew!
Only a vet would do something like that...
Er, a vet on TV said that...
But Mom was crying, wasn't she?
She said she couldn't stop shaking,
and had tears in her eyes...
And he went and said
"It was just a dream!"
Don't be silly.
That wasn't about me.
I was talking about Goro-chan!
G-Goro?
Goro-chan has started twitching
in his sleep, and won't stop.
My last cat never did that,
so I thought he might be ill,
and I was really, really worried.
That's why I asked Tobe-sensei here for advice!
I didn't have time to visit
his clinic because of work,
so I called and asked if he could find
some time to talk about it with me.
And today he returned my call.
He said, "There's a dog café
I visit every morning,
if you'd like to talk to me about it then?"
Was that the phone call
you got when we visited?
Right.
Actually, I wanted to bring Goro-chan
so he could look at him right away,
but this is a dog café, after all...
Then that stuff about a dream...
That's why the cat's twitching.
They do that sometimes.
Sometimes, a cat plays in its sleep
and its nerves twitch in reaction.
It's just like when Uncle Kogoro
throws his arms up in his sleep!
Yeah! I've hit the jackpot!
That happens to cats too?
Sure. They're like humans in a lot of ways.
They can talk in their sleep too.
So there's nothing for you
to worry about, Mouri-san.
I see. I'm glad to hear that.
So glad...
But how could you throw
your wedding ring in the trash?
The trash?
That vase you told me this morning not to use when
I was looking for somewhere to put the flowers!
I found your ring thrown away
in it, along with waste paper!
Oh! I was wondering what happened to it.
So that's where it wound up?
Then...
You didn't put it there?
That vase is Goro-chan's toy box!
He loves to play with waste paper.
He bats it around like
a little soccer player!
Goro-chan's a smart cat. He often hides his toys
in that vase after playing with them.
I caught him playing with my ring once.
He must've snatched it off
my desk and added it to his toys.
He keeps a photo of Tobe-sensei in the vase too.
So you weren't hiding the photo from me...
I see.
You thought I took off my ring
to meet a mysterious man,
and figured I was having an affair.
Y-Y-Yeah...
But, Mom! You seemed annoyed
when I stopped by the office,
but you brightened up after that call.
I had no choice!
I was worried about Goro-chan,
and I didn't want you worrying
unnecessarily if I told you.
Now if this is all cleared up, go home!
Don't you leave for karate
training camp this afternoon?
Oh, yeah...
Well...
She's scary.
I'm sorry!
Conan-kun!
We're going!
Thank you!
Oh, geez...
Well, that's a letdown.
To be honest, I had some hope...
this could be a date.
What's wrong?
There's something about Mom
today that's bugging me.
Something seemed different.
It's just that she was worried about Goro.
No, that's not what I'm talking about.
It wasn't like her...
Oh...
That...low-cut neckline.
You don't usually wear things like that.
When you showed up dressed for a date,
I thought maybe the cat was just an excuse.
I guess I was wrong.
Am I?
Oh, er... This is...
That's it! Her clothes!
Mom never wears sexy clothes like that!
I knew it! She does like that guy!
Uh, wait a—
I'm going back to that café!
Ran-neechan!
W-Why did we go there?
I just told you...
Why'd we stop by Auntie Eri's
office this morning?
Did you forget? I was straightening up...
...and found an old photo album...
...with a picture of...
...Mom and Dad...
...on their first date...
Your first date?
You're dressed the same way?
Yes.
I know I'm too old to pull it off now...
But the truth is, if there was nothing
wrong with Goro-chan,
I was planning to finish work early
and invite that person out to dinner.
I thought this outfit might break the ice
and stir up fond memories...
Why don't you just get back together with him?
It's not that easy!
Anyway, when my daughter
found out about the anniversary,
I got so flustered I snapped at her.
It's best that I cancel my plan.
I can't help being jealous.
Your husband's a lucky man.
Thanks.
But I bet he's long forgotten...
the memory of that day...
Hey! Kogoro-chan!
Forget about him. He's totally wasted.
Strange. Until a minute ago, he kept muttering
to himself and glancing at his cell phone.
And what's with those clothes?
It's like he's dressed for a date!
Look at him, all sprawled out.
Geez. What's he remind me of?
Really...
Where'd that pose come from?
How can I focus on camp now?
We need an ambulance!
That person... Where do I...?
Who was that car targeting?
Tatematsu-kun or Okonogi-san?
But could this case really be that simple?
If so, someone had to have caught
a glimpse of the one who did it!
Next Conan:
Bad Luck Grand Prix
Next Conan's Hint:
Unlucky person
Next week, Conan's on break!
Am I unlucky?
After that, ten weeks without a break!