The light of summer is the radiance of yesterday.
After the tears is a chance of life.
Even unluckiness has a limit.
It's a case with lives at stake!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Man, that's weird...
I was sure that Korean BBQ restaurant was on this street.
It isn't important.
Let's go to another one.
Shut it!
Let's search one more time.
We're looking again?
Let's go back home, Uncle!
It's starting to look like you’ll never find it, and isn't it already 6:30?
It's only 6:30!
I told you that I'd treat you to a luxurious meal while Ran is away.
An accident!
Hey, wait!
You hit someone!
Damned food!
Please, send an ambulance!
Two pedestrians have been struck by a car!
The place is Beika Park, in the back street.
Make it quick!
Tatematsu Shinzaburaou
Company Employee(25)
This person--where have I seen him before?
The most unlucky man in Japan...
The most unlucky man in Japan?
He was on a TV program before, in a video made by his nephew.
It won the program's prize for being the most interesting submission.
My uncle, Tatematsu Shinzaburou san, is
probably the most unlucky man in Japan!
When he's walking, a lot of things fall from the sky.
And when he avoids them, he always twists his ankle.
Ow, that hurts!
When he's waiting in line, they always sell out right before him.
Sorry.
Why am I the only one who's so unlucky?
And now he's finally ended up involved in an accident.
No, that's not it.
That's not it?
That car—it'd been waiting over
there to ambush him for quite a while.
As soon as he showed up, they targeted him and ran him down.
What now?
Then...
This wasn't a mere accident.
It was a case of attempted murder...
The witness remembered the car's license plate.
However, it turned out to be a stolen car.
The car has yet to be found.
And, how are the victims?
Their lives aren't in danger.
That's great.
What are the details?
Yes...
According to the witness, the culprit was wearing
sunglasses and a hat, so his face couldn't be seen.
Tatematsu Shinzaburou-san was heading home
from Beika Station after getting off of work....
Okonogi Kiyotaka (65)
Wealthy Person
When he stopped to exchange greetings Okonogi
Kitoyaka-san, who was taking a liesurely walk.
Then, the car waiting in ambush suddenly...
Was that car aiming for Tatematsu-kun or Okonogi-san?
We don't know, since it sped towards
them exactly when the two met.
Then, the culprit was aiming at both of them?
That's not likely.
Even if the culprit wanted to kill both of them, he'd
likely try to do so separately, one after the other.
That's true.
That means he was really just targeting one of the two.
But if that's the case, why did the culprit
act exactly at such an odd moment?
Doctor?
We should ask the victims if they recall
anyone having a grudge against them.
Thank you very much for your work.
We should be able to speak to Tatematsu-san soon.
But Okonogi-san...
Is Uncle safe?
You are...
He's Okonogi-san nephew, Sakaki Kazuma-san.
Sakaki Kazuma (27)
Okonagi's Nephew
His nephew, huh?
And his fiancée.
Ichikura Tomomi (25)
Kazuma's Fiancée
I'm Ichikura Tomomi.
When I heard about the accident from
Kazuma-san, I was surprised.
Thanks for coming.
His life isn't in any danger, but it may take
some time before he regains consciousness.
Why did it have to happen to Okonogi-san?
Geez...
What kind of person would do this?
Takagi...
Something's bugging me.
Okonogi-san is quite wealthy, but he has no family.
His nephew is his only blood relative.
So that means...
Yeah.
If Okonogi-san were to die, all of his
belongings would become his nephew’s.
Furthermore...
It seems that this guy has a huge debt to Okonogi-san.
This evening at around 6:30, when Okonogi-san was hit by a car...
Where were you, Sakaki-san?
Are you suspecting me!?
No way!
Now, now, please calm down.
I'm sure the culprit was aiming at the other guy who was there!
Okonogi-san ended up involved against his will.
In any case, the police must check the alibis
of all close family members for both victims.
Sakaki-san, Ichikura-san, please cooperate with us.
I was in my house.
Ichikura-san, what is it?
No, it's just that I heard he was going to the
farewell party for a senior in his company.
That was the plan.
But I felt sick, so I left the office at noon.
I then went to sleep in my room.
I live alone, so I have no witness.
And you, Ichikura-san?
Yes.
I was loitering around near the Touto
Department Store in Ginza from about 5:00.
And it was exactly 6:00 when I decided
that it was time to head back home.
Were you with anyone?
No.
I was also alone.
As for someone who can prove it...
Oh, at that time, there was some commotion.
Commotion?
Yes, I sent a message to Kazuma-san about it.
Oh, that's true.
I remember.
Let's see...
Ah, here it is.
A bomb case?
Hey, Okumura, did you know about this case?
No, I'll go confirm it.
What, what, what?
Oh, Mouri-san.
Let me see.
"I just arrived at the Touto Department Store, however...
"A timed bomb has been discovered in
the women restroom on the 5th floor.
"Scary."
Is that so?
Understood.
There's no mistake.
A suspicious object had been found in the restroom at about 6:00.
All of the guests and employees were
evacuated, so there was a lot of commotion.
But it turned out to be a bad prank.
The bombs were completely fake.
Fake?
It was a prank?
Furthermore, the bombs were not found in
the women's restroom on the 5th floor...
But rather in the men's on the 6th floor.
What?
To make a mistake when giving information while
a commotion is going on happens quite often.
And whether it was on the 5th floor or the 6th floor...
Or if the bombs were real or fake,
this has no connection to our case.
Given that it's true the bombs caused some commotion at 6:30...
You being able to communicate that correlating
information at 6:40 proves you were there at the time.
Even if you drove at high speeds, it would take at least an
hour to go from the Touto Department Store to Beika district.
In other words...
The commotion caused by those fake bombs just
so happened to give you an alibi, didn't they?
Maybe this lady is lucky!
Really!
By the way, Sakaki-san...
It seems you owe Okonogi-san quite a large amount.
Excuse me...
You're police officers, right?
Tatematsu-san!
So you're the other one.
That car...
That car tried to kill me in order to silence me!
Silence you?
My payday was the day before yesterday.
I thought about getting some luxury food, as I do once in a while, and
bought some expensive meat and sashimi at the nearby supermarket.
But as soon as I left...
Someone snatched it!
And when I started to run after the thief...
I tripped.
It was really terrible.
You really are an unlucky guy.
I thought I'd seen your face somewhere before.
You're the guy who was on TV, and is said
to be the most unlucky guy in Japan.
I guess everybody watched that...
But that isn't the end of the story yet.
That night, I got a call from the snatcher.
How dare you inform the police.
Now that you've seen my face, I cannot allow you to live.
I'll seal your mouth for all of eternity.
A murder declaration?
And today, just as he said...
But, to kill someone just to silence them over snatching
some groceries is going a bit overboard, isn't it?
Indeed.
But...
But it was the same guy!
The same guy?
That settles it.
The theft and attempted murder to silence him are linked.
Come on, let's go check on the old man's condition.
But is this case really that simple?
Say, Tatematsu-san...
Are you an acquaintance of that old man, Okonogi-san?
I didn't know his name, but...
We'd met at that place every day.
I always come back on the same train, and he
also goes for leisurely walks at the same time.
Please tell us further details regarding the snatching
incident that happened the day before yesterday.
And the call you received the same evening, too.
Yes.
Hey, we're leaving.
We know who the culprit is, so the rest is just police work.
Something...
Something just isn't right.
The Next Morning
What concerns me the most is the
timing of when the car sped forward.
If it was an attempt on Tatematsu-san's life, he
would've been targeted when he was alone.
Why did it have to be then?
Hey, brat.
Uncle!
You're already here this early in the morning?
A brat shouldn't stick his nose into things uncessarily, you know?
I'll take a look at the hospital.
Understand?
I'll be back soon.
Did something happen?
Yeah, that "most unlucky guy in Japan" is quite depressed.
He's thinking, "Okonogi-san has nothing to do
with it, and only got involved because of me."
I figured I'd go cheer him up.
Even Uncle has some good ideas!
Idiot.
I have a lotta good ideas.
Got involved?
Maybe, on the contrary...
If the culprit resorted to snatching in order to hide something else...
Then it all makes sense.
And if that's the case, the person who
saw the culprit has to be there!
Someone following Tatematsu-san?
Yeah, I think it happened here a few days ago, but...
Let me see.
There was?
It may have something to do with Tatematsu-san.
A strange guy came.
Was that guy short and a little bit overweight?
No, it was some beautiful woman.
Some woman?
At first, I thought it was his girlfriend, but
Tatematsu-san isn't that kind of guy.
Woman?
That's right.
The discovery of the suspicious package was not unexpected.
At 6:30, an anonymous call was made
to the Touto Department Store.
They said they set up time bombs in the restrooms.
And the women's restroom on the 5th floor?
You know a lot!
We haven't made it public because it's a secret investigation.
But, it seems a boy who came to shop moved
them to the men's restroom on the 6th floor.
All the while being unaware they were fake bombs.
That's how it happened?
Everything fits with my deduction.
Sakaki-san!
You're that boy from yesterday.
How's Okonogi-san?
We don't know when he will regain consciousness,
so I figured I'd get some lunch in the meantime.
So, only Okonogi-san and Ichikura-san
are in the hospital room now?
What is it?
We have to hurry!
What is it, boy?
Wait!
I completely solved the mystery?
Yeah, that's why we hurried over here.
That's what I said?
That's why we rushed here.
I don’t remember that, but maybe I'm schizophrenic...
I've brought him here.
It's exactly as you said, Uncle.
I told you something too?
C'mon, hurry up!
Hey!
What are you doing!?
What...
What were you about to do, Tomomi?
What's the meaning of this, Mouri-san!?
Mouri-san!
Me?
Even if you keep asking, I can't really...
May...be.. my schizo... phre... ny...
Did it come?
Ichikura-san...
Even though you rushed to hide that
wet towel, your act has come to an end.
Yesterday, you failed to kill him, even though
you tired to disguise it as a car accident.
But Ichikura-san has an alibi for the incident yesterday.
The person who drove into us yesterday
was the culprit who stole my groceries.
All of that was part of Ichikura-san's plan.
First of all, the culprit was targeting Okonogi-san in this incident.
What?
Tatematsu-san, you were used by the culprit.
I was used?
Ichikura-san intended to kill Okonogi-san.
But with a simple murder, she knew
she could fall under suspicion.
She had to put great effort into hiding it.
Therefore, she observed Okonogi-san's everyday life.
Then, she noticed that he was meeting
Tatematsu-san during his leisurely walk each day.
Ichikura san remembered having seen
Tatematsu-san's face somewhere before.
It's because she had seen him on TV
as the most unlucky guy in Japan.
That's when Ichikura-san considered
using Tatematsu-san in her plan.
So, she followed him.
Even though she remembered his face from
TV, she couldn't remember his name.
So to get his name...
Conan confirmed this with a resident of the same building.
She remembered a suspicious woman following
Tatematsu-san on his way back from work.
You then put your plan to action.
First, you stole something from Tatematsu-san.
Huh? You?
Later that night, having discovered his name and address, you looked
up his phone number, called him, and threatened to silence him.
You chose yesterday because you knew your fiancé,
Sakaki Kazuma-san, was attending a farewell party.
Therefore, he wouldn't be suspected.
Then, you put fake time bombs in the women's restroom
on the 5th floor of the Touto Department Store.
After that, you quickly rushed to Beika District in order
to execute your murder plan on Tatematsu-san.
At that time, you tried to kill Okonogi-san while trying to make
Tatematsu-san's death seem like nothing more than collateral damage.
Finally, you called the Touto Department Store.
I've set time bombs up in the women's restroomon the 5th floor.
Better hurry, before they explode.
With the bombs revealed, you gauged the time for when
there'd be a large commotion and typed out the message.
Isn't that right, Ichikura-san?
But the truth of this fabricated alibi finally came to light.
There was a contradiction between the place where the
bombs actually were and what your message said.
This is conclusive proof of your evil deed.
Tomomi?
I was an idiot.
Why was the position of the bombs changed?
Tomomi...
You...
It seems that a child moved them while shopping.
This world just isn't fair.
The bombs changed position...
The old man who I thought would finally die didn't die...
And a famous detective appeared.
I might be as unlucky as you.
Why did you try to kill Uncle?
Because...
I wanted the money.
When I thought about marrying you, I knew that
if the old man died, I'd get the inheritance.
But isn't he quite healthy for an old man?
I couldn't wait for him to die naturally.
Money?
Of all things, that was your goal from the beginning?
Isn't that obvious?
Without that, do you think you'd be anybody?
I really...
Was an idiot.
Tomomi-san...
Uncle!
Kazuma...
I'll go call for a doctor.
What's troubling you, Tomomi-san?
I'm just glad that you woke up.
What a horrible woman.
I got the impression that she can still get a fresh start.
I know it's a little bit strange coming
from an unlucky guy like me.
You're right.
That's the only thing we can believe.
Beer in the morning is good!
Drinking it with coffee might be the perfect mix!
And that's the reason why...
He's really an unlucky guy!
You shouldn't laugh at others, you know.