The light of summer is the radiance of yesterday.
In the aftermath of the tears lies a soccer ball.
When Genta kicks the ball repeatedly,
the goal is this honorable case!
Recognizing that single truth,
child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Hide missed!
Here at the Sunday Cup's semifinals...
The Tokyo Spirits lose on the penalty kick and are eliminated!
I've been craving cake all day...
Hey, hey...
What's this?
I'm going to treat you all to some cheesecake.
So what's with all this sighing?
Luck is part of the game.
Sometimes you lose.
But...
I can't believe Hide missed a penalty kick.
Maybe he wasn't feeling well?
How's that?
Hide played at his best, with one goal and two assists in the game.
In other words, he's only human.
Maybe the pressure got to him.
Hide's so pathetic.
That's not the case.
The soccer superstar known as the Treasure of Italy once said...
"The only one who can miss a penalty kick...
is the one who has enough courage to take the penalty kick."
That's gotta be true!
People always assume penalty kicks will go in!
Hide's not pathetic after all!
But...
Hide and Naoki were both there!
The Tokyo Spirits had won six in a row!
They were so strong!
Why'd the have to lose!?
Kojima Kanji (28)
Hey!
The hell are you trying to do my car!?
Ah, I'm sorry.
This child's favorite team lost, so he's a bit irritated.
Be careful.
Huh? Where did the ball go?
Like I'd know!
Genta, remember.
"The strong one doesn't win..."
"The one who wins is strong."
I cherish them greatly...
Ludger Heinen (42)
Those are the best words.
Who're you, old man?
Oh, I'm just...
A person whose beloved car got dirty and scratched
due to some kid who kicked a ball carelessly.
An unlucky foreigner, in other words.
Oh, I'm so sorry about that...
Here.
No problem.
Don't worry about it.
Mister, you're very skilled in Japanese for a foreigner.
Ah, my wife is Japanese.
When I love someone, I happen to fall
in love with their language as well.
Although, I'm at strike one.
Because of that, I can now speak three languages.
"Strike One"? This guy's really become Japanized.
That's all great, but if we don't head to the store now,
the cheesecake is going to be entirely sold out.
Oh, that's right!
Huh, cake?
Oh! You're talking about that store on
the second floor called "Ikenaka."
My wife really likes their cheesecake.
Actually, I came here to buy some as well.
Second floor?
That shop is on the third floor.
Oh, that's right, it's the third floor!
Hello?
You always tell this...
Oh, no. My ex-wife called from home to talk about
our son's schooling, but the connection was bad.
For important matters such as that,
wouldn't it be better to talk in person?
No, that can't be done easily...
Because his ex-wife is in England.
H-How did you know that?
"The strong one doesn't win, the one who wins is strong."
Those words from earlier were those of "The Emperor"'
of the German soccer world, Franz Beckenbauer.
You don't only like them, but cherish them.
That means you're German, right?
Y-Yeah...
The three languages you speak must be German,
Japanese, and the one you just showed us, English.
If your current wife is Japanese, that means your
previous wife must be someone who speaks English.
But couldn't someone who speaks English be an American?
I see.
He said "second floor" before, right?
In America it would be called the third floor,
but in England, they call it the second floor.
Why's that? "Second" is two, right?
In England, the first floor is known as the "ground floor".
After that, they use "First", "Second","Third", and so on.
That's how I knew his ex-wife was English.
Is this kid really a kid?
Well, yeah...
Well then, would you like us to get your cake for you?
Oh, that would be very helpful.
I guess I'll have to call my ex-wife back, so I'll be busy for awhile.
Could you try to get me a whole cheesecake?
Sure.
We plan to eat ours in the shop though, so we may be awhile.
Then let's hurry!
I'm not going.
You're not gonna eat!?
It's because the Tokyo Spirits lost.
I can't sit around and eat cake.
Genta-kun...
You guys can go by yourselves.
I'm not in the mood.
That's fine.
Food's never as good...
When consumed with a grumpy person.
Haibara-san...
Well then, just sit in the car and wait patiently.
O... K...
What's wrong?
Why aren't you eating?
It's great.
But...
Whenever I think about Genta-kun, I just...
How foolish.
Don't worry about him, he'll be fine.
The customer who ordered take out...
Ah, right here.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
This big one is what that guy from earlier wanted...
And this small one is, of course, for Genta-kun.
It is good, right?
I...
I have to be the one to do it.
I have to become much better than both Hide and Naoki...
And turn the Tokyo Spirits into...
An unbeatable team!
After Genta-kun eats this cake,
I'm sure he'll be in a better mood!
Of course!
S-Sorry... I-I'm in a bit of a hurry.
That was dangerous.
Is the cake OK?
A license...
Inagaki Hiromasa (35)
That guy from just then...
Hey, hurry up, will ya?
Ow, ow, ow...
That's right... I fell and hit my head.
When will it be fixed?
I'm sorry. This machine hasn't been working correctly lately.
Genda Tatsuzou (44)
Then how about I just break through this gate, dude?
Please be patient.
That hurts...
Hey, where's the ball?
Where did I...
Ah, over there!
Here it is...
Legs?
They'll catch a cold sleeping in a place like this...
Genta!
Hey, where are you, Genta!?
What happened, Genta-kun!?
Genta-kun!
Kojima-kun!
I found him!
Over here!
D-Dead!
What is it, Genta!?
The foreigner from before is dead!
What?
No, he's still breathing, but barely.
Professor, call an ambulance and the police!
Got it!
Hey, what happened?
Who did this to you?
Wait.
He was hit in the left side of his forehead,
possibly resulting in a speech impediment.
It's impossible for him to speak.
Criminal...
Me!?
It's me?!
No way!
Please wait.
He's probably pointing at something that's behind Genta.
It's got to be a clue that singles out the criminal!
So, if we move Genta-kun,
we should be able to find out what it is.
Huh?
I-It's me after all!
E...
El...
It can't be!
Mister, please don't die!
It's fine.
It seems he only fainted.
However, things still don't look good.
Regardless, the question is...
Why did he point at Kojima-kun?
Say, Genta...
Before you found him here, did you see the criminal?
That would explain why he pointed at you.
I-I didn't see anything!
But I did hear a loud sound that surprised me.
It made me miss the ball, fall backwards, and hit my head.
I guess I was out the entire time.
You were kicking the soccer ball in this parking lot?
I-I was...
That was dangerous!
And so, that's why he said you were the criminal.
When I went to look for the ball, I did find it by this foreigner...
Then, could it be that the ball is what hit him in the head!?
That means Genta is the criminal!
Fool...
A ball kicked by a kid wouldn't cause this type of injury.
B-But, when Conan-kun kicks them,
doesn't it always knock out the criminal?
Edogawa-kun is an exception.
He's cheating by relying on the power of machines.
Cheating, huh?
Well, regardless, we know Genta holds the key to finding the criminal.
We'll find the criminal soon and get him.
Don't worry, Genta.
I'm the criminal.
He didn't hear me...
The victim is Ludger Heinen, a German.
He's an employee of a German sports equipment
manufacturer dispatched here to Japan.
The weapon was this steel pipe that was lying nearby.
Judging from his wounds, he was struck twice.
Once from behind and again from the front.
And how's he doing?
He's been taken to a hospital, but he's still unconscious.
Since he was struck from the front as well.
I'm hoping he saw the criminal's face.
This car is Ludger-san's so he was probably meeting someone here.
He was most likely hit when he got
out of his car to talk to that person.
Then, the motive was abhorrence?
Yeah, most likely.
Since there was 10,000¥ in Ludger-san's wallet,
so I doubt the criminal was after money.
Well then, let's head to the Japanese company
he was visiting to look for suspects.
Yes, sir!
It... was me...
I'm...
Genta-kun?
What are you doing here?
I was the one who did this to the foreigner!
Oh, no, Genta was just the first to find him!
The foreigner was lying over there, covered in blood.
Right, right!
You guys again?
We were here to eat cheesecake,
which is how we met Ludger-san.
Oh, Agasa-san.
He also asked us to buy this cake for him...
But when we got back, Genta-kun, who had stayed here in
the garaged alone had found Ludger-san covered in blood.
Then, Genta-kun...
Did you see any suspicious people?
Oh... No, see...
He didn't see any suspicious people,
but the motive probably was money.
But, Officer Takagi just said that the
money in his wallet wasn't stolen...
Then, would you look inside Ludger-san's car?
There's a lot of change, right?
It's true, scattered all over the seats.
And how does that suggest the motive was money?
Before you came, Inspector, I looked in the car, but...
I couldn't find it...
His parking ticket for this lot.
What?
When you get a parking ticket, where do you put it, Inspector?
Let's see...
My car's glovebox?
My pants pocket?
Maybe in my wallet?
I know!
The coin purse!
The criminal took the coin purse holding the parking ticket and ran!
I see.
Since the coin purse was sitting in the
passenger's seat and wasn't closed...
Some of the change fell out when it was stolen.
And he didn't think to check in his pocket for a wallet full of money?
He was probably in such a hurry that he didn't have time
to look, instead taking the coin purse and fleeing.
In a hurry?
Yep, most likely.
Just when the criminal hit Ludger-san,
I think Genta's soccer ball came by.
The culprit thought someone would come looking for the ball.
But, since the sound of Ludger-san getting hit surprised Genta,
Genta ended up slipping and got knocked out for a bit.
But if this is a robbery case, that changes everything.
Yeah, now we'll have to get their testimonies and investigate further.
Nope.
There are only three that are suspicious.
While we were buying cake, Ludger-san was
on the phone with his ex-wife, but...
The connection was bad here, so he had to keep trying.
According to the call history, the last call
was made four minutes before we returned.
In other words, the case had to happen in those four minutes, right?
Y-Yeah...
So, during that time, it could have been the guy stuck at the gate...
The guy still in his car...
Or the guy that ran into us in front of the elevator on our way back.
S-Sorry... I-I'm in a bit of a hurry.
The one who dropped their license...
This guy.
It's just those three.
I see, those three...
All right, Takagi-kun!
Get the two men in this parking lot and
find the man who dropped this license.
Bring them all here!
Yes, sir!
Got it.
It'll be easy with only three of them, as the one with the coin purse
Once he found out there was only
change inside, he probably tossed it.
But it's OK.
Ludger-san gave us all a hint.
A hint?
Before he fainted, Ludger-san pointed at Genta...
And said: "Criminal".
Y-You?
Yeah...
I-It was me.
And then he latched onto my shoulder and muttered, "El."
E—
El...
In other words, the criminal has some connection with both Genta...
And whatever it is that "El" refers to.