The light of summer is the radiance of yesterday.
In the aftermath of the tears lies a cheesecake.
It's time to catch the killer,
but we'll need Japanese, English, and German!
Recognizing that single truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Our usual group went to see the Tokyo Spirits soccer game.
Unfortunately, the Spirits lost.
We then parked to get our food.
And then, when we returned, a German man we
had met earlier named Ludger had been attacked.
Ludger Heinen (42)
To our surprise, Ludger-san said "criminal" and...
Pointed at Genta.
Me?
It's me!?
But it's OK.
Ludger-san gave us all a hint.
A hint?
Before he fainted, Ludger-san pointed at Genta...
And said: "Criminal".
Y-You?
Yeah...
I-It was me...
And then he latched onto my shoulder and muttered, "El."
E-
El...
In other words, the criminal has some connection with both Genta...
And whatever it is that "El" refers to.
You wanna know why I'm here?
Why do I have to tell you police officers that?
Did something happen?
Inspector, here he is.
Excuse me, I don't have time for this...
Inagaki Hiramasa (35)
I'm sorry, bot someone was attacked here and you
three are the only ones that were in the area.
Genda Tatsuzou (44)
We ask you cooperate.
Kojima Kanji (28)
What? Where's the proof? You can't hold us here.
Even if you refuse now, we'll come to your home later.
Whatever.
I get it.
I'll tell you then.
I was listening to the horse race in the car.
The off-track waging office is in here, so if I won,
I planned to go collect and then go shopping.
And, your name?
It's Kojima Kanji.
K-Kojima!?
You're the criminal!
Because you have the same last name as Genta-kun!
Genta-kun?
The number on your shirt is the evidence!
Hide from the Tokyo Spirits wears the number 11!
Genta-kun is wearing a Tokyo Spirits shirt right now!
Stupid, the Spirits also have the quick Naoki on their team.
That's true, but still...
Besides, we always called him "Genta" in front
of Ludger-san and never used "Kojima", right?
Right, since he wasn't aware his family name is
"Kojima," that can't be why he pointed to him.
I guess you're right...
You're next. Why were you are?
I came to buy a bag for my girl, but they don't sell it here.
I was trying to hurry and get to the next store,
but some guy was there fixing the gate.
Really, what a hassle.
What's your name?
It's Genda.
G-Genta!?
That's the criminal!
G-Genda!
Genda Tatsuzou!
I don't know what you're implying, but I'm not "Genta".
Ludger-san probably misheard you as well!
And you're fat, just like Genta-kun!
That's foolish, there are plenty of fat people.
The Professor and Inspector Megure, for example.
It'd be different if Ludger-san knew these
three were the only suspects, but...
I doubt think he'd leave such an oblivious hint.
Besides, after Ludger-san pointed to Genta
and said, "Criminal", he also said "El".
If he knew his name, wouldn't he have just said "Genda"?
I guess you're right...
And finally you. Why're you here?
I just came to see the press event for the idol
Sakaguchi Ai on the sixth floor of this building.
My name is Inagaki Hiromasa...
I'm just a fan.
Hold on a second.
On his driver's license, the kanji he uses for
"Hiromasa" can also be used for "Taishou", right?
I guess it is.
INAGAKI
So, if you took out the "Ina" kanji from your name...
GAKIDAISHO
"Neighborhood Kids Leader"!
That's Genta-kun!
Weren't you listening?
I just said Ludger-san doesn't know the criminal's name.
But it's too convenient to be a coincidence!
A-And also, look at his hat!
It has a big "L" on it!
This is...
Official Sakaguchi Ai merchandise...
I don't think it's that "L" either.
If he were referring to that hat, he would
have said "love" instead of "El-".
But, with him being German, maybe he couldn't read it..
Did you forget?
His previous wife was British, meaning he can speak English.
He would have definitely read L-O-V-E as "love".
KARAI
SPICEY
TSURAI
TRING
It isn't like Japanese where "karai" can be "tsurai" and
"osatsu" can be "ofuda". (Spicy -> Tiring, Bill -> Label)
OSATSU
BILL
OFUDA
LABEL
I see...
That's how it is.
Actually, there's a word in both German and English
that's spelled the same, but has different meanings.
And? That relates to his message?
Yeah.
His message was about another mischiveous boy.
Hey, hey, Officer...
When can we get outta here?
I was only here by chance, why should I have to stay here?
Not to mention, the press event will be over soon...
Ah, but, we need to get your stories first.
I already told you!
I have nothing to do with this case!
I was in my car listening to the horse race.
As I said earlier, I came here to get that bag.
Unfortunately, they don't even sell the damn bag here.
I need to hurry off to the event and get a god seat.
I didn't see anybody get attacked.
I see.
You three are saying that all three of you just happened to be
here at the time, and yet none of you saw anything suspicious?
Yeah, that's what we're saying.
I guess that means we're free to leave, Officer?
Besides, what about that fat kid?
That guy pointed to him and said "criminal", didn't he?
Wouldn't that mean this boy did it?
That's right.
He was down here kicking that ball, right?
Then, isn't it more likely he accidentally kicked the ball and hit him?
No way!
Genta isn't the criminal!
Ayumi...
Officer, are we done here?
Oh, well...
Genta-kun couldn't be the criminal.
The reason Ludger-san pointed at Genta...
Was to say that Genta had something in
common with the one who attacked him.
Because just like Genta-kun, the culprit was...
A mischevious boy.
A mischevious boy?
Are you serious?
Um, Agasa-san...
This is a serious assault, not some mischief...
What I refer to is the very image.
I see! That's it!
The criminal is...
Inagaki Hiromasa-san!
It's you, isn't it?
Since you came for an idol's press event, you must have a camera!
Thus, you're a camera kid!
A mischevious boy!
A camera kid and a mischevious boy are completely different.
But, they could be the same...
But then, but then...
Doesn't that make this guy the criminal?
What?
I bet he pulled a lot of pranks as a child!
The hell is going on here?
How does that make me the criminal?
Even so, Ayumi-chan, how would Ludger-san
know how his childhood went?
That leaves us with this Genda guy...
But he looks more like a bad guy than someone into mischief...
He actually does seem bad.
Please hold on a moment. That's not what I'm trying to say.
Um, could you please explain now?
It isn't Japanese, it's English...
Elf.
Elf?
The small fairies that appear in fantasy tales.
Fairies?
Haibara...
The title "elf" can applied to a small kid...
But there's also another application which means a "mischevious boy".
I see!
That's why he said "El" after pointing to Genta-kun.
He was trying to say "elf "!
But how does that relate to Genta-kun?
While it's true that Genta-kun looks like the most mischevious,
a small fairy or elf should've been Ayumi-chan...
It's from when Genta-kun kicked a soccer
ball in here and hit Ludger-san's car.
After Genta did it, he called him...
A naughty boy.
Ludger-san was trying to say that the criminal was an elf like Genta.
A criminal elf?
I see. The hint was to say the criminal was mischevious, like an elf.
I can see him saying that about Genta-kun...
But with them?
I can't imagine any of these three as a small, prank loving fairy.
Can you explain it, Agasa-san?
I failed to mention earlier that Ludger-san is German
and can speak German, English, and Japanese.
So, when they asked who did it, the numbers
in his native language came to mind.
Numbers?
Takagi-kun?
Um, let's see here...
Eiens, zwei, drei...
Right, in German, we have...
One is "eiens"...
Two is "zwei"...
Three is "drei"...
Four is "vier"...
Five is "funf"...
Six is "sechs"...
Seven is "sieben"...
Eight is "acht"...
Nine is "neun"...
Ten is "zehn"...
And eleven is...
"Elf."
What?
Kojima Kanji-san
It's the number on your back.
I see, so Ludger-san pointed at Kojima-kun and tried to say
"eleven" and "elf", to give a German and English hint.
With his knowledge of a Germany and
England, he went to Conan-kun...
Right, right, he hoped the Professor
would be able to figure out its meaning.
But if he knew Japanese, wouldn't it be easier
to have just said "eleven" in Japanese?
He probably did that on purpose, just in case the
criminal were still nearby and saw us talking to him.
He was afraid we would get attacked if we knew anything.
I see.
Well then, Kojima-san, would you please come with us?
You've gotta be joking, Officer.
I don't know what this elf thing is...
But why am I automatically the criminal for wearing the #11?
Besides, that German guy didn't even
get to completely say "elf", did he?
Well, Old man?
Don't tell me this is all of your reasoning.
But his reasoning seems perfect...
You seemed confident back there, Old man.
Well, see...
I'm Japanese, not some stupid elf!
Please relax.
If you think he's right, show me some proof.
You know, some proof that shows I'm the criminal.
Oh, what's this?
None of you saw me hit that foreigner and run away, huh?
It seems like no one here can prove I did it...
Officer.
Well, I guess we're done here.
Have a nice day.
Wait, Kojima-san!
I saw it!
I saw this man named Kojima hit Ludger-san and run away!
I saw him do it!
What?
Is that true, Conan-kun?
After I found Ludger-san covered in
blood, I saw this man running away!
Hey, brat!
You guys seen him too, right!?
Conan-kun...?
You can't let him just say that!
Can you testify to that?
Hey, don't let him lie to you!
Don't you find this a bit strange!?
If he saw me then, wouldn't he have said so from the start?
He's just playing along with what that old bastard said!
He just made it up!
Regardless, we've known Conan-kun for awhile now.
He's honest enough.
Are you insane!?
How can you not see he's making this up!?
I'm not lying!
I even saw the number on your back!
Why you... If you don't shut up...
I really did!
I saw him! I saw him! I saw him!
Because I was the first one to find Ludger-san!
Conan-kun?
I hope you got that, Officer.
I think you messed up, kid.
Remember? The first to find him was the fat one!
It wasn't you!
How'd you know...
That Genta was the first to find him?
Takagi-kun, did we tell them that?
Oh, no, we didn't...
No...
No, it's not like that...
Oh, that's right! I saw this kid by himself earlier.
He was playing soccer by himself, earlier!
Really now?
What?
I thought you were listening to horse racing
in your car and didn't hear Genta scream?
If you didn't hear him scream...
How did you know he was first to find him?
I told you, I saw him!
I saw him kicking the ball by himself, so assumed...
Even if I couldn't hear anything, I could've just looked out the window.
Right, Officer?
Even though that's true...
How could you know it was Genta-kun just by that?
He was just kicking the ball, right?
Of course I'd know, because at that time...
At that time?
Ah, see...
It's this, right?
After you hit Ludger-san with the steel pipe...
You saw this soccer ball come by and you knew, right?
You knew Genta, who was kicking the
ball around, would come looking for it.
Ah, no...
I really was listening to the horse race!
Then, why don't you tell us...
The name of the horse that won the main race today?
If you were listening to the horse races, you'd have to know...
Because we came back during the main race.
Ah, see...
Of course, I don't expect you to know.
Because after Genta-kun's ball came by...
You tried to hurry out of the parking lot...
Only to realize that the broken gate was being
repaired and Genda-san was in front of you.
There's no way you could get out.
Next, you hid in your car to avoid the police and pretended
to have been listening to the horse race the entire time.
Your heart was pounding and your mind was missing.
It...
It can't be.
It wasn't me!
Wait!
You bastard, you're not getting away with this.
Don't do it, Genda-san!
Genda-san!
Genda-san...
Don't do... it...
Well, at least now you'll know some of the pain you've caused.
Oh...
So the criminal did it just for the money?
Yeah, that's what Officer Takagi said when he called the
Professor earlier to thank him for solving the case.
He was apparently on the run from loan sharks and got desperate.
It seems Japan's crimes are being more and more Americanized.
But I'm so glad Genta-kun wasn't the criminal!
I had lost all reason to live...
That was pretty cruel of that foreigner...
Pointing at a kid and saying "criminal".
It really was, wasn't it?
Welcome!
Genta could have really become a suspect.
I believed in them...
These little detectives.
Ludger-san!
Is everything OK with your head injury?
Yeah, mostly.
Thank goodness!
Is this that German?
It looks like it.
I'm sorry, boy.
Y-Yeah...
Take this as a gift, please.
This is cheesecake from that store!
How nice!
I didn't get any the other day!
This is my chance!
I hope you enjoy it.
This is very thoughtful of you, Ludger-san!
Thanks!
Hey, hey! Why did such a weak horse have to win!?
This race should've been in the bag!
Uncle...
It's not the strong one that wins...
The one that wins is strong!