The light of summer is the radiance of yesterday.
In the aftermath of the tears lies a live broadcast.
This is the best animation so far.
Watch carefully and don't go away!
Perceiving the one and only truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Hello there!
We're back!
Every Monday at 7 30 P.M...
It's the find the girl Run Away special!
Tonight, we'll be broadcasting live from Nengjo Street.
The Run Away areas for the girls tonight are...
Nengjo Street...
Hamahacho Street...
And...
Kabutobi Street!
If the participants are able to find all of the
girls within thirty minutes, they can win...
¥1,000,000!
Now, get ready...
3...
2...
1...
Go!
It's begun!
It'll be as exciting as last time!
Run Away!
There aren't many customers.
I wonder if they're making any money here.
That's just what they need...
More customers.
Look at that big hourglass.
They wanted to make this an appointment place.
A thirty-minute hourglass is enormous, though.
How stupid of me, I should've made a reservation.
It's completely full.
Well, let's eat somewhere else then.
Um, how can I say it...
I made a reservation for 8:00 P.M.
That mean we still have thirty minutes.
The food at that restaurant is good.
But it doesn't look like a cheap restaurant...
Anyway, let's meet here just before 8:00, all right?
Until then, you can roam around freely.
Until then!
Dad!
Again...
What should we do, Conan-kun?
There's a mystery bookstore on the second floor here.
I'll be looking at clothes, then.
I'll see you before 8:00, all right?
Got it.
Let's see...
Sorry, these stairs are closed today.
Use the stairs over there, boy.
Sugar nuts for sale.
Very delicious.
Giving you more tonight.
That's right!
A man was stabbed on the second floor of the Beika shopping mall!
P-Please hurry!
He's still breathing...
He was stabbed from behind, which caused him to fall forward...
And hit his face on the ground.
He was only stabbed a moment ago...
Which means it's highly likely that the culprit is still in the building...
Haibara?
You must love these cases...
Or maybe the cases are calling you.
Were you here as well?
I was in that bookstore over there...
And then I heard a scream.
Say, did you see anyone suspicious?
Since the wallet is still there...
It doesn't seem to be robbery.
What are you all doing here?
You can't stay here
Go over there.
You all, too.
The police are on their way.
Stay back, please.
Up here!
End of the second floor!
Dad!
Who is this "Dad"?
Jeez...
Yes!
Miou-chan has been found.
There are still four girls left.
Good luck.
We're the police.
Please, stay back.
Make room.
Inspector Megure got here quickly...
Yeah, seems so.
The victim is Nishiyama Yukio-san.
The ambulance is on its way now.
I see.
The first eye witness is Yamaguchi Shiori-san.
She claims to be employed at that store over there.
This is Koide-san.
He's the manager of that cosmetics store.
There was a call to headquarters at 19:30.
Were you the one who called?
Y-Yeah...
But that time...
19:30?
I see.
So, did you notice anything?
Anything at all.
Now that you mention it, Nishiyama and
Yamamuchi san were always fighting.
Nishiyama?
Do you know the victim?
He's known in this shopping mall.
He's always messing with clothes and toys, but never puts them back.
He breaks a lot in here as well.
He's always messing with everyone.
At any rate, he's very unliked.
But...
Shiori—I mean, Yamaguchi-san—wasn't
always on good terms with Nishiyama.
How rude that he used her first name...
That's how it goes here.
Just yell it already!
Say I stabbed Nishiyama.
I wasn't saying that...
What do you mean by that?
He's hated me ever since I broke up with him.
Now he wants to make me a suspect for some reason.
Don't joke around.
Everyone knew that Nishiyama had an eye on you.
That's why he never messed around in your store.
Even two days ago, you two were arguing about something!
Everyone could hear you two!
Even I could.
Don't talk like that about me.
I know something about you too.
You were paying back money to Nishiyama.
What now?
N-No, it's not like that.
You were always fighting with him.
That means you have a motive, right?
You don't have to talk like that!
Why not?
Excuse me, may I come through?
The famous detective Mouri Kogorou has arrived.
You have nothing to worry about now.
Conan-kun?
Oh, Ran-neechan...
Mouri-kun...
No touching.
Sorry about that!
What's with that bag?
His pachinko prizes.
That's why there's no use bringing him anywhere...
Uncle...
And, what were you two doing at that time?
Jeez, Dad!
Another girls has been found!
Only three girls remain!
But...
The time-limit is approaching fast!
Girls, run!
I heard the scream on the second floor...
And immediately ran to the scene.
Not a lot of time has passed since the criminal stabbed Nishiyama-san...
The other stairs were closed...
That means the criminal...
Would have to use these stairs.
Who wants sugar nuts?
Mister!
Oh, boy.
I have enough for you too.
Sorry, I'm not a customer.
I figured...
You were here the entire time, right?
Yeah.
I couldn't get upstairs.
Was someone really stabbed?
Did anyone come down the stairs before the scream?
No one.
And after that?
You were the first.
There were a few who went upstairs, though.
Right.
All right, everyone, please clear the crime scene.
We need to seal the scene.
Don't!
Get everyone back upstairs.
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
After the scream, no one went down the stairs.
That means it's likely the criminal is still upstairs, right?
I see.
That's true.
Hey!
Wait!
That's right!
The criminal must still be inside.
And now, I shall get him!
Hey, hey, hey...
Let go of me, you idiot!
Why did you run?
Why do I have to stay here?
Because this is an assault case.
You have to stay with us.
Don't let anyone in or out of this building, no matter the circumstance.
This is...
Why can't I come in?
There's been an assault case inside.
You can't come in until we're done.
Shut up!
Move!
Please calm down!
Hey, pal...
My boss can get you fired easily.
His boss must be powerful...
Regardless, we need to get in this building immediately.
No.
No one enters.
Hasegu here.
I'm in front of the building, but...
The police won't let me in.
Call me when you're done.
I'll be waiting outside.
The third Run Away girl has been caught!
Now we're down to two girls!
Go, go! Run Away!
I guess we can't eat dinner now, huh?
Seems that way.
This is Koide-san's cosmetics shop, huh?
I see!
You again!
You stole something from my store again, didn't you?
That's just nonsense.
When did I steal something?
You're always stealing.
I know it.
Then, why don't you check my bag?
Here.
Manager, could you come here?
Yes!
What now?
Stealing is a crime...
Miss.
That was the last time.
One more girl until ¥1,000,000!
Can they make it!?
What was that, all of a sudden?
Miss...
You saw the culprit, right?
The display glass with lipstick behind it is in the front of the hall.
See, from there...
You were looking right at the crime scene
while you were stealing lipstick.
Why do you say that?
It's because you were acting so strange after the crime.
You usually run away immediately after stealing, don't you?
But this time, you didn't.
It's because...
You were scared.
If you left the building and met the
criminal outside, what would you do?
That's what you were thinking, right?
But later, you thought you could escape through the crowd.
Am I wrong?
That's amazing.
You're right.
How'd you know?
I'm...
A detective.
That's pretty cool.
So, what was the criminal like?
Actually...
It happened so fast that I couldn't see what he looked like.
That man looked at me...
I was scared, so I closed my eyes.
Was the criminal male and left-handed?
Yes, he had the knife in his left hand...
Did you notice anything else?
Oh yeah, he was wearing a coat.
A coat?
It was black and very thick.
By the way, Miss...
About this...
I feel so good now!
I won't steal anymore.
Don't worry, Detective-kun.
Haibara, what is it?
I searched the second floor.
Did you find anything?
I searched for the weapon and anyone suspicious, but...
There's nothing else on this floor...
And all that's above are offices and clinics.
I'd say the police have already searched up there.
Probably.
Did you find a black coat?
Coat?
The culprit wore a black coat.
I didn't see one.
I didn't get to look in the male's restroom, though.
The police would have searched there too.
That's true.
It doesn't seem like there are any other places for him to hide.
Why would he stab him?
That's the whole point.
The woman and manager that were
arguing earlier can't be responsible...
It doesn't seem like a revenge.
The wallet was there, so it can't be a robbery either.
If the culprit and victim had been fighting,
someone would have overheard them.
It seems no one did.
That means...
Maybe the culprit's bigger goal wasn't to attack him...
As in, if it wasn't revenge, what was it?
There were two people who called the police.
Two?
First we have the manager, Koide-san...
And then we have the one who called the police before him...
Probably the man in the black coat.
There was a call to headquarters at 19:30.
Were you the one who called?
Right...
Someone called the police before stabbing Nishiyama-san.
He had a reason for getting the police here as soon as possible, right?
But why?
That's how it was!
What is it?
Those two.
They look creepy.
The culprit didn't want those two to get in the building.
He used the police to have the building sealed off.
That's why he called them.
It was the only way to hide a certain something...
But to hide what?
That guy outside...
He was calling someone inside the building after it was closed off.
Call me when you're done.
I'll be waiting outside.
That means he was leaving a voice mail.
So now we need to find someone inside
who can't answer their cell phone?
The one that those two want to meet...
You mean the culprit's motive was to prevent them from getting in?
The culprit's true motive is to attack
the person who was to meet those two.
That guy is probably...
At the dentist, where your phone has to be turned off.
I see.
If you match the appointment with the dentist...
And coincide it with the crime...
You can close off the entire area.
Good evening.
Do you have an appointment?
Yes, um...
Haibara...
The inspector.
What's wrong?
You can wait in line if it's urgent.
Is there someone else who's waiting for their appointment?
There are other urgent patients...
Hey, hey...
Is it one of them?
I said...
It's one of those three, isn't it?
Um...
The one in the middle.
Shit!
Next patient, please.
Who the hell are you!?
I've come to take revenge for Nobu!
W-What?
Shut up, asshole!
Go!
Is the criminal here!?
That's him over there!
Oh, I thank all of yo..
I'm Masuda Taizo, a Diet member.
Thanks for saving me.
He almost killed me.
It was you who killed her!
What?
This guy...
He had someone else confess to that accident!
What the hell are you talking about!?
I've looked into it!
After three months of searching, I found some witnesses!
Why didn't you just tell that to the police!?
They didn't want to help me!
Since the opponent is a...
That's why...
This guy has to...
That's not a reason to do this!
Stop it!
That's right, you criminal.
I want to hear more about this running
away from the scene of an accident...
At the station.
That's how it is.
Let's put a stop to this.
Please drop the knife.
2...
1...
0!
Too bad!
Time has run out with one girl left!
We couldn't give away the ¥1 000,000 again this time.
See you next week at Beika!
Until then!
Dad is gonna treat us to Italian food tonight.
Would you like to join us, Ai-chan?
Don't refuse.
This is probably the only time Uncle will treat you to dinner.
What's wrong, Dad?
Oh, see, the restaurant is very crowded...
I wasn't sure if they were even open...
Did you...
Forget to make a reservation?
I, well, see...
But what?
I'm gonna go alone.
What's with that?
There's this really young waitress working there.
I couldn't refuse!
So, sorry about this!
Here's your food, Ran-chan!
Bye!
Is this how you lie to me?
Sorry, sorry!
He does this a lot, huh?
This is the worst time ever...