Help me!
This is the police! Open up!
The light of summer is the radiance of yesterday.
In the aftermath of the tears lies a two-hour special.
During a long three day vacation, we have two cases to solve.
Let's go to the Detective Koushien!
Perceiving the one and only truth,
With the body of a child and the brain of an adult,
His name is: Detective Conan!
Three days with Heiji Hattori
Light Pink
Cherry Blossom Festival
What pretty cherry tress!
Sure are! This is such a lively Sakura
festival. Aren't you glad we came?
Yeah! Thanks, Ran-chan.
Speaking of thanks, who rushed to pick up some high schoolers
from Osaka and drive them like mad here for the flower viewing?
It was me, Mouri Kogorou-sama, was it not?
Yes, yes.
We know.
Well, even in the midst of it, instead of thanking me, it looks
like those guys are more interested in the dango than the flowers.
What's this? Wasn't Heiji the one
who wanted to come flower viewing?
Hey, Kazuha-chan!
Aren't these pinwheels cute?
They sure are! I'm buying one.
How much, sir?
They're 200¥.
Then, I'll take one too.
Hey, what're you so dazed by?
Didn't you call me because you wanted me to do something?
I think it was about some high schooler with glasses.
Oh, right, right. Hondou Eisuke.
He's a second year high school student. It
seems he's in the same class as Ran now.
I want you to check on something for me.
Why me?
Does that guy have something to do with Osaka?
No, I want you to check out the one
who has the same eyes as Hondou Eisuke.
A colleague of those men in black,
Mizunashi Rena.
M-Mizunashi Rena?
You mean the announcer on Nichiuri TV?
I think she's on vacation now, though.
You're saying she's one of those bad guys?
Ah, Hattori!
Lower your voice!
She's on vacation because she was badly injured
in a bike accident while the FBI was pursuing her.
Right now, she's at a hospital in a coma.
And? How do I fit in?
If you want something checked out, wouldn't it be
better to ask that skinny detective, Takagi, or whatever?
It's a picture.
A picture, taken at least 10 years ago, that coincidentally shows a girl
who looks exactly like Mizunashi Rena was put up on a website briefly.
She was carrying a bag from an convenience
store, with Tsuutenkaku Tower in the background.
If that's true, that'd mean she lived in Osaka?
I haven't made any conclusions yet, but...
When someone took it to the TV station to confirm if it was
authentic, a few days later the site it was posted on was shut down.
It makes you think something's going on, doesn't is?
That's why I want you to hurry and check it out there.
If you can quietly look into that girl, I
can get a step ahead of Hondou Eisuke.
Well, if that's the case, why don't you investigate here instead?
If you want to catch this Hondou guy,
wouldn't approaching him directly be faster?
If they look alike and really are related, that would
mean he could be in league with the bad guys as well.
No, he's probably not with them.
It's strange, but the way Hondou Eisuke behaves...
It's great to meet you, Detective Mouri.
It's such an honor.
Look, it looks like there was no wound to begin with.
He appears to be a genuine transfer student.
Then, that would mean the one
with the same eyes, Mizunashi Rena is...
Yeah, a colleague of those guys in black...
Who murdered Hondou Eisuke's sister and with plastic surgery,
Was simply able to take her place.
In any case, please have Inspector Ohtaki look into it.
Make sure he's careful.
Have him see if a woman named
Mizunashi or Hondou ever lived in Osaka.
I see.
If such a woman was really there...
And if, after some unknown time, there's a
record of her disappearance, it'd be a 'bingo', right?
She disappeared!
She really did!
It's as if the gods spirited her away!
It must be some sort of sign for me to run
into a famous detective such as yourself!
I'm begging you, could you please solve this mystery?
What is it?
What's going on, Uncle?
This monk suddenly...
What?
Someone disappeared?
Y-Yes.
I'm an apprentice at that temple and my name is Denkyuu.
A few days ago, a guest came and visited the head monk...
Denkyuu (18)
Shougaku Temple Disciple
And then suddenly disappeared from her room.
Suddenly?
The guest was a long-haired woman who
had come to stay at the temple for the night.
When I went to tell her that breakfast was ready...
She was gone?
Couldn't she have just gone home before breakfast?
No, when I went to the guest room she was staying in...
She had a knife stuck in her stomach and
wasn't breathing! It was a horrible sight!
You're saying she was dead?
Yes...
Did you tell that to the police?
Of course.
I went right away to the head monk, who was asleep in the temple.
Then, when you said she 'disappeared'...
Y-Yes...
When the police arrived, I lead them to the
detached shrine to find the head monk there, alone.
Not even a shadow remained!
That woman's body and even the
blood on the tatami mats had disappeared!
No way...
And then? What did the head monk say?
H-He said she had left earlier that
morning and that I had just dream it all.
Are you sure you weren't just half asleep?
That's not possible!
I definitely saw it, with my own eyes!
All right, all right.
If you're so sure, why don't we go to
the temple and talk to the head monk?
Oh, so you're the famous Mouri Kogorou-san.
Shakuren (57)
Shougaku Temple
Head Monk
Such a famous detective as yourself, coming to such a small mountain temple...
Why have you come?
It's because of your Denkyuu-san.
Oh, perhaps this is about my guest
who supposedly disappeared like the mist.
You're interested in his dream story, then?
Well, you know...
Well, to be blunt, we came to see whether,
What this monk saw was an illusion,
Or whether someone actually died and you
secretly cleaned up the body before the police came.
H-Heiji!
Oh, what an interesting young man you are.
Fine then.
Let's go visit the detached shrine, shall we?
To see the room that Denkyuu claims can swallow a person.
You know, it's a long way to get to this detached shrine.
Wow, the temple we were just in looks so far away.
Sure does.
You can see it.
That's it there.
This building looks pretty old.
Indeed, because it was built some fifty years ago.
Please, come inside.
Each room contains eight mats,
Making four rooms.
Well? Where was that woman's body?
In the upper right corner of this room...
Right about there.
Anything?
Nothing really.
It doesn't seem these tatami mats are two-sided.
Ah, a Buddhist statue.
Niou-sama?
That's one of the four heavenly kings, Tamonten.
In this room, which faces north, is Tamonten.
West is Koumokuten.
South is Zoujouten.
And east is Jikokuten.
That's how each statue is placed.
Oh, I don't mind if you touch them, but please do not damage them.
These are valuable Buddhist statues of this
Shougaku temple that have been passed down for generations.
Is that so...
Well, it's become quite late now.
Why not stay here at the temple for the night and
continue investigating in the morning when it becomes light?
Of course, that's only if you say that you haven't searched enough.
Hey! You really want to stay at the temple?
Surely that monk was just half-asleep and made a mistake.
Yeah, that's right.
Since that's the case, let's head back to Ran-chan's house.
What do you want now?
T-That woman's body is back!
This time she's right in the middle of the room!
Was it in the same room?
Yes, the exact same one!
There's no one here.
That can't be.
I really just...
As expected, when you tell someone, it disappears.
Head Monk...
The truth is, that day, no guest came to the temple.
You were probably chasing the shadow
of your mother who passed away long ago.
It can't...
It can't be...
I really saw it!
Red
Disappeared Bloodstain
As I just said, it's an illusion brought
forth by a heart that yearns for his mother.
It can't be.
Eighteen years ago, that mother entrusted you to this
temple and then threw herself into the sea in her grief.
Entrusted?
Yes.
Denkyuu is the foundling child I have raised for
18 years, ever since I accepted the job of head monk.
I cannot refuse anyone, such is my nature.
Two or three others were entrusted to us as well, but
they weren't suited to temple life and have departed.
Even after being apart so long,
Denkyuu can't forget about his dear mother.
Then, Head Monk, you mean to say that the
woman's body Denkyuu-san saw the other day...
Yes, no guests came that day.
But, on that morning three days
ago, after I saw Denkyuu so shaken up...
I thought perhaps someone did get lost in the
mountains and wound up in the detached shrine.
But I could find no one, just like tonight.
So, I pity Denkyuu for having to see such an illusion...
When the police came, knowing what I knew, I simply
told them the woman guest had left earlier that morning.
So, does that solve the mystery?
Ah, well..
No.
There was a woman in this room.
Even if it was only briefly, three days
ago Denkyuu-san really found her.
Say, Head Monk, does Denkyuu-san
like to dress up in women's clothing?
Women's clothing?
Hey, brat!
What the hell are you talking about?
It's because I found this in here.
Look!
Isn't this a pierced earring clasp?
Earlier this evening, when we were checking if the
tatami mats were two-sided or not, this boy came across it.
This earring clasp was all by itself.
Meaning it most likely came off and
fell below when the mats were moved.
So, the only question is: Whose earring is it?
The shiny earring clasp went unnoticed
because it was in a place the sun didn't shine.
N-Now that you mention it,
That woman I saw three days ago...
Was wearing a pierced earring!
If that's true, please explain...
If what Denkyuu-san saw was an illusion...
No, no...
That was probably left by one of those
two that served here until two months ago...
Bunkyuu or Rinkyuu, one of them.
Bunkyuu and Rinkyuu?
Didn't I just tell you?
Other children aside from Denkyuu have been left here.
Unlike Denkyuu, those two were always troublesome kids.
Night after night they would sneak out of the temple to visit the town.
They disguised themselves so they wouldn't be recognized as monks.
Disguised?
Yes.
I don't know where they got them,
But they wore wigs, earrings, and casual clothes
in the modern style young people wear these days.
Is that true?
Yeah, those two would hide in the shrine and drink alcohol too.
When the head monk found out, they got a good scolding.
When they couldn't stand this temple anymore, they both left together.
Since those two used this shrine to change
clothes in, some things were probably left here.
That's how it is. You get all that?
Your face tells me you're not happy with that explanation.
Would you like to check around here again?
If it's as Denkyuu says and a bloodstained woman's body
was here, there should be some blood on the tatami mats, right?
Hey, Ran-chan...
Aren't Heiji and the others kinda late?
Yeah...
I wonder if something happened over there...
Wait here just in case, Ran-chan.
I'll go take a look.
Ah, then I'll come too.
You know, waiting here quietly would be better.
Right, Ran-chan?
You may be right.
Hey, what location was that woman lying in?
Ah, right!
Three days ago, it was...
In this spot.
And the woman you found just now?
In the middle of the room, right here.
Was there a lot blood?
Yeah.
Both three days ago and tonight,
There was quite a bit around the abdomen.
Well, nine times out of ten,
Even if we exclude the body three days ago...
If the body you found tonight was really in that position,
there should be blood on some of the tatami mats around here.
We checked all of the mats and found nothing at all, right?
I guess so...
As he said, I really was just seeing the phantom of my dead mother...
Well, does that satisfy you?
Yeah, we're done.
Then, Denkyuu, escort them to the gate.
Yes.
I'll be worshipping the four heavenly
kings placed in these rooms for a moment...
To apologize for the small annoyance we've caused.
I apologize for having you all out this late because of my foolishness.
No, no.
But still, what were you doing in the shrine at that hour?
I always come to make sure the doors are shut before dinner.
Actually, cleaning up and locking the
shrine door had been Bunkyuu and Rinkyuu's job.
After they were caught drinking, the head
monk took over the cleaning and I began locking up.
It wasn't just alcohol, either.
Those two also smoked in there, didn't they?
H-How did you know that?
Those two said they cleaned thoroughly so they wouldn't get caught.
No matter what, they couldn't clean the burn mark on one of the mats.
That's true, I saw a beer stain too.
Yeah, but I don't get why those two marks are there now...
But weren't when we searched earlier this evening.
That's what you were going to say, right, Heiji-niichan?
Y-Yeah.
Hey, hey...
You aren't trying to say someone switched the mats around, are you?
I'm saying that would explain it.
That's stupid.
Since you two checked the mats in that
shrine, you should know they aren't double-sided.
Besides, they're old and tanned from the sun.
If a new mat was brought in and placed somewhere,
the color would be wrong and you would notice right away.
But if it were from inside, it'd be different, right?
One of the tatami mats could have
been moved from another of the four rooms.
It takes about seven or eight minutes to get to the shrine from your car.
That's more than enough time to switch the mats.
Now that you mention it, something
did feel different when we returned...
Is that true? So, the mats really were different?
But, it was just a feeling...
No matter how you moved the mats
around, you couldn't hide the blood.
If the bloodstains were in the middle of the room,
at least two of the mats would have blood on them.
Those four heavenly king statues in the
corners of the rooms were also strange, but...
They're in cases made of glass.
When you take out the statues, you can see the tatami
through the bottom, so hiding anything there is impossible.
All right, it's time to get out of here.
I'm tired of having this stupid conversation.
A mistake!?
You're saying the body was never there?
Yeah, it was just this monk seeing things.
I apologize.
But I'm glad. This means no one died.
Then hurry and get in so we can go to Ran-chan's house.
Was that your pinwheel?
Rats, I smashed it...
It's all right, at least it didn't get bent.
Why?
Why was the burn mark not present
earlier but suddenly is now at night?
Did we miss it because it was hidden?
Where'd it go?
Hey, Heiji-niichan!
Hey, now you're doing it.
This is it! This!
I know where the blood is hidden!
Yeah, that's the way...
Yeah.
That's it exactly.
Orange
Pinwheel Room
So the woman I found both tonight and three days ago was real?
Yeah, it was no phantom, that really was a dead body.
It was cleverly hidden to make it look like it had just disappeared.
Because of a fantastic device.
A device?
Hey, what kind of device was it?
Tell us, Father.
The hint was this pinwheel. I figured it out when I saw this thing.
That's how you got it as well, right, Brat-from-Osaka?
Y-Yeah...
Why had the body disappeared when
Denkyuu-san brought us back there?
This pinwheel is like that detached shrine.
That shrine has no railings, and it's
square-shaped with 4 rooms with 8 mats each.
Railings?
Square-shaped?
What's this?
The incompetent detective brat
from Osaka doesn't quite get it yet, huh?
Well, this is your deduction...
See, the shrine was rotated 180 degrees.
Um, I don't think there's a device like that in the shrine.
Of course you wouldn't know.
After all, it was built fifty years ago.
But still, when the police searched three days ago...
And when you all searched tonight, after I brought you here,
We completely searched each of the four rooms, didn't we?
And we didn't find a body or blood in any of the rooms, did we?
Well, that's true...
What's more...
If a building was built like today's amusement parks fifty years ago,
It would've been a big tourist attraction around here, you moron!
Well, there wasn't a body then.
You were just hallucinating.
No, there was both a body and blood.
You couldn't see it because it was hidden.
It was hidden?
Mind telling us where?
Conan-kun!
Are you all right?
I slipped trying to pick up the badge I dropped.
You should be careful.
It was raining since this morning and
it looks like it's still muddy in this area.
More importantly, is my Detective Badge lying around here anywhere?
I don't see it.
Well, for starters...
Here are your glasses.
Thanks.
I found the badge.
Really?
But that's weird...
It wasn't there when I looked a second ago.
You're right.
Oh, maybe it's because of this leaf sticking to my glasses?
See, like this, you can see the badge.
But if you put down these glasses
with a leaf on them, you can't see it, right?
He's right, it blends in with the leaves scattered on the ground.
You can't see the badge at all.
Hey, perhaps this is the same trick?
Maybe.
Did you say 'trick'?
Yeah, you can hide the blood using this same trick.
Underneath cases of the four heavenly kings
statues in the corners of the rooms in that shrine, right?
But I didn't see anything under the cases...
After taking out the statues, you can see the
tatami mats underneath through the transparent bottom.
You see,
If you cut out a piece of the tatami and stick it to the bottom
of the glass case, and place it over the bloodstain on the mat,
It completely hides the blood and the glass case still seems transparent.
That's true...
But wouldn't anyone that picks up
the cases discover the trick right away?
They wouldn't do that.
If you pick the case up with the statue in it,
the statue may tip over and break the glass case.
So, by just picking up the statues, you'll see
what you believe is the unaltered tatami below.
Likely no one would bother to move the cases.
And naturally, none of us even thought to move the cases.
But still, why would anyone set all of that up?
Would a murderer do all that just to hide the blood?
It was probably originally done by the two
monks who left the temple two months ago.
In order to hide the alcohol stain and the burn mark.
They must have gone searching for
tatami the same color as the mats in the shrine.
And glued it to the bottoms of the statue cases, and placed the
cases on top of the stain and burn mark so they wouldn't be seen.
Those two were in charge of cleaning that shrine
and bragged about hiding all of that, didn't they?
Yeah...
Since we didn't see the stains when
we investigated the shrine this evening...
But they were suddenly there when we investigated tonight
after Denkyuu-san told us he saw the body again is the proof.
And so what?
Are you saying those two monks secretly
came back to the shrine and killed some woman?
No, all those two did was set that trick up.
The one who used the trick was the
one saw through it and scolded them for it.
The head monk, Shakuren. Who else could it be?
The head monk?
You're saying he killed that woman?
No, no!
If he had killed her, he wouldn't have left the body there three
days ago for Denkyuu-san to find and returned to the temple to sleep.
That woman most likely committed suicide.
When Denkyuu-san told him a woman was
dead in the shrine, it occurred to him right away.
To make it seem that Denkyuu-san was
seeing things and that there was never a body.
That can't be...
The woman's blood was in the right spot on the
mats, just like the alcohol and cigarette stains were.
He used the trick with the cases, cleverly moving the
mats around and placing the cases on top to hide it.
And where did he put the body?
He probably hid it under the floor of
the shrine, or at least until the police left.
So, the body I saw tonight was the
same as the one from three days ago?
No, the body you saw tonight was probably...
The head monk lying down, dressed as a woman.
The head monk?
Yeah, he probably wore one of the wigs those two monks left behind...
And ketchup for the blood with a knife held to his stomach.
He thought that if the same thing happened
twice, both we and Denkyuu-san would believe,
The woman's body was a hallucination and would move on.
But don't you think it's strange?
If I remember correctly, the statues in the
shrine were placed in the four corners of the rooms.
Either in the upper right or lower left corner of a mat.
The stains those two monks tried to hide with the cases,
Were two stains from a cigarette burn and alcohol.
Even though the blood from the body three days ago could be hidden,
The blood from the corpse Denkyuu-san
saw today was in the middle of the room.
That means there were four bloodstained mats.
I don't think the blood from tonight
could be hidden with just two cases.
No, he used four cases, not just two.
The priest copied those two and did the
same trick with the two remaining cases.
This way could hide four places.
Tonight, he used the two originally
bloodstained mats and two other mats.
Stained the top of the 4 mats with something that looked like blood,
and lay down in the middle of the room like the woman's corpse was.
He pretended he was dead and waited for Denkyuu-san to show.
After he got scared by the corpse and went to get
us, he hid the bloodstained mats in the four corners.
Then he showed up behind us as we came to
the shrine and acted like nothing had happened.
But the head monk laid down like the corpse in the center of the room.
So the fake blood stains wouldn't be on the corners of the mats.
Even with four cases, it would be impossible to hide.
Are you sure about that?
Ah, I see! The bloodstains could have been
where the corners of the mats came together.
So the blood would be same places in the upper-right and lower-left,
and on the remaining two it would be in the upper-left and lower-right.
Ah, that's no good.
A-Ah, the other way. That way there are two in the upper-left,
so no problem. As I thought, there are two in the upper-left still.
The statues are in the four corners of the
rooms, so you can't hide all four mats, right?
Are those the only ways to arrange them?
Ah-le-le!
Look at this.
It's like a pinwheel, right?
I see!
If you arranged the mats like that...
Then the blood is always in the upper right corner!
So, that's it.
That's why I sensed something was strange...
The arrangement of the tatami mats was different.
But why would the head monk go to so much trouble to hide the body?
The body of some woman who committed suicide...
Well, why don't we just ask him directly?
Black
Monk's confession
That's true, why did the head monk do this?
Why did he try to hide it so much and even pretend to be the body?
Because if they found the corpse, the
woman's identity would be discovered?
He didn't want the woman's identity to be known?
Who was she?
Since you seem to have returned,
I guess I wasn't able to keep hiding it.
Of course not!
You're ten million years too young
to deceive the eyes of Kogorou-sama!
I'm sorry, but I must ask Denkyuu to
leave before I can answer your questions-
We already told him to return to the car.
We asked him to make sure the girls didn't get lonely.
Since you had him in mind, the woman who
killed herself three days ago must have been...
Yes, it was the woman who, eighteen years ago,
abandoned Denkyuu in front of this temple in a cardboard box.
Denkyuu's mother.
Really?
Yes.
She appeared suddenly in the evening
three days ago, asking that we return her son.
She even claimed she had visited
every year, watching over him as he grew.
So, I decided to show her an album with
pictures of all of the monks that had served here.
However, as I feared, she couldn't pick out her son and broke into tears.
She didn't even recognized that her son
was the one who brought the album to her.
After I had Denkyuu retire, I felt compelled to scold her harshly.
I said, "Cool your head in the separate shrine for the night."
"Experience the eighteen years of grief you
brought on your son, down to your bones."
And as dawn broke, I found her in that state.
I thought it would be too painful for Denkyuu to know about.
So I came up with this plan.
Well, I guess we should be going.
Would you mind driving me to the police station?
Oh, sure.
I guess after doing something like that, I
shouldn't have the right to say this, but...
If you plan to continue being a
detective and using words to entrap people,
Inscribe this in your hearts: Words are like knives.
When used incorrectly, they turn into foul weapons.
You have to understand the
opponent's heart and use them with discretion.
No matter who it is you're dealing with.
So, why did the head monk hide the body?
Yeah, yeah! Don't be stingy, hurry and tell us!
Heiji! C'mon, Heiji!
Heiji-
Be quiet!
Didn't I just say I didn't want to talk about it, moron?
In his case, I have a feeling he puts all
his strength into using words incorrectly.
Oh no, it's already past 9:00!
Geez, he must have been out
partying last night and come home late.
How fortunate that it's Sunday.
As expected, it looks like Hattori and Kazuha left early.
We're leaving early in the morning, so I'm off to sleep.
Well, he said he would.
But that guy, does he even remember...
That he promised to look into Mizunashi Rena?
Well, I'll e-mail him later...
Damn, its empty.
Here. I'll loan you mine.
Oh, thanks.
Why are you still here!?
You said you were leaving early!
Yeah, I planned to, but with that old man's snoring...
I didn't get enough sleep. Thanks to him, that plan's messed up.
Then, why aren't you hurrying to exchange tickets?
It's OK, I'm not going home yet.
Why?
What? A deserted island?
You're going there after this?
Yeah, were going to go after the flower viewing.
Is it a case or something?
No, no, it's for a TV program.
Thanks, loudmouth.
But is it OK to wait this late to go to the ship?
Doesn't it leave early?
No, even if we leave now, we'll be there in plenty of time.
Why so?
If I had wanted to get up early, I could have gotten there before them.
And checked out the faces and
characters of the other guys who were invited.
People like me. High-school detectives.
H-High-school detectives?
That's right.
Nichiuri TV has gathered guys like that from all
over the country to see who's the best in Japan.
They're advertising it as a Detective Koushien.
Detective Koushien?
Blue
Beyond the see
That's why I told him not to go.
He'd be an idiot to go like that, just because he was invited.
I think so too, but I have to go.
It was right there in the invitation letter.
I, Hattori Heiji, was invited as the representative from the West.
The West?
Yeah, since the West is me, the East is obviously...
Shinichi...
Oh! Ran-chan's face is red!
Hey, it's just that it's a little warm today.
Hey, you don't think, that detective boy...
...might be coming?
I'm not coming.
As this guy well knows.
Well, do you two want to come with us?
They said there's lodging for any escorts.
Who knows, maybe that conceited
high-school detective Kudou Shinichi will...
But then again, we may find out otherwise, right, kid?
Hey. Hey. Hey!
You're late, Hattori-kun.
Please try to be on time. We're
getting underway in a matter of minutes.
Oh, sorry, somebody took the wrong road.
Tsuchio Hiroo (41)
Nichiuri TV Director
Well, nevermind, let's head to the island.
Everyone else is already aboard the ship.
Then, that means Shinichi's already here?
Kudou Shinichi, the high-school detective of the East.
Ah, I couldn't contact that young
man, so I don't know if he's coming or not.
Really?
Oh, is that so?
That was obvious enough.
Say, is the place where escorts like us
are staying there on the deserted island?
Oh, no, there's only an old lodge on the island.
Everyone's guardians will be staying at a hotel for the evening.
Tomorrow when the filming's over, we'll come pick you up.
I see.
Hey, would it be OK to take this kid with?
He's kind of like my assistant.
If he stays in your room, that's fine.
But look at this huge ship...
Could it be there are people here from each of the 47 districts?
Oh, no, we only invited four people,
from the East, West, South and North.
This ship was just an easy to find meeting place.
Our ship is this way.
This is our ship.
Hurry and board, time's getting short.
Hey, Hattori...
What?
Do you know that director guy from Nichiuri TV?
No, this is my first time meeting him.
You've noticed his Nichiuri TV staff jumper, huh?
Heiji!
As the Kansai representative, you'd
better win! Or I'll never forgive you!
Oh, I won't be left behind.
Hattori Heiji is here!
According to this, when we arrive on the
island, you should stay in your rooms until dinner.
And things will start after dinner.
Please be ready.
When we arrive at the island, the competition will have begun.
Yes.
Statement understood.
How strange.
I would expect them to be more excited about this Detective Koushien.
Hey, why'd you bring me along?
You better not be thinking I'm gonna help you win.
No, no.
After all, since the East's Kudou Shinichi cant come.
I just thought I should give you a
chance to compete, or else I'll win too easily.
You're the only real competition for me.
So that's why you asked Ran and the other to come.
So that's was your stupid plan, since I couldn't come alone.
Hey, are you getting seasick?
Oh, no, it's just a hangover.
After the recording was finished
yesterday, I drank too much with the staff.
Then, you went over the top?
The top?
Ah, well, it was at a high-cost place.
Hey, Uncle.
Won't you at least laugh for me? You're so small-minded.
Laugh? Small-minded?
Oh, that pun between "high-cost" and "top" just now...
Oh, those two, they're not too bad, huh?
Yeah.
Detective Koushien?
Nichiuri TV?
We don't have any reservations for anything like that.
Hey, check again.
It should include dinner and breakfast too.
But, you see...
What's this?
What's going on?
Welcome. I'm the one appointed to look
after you, Kouya Renzou. Nice to meet you.
Kouya Renzou (58)
Official Caretaker
Shall we head directly to the lodge?
Hey, Director-san.
It looks like the high-school detective of the East hasn't come, huh?
What shall we do about that?
Hey!
Well now...
As for the boy representing the East, he was
here early this morning and is already at the lodge.
What'd you say?
Are you sure?
I think his name was...
I see. We're completely isolated from
the outside world. Quite the solitary island.
Subject: To my dear housekeeper
please cancel tomorrow's
dinner reservations.
It seems I won't be back home
for a while.
I will definitely make up for it
some later day.
-Saguru
For this scene of the mystery...
This is the perfect situation.
Ha-Hakuba Saguru?
W-Who's that?
Well now, can you high school
detectives from the East, West, South and North.
White
Highschool Detective in East
Please introduce yourselves.
Well, all right.
Is this OK?
Without any TV cameras around?
Yeah, there aren't any TV staff here either.
Oh, the crew and hosting talent aren't
scheduled to arrive until tomorrow morning.
We brought you here earlier to get acquainted.
Well, then...
I'm Koshimizu Natsuki, a third year high-school student.
Koshimizu Natsuki (18)
High-School Detectives
from the South
I was born in Fukuoka and for now
I'm the representative from the South.
I haven't even solved 100 cases yet, so I'm still a novice.
Please don't be too rough on me.
This one is Tokitsu Junya.
Tokitsu Junya (18)
High-School Detectives
from the North
Though I was born in Tokyo, I grew up in
Hokkaido, so I'm the North's representative.
I've handled approximately 300 cases, where
more than 250 people were arrested and prosecuted.
I've had some cases where they got away or committed suicide.
I'm Hattori Heiji, a pretty well-known detective from the Kansai region.
As for how many cases I've solved...
One, two, three...
Heh, it's more than 1,000, so it's hard to count them individually.
1-1,000?
That's amazing.
Hey, quit it with the nonsense.
It's true, even if I may have included searching for cats as a kid.
I see, so you're Hattori Heiji-kun.
My father speaks well of you.
He said you're a very perceptive detective.
What's that?
How does your dad know about me?
He's just like you, Heiji-niichan.
Like me?
Isn't that so, Hakuba-niichan?
Yeah, my father is a police commissioner.
Hakuba Saguru (18)
High-School Detectives
from the East
Strangely, since your father is the director general of the
Osaka Prefectural police, our circumstances are very similar.
By the way, how many cases have you solved?
Ah, I see. I would say around 500?
Heh, that's only half as many as me.
Yeah, but then again, I'm only talking
about the cases that occurred in Japan.
What do you mean?
I've been studying abroad in England for awhile.
I don't come back to Japan often.
My old housekeeper has been accepting cases for me.
That's quite unexpected. That someone who's famous
overseas like Hakuba would be the representative from the East.
Yeah, I was sure it'd be Kudou Shinichi-kun.
Exactly.
The high-school detective from the East is Kudou.
You shouldn't be here.
It was my housekeeper, you see, who
received the call from the director here.
He asked that I participate as the representative from
the East to replace Kudou-kun, who could not be contacted.
It seems the term replacement hurt my dear housekeeper's feelings.
"The world should know that Hakuba is the
representative from the East," she told me in tears.
What could I do? I zipped back from England.
However, it would seem I'm not an
appropriate representative for the East.
You got that right.
Then, how about this?
I'll take the role of "guest from abroad,"
And let Edogawa Conan-kun here be the East's representative.
This boy is surprisingly good at deduction.
I think he's even better than that Kudou Whoever-kun.
Who're you calling 'whoever'?
But he's just a kid...
That's fine. It works for me.
More importantly, where are our rooms? I'm kinda tired.
I'm hoping for dinner.
Ah, right. Well...
Kouya-san is making dinner now.
He'll call for you when it's ready.
Oh, one last thing. I want to check
your clothes for the recording tomorrow.
I'll call you on the phone when dinner's ready.
Please wear clothes appropriate for the Detective Koushien.
What?
There's no such project?
Are you sure, Yoko-chan?
Yeah, I asked around the station, but...
Everyone said they'd never heard of a 'Detective Koushien'.
Are you sure that guy was from Nichiuri TV?
Yeah, he was wearing the station's
staff jumper and I think his name was...
Tsuchio Hiroo.
What!?
There's no such director?
H-Hey...
That means they were taken by...
Who?
I see.
So that's your Detective Koushien outfit?
Yeah, I only wear this outfit at school and to ceremonies.
But, you know, I was surprised...
That you knew that annoying guy.
Oh, Hakuba Saguru?
We met before on a case.
You really think he's that annoying?
Yeah, looking down on others and talking trash.
Kinda like you.
Oh, really?
Still, you have more of an innocent child-like charm.
I see...
Regardless, from now on, we're mutual enemies.
No matter what happens, no consulting with me.
Come in.
Excuse me. Dinner has been made
ready, so please come to the dining room.
You know, this lodge is pretty old.
There are many places where it been repaired.
Who's the owner?
Who knows. I've heard the lodge is being rented
cheaply by some rich owner who no longer uses it.
Oh, by the way, has she already gone to the dining room?
She?
No, I'm just about to call her now.
Is there a woman on the island too?
She's been with us from the beginning.
Yes?
Dinner is ready.
It's already time?
Oh, no, I've been relaxing too long!
That guy's... a girl?
My school regulations are very strict.
Skirt: 3 cm below the knees!
Scarf: Bilaterally symmetrical!
Socks: Black!
Perms are forbidden, shaving your eyebrows is a suspension.
And how many times have I been
warned about my naturally brown hair.
But, the cameras aren't here yet tonight.
So whatever works is fine.
Yeah, you're right.
What's with you?
Not changing clothes?
Yeah.
Unlike you all, students in England can wear casual clothes.
Wow, looks delicious!
You made all of this, Uncle?
Yes.
Huh? Where's the director?
Well, he didn't answer when I went to his room
a while ago, so I assumed he'd be already here.
Would you please show us to his room?
Tsuchio-sama? Dinner's ready.
Tsuchio-sama?
Damn, I guess he locked it so he could sleep.
Blood...
There's blood on the knob!
Is there a master key?
No, there aren't any keys.
It's like your rooms, you can only lock them from the inside.
If it's like our rooms, there must be two windows.
Then let's check from the window!
Hey, you!
T-Tsuchio-san!
Tsuchio-san!
Gray
Highschool Detective in North
The window bolt...
Is locked.
It seems the door was locked properly.
So, this is a locked room murder?
Yeah...
It would be, if he were actually dead.
He's still alive?
Hey, how are you?
Thank God. What happened?
Someone knocked at the door...
When I went out to check, there was no one there. Then when I was
going back into my room, someone suddenly drugged me from behind.
Detective Koushien: Case #1.
Solve the mystery of this locked room.
When you solve it, write down your
deduction in a letter and quickly bring it to me.
If your reasoning is correct, you'll advance to
round two and learn how to escape this island.
In other words, the battle's already begun.
Then, does that mean there's a hidden camera somewhere?
What a surprise.
I thought having us find out this guy
was a fake director would be the first round.
What're you talking about? I really am a Nichi-
Don't try to play dumb.
Remember when that guy said you went 'over the top'?
He meant that you over-did it by recording passed midnight.
When this girl said "laugh for me" after that.
It meant to move something.
Even an novice assistant director should know that.
There's no way a director would not know those terms.
Besides, the spiral eyeball on your Nichiuri TV mark is funny.
The real one spins the other way.
That's probably how everyone knew you were a fake.
Well, this means we've broken into the first round, so...
Sorry, but this one has passed you up.
I've solved it...
This locked-room trick.
Shall I show you how it was done?
You solved it already?
If that's so, please show us.
Don't do that.
If you did, the others would know the trick.
As I said before, write down your
deduction in a letter and bring it to me.
You must follow this rule throughout the first round.
This is not the final round.
Don't worry, I'm not telling it right now.
Anyway, the result will be the same whether it's the final round or not.
How self-confident you are.
I don't care how the trick was done.
I just wonder if Tsuchio-san didn't tie himself up after locking the door.
How could that be?
Wouldn't the representative from the
West have noticed when he untied the rope?
No matter how incompetent a detective he may be.
In-Incompetent?
It was most unsatisfactory.
When you discovered blood on the door
knob, you immediately smashed in the door.
In that situation, it's best to check
the situation inside from the window.
Afterwards, you can decide whether to
smash in the door or break the window glass.
If Tsuchio-san were dead and leaning against the door,
You would have destroyed potential
evidence when you smashed in the door.
l-Idiot! How could I wait?
He was eager to get to the crime scene before the rest of us.
Doesn't that disqualify him as a detective.
What'd you say!?
No, he's not unqualified.
Kudou...
Heiji-niichan is simply hot-blooded!
Hey!
Anyway, this one will be going upstairs
to setup my room like this locked room.
Wait for me while you enjoy your dinner.
It'll take about one hour.
An hour?
I see.
Rom when Kouya-san showed us our rooms to our
discovering the locked room case was about that long.
So, the trick took that long to set up?
Well, something like that.
Ah, I'll tell you this just to be sure, this trick doesn't
require any foolish behavior from any violent detectives. Thanks.
Well, he won't repeat the same mistake.
The one who made his name because his father is
the famous Osaka Prefectural Police Director-General.
Isn't that right, representative from the West?
But, you know...
I like hot detectives like you.
Like I said, it was moored around
here, a boat some children boarded!
What's wrong, Kazuha-chan?
Well, I've got a kinda bad feeling.
Do you know who's boat that was?
No luck calling his cellphone?
No, I just keep getting an out-of-range message.
The phone you have called is either in a location beyond
signal range or can not be reached because it is not receiving power.
I see.
Ran-chan, you don't feel something's wrong?
I just have this feeling that something
horrible is looming over Heiji and the others.
You're over reacting!
I'm sure Hattori-kun is fine.
He and Conan-kun will definitely be coming back.
Even so, it's still bothering me...
Heiji's face before he left with them.
Over and over, it keeps running through my head.
Well, what about Conan-kun's cellphone?
Still nothing?
No, no luck there either.
I'd feel a lot better if the representative
from the East, Kudou-kun, was with Heiji...
The phone you have called is either in a location beyond
signal range or can not be reached because it is not receiving power.
I can't reach Shinichi's cellphone either.
Could it be that Shinichi's there too?
Purple
Scent or Lavender
I knew it, we're out of range.
Well, this is an isolated island.
No way!
I just go to the bathroom now it's all almost gone!
Don't eat so much!
Sorry, I was hungry.
Geez..
Well then, now that your stomach is
full, will you talk to us, fake Director-san?
Why did you lie about your position
and arrange in this 'Detective Koushien'?
If it isn't to test our abilities, what is your job?
Can't say.
If I told you, I wouldn't get my promised fee.
From Nichiuri TV?
Well then, will you answer this?
Something's been bothering me since I got to this lodge.
It's the aroma of lavender everywhere.
Now that you mention it, it was in our room too, wasn't it. Lavender.
Yeah.
My room, too.
It looks like it's in every room.
Also, there was a toolbox next to it.
I guess that means something, too?
I couldn't tell you.
Finding that out is a task for you detectives.
The rest is up to you.
Exactly.
I rather find out why we've been cut off from the outside world.
The Lavender Mansion Murder Case.
Hearing "lavender" reminds me of a
case that happened in Shikoku a year ago.
I've heard about it as well.
If I remember correctly, the one who
died was the young mistress of the mansion.
Y-Young mistress!
For some reason, half a year later, they decided it was a murder.
So, who was the culprit?
I heard they committed suicide before they were apprehended.
What's wrong?
Oh, it's nothing.
I forgot my cigarettes in my room.
It's really coming down.
Why are you so wet?
Don't tell me you were looking for a cigarette vending machine outside.
Oh, no, I just stepped outside for a second.
By the way, don't you think he's a little late?
That guy.
That's true, it's been over two hours.
Then I'll go ask how much longer it will be.
Oh, thanks.
What!?
He wasn't in his room?
Y-Yes!
I knocked a lot, but he didn't answer.
The door was locked, you don't think...
I see.
He may have already finished preparing the
locked room and is off snickering somewhere.
In that case, wouldn't he want to show his grinning face to all of us?
In that's so, I'll check from outside. Wait a second.
I'll go too then.
I would be worried if you went alone.
Please yourself.
What? Isn't that him by the window?
Just now, isn't that blood?
Quick, to his room!
H-Hey!
You!
What do you see, Hattori?
It's bad.
He's really dead.
What's the situation?
As you can see, he was killed by a blow to the head.
The murder weapon must be that hammer, there's even blood on it.
It was probably taken from that toolbox next to the lavender flowerpot.
And the window lock?
It was firmly locked until I broke it open.
And the window frame is held by screws.
Same with the door, no sign of any trick.
With no secret entrances, that means this really is...
A locked room murder.
And moreover the criminal is...
Koshimizu-san, Kouya-san or Tsuchio-san. It's one of you.
Hold on now, boy...
Why us?
He's right.
Tokitsu-kun went to his room upstairs,
claiming he would demonstrate the locked room trick.
All of us were in the dining room on the
first floor and had started eating dinner.
I went to the bathroom, which took about 10 minutes.
A while after I returned, Tsuchio-san went to his room to get cigarettes.
And Kouya-san went to check on Tokitsu-kun.
If Hakuba-kun and the other two were in the dinning
room the whole time, what he said would make sense.
W-Wait!
I only came here because I was hired!
By whom? I don't think any TV channel
would film something with people actually dying.
I really thought it was a TV program!
The truth is I'm in a small theater troupe.
I got a letter from someone at Nichiuri TV asking,
"Would you like to be a director for our channel?"
I got 500,000 in advance.
He promised another 500,000 if I wasn't uncovered as a fake.
Who wouldn't jump at such a sweet deal?
And? If we found out?
If I was found out, I was to maintain it really was a
Detective Koushien until the end and I'd still get half, 250,000.
But I thought you said were going to your room for cigarettes?
Instead, you came back soaked. Why is that?
I went to use radio in the shed to call for emergency help.
But...
It had been broken!
I know it was fine when I came here three days ago to prepare.
Is that the truth?
Y-Yes!
But that's strange...
When you went to the shed, it was still before the murder.
How would you know an emergency would happen?
I just felt something would happen...
Really.
And you, Kouya-san? Were you also called here like Tsuchio-san?
Yeah, I came here two days ago to look after everyone.
I had just quit my job and left the house
where I had been employed as a butler.
But, you did know about the locked room trick, right?
You told us to write it down and hand it to you.
I was instructed to say that when the "locked room" occurred.
I was also told to hide the solution under the bathroom mat.
Funny you should say it that way.
It makes it seem the mastermind is someone other than you.
No, I'm telling the truth.
I don't care about that, I'm just like the rest of you.
I was called by this fake director to be the
representative from the South and brought here.
I hate thunder!
Please, close the window! Please!
Sure.
It's all right.
I'll take care of the thunder and the case for you.
What's with this guy?
Anyway, I'm going to look around.
You three suspects should wait in the dining room on the first floor.
I hope you want me to be on alert with you.
Because you're so hot-blooded, or should I say uncivilized?
What!?
Don't you see?
You've scattered glass everywhere and
got your muddy footprints on the desk.
That's a horrible situation.
Could you have carelessly touched the lock with your bare hands?
Yes, to open it!
Got a problem with that?
Why's he the one who's angry?
I'm disappointed in you.
My father had me thinking you were a better detective than this.
Anyway, after I take them to the
dining room, I'll begin investigating again.
Try not to get in the way, representative from the West.
Say, Kudou...
Am I in the wrong?
No, not at all.
"Not at all?"
It was a boat that a man with a moustache,
three high-schoolers, and a kid got on board!
How can you not know anything about it?
What's wrong, Kazuha-chan?
For some reason, I'm sure, something was bothering him.
That time, with what Heiji said.
Yeah, I wont fall behind!
Hattori Heiji is here!
Heiji said 'here'. "Come here?"
Hey, Ran-chan, what Heiji said then.
He might have meant, "Come here."
Could it be...
Blue, White and Black
Each person's reasoning
There's one thing I don't get.
Why'd the murderer bother to put
Tokitsu's body on the table by the window?
And in this position.
Does it mean something?
Probably just for the appeal of having us see this
locked room murder from outside. That's how I see it.
And what's with the lavender and the tool boxes?
Everyone's room seem to have them.
Just looking it from the outside won't tell us anything.
Let's open it up.
Wait.
Allow me.
Ah, go ahead.
Wire, nails, wire cutters, a screwdriver, a drill, a
square, pliers, wood bond, a saw, a utility knife.
I knew it. No hammer.
I guess that means the murder weapon came from here.
Using a hammer like this, the guy of course, the
woman, or even the old man could have committed the crime.
Going by time, I can say those three were out of our vicinity as follows:
Koshimizu-san went to the toilet between 19:26:32 and 19:39:15.
Tsuchio-san went to get cigarettes from
his room between 20:06:47 and 21:28:31.
Finally, Kouya-san went to check on
Tokitsu-kun between 21:30:06 and 21:38:52.
All three had the 10 minutes that
would be needed to commit the crime.
He recorded the seconds?
But Kouya-san was mostly in the kitchen and
out of our sight, so wasn't he able to move freely?
No, all of the windows in the kitchen are fixed and can't be opened.
Same with the skylight.
The kitchen door is here. In other words, he couldn't have
gotten out without passing through the dining room where we were.
So most-likely Kouya-san was always in the kitchen.
Now, this is a rough sketch of the second floor. All four
rooms have windows that face slightly different directions.
And they're furnished in roughly the same way.
You sure work fast.
It's because I arrived a half-day ahead of you.
Now that you mention it, how do we have electricity here?
Yeah, this is a deserted island.
I heard there's a small generator in the shed.
Shall we have a look?
The radio he mentioned is there as well.
It's true.
It really has been broken in pieces.
This is the generator, huh?
This place doesn't have a lock?
No, there should be a padlock.
I believe Kouya-san keeps the key.
The padlock...
Someone was forcing it.
Look at all these muddy footprints.
They must be Tsuchio-san's.
He's the one who went out after it began to rain.
Isn't that right, Hakuba-niichan?
Huh?
What?
That guy vanished.
Not here... Not here...
It isn't here.
As I thought, the toolbox in that person's room..
Has no wire.
Huh? Hakuba hasn't come back?
No, wasn't he with you?
Regardless, did you find anything? It
looks like you went looking in the shed.
Well, yeah.
Impossible, impossible.
Looks like this guy's drunk.
You may act like you're detectives, but
in the end your abilities come up short.
It's all just mere show.
In that case, shall I'll let you hear my mere show of a deduction?
I see.
So that's how it is.
No doubt about it.
The criminal is...
That person.
That guy.
Am I wrong?
You murdered Tokitsu and then created the locked room scenario...
Kouya Renzou-san.
Well, it's quite simple when you think about it.
Tokitsu said he'd take one hour to
recreate the locked room in his own room.
That means it's a time consuming trick.
Most likely you went to see him just
as he was finishing his preparations.
And killed him.
Then naturally you decided to use the already
completed trick to make it a locked room murder.
That's why neither Koshimizu-san, who went to
the bathroom right after Tokitsu left for his room,
Nor Tsuchio-san, who went to get cigarettes
from his room thirty minutes later, could do it.
That means the one who went looking for him just
before Tokitsu was ready to demonstrate his locked room,
Kouya-san, you're the only one who could be the culprit.
My, my...
When will you ever stop disappointing me?
Sorry, but he didn't do it.
That's because the real sinner is the one who was
able to open and close the lock with a single wire.
And, Tsuchio-san,
That person is you.
Wh-What kinda of dumb...
You pretended to leave to get your cigarettes and
instead went to the shed and forced open the padlock.
The padlock had been tossed into the
shed, wet, with fresh pick marks on it.
In other words, it was picked by the one who
went outside after it began to rain: Tsuchio-san.
Not to mention, the toolbox in your
room is the only one without a wire.
Then, how did he get into the locked room?
Tsuchio-san came here three days ago to check the place out, right?
Probably at that time he made a small hole in the window of the room.
And tonight, after murdering
Tokitsu-kun, he went outside through the window,
And used the wire to lock it through
the hole in the glass he made before.
Later, because of Hattori-kun's carelessness,
He smashed the window glass to pieces to get into the room.
As you anticipated, this hid the hole already made in the glass.
Afterwards, breaking the radio in the shed was to make us all
uneasy and drive us into believing another person might be murdered.
Am I wrong?
Th-That's...
I think you're wrong.
Even if he could predict that
Heiji-niichan would smash the window glass,
He couldn't know which of the four panes he would break.
And what's more, no matter how hot-blooded Heiji-niichan
may be, if there was a hole, I think he would have noticed it.
Adding "hot-blooded" wasn't necessary...
But I'm sure he's the one who picked the padlock on the shed!
Yeah, I think it's pretty likely this guy just a lousy thief.
But so what? In your head, does being a thief
automatically equate to him being the culprit?
That's how it is for me...
So, do you know how the locked room trick done?
Yep, it was a really simple trick!
First, you undo the screws that hold the
window frame in place, leaving the window alone.
The setup is "OK" when the all the pulled out screws are cut by pliers.
After that, you reinsert the cut screws in the frame, fasten the edges
of the frame with glue, and fit the entire window back in from outside.
In other words, even though outwardly it
appears to be fastened, the screws are too short.
When you're done, the window is attached only because of the glue.
So you see, the one who-
Allow me.
Yeah, the one who happened to be the
last to go to Tokitsu's room, Kouya-san...
It must've been you.
What're you talking about, Heiji-niichan? That guy...
You saw the chance when Tokitsu was working carefully,
immersed in creating the trick, to attack and murder him.
Sorry to interrupt your speech, but why would Kouya-san.
There's proof.
I found this in Tokitsu's room...
This screw with it's head cut off.
T-This guy...
C-Could it be...
How about it? This is conclusive proof.
Green
Message from Heiji
I guess you couldn't collect them all.
That's right, when you used the pliers to cut the
screws, you couldn't know where they would fall.
Just as I thought.
I knew it was you... the one who killed Tokitsu.
Hattori...
The reason Tokitsu said it would take an hour to
prepare was because he had to wait for the glue to dry.
No matter how quickly he could unfasten and cut the screws,
even a quick drying glue would take at least thirty minutes to dry.
That means Tokitsu finished in less than thirty
minutes and was planning to wait outside the room.
Basically, the murderer went to kill him while he still was in his room,
Meaning it had to be you because you
left your seat just as we started dinner.
Perhaps you pretended to go to the
bathroom and went to Tokitsu's room instead.
You must've said "I figured out the locked room trick, can
we compare solutions?" to get inside and beat him to death.
After that you completed the trick and made it a locked room.
Then you entered through the main door, and
returned to the dining room pretending to know nothing.
However, this story is just my
hypothesis about what you could have done.
I had no proof.
That's why I took this screw from the radio in the shed.
Thinking you got them all, you got nervous, thinking you missed one.
But, thinking we suspected Kouya-san, you tried to
take the chance and look where you were hiding them.
Who would have thought you'd carry them in
your pocket and keep fumbling around with them.
It's hard to believe.
Well, I expected you to at least have the one you
picked up when pretending to be scared of thunder.
You knew we would check the shed.
The proof is that you were looking outside next.
to the window without being scared of the thunder.
At that time, you crouched down in order to
pick up a screw that you had missed before.
Am I wrong?
It must have been...
Your ears are pierced.
You blocked your ears then to hide that, didn't you?
Pierced?
But...
That's why you were wearing headphones on the boat.
Because if the sea breeze blew your hair, we'd see them.
Well, in England, students with earrings
are everywhere, so I would've missed it.
But I remember you mentioning the school's strict
regulations, meaning you can't wear pierced earrings, right?
Yeah, but it's OK.
I'm already 20.
I graduated from high school two years ago.
I brought my old uniform so I
wouldn't be exposed, but that was a mistake.
I thought I'd seem like a schoolgirl if I talked about school regulations.
But, why did you do this?
Why did you gather us high-school detectives here?
There was something I wanted to discover.
What's that?
The Lavender Mansion Locked Room Murder Case.
You wanted to find the high-school detective that solved it.
You mean it was Tokitsu?
The newspapers didn't include the name or details of the case.
Yeah, that guy just randomly stopped
by the mansion on his trip to Shikoku,
Solved the locked room murder, and left without leaving his name.
Due to that, my close friend, who,was a housekeeper at the mansion,
fell under suspicion since she had been alone with the young mistress.
I went to the mansion as well, as a
detective, one month before that guy appeared.
My friend asked me to investigate
whether it might have been a murder.
But I couldn't find anything.
The only conclusion I could come to was that she
had closed herself in her room and committed suicide.
But why?
Why did your friend become a suspect?
One month later, that high-school detective found them.
Screws with their heads cut off scattered outside of
her room. The window had been fastened by glue as well.
Couldn't you have overlooked it?
I didn't overlook it.
This Tsuchio guy turned up dressed as
a cleaning contractor and setup the trick.
He probably only unfastened the window so he could rob them later.
So that's why your expression changed when the Lavender
Mansion was mentioned and you tried to get away from the island.
Half a year after the case, Tokitsu bit into that trick, and displayed his
deductive powers by telling the police and the media it was a murder.
If he had checked the corrosion on those
scattered screws, he should have known.
I'm sure Tokitsu had been bothered
by that, and didn't disclose his name.
That's why I didn't know where the high-school detective was from.
My only clue was the message my
friend left on the phone before she passed on.
A high-school detective with a weird accent is suspecting me!
Help me!
Help me, Natsuki!
Those were her words.
I see, someone who spoke strangely.
I've been studying abroad for a long
time, so I've been neglecting my Japanese.
Hattori-kun has a broad Kansai accent.
And Tokitsu-kun used "this one" to refer to himself.
Yeah, and not to mention, you three were the only
high-school detectives that have influence with the police.
Then Kudou wasn't on your list from the beginning?
Yeah, yeah...
Right, he's quite popular though, so I just
used his name for the call to Hakuba-kun.
And after gathering us detectives at this lodge,
First after putting Tsuchio-san to sleep and tying him up, you used the
same locked room trick from Lavender Mansion case to find your target.
That's right.
I left the necessary tools in the rooms,
And filled the place with the smell of lavender.
That high-school detective should
recall the case right away and figure it out.
That mansion was so full of lavender flowers...
Isn't that right? You worked as a
butler there after all, Kouya Renzo-san.
Yes.
I was very fond of the young mistress.
Young mistress!
Then why did you bring him here?
Because he knew the young mistress
planned to commit suicide, but he kept quiet.
You see...
Young mistress, your medicine!
Stop! Leave me alone!
I could not say anything...
That would dishonor the young mistress.
I thought any doubts about her would soon clear up.
I never thought that would happen.
I am truly sorry!
But hey, hold on...
Since you brought those two here because you hated them...
Yeah, no rescue ship is going to come.
I told that ship's captain if he didn't keep it
secret, he wouldn't get the rest of his money.
I never intended to leave here.
I considered the possibility that my
opponent might figure out my intentions.
But Tokitsu bragged about his incorrect Lavender
Mansion deduction right up until I bashed his head in.
What a worthless guy.
Then, the one who broke the radio...
Of course it was me.
We'll all die here together.
I'm sorry, boy.
No need to apologize.
We'll be rescued.
Definitely.
Hey, you.
You said you came half a day ahead of us, didn't you?
You didn't come on your own cruiser or something?
No, I just arrived at the harbor earlier than I planned.
I asked about a seldom used lodge where
a large number of people were going to stay.
And looked for a ship that had brought food and
fuel to a deserted island, and had it bring me here.
For an appropriate fee.
You mean no one knows you came here?
Yeah.
You didn't tell anyone either?
Well, I did tell someone, but...
She's kinda slow.
What did you say?
That sound...
What's that sound?
Don't tell me the generator broke.
That's not the sound of the generator.
T-That means, that sound is...
Heiji!
It's Kazuha!
Kazuha brought us a boat!
How?
Heiji-niichan left behind a message and a marker.
Yeah, I won't fall behind!
Hattori Heiji is here!
Ah, I can see Hattori-kun!
And Conan-kun too!
Really?
Heiji!
Geez, if you'd have just been frank with me, I
wouldn't have had to give you five judo throws.
It was six, actually...
What!?
Hey! Hey!
So they exist...
Hot-blooded detectives like you.
Busting down a door over a
bloodstained knob or breaking in through the glass.
That's why I put the body against the window.
If you rammed your way in and
disconnected the window, I would have been found out.
Sorry, because you know...
I'm hot blooded.
The right thing is...
To have faith in life, until you're sure of death.
That's what makes a great detective.
Right, boy?
If God ever forgives me...
I'd love to do a real Detective Koushien...
...with you.
And return to the days when I called myself 'boku'.
Is he? Is he? Is Kudou-kun there?
I can't see him!
But I'm right here.