The light of summer is the radiance of yesterday.
After the tears is a yellow sunflower.
Unexpectedly, a sad case has occurred.
No matter how skillfully it's covered up,
the sunflower will be the sole witness.
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Inspector!
Mouri-kun!
I just heard... Inoue Hiroko-san... was murdered!
The victim was an acquaintance of yours, then?
Takaoka-san...
There are no words to express how sorry I am.
I was about to ask her to make me the happiest man on earth.
Takaoka Akira (35)
Independent Film Director
For this to happen just when I was about to do that...
I understand how you must feel.
Just who could've done this horrible deed?
Well then, Inspector...
The estimated time of death is?
According to the coroner...
It was between 11:00 AM and 1:00 PM today.
Sunflowers, huh?
Hiroko-san loved these flowers.
Hey, you!
You saw the culprit, right?
What kind of person was it?
The person that did such a thing to her...
Just what kind of a person were they!?
Hiroko-san ran a bar called "Sunflower."
I've gone there often.
Sunflower?
Yes.
Thrusting its chest out to the sun that beats down on it...
Upon seeing its image, she would be able to
gather the strength and courage to carry on.
As a result, that's the legacy of the shop's namesake.
And, when I went there yesterday...
She said happiness had finally come to her.
Inoue Hiroko (38)
"Sunflower" Bar Proprietor
She was already really overjoyed.
Cheers!
What did she mean, "happiness had finally come"?
Well...
Takaokda-san over there was Hiroko-san's lover.
He's worked on directing independent films for the past seven years.
And recently...
A large movie studio asked him to direct a film for them.
I hear the movie was to be themed after the "crying-sands" of
White Sands Beach, from his hometown in Fukushima Prefecture.
It seems he went there by himself last night to
do a preliminary inspection of the filming site.
Hiroko-san always believed in his talent...
Knowing his day would come, she had
been financially supporting him all along.
And just when those seven years of hard work had paid off...
It's really a heartbreaking blow.
Megure here.
The old woman at the cigarette shop across the
street has been tending to her shop all day, but...
She says she didn't see anyone go in or out of the
apartment complex around the estimated time of death.
Only that afterwards, an electronics shop employee went
into the complex with a large cardboard box, but...
It was quite a while after, at approximately 4:30.
It appears it would have nothing to do with the current case, then.
Continue to gather information.
The person next to Takaoka-san?
It's Kitzuka Osamu-san.
They're both coworkers at a part-time job.
He's the one who discovered the body, and called 110.
The one who discovered Hiroko-san was that person?
Not Takaoka-san?
Yeah.
He's hoping to become a scenario writer.
Kitzuka Osamu (35)
Scenario Writer Hopeful
Because Takaoka-san had asked if he could borrow some story
ideas from him, they arranged to meet in this room at 5:00.
The door was unlocked, so...
Hello!
It's Kitzuka!
Hiroko-san, has Takaoka come home yet?
Hiroko-san!
After receiving the report, we arrived at 5:20.
A little before that, Takaoka-san had arrived home.
He'd arrived about fifteen minutes later than the
appointed time due to being stuck in traffic.
Detective Takagi...
What about Kitzuka-san's alibi?
Yes, we've confirmed it.
He was at his part-time job as a deliveryman for Oogata Electronics.
From 11:00 to 1:00, he was in the storeroom conducting inventory.
Say, Kitzuka-san...
When you came to this apartment, the door wasn't locked, right?
Yeah, that's right.
Then, I wonder if Hiroko-san forgot to lock the door...
Because, usually, when women are home alone,
they lock the door as a safety precaution.
She did often forget to lock the door.
If only I had warned her more strongly...
This sort of thing wouldn't have happened.
A comedy program is the only one that's been circled in red.
I wonder if it was so she wouldn't forget.
Did she like comedy programs?
Dunno...
That might have been the case though.
It looks like she'd planned to watch
it today from 3:00 to 5:00 as well.
She wasn't even able to watch her favorite television program...
A random crime?
No, something's off.
Inspector!
How was it?
Yes, sir.
Here it is.
What's that a photograph of?
We asked for Takaoka-san's alibi from 11:00
to 1:00, when Hiroko-san was murdered...
He was in Fukushima, right?
At the filming site.
Yeah, at White Sands Beach.
But, he said he didn't see anyone else there.
I see...
So his alibi cannot be substantiated.
He mentioned that he withdrew some money at a nearby bank...
And through the White Sands Police Station,
we confirmed that with this photograph.
I was recorded on a security camera?
Yeah, looks that way.
I'd always felt uneasy around them because
I felt like I was being watched, but...
I guess this time I should be grateful for the security cameras.
Takaoka-san, it's not that we're suspecting you, but...
What happened after you went back to the hotel last night?
Did you meet with anyone?
No, no one at all.
You didn't, huh...
Oh, that's right.
At some point after midnight, I had room service come to my room.
I've got it.
Why don't I take this chance to detail
all of my movement from yesterday?
We usually use this in meetings with the cameramen.
As far as putting this down as a random crime, something's strange.
Sunflowers.
I see, this is what was bothering me.
And also, the empty video case.
At 5:00 last night, I separated from Hiroko in front of the store.
That's right.
It was right when I had come to the shop.
Hey, don't loiter around touching that stuff!
Yes, sir!
This plug was probably...
I gave an interview at a newspaper company in
Fukushima a little past 10:00, if I remember correctly.
These are the business cards of the
cameraman and the reporter I met with.
These weren't removed in the normal way.
Did the culprit kick them out of the way...
Or was it...
What's this?
I checked out from the hotel the next
morning, at a little past 8:00 today.
These are...
The voucher and the receipt, huh?
At 2:27 in the morning, and the order was curry.
Takaoka-san's signature is also present.
In short, his alibi for the night is also proven without a doubt.
I knew it, so that's how it was!
And then, the bank's security camera caught me at a little past 12:00.
In other words, from last night to a little past noon today,
you didn't set one foot outside of Fukushima, correct?
Yes.
It's perfect!
A beautiful alibi with no flaws or time left unaccounted for!
Don't do that, Conan-kun!
You can't just go around touching things!
Oh, sorry!
But perfect timing!
I forgot that Uncle Kogorou asked for some things.
He said he wanted these investigated.
Investigated?
The inside of Hiroko-san's bag and her shoes?
He said they were important in determining who the
culprit is, so it was an extremely urgent request.
Mouri-san, here are the things you requested.
I didn't...
But, earlier, Conan-kun...
Takagi-kun, where have you been?
Prepare an investigation headquarters for me.
We need to take a look at the modus operandi
of each known burglar and look for witnesses.
Takaoka-san...
You've probably had the strength drained from you, but...
Please, in memory of Hiroko-san as well as for your own sake,
pull yourself together quickly and create a great work of art.
Mouri-kun!
Mouri-san?
Inspector, through Detective Takagi's efforts,
a number of true facts have been confirmed.
True facts?
Yes.
By the way, Kitzuka-san...
Could you please take a look inside the video appliance for me?
All right.
There's a tape inside, right?
Yes.
I wonder what had been recorded.
Could you please rewind it a bit and play it back?
One, two.
Oh, isn't this a rerun?
I watched this program.
It was about a month ago...
Huh?
The overturned chair leg caught on the
cord, and unplugged it from the outlet.
Probably during the struggle with the culprit.
But, the fact that it had been recorded up until there...
The culprit didn't know that Hiroko-san had been recording it.
It had been cut off about 3/4ths of the way into the 2-hour special.
It started recording at 3:00, and was cut off an hour and a half later.
That means the room was thrown into disarray at approximately 4:30...
Which is not the same time at which the murder took place, then?
Thinking the culprit murdered Hiroko-san during the day, and then
returned here again in the evening to rummage around for something...
It's a bit hard to imagine that being the case.
The culprit murdered Hiroko-san between 11:00 and 1:00 at
a separate location, and after transporting her body here...
Threw the room into disarray in order to make
it appear as if it was all the result of a robbery.
Detective Takagi, if you could give the thing you found to the Inspector.
Yes.
Inspector, this is it.
It looks like ordinary sand.
That was found at the rear of Hiroko-san's shoe, underneath the insole.
What?
I had the crime scene investigator research it and
he said it was something called "crying sand".
Crying sand?
Yes.
With a high composition of quartz, a rare type
of sand that only exists at unpolluted beaches.
There are twenty such beaches in the entire country.
One of them is White Sands Beach in Fukushima Prefecture.
In addition, it is the beach at which
Takaoka-san was location hunting yesterday.
Takaoka-san, perhaps you telephoned Hiroko-san last night.
Likely saying something akin to...
"I've finished location hunting, so how about you come over
here to Fukushima so we can spend some time together?"
Accordingly, Hiroko-san set up her recorder to record
the comedy program she had wanted to watch...
And headed to Fukushima early this morning.
The meeting time was after 12:00...
Right after you showed yourself to the bank's security camera.
Hiroko-san got to the beach first.
Because it was the beach which was to become
the stage for the film her lover was to direct...
She probably had some special feelings for it.
But...
The White Sands Beach is in your hometown.
You were very familiar with the times
at which no one would be around.
After that, you quickly took off in your car and came
back to the area around this apartment complex.
You parked in a place where there were unlikely to be any witnesses...
And, after dressing as a deliveryman, delivered the cardboard
appliance box containing the body to this apartment.
And so the electronics shop employee that was witnessed at 4:30...
Takaoka-san, you disguised using the uniform and hat
from the company you work part-time for, right?
Mouri-san, please stop that kind of talk.
I didn't think that just because I was silently listening
to your story that I'd be taken to be the culprit.
Excuse me for a moment!
Hey, Takagi-kun!
Where are you—?
It appears he just remembered something
else I had asked him to investigate.
Well then, allow me to continue my explanation.
Having transported Hiroko-san here...
In order to make the scene look as if she had been murdered during
the struggle with the burglar, you threw the room into disarray.
Then, you disposed of the cardboard box,
the hat, and the uniform somewhere.
Then, saying that you had been caught in traffic, you purposely
showed up later than the meeting time with Kitzuka-san.
Hiroko...
Hiroko!
Doing so, you made it seem as if
Hiroko-san was murdered in this room...
So that you could fabricate your alibi of having
been in Fukushima at the time of the crime.
Ridiculous.
Mouri-san, your deduction is that I called
Hiroko-san to White Sands Beach...
And then that I murdered her there between 11:00 and 1:00...
You seem to be under the impression that's right.
But, there really isn't any evidence that Hiroko went there.
But there is.
Inspector, please look inside the envelope
that Detective Takagi brought here.
Is this it?
It's an article from this morning's issue
of the Fukushima daily newspaper.
Probably from the interview he gave yesterday
That newspaper clipping was inside the pocket of Hiroko-san's bag.
After she arrived in Fukushima, Hiroko san had bought a newspaper
since she knew that you had given an interview yesterday.
It was just a brief mention, but since it was about you...
To Hiroko-san, it was the top news of the day,
more important than any of the other articles.
It was a reward for her unwavering support these many years.
The flower bud had fully opened; the large sunflower had blossomed...
She probably treasured it with dancing emotions.
No, that's not it.
Hiroko never came!
I bought the Fukushima newspaper.
And then I cut it out and put it in her bag...
Takaoka-san...
Have you ever looked closely at the words
written on that picture on the wall?
"Gazing only at you"...
In the language of flowers, that is what sunflowers represent.
And that was Hiroko-san's everything.
Takaoka-san...
How about if you admit your crime, and atone for what you've done?
That's absurd!
I did not murder Hiroko!
Oh, Takagi-kun?
What's going on?
What?
Inspector, please take a look!
I'm sending you the image.
It looks to be sand, doesn't it?
White sand.
That's a lie!
There shouldn't be anything like that there!
I made sure that the blanket—
"Made sure that the blanket" what?
What were you going to say after that?
"Was rid of all the sand," perhaps?
It's just a trace amount, but there is still some under the blanket.
Takaoka-san, that sand is probably the
same as the aforementioned crying sand.
Please explain why there is some remaining in the trunk of your car.
Are you still saying that?
That you really want to break up with me?
Is it because your luck has turned?
Is that it?
Don't say it's that simple!
I feel bad about it.
It's not a joke!
Do you know just how much I've
suffered through purely for your sake?
And now you're going to treat me as a burden?
I'll have you return the favor to me.
For the rest of your life.
There was a spare key in Hiroko-san's bag.
I borrowed it for a moment.
I knew...
That Hiroko had intended to have me support her from now on.
For me to be bound to her my entire life...
I knew I had to protect my independence somehow.
By the way, Mouri-san...
Your guesswork was amazing.
You saw through my trick by sheer chance.
Takaoka-san, take a look at the
potted sunflower on the floor there.
Do you feel anything?
I don't know how it was in Fukushima, but in this town
there were no clouds—it was a beautiful Japanese day.
And so what of it?
This room faces south.
Additionally, the curtains were pulled back, so
there was absolutely nothing to block the sunlight.
If that potted plant had fallen between
11:00 and 1:00, the time of death...
During the time from then until 5:00, when Kitzuka-san discovered the
body, the sunflowers would have been exposed to plenty of sunlight.
Sunlight is energy for sunflowers to bloom
in, so naturally the flowers would...
But here...
The flowers were face down, weren't they?
Because of that, I surmised that the potted flowers were toppled
much later, perhaps right before the body was discovered.
As such, I revised my reasoning accordingly.
I see, you figured it out well.
But Mouri-san, there is one flaw.
It was after everything was over, and I was leaving...
That those sunflowers...
Well, it was probably due to some sort of chance
that the dirt inside had become unbalanced.
I never laid one finger on them.
No, it seems he said that, but...
I think you fell in order to make the truth known.
That's right.
You were the flower that had fallen from Hiroko-san's fruit.
Does Uncle have a customer?
I'm thinking it's like that.
But what do you think?
The sunflower is his captive audience...