The light of summer is the radiance of yesterday.
After the tears lies the legend of the mountain witch.
The Detective Boys Have found themselves lost
where the mountain witch is said to dwell!
It definitely seems something's
going to happen tonight!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
ROAD
CLOSED
It's a dead end.
Again?
The seventeenth one.
It's hard figuring out the roads around here.
There are a lot of forks and dead ends that aren't on the map...
That's why I told you to not to do it!
When you said you were going to avoid traffic by taking a side road...
Traffic and heat are a cool engine's biggest enemies!
I thought that, even if we did get lost, we could
just use the GPS on our cell phones...
Yet never expecting that this would be out of the service area.
Why don't you have a GPS installed in your car?
If you did, it could tell us which way to go!
I'm hungry!
Car-mounted GPS systems are still being developed...
They'll really be something when they're perfected!
Fully loaded with all kinds of neat functions, they'll be amazing!
If they ever are perfected.
Anyway, let's head back.
If we keep going, we may be able to find
our way back into the service area.
Or at the very least meet some other cars or people.
Guess you're right.
Geez, it's so hard to figure these places out.
This is bad.
It's completely punctured.
Did you bring a spare tire?
I just exchanged these tires out for new ones...
So I never expected to end up with a flat...
On top of that, we had too much baggage, so if I didn't
take the spare tire out, we couldn't have fit everything.
Geez, the sun's already completely set,
and we don't know where we are.
That being the case, I guess we'll have to camp here.
What do you mean, "Eh"?
We had originally planned to camp out anyway...
And we already have all the camping equipment.
But, this mountain...
It's kinda creepy...
Like ghosts or monsters could come out...
Or even those creatures from the folktales...
Man-eating hags or mountain witches!
Mountain witches!?
Now, now...
There's no way those kinds of monsters actually exist.
But, if you're looking for a house that fits that image...
There's one over there.
Hey, could that be...
A mountain witch's house...
No way!
Idiots, as if that were even possible.
That's right!
Since it looks like a fairly big house, we should
see if they'll let us stay there for the night.
In that house?
But it's strange, isn't it?
Since I'm not seeing any other lights in the
area, it's probably the only house here.
That such a big house would be alone
here in these mountain recesses...
That's right...
It's almost as if it were beckoning us...
Saying, "Come here, come here!"
Anyway!
Shall we camp here, or shall we ask to stay in that house?
Make a decision!
What should we do?
Ayumi's scared!
But camping out here is dangerous too...
Let's go!
To the mountain witch's house!
Haibara-san and Ayumi-chan, I'll protect both of you with my life!
Thanks!
Then, does that mean you'll be eaten in my place?
Well, that's...
Not to mention, the mountain witch would probably think
Genta-kun would make a better meal, and be tastier.
You'd make a good soup too!
Are you guys morons?
All right everyone!
Carry your own things!
All right.
What a fine thatched-roof house!
It doesn't look much like a mountain witch's house, does it?
Let's go!
Because mountain witches seem like
they'd live in small, run-down hovels...
Yep, yep, and they hold kitchen knives in their hands...
A big kitchen cleaver, right?
Would that be...
This sort of kitchen knife?
It came!
The mountain witch!
Grandma, do you live in this house?
Yes, I do...
I wonder if you would let us stay for a night...
Our car got a flat tire!
A flat tire, in these parts?
Excuse us for the abrupt request...
We were headed to the campground
when we lost our way, you see...
And just as we were at a loss for what to
do, we happened upon your house...
Oh, is that so?
If that's the case, you should have said so earlier!
What's that kitchen knife for?
Well, I was cutting pickled vegetables in that
shed over there when I heard your voices...
Wondering who it could be in a place like this, I came out and heard
you all talking about what a mountain witch would be like, and...
We haven't seen lights from any other
nearby houses apart from yours.
This is the only house in this area.
All the people that used to live here left to live in town.
Well, we can't talk comfortably out here...
So if it's all right with you, do come inside.
Thank you very much!
Is there anyone else living here besides you?
No, it's just me.
But there's another pair of slippers left out...
Those slippers are my grandson Shouta's, who
left this house ten years ago to become a chef.
Tanaka Iwae (74)
It's just that I left them there from when he took them off.
If you want to use them, go ahead.
There are also many slippers over
there in that shoe cupboard.
Oh, no—I wasn't really asking with that intention...
Here you go, Ayumi-chan, Haibara-san!
I've got yours too, Conan!
Thank you.
Huh?
I wonder who this person is.
Dunno...
That's Shouta.
These past ten years, his letters have all been lacking and he's
never come back to visit me even once—a thoughtless child.
It seems that he's been gaining skill as a chef, though, because
he sends a large amount of money to me every month, but...
I haven't touched 1/1000th of a yen
of that thoughtless child's money!
Goldfish!
These are also my grandson's.
Leaving such troublesome things...
But those goldfish are quite large...
It's because they've been alive for over ten years now.
Are you fattening them up to eat them?
Eat this, eat that—Genta-kun, you're
no different from a mountain witch!
Right, Conan-kun?
What's wrong, Tsuburaya-kun?
Just now, from the gap in that door,
someone was looking this way...
Well now, just who could it be, at a place like this?
Hold on, Conan-kun!
Who are you guys, and what are you doing there?
Boy, is someone from this house here?
Yes, they are...
Can you call them over here for a bit?
What business do you have with me?
Oh, sorry, but...
We came to this mountain to go on a forest retreat, but...
Ooba Akane (25)
We got lost, and ended up running out of gas.
Adachi Raito (29)
If it's all right with you, could we sleep here for the night?
Kahara Fuuga (28)
Oh, we're not suspicious people or anything!
I'm Kahara Fuuga!
I'm Ooba Akane
I'm Adachi Raito.
I work in the service industry in Tokyo.
And I'm one of his customers!
Could you please let us stay for just the night?
I'll let you stay for tonight.
You're a lifesaver!
But, I won't have you cross
this threshold a second time.
What a bitch!
She certainly doesn't seem very welcoming.
Whatever, I really didn't want to ask to stay here in the first place.
Now, now...
You all, don't just stand there.
Take a seat over there!
Yes, ma'am.
Wouldn't want to harm the mood any further, so...
All because Fuuga got lost!
So sorry, Milady!
Well, at any rate, let's go inside.
Hosts?
You two are hosts?
Yeah!
Right now, I'm the number two in our
shop, and Raito-san is number one!
It's all thanks to the patronage from milady.
Hey, look, look!
Goldfish!
Aren't they super cute?
Oh, there sure are a lot.
Oh, it's a Tamasaba!
Tamasaba?
See, it's this one!
The one with a body that looks like a
ryukin, and a tail like that of a mackerel!
Out of these twelve, its the only one of a
variety that you don't get to see very often!
Amazing, Fuuga sure knows a lot about them!
It's because I used to have goldfish!
What a stinker!
Well, for me, it's rocks.
The ones placed on the right side are quartz...
The speckled rocks next to them are mica...
And then the shiny black ones on this left side are
obsidian, which were used in the Joumon period.
Amazing, amazing!
You're both super geniuses!
Rather than geniuses, wouldn't they just
be called knowledgeable, in this case?
She's calculating.
Doing that and acting dumb so that the men can feel
good about themselves and make a fuss over her...
A type of woman that'll ruin a man.
Oh, really?
Yeah, it's true!
Uhm, excuse me...
If it's all right with you, could I borrow your kitchen?
The kitchen?
Actually, I had planned to do some rudimentary
cooking with these children at the campground...
So we brought ingredients for curry and such.
I'm hungry!
Since it's a simple dish, I was thinking I could prepare it...
There's no need for men to be in the kitchen!
If it's just curry, I can make it as long as you have the ingredients.
My, sorry to trouble you.
Ayumi will help!
It's not a matter children need to concern themselves with.
Sit down.
Yes, ma'am...
I've never prepared food, so...
If it's just curry, I can make it myself.
After all, it's something I often made in the past for my grandson.
Where are the ingredients?
They're in that bag there.
What a large bag...
I was wondering what he'd brought along.
Grandma's curry was delicious, wasn't it?
Genta-kun will be happy as long as he gets to eat, huh?
But it really was delicious!
It was, wasn't it?
The children will use the room on
the right side of that dead end.
Yes, ma'am!
Sorry for the trouble!
Then, the menfolk will use the room
on the left side of this dead end.
You will use this room!
I want to be in the same room as the two of them.
Males and females seven years old and
above shall not be behind the same doors!
Huh?
Is that some sort of incantation?
What are you saying—you're a young, unmarried woman!
It's improper!
What does that mean, it's "improper"?
We're seven years old...
Is it still all right to stay in the same room?
Ayumi's not married either...
What's that noise?
It's coming from here.
I think this is the kitchen.
What is it, Mitsuhiko?
It's not even 4 AM yet.
Please... run away...
Hurry... we must...
If we don't, we'll be killed!
That voice just now...
It was that young woman, wasn't it?
It came from outside!
Hey, Milady!
Milady!
What's wrong, Akane-san?
Akane-san!
What was that sound?
What's going on?
Akane-san...
Akane-san!
An ambulance and the police!
Hurry!
Got it!
Akane-san!
Raito-san...
Fuuga...
In any case, bring her inside.
Oh, that's right, huh?
It's no use.
Her carotid artery has been slashed with a sharp weapon...
She's lost too much blood.
It's too late then...
Hey, kid—don't say such things!
Fuuga...
I can't believe it.
The sharp weapon?
Normally, it'd be a blade.
Like a knife or a kitchen knife.
But who, and why at this hour...
And with what sort of blade...
In these mountain recesses...
Mountain recesses, and blades...
Could it be...
The mountain witch...
The police and ambulance will both be here in an hour.
Hey, hey...
What's wrong, Mitsuhiko-kun?
No...
I don't suppose you could be thinking that I'm a mountain witch?
Oh, grandma.
Would it be all right for me to use the washroom?
I don't mind.
As you can imagine, I'd like to get rid of this blood...
Let's see...
For the washroom, you go out those shoji doors and
it's at the dead end when you turn right at the stairs.
Right after the kitchen.
Kitchen?
Then, putting together what you all said...
This morning, at approximately 3:58 AM...
You suddenly heard a woman's scream
and when you went out to take a look...
You found this woman with her neck slashed, correct?
Yes.
Let me see.
The victim's name was Ooba Akane-san, 25 years of age.
She was a loan company president's daughter, right?
Yes, that's right.
And so, from what you've said...
When everyone got to the scene, there was
already someone there next to her...
That was me.
Would you be the culprit?
Oh, no.
When I heard her scream, I was on the first
floor in order to use the restroom...
So I got to the scene before everyone
who came from the second floor.
Then, at that time, did you see anyone suspicious there or anything?
No, nothing in particular.
It was still quite dark, and I was more
concerned with her, who had collapsed...
By the way, your name is?
Adachi Raito.
Adachi Raito-san?
Then, you are?
Kahara Fuuga.
Kahara Fuuga-san, and...
If I remember correctly, this house was Yamada-san's...
Tanaka!
This is the Tanaka house.
I am Tanaka Iwae, who reported the crime to you all.
Sorry—that's right, that's right.
The name of the person who reported the crime
is indeed somewhere in my memo book...
Is he really all right?
Well then...
It occurs to me to ask why Adachi-san and
Kahara-san are here in Tanaka-san's house...
And also, how you're related to the victim...
She was a customer at the shop that Fuuga and I work at...
Milady Akane said she wanted to go on
a forest retreat, so we drove her here.
We're just your ordinary hosts.
Hosts?
Yeah.
Yesterday, he got lost on the road, and we ran out of gas.
Last night, we were give permission to
stay the night in Tanaka-san's home.
Let's see...
Tanaka-san, as far as your family members.
There are none.
Since my grandson left ten years ago, it's just been me.
Then, for you all, is it the same as usual?
The same as those guys over there.
On the way to the campground, we got lost
and on top of that our car got a flat tire.
And then we asked grandma if we could stay here!
We got here a bit before those people.
Then it's the same as usual, you've found
yourself involved in a case, huh?
Well, it appears that way.
Ran out of gas, and a flat tire.
Let's see, Conan-kun, was it?
Honestly, you should get exorcised or something!
Because there's no doubt you have some
sort of sinister thing possessing you.
Anyway, do you have any clue as
far as the culprit is concerned?
Well, about that...
Even though it was raining at the time of the crime, there were no
footprints around the house except for in front of the entrance.
The weapon hasn't been found...
And to make matters worse, no one
witnessed any suspicious characters, so...
The culprit and the weapon...
Would still have to be in this house!
Hold on...
You couldn't be suspecting us, could you?
There's no helping it.
We were the ones who brought her here after all.
No way...
Of course, it doesn't mean we are just
suspecting the two of you, but...
We'll have to conduct a thorough police interview
with each of you, one by one, about the incident.
First, the one to discover the body, Adachi Raito-san...
That's just the name I use at the shop...
This isn't funny!
A thorough police interview...
How are you going to treat us like criminals even without evidence!?
It's not necessarily that we're treating you like criminals, but...
Hey, Fuuga!
Until some evidence or the weapon presents
itself, you won't get one word from me!
That's fine, but with that attitude you're
not giving off a good impression...
A saw, a knife, a wide-bladed hatchet, and two kitchen knives...
Agasa-san!
Why did you bring such a large quantity of weapons with you?
It's to be expected!
Since we came intending to camp...
Let's see...
You two really don't have anything on you, huh?
Right.
We just underwent a body search as well.
And then, in this house there are three kitchen
knives, a hoe, a sickle, an axe, and scissors.
Is this really all?
The only thing left is my grandson's
toolbox that's locked up in the shed...
But I'd imagine they're all rusted by now.
That's a lie!
What is?
I saw it this morning!
While I was on the way back to the room from
the restroom, I noticed a strange sound...
It was coming from the kitchen...
And when I peered in...
This old woman was...
Was...
Sharpening a kitchen knife!
While her hair moved to and fro...
A kitchen cleaver with a deep red handle...
With a demonic expression on her face!