Is that true!?
Is it?
It's true.
Then...
There's no kitchen cleaver with a deep red handle here, is there?
Right.
And that's the situation we find ourselves in...
Well, I don't know anything about a kitchen cleaver with a red handle.
You were probably led astray because you wanted to see me as a
mountain witch, and that's why you witnessed such an illusion.
But, I'm certain, with my own eyes...
Anyway!
We will now thoroughly search this house, so...
If everyone would stand by in a back room!
Come on, we're going, Yoshida-san.
Huh?
That's strange...
What's strange?
The hammer for pounding in the tent pegs is gone.
The hammer?
That bag was left unattended in the hallway, wasn't it?
Could it be that the culprit used it...
Don't be stupid.
A hammer can't cut a person's neck.
That's right, huh?
I'll go and ask the detectives.
Ayumi too!
Well, as far as a hammer, we found one in the forest near here.
A fairly new one.
Really?
Then you should investigate it!
Because the culprit may have used it!
But hammers aren't blades, you know?
What's wrong?
Say, have you investigated that box?
No, we haven't yet got to the boxes in this area...
Hey, kid!
Hey, isn't this a kitchen knife!?
A kitchen knife with a red handle.
Was this the one Mitsuhiko saw?
It's been very well maintained, and there
aren't any nicks or scratches on it at all.
Below the knife maker's signature, a name...
Shouta?
Shouta was, if I remember correctly,
that old woman's grandson...
No reaction?
There was no reaction to the luminol?
Yeah, not from the cutlery from this house...
Nor from the camp tools you all brought.
Of course, even from that kitchen knife
with the red handle, there were no traces.
Even though you went through all that trouble to find it...
It's too bad, huh?
I see.
Of course that's how it was.
By the way, you all...
Did you play in the mud or anything?
Play in the mud?
We found traces of multiple people from this
household having walked around with muddy feet...
Muddy footprints?
Moving the body without permission,
walking around with muddy feet...
Geez, it makes it hard for us, you know?
Hold on...
Speaking of muddy feet, if I remember correctly, at that time...
I understand!
Grandma's feet were bare.
Fuuga's feet were as well.
I also ran out with bare feet.
That Raito person...
Raito-san!
Fuuga!
Was wearing shoes!
Hey, look here!
What are you doing?
Because!
The goldfish are thirsty, so I felt sorry for them!
See, last night the water in this tank
was filled up to this mark, but...
It's a lot lower now.
That means the goldfish felt hot, and drank a lot of water, right?
I see...
That's why the culprit took the hammer...
That's why Ayumi got water from the tap...
You can't do that, Ayumi-chan.
If you put that water in which hasn't had the chlorine extracted...
It'll actually be bad for the goldfish.
Plus...
Since the goldfish are expending so
much energy to keep watch over it...
You shouldn't disturb the water.
Keeping watch?
Yeah.
The weapon which has been in use since
ancient times, over its location, that is!
Let's see!
From the results...
The weapons in this house, or in other words the weapons
owned by you all, all show no luminol reaction...
That is to say, there is no trace at all of
blood having been on any of them.
Additionally, after everyone rushed to the scene...
Which is after Ooba Akane-san had the carotid artery
in her neck slashed with a blade and screamed...
No one left this house, and based on that...
It means that it's impossible to have left with the weapon, so...
Everyone is innocent!
That's what it comes down to.
Then, in that case, we won't have to
undergo the police interview either, right?
No...
For further investigation, we'd like to hear
everyone's stories, so we'd like to consult with you...
If we could trouble you all to come to the station at a later date...
Well, if I'll only be used as a reference, I'm fine with it!
Uhm...
What happened as far as the kitchen knife?
As for that, Conan-kun found it for us
in a box made of paulownia wood.
As to why you kept silent about that kitchen knife...
We'll ask you about it in detail at the station.
I just forgot about it!
After all, I am getting on in years.
But then, how did the culprit escape?
There weren't any weird footprints left around the
house except for in front of the entrance, right?
Well, that'd be...
I'm thinking it's quite certain the culprit used some sort of trick...
No, no.
It's quite natural that there were no footprints.
Because both the culprit and the weapon are still inside this house!
What?
Hey, if you're gonna use my voice, at least tell me before you start!
You surprised me!
Sorry.
Uhm, if I could have a word...
We police have searched this house thoroughly and found
nothing, so where would you say the weapon is hidden?
It wasn't that you haven't found it.
It's that you haven't searched for it yet.
That's because that weapon...
Was an object the culprit made by changing the shape
of something originally from this house into a blade.
In appearance, it looks nothing like a weapon.
Changed the shape?
Something originally from this house?
Please hold on!
If you're talking about something that was
originally in this house having been used...
Then that means the culprit is someone
who's familiar with this house...
Which means the culprit really was the inhabitant
of this house, that old woman, after all!
No, no.
As far as someone that's lived in this house for nearly
twenty years, there's one other person here.
One of these people?
Isn't that right?
The grandson of this old woman...
Kahara Fuuga-san?
Hey, Fuuga, is that true?
That's ridiculous!
That reminds me, you...
When you were asked where the washroom was in
this house, you replied immediately, didn't you?
I remembered!
Because I used it last night!
Then, why did you say those words?
Those words?
Right?
You said it when you guys first came to this house.
"Boy, is someone from this house here?"
That means you knew that I wasn't one
of the children from this house, right?
Oh, no, that was...
Is that true?
Actually, I was asked by that grandson guy...
To come and check up on his grandmother that he
hadn't seen in a while, to see if she was doing well...
That's when I heard that the old woman was living alone.
If that's the case, how come you knew about the goldfish?
The goldfish?
You said it, right?
That, "Out of these twelve, the Tamasaba is the only
one of a variety that you don't get to see very often."
Well, I said it, didn't I?
That I used to have goldfish!
As far as what variety of goldfish it is, I'd know just by seeing it!
No, not the variety...
The number.
The number?
No matter how much you know about goldfish...
To know at a glance that there are twelve
of them swimming around in the tank...
No one would know except for the
person who owns the goldfish, right?
I see.
That's certainly true, isn't it?
No, that's not it.
I...
Then, could it be that getting lost, running
out of gas, and coming here was...
Yeah, probably.
He did it on purpose to check up on his grandmother.
Having undergone cosmetic surgery for his face,
he thought that he wouldn't be found out.
I see, I see.
Which means...
The reason why you were extremely reluctant
to undergo police questioning was because...
You were the culprit, isn't that right!?
No!
I didn't do it!
It wasn't me!
No, it was to hide his real name.
Real name?
Raito-san, you were about to say something
when Fuuga-san got all riled up, right?
Yeah...
I was going to say what my real name was...
Because Adachi Raito is a name that I am known by at the store.
So it's a professional name, is it?
Then, your name is as well?
That's how it was.
And in order to break that line of questioning, he got
all riled up about having to undergo questioning.
What Fuuga-san wanted to hide was...
The fact that he was in fact Tanaka Iwae's grandson, Tanaka Shouta.
So if you're saying it was because he wanted to hide
his real name, then Fuuga-san is not the culprit?
Yeah, that's right.
But earlier, you said that the culprit skillfully
used something from this house, didn't you?
That's because even if one isn't familiar with this house...
It's an object that, as long as one recognizes what
it is upon sight, it can be utilized as a weapon.
If you use that certain thing and the
hammer that was stolen from me.
The hammer?
Now, wasn't Ayumi-chan worried about it?
Ayumi was?
You were wondering if the reason the water level in the fish tank had
dropped since last night was due to the goldfish drinking the water.
But, in actuality, it wasn't because of that.
Then that means that something was
taken out from the fish tank, right?
Then, what is that "something"?
It's something that, in the distant past, in the Joumon Era...
Was often used as a weapon...
Obsidian!
Obsidian, you say?
That's right.
If you break it apart, you'll end up with
fairly sharp blade-like fragments.
The culprit used that, and cut through Akane-san's neck.
What's that?
Obsidian into a blade?
Le's see, and then?
What was used to break it apart was my hammer.
The place it was broken apart was in the forest
where my hammer was reportedly found...
In order for no one to be able to hear the loud
noise produced when breaking it apart.
The culprit likely made the weapon last night
sometime, before the rain began to fall.
That's why there were no footprints left behind.
I see.
And so, who was it?
The person who did all that, the murderer?
That would be the person who looked at the rocks in the
fish tank and immediately identified them as obsidian...
Adachi Raito-san.
It has to be you!
Please hold on a second...
To say I'm the culprit because I'm familiar with rocks...
That the rocks were obsidian...
This old woman, and her apparent grandson
Fuuga, would both know that as well!
So why would you say it was me?
What first drew my attention to you was...
Your shoes.
My shoes?
When hearing the scream of a woman familiar to you coming
from outside, and then while rushing to the scene...
Do you think there would be anyone
who would put their shoes on first?
Putting on shoes requires time.
In a case where the entrance is not level with
the rest of the house, like in this house...
You'd have to first find your own shoes, place
your feet in, and then slip your heels inside.
In that sort of situation, one wouldn't put on their shoes, but would
rush to the door to check on the situation in their bare feet.
Like Conan-kun, the old woman, and the grandson did.
But, not only did you have your high-top shoes on
firmly, you also had your shoelaces properly tied.
In short, you didn't rush to the scene...
You were there in the first place.
And that indicates you murdered Akane-san!
I understand how that's suspicious, but...
To know for sure that he's the culprit
just because he had his shoes on...
I said it before, didn't I?
That the shoes were just what drew my attention to Raito-san.
Drew your attention?
The deciding factor was the hammer.
The hammer...
But we still don't know who stole it...
In order to make the weapon, the old woman or the grandson
would have just used something that was originally in the house.
For example, something from the toolbox that was in the shed.
They wouldn't have lingered in the hallway, where
someone could have come out at any time...
To take a hammer from my bag.
I see, that's certainly true.
In such a situation, it would be easy to narrow down
the suspects to those who were related to the victim...
Something probably happened last night that
caused you to resolve to commit murder.
And then, this morning...
I don't know what excuse you used, but
you invited Akane-san outside with you.
And because she didn't hear any quarrelling voices nor any
suspicious sounds, Akane-san agreed and left her room.
You both made your way in the dark to the
entrance without anyone noticing...
Put on your shoes at the entrance, and were
about to go outside when something happened.
And what would that something be?
Perhaps, Akane-san, who had been obediently
following directions up until that point...
Noticed that it was raining outside and decided
that she didn't want to go outside, or...
It was the sound of Mitsuhiko-kun running up the stairs
that made him feel as if the situation took an abrupt turn.
How are you able to tell, to that extent?
If not for that, the incident wouldn't
have occurred in front of the entrance.
It shouldn't have been in the plan to murder her there.
Nervous, you decided to kill her there, and...
As if you had tripped into her, you dragged her outside...
And sliced her neck open with the weapon
you had hidden on you, killing her.
Afterward, you left Akane san's body
there, returned to the entrance...
And after opening the door, returned
once again to the body's side...
Sweeping Akane-san's remains up into your arms.
In order to make it look as if he had rushed
to the scene after hearing her scream...
He camouflaged the true nature of the crime scene.
It was because he had no way to hide the blood
that had gotten onto his clothes and his body.
Let's see, so...
Where, then, is the weapon?
If you haven't found it yet...
Then perhaps it's inside the fish tank.
Because before you went to the washroom, saying you
wanted to wash off her blood, you touched the fish tank.
That's likely when you put it inside.
Because you didn't have time to wipe it
off, they should still be on the stone...
Both Akane-san's blood, and your fingerprints!
Having had it explained like that...
How about it?
Yeah.
I felt bad...
For those goldfish, that is.
The goldfish?
Because, it really was.
In order to kill that sort of woman, I disturbed their home.
But why?
For you as a host, she was an important customer, wasn't she?
I had already planned to quit being a host very soon.
Since my parents had finally gotten enough money together
to repay the loan they had taken from her father's company.
But last night, that woman...
Oh, that debt?
It's being inflated to about three times as much.
When I recommended a stock to Raito-san's parents that
seemed like it'd go up, they went right along with it...
I wonder how their faces look now...
Since the president of the company that issued those
stocks was arrested and the stock price plunged...
But, I really should direct much of my gratitude toward God.
Because of this, Raito-san will be my manservant for life!
To break off from that woman who said those words...
Because I only became a host out of
necessity in order to repay that debt...
But as I had expected, it was an uphill battle.
I've always been an old-fashioned sort of man.
This sort of job where I served women is not who I am.
But, I never expected my way of being old-fashioned
would have extended to my choice of weapon.
If you could take care of the rest.
Yes, sir!
What about this kitchen knife with the red handle?
I'll take care of returning that.
Uhm, excuse me.
Could I please take a look at that?
I don't mind...
Thanks.
This is...
Hey, young man...
If you know my grandson, would you please tell him...
That he doesn't need to worry about me...
And that his own body...
His own body is the only thing he needs to take care of for me.
Yeah, I'll tell him that.
Instead of telling him that, could I...
Could I take this kitchen knife?
Because I'm sure he'd be delighted to receive it.
Yeah, please do so for me!
That old woman knew he was her grandson?
Yeah, probably.
It's likely why she hid that kitchen knife.
Because she'd planned to give it to her
grandson when he came back as a fine chef...
It was a precious kitchen knife that she sharpened every day.
But she really was sharpening it with a scary demonic face...
It's the same as the Hannya mask!
It's a scary face, but you can also see
how it's a sad face as well, right?
She must have been desperately sharpening it
while trying to hold together her broken heart.
Entrusting to that blade her faint hopes that her grandson...
Who had changed in both appearance and aspiration...
Could possibly return to his original path.
Because the light from the mountain witch's cutlery...
Is the light from the sad tears of the old
woman who thinks of her grandson.
A month later, at a Japanese restaurant I visited with Ran...
I saw a young chef being yelled at.
You're slow, Tanaka!
Haven't you filleted it yet?
Sorry!
A young chef with a face I recognized
was filleting fish with all his might...
Grasping tightly in his hand a kitchen knife with a red handle.
Eventually, he'll surely...
Conan-kun!
Conan-kun?
You're slow, Conan-kun!
Haven't you decided yet?
I thought she was a Hannya for a moment there...