The light of summer is the radiance of yesterday.
After the tears is the ramen shop owner.
Thought to exist, but actually doesn't...
The truth behind the police officer that vanished!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
This happened on the first Sunday of the month.
What is he doing?
Geez, he's slow...
Genta-kun!
Here! Hurry! Hurry!
What it is?
The news that you've been dying to tell us...
Did you guys watch the Saturday drama yesterday?
You mean "Run! The Running of 100 Police Officers," right?
That's right!
We watched it.
Is there something wrong with it?
I noticed this right away...
That drama must have been filmed in this Beika Park.
Seriously, who doesn't already know that?
Ayumi already knew.
Oh, really?
"The case happened in this park."
The main character shouted that cliche like it had
been said somewhere before over there, didn't he?
The flowers in the background hadn't blossomed yet...
Indicating that the filming was likely done at least half a month ago.
Don't tell me this was the big news you had for us, Genta-kun.
That's right...
I thought I was the only one who noticed it.
But that drama wasn't very good.
You're right.
Only the part with the groups of uniformed
officers running was actually funny.
Would you guys stop talking about the drama?
Miss!
Ayumi-chan, hello there.
Hello!
This is Akimoto Yasuyo-san.
Akimoto Yasuyo (24)
Office Lady
She lives on 3rd Street now, but...
She used to live in the apartment next to where I live.
Did you go shopping?
Oh, this?
This is a snack sent from my hometown.
I was going to give it to a police officer.
A police officer?
Even though I don't know his name...
He's a very hard-working person.
He even had a beard.
A beard?
I wanna see him too!
Right, Conan-kun?
Yeah.
There's no one like that?
No one has a beard and wears glasses?
No—not here, and no one like that at
the Beika Police Headquarters either.
But I saw him many times while he was patrolling.
But there really isn't someone like that...
What's going on exactly?
Strange...
What's happening?
As I thought...
I instantly recalled that uniformed police officers
aren't allowed to have noticeable facial hair.
In other words, that person is...
A fake.
Give me a break...
Don't just call me whenever you want!
But we have something to tell you, Detective Takagi.
Isn't a fake police officer an issue for police officers?
A fake police officer?
Someone who isn't a police officer and yet disguises as one...
To fake his identity in that way is definitely an unforgivable crime.
Akimoto-san, you saw that person many times, right?
Yes.
Because of work, I had to stay late every night last week.
I was home late every night, up to last night.
The first time I saw that police officer
was the very first night I stayed late...
That Monday night...
When I was walking towards 3rd Street,
where I live, after getting off the last train...
It's really dangerous for a young girl to be walking by herself at night.
Please be extremely careful.
After that, I saw him every night.
In other words, I saw that police officer every night that week.
Several days earlier, I saw him helping an elderly couple.
You shouldn't go out late at night, it's really dangerous.
My wife suddenly just had to have some cider.
Didn't you say you wanted to have some pudding?
Good evening!
Have a good night.
Last night, he was helping a drunk man get home.
Hey, pull yourself together...
Is your house still far away?
I can't.
I guess I'll call a taxi for you then.
I'll be fine aaalll by myself!
You won't be fine at all.
I'll help you up.
You're always having some kind of trouble, aren't you?
No, it's my responsibility.
Please have a safe journey home.
Right.
He seems like a good person.
I guess it's natural to believe he was real.
But, why did that person disguise as a police officer?
His intention...
Disguising as a policeman, he's likely aiming to do bad things.
Bad things, like what?
I'm not sure about that part yet...
Hi, this is...
There was a theft several days ago?
No, we haven't found the culprit yet...
From his methods, it seems like all the thefts from
this past week were done by the same person.
There were more thefts?
Isn't there somebody else that's seen that person before?
Such as that old couple and that drunken man?
That's right!
If we go ask them, we can probably find some clues.
Akimoto-san, do you know who they are?
I didn't recognize that drunken man, but the senior couple...
I've seen them many times at Tetsuryuu.
Tetsuryuu?
Odawara Tetsuji (33)
Ramen Shop Owner
Fake police officer?
He seems angry.
More like very angry.
I'm not angry at all.
Although this owner seems unsociable, his ramen is very delicious.
That's why I often eat here.
Look here!
It's true!
So this is the secret of the ramen shop.
You can't just touch anything you want!
Oh no!
Geez, Genta-kun.
It flew on my clothes.
I sent it flying?
Even though I haven't eaten yet, I smell like ramen.
Genta-kun!
I didn't do it on purpose.
Uhm, we came here to gather more
information on that fake police officer.
There's an old couple who seems to get along really
well with each other that seem to come here a lot.
Takayanagi-san?
I think they live...
Oh, that old couple.
Fake police officer?
You guys must have made a mistake, right
That's right.
That man is very nice and gentle.
Is that so?
He has a good reputation...
We're getting nowhere at this rate.
Who is he really?
Takagi-san...
Someone just called in.
There was a theft on 2nd Street last night.
Speaking of which, didn't you say
something about serial burglaries earlier?
Yes, sir.
I think I've figure out the identity of the fake police officer.
By patrolling, he can easily go inside the
residents' houses and commit thefts.
Which means...
He is a thief?
That possibility isn't entirely zero.
You're wrong!
I personally don't think he would do that.
Then, why else would he disguise as a police officer?
Wait, Arai-kun...
I think that the culprit is someone else.
At any rate, I'm going to the crime scene.
Excuse me.
I thought he was a good person.
Miss...
Humans are hard to trust.
Well, you go find that fake policeman.
What about you, Haibara-san?
I'll pass.
So the fake police officer is a thief.
Yeah, but this differs from what Akimoto
Yasuyo-san and the others described.
That's right.
Anyway, I'm going to find some witnesses
related to the fake officer and gather more clues.
You also need to investigate where that person got the police uniform.
You're right, that is a suspicious point.
Losing a uniform should've already gotten a lot of attention...
It might be hard to get a real uniform, but...
If it's a costume from a drama, then...
A costume from a drama?
That!
That?
The two hour drama that was broadcast last night...
Yes, "The Running of 100 Police Officers."
Those 100 uniforms that were used to film...
Would you have lost one?
While we were waiting for the TV station report...
We went to find more information about
the fake officer with a beard and glasses.
The result was...
That police officer appeared about a week ago...
Apparently, it began last Monday.
That was the first day Yasuyo-san worked late.
Oh, that's true...
No one saw the police officer during the day...
He always appears at night...
Around the time when the last train arrives at Beika Station.
What does that mean?
The times that he was seen...
Once at the station...
Five times on 2nd Street...
Three more times on 3rd Street...
If we connect these places together...
This is the route Yasuyo-san takes to go home on 3rd Street.
You're right!
In other words, the date, time, and place
that the fake police officer appears...
All have connections with Akimoto Yasuyo-san working late.
Correct.
Yasuyo-san also said it earlier, didn't she?
In other words, I saw that police officer every night that week.
Seeing him every night, isn't this too much of a coincidence?
So the fake policeman intentionally appears in front of Yasuyo-san?
I don't know what his intention is yet...
But if we think about it that way, then
the beard and glasses make sense.
I see, a disguise!
Which means that the fake police officer
is someone Akimoto Yasuyo-san knows.
That fake police officer is someone she knows?
Who is he then?
How am I supposed to know?
You don't know? How boring!
Hey, stop!
Again, Genta-kun!
I spilled it again?
Where's my handkerchief?
What's wrong?
You probably dropped it at that ramen shop.
I'm scared to go there by myself.
Then, let's all go together.
Right, Conan-kun?
Well, looks like he's out.
Yes?
Oh, Nichiuri TV?
What's wrong?
Yes...
Yeah.
He went out not long ago.
He probably went home to eat.
He lives near Beika Park.
What should we do?
Want to wait?
I found it!
Sorry.
Thank you very much.
There was one uniform they were unable to locate.
As I thought...
That fake officer must have stolen it
while they were filming in Beika Park.
Most likely...
It was a Sunday, half a month ago.
It was filmed on a Sunday half a month ago?
That's what they said.
Why?
That'd be the third Sunday of last month, right?
This shop was closed on that day as well.
That guy lives near Beika Park right?
Right.
He probably went to the filming scene during his break.
If a drama's being filmed near the park, they're likely to go.
That means he had the opportunity to lift one of the police outfits.
Since the fake police officer is someone near Yasuyo-san...
Conan-kun, could it be...
That person is the fake police officer?
Is that true?
But, why would that person...
Conan-kun?
Could it be...
So the owner chose this photo?
Yeah, he said to use this one if we wanted to use a photo.
This lady has a good expression.
That guy probably likes her so he chose her picture.
I see, so this is her...
That owner's name is Odawara Tetsuji...
Actually, he and I were high school classmates.
After the interview, both of us went drinking.
You already have someone you like!
But it's a one-sided love.
What's wrong?
I have a scary face...
Idiot, I already told you that you think about it too much.
It's fine...
I'm satisfied as long as I can stay by her side watching her.
You're really...
He doesn't really talk much, and he looks angry all the time.
Even though he seems unsocial, he's more
gentle and attentive than anyone.
At Tetsuryuu?
Yeah.
I talked about it with some acquaintances.
I have to work late for a whole
week at the end of the month.
What a bummer.
I don't feel safe having to take the last train home.
It was about half a month ago.
So they heard it then, that person...
Is there a problem?
The police officer you saw every
night is definitely not a thief after all.
You figured it out?
We only have circumstantial evidence right now.
We still need to ask the person involved later.
Upon hearing that the girl he cares about...
Would be going home late for an entire week...
He started to worry about her.
If possible, he wanted to secretly guard her, but...
He was afraid that his scary face...
Could cause some misunderstandings, so he gave up on the thought.
But not long afterward...
The case happened in this park!
He found a police uniform used in the filming.
He came up with an idea that would
allow him to guard Yasuyo-san...
He then disguised as a police officer and appeared in front of her.
It's really dangerous for a young girl to be walking by herself at night.
Please be extremely careful.
He's not back yet?
Where could he have gone?
He probably ran away.
No, that person probably...
Went to catch the real thief...
For Yasuyo-san, who deeply believes in him.
He can't do that, it's too dangerous!
Let's split up and look for him.
Hey, you guys!
It's impossible...
With no clues, how am I supposed to catch the culprit?
I'll be fine by myself...
Oh, that person from yesterday.
Even though I haven't eaten yet, I smell like ramen.
The smell on clothes?
He's not here.
Where'd he go?
Who are you?
Do you remember me?
We met last night.
Last night?
Sorry...
I was so drunk last night.
Certainly, your clothes did smell of alcohol...
But, that smell was only on your clothes.
The smell was not on your breath.
What are you talking about?
You acted that you were drunk and swayed while you walked...
So you could sneak into other people's houses, didn't you!?
Wait!
Wait, you thief!
Thief?
Wait!
I have some questions for you about the recent serial burglaries.
Got it.
Arai-kun, if you would.
Yes, sir.
You're Odawara Tetsuji-san, aren't you?
Yes.
Miss...
Why did you...
Akimoto-san...
This person...
Only wants to protect a young woman
walking home late at night.
In order to safely return her to her house,
he disguised as a police officer, right?
How did you know that?
What are you saying?
But, mister, it is absolutely forbidden to
disguise yourself as a police officer.
No matter the reason.
I trust you understand what Conan-kun just said.
You chose the wrong course of action.
Miss...
I will now place you under arrest on the charge
of impersonating a police officer and theft.
Let's go.
Uhm...
I'll continue to eat our ramen.
It's true!
Since the theft was his first offense...
And his intention in faking an identity wasn't to commit a crime...
Furthermore, taking into account his aid in catching the thief...
He was released immediately.
We gave him strict lectures, of course.
In other words, we scolded him for a while.
Sorry for the wait.
Thanks for the meal.
As adults, that man and woman are socially inept.
I bet those two wouldn't want you saying that.
What'd you say?