The light of summer is the radiance of yesterday.
In the aftermath of the tears lies a black photograph.
According to Hattori Heiji's clue,
the black photograph is very important.
Who could the person in the photograph be?
Perceiving the one and only truth,
With the body of a child and the brain of an adult,
His name is: Detective Conan!
G a h!
Why is it so hot like this?
Are you planning to pick a fight with Sonoko-sama's beautiful skin?
Really, and it's already past August.
With it like this, I should have gone straight
home where it's nice and cool like Eisuke-kun did.
Eh? Eisuke-niichan went straight home?
Yeah, he does that all the time now.
It's like he disappears when classes are over.
Could it be he likes some girl who works in
a store in the neighborhood or something?
That clumsy kid? You think he keeps going to visit with some girl?
It's true!
No, that's not it. Mostly likely that guy...
Has figured out that that woman is in a
hospital somewhere and is trying to find her.
Mizunashi Rena.
The partner of those black-clothed guys
who still hasn't regained consciousness.
She's being guarded by the FBI, so I don't think he could
discover the location of the hospital without some difficulty.
But I still don't know who Hondou Eisuke really is.
Oh, the phone.
Let's see, the one on the left side is for Conan, and the right...
Is Kudou Shinichi's.
Ah, Ran-neechan, I just remembered I had
something to do, so I'm going to head home before you.
Oh, OK.
Yes, hello.
Hey, how many times are you gonna make me call!?
Pick it up right away, idiot!
Eh, sorry, Hattori.
I have things going on here too.
So, did you find anything out?
Yeah.
I grabbed Ohtaki-han on his day off and asked him
to investigate. I said I couldn't tell him the reason yet.
He checked the Osaka school registries going back 20 years.
But there wasn't any student named Mizunashi Rena.
There wasn't anything to do but show that picture
of the woman who resembles her taken 10 years ago,
And ask around the Tsuutenkaku area
for information about the two in the picture.
Everyone knew she was now an announcer who's
taking a vacation, but no one knew her when she was young.
I see.
That's regarding her at least.
When we showed around the picture
of Hondou Eisuke you transferred to me,
We got a hit. There was someone who knew him when he was a kid.
R-Really?
Yeah, it seems there was an okonomiyaki shop near
Tsuutenkaku where he would always come to eat with his father.
Was his father a normal sort of person?
It seems he was kind of uncommunicative.
What I do know was that man's name was Hondou.
At least that's what he was called.
Was called?
Yeah, it seems he occasionally came in with his co-workers.
But he stopped coming abruptly a few years ago.
What kind of work did he do?
I don't know, but the current manager said
the previous manager might know something.
He said those two got along strangely well together.
They would talk together even after the shop had closed.
What did they talk about?
You went to see the previous manager, didn't you?
I couldn't go see him. He's no longer with us.
Oh, no. Could it be because those black-clothed guys...
No no, he died a natural death.
I heard it was cancer. I heard he was pretty old too.
So, this trail ends there then?
Nope, the game starts here.
That manager had a grandson he was really close to.
He may have told that grandson everything they talked about.
Grandson?
The grandson went to college in Osaka for 4 years.
He ate at the shop often, so he might have met that man.
So, where is that grandson now?
He works at a model store up by you.
I asked about the address and the phone number, but...
If you're going to question him, be careful.
That Hondou Eisuke's father isn't some ordinary person.
Among the co-workers he brought with, there were different
faces almost every day, and more than half were foreigners.
What's more, all of them, including the father, wore
black clothes, as if they had just ducked out of a funeral.
A-Are you sure about that?
Yeah, and I heard he really hated to be photographed.
So I have no idea what he looks like.
One more thing, every time his name came up, it was different.
Like Tsubouchi or Ishikawa. Hondou was just one of them.
I see. So being uncommunicative
was part of him being extremely cautious.
Yeah. So, if that grandson has met Hondou's father, it could be...
The grandson could be under surveillance.
What? You don't need dinner?
You're at the professor's?
OK, I got it.
Geez, that Conan-kun...
Huh? Come to think of it, where's Dad?
Eh? You want to go find out about Hondou Eisuke?
At this time?
Yeah, right now. To be precise, we going to
see someone who knew Hondou Eisuke's father.
Still, is this safe?
It's fine. I told Ran I was staying here tonight over the phone.
That's not what I meant. That person is
connected with those black-clothed guys.
That's why we have to hurry. If we wait,
she might hear what we're talking about.
And then she'll suggest coming with us.
'She'?
You know. She's in the bath now.
Ah, did you call me?
She's already out?
Ah, yes, the thing is, your grandfather
asked me for a favor when he was alive.
It was to give something to one of his
regular customers that he got along well with.
I have a pretty good idea who that
person is, but I just want to confirm it.
It's a really valuable object you see.
Ah, maybe you mean that customer
who came in all the time with his son.
Ah, th-that might be the one.
Do you know that person's name or where he worked or anything?
Well, I only met him two or three times.
Did he have any unique characteristics?
Because I have two or three people in mind.
I can't seem to remember anything right now.
Ah, in that case, would you like to see a photograph of him?
You have a photograph?
I had heard he really hated to have his picture taken.
Ah, that's right. However, I do have one that was taken by chance.
It seems his son must have been messing around with my camera.
W-Would it be all right if I came by now to see that photo?
Eh? Now?
Today's the day I go to the sports gym after I close
the shop at 7 o'clock, so I won't return home until 11.
I don't mind. I'll be waiting in front of your house.
Well, what the heck. I'll cancel going
to the gym and head home right away.
Are you sure?
Yeah, it's been a long time, and I'd
like to talk about my grandfather too.
Thank you very much.
That's strange, it's already past 8 o'clock when we promised to meet.
According to what he said, this is the place.
I'll go and check.
Haibara, you stay here.
Let's see, I think his room number was...
Number 302.
I thought I told you to stay in the car.
Maybe he's asleep.
Strange...
Yo.
What?
Professor!
I heard...
You'd be here...
Old man.
Ah, this is only a model I sell at my shop.
Hey, you had this joke played on you before, haven't you.
You're the one who called me earlier, aren't you?
Ah, yes.
Nishigun Souhei
Model Store Manager
If you were my grandfather's friend,
you must have known about this lousy gag.
My grandfather was an unrivalled gun-maniac and suspense fan.
He used to greet people like that a lot.
Ah, ah, that's right, he did.
You just completely surprised me.
I see. In order to do this, he waited until we
got impatient and came in to ring the door chimes.
Well now, who are these children?
Ah, they're my grandchildren. They made
me bring them with. I hope you don't mind.
Nope, that's fine.
It's a bit messy, but please come in.
Geez, it really is messy.
The slippers are scattered everywhere.
Excuse me but, may I use your toilet?
Please go ahead.
It's a bit warm, isn't it?
It was really hot and humid during the day.
So the heat's been trapped inside the apartment.
Let's see, I think the album was here on the top.
Huh? It's not here...
I'm pretty sure I put it here. What the...?
It's wet.
Is this water?
Damp tissues.
Hey, do you have the photo on that computer?
Huh? Oh, yeah.
I'm bringing it up, so wait just a second.
Huh?
The data's been erased. That's odd.
I don't remember erasing it.
What's going on?
Probably somebody snuck into this apartment.
And they were here until just a few minutes ago.
Someone snuck into my apartment? They were just here?
That can't be true.
There are several pieces of evidence. For example, the slippers.
The slippers in the entryway are all scattered about.
Please go ahead.
You just returned to this apartment after leaving work, but
the slippers in the toilet are the only ones neatly arranged.
So it seems likely that someone other than
you used the toilet in the meantime, doesn't it?
But I do arrange the slippers in the toilet sometimes.
Sometimes, right? But not every time without fail?
I-I guess not.
Then that's enough to become suspicious.
The next thing that caught my eye was...
These scattered drops of water on the floor.
Water?
See?
I can't really know just from looking, but seeing these
droplets around the desk and in front of the bookcase,
And with the wet tissues in the wastebasket...
I think these drops of water are likely to be from someone sweating.
Obviously, it's from the person who snuck in here.
What? Sweating?
You see? That person must have sweat a lot
in this stuffy room during the heat of the day.
They wiped it off and discarded it into the wastebasket.
And the sweat that fell probably came from when
they stopped to look around the bookcase and the desk.
But if it was that hot, wouldn't they have turned on the air conditioner?
Exactly! Whenever I'm away from home, I
always keep the lights on in the apartment,
And I always leave the remote
control for the air conditioner on the desk.
It would have been easy to notice.
Nope, they didn't dare to use the air conditioner.
Because if you came back and found the room
was pleasantly cool, I think you'd be suspicious.
And how long would it take for the cold room to return to
normal temperature once they turned off the air conditioner?
They couldn't know that for sure.
That's true.
And the conclusive evidence is the
small amount of heat this computer retained.
Even though you just turned it on, it's
strange that the CPU area is already so hot, isn't it?
Hey, could it be the thing they were after...
Yeah, I think it was probably the photograph.
The one we asked you to show us.
The photo that might show the person we are looking for.
The picture data on the PC was erased, and isn't
the album that should be on the bookshelf missing?
Incidentally, the reason I said the
person was here just a few minutes ago was...
In this hot and stuffy room, neither the droplets of sweat on the floor,
Nor the tissues used to wipe it off have dried yet.
From the surface area of the droplets and
the temperature and humidity of the room,
And since in this closed-up room, there was no air flowing,
Even the smell of the leftover food has been trapped, right?
So, guessing from the amount the sweat droplets have dried,
I'd say someone was here less than 10 minutes ago.
What the heck, kid? Who on earth are you?
Edogawa Conan, a detective.
D-Detective?
The problem is, how would anyone have gotten in?
From the way it looks, there's no sign the door was forced.
And there's nothing unusual about the
small window in the kitchen or its lock.
Then they must have broken in somewhere else in the apartment.
Ah, hey.
I'm going in this room.
Are there only these two rooms here?
Y-Yeah.
The curtains...
The window's open.
So that's where the culprit got in. Not very secure.
Nah, I always leave that window open like that.
I'm always making dioramas in this room.
When I paint and glue the parts and
make carvings, it can get bad in here.
So I figure I should always keep the air circulating.
What's more, look at the street below.
There are plenty of stores, and lots of people.
If someone tried to get in and out of here
using a rope, they'd be noticed right away.
It would be different if it where the
dead of the night, but it's still 9 o'clock.
Then I guess this isn't the place where they got in.
Yeah, it's be impossible from here.
What's more, wasn't it during broad daylight?
On the other hand, what's really bothering me is you guys.
You guys told me my grandfather entrusted you to return
something to a regular customer of the shop he used to have.
But when you came to my apartment to see the photograph,
All of a sudden this boy is pretending to be a detective
and searching around here and there. Isn't that a bit strange?
First of all, if you want to find that customer, shouldn't you
show them what you've been entrusted with and find out?
Tell them it's from my grandfather and ask if they recognize it or not.
Well, you see...
It's because...
It's a wallet. A big wallet with lots of money in it.
A-A wallet?
A wallet, eh?
Ah, that' right. It was a wallet.
It seems it had been left behind at the shop.
But when it's about money, some
people might say it's their's when it isn't.
I guess it can't be helped if it's a wallet.
Say, by the way, is there anyone who's had a spare key to this room?
There are. Three of them.
Who are they?
The first is my ex girlfriend, Saori. She used to come by here.
She was a really fun girl.
Come to think of it, she still hasn't returned my key.
The other two are my modeling friends, Tago and Furushou.
Those two always help me out when a diorama convention is coming.
I gave them a spare key so they could come and go whenever.
Those three are the only ones who
could get in this room without difficulty.
But none of the three are the type to break in here like a burglar.
Just in case, why don't you call them and
check. You can ask them what they did today.
H-Hey!
Edogawa-kun.
Shinichi, shouldn't we be calling the police now?
What if the people who broke in here were...
It wasn't those black-clothed guys.
It wouldn't be like them to leave so much evidence.
But weren't they in a hurry because the owner suddenly came home?
You know, he had planned to be at
the sports gym until 11 o'clock tonight.
Then he suddenly changed his plans.
If that was so, then when we were in the
entryway, someone would have been in the apartment.
Well, if there was a lookout, they could
have known he was coming home unexpectedly.
If they had left this much evidence,
they would have ambushed and killed him.
So why aren't we calling the police now?
If the police come, they would find it out under questioning.
That you aren't his grandfather's friend, and we'd be exposed.
Therefore, before we do that, we have to be
quick and figure out this case from that guy.
Then catch the culprit who broke into
this apartment and get it back from them.
The thing that's captured Hondou Eisuke's father - that photograph.
It's wet.
W-What did you say?
Right it front of our noses?
You mean they're in this apartment?
Ah, that's...
Right there!
No way.
C-Company?
Next Conan's Hint:
Washing Machine
Look forward to the next episode
Professor, what about the laundry?
I'm sorry, Ai-kun.
You too it?
Ah, it's in the dryer.