The light of summer is the radiance of yesterday.
In the aftermath of the tears lies the Company.
In the end our reasoning leads to a discovery.
In the black photograph linked to the
organization there's a unexpected person.
Perceiving the one and only truth,
With the body of a child and the brain of an adult,
His name is: Detective Conan!
I received information from Hattori that provided a white doorway
into the past of the mysterious transfer student Hondou Eisuke.
Accordingly, we visited the home of the manager of a
model shop to see a photograph that captured Eisuke's father.
However, the photograph in question has disappeared.
From the tracks left behind in the
apartment, I infer the actions of the intruder.
Say, by the way, is there anyone who's had a spare key to this room?
Nishigun Souhei
Model Store Manager
There are. Three of them.
Just in case, why don't you call them and
check. You can ask them what they did today.
H-Hey!
Edogawa-kun.
Shin'ichi, shouldn't we be calling the police now?
What if the people who broke in here were...
It wasn't those black-clothed guys.
It wouldn't be like them to leave so much evidence.
So why aren't we calling the police now?
If the police come, they would find it out under questioning.
That you aren't his grandfather's friend, and we'd be exposed.
Therefore, before we do that, we have to be
quick and figure out this case from that guy.
Then catch the culprit who broke into
this apartment and get it back from them.
The thing that's captured Hondou Eisuke's father - that photograph.
Ah, Saori-kun?
Nothing much... No real reason, I
was just wondering what you were up to.
Like what did you do today?
Huh? Why should I be telling my ex something like that?
Y-Yeah, that's right.
No big deal. I went out to buy some clothes and
stuff. I'm going out later on a date with my new boyfriend.
Really? That's great.
Yeah, we're having Italian at the Beika Hotel.
You should eat good food occasionally too, Souhei.
All you eat is cup ramen.
Y-Yeah.
And you should take proper baths. Got it?
Ah, yeah.
Well, my boyfriend will be here pretty soon, so don't call again, OK?
Sorry about that.
I wonder if I should really be doing this.
Just in case.
Eh? What did I do all day today?
Yeah.
Stuck in my apartment with a tank.
I've been making this tank. A Tiger-I. The contest is coming up.
I see. And so? Is it coming out good, Tago?
Yeah, it's perfect. The rust effect is really awesome.
I'll look forward to seeing it. Your
skills have gotten a lot better recently.
Ah, that's right, put the finishing
touches on your soldiers for me by tomorrow.
Because I want to see if they fit properly in my tank or not.
T-Tomorrow?
It's be great if you could paint them too.
Since it looks like I'm going to be busy starting the day after tomorrow.
Are you serious? I'd be up all night.
The dirty dishes and dirty clothes are piling up too.
What are you saying, do them when you get up! It's
already late at night and you'd bother the neighbors.
Ah, right.
If you like, I could come over in the morning
and do the washing and stuff while you're sleeping.
Oh, thanks! That would be a big help!
Ah, it looks like someone's here.
Well, see you tomorrow.
Delivery!
OK. I'm coming down now.
What? You've been laid up at home all day from a cold?
Hey, are you all right, Furushou?
Yeah, somehow. It's seems I've come down with a bad virus.
Nishigun-san, you should really clean your apartment too.
Y-Yeah.
Because your place is just as messy as my apartment.
Ah, right.
Speaking of viruses, please upgrade the
anti-virus software on your computer, OK?
Y-Yeah, it seems some nasty viruses are spreading these days.
Yeah, because if that picture we put up on your blog of
the diorama we created got erased or something, I'd cry.
But, something like a picture can just be retaken.
A diorama is alive!
If you do it again the feel of the materials
and the facial expressions will have changed!
OK, I got it, I got it! I always appreciate your photography skills.
Well, sleep tight and get over your cold.
OK, I got it. I'll upgrade
properly, so don't worry.
It's wet.
Is it sweat?
Do you remember how many slippers there are?
Nope, when I complete a diorama, I have a lot of
friends over and celebrate the work with a lot of alcohol.
I think I bought quite a few.
No idea how many.
None of the slippers are wet.
So, was there anyone suspicious out of those three?
None at all. They all seemed the same as usual.
Well, I guess we should call the police now.
A-Ah, say, what kind of people are those three?
"What kind." Didn't I tell you earlier?
Ah, no, I mean, are they fat or skinny or tall?
Saori, the one I called first, is around 150 centimeters (4'11") tall.
She's kinda overweight.
Heh, how rude.
The one I called next, Tago, is fairly short.
He's even shorter than she is.
The last one, Furushou, is skinny and is
probably over 180 centimeters (5'11") tall.
But that doesn't matter now—
No. That's made it clear.
The culprit who snuck in here and
took the photograph is one of those three.
W-What did you say?
What's more, surprisingly that person is now...
Right in front of our noses and holding their breath.
What? Right it front of our noses?
You mean they're in this apartment?
That's interesting, kid.
The culprit has to be someone who has a spare key
to this apartment, either my former girlfriend Saori,
Or my modeling friends, Tago and Furushou. If you're
saying they are still hiding somewhere in this apartment,
Why don't you drag
them out and show me.
OK, that's fine.
But in exchange will you promise me something?
W-What do you want?
If I find the culprit, before you call the policemen, will
you show us he photograph that the culprit is now holding?
When the policemen come, they'll
probably take the album in as evidence.
If that happens, we might not be able to see the photograph this time.
That was the photograph of the customer from
my grandfather's shop who lost his wallet, wasn't it?
Right!
I think he's probably really upset about
losing his wallet, so I want to return it right away.
Yeah, yeah.
But still, how do you know the one who stole
the photograph is still here in my apartment?
The sweat.
It's the sweat.
Sweat?
That chair I was using as a footstool, it's wet with sweat.
That means the culprit did the same thing I
was doing, and used that chair as a footstool.
That's when it must have got wet from
the sweat from the bottom of their feet.
So you're saying it's because that sweat hasn't
dried yet that someone's hiding in the apartment.
It's not there.
Not there? What isn't?
The slippers that the culprit must have worn,
which should have been still soaked with sweat,
Are nowhere to be found.
See, there are no footprints on the floor. That
means the culprit must have been wearing slippers.
Couldn't they have just wiped the footprints
off? It was a sneak thief who got in after all.
If that was the case, they would have wiped the sweat off the floor too.
But you've only checked the slippers in the entryway, right kid?
You haven't checked the ones I'm wearing yet, have you?
It's possible these really might be the slippers the culprit used.
My socks are pretty thick, so they're probably a bit wet.
I think even a really thick-headed person would know.
Those slippers wouldn't just be wet, they'd also retain some heat.
If you had put those on, you'd know for sure someone had been here.
Since nobody said anything when we came into the apartment,
When you came home, the culprit must have
hid somewhere in a panic, and kept the slippers on.
T-That's true.
But the culprit was looking for a
particular photograph in the apartment, right?
How would they know that he was coming back to his apartment?
Ah, that's...
Right there!
The intercom.
Yeah.
Earlier, when we got here, we pressed the intercom
in the entrance of this apartment building, didn't we?
And immediately thereafter, he came up from behind us.
That's how the culprit knew he had come home.
The intercoms here just ring a chime
and you see who's there using the monitor.
Just like when the home deliveryman came earlier, right?
Come to think of it, that's right.
During the time between when we rang the
chime and when we got up to the apartment,
Before we opened the door in the
entryway, they must have hid themselves.
Exactly.
W-Well then, who was the culprit?
If you think back over what those three said
when he phoned them, I think you will all figure it out.
Because, over the phone the culprit gave away...
Their hiding place.
S-Seriously?
So, what did they say over the phone? Those three?
Eh? Well, if I remember...
Saori was scolding me, like she always does.
Like to eat proper meals, and to take a bath.
Tago told me to finish up those models by tomorrow.
And to do the dishes and the laundry when I woke up in the morning.
Furushou told me, so that I wouldn't catch a cold like he did,
That I should clean my apartment and I should
upgrade the anti-virus software on my computer.
In that's so, that puts Furushou-san out, doesn't it?
Because if he got you to clean the
apartment, his hiding place would be discovered.
Ah, that's right.
Then maybe it's Saori-san. She told you to
eat proper meals and take a bath, didn't she?
Because if you went out to eat, or went to take
a bath, she would be able to escape from here.
That is suspicious. And Saori said I shouldn't
call again because her boyfriend was coming.
I don't think it's Saori-san.
What?
Because when you called her, we couldn't hear her voice.
That means the culprit is hiding somewhere
where they can't hear voices or sounds from here.
From that place, I don't think they could tell if you left or took a bath.
And what's more, you told us you
leave the lights on whenever you go out.
In other words, you mean the only useful
information the culprit can get is the time on their cellphone.
Yeah, that's their situation now.
H-Hey, wait a sec.
If the culprit isn't Furushou or Saori...
Exactly, the culprit is the one who asked you
on the phone to finish the model by tomorrow.
And then told you to do your dishes and
laundry when you woke up in the morning.
I think it's that guy Tago.
T-That's crazy. In order to finish by
tomorrow, wouldn't I have to stay up late?
He couldn't escape if I was still awake.
Even with that risk, he had to have you do that in order to escape.
Say, what kind of things do you do
when you prepare to finish up a model?
What do I do? First I get out my file, putty, paints and tools and such.
And when your tools are ready?
Well, now. First of all, I'd open the window for ventilation.
Hey! No way.
You're not saying Tago is out on the veranda are you?
That's it exactly.
At any cost, he needed you to open it.
In order to get off of the veranda.
Earlier, after we left the veranda...
You locked the window, didn't you?
That's it. Since you always leave the window open...
He expected you to leave it open when
you went to sleep after finishing the model.
Yeah. As long as you left the window open for him, he could
peer through the curtains to see what was going on in the room.
But when we went out there earlier there was nobody there.
Yeah, not where we could see, right?
Eh? Where we could see...
You see it now, right? That's why he told you to
do the washing and the laundry when you woke up.
H-Hey. Could it be he's...
Right. He said that because...
Of course, he didn't want you to open the lid of that washing machine.
T-Tago! It's you!
Ah, well...
Incidentally, the reason he told you he would
come in the morning and do the washing was...
He planned to enter the room from the veranda at
a time he decided it was likely for you to be asleep,
And would have an excuse if you
caught him on the way out to the entrance.
"I figured it would be a bad idea to wake
you up since I came early to do the washing."
Is what he would say.
Even if he was acting suspiciously and tiptoeing
around, that would provide a reasonable explanation.
Yeah. Of course, his height and physique
I asked you about was the deciding factor.
Since he used that chair as a footstool in order to get the album
from the top shelf of the bookcase, the culprit must be a short person.
Besides, if he wasn't a fairly short person,
he couldn't hide inside that washing machine.
I'm sorry, Souhei! I didn't mean any harm.
I didn't touch anything at all in the
apartment except the photograph, so please forgive me.
Then you're the one who erased the picture data from my computer?
Ah, yeah. But it's OK, I made a backup.
I planned to restore it secretly after I removed the problem photograph.
I only planned to take the photograph from the album.
So what photograph was it? How do I
have any photograph that's bad for you?
I-It's the model.
The one I showed you before. The German Panzer IV Type H.
Eh? That tank was really awesome wasn't
it? Our other modeling friends were praising it.
You're really becoming inspired.
No, I'm not.
I didn't make that that tank.
It's something I bought on an overseas business trip.
The truth is, I bought it to use as a pattern.
But I thought I'd surprise you guys a bit, so I
replaced the nameplate with mine and showed it to you.
And then you guys believed me, and even took pictures of it.
And on top of all that, you said you would link to them on your blog.
So, before it could be distributed on the
internet, I came here to recover the photograph.
But even though this was your day to go to the gym, you came home.
Then, all I could think of was
to get in the washing machine.
Idiot!
Even though you went and lied, you
didn't have do something so serious.
We knew it. We knew you hadn't made that tank.
That's why everyone agreed beforehand
to pretend and trick you until you confessed.
You pretended? That's cruel!
The one being cruel was you! You're
the one who tried to deceive us first!
Ah, excuse me.
Could you show us the photograph sometime
soon? You're not calling the police, are you?
Help me look for the photo too.
Photo? What photo?
The photo of that regular customer who
got along pretty well with my grandfather.
Ah, that guy who often came in with his son?
Tago-san knew him too?
Yeah, he went to the same college in Osaka as I did.
Souhei used to bring me a lot to his grandfather's okonomiyaki shop.
He introduced me to him there.
He used to say that man was his best customer.
If I remember correctly, wasn't that man was a scuba diver?
Eh? Didn't you tell me he was a
member of the Maritime Self Defense Forces?
Is that was the man said?
Ah, no. Once when I was paying my
bill at the shop, I dropped some change.
And they happened to roll under that man's
table, and when I was picking them up I heard him say,
"I'll dive in deeper."
Dive?
I've been into making tanks and battleships ever since I was a child.
At that time, I was sure he was talking about submarines.
But when I asked Souhei's grandfather, he said
that man was just a regular company employee.
So I figured he must have been talking
about going scuba diving with his coworkers.
His coworkers?
Yeah, they were with him at the time.
Three or four foreign men wearing black clothes.
But, somehow it seemed they were going to
challenge a really dangerous place in the ocean.
They were all saying things like, "Good luck,"
And "No pain, no gain."
Kentou wo inoru... Good luck...
Itami nakushite erareru mono wa nai... No pain, no gain...
Say, did he have his son with him that time?
No, he wasn't there.
When he brought his son with, it was just the two of them.
Ah, isn't this the one?
Yeah, yeah. This is the photo.
That kid must have pressed the shutter
when he was looking into the lens of your camera.
Yeah, I didn't notice it either until I developed the film.
Hey, are you sure that man was just a regular company employee?
Y-Yeah, that's what my grandfather said.
That guy is a company employee. He works for the "company".
So, do you know which company he worked for?
That's all I know.
C-Company?
That was lucky, Shin'ichi.
Shin'ichi. Shin'ichi?
It's no use, professor.
He's been having a staring contest
with that photograph the whole time.
It doesn't look like your voice can get through at all.
Leave him be.
Company.