The light of summer is the radiance of yesterday.
After the tears is a beckoning cat.
Can this cat also beckon crime?
Which hand is raised?
The left hand? The right hand? Or even both hands?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Hey...
Absolutely no looking up.
If you do, I'll kill you.
I said I wouldn't look...
Hurry up and get it over with already.
Why?
Why did I, who just happened to be passing
by, have to get roped into doing this?
It's all right.
Come here...
Just a little further.
It's all because Edogawa-kun is shorter than we need him to be.
Excuse me.
I'm only like this thanks to a certain someone...
Do you know where this kitten is from?
No idea.
Does anyone know this cat?
Cha-Cha!
Where have you been, Cha-Cha?
Sorry for startling you.
Ishigami Tomatsu (35)
Cafe Owner
See, this is my cat.
She disappeared a while ago I've been looking for her ever since.
She was in the park.
It seems she hurt her right paw, since it was bleeding a little.
And you bandaged her up for me?
Thank you.
No problem.
To show my gratitude, won't you join
me in my shop and have a cold drink?
There's a lively customer here at the moment, though.
Still, come inside.
There, that's it!
Run!
The whip, the whip! Use the whip!
Go!
How unfortunate.
Master!
Ishigami-san!
Something terrible has happened, come quickly!
Kanemaru-san...
Master, coffee!
Another cup of coffee!
Inspector Megure!
The inspector?
What the...
Inspector!
You again?
I was taking a stroll and saw the patrol cars...
I wondered if I might be needed.
Why are you here?
Whatever.
Is there a case?
The president here...
The "Office Kanemaru"?
What sort of business does this company currently conduct?
He just acts important by using a foreign name, but...
All he really does is issue high-interest loans.
And even though he's the president of the
company, there aren't any other employees.
The victim's name and family?
Kanemaru Kenzou-san, age 65.
He was single with no family.
According to the coroner...
The cause of death was a blow
to the head by a blunt object.
The weapon was probably one of the beckoning cats in this room.
Even so, there are a lot of pieces here.
The broken pieces lying around the victim's body are likely from that.
The weapon was a beckoning cat, huh?
Then, how about the estimated time of death?
Yes.
The time of death was a few hours ago.
It was sometime between 11:00 AM and 1:00 PM.
Who's that person?
He's that detective, Mouri Kogorou.
And...
Imoka Fumie (65)
Janitor
This lady was the first to discover the body, Imaoka Fumie-san.
She comes here once a week to clean.
Today, she arrived at her usual time of approximately 1:30 PM.
Hey...
Just who are you reporting to here?
I apologize, sir.
It looks like the safe has been opened as well.
Inspector Megure...
The safe contained nearly a million yen in cash...
But it doesn't seem to have been disturbed.
I see.
Inspector...
The one who first discovered the body is, in fact, the criminal.
This proves it.
This Imaoka-san here...
She owed the victim 300,000 yen.
She probably underwent a harsh collection
process, and not knowing what to do...
This happens all too often.
Hold it, Detective!
You're suspecting me, aren't you?
It's true that I borrowed 300,000 from him.
But he said he would ignore the interest on
the loan if I came here to clean once a week.
That's why I was here!
Now, now—there's no reason to get so agitated.
Inspector!
What is it?
We found this on the president's desk in the other room.
If you'd have a look at it please.
It seems to be a memo of some sort.
September 3rd, 12:30 PM—Murai Chika.
In other words, today...
The victim, Kanemaru-san, had plans to meet with this woman.
About that...
The master of the cafe across the street, Ishigami-san...
Claimed to have spotted a young woman
approaching the office around 12:30.
A young woman?
Sorry...
And, what'd she look like?
Yes...
She was dressed quite glamorously, wearing
designer brand clothes and a shoulder bag.
Murai Chika (22)
Motojo University Student
But, after only about ten minutes, she ran out.
Since she arrived at 12:30, she must have left at 12:40.
Both of which happen to fit the estimated time of death.
Yes.
We have already ordered a search party...
And provided them with the description given here.
I see.
Understood.
I'd like to speak with her directly, so bring her here.
They've found a woman who appears to be Murai Chika-san.
They're headed here now.
I see.
But, the victim, Kanemaru-san, sure has a weird hobby, huh?
Collecting beckoning cats...
For Kanemaru-san, it wasn't a hobby, it was pure greed.
He collected them because he liked money.
He collected them out of greed?
As you can see, all of the cats lined up
here have only their right paw raised.
Yeah, that's true...
When I asked why none had their left paws raised...
He said it's because the cats with their
left paws raised beckon customers...
While the ones with their right paws raised beckon wealth.
As long as I have money, it doesn't matter if no customers come.
It'd be wasteful to spend money on tea for them anyway.
He simply felt that money was the most important thing in this world.
I see...
So the cat's raised right paw brings in wealth, huh?
You ever heard anything about a cat beckoning wealth?
No.
But, even though I won't have to come here and clean anymore...
I feel like I'll kind of miss it.
Cleaning?
Say, miss...
Did Kanemaru-san ever use the vacuum cleaner himself?
Never.
He said it'd waste money on electricity,
so he only got me to do it once a week.
Hey, don't wander around and get in the way of the investigation!
The dust bag?
I didn't throw it out...
And there's no reason why Kanemaru-san, who
didn't clean, would throw it away—how strange...
Well?
Yes!
There's no mistake, it was that person.
Just what was the vacuum cleaner used for here?
And why was the bag...
What purpose would be served by removing it?
Well, well...
With the lending agreement she'd taken found on
her and the appointment memo, she can't deny it.
I guess I wasn't needed for this one after all.
What's that?
It seems like a beckoning cat's paw.
It was under the sofa.
It probably flew here from the force of the blow.
This is a flip clock, isn't it?
The panels flip as the time changes.
To still be using something as unusual as this...
It's as Imaoka-san said, he was a pretty weird guy.
This piece flew all the way over here?
I guess I can't rule out that possibility completely...
No, wait...
That's not it...
This didn't fly here!
I see...
So that's why they used the vacuum cleaner!
But, who did it?
She's confessed to her crime.
And her motive?
It seems that, in order to buy all her brand-name
clothes, shoes, accessories, bags, and watches...
She accumulated a sizable debt with Kanemaru-san.
She even quit college and started a
part-time job, but it wasn't enough.
That's why today, she finally...
¥100,000?
That's not even enough to cover the interest.
This is the limit of my patience.
I'll just ask your parents in the countryside to cover it.
Please stop!
Please, don't tell my parents!
I'm begging you!
I'm not doing this for free, you know?
If you don't bring all of the money by tomorrow...
And then she grabbed the lending agreement and fled.
That's how it was...
This is... blood?
Something happened in this room, didn't it?
Yeah, looks that way.
1/60th of the evidence exists.
1/60th of the evidence?
That's right.
The "once-an-hour" evidence.
Well, then...
I just remembered something I have to do, so I'm heading home.
Hey, Haibara...
So you, wielding the beckoning cat,
proceeded in the direction of the safe...
And swung downward, right?
That's not it.
This isn't that simple of a case.
Looks like his paw has stopped bleeding.
Thank you.
But it'd be best if you had a veterinarian take a look at it.
That's true.
It's as I thought.
Come on, Conan, we're leaving.
And we still have ten minutes before the last race.
May I watch it back at your cafe?
Yes, please do!
All right then, Inspector.
Thanks for the hard work.
Hey, Mouri-kun...
Don't tell me it came, and that we've got the culprit wrong again?
Yes, that's exactly it, Inspector.
Murai Chika-san did indeed strike
Kanemaru-san with a beckoning cat...
And in this very office.
But her crime is merely assault, is it not?
Assault?
That's it?
Having been struck by Chika-san,
Kanemaru-san likely lost consciousness.
And not long afterward...
At around 12:40 PM...
Ishigami-san witnessed the fleeing Chika-san.
Minutes later...
Kanemaru-san was struck once again.
Are you saying he was attacked twice?
If you would, please bring out the clock from the president's office.
Hirota-kun.
Please turn the time back to 12:59 PM.
What a unique retro clock!
If I recall, you just do this...
This is—!
Blood that flew from Kanemaru-san's head when he was struck.
Furthermore, it happened in the president's office in the next room.
The time was 12:59 PM.
In other words, she had already left.
Which means...
Someone else attacked Kanemaru-san?
Yeah, and that person was the
one who killed Kanemaru-san.
You're saying the President's office
was the scene of the second attack?
The culprit tried to clean up the blood stains, but...
Because the clock's dial had changed during that time...
The culprit didn't notice that any blood had sprayed there.
I see.
Well?
Just who is the murderer we're dealing with here?
Please look at the notepad over there.
Kanemaru-san left a clue for us.
12:30 PM—Murai Chika.
It's the next page, under that memo.
A blank page.
There's nothing written here.
What was once there was likely a memo detailing a meeting
time around that of Chika-san's but with the culprit's name.
Realizing this, the murderer removed it.
Inspector...
Please shade the page using a pencil.
A faint impression from the writing should still remain.
Some characters have appeared!
September 3rd, 1:00 PM...
Ishigami.
Ishigami-san...
Were you scheduled to meet with Kanemaru-san at 1:00 PM today?
Yes...
I had scheduled to meet with him...
But, it was very busy in the shop, so I couldn't make it.
Conan...
Give that thing to the inspector.
Yes!
Here you go.
A handkerchief?
This is... blood?
Yeah.
It's the pawprint from Cha-Cha, whose front paw was injured.
Inspector...
The pawprint on the window of the president's office...
Should be the same as the one on that handkerchief.
Please confirm this.
Ishigami-san said that he hadn't come over.
However, Cha-Cha did.
But it's unimaginable that a kitten opened the door and came in.
The window was open, but...
There's a crime-prevention lattice, so even
a cat couldn't jump in from outside.
Just as you said, Detective Mouri...
The pawprints match perfectly.
Which leaves us with one possibility:
Cha-Cha came here with Ishigami-san.
Ishigami-san, you came here at 1:00 PM as promised on
the memo and met with Kanemaru-san, didn't you?
No, I...
I didn't come!
Ah-le-le?
There's something over there.
What could it be?
Look, under the sofa!
It seems to be a beckoning cat fragment.
Inspector...
That is a fragment of the weapon
Ishigami-san struck Kanemaru-san with.
What?
But, Mouri-kun...
She said she struck him with a beckoning cat that was on the shelf.
That's most likely the one missing from up there.
There's only one cat's worth of shards.
Where would you say the beckoning cat that Ishigami-san used is?
Hey, Inspector Megure...
That beckoning cat fragment is the left paw, isn't it?
Now that you mention it...
All of the cats here are ones with their right paws raised, aren't they?
Their left paw is...
In other words...
That fragment came from another beckoning
cat that didn't belong to this collection.
Are you saying another kind of beckoning
cat was brought in from outside?
Ishigami-san...
You brought a beckoning cat with its left paw raised, and
came here a little before the 1:00 PM appointment.
And that was when you saw Chika-san.
Kanemaru-san, who had been struck by Chika-san...
Only lost consciousness, and woke up soon after.
Then...
Hello.
Kanemaru-san?
What happened?
What a mess.
On top of not returning the money, that woman suddenly...
Anyway, do you have the money ready?
No, not yet.
What!?
That's why I got you this, to apologize.
Oh, a beckoning cat?
How thoughtful.
Are you stupid?
The only ones I collect are money-beckoning
cats with their right paws raised.
Not the left paw!
I don't want this rubbish.
Go back to your shop and prepare to vacate it!
Beat it.
You and that woman are the same.
What kind of idiot does he think I am?
Startled at the situation, Cha-Cha injured her paw...
And, frightened, escaped out the window.
Meanwhile, you decided to frame Chika-san for the crime...
And dragged Kanemaru-san's body out into the main room.
You then looked around for any blood
splatters and cleaned them up...
Collected the large fragments, and used the
vacuum cleaner to collect the small ones...
Then, along with the dust bag, you took them away.
Unfortunately for you, a few pieces of evidence were left behind.
Ishigami-san, what do you have to say?
Not that much time has passed since the crime occurred.
Your means of escape are limited.
It won't be difficult for us to locate the fragments of the weapon.
Then, all we'd have to do is match the
fingerprints and blood to reveal everything.
Everything...
Happened just as Detective Mouri described it.
But, since I wasn't able to repay the money today...
He was going to take my shop away from me!
That's why...
Beckoning cats are supposed to bring good luck.
Only this time, it was different.
Hey, Conan!
Come here a minute!
What?
Here we are, perfect!
Take a look, a beckoning cat made by yours truly.
Beckoning both money and clients, it raises both paws.
"Banzai"!
It hits it right on the mark!
Banzai!
It looks more like it's giving up...
Giving up hope.
The body of a famous mystery author was discovered in a villa.
On his finger, a ring that had been put on upside-down...
Both Detective Satou and Detective Takagi rushed to the scene.
On Detective Satou's finger was also a mysterious ring!
Unsolved mysteries of both the case and love!
What will you do, Detective Takagi!?
Next Conan's Hint:
Tightrope Walking
Look forward to the next episode
No more beckoning cats for you...
Why not?
Because you only beckon cases.