But was that really true, what you said before?
That's definitely what he said.
Maybe he's mistaken.
In that case...
She's here.
Suwa, about those three suspects assigned to Yoshioka,
it's particularly likely one's an accomplice.
Yeah, yeah.
Hmm? What is it?
Is there something on my face?
Then what the heck is it?
Ah, sorry. Ha-ha. No, no, no.
I keep seeing people whispering in secret. Is something going on?
Something about me?
No, it's nothing. Right?
Yeah. N-Nothing at all.
Ha-ha, it's nothing. There's nothing going on. Right?
Ha-ha-ha, nothing to worry about.
R-Really?
I've finished examining the suspect in the Haido City case.
Ah, yes. Yes.
Now, regarding that case...
Well, I've outdone myself.
Ah, I'm amazing, don't you agree?
No, really. I really need to brag about my examination.
It's like the feeling after you've eaten some
katsudon while watching a drama that just came out.
TAKAGI!
W-What is it?
Hey! Don't give us "What is it?"
C'mon, we want you to tell us.
That's right, Takagi!
You know, there are others here who's hearts are ready, Takagi!
Hearts ready? Hearts ready for what?
T-T-Takagi!
Now, now. So, Takagi-kun...
Yes?
That's... yours, right?
Something about Inspector Megure's phone call?
Takagi-kun, that's very funny.
I'm talking about Satou-san.
Yes?
See it shining there on Satou-san's finger?
Ah, Ran-chan. What's wrong?
That ring. The ring!
A ring?
A ring...
Ah, you're right.
It's a ring.
A-A ring?!
I've never seen that ring before. And what's
more, it's on the ring finger of her left hand.
Who could have given her that?
No, no. Calm down. Remain calm.
Keep your cool. Keep your cool.
Go and ask Satou-san.
Excuse me, Satou-san. About that ring...
I'm sorry. I found someone I like.
Miwako-san.
Satou-san.
Miwa-chan.
Eh-hah-hah. Just like that.
When it's on the ring finger of the left hand that means...
An engagement.
That's what it means, right?!
What it means is what I want to ask.
What? That ring? It isn't yours?
N-No.
Didn't buy it; never seen it.
T-Then, who the heck did?!
Who was it?
Could it be a patrolman?
Maybe it's a judge.
I heard it was a lawyer.
Ah, hold on for a moment.
Hey!
Hey! Quiet down!
I must be missing something.
Hello.
Ah, sorry. And then?
Eh? Someone is...
Somebody's dead?
I understand, Ran-chan. I'll be there soon.
Takagi-kun, let's go.
There's trouble at a villa in Okutama.
Takagi-kun...
Ah, yes!
Sorry, please take this.
No problem. Now about what we were discussing...
But...
Right here there's...
Big trouble.
It's one step to a glorious future.
Having your heart ready is OK, of course.
As the light flashes off the ring on Detective Satou's
left hand, will Detective Takagi make a decision at last?
Perceiving the one and only truth.
With the body of a child and the brain of an adult.
His name is: Detective Conan!
Wow, what a magnificent ring.
That sure is an amazing number of gemstones.
Are they all diamonds?
This the first time I've ever seen anything like it.
Ah, isn't it?
It's a ring I had made to commemorate the debut of my 100th work.
I had "100th" engraved on the reverse side.
See?
The truth is I had ordered 100 diamonds to be affixed, but...
Moroguchi Masataka (52)
Mystery Author
If I did that, the size of the ring would be too large, and I was against that.
I guess that's how it is.
Ah, excuse me. I need to change the tape.
Isn't it unusual to be using a cassette tape recorder nowadays?
Yeah. It's generally all digital recording now, but...
Dejima Kakuji (34)
Writer
I'm just not happy unless I can see the tape spinning.
And I'm scared of errors with digital.
Ah, I see.
In truth, I'm the same way.
All of my fellow cameraman are using digital cameras, but...
Tarumi Wataru (33)
Cameraman
I've been using this analog guy for so long I just can't let it go.
Well if I can't finish this up soon, I'll be in trouble...
Hey now, I'm sorry to interrupt the pile of analog stories, but...
Anabuki Harue (33)
Magazine Editor
The deadline for Moroguchi-sensei's on-going serialization is getting close.
If you're done with the useless chatter, can you finish what you came to do?
Don't be so grumpy, Anabuki-kun.
The official conversation between me and
Detective Mouri isn't until tomorrow morning.
This evening we'll feast on my home cooking, and after
a good rest, we'll do it in the morning sunlight tomorrow.
Isn't that right, Writer-san?
Yes. This is, well...
Something like an introductory rehearsal meeting.
It's even on the announcement page in this
month's edition. Look, the author Moroguchi Masataka...
Speaks with great detective Mouri Kogorou on
the new dawn of mysteries. There's a lot of publicity.
Please take a look.
Let me see...
What's wrong, Conan-kun? What's with that face?
I'm just thinking he's kind of different from what I imagined.
Different? You mean Moroguchi-sensei?
Yeah.
Because the sensei's mysteries pay excessive attention to minute details.
I thought for sure he would be an easily irritable and highly strung person.
Anabuki-kun!
Yes?
Do you have a ruler?
Ah, yes. I do happen to have a measuring tape.
Just as I thought.
When compared to the other authors, the
characters of my name are one millimeter smaller!
Are you trying to make a fool of me?
N-Not at all. It was just the way the size of the characters came out properly.
If that's the case then make characters of the other author's names smaller!
This is a piece of crap!
I'm very sorry.
It won't happen again.
Of course not!
I see...
In that area he's pretty high strung.
Really! My chief editor before you, Akiba-kun, was really good.
He would grant me anything I desired.
Ah! He sounds like an excellent editor.
Yeah. When searching for a file photo or when
investigating or collecting specialized knowledge regarding a trick,
he would exhaust his flesh and bones without sparing for my sake.
Until even his very life was exhausted...
H-He passed away?
Yeah. In the spring of this year his body was found in his home.
With all the locks locked, in the middle of a sealed room.
A-A sealed room? Suicide?
It had to be, right? It wasn't one of my mysteries after all.
The truth is I thought I would write a book based on his death, but...
I was stopped by Anabuki-kun.
Of course! His sudden death was well-known in the publication industry.
If a novel like that were published,
I figured it would lead to a bunch of gossip articles on the Internet.
Please understand.
Gossip is just gossip. It's not the truth.
Besides if it was called a memorial of sorts to my editor Akiba,
don't you think, on the contrary, it would be a hit?
W-Well, I...
What the...
Crap, I'm out of lead.
Then why don't you use mine?
I'd like to say this is something I use a lot, a pencil. Even though it's analog.
I'll use it proudly.
Well, for now, since tomorrow's plans have been decided,
and the production will be tomorrow morning,
I'd better wrap these up.
So I don't waste the film.
After that, we continued the program
planning for two more hours, only breaking for dinner.
If we had only known all that work would be useless...
Yes, because, the single main participant in those plans was...
Moroguchi-sensei?
It's already five o'clock in the morning.
Sensei?
What's wrong?
Ah, Mouri-san.
Is he still sleeping?
Ah, yeah, it's possible he was up late last night working.
Then let's use the master key and wake him up.
The thing is, the sensei really hates it
when other people come into his room.
So there isn't a master key. It seems he stole it...
Hey, Conan-kun! What are you doing?
I have a bad feeling. A sensation like a
strangling in my chest, suffocating me.
Like it always does at a time like this.
I'd say the time of death was about an hour ago.
An almond odor. Cyanide poisoning?
There's a coffee stain around his mouth.
Did he drink it with the coffee?
All of the locks in the room are secure.
The only way in was what I used when I came in, a
ventilation window that only a child could get through.
And probably what's in his hand is the key to this room.
Suicide?
No, this is...
Murder.
The deceased is the mystery author, Moroguchi Masataka-san, 52 years old.
The cause of death is suffocation from the ingestion of cyanide.
And from the coffee stains around his mouth, most likely...
He either mixed the cyanide in his coffee and
drank it or was forced to drink it, but which one?
I wouldn't say he was forced to drink it.
The door and windows in this room
securely locked, so it was definitely a sealed room.
Not to mention Moroguchi-san's holding the key
to this room in his hand, and there are no spare keys.
So it must be suicide, right?
H-How come? Someone could have
placed cyanide on his coffee cup beforehand,
so a crime in this sealed room is still possible.
Of course they would have to know that
Moroguchi-san drinks coffee when he wakes up in the morning.
Idiot! People don't normally drink coffee while holding keys, do they?
And, of course, it would be completely unreasonable to
grab it right after realizing that the coffee had been poisoned.
So he was probably holding that key before
drinking the poison as some kind of message.
Ah, but Moroguchi-san was scheduled to have an
interview with you this morning, wasn't he, Mouri-san?
So maybe because he overslept he grabbed the key in haste and
just before leaving the room he drank the coffee to wake himself up?
Come on! Look more carefully.
The coffee cup is lying right next to the bed.
Yeah. That's right.
And the coffee maker is in the kitchen over there.
If he was in a rush, he would have drank
the coffee in the kitchen where he got it.
He wouldn't have bothered to place it on a
saucer and bring it over to the bed to drink.
But, did you think about this?
Someone came to wake up Moroguchi-san this
morning, poured him a cup of coffee and mixed in the cyanide,
and brought it over to his bed.
Asking him to be quick, they handed him the key and left the room.
That can't be it either.
If that was the case, then whoever it was would have had
to leave the room before Moroguchi-san drank the coffee.
It would be impossible to get Moroguchi-san to lock the door.
It's up to the person whether they drink the coffee right away or not.
But since he was being pressured he probably drank it right away.
But maybe Moroguchi-san has a sensitive tongue
and couldn't drink it right away because it was too hot.
That's not the case.
Moroguchi-sensei absolutely loved coffee.
Hot or lukewarm, he always said it was good.
Isn't that right?
Ah, yeah.
It's a well known fact in the editorial department.
And you guys are?
Yes. I'm the editor in charge of Moroguchi-sensei, Anabuki.
As for the two behind me, on the right is the cameraman, Tarumi-kun.
On the left is the writer, Dejima-kun.
So the three of you came here this morning
to Moroguchi's villa for the planned interview?
No, all three of us spent the night.
It would sure be rough to come here by five in the morning.
But, it's strange, isn't it?
Since this room was sealed, you would have had to
break down the door or smash a window to get inside.
And there's no sign of that.
So, how did you get in?
As for that...
This brat did it.
Conan-kun came in through the ventilation
window and unlocked the door from the inside,
so we could get into the room also.
And then we found Moroguchi-san dead.
So that window was open?
Yeah. That's right.
But it looks like it's only wide enough for a child to squeeze through.
Still, if this was a suicide, then how come
Moroguchi-san was holding the key when he died?
Well it could be that he didn't want any
of us in the villa to be suspected of murder.
And like I said a second ago if this was a murder,
then unless the murderer said, "Close the door
and drink the coffee while holding the key" to him.
It would be impossible to create this situation.
In that case, any idea why Moroguchi-san would commit suicide?
No, not really.
He didn't seem that type at all.
Yeah, that's right.
Well, he could have had troubles that he didn't discuss with certain people.
It seems his previous chief editor, Akiba,
committed suicide in the spring of this year.
Perhaps he might have felt responsible for it.
Well anyway, let's wait for forensics to arrive.
If this was murder, then the culprit's
fingerprints should have been left around here somewhere.
Because if the culprit had poured the coffee or
opened and closed the door while wearing gloves,
then Moroguchi-san would have become suspicious.
And there was no chance to wipe them off after the room is locked.
Of course, that's only if you guys didn't touch anything before we arrived.
We didn't Detective Mouri warned us not to go in until the police arrived.
We've already decided it was suicide. There's no reason to call forensics.
Hey, Detective Takagi.
Doesn't it bother you?
What?
The R-l-N-G.
What are you talking about, Conan-kun?
I-I'd be lying if I said it didn't bother me,
but we're in the middle of an investigation...
That's not what I meant.
Where are you looking? It's over there.
This man's ring.
The word "100th" is upside down.
Yeah, you're right. But maybe he just put in on wrong.
But this man was really neurotic, I don't think he'd make a mistake like that.
Also this ring...
See? It has so many diamonds on it.
T-That's it! This really was a murder after all.
The motive for the murder was this ring.
After killing Moroguchi-san, the culprit switched the real ring with
a fake ring; but, in a rush, ended up putting it on the opposite way.
Did Moroguchi-san never take off his ring?
Ah, that's right. He was really fond of it. He
always kept it on even while taking a bath or when in bed.
If it's like Detective Takagi says, then the
possibility of this being a murder has gotten stronger.
One more puzzle has arisen.
Yeah. The culprit could have have only
switched the rings after Moroguchi-san was dead.
Therefore, the culprit must have still been in the room at that time.
So then how did the culprit escape from this locked room?
How did they get the key into Mogoguchi-san's hand?
Or maybe after poisoning Moroguchi-san, the
killer took the key and left the room, locking the door.
Then they somehow managed to find a way to
return the key to Moroguchi-san's hand from the outside.
The only thing that was open was that ventilation window.
It's about four meters from there to the corpse's hand.
With that much distance...
Is something like that even possible?
So, while we wait for forensics to show up, let's hear from you guys.
Where were you and what were you
doing before Moroguchi-san's body was found?
First up is Dejima-san.
I-I was fixing this tape recorder in my room.
It wasn't working very well. The tape inside got
messed up and when I tried to rewind it, it made this sound.
T-That sure is a strange sound.
Next is Tarumi-san.
After I finished setting up my photography stuff, I was
also in my room organizing the negatives for some other work.
Using these rubber bands to tie them up.
I see. Then, next is Anabuki-san.
I was in my room as well checking the galleys for other authors.
That reminds me, Auntie. You had a metal tape
measure, didn't you? Do you always carry that?
Yes. Because the sensei always asks me
to measure things, like the size of words.
But if it's just to measure words then why not a ruler?
You know, boy. It's not just used for
words, you can measure lots of stuff with it.
Like a door or a window that can be used for a trick.
You know a lot about him.
We learned a lot from Akiba before he died.
Since he and the three of us joined the company the same year.
Although I ended up quitting and became a freelance writer.
I see. So that's it?
U-Uhm, Detective Satou.
This isn't related to the case, but...
What is it, Ran-chan?
That's probably forensics.
Sorry, Ran-chan. Later, OK?
Yeah.
What? It's real?
The ring is genuine?
Yes.
Yeah, we took it to the station right away and had
an expert take a look at it, so we're positive it's real.
Then I guess the culprit's motive wasn't the ring after all.
Yeah. It seems so.
Then why? What reason did the culprit have for taking the ring off?
Oh, come to think of it, when we took the ring off we found a strange mark.
A strange mark?
Yes. Right here.
It faded a lot, but there's a blackened circle around this finger.
It's blood.
Blood? Why is there blood there?
Perhaps he cut himself while shaving and he touched the cut.
How's that?
See? There's a cut under his right jaw. There's no mistaking it.
Incidentally, on the coffee cup, this saucer,
the coffee maker or on the doorknob there
were no prints other than those of the corpse.
I see.
U-Uhm, Detective Takagi.
Huh? What is it?
This may be inappropriate at a time like this, but I really wanted to say...
W-What is it, Ran-san?
Congratulations on your engagement!
Ran-san?
Because, look! The ring that Detective Satou has on he
left hand ring finger, that's an engagement ring, isn't it?
Looks like it...
"Looks like it?" Are you saying you didn't give it to her?
Nope. It's someone else's.
So she's replaced you with a more reliable and good looking guy?
D-Dad!
I suppose so.
You suppose so? Shouldn't you find out for sure?
It'll be nice if I could, but I'm kind of scared of the answer.
Seriously. It's like having to walk a tightrope.
Are you sure you haven't fallen off the rope already?
I suppose so.
Geez, Dad, stop teasing him!
That's it! So that's why!
That's why the culprit took the ring off.
It was to make sure the "tightrope
walk" in the sealed room would be a success.
I still don't quite get this.
The door and the windows in the room were locked.
The deceased, Moroguchi-san, died
from drinking coffee poisoned with cyanide.
In his left hand was the one and only key to the room.
The only opening was a ventilation
window that a child could barely get through.
Just from this it looks like he killed himself and didn't
want anybody else in the villa to be suspected of murder.
The problem is that the ring on the middle finger of his left
hand that was holding the key, was placed on upside down.
According to this woman, Moroguchi-san almost never took his ring off.
And since he's not the type who would put it on wrong...
Then after someone poisoned
Moroguchi-san, for some reason they took the ring off.
And when putting it back on they accidentally put it on upside down.
Maybe they took the ring off because there was blood on it?
I mean, there was blood under the ring
from when he cut himself shaving, right?
Then maybe the culprit took the ring off his finger to wipe the blood off.
No, if that was the case, then they
would have wiped the blood off his finger too.
Even if they wiped the blood off the ring, it'd be
meaningless if there was still blood on the finger.
Maybe the culprit wiped the blood without taking the ring off?
I suppose so.
Maybe that guy...
Was sewing?
S-Sewing? What do you mean, Conan-kun?
Ah, I mean... Remember? Earlier when you were making me the
dust cloth I take to school, you were wearing a ring, right, Ran-neechan?
Eh? Oh, you mean the thimble?
When you have that on it's easier to
pass the thread through the needle, right?
That's wrong! Conan-kun, a thimble is used in order to push on the needle.
Oh, really? I thought for sure that they used that
ring to push something through the hole in the key.
Oh well, I was just wrong.
Put something through the hole in the key.
So that's why the ring...
That's it!
Huh? Uncle...
Rubber bands!
Rubber bands?
First you chain the rubber bands together, then you pass the
bands through the ring and create something like a slingshot.
You hook the top and bottom of the key on both ends of the rubber
bands and you fling it into the room through the ventilation window.
You can control the length of the rubber bands by how many you attach.
And of course this was done after poisoning
Moroguchi-san and leaving the room with the door locked.
And the only person who could have done this is the
person who is still wearing tons of rubber bands on his wrist.
The cameraman, Tarumi-san! It was you!
So? Am I wrong?
Ah, no. It wasn't me.
Wrong again, Uncle.
But, if that was the case, shouldn't the rubber bands still be in the room?
Since you're flinging them into the room along with the key.
T-Then he only used one side.
He held one end of the rubber bands
and hung the key on the other end to fling it.
That way he just has to pull on the end
he was holding to be able to get it back.
But even if he was able to get them back that way,
the knots in the rubber bands would get caught in the
ring and pull, making the corpse's arm dangle from the bed.
Besides, would the culprit really choose an impossible task
like flinging a key into the palm of a hand with rubber bands?
If it failed, people would think the key was
just thrown in through the ventilation window.
Come to think of it, that might happen.
It will happen.
Damn, I could put him to sleep and
perform the deduction show like always, but...
Detective Satou is here.
She came close to finding out once already.
Guess I'll have to just lead them into realizing the truth.
They're right, Uncle. I don't think even the
people at the circus can do a trick like that.
The circus? Are you talking about magicians?
Because Detective Takagi was saying that he
was walking a tightrope with Detective Satou.
That means the two of them are doing a circus trick, right?
Aah, w-wait, Conan-kun! That was...
What did you mean, Takagi-kun?
Conan-kun, what was mean!
Wait, walking a
tightrope. Walking a tightrope.
Oh yeah, there is one thing!
Something long and narrow that won't get
caught in the ring and you can get back right away.
Ah, you finally figured it out, Uncle.
The thing that Anabuki-san, the editor, carries...
The metal tape measure.
What? Whoa, whoa.
So she put the measuring tape through the ring?
No, she just hooked the tip of the measuring tape on the ring!
Then she put the measuring tape through the hole in the key and
sent it from outside the ventilation window into Moroguchi-san's hand.
Just like a tightrope walk.
W-Wait a sec. When did she put the
measuring tape through the hole in the key?
She did it immediately after poisoning Moroguchi-san of course.
The key went on the measuring tape first, then she hooked the tip
onto the ring, and then stretched it out to the ventilation window.
And if the body of the tape measure along
with the key is hooked on the window edge,
then, afterwards, she just has to lift it up from the window and the
key will follow the measuring tape right into Moroguchi-san's hand.
And, of course, you can get it back with just one button.
What I meant was, how do you lock the door if the key
was already on the tape measure before you left the room?
Oh, right.
Well, maybe she stretched out the measuring tape after
committing the crime and leaving the room with the door locked.
Maybe she did it after going outside to the ventilation window.
Y-You know, since it's a rigid metal
tape measure, you could use it like a stick.
And if you cleverly get the tip of the tape
measure to the corpse on the bed and hook it on the ring...
That can only be done up to one meter.
Anything longer than that and it'll bend before
even reaching either the palm of the hand or the bed.
And besides, what's the point of taking the
ring off if you just need to hook something on it?
T-True.
Yeah. If only there was something long and thin like a thread.
But none of the three suspects had anything like that.
We checked around the villa and there's
been no report of anything like that being found.
How could there be?
Unlike a rubber band, it would have to be something that wouldn't
get caught in the ring and was thin, smooth and long like a thread.
Plus you'd have to always be able to wrap it up like a
tape measure. There can't be anything that convenient.
W-Wait a minute.
Hey! Could that be a...
Ca-
Cassette Tape!
Now I see, using a cassette tape you can
pull out the tape and put it through the ring.
And pull the end of the tape back to where the
cassette is placed outside the ventilation window.
That way after you poison Moroguchi-san,
you lock the door and leave the room.
Then from outside the ventilation window you put
the tape you left there through the hole in the key.
And just by lifting the tape up high...
The key will slide down the tape due to
gravity and arrive on the corpse's hand.
After that, if you wind up the tape, it'll slip through the key and the
ring and return to the cassette. And so the sealed room is complete.
That means the only person who was able to use this trick
is the person who habitually carries a cassette tape around.
And who wouldn't regarded as
suspicious by the police when examined later.
That person is right here.
The writer, Dejima-san.
It couldn't be anyone except you.
Most likely you said you had some last minute checks for the
arrangements of the interview that was planned this morning.
So you asked Moroguchi-san to let you into his room.
Then when he wasn't looking you
mixed cyanide in his coffee, thus killing him.
Then you used the trick we just discussed making this a sealed room.
So? Are we wrong?
Anyway, we'll know if we just examine the cassette tape you're carrying.
You want to say that the tape will be
twisted, but I told you about that, didn't I?
That this recorder...
Wasn't working correctly.
So I have plenty of tapes that are twisted.
Plus it makes a loud noise whenever it winds
something up, someone would have heard that.
If I didn't use this and just quickly reeled in the tape by hand
then a large portion would have been twisted. Go ahead and check.
I don't have a tape like that.
Nope.
The pencil!
You stuck the pencil you borrowed from
Moroguchi-san last night into the hole in the cassette to wind it.
This way you can wind the tape back in a short amount of
time without using the recorder and without damaging it.
I did it a lot when I was a kid too.
Whenever I was goofing around and ended up pulling out a lot of
tape I had to wind up, I'd put it on my knee and roll it up with a pencil.
And when Satou-san was talking about examining the
tape, it wasn't about whether the tape was twisted or not.
Like we said before, there was blood under the ring on his left middle finger.
For some reason there was one place where it was rubbed off.
So, it should be somewhere on the cassette tape that you're carrying.
The one you used for the sealed room
tightrope walk, a tape with Moroguchi-san's blood on it.
D-Dejima-kun?
Hey! Could it be, because of Akiba?
Hah, a tightrope walk? Akiba used to say that a lot.
That his relationship with
Moroguchi-sensei was a continuous tightrope walk.
A tightrope walk?
Akiba was a careful sort-of guy,
but ever since he became in charge of the
sensei, he was always wearing a bandage somewhere.
Why do you think that was?
As the sensei told him to, he was testing them out.
All the murder tricks the sensei thought up, he was
using his own body to confirm if they would work or not.
Of course taking meticulous care to make sure he didn't die for real.
Hey! So the incident where Akiba was found dead in a sealed room was...
Yeah. When I was sorting through the
effects in Akiba's desk at the office, I found it.
A notebook of tricks in which was
written the exact same way that Akiba died!
Then why didn't you turn that over to the police?
It would've been useless. If put on the spot, the
sensei would have just said, "Akiba did that on his own."
But it was still an accident, right?
No, the sensei said it like this in another interview:
At this age, I've finally started to understand the murderer's feelings.
As a mystery writer, there's nothing more joyous than that.
That's what he said. And that's when I knew for sure.
What the sensei wanted to know by making use of Akiba...
Wasn't the reality of the tricks...
But rather the mentality of the murderer.
So? I've been wondering about it for a while now.
About what?
Don't "about what" me. What did you
mean about walking on a tightrope with me?
Ah, no. That was, well...
It was your ring! Detective Satou, you always say you dislike shiny things.
So Detective Takagi was wondering why you're wearing a ring!
I guess it's good that she's just as blunt as Uncle.
Oh, this? You mean this charm?
C-Charm?
That's all?
What do you mean?
Silver and turquoise.
If you wear one on your left hand ring finger it'll keep the
bad bugs away, killing two birds with one stone, Yumi said.
So I'm doing it too.
You know I'm cursed and I hate bugs, so...
Ah, no, when Yumi-san said bugs she didn't mean those bugs.
l-In that case, Satou-san, please wear my ring!
On your left hand ring finger!
OK, that's fine.
Man, I bet she was grilled by everybody today.
After all Satou-san is wearing my ring...
On her left hand ring finger.
But today I need to act dignified.
And face them like a man.
Takagi, we heard about it. Satou's ring.
Here it comes...
It was...
So, it was just a charm!
What's going on with everyone?
That's a good thing.
Don't let it bother you.
But to think that she doesn't know the meaning of the left hand ring finger...
That makes it even more exciting!
Come to think of it, I didn't tell her yet.
The meaning of that ring. Oh well...