Cancelled!?
The live breakup performance?
Yeah.
Your group probably won't be able to fill
all of the seats in that hall anymore.
It's for your sake as well.
Mr. President—hold on, sir!
I've worked so hard to arrange this live breakup performance!
This is merely business as usual.
We can't keep this up until we land ourselves in debt.
If that's it, how will we announce the split to the fans?
Just write it on your homepage.
Or, if you'd like, I can do it for you, as I have before...
However, I'll keep you employed for another six months...
Since it seems that you still have value as far as
variety programs and talk shows are concerned.
You must be joking.
Can't you release me now since we can't
do the live breakup performance?
Yeah, that'll be fine.
Provided that you pay damages for breaking your
contract and retiring earlier than planned.
Well, that's how it is.
The glorious future is just one step away.
Naturally, all my preparations are A-OK!
Today's stage is a television station.
A brilliant masked world and a dangerous true face!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Filming at the television station's been suspended?
Are you serious?
I'm sorry...
And we were looking forward to it, too...
That's right, the new Joker villain...
I thought we'd be able to see him.
Everyone's schedule got packed...
Something came up suddenly this morning...
And I thought I'd be able to eat the film shoot's lunch too...
I invited you guys because the director
was an acquaintance of mine, but...
It seems like they aren't able to show visitors around...
I'm really sorry about this!
Don't mention it.
I'm really sorry!
It's all right, I suppose.
Since we were already invited to the television
station, we can just tour around while we're here.
That's true!
That's true, isn't it?
There should be a lot of famous people here.
Ayumi wants to meet the weather lady!
It's Toraya for me!
I'm going for Yakkun!
All while the famous idol Okino Yoko-san is right in front of you...
Good morning, Yoko-chan!
Good morning!
Look, it's Inoue Waka-san!
It's true!
The lady from Gochi?
Inoue Waka
Actual Japanese Actress
Yoko-chan, good luck to you today.
You too.
Go easy on me, please.
Don't her parents run a soba restaurant?
I wonder if she has grilled eel...
Come on, Genta-kun.
Inoue Waka-san...
Birthdate: May 13th.
Height: 166 centimeters.
Hey, hey...
Good morning!
Morning.
Good morning.
Yamamato Azusa
Actual Japanese Actress
Good morning.
This time it's Yamamoto Azusa-san!
Famous people all around...
Awesome!
Okino Yoko, Inoue Waka, Yamamoto Azusa—wow!
You guys...
But isn't that great?
You were able to meet them all already!
Yeah!
You guys...
Haven't we met before?
Azu also feels like she's met them before...
You must have seen us in the newspaper or something!
Because we are...
The Detective Boys!
The Detective Boys?
Yeah, we're the Detective Boys.
We capture criminals and other bad guys!
Right!
Is that so?
Amazing!
It's nothing, really...
Especially...
Conan-kun here is a great detective on par with Mouri-san!
By "Mouri-san," you mean...
That's right, Mouri Kogoro.
The one who's always supporting my efforts!
Now that you mention it, he is quite famous for being your fan.
I guess that means Yoko-chan will snatch away all the
questions dealing with cases and deductions, huh?
It's not like that!
Hey, what's this about questions?
We're recording a quiz show today...
The three of us will be competing as contestants!
Oh, that's why you said, "Good luck to you today."
Yoko-chan, today our friendship is on-hold!
I'm turning my heart to stone so that I'll win for sure!
Is that so?
Demon!
Is she a demon?
She sure is!
Is something wrong?
Ayumi-cha—
It's here!
It came!
It's you!
You're the new K-K-Kamen Yaiba villain, aren't you!?
N-Not just a villain—he must be the leader
of some sort of evil organization!
He's the new boss!
He's got to be the boss!
What's this, brats?
You saying you really don't know who I am?
Yes!
How disappointing...
Although I may not be that different from a Kamen Yaiba villain...
Good morning!
Who was that?
I've never seen him before...
Me neither.
He's the vocalist from the rock group, "The Styx Three"...
Satan Onizuka-san.
Satan Onizuka (32)
Vocalist for The Styx Three
I think I heard that he was supposed
to appear in a variety show today...
A rock singer in a variety show, huh...
A devil's life sure is tough.
Onizuka... Satan...
Satan?
Onizuka Satan.
Satan Onizuka?
What's wrong, Mitsuhiko?
Oh, nothing...
Satan Onizuka...
I feel like I've heard that name somewhere before...
That's right!
My sister asked me, because she's his... Satan Onizuka's fan...
She asked me to get his autograph if I saw him at the television station!
If I don't go after him and get it...
But it looks like he's already gone off somewhere.
Aren't you taking this a bit too far?
Now, now...
We could at least find out where his
dressing room is if we ask Yoko-san.
Right, Yoko-san?
Where's Yoko-san?
So excited, so, so excited!
Wasn't Yoko-san just here?
The assistant director took her away just now, saying, "You're up."
Along with the other two contestants.
Well, I'm sure it'll be all right if we search for him on our own.
That's right!
We at least know that he's somewhere in this television station.
Yeah!
If we all search, we should be able to find him!
Satan Onizuka-sama
Huh?
Satan-san...
You're already here?
If I remember correctly, you didn't have
to show up until this afternoon, right?
Yeah.
I had nothing else to do, so I came early.
By the way, Manager, could you order
me some food to be delivered?
I haven't had lunch yet.
Sure, no problem.
What would you like?
Ramen from Tenpuku-tei, and...
Ramen from Tenpuku-tei...
Fried rice from Jan Jan Ken.
Fried rice from Jan Jan Ken, and...
Oh, that's right!
Some gyoza from Eirinan...
Gyoza from Eirinan...
Ramen, fried rice, and gyoza, all from different shops?
Since those dishes are all Chinese, it'd be
better to order from the same shop...
What's the problem?
I like those dishes from those particular shops.
Not to mention, I eat at those three shops a lot, so even
if it's just one dish, I'd like to give them my business.
Oh, reminds me.
Did you find the mirror I asked about?
Yes.
An acquaintance had seen something similar,
so I was actually on my way to that store now.
Is that so?
Thanks for that.
Without it, there's no way I'd be able to fix my makeup quite right...
I'll get right on that.
I'll be back soon.
Oh, also...
I'm going to nap after I finish eating, so please
don't wake me until it's time for my appearance.
Got it.
I had an argument with the company president last
night, and it bothered me so much I couldn't sleep.
If I remember correctly, he's here too, right?
Yeah, I think he's in the meeting room two floors above this one.
All right, I'll be back!
I guess I have to go apologize to him after we finish filming...
Good idea.
At any rate, this television station sure is complicated...
One can't quite tell where anything is...
Even the toilets are hard to find, huh?
It's like a maze!
Looks like it'd be better to ask someone...
Yeah, seems like it.
Yes?
Early, aren't you?
The meeting was supposed to be at 2:00...
Oh, it's you...
Sorry about last night.
A meeting at the television station, huh, Mr. President?
Yeah, they wanted to use some talent from our
company as a regular for a new program...
Don't you have a program to record at 2:00 as well?
Are you ready for it?
Yeah.
For that kind of thing, 30 minutes is more than enough.
Right, about that matter—it was I who turned them down.
You might be angry, but it was for your own good.
It's all right; let's not talk about that.
Take a look at this—what do you think of my raincoat?
It's light and water-repelling...
On top of that, it was cheap.
That's good...
You want to know what part I like about it most?
If I put the hood on like this...
It's harder for the blood splatter to get on my person.
Pretty handy, I'd say.
Satan Onizuka-sama
Here we are.
Satan Onizuka-sama.
There's no doubt that this is it.
All right, Mitsuhiko!
Yeah, but do you think this is polite?
Satan Onizuka-sama
Seeing him without an appointment...
He might get mad at us with that scary face...
It'll be fine.
There are a lot of people passing through this hallway...
If it turns bad, we can call for help!
What's this "call for help"?
I'm gonna knock, then.
Hey!
You can't...
Satan-san's in the middle of a nap right now...
He sleeps?
Yeah...
I sleep.
If I don't, my powers won't recharge!
Excuse me!
Could you please sign this?
My sister's a big fan!
Name?
Asami.
The "Asa" character from "breakfast," and "beautiful"!
"For my true believer Asami."
Here.
Thank you very much!
With this, your sister becomes a member of our demon clan!
It's origami!
Hey, hold on...
So many cranes!
It's true!
Hey, did you fold all of these?
Yeah.
While lying in wait, I occasionally partake in human pastimes.
But I wasn't able to fold more than those five today...
What is this ruler doing here?
Using the ruler, I can better fold them.
However, a devil folding origami—doesn't it ruin your image?
Yeah.
That's why I forbid you to tell even my true believers...
If it's revealed, I'll put a death curse on you!
Yes!
That's right, Satan-san.
I have the mirror you wanted.
Let me see...
It was this one, right?
Here you go.
Yes, this is perfect.
With this, I can do my makeup even in the dressing room.
Thanks.
You're welcome.
Is something wrong?
Oh, no, my contact just shifted a little...
Please come in.
Excuse me.
Are you all right, Mitsuhiko?
You look pretty tense...
I'm fine!
Oh yeah, here we are.
I also bought eye drops.
You were out, right?
Yeah, set it over there for me.
Got it.
Hey, all the names on these plates and bowls are of different shops...
How come?
Satan-san has all kinds of strange tastes...
Well, it's because human food really isn't up to my standards...
Patrol cars?
And an ambulance too?
I wonder if something happened near here?
It appears that "something" occurred at this TV station.
At this TV station?
What's that!?
Yes!
Sorry, we're about to head to the studio...
No...
The company president, he...
It's terrible!
Anyway, please...
Please come quickly!
Excuse us!
Please clear the way!
Satan?
Satan Onizuka?
Excuse us!
Satan Onizuka!
Satan?
Excuse us!
Right here.
Mr. President!
Who... in the world...
Did this?
The deceased is Urushibara Tenji-san, president of an
entertainment production company, 47 years of age.
The estimated time of death is around 1:00 PM.
Cause of death is loss of blood via a bladed object.
And the first person to discover the body was?
Myself.
There was supposed to be a meeting held here at 2:00 between Mr.
Urushibara and the producer of the program I'm in charge of, but...
When I came to tell him that we were going
to be a little late for the meeting...
I immediately called the police and ambulance, and...
On the way, I notified Satan-san as well, who
also belongs to the president's company...
Satan-san?
Me.
What are you!?
A Death God!?
I am that Satan.
Satan Onizuka, the vocalist from The Styx Three.
River Styx?
Santa Onizuka?
That's not it, Inspector.
I know of Satan Onizuka.
He's from a visual kei rock band that
was popular three or four years ago...
Hey, hey... Was popular?
You're using past tense...
Regardless, do you know of anyone that
would have a grudge against the president?
With his personality, I'm sure there were
a lot of people with grudges against him.
Myself included.
Then, just to be sure...
At approximately 1:00, when the crime occurred,
where were you and what were you doing?
Around that time, I was in the dressing room...
Origami!
You guys!
That devil said he was folding origami!
Origami?
Five cranes!
It looked like he was just killing time, though.
But we can't tell anyone!
Otherwise he'll put a death curse on you!
A death curse?
That's what I tell the fans—it isn't a hobby befitting of a devil, after all.
I see.
And you were in the dressing room by yourself
the whole time up until the children came?
Yeah, I ate the delivered food, took a nap, and folded origami.
So you were here at the TV station quite some time
before you were scheduled to make your appearance?
I went to the dressing room a bit before 11:00.
Immediately afterwards, I had my manager take
my food order and go buy some things for me.
Yeah.
When I came back, the children were about to enter
Satan-san's dressing room, so I stopped them at first...
Since I was told not to wake him until
he was to go to the studio at 2:00.
I see.
So, in short, when the murder occurred at
approximately 1:00 PM, you have no alibi.
Yeah, but it would've been impossible for me anyway.
If I'd come out of my dressing room with this face and
loitered around, it'd definitely have attracted attention.
Get all the station personnel together and ask them.
Find out if there's anyone who had seen
me during the time in question.
However, if you removed the makeup and left with your true face...
That's right!
If you went through the station using your true
face and headed towards the meeting room...
And, after committing the crime, reapplied the makeup...
I believe that'd be impossible.
You mean...
Does it take that long to apply the makeup?
No, it would only take about 30 minutes.
Except for the fact that there are no mirrors in that dressing room.
There are no...
Mirrors?
There was an influential actor who hated mirrors more than anything,
so there are two or three dressing rooms like that here, and...
Satan-san always uses one of those dressing rooms.
I hate mirrors too, you know?
Especially big ones.
If you'd like, you can take a look at the dressing room.
It certainly seems that there are no mirrors on the walls...
Inspector!
There is one, isn't there!?
Wait, no...
I just bought that mirror and brought it here.
I gave it to Satan-san when I came in with the children.
Then, please share which store it's from so I may confirm it.
Yes, sir.
Also, if you would, please let us investigate this dressing
room and Satan-san's belongings, as well as his person.
Is that all right?
Yeah, I don't mind.
Inside the bag...
It looks like there are various supplies for applying makeup, but...
There aren't any mirrors...
None on his person, either.
What's with this slightly dirty jacket and hat?
On the chest, it says "Devil Shop"...
I brought that to use in the scene in today's
talk show where I first come on stage...
During our live performances, we always
do a short skit in between songs...
Good day, I am the devil!
I have come to deliver misfortune!
We do that sort of thing.
Takagi-kun, confirm with the program's staff just in case.
Yes, sir!
By the way, the makeup supplies are used
for touch-ups during the performance...
If it's just a slight touch-up, I can borrow a compact
mirror from one of the female staff members and fix it.
Well, I don't sweat much, so it rarely happens.
But it looks like that purple lipstick
comes off pretty easily, doesn't it?
See, from Satan-san's cigarette butts.
There's purple coloring on the filters...
And the same color is all over the autograph
board that Mitsuhiko received from you.
It's true!
How come?
At the time, Satan-san used his mouth to remove the cap.
That's how the purple color got on the cap...
And the color got onto your hand from
the pen that he handed back to you.
Because you were holding it with that hand this whole time,
you transferred the color onto the board without realizing it.
Really?
I see.
Ah-le-le...
It's strange, isn't it?
There's no purple color on the chopsticks or spoon
from the delivered food that Satan-san ate...
Even though they'd all come into contact with his mouth...
How could that be?
That certainly is odd.
When I eat, I take the lipstick off with a tissue.
I don't like getting purple all over the chopsticks and the bowl...
If it's just the lipstick, I can easily reapply it without a mirror.
Then do you use the lipstick around your eyes too?
It's the same purple color...
It's not lipstick, but it's from the same brand.
Of course, that cannot be done without a mirror...
Well, if there are people who can put it on themselves
without a mirror, they might be gods or devils themselves!
That much is true...
Devil-san sure likes that purple color!
Yeah, it's a color that I've liked since we were still indie.
No other brand makes this color.
But, since today isn't a live performance...
The white for the face and the gray for the cheeks can be
done with a readily available water-soluble foundat—
Is something wrong?
Satan-san has dry eyes because he's wearing contacts...
Here, your eye drops.
No, it's all right.
But your eyes—they're red.
No, I said it's all right!
Just drop it already.
Geez...
You can't find any mirrors in this dressing room, or my bags, or
on my person, so tell me how I could've done my makeup!
The food delivery.
For example, after committing the crime...
You could have secretly given the mirror that you used to fix your
makeup to one of the three people who delivered the food here.
Certainly, if he did that...
That's impossible.
I just asked the guards at the doors...
The food couriers that came before the body was discovered at
2:00 were only those three, and they all came at around noon.
I asked all three of them just in case.
They confirmed that they brought the food at roughly 12:00...
And that they were told by Satan-san to
come back for the plates in the evening.
They haven't come back to collect the plates yet.
Oh, of course, all three said that when they delivered
he food, Satan-san had his makeup on as usual
If they delivered the food before the crime was committed, he
couldn't have passed the mirror to one of them after the fact.
The remaining possibility is that, when the
assistant director came to call them...
He threw away the mirror he had hidden
while hurrying to the scene of the crime.
I don't think that's the case.
I was watching him the whole time.
Satan-san was only running normally.
Is that so?
Also, the manager bought that mirror at around 12:30 PM.
From that shop to this television station,
it takes about an hour by car...
So it's impossible for him to have brought it before the crime, is it?
Furthermore, there's no mistake that the food delivery
costume was scheduled to be used in the program.
The station even had the delivery box prepared.
But do you really play the food delivery person with that makeup on?
Yeah, we do it at our live shows a lot.
My hair is set well enough that wearing a hat won't affect it.
Now that you mention it, where did you
make yourself up into this devil form?
You were already like this when you entered the dressing room...
At home!
I'd already finished doing it at home, come to the station
by car, parked the car in the parking lot, and arrived here.
Of course, I had my manager take the bag.
If I had a bag on me while made up
like this, it'd be strange, you know?
Hey, were you smoking when you folded the origami?
Yeah, I usually smoke while performing detailed tasks.
Got a problem with that?
Nope, no problem—I was just curious.
That's a lie.
He's lying.
Mr. Sun has gone down...
It has, hasn't it?
As I thought, the culprit is this person.
Most likely, he temporarily removed his makeup
and did the deed wearing his true face.
And after killing the president, he reapplied
the makeup and became a devil again.
But there's a problem...
When did he acquire the mirror needed for
the makeup, and where did he hide it?
There are a number of bathrooms on the
route from here to the meeting room...
But if he had used one of those, he'd have been seen for certain.
Even if he was lucky and wasn't seen...
There's no doubt that someone would have
remembered him in the hallway with that getup on.
If he hid his face, it would attract even more attention.
I guess it makes more sense that he came back to
the dressing room and reapplied the makeup.
Those origami cranes bother me too.
If he was planning on using the idea that he wasn't able to commit
the murder due to his folding cranes as an alibi, five are too few...
Also, he should have been able to foresee that someone could just point
out that the cranes could have been brought here inside the bag...
And that his alibi would fold just like that.
Then, what do the cranes and origami mean?
Couldn't this be the mirror?
See, in this window...
Genta-kun and Mitsuhiko-kun are clearly reflected!
Sure, but take a good look.
Little girl, can you see your own face?
Look, it's dark and you can't really see it, can you?
It's true!
If you get too close to it, it becomes dark and you can't see clearly.
The crime occurred in the middle of the day, at around 1:00.
It was bright out.
If it doesn't get dark, it can't reflect.
I see, that's the reason for the origami!
I'm finally able to see it—the trick you used to hide your devilish form!
Professor, where have you been?
Sorry there...
My cell phone ran out of power...
I went to contact everyone's parents using the public telephone.
Hey, detectives!
Have you found your answer yet?
If I had come out of this dressing room with this face and roamed around
the station, nine times out of ten someone would've spotted me.
I've said this earlier, but if I murdered the company president...
To get to the meeting room two floors above this one,
I'd have to temporarily remove my makeup...
And reapply it here after committing the crime.
But take a look!
The mirror that would have been essential to this task doesn't exist.
Of course, it doesn't exist in my bag or on my person, either.
The only mirror here is the one that my
manager bought and brought here for me...
But it only came into my hands after the time of the crime.
And at that time, I was already dressed like this with my makeup on.
Isn't that right?
Yeah.
It wasn't just me—those children were also present.
Without a mirror, I can't paint this face.
Yeah...
That's why, after I entered this television station today,
I had this costume on the entire time up until now.
So please, will you leave me alone and let me
mourn the death of my company president?
I can't cry in front of others while still calling myself a devil.
However...
I understand.
At least let me take off this makeup, then.
I'll be done in three minutes.
If it weren't for this face, no one would notice me even if I cried.
I see.
So you want to wipe it away along with your makeup, huh?
The evidence that proves that you really are a devil...
Those flame-colored remnants.
Hey, old man!
Using my voice without permission again...
What kind of joke is this?
I'm not laughing.
It certainly is impossible for you to have
wandered around in that getup...
But if you removed your makeup and wore the food
delivery costume, no one would have noticed you.
That's why you had delivery personnel from three different shops come.
In short, at around the time of the murder, those three
food delivery people came in and out of this room.
You were able to slip in among them to comm it the crime.
If their uniforms were similar, it'd be even better.
Those that would have seen you would
not have paid attention to your face.
Then, could it be that the clothes he
wore then were the ones in the bag...
Correct, he used the "Devil Shop" costume
that was intended for the talk show.
You're speaking as if you'd actually seen it.
Exactly—I did see it.
At that time, a strange food delivery
person running without a delivery box...
I see!
A food delivery person would normally have
a delivery box in their hand, wouldn't they?
Both coming and going...
But this is a television station.
Occasionally there would be an actor wearing such a costume...
I did think that for a moment, but no matter the role,
they'd at least put on some simple makeup.
Even so, that man was wearing only his true face.
And what's more, the bottom part of his head that I was able to see
under the cap was exactly the same inverted-V style as Satan-san's!
But there's no evidence that that delivery person was me, is there?
There are other people who have the same haircut as me.
They could even have been one of my fans.
Plus, if I murdered the president like that, how did
I reapply this makeup after I came back here?
Certainly, there's no mirror in this room...
But you can make one, can't you?
Using a transparent board.
Transparent...
Board?
If you're talking about this window glass, it's impossible.
Like the children said, if you get too close to it as if you were putting
on makeup, your face becomes a shadow and can't be seen.
And since the crime was committed during the day,
nothing would have been reflected anyway.
I know what it is!
The culprit didn't use the glass...
It was that ruler!
Ruler?
But how?
It's the same as the window glass.
If you use this origami and make it dark, it'll work.
Will that really turn it into a mirror?
Do it, do it!
Actually, window glass and this sort of
transparent plastic reflect light all the time.
I don't see anything being reflected!
That's only because the light from this side
is so strong that you can't see it clearly.
But if you do this, and put the black origami
behind it to obstruct the light...
It really is being reflected!
It's true, amazing!
It's like a mirror!
By the way, as far as the nighttime window glass, what's
reflected gets dark and hard to see due to the shadow.
But what's reflected is a far cry from the real thing.
You can't clearly see the color.
If that's the case, what if we use silver?
Look, we can see the color this way.
But it's blurry and you can't see very well.
Silver has the power to reflect, but because the
surface of the paper is rough, it becomes blurry.
But it's all right even if you can't see the color.
Satan-san's makeup is such that it's always a matter
of painting a certain color on a certain area.
I see.
If it's like that, then it seems that you
really could apply your makeup here.
Yeah.
In short, Satan-san actually...
Removed his makeup immediately after the deliverers
brought the food and, wearing the delivery uniform...
Headed to the meeting room where the president was.
After the murder, he quickly returned here, reapplied
the makeup using the mirror made from the ruler...
And waited for the manager to come wake him up.
But if that's the case, there should have been a lot of blood
spatter on this delivery uniform from the company president...
That's why he probably prepared a different sort of clothing.
For example, something like a raincoat that had a hood attached.
All right, mobilize the investigators and find it!
Yes, sir!
Even if that sort of thing is found, it doesn't matter.
I didn't do it, and you have no proof.
Making a mirror out of the ruler and origami?
How would I know about something like that?
I was only in here folding origami cranes
while waiting for my manager!
Oh, if that's the case, I wonder if you could fold one for me?
Another origami crane.
What?
I won't mind if you smoke...
When you do detailed tasks, you like to smoke, don't you?
That's ridiculous.
How could I fold one in these circumstances?
Then, Ayumi-kun, could you fold one in his place?
First, you make a triangle...
Then you do this...
You're really good, Ayumi-chan!
When my dad was in the hospital, Mom
and I folded a whole bunch, so...
All right, done!
That's a well-made crane, but it's skinny
and doesn't look very healthy, huh?
That's true!
I see, that's it!
You must blow into origami cranes in order to make them expand.
If you did apply your mouth there, your
lipstick would have rubbed off on it.
Like the cigarette butts in the ashtray.
But there is none on your cranes.
So then, does that mean he didn't fold those
cranes today with his makeup on?
Hey, Agasa-san, do you even know what you're talking about?
Oh, no...
Whatever the case may be, whether Satan-san
can't fold the cranes or forgot how...
The point is that those cranes were folded beforehand, and
brought here in order to camouflage the mirror trick.
The reason why he deliberately offered up to you detective
the fact that he held a grudge against the president...
Was so that you could immediately come to his dressing
room and confirm that there was, in fact, no mirror there.
If it were later, the food delivery personnel would
have returned to collect the plates and bowls...
And the possibility of the presence of
a mirror would have become unclear.
Then the reason he asked the food delivery personnel to return in
the evening was so that he could allow time for us to investigate?
That's a lie!
Satan-san would never murder anyone—it just can't be!
Then, I wonder if you could take that makeup
off here, and show us your true face.
I understand.
Satan-san, let's remove your makeup.
Satan-san...
Sorry, but I can't, Manager.
If I peel off this devil's mask...
The shameful face of a murderer will be revealed.
No... It can't be...
You know about what happened three years ago, right?
The story of when, in the middle of a tour, I
had to be hospitalized due to throat pain.
Back then, there was a child that sent me
a letter wishing me well every day...
Along with a small box containing a folded origami crane.
She believed that I was actually a devil.
I was so happy to read those letters.
But one day, the letters from that child stopped coming.
At the time, I thought that maybe she'd just lost interest...
But last month...
When I went drinking with the president,
the reason behind it was revealed.
That man said: "Should we make another
sacrifice in order to push you to glory?"
A sacrifice?
That's right.
When I was hospitalized, I didn't know, but...
On the band's homepage, the company president
made comments in my name without my permission!
"In order for my powers to return, I need a sacrifice... I want blood!"
Could it be that that fan took it seriously...
Yes.
When I pressed the issue with him, he laughed...
Saying that the last letter read, "I am overjoyed
to present you with my blood. Goodbye."
The live comeback performance a half-month later was much more
popular than before I was hospitalized and before someone died.
I immediately searched for and went to visit that
child's home and found out that, sure enough...
She apparently committed suicide for unknown reasons.
Then, it was revenge for that child?
Yeah, I did him in!
That man who, for the sake of money,
didn't give a damn about human life...
Who destroyed the live breakup performance that I'd
worked so hard to set up without having been asked...
And insisting that I'd have to pay damages if I
wanted to break the contract and retire early...
That real devil!
Well, I gave you a nice list of reasons, but...
We've actually been in a slump these past two
years and just wanted to end things early...
That may have been the real reason...
But my sister said...
"The Styx Three will definitely make a comeback!"
And that they'd definitely come up with some
marvelous songs, boiling over with spirit...
It wasn't to be.
I say things like "I'll possess you," and "I'll put a
death curse on you," but I've never said "Die."
The only ones who babble things like
that are villains from Kamen Yaiba.
I've become that sort of man, I have.
But that's...
You know what else?
After the letters from that child stopped, it really bothered me...
I kept thinking...
"Did I do something wrong to make her hate me?"
When I started thinking like that, I began to cry...
And I couldn't write songs or lyrics...
Not even one phrase...
I'm not qualified to be a devil...
Huh?
Devil-san's tears are a little red...
It's because of President Urushibara's blood spatter.
Blood?
Remember how you couldn't see color very
well in the mirror made from the ruler?
Without noticing the blood under his eyes,
he put the white foundation over it.
He finally realized it when he gazed in
the mirror the manager brought him.
That's why he didn't use the eye drops...
Because if the eye drops were to overflow, the
conclusive evidence would have made itself known.
Really...
Let's go, shall we?
But it's just like a fairy tale, isn't it?
It's often said that if the devil cries, he loses his powers.
My, the game has turned serious!
Inoue Waka-san, Okino Yoko san, and
Yamamoto Azusa san are tied for the lead!
There's only one question left!
The winner will be determined by this last question!
Hey, this program was recorded when
you all were at the station, right?
Yeah, but we didn't meet with Yoko-san after the case
was over, so we didn't find out what the results were.
Come on, there's no doubt the winner will
be the beautiful and amazing Yoko-chan!
Inoue-san, how's your confidence level?
I'll do my best!
Okino-san!
Please support me, fans!
All the way, Yoko-chan! I support you!
Yamamoto-san?
Azu will also do her best!
All right then, let's go!
The 10th question!
If you say Conan Doyle, it would be Sherlock Holmes.
If you say Yokomizo Seishi, it'd be Kindaichi Kousuke.
So then, if you say Edogawa Ranpo?
She got it!
Yes, Okino-san?
Akechi! Akechi!
That's too bad! Okino-san has been disqualified!
The winners are Inoue Waka-san and Yamamoto Azusa-san!
Let's have a round of applause!
Congrats!
Congratulations!
Geez, saying that name even by accident...
Mouri! Kogoro!
You make me lose hope.