On the day of the incident...
You visited a bar on Suehiro Street by the
name of Esper immediately after work.
There, you drank one liter of beer and sake...
And had left by 8:00.
Is this information correct?
Yes.
Just after 11:00, at an intersection in Toriya City,
you struck a victim with your car while heading home.
Can you please recount your actions between those two intervals?
I thought I was sobering up, so I decided to head home.
I rested a bit in my car, but soon dozed off.
Is there anyone who can attest to that?
No.
Do you mind telling me why you struck the
victim and fled without providing aid?
I panicked, and...
That's why.
Are you certain that's the extent of it?
This is your tenth day of imprisonment.
What all has the prosecutor asked about over the past ten days?
Prosecutor Kujou, the official heading your
case, is an accomplished professional.
She wouldn't confine you for such a long period
of time with nothing else up her sleeve.
I'm here to represent you.
So please, even if it's devastating, I ask that you tell me the truth.
Kisaki-sensei!
I take it you visited your suspect?
Yeah, well...
You have good timing, Kujou-san.
I have something to ask you.
What is it?
It's been long enough since you detained him.
I was wondering if you could release Takeuchi-san already.
He reported himself, and even admitted to the crime.
What reason could you have to hold him any longer?
Allow me to remind you...
That whether a suspect is released or not
is solely my determination to make.
In that case, I'll petition for justification in court.
Do as you wish.
Then, if you'll excuse me.
What is it you're after, Prosecutor Kujou?
The complete truth of the matter.
How very unlike you, Kujou-san.
See you in court.
The glorious future is just one shining step away.
Naturally, all my preparations are A-OK!
A fierce showdown between two rivals:
Lawyer Kisaki will be facing off against an elite public prosecutor!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Damn, why do I have to go meet her?
Because it's a job that you asked mom to take, Dad.
I was only asked by a bar hostess if I knew a good lawyer around.
Yet you still concealed the fact that Kujou was the prosecutor.
The suspect already admitted to the crime.
It's all just a matter of how to plead into a lighter
verdict with the judge; it's a simple court session.
It doesn't matter who the prosecutor is!
Uncle's right...
There's no call for a battle in court at this point.
But just what is it that Prosecutor Kujou's up to?
Thanks for coming all this way.
This is the car involved in the accident.
The victim was riding a bike, right?
Yes.
According to the witness, the suspect ran
a red light and collided with the biker.
Judging from the tire marks, we estimated
the driver's speed to be around 60 km/h.
Cruel...
Hey, brat!
Don't go getting your hands all over evidence!
Say, Uncle...
How tall is this Takeuchi person?
His height...
He's a little taller than me, I guess.
Then, after the incident, maybe someone else drove this car.
That's nonsense!
Nobody would drive a car that was just involved in an accident.
But look over here at this seat.
See, the driver's seat has been moved forward, hasn't it?
I don't think even Uncle Kogorou could drive in this position.
It's true.
That would just work for me.
Say...
Did a female officer drive this car during the confiscation?
No way!
We never drive cars marked as evidence!
This car was towed from the suspect's residence.
Then, could it be the scene investigators
moved the seat during their examination?
No, they said they didn't move anything.
Prosecutor Kujou warned against it
as well, so there's no doubt about it.
That Madonna?
Yep, that's right.
She nagged and nagged about it.
When the biker crossed the street at that
intersection, that car hit them head on.
And, where were you then?
I was waiting on that corner for the light to turn green.
Man, this is bad...
The driver did brake to a stop, which made me
think they planned to help the biker, but...
They instead just made a run for it.
Did you happen to see the driver's face?
No, it was dark, after all.
And the driver didn't get out of their car.
I see...
Mr. Taxi Driver...
Could it be that the driver was a shrimp?
Why ask that, kid?
How about it?
Ah, well, the prosecutor asked that too.
But since the driver didn't get out...
I don't know if they were short or a woman.
Hold on a minute!
What's this about a woman!?
The one who confessed was a man!
I know that!
Since I'd read the papers, I thought her question was strange too.
And what did you answer, mister?
I didn't have an answer because I didn't see anything.
Guess so.
Well, what else did you notice?
Let's see...
Anything else I noticed...
Right, right!
Then the driver was making their getaway
I saw a small flash around this area.
Glare from their glasses, you mean?
No, it was brighter than that!
From accessories, then?
We're here.
Welcome, Ran-chan, Conan-kun.
From here, we have to wait and see how the police handle the case.
All right, I'll pay you afterwards, so please do your best.
Your husband looks tired, so please pay him a visit sometime.
I'd love to, but I'm a busy woman.
Please excuse me.
So you're saying the driver could have been a woman?
It seems Prosecutor Kujou asked the taxi driver about that.
The client I'm defending was lying, then?
Maybe he was covering for somebody!
A hit-and-run is a serious offense.
Who would want to take the fall for...
Could it be...
His wife?
The position of the seat seems to match his wife.
That must be why Prosecutor Kujou won't release him, huh?
Say, Kuriyama-san...
That lady said she was busy, but...
What does she do for a living?
After her father became hospitalized
following a cerebral hemorrhage...
She became the president of the company.
That must make that lady a powerful businesswoman.
But, unless there's something else going on, I don't
think that's why her husband wanted to take the fall...
Kuriyama-san.
Yes?
Call a private investigation company and gather enough manpower.
We need to reopen the investigation.
I'm on it.
This case...
Doesn't seem to be a simple hit-and-run...
Kujou-san?
May I have a moment?
Please wait ten minutes.
I still have 2 km left.
Well then, I'll wait in the lounge downstairs.
Understood.
My apologies, for calling you out during your break.
It's nothing.
And, what was it you wanted?
That's right.
I guess I'll be frank.
Please call for Takeuchi-san's immediate release.
The one you're aiming for isn't him, but instead his wife, no?
What is it you think you're doing?
You're arresting people without just cause, you know.
Or could you have your sights on something more?
I get it.
I'll approve his release.
Excuse me, I have work to do.
Wait, Kujou-san!
Kujou-san!
He was released?
Yeah, just now.
He's talking with Sensei now.
Even though you've been released...
That doesn't mean this problem is behind us.
If you really desire my help, I'll need the whole truth.
I've already told you everything, Kisaki-sensei.
Well, then.
I'd like to down a few glasses of wine after all this time.
Takeuchi-san...
You're really just acting as your wife's scapegoat, aren't you?
Why would you do something so foolish?
No, I was the one responsible.
Quit with the lying.
Have any proof to back that up?
The police are checking it out now.
If they had evidence to support that accusation,
would my wife not already be in handcuffs?
Do you really think you can talk that way with Prosecutor Kujou?
That female prosecutor is someone I know all too well.
What do you mean by that?
At any rate, I'll see you around.
Wait!
Uh-oh!
How naughty of you, kid.
Eavesdropping is a crime, you know.
Well, if you'll excuse me.
So that guy knew Prosecutor Kujou beforehand, huh?
What?
A suspect by the name of Takeuchi is on the line.
What should I do?
Got it.
I'll take it.
Line three.
Hello.
Kujou speaking.
A COMPANY-WIDE CRIME?
Takeuchi Construction Company
Subject of Construction Scandal
Found it!
Here it is!
What are you reading, Conan-kun?
It seems Takeuchi-san's company was involved in a scandal five
years ago, over some defective townhouse construction work.
Is that really true?
Yeah.
It was a big ordeal—even some politicians were involved.
The president committed suicide, though, and the primary
prosecutor ended up being reassigned elsewhere.
Why, something wrong with that?
It may not be directly related to today's case, but...
I wonder how Takeuchi-san came to know Prosecutor Kujou.
What?
You're telling me Takeuchi and that Madonna are acquaintances?
He said so at Kisaki-sensei's office.
He said he knew Prosecutor Kujou "all too well."
I didn't know he'd been arrested before this...
Say, Uncle...
I saw something about these kinds of cases on the news.
Aren't these handled by the Special Investigation Department?
I see...
So, if that Madonna was in the S.I.D...
And Takeuchi was involved in that case...
That must mean this guy's up to something.
Hello, this is Mouri Detective Office.
Kuriyama-san?
Yes, he's here.
Dad, it's Kuriyama-san.
It sounds urgent.
What is it?
What!?
Takeuchi's dead!?
What the hell's going on!?
How'd he die!?
Sensei, Mouri-san's here.
Honey...
Hey, what's going on?
Is Takeuchi really dead?
Yes.
He jumped from the balcony on the 6th floor.
It seems it was an instantaneous death.
He "jumped"?
You mean it was suicide?
It appears so.
That's crazy.
Why would he after just being released from jail?
I realize that, too!
I'm confused myself.
Could it have been an accident?
No chance.
His will was found.
And...
There was an eyewitness.
Eyewitness?
Hey, don't tell me...
I'll give you a ride.
You don't have a car, right?
No.
I'll call for a taxi.
Kujou-san...
Are you all right?
Hit-And-Run Suspect Committed Suicide
Pressure From the Prosecutor's Investigation!?
A Protesting Dive for the Cruel Prosecutor
You there, wait!
What do you think you're doing here!?
Leave at once!
I told you to leave!
You led my husband to his death!
Murderer!
Mariko-san, calm down.
My apologies, Prosecutor.
Please, if you would go.
Could I at least burn an incense?
Kujou-san...
Not today.
Well then, I'll visit another time.
Come on, I'll give you a ride.
I still have questions for you.
Thank you.
Would you mind if I asked you a few questions?
Sure, if I can answer them.
First, why did you go to Takeuchi-san's condo?
He called me that day.
He said he wanted to tell me the real truth, and invited me over.
What did he mean by the "real truth"?
About his wife?
Or maybe that case five years ago?
So you knew?
Looks like he was one of your fellow members in the S.I.D. right?
It started as an investigation into the
Takeuchi Construction scandal, but...
We began to suspect it involved bribery
on a political level and joined forces.
But then the key deponent of your case,
the construction design office's manager...
Committed suicide and turned the case into a maze, right?
And that manager was actually Takeuchi's boss.
I see, so that's how it is...
We could have resolved the case on his testimony, but...
He suddenly changed his story entirely...
Which caused me to have no choice but to cease the prosecution.
And then, he married into Takeuchi Construction...
And became a key figure in the company.
Then, five years later, he became your
suspect in that hit-and-run accident, right?
From the beginning, I suspected he was covering for his wife.
But...
I didn't want to lose the chance to reopen that case.
And that's why you held him on further grounds, huh?
My apologies.
But still, if he said he wanted to tell you the truth...
Why would he jump to his death beforehand?
That's something I wish I knew as well.
It certainly is strange.
Would you mind detailing what the situation was?
At 8:00 that day...
I arrived at his condo.
Hold it!
Thanks, I made it.
Oh, Prosecutor!
Going to see my husband?
Yes, you could say that.
I assume you're on your way home?
Actually...
I rushed here after receiving a strange e-mail from my husband.
A strange e-mail?
"Thanks for taking care of me for all these years."
"But please forget about me now, and find happiness elsewhere."
It does seem very unnatural.
Honey?
Where are you?
Honey!
Honey!?
What are you doing out there?
Stop this!
Prosecutor, please stop my husband!
I'm coming.
He's on the balcony!
Takeuchi-san!
What are you...
It can't be...
Honey!
It's peculiar...
To call a prosecutor and commit suicide.
Something doesn't feel right.
But really...
I still can't believe Takeuchi-san committed suicide.
He jumped off right in front of his wife and the prosecutor.
No doubt about it.
But, you know...
The day before, Takeuchi-san came to
my bar here and drank rather joyfully.
Joyfully?
He said that, now that he'd regained his freedom...
He'd like to take a nice, long vacation out of the country.
But he was only on a conditional release and
the hearing hadn't even been rescheduled!
I said that too.
That's when he replied by saying the
hearing would go well no matter what.
He was most concerned with divorcing
his wife and hitting the reset button.
That's crazy.
He'd already covered for his wife, so he must've still loved her.
But it sounds like they'd already agreed to a divorce...
The hell's that about...
It's definitely strange.
Why did Takeuchi-san wear these?
And what's with those marks?
Hey, you glasses-wearing brat!
Don't you dare go putting your nose in my files!
Say, why'd Takeuchi-san wear those when he committed suicide?
Because look, for someone who was about to die, it's
unlikely he'd wear a suit jacket like he was going out.
Guess he figured he was on a one-way trip
to death and wanted to look the part.
But jeans instead of trousers?
I guess he was just confused and unfocused.
And also...
From the middle of the jacket down to the knees of the jeans...
Aren't there some friction marks there?
What're those from?
Hey, what do you think?
For some reason, I feel there's something strange about his suicide...
How should I know!?
Don't poke your nose into adult business!
But didn't you find it strange as well, Uncle?
Isn't that why you borrowed the evidence files?
Shut up.
Where are you going, Dad?
Pachinko!
Wait, Dad!
What about the case?
There aren't any bricks, huh?
Hey, brat!
You read the files, right?
It mentioned a contusion caused by a
brick near the victim's posterior cranium.
Geez, just take a good look over there.
See that mark outlining the victim's head?
It's right near that brick flower plot.
But if you're saying he smashed his head onto the bricks there...
Wouldn't it have at least bent the flowers?
Not to mention that the bricks would have broken, right?
He did fall from the 6th...
Why is that...
She said she couldn't stay in a place where
her husband had killed himself...
So the missus moved back to her parents' house.
I guess she's gonna sell this condo.
Hey, brat!
Well then, Mouri-san; please return the keys
to the manager's office when you're done.
Got it.
So it is here after all...
But why is that satellite dish antenna facing downwards?
This is the balcony in question, huh?
So he jumped from here...
Where's that brick?
It's soil.
I see, the brick was exchanged!
And most likely from that flower pot.
Now it's down to how to have him fall in front of Prosecutor Kujou...
The hook on the hanging rod is bent.
I see.
Where is it?
Where?
It can't be disposed of, can it?
Dammit...
Found it!
Now I know...
Why the body was wearing a suit jacket...
Why there were friction marks
between the abdomen and the knee...
And why the antenna faced downwards, the hook bent outwards.
This is a murder case.
What?
Attorney Kisaki wishes to speak with you.
Let her in.
Please.
Thank you.
Kujou-san...
Want to take a walk?
Yeah, sure.
Thanks for the other day.
Did you receive a follow-up call regarding Takeuchi-san's case?
Yes.
With the suspect deceased, the case has been dropped.
I brought enormous trouble to you as well, Kisaki-sensei.
By the way...
I heard that you requested approval for your resignation.
That true?
Are you telling me you wish to quit being a prosecutor?
It's a fact that my actions led to a suspect's suicide.
I am prepared for any punishment that may be handed down.
And what of the hit-and-run case?
Another prosecutor will be collecting evidence
and preparing to prosecute his wife.
Are you sure this is all right?
The law demands that the truth be uncovered.
It has no relation to my personal matters.
Is that true even if you're letting the murderer off the hook?
Murder?
Yes.
Takeuchi-san's murder was only made to appear
a suicide, or at least that's a strong possibility.
That's impossible.
I saw it myself!
And what was it you saw, with your naked eyes?
Takeuchi-san, what are you...
And where was his wife?
I don't know.
I was transfixed with stopping Takeuchi-san.
I didn't pay any attention to his wife.
Could it be...
The wife had a motive to kill her husband.
Then, are you telling me that it was all planned by her?
If she could call a prosecutor as her eyewitness...
The follow-up investigation would be nothing but red tape.
The investigators would never doubt your testimony, would they?
That's true.
How awful...
I hadn't even considered that possibility.
What now?
If you quit, you'll be walking right into her trap.
Is that all right?
Kisaki-sensei, excuse me, but I must go.
I have to get back to my work.
Hello?
Sasaki-kun, bring me a complete copy of the
investigation into Takeuchi-san's case.
Oh, and get in touch with the police
officer in charge immediately.
At 11:00 PM on the day in question,
the defendant, Takeuchi Mariko...
Drove her car through an intersection in Toriya City...
And hit Matsukawa Yasuyuki's on his
bicycle as he was crossing the road.
She did not stop but instead sped away.
Afterwards, she ordered her husband,
Takeuchi Hiroaki, to surrender to the police.
All in order to cover up deeds all her own.
So they pointed the finger at the wife
because the husband committed suicide?
Yeah.
I guess even that Madonna's nerves were
wrecked after being grilled by the media, huh?
Say, Conan kun, if the wife could be the
one responsible for the hit-and-run...
Why did Mom decide to defend her?
I think she's definitely up to something.
How will the tables turn now?
Does the defendant admit to the crime?
I am innocent!
That woman pressured my husband to his death even when he
gave himself up to the police, and yet she's trying to take...
Silence.
Should the defendant wish to dispute, the
time for that will be during their rebuttal.
Let us proceed with verifying the evidence.
Prosecutor?
Yes, your Honor.
The trace evidence covers results from the vehicle in question:
Including a fingerprint lifted from the steering wheel...
Glass shards and paint chips collected from the scene...
Along with a paint mark collected from the victim's bicycle.
The banquet ended at 10:00, and the CEO drove herself home.
Thank you.
No further questions, your Honor.
All right.
Will the defense please proceed with the cross-examination?
Yes, your Honor.
Tanishima-san, I would like to ask one question.
Did you really see, with your own eyes,
the defendant driving home by herself?
Well, I was busy talking to a client...
"Yes" or "no," if would please.
No, I did not.
No further questions.
Such a good thing that I paid you a ton.
Your Honor...
The defense would like to summon a special witness.
Prosecutor, the defense has submitted
a request to call a special witness.
Do you have any objection?
No, your Honor.
With that, will the special witness for the defense...
Mouri Kogorou, please step forward.
Prosecutor, is this all right?
Yes, it's no problem.
Even Dad was...
Show me your best, Uncle.
Well then, Mouri-san.
Are you and Takeuchi Hiroaki-san acquaintances?
Yeah, I met him at a bar I often visit.
In that case, to your knowledge, had Takeuchi-san
ever driven under the influence before?
No - as far as I know, he never had.
That's why, once I had heard he was
supposedly involved in a DUI incident...
My clever little cells began to tip
me off that something was amiss!
After some investigating...
I started to doubt that his wife was the one behind all this.
And why was that?
Many reasons, but I'd like to focus on the reason
why he would have became his wife's scapegoat.
I'd heard that that couple argued all the time.
So if not for love, it would be something more
that made the husband want to take the fall.
And what is that "something else"?
That is - freedom.
Freedom?
Yes, freedom.
He swallowed his pride to be married to his boss's daughter.
After his boss, or rather, his father-in-law,
fell ill, his wife became the new CEO.
He was forced to see his wife's bossy look whether
he was home or at work, every single day!
It must've been worse than living in hell!
Oh, no, as I was saying...
He must've volunteered to become
the fall-guy in return for a divorce.
The defense, please approach.
The prosecution as well.
What exactly was it the defense meant for him to say?
After hearing Mouri-san's testimony, I began to feel
he was better suited as a witness for the prosecution.
I intended to make clear the background of this case,
primarily the defendant's relationship with her husband.
And what about for the prosecution?
I aimed to establish this as a homicide case.
Homicide case?
It seems I need to hear more from the both of you.
We will recess and halt the witnesses testimony for thirty minutes.
You two come to my chambers.
Conan-kun, where are you going?
Just the restroom!
Would you mind explaining what's going on here?
I was under the impression you two were aware today's
court was in place only to try the hit-and-run case.
Yes, of course.
However, I would like to note that this case is
closely related to the death of Takeuchi Hiroaki.
If I could establish this, it could have a grand
effect on the examination of today's case.
Understood.
Given that even the prosecution believes this to be
necessary, I'll allow Mouri-san to continue his testimony.
However!
If he causes confusion in today's court, I'll
have no choice but to dismiss the hearing.
Are we clear?
Especially for you, Kujou-kun.
I cannot help but assume that your
personal matters are weighing into this.
I understand.
Looks like it's time for Uncle to leave the stage.
Silence.
We will now resume session.
Where has Conan-kun gone?
Now, if the witness would please continue his testimony.
All right then...
Let us return to our main topic.
As I was saying before...
It was Prosecutor Kujou who was waiting
for Takeuchi, the scapegoat for his wife.
Then, when she called upon him to speak of
the construction scandal from five years ago...
There was an idea that occurred to him.
And what idea was that?
After seeing that the prosecutor still wouldn't
let go of that case from five years earlier...
This appeared to be a great opportunity to blackmail his own wife.
In other words, he was not only thinking of freedom,
but of getting away with a large sum of his wife's money.
A hundred million yen!?
What do you mean by that?
Our deal was to pay you 30 million yen for
divorce and taking the fall, wasn't it?
I had to stay in jail because of you, so up goes the price.
There's no way I can pay that much!
No worries if you don't.
I'll just go and tell that prosecutor everything I know.
How would you like to get put behind
bars along with that sick father of yours?
And it was then that Takeuchi's wife began thinking of killing him.
Hey, what do you mean "killing"?
Defendant!
Silence.
Witness, are you saying that you believe the death of
Takeuchi Hiroaki to be connected to the defendant?
That's exactly it.
Your Honor...
I ask that you consider his testimony in
order to shed some light on this case.
What are you saying!?
You're supposed to be my attorney!
What is the prosecution's opinion?
The prosecution shares the same feeling
that the truth should be revealed.
Witness, please continue with your testimony.
Wait a second, why am I being...
Defendant!
You will only speak when called upon!
Proceed.
That day, Takeuchi called Prosecutor Kujou under the
front of confessing the truth, and invited her over.
Of course, this was likely a bluff
designed to have his wife pay up.
That's far from enough, you know
A huge sum like 100 hundred million, it's impossible for
me to gather that much in such a short amount of time!
Well, just make out an IOU.
What!?
In just two hours, the prosecutor will arrive.
What should I tell her?
I guess we can start with the truth
behind that hit-and-run, huh?
And I know she'd love to hear the dark secret
behind that construction scandal five years ago.
And that was the moment the wife resorted to murder.
But Mouri-san, I was told Takeuchi-san
jumped in front of an eyewitness.
Takeuchi wore a suit jacket when he
appeared to be jumping off the balcony.
But, with that, he wore a pair of jeans.
That's where the trick lies.
After his wife killed him, Takeuchi's
body was dressed with the suit jacket...
And a hanger was placed at the back.
Then, she took the body onto the balcony and leaned it outwards...
Tied one end of a rope to the hanger...
And ran the other end over a hook above him,
before bringing the rest to the bedroom.
All she has to do is pull the rope
with enough force from the bedroom.
With the body being raised upward by the
rope, it gives the illusion that he's standing.
Lies!
Why the hell do I have to...
Defendant!
Wait for your rebuttal.
But, witness, a trick like that would make the body stand,
but would not be enough to make it fall over, correct?
Correct.
In order to achieve that, the pulling force
would have to come not only from above...
But also from the front.
So, to pull from the front...
She used the satellite dish as a fulcrum
and passed the rope behind it...
Before tying it to the chest of the body.
Then, all that was left was to place
the fake will in the living room...
And wait for Prosecutor Kujou's arrival.
Hold it!
She would pretend that she just came back from
work, opening the door with Prosecutor Kujou.
Honey?
Where are you?
Honey!
Honey!?
What are you doing out there!?
Stop this!
Takeuchi-san!
What are you...
Most likely, due to the fact that it was dark and
the sheer shock of seeing someone jumping...
Even Prosecutor Kujou wasn't able to notice the unnatural
movement he showed nor his wife's location at the time.
Stop talking nonsense!
Do you have proof?
You figured the rope would come
out smoothly when you pulled...
But it got tangled up on the dish, causing it to
bow downward unlike those your neighbors own.
Who knows when the dish antenna started facing downwards!
Maybe it was already like that...
I also found the distorted hanger in your bedroom closet.
I planned to throw it away after bending it sometime before!
There was human hair and blood on the
brick under your outdoor A/C unit.
Stop screwing with me!
I'd already gotten rid of that bri—...
You exchanged it with one of the bricks under the flower plot.
The brick that was used as the murder weapon
was already collected and examined.
What is this?
You all teamed up to incriminate me...
Silence!
But!
Be quiet, Defendant.
This court is no longer in session.
The next hearing will be scheduled
after we've come to a decision.
The prosecution will move forward
with the new case as a homicide.
Dismissed!
Welcome, Kujou-san.
Thanks for taking care of me the other day.
Due to that case, I've been given a six-month salary deduction
as punishment and am on technical leave for a month.
I see, that's too bad.
I was grilled by the higher-ups as well.
But, oh well, it looks like it's a good break for me.
I haven't been on vacation for a while now.
Take it nice and slow.
Forget about the case.
Yes.
Say, Prosecutor Kujou, where are you going?
You even brought a suitcase.
Well, I'm heading to Tottori.
My former boss's third anniversary memorial
is coming up, so I plan to visit his grave.
I see.
Have a safe trip.
Thanks, and excuse me.
Let's meet in court again next time.
I won't lose to you.
Same goes for me.
Until then.
That's good.
She's back to her old self.
Yeah.
The "Madonna" among prosecutors.
Welcome back.