What I mean is: four, five or six.
I've had six cases this month. Count 'em, six. Kudo, what about you?
Ah, me?
I've solved seven cases.
Dang, I lose again!
But say, Kudo, doesn't it seem that an awful lot of cases occur around you?
Translator's Note: The ji character in Heiji's name means next or follows.
Well, if your resigned to defeat, then the way you write your name suits you.
Translator's Note: The ichi character in Shin'ichi's name means one or best.
I'm Shin'ichi; therefore, I'm number one.
Idiot, you're number two.
Eh? Number two?
Yeah, it happened a while ago.
There was someone whose brain was sharper than yours.
A detective.
Middle school detectives Heiji & Shin'ichi fight a deduction battle on the ski slope!
Will they solve the lift riding mystery?
Perceiving the one and only truth.
With the body of a child and the brain of an adult.
His name is: Detective Conan!
HATTORI HEIJI vs KUDO SHIN'ICHI
DEDUCTION SHOWDOWN ON THE SKI SLOPE
Kazuha, say, are you all right?
If your leg's sprained badly, shouldn't you go back to the hotel?
It's fine, I said. Fine.
Being alone at the hotel would be boring. It'll be more fun to be where I can watch everyone skiing.
And also...
Ah, sorry, sorry.
Translator's Note: Jizou statue - Statue of the popular Buddhist deity Jizou (a bodhisattva who guards children). A common sight throughout Japan.
So what I thought was a homely Jizou statue sitting in the snow is really a person?
What the heck's wrong with you? This is the fifth time!
Apologize to Kazuha now!
Why should I have to apologize?
I'm just tossing snow on her sprain so it'll cool down and heal faster.
Teacher! Hattori-kun is flirting with some girls again!
What'd you guys say?
He's got nothing to do with us!
The old ladies are getting angry!
Old ladies?!
H-Hey...
Kazuha.
Give it up and hurry back to the hotel; you'll catch a cold.
Y-Yeah.
Why are boys like that?
Translator's Note: Yuki-onna (Snow Woman) - A youkai (spirit) popular in Japanese folk tales who appears as a beautiful woman on snowy nights and lures travelers to their deaths.
I hope the Yuki-onna of this mountain eats you for dinner!
Y-Yuki-onna?
The teacher told us a folklore story about these mountains called The Legend of the Yuki-onna's Silver Gown.
A long time ago on this very mountain, there was an extraordinarily beautiful woman who wore a silver gown that sparkled with white light
She caught sight of a good man traveling by foot on the mountain and she began to beguile him with a voice like the song of a snowstorm.
"Will you exchange your most treasured possession for my silver gown?" she said.
The foolish man was overcome with lust by the sight of the white skin beneath the gown, and so he agreed to the condition.
A-And then?
While the man was bundling the delicate gown in a wrapping cloth, he said:
My only really treasured possession is this gun, but do you really want it?
And the woman responded from behind him:
That's not it.
In that case, do you want money?
My hat?
That's not it.
Then, without making a sound, the woman embraced him from behind with her naked body and:
Not cold things like those.
What I desperately want are the warm, warm...
...drops of blood...
...from your heart!
She cried.
Later, when they found the man's body, inside the wrapping cloth, instead of the silver gown,
it was said they only found a large quantity of snow.
They say whenever there's a blizzard on this mountain, another victim appears.
It seems there was a new, awfully similar incident here four years ago.
Hey! Kaihou Academy Middle School students! Lunch!
It's already past two o'clock.
Eh? Really?
No wonder I was hungry.
It looks like some other school is staying at this hotel too.
So it seems they shifted the time so we wouldn't get mixed-up in the cafeteria.
Hey, isn't that Minowa Shouhei, the actor?
Minowa Shouhei (32)
Actor
What's he doing here?
Oh yeah! I heard on TV they were making a movie based on an incident that really happened up on the snowy mountain.
Huh? I heard it was a mystery movie about the Yuki-onna.
Heh, whatever.
Well, in any case, since that Minowa Shouhei guy is the lead,
no matter which mysterious incident they're going for, I think he'll play the role of detective.
Detective eh?
Excuse me, I heard you'll be filming the third and concluding episode in the Yuki-onna series this time.
But didn't they say it would be a motif about an actual incident?
That's correct too.
The deceased was my friend and our stuntman.
I was there where it happened, you see.
Excuse me, Minowa-kun.
The fact that the deceased was our Mizugami Jirou-kun is kind of a secret.
What are you saying?
People on the Internet already know we're filming something about our late friend.
Ooyama Morizou (56)
Movie Director
Hey, now. This film is being made in memory of his death.
Well, it's OK, isn't it?
Someone who's dead and gone isn't going to come back and do handstands about it
If we say our last movie is being devoted to Mizugami Jirou,
it might bring out the sympathy of the audience.
Mimata Kousuke (27)
Stuntman
That way the movie will be a hit or even our best.
We should be grateful to Mizugami-senpai; he might make this movie a success.
And so should you, after all it was due to his death that you got the job as his replacement.
Hey, shouldn't you be more careful?
After all, you're the one who has to take on the deceased Mizugami's stuntman role.
Tateishi Shizuku (31)
Make-Up Specialist
Don't be lured by the Yuki-onna, OK?
Yeah, yeah.
But, I still don't really understand...
Why would Mizugami-kun go and leave a fiancée like you?
To have ended his own life...
Who knows.
It wasn't suicide; it was murder.
And I figure one of you was the murderer.
It's that police detective again.
No, he's not a police detective anymore.
I was canned for putting too much time into the incident on this mountain, which was in the wrong prefecture.
Katashina Rikuto (35)
Private Detective
Now I run a simple private detective business.
But still, no matter how you look at it, he committed suicide!
It does look that way.
Four years ago, a man riding alone on the lift at this ski joint, had a bullet shot through his head by a pistol and stopped drawing breath.
There was a gun in his right hand, gunpowder residue on his cuff.
Considering it normally, it looked like he offed himself with the pistol, but...
It was a trick.
Why had the bag sitting on the seat beside him been packed with a large quantity of snow?
That's because he was imitating the legend of the Yuki-onna that's told in these mountains.
That's stupid. I've known that guy since he was a kid.
He never gave a hoot about ghost stories.
And, even assuming that was true, I can't understand the reason for it.
Who knows?
Since we don't know how to ask a dead man, here's what I say...
If it was murder, it would be one no human could possibly have done, an impossible crime.
Yet, if we assume it could be done, naturally it could only have been the beautiful demon of the snowy mountain, the Yuki-onna.
Are you dumb or what?
It's called a crime because a human being did it! And what's more, how could it be impossible! Idiot!
Someone said that earlier.
A boy came and objected to this story saying the same things that you just did.
He was a middle-school student around the same age as you.
A-A middle-schooler?
H-Heiji
Exactly. You made such a big scene in the cafeteria, someone must be making fun of you and laughing.
Idiot! That was because you were frightened by that Yuki-onna talk.
I just thought I'd wake up your sleepy-thinking head.
I wasn't frightened! I just thought it sounded real.
Yuki-onna stories... There are a lot of them that are sad and feel real.
Ah, it definitely sounded mysterious.
In Japan's most famous Yuki-onna story, the monster is called "Woman of the Snow." Isn't that right?
English? Doesn't the Yuki-onna come from a Japanese story?
No, it's from Japanese folklore.
Translator's Note: Lafcadio Hearn was a writer and journalist who moved to Japan in 1890 and wrote a number of works including Kwaidan: Stories and Studies of Strange Things, in which the story in question is included.
That story was written in Japan by an English teacher; Lafcadio Hearn he was called.
It was published in English. You've heard of Koizumi Yakumo? That was his pen name.
Yes, yes. Shin'ichi is so clever that he knows everything.
But, thank you. You said those things so I wouldn't be frightened, didn't you?
Even though I didn't say it, I had a bad feeling.
A premonition that this might turn into a storm.
Wait, Heiji. What would you do if a real Yuki-onna appeared?
Idiot, if there were such a woman, I'd like to meet her.
Heiji!
To solve this four-year old case, first I have to examine the lift in question.
And I need to get ahead of that other middle-schooler.
You don't need to worry about that It just means there's another person who thinks the same as you.
That's why I can't lose! If he beats me, people will think I'm at a middle-schooler's level too.
You are a middle-schooler.
There's the couple in love!
Idiot, it's not like that!
They say when two people trace out their love with their ski tracks, the snow will melt!
I see, she's talking about those other people.
Well, if you're going to check out the lift, you'll have to come back later when this snowstorm's settled down.
That's OK, but first...
Ah, excuse me.
Ah, no, it was my fault.
Heiji?
Hey! Knock it off already!
You've been watching us and filming for quite a while.
Heiji, it's OK! She's probably just filming the snow-covered scenery.
No, no. This old lady's been filming me!
Because she's my mom!
That's my Heiji. You're perceptive instincts are just like Heizou's.
But, what are you doing here?
Heiji's almost never been to the north-east before, so I was worried!
Don't be silly! She's just adding to the video collection she's making of me from when I was born all the way until I'm an adult
I think I want to see that.
There was a snowstorm just like this then too.
On that day four years ago when Mizugami-kun committed suicide.
t feels like that day too. Were we're also waiting until we could film.
And Minowa-kun was surrounded by fans then also.
Looks like the snowstorm is starting to settle down.
Ah, you're right.
So, will you let us see you ski?
Show us you're skiing techniques from Yuki-onna's Love and Mystery.
Please!
That'll be difficult We'll be starting to film now.
No way!
Since we got here, you fans have demanded he ski for you three times already.
If you want to see him skiing, go and watch the movies!
What should I do?
Wei I, the schedule is tight, but we have to make sacrifices for our important fans.
Wouldn't Mizugami-senpai have said it this way?
It will work out somehow.
Geez, he's no longer here, so forget that stuff!
Sorry. Here you and Mizugami-kun were going to become man and wife, and we have you involved in this movie about his death.
No, I was the one who asked to participate. One way or another I feel there's something I need to know.
Some truth about his death might come out when we film this movie.
Two places then...
What?
You can see it from below. There are two places where the lift gets close to the slope.
Then, could somebody have jumped on?
No, it gets close, but it's still three meters difference.
It'd be impossible without a trampoline.
Isn't that the Minowa Shouhei guy we saw at the hotel?
He's pretty good.
Encore! Encore! Encore! Encore! Encore!
No way, that was the one time for today.
For the next one, please watch the movie.
It's already close to four. We need to hurry and shoot the scene at the top of the slope.
Then why don't you ride the lift up before me. It'll be pitch black after five.
Hey, Director.
Have you seen hide or hair of the make-up specialist girl or the stuntman?
Ah, those two said they were starting up on the lift before us.
There's something...
There's definitely something about this lift.
H-Hey, Heiji. Doesn't this lift scare you?
What's that, Kazuha? Since you're in the advanced class, you've been on lifts before, haven't you?
I have, but they were a different type than this one.
Oh no, it starting to blow up again.
I can't even see the outline of the detective guy that's riding ahead of us anymore.
Hey, Tateishi-san!
Ah, Mimata-kun!
What are you doing on the down lift?
I kinda missed my chance to get off.
I'm not very good with things like this.
Shin'ichi!
W-What was that noise?
The sound of a pistol. That's what the sound was.
The director, Ooyama.
The actor, Minowa.
Then the detective guy. That was the order.
D-Did something happen?
Ah, it's you.
Well, I don't know. I was just getting off now too.
Stop the lift!
Take a look and figure it out! At that!
Just stop the lift right away! Then call the police and paramedics!
What is it, Shin'ichi? Did something happen?
Ran, don't look!
The lift's stopped.
What's going on? First that "bang" noise, now a scream.
The lift, a gunshot Could it be that the same thing that happened four years ago is happening now?
We are extremely sorry for any inconvenience to our guests. Please wait a short while until lift operations are restored.
What does that mean? It's like that day.
Yeah, it is.
When Mizugami-senpai shot himself. That day.
Mizugami...
The muzzle of the gun was pressed into his temple. Bang! It's suicide.
Yeah. He was holding the gun in his right hand.
The problem is this bag next to the dead man.
I have an unpleasant feeling that I know what's inside.
Like I thought, it's snow.
Geez, it's just like four years ago.
I think I remember hearing that you were going to film a movie here.
Yeah.
A movie relating the incident four years ago to the legend.
But now our lead actor, Minowa-kun, has ended up like this.
Eh, Minowa? The actor?
If I'm not mistaken, you were there at the time of the incident four years ago as well.
I'm the movie's director, Ooyama. I was riding the lift directly in front of his.
When I heard the gunshot, I was just getting off the lift
That boy was the one who noticed what happened to Minowa-kun.
Hey, kid! What do you think you're doing?
Excuse me, if we don't start the lift soon, what will we do about the customers?
OK, once we get the body and check for any related articles, you can start it up.
Need a hand?
No, it's relatively light.
He's slimmer than he looks, no more than 60 kilograms (132lbs).
He wouldn't appear in anything except winter dramas and movies.
He said he didn't want people to see his underweight body.
But why did he have his skis behind him instead of wearing them?
Well now, that's probably because he had to carry this bag stuffed with snow.
Although it's full of snow now, it's big enough for a child to fit in.
OK, go ahead and start the lift.
Ah, Mr. Policeman!
There are three points I'm concerned about.
Ah, it's finally moving.
There are a lot of people gathered there. I'm afraid.
Idiot! It's making me all excited!
Outsiders stay back! Stay back!
What? What happened?
Ah, it's you, kid.
Roughly, according to what they said, it looks like it's the same as the case four years ago.
It seems a man riding by himself on the lift, with a bag full of snow beside him, shot himself with a gun.
As if he'd been possessed by the Yuki-onna.
Geez, you again.
This isn't your jurisdiction!
Nope, I've quit being a police detective. I'm private now.
And what's more, I was riding on the lift directly behind the victim.
Don't you have some things to ask me, Mr. Detective?
"Victim?" He committed suicide!
No, it's too early to decide that
H-Hey, Heiji! Save me!
What are you doing? Hurry and get off!
How? I don't know how to get off!
In that case, when you reach the bottom the lift will stop again. Be sure to get off then.
OK. OK.
That idiot, that's why I told her not to come.
Come to think of it, there was another customer who didn't get off earlier.
Is that true?
Yeah, it was a pretty woman who had her hair tied in the back.
Noway! Minowa-kun killed himself? Why?
Before we wonder why, could you answer a few questions for me?
Like why you didn't get off the lift here before.
I couldn't get off! I'm not good with these things.
Isn't that kinda strange? Shouldn't you have come here four years ago to film that movie?
That time Mizugami-kun rode up with me. This time I came with Mimata-kun.
She's not very athletic.
Huh? Didn't I hear from the director that you went up earlier?
How is it you were riding the lift with her?
The film crew was standing by but the director and lead actor hadn't come up yet So I skied down to call them.
On the way I noticed her riding down on the lift, and when I called to her, the gunshot went off.
I had a strange premonition about it, and so I asked Mimata-kun to ride up on the lift with me, and that's how we came up here.
Because of what happened four years ago.
And then the lift stopped, and we were just now able to get off.
I see. In other words, the director, Ooyama, who rode the lift in front of Minowa-san,
the detective, Katashina-san, who rode behind,
Tateishi-san, who was on the down lift as it passed by,
and Mimata-san, who was on the slope.
All of you were able to shoot Minowa-san.
H-Hey...
Hey, now! Didn't you hear what I said just now? When the gunshot went off, I was with Mimata-kun.
If that gunshot was a fake, then the crime becomes possible. That's what you were going to say, right, kid?
Yeah, that's it exactly.
But don't you remember that Minowa-kun was holding onto the gun?
How could something like that be done from a distance?
You aren't going to say we held onto the murder weapon after shooting him are you?
Furthermore, at the time the snow was blowing pretty violently.
Wouldn't you think it'd be impossible to shoot him without a considerable degree of skill?
Well, I haven't considered all that yet, but there are some things that are suspicious.
First of all, the ski poles from the lift Minowa-san was riding.
The circular fittings attached to the ends have been inverted on both poles.
That's proof they were used for something.
The next one is the lift Minowa-san was riding.
In the plastic on the left side of the seat, there's a place where it's been cracked.
That could also have been used for some kind of trick.
And the last one is the cloth bag that Minowa-san had riding beside him, stuffed with snow.
I don't why, but it's frozen solid.
Stop that You mustn't touch the evidence.
But I must say everywhere I go nowadays there are middle-school students brimming with curiosity.
There was one earlier. A middle-school student who was arrogantly pointing out the exact same three points to us policemen as you did.
What did you say?
He was here just before you came.
I'm finally off. I'm never riding that lift again.
Kazuha!
Aren't you in the advanced ski class?
And you don't know how to get off a lift?
Confess!
You wanted to be in the same advanced class with Hattori, didn't you?
So your sprained leg is fake too...
Ah! That's not true!
It's OK, we'll keep it a secret from Hattori.
Excuse me! Is there anyone here who happened to videotape Minowa-san earlier when he was getting on the lift?
I'm really sorry.
You're welcome to my video.
Ah, thank you.
My, this is really well filmed.
I would have expected Minowa-san's fans to only follow him.
No, my son asked me to do that He told me to film the lift boarding platform as a reference for the incident four years ago.
Is your son a police detective or something?
He's just a regular middle-school student It seems he wants to be a detective though.
Detective, eh? It's the same with me.
What's this? Shin-chan is busy chatting with some beautiful madame.
Geez, he sure takes after someone.
Nope, that face is his detective face. He's still a greenie.
So, can the self-styled world's preeminent mystery writer solve this case?
Yukiko, that's a silly question.
Eh? Yu-chan already figured it out?
But I just came here to get hints about the incident four years ago for a book I'm writing.
But it's already too late, what with that movie their filming. And then virtually the same incident occurs a second time...
Hey, if you know who the criminal is, rush over and tell the police.
Nope, I'm going to entrust this to the youngsters and sit back and watch what develops.
But won't you give me a little hint?
Do you know? There's another legend in these mountains about the Yuki-onna.
A painful and sad tale...
What? The actor, Minowa-san, committed suicide?
Are you sure, Heiji!?
Don't use such a loud voice!
This is still off-the-record.
But why do I have to be quiet?
Wei I, I'm still not sure what happened.
For a suicide, it was suspicious.
It's just like a case from four years ago.
But it really was suicide, wasn't it?
That's exactly why I need to see the video.
Well? Did you figure something out, Heiji?
Just as I thought...
It was definitely murder.
You know, I didn't expect this video to be so popular.
Popular?
There were some other people besides you who asked to see this video.
Don't tell me it was a middle-schooler!
Yes, one of them was.
One of them? You mean there were others?
A long while before that boy, there was a dandily dressed man with a mustache.
A man with a mustache?
Another Yuki-onna legend?
Is there a hint about this case in it?
Listen to the whole story before you ask questions.
A long time ago, on a snowy evening...
Descending from the mountain and hurrying along the road home was a man by the name of Mokichi.
Along the road, he came across a very beautiful woman with long hair dressed in a silver gown.
The woman gave him a friendly look and said:
I've injured my leg on the mountain.
I can no longer manage even a single step.
Would you please carry me to my home?
When Mokichi inquired where her home was, without speaking she pointed at the dark black forest where no road ran.
However, the farther and farther they went, the deeper the snow became, and they never came within sight of the house.
The Yamato man earnestly inquired:
Have I perhaps lost the way?
The woman nodded silently.
She had been waiting...
For the man to abandon her.
Yes...
The woman's true character was one who waits until a man's strength falters, and then consumes his soul: a Yuki-onna.
Before long the man's progress started to slow, and after a long silence, his lips began to move:
Miss...
The woman had been waiting and hoping for this, and with a smile she replied:
Yes? What is it?
Out of breath, in a strained voice Mokichi said:
Aren't you cold?
The man's unexpected question surprised the Yuki-onna and left her at a loss for words.
Mokichi was numb from the cold, and afraid for his life, but nevertheless he continued:
It's uncomfortable in that basket, isn't it?
Aren't you hungry?
Just a little more patience. Hold on. Just hold on!
The woman's only reply was "yes".
Her voice gradually grew weaker, until at last he could no longer hear her.
Concerned, he stopped walking...
And when he peered into the basket...
The woman had disappeared.
In her place there was only a large quantity of snow wrapped inside her silver gown.
I see.
The warmth of Mokichi's heart melted the Yuki-onna's cold one, right?
Yeah.
And?
Where was the hint in that?
Hmm. As I feared, the load was too heavy for you, wasn't it?
But for him, it might make a good practice exercise.
Him?
Perhaps he's watching Minowa-san's movies at the hotel now, if he really is my son.
Look! Just as I thought!
Didn't you think Minowa-san's skiing in this video is a little different from what we saw today?
Really? I think they're both great
He's a well known professional after all.
Hey, look!
This part, where Minowa-san is rescuing the heroine that fainted.
When he's skiing down, until he goes out of frame, his cap strap... Look, it's attached.
But when he comes into the frame again, when he rushes over to her, it's no longer attached.
Even though they're both in the same cut
It's true...
Could it be a double?
Maybe he can't really ski.
That can't be it! Earlier he was really ripping! It was cool!
Are you sure it was him?
Of course I am!
I have it on video.
See, told you.
Say, Sonoko...
Do you know where Minowa-san left his bag while he was skiing?
Oh, he left it in front of his fans.
He said there was something important in it and asked us to watch it until he returned.
Souvenir Counter
What? This bag?
A middle-schooler came to look at it?
When was this?
Just a bit ago. He didn't buy one though.
Ah, if that's too small for your needs, we have a larger size with the same design.
Ah, no thanks.
This belt can be lengthened like this; that can be very convenient.
Ah, it really is!
How's that convenient?
Hey Heiji, what are you so angry about?
Why shouldn't I be?
No matter where I go, that middle-schooler is one step ahead of me.
He rented the video from the hotel before me.
And then there's that weird guy with the mustache.
If this keeps up, they'll solve the case before me.
You mean you haven't figured anything out yet, Heiji?
No, I already knew who the murderer was and how they did it when we were back in the shop.
If that case, shouldn't you go to the police right away?
But it's not completely solved!
Like the inverted ring on the ski poles and the frozen bag full of snow...
If I can't figure those out, then my reasoning won't be complete.
What is it, Shizu? Didn't I tell you not to make personal calls to me while I'm working?
What? A case you say?
Found it!
This is it!
What is it?
Remember? Didn't we hear a sound just before the deceased Minowa-san reached the top of the lift?
A sound like a gunshot?
Since they haven't retrieved this yet...
The criminal must still be somewhere they can't get away from.
Oh, sounds like you know everything already.
No, the crucial trick used to commit the murder still hasn't come to me.
The crack left on the lift to the left side of the corpse...
What caused that?
And that bag of snow. Even though I know who the criminal is, I don't see how that's connected.
Eh? You know who the criminal is?
Yeah, it's one of the four suspects the police are questioning now.
The one who was riding the lift just before Minowa-san: Ooyama, the director...
The one riding just behind Minowa-san: the detective, Katashina-san...
The one on the slopes going to call the director and the others: the stuntman, Mimata-san...
And the one who missed getting off the lift: Tateishi-san.
Wait a second, other than the director, Ooyama, how do you know which order the other three boarded in?
That's because I told him.
S-Shin'ichi's mother?!
I just happened to be in the right place to overhear when they were talking with the police.
Really? But how... why?
It's a complete coincidence!
My husband's and my vacation just happened to coincide with Shin-chan's ski lessons.
Just happened to coincide, eh?
But Shin-chan...
You're thirty minutes late.
He was just here. Another middle-school boy just like Shin-chan.
What? You mean there's another middle-school detective idiot like Shin'ichi here? How weird!
Speaking of another, did you know?
There's another legend about the Yuki-onna and her silver robe.
Damn, it's already pitch black.
Even though the criminal's been held this long for police questioning, when they release them, they'll be able to hide the evidence.
Heiji!
What is it?
Using the rain will form a puddle.
With snow, you can make a snowman.
But if it's ice, you can use it to make an enormous statue.
Yusaku said it was the key to solving the mystery of this case.
Don't be led astray by the way things appear, Heiji. By Heizou.
Huh? What are you talking about?
What does that snowman story have to do...
H-Heiji?
Can we get this over with?
Sorry, but could you get the phone from my coat pocket?
Who's there?
We're a little busy right now...
I understand it all now.
I know who murdered Minowa-san and made it appear to be a suicide.
And the trick the murderer used to make it possible.
I know it all.
Geez, that middle-school kid again.
So are you here to tell us again that how the four of us could have killed Minowa-kun?
We already told you, it was impossible for us.
He was by himself on the lift, so we couldn't have placed the gun in his hand.
Besides, except for the detective who's a former policeman,
We wouldn't have been able to aim at and shoot him in the head during that snowstorm.
Hey, hey...
That'd be impossible for a former policeman also.
At any rate, in that snowstorm I could barely see his lift in front of me.
That's exactly it.
The murder would have been impossible in that situation.
If Minowa-san really was...
Really riding alone on the lift.
What did you say?
Hey, now...
You're not saying there was someone riding along inside the bag are you?
But that bag was packed with snow, and an adult would be way too big to fit inside.
No, no. They hid in this bigger bag.
They sell a larger sized version with the same design as the bag that was packed with snow at the shop in the hotel.
That's crazy.
Are you saying Minowa-san intentionally carried a bag with the criminal in it and got on the lift with it?
No, the person in the bag wasn't the criminal, but Minowa-san himself.
Noway! How can that be?
Then the one carrying the bag...
That was the criminal.
Minowa-san's face was mostly hidden by his hair, and he was wearing sunglasses at the time.
If he was wearing a wig, a knit hat, sunglasses, and ski-wear...
It could easily seem like it was him.
But didn't he have a conversation with our fans?
They'd have no problem hearing Minowa-san's voice.
But how?
The real Minowa-san listened carefully from within the bag and replied appropriately.
That way it wouldn't be that much of a stretch to believe the disguised criminal was Minowa-san, would it?
N-No way...
I see.
That's why he didn't say anything at the time until he picked up the bag.
You must be joking.
With his excessive pride, he'd never hide inside a bag.
That's probably...
Exactly why he hid, because of his pride.
Likely his professional level skiing skills...
Were just a facade, made up for appearances. They were nothing but a lie.
A lie?
Yeah, he may have been able to ski a bit, but I don't think he was at a professional level.
I watched Minowa-san's ski-scenes in the movies Yuki-onna's Love and Yuki-onna's Mystery at the hotel.
And in the scenes where he was skiing over to the heroine, he always intentionally went out of the frame and then came back in.
What's more, when he was skiing the strap on his cap was attached, but in the close-ups, it wasn't
So, the skiing must have been done by someone else.
Isn't that right, Mr. Director?
Yeah...
It wasn't because he couldn't ski, but he had injured his leg during the first movie.
Nevertheless, he still insisted on doing the skiing himself, so in order to convince him we secretly put in a double.
Ironically, those ski scenes were praised by the critics.
In the second movie we used a double again so no one would notice.
You did?
And so, when the fans demanded it, he asked the double to ski for him and got inside the bag and waited at the bottom.
When the double came to pick-up the bag, he could appear to be holding up his end of the conversation with the fans.
Hey, wait a second...
Are you saying the double was...
The one who Minowa-san asked to take on his role and carry him around in a bag, and used that to kill him was...
The stuntman, Mimata-san.
It can only have been you.
Mimata-kun?
Is that true?
But I think the double used in the movies was the one who died four years ago, the stuntman Mizugami-san.
The skiing in the movies was different from the skiing I saw today.
More than likely before Mizugami-san died, he passed on the secret of the substitution to Mimata-san.
And he cleverly used it on this occasion to commit the crime on the lift.
Exactly...
While on the lift, he pulled Minowa-san's head from the bag, held it down, and shot a bullet through it.
He then pulled Minowa-san out of the bag, put the gun in his hand, and jumped off holding the bag.
On this lift there are two places where the height above the ground is around three meters.
So the hole in the seat was made when Minowa-san was shot.
And when Minowa-san got onto the lift, he was sitting on the left side.
But when the body was found it was sitting on the right That's proof a crime occurred.
It would be difficult for a dead person to have switch seats on the lift, wouldn't it?
But Mimata-kun was talking with me when we heard the gunshot.
That was probably the sound of a bottle rocket.
After he jumped from the lift and put on the ski-wear he'd prepared,
He used the flame from a cigarette to light the fuse and placed it in a plastic bottle so it would launch later.
By skiing to the bottom and talking with someone when they heard the sound, he could provide a witness for his alibi.
But where did the bag filled with snow come from?
Didn't I just say?
There are two places on that lift where it's only three meters to the ground.
He could place a bag there, and then invert the ring on a ski pole and use it to hook onto it and pull it into the lift
I see.
Three meters to the ground...
A ski pole is approximately 1 meter and 20 centimeters long. If you hook one strap onto the other to get more length, it might reach.
But I wonder if you could use it to grab something during that snowstorm.
No, no.
You use just one ski pole, and for the remaining meter...
You just have to lengthen the belt on the cloth bag, dampen it with water, freeze it, and it will provide the remaining meter.
The ring on the other pole was inverted so that the other one wouldn't be so noticeable.
But could he see the bag from the lift?
It was blowing so badly you couldn't even see the lift in front of you.
Don't you know?
The interval between the lifts is more than six seconds.
The speed of the lift is around 1.5 to 2 meters per second, meaning the interval between the lifts is about 10 meters.
Even if you can't see something ten meters ahead, you would be able to see a bag three meters below.
It would be even easier since he knew where the bag was.
But, the evidence...
Oh, there's evidence.
Since Mimata-san met Tateishi-san and went with her like that...
And was detained in this lodge for questioning, he should still be wearing it
Minowa-san's matching ski-wear.
Do you happen to still have the bag Minowa-san was hidden in?
I've been enduring it this whole time.
And it's been pretty hot.
M-Mimata-kun!
So it was you after all.
You noticed it too, Director?
Yeah.
At first I thought he'd just got better at skiing.
When I saw his body, I realized it must have been you.
But, why?
I did it to avenge the man who would have been your husband, Mizugami-senpai.
Four years ago, Minowa used this same trick to kill him.
W-What do you mean?
Remember, that day four years ago when Minowa was surrounded by demanding fans? Didn't he say it?
"It will work out somehow." He planned to transport Minowa secretly inside a bag.
But Minowa took advantage of his good will and killed him.
Because he said he wanted to quit being a stuntman and become an actor.
When I shoved the gun in front of him, he finally admitted it.
That guy, how could I let him become an actor?
If we came into conflict, he'd expose me!
That's what I scared out of him.
It's ironic that the movie you were making matches this revenge plot.
The truth is I suspected Minowa-kun was the criminal four years ago.
That's why I decided to make this movie.
It was a secret until now, but the criminal in the movie was the detective that Minowa-kun was playing...
And the trick was the same one Mimata-kun mentioned from four years ago.
I thought he might give himself up when he saw the script.
Even though I'm no longer a police detective...
I wish if you knew that much, that you would have stopped this senseless murder.
Revenge just calls for more revenge, and the feeling of achievement fades quickly,
Like a snowflake in the palm of your hand.
Well, well continue this down at the station.
Would you come along as well?
Inspector!
What do I do about this other middle-school student on the phone?
His deduction was exactly the same as this kid's; he said everything over the phone at about the same time too.
Heiji, why didn't you go with the police?
Idiot, didn't I say someone would carry you down to the hotel? Fool.
I only solved the thing about freezing the belt on the bag because of Dad's hint.
That middle-schooler was able to solve it all by himself.
I don't want to meet him.
Why not?
You just have to take the plastic bottle and say you solved the case, so shouldn't you go see them?
I had to hear the story from Dad about the Yuki-onna pretending her leg was injured and getting into the basket
Until then, I didn't realize Minowa-san was just pretending to be good at skiing and got into the bag himself.
But you did all the deduction yourself, didn't you?
No, that other middle-schooler was the one who solved the case by himself.
It wasn't me.
Hey...
Be quiet.
Even with a sprain, you had to scamper around with me.
You wanted to show off by getting into the advanced ski class, but you overdid it while practicing and sprained your leg, right?
But, thanks to you showing off, I knew that Minowa-san was the one in the bag right away.
Since you helped me out this time, I'll let it slide.
Idiot...
The reason I practiced so much wasn't to show off.
But why are there two different Yuki-onna stories?
It's because mothers tell them.
The original Yuki-onna legend was used to caution people not to go out during snowstorms.
When they tell the stories to their children, they sympathize with the Yuki-onna, and little by little they change the way they tell them.
That's why the original story where making the exchange for the silver gown leads to death
changed into the story where she returns to the snow without taking his soul.
That's why there are a lot of Yuki-onna stories that are sad and seem real.
Although I couldn't see very well through the snow...
That was him.
The other middle-schooler.
Well, even though we didn't meet, we're both detectives...
Well meet again someday, upon the stage of mystery.
That's how it was! And then that super smart detective left without even giving the police his name.
So? Isn't he a lot different than some other detective was before he was shrunk?
Wasn't he was so cool and modest?
But that was me...