And so, how'd it go?
You know, about that old guy who knew Hondou Eisuke as a kid.
You must've met with his grandson, right?
Yeah.
Come on, can't you spare the details?
I'm kind of interested in this.
When I went to talk to the old man's grandson, I also met a friend of his.
I got some information from them.
And I acquired a photograph.
A photograph?
Yeah, one of Hondou Eisuke as a child, and behind him...
A man they say is Eisuke's father.
Oh!
That's great, Kudou.
And then? And then?
Does that man look familiar?
Actually, no...
According to what the grandson's friend told
me, that guy said this to his colleagues:
"I'll dive in deeper."
Dive?
Then his colleagues replied with "Do your best" or "Be careful."
He said those were the words they used.
What normally comes to mind when I hear dive is "water" and "ocean."
Yeah, when the grandson's friend asked the
grandfather if the guy was a businessman...
He said he thought he was a diver.
But when he actually said was:
That guy's just a regular businessman.
He's an employee of the "Company."
The "Company"!?
H-Hey Kudou, are you thinking what I'm thinking?
Yeah, I'm not sure if the meaning of "Company" is what
we're thinking or if it's just some regular business.
The grandfather got along so well with the man that they
were often deep in conversation with one another.
If you take into account that the grandfather
was a big-time suspense fanatic...
And that the way the man spoke might have
included some specialized terminology...
You know that means he may have figured out if he was an
employee of the "Company" we're thinking of or not, right?
Yeah.
You know, Kudou...
If this is what it sounds like, then this could be really dangerous.
You should really lay low for a while and see what happens.
What would you do?
If you were in my position?
If I were you, I'd charge in without worrying―
No, no, I mean, I would...
I'm the same as you.
I'll dive in as deep as possible...
Until I quench the curiosity about those guys that's inside of me.
Right?
Come on!
Conan-kun, how long will you be in there?
We have to go.
Ah, sorry, I'll be out in a second.
Hey, you...
Are you really making such an important call from the bathroom?
I wonder if his stomach is bothering him...
Ran, let's leave the brat alone and get going.
It's time to go see our friend from middle school.
But Sonoko, it's not even noon yet, is it?
After all, it wouldn't be a bad idea to have lunch
on the way back from the hospital visit.
And since Dad already went to the race track,
I can't just leave Conan-kun alone.
Bad timing, Hattori.
I guess I'll call you back.
Hey, Kudou!
W-Wait!
Be careful, Kudou.
The tingling suspense is building.
Running in the darkness, a red scream and a black shot.
The mystery of Hondou Eisuke and Mizunashi
Rena's involvement with the Organization.
The curtain is on the verge of opening to a new type of series.
Perceiving the one and only truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan.
West
Beika
Hospital
Bye!
Come again!
Geez, that Aya's something else.
Here I was so worried about her when
she said her appendix almost ruptured.
But she smiles as if nothing happened, and says stuff like,
"Please get me a lot of cakes and parfaits to eat!"
That's great, though.
It means she's feeling good.
Well, you did mention food before, and my stomach...
Then, let's go get something to eat right away.
I heard a good hamburger shop opened nearby.
Of course, they'll have one of the kid's meals that Conan-kun loves.
The one with the toy, you mean?
Well, why not invite him to come along?
Him?
That clumsy boy.
Eisuke-kun!
Oh, Mouri-san, Suzuki-san.
S-Sorry...
Are you all right?
Yeah, somehow...
But why are you two here?
We're here to visit a friend.
As I thought.
He's figured out that Mizunashi Rena might have been
taken to a hospital and is now looking in them.
Hey...
Isn't this Mizunashi Rena?
Remember, she's that popular announcer that went on a break.
It's true, but she looks so young.
No, actually...
That's my sister.
You sister?
No way!
You're that announcer's brother?
No, even though they look alike, they're different people.
Their names are different, too.
Not to mention, ten years ago, my sister left home.
Left home?
So I'm looking for her by showing people this picture of her.
But why are you asking in hospitals?
Because she always said she planned to become a nurse.
Also, my sister saved me many times in hospitals.
No matter what, I'll never forget.
Saved you?
When I was young, besides being clumsy I was sick a lot.
Every time, my sister would carry me to the hospital.
Whenever I was bleeding from my injuries...
She would say, "God gave you this blood type that
you can share with anyone, so treasure it always."
But in the end it was my sister who always gave me her blood.
Shortly before she left, I was seriously injured.
At that time, she gave me a large transfusion of blood.
That's what's flowing inside of me...
Her blood.
Every time my heart beats I can feel it...
My sister's kindness.
But when I was released, she had disappeared.
Maybe she thought if that if she didn't leave,
you'd end up draining all her blood.
Jeez, Sonoko.
I don't know why she left.
But with all my heart, I want to see her again and thank her.
She's the reason that I'm still alive.
What he just shared with everyone is definitely possible.
And the story he told just now didn't seem to be made-up.
It definitely looks like he may be searching for his actual sister.
But you know, that's just like us.
Remember, I gave you a lot of my blood that one time.
Can you feel my kindness?
You have no idea.
But still, how can you be so sure Mizunashi Rena
and you sister aren't the same person?
Well, she just can't be.
Why?
Maybe she's using a stage name for her TV job.
Maybe, but...
Then, how about this?
One of my Dad's friends is a big fan of Mizunashi Rena.
He has a whole pile of videos he's recorded of her.
We can go ask if we can watch them.
If we looks closely, maybe we can tell whether she's your sister.
I guess so.
That's fine with me.
Oh, yeah.
We should show him the picture and see if he
knows whether it's Mizunashi Rena or not.
Y-Yeah.
Well, let's get going.
Before that, we're having lunch.
Lunch!
I'm really craving a hamburger right now.
Yes?
Hello?
It's been a while.
This is Mouri Ran.
Do you remember me?
That dog lover guy, huh?
Um, this is Mouri...
Huh?
Excuse me...
This is Anno-san's residence, right?
Wrong number.
I guess I dialed the wrong number.
Calm down.
But if Eisuke-kun's sister turns out to be
Mizunashi Rena, it would be big news!
It's been awhile.
This is Mouri Ran.
Is that you again?
I told you: Wrong number!
How strange...
That should have been it.
Could he have moved?
Dad didn't mention that earlier.
Why not ask him again?
Racetrack Stop
What?
Anno's phone number was changed?
That shouldn't be!
He just called me for a mahjong game earlier.
But when I called, it wasn't him.
Did he say he was moving?
Then why don't you go to his parent's house and ask?
It's right nearby that hospital you said were going to today.
My son's moved?
Yes, when I tried to call him earlier, it seemed his number had changed.
Strange, I was just talking to him a bit ago.
He said he caught a cold yesterday, so his voice is a little rough.
He even had to cancel his plans for a trip
this Thursday and Friday because of it.
Oh, right!
I remember he said his number had changed
because he broke his cellphone yesterday.
That could be it, right?
No, I called his home number.
Let's see, you're Mouri-san's daughter, right?
Forgive me, could we talk about this later?
I'm a bit busy now.
I have to hurry to the bank.
Could your son be in some kind of trouble?
Well, yes...
And did he by any chance say:
"I don't want anyone else to know, so don't discuss it with anybody."
The truth is, his partner stole the company's money...
They were just starting a new project, and if they couldn't transfer
money to the client by the end of the day they'd go bankrupt.
I told him I'd ask his father, but he said he didn't have the time.
Did he tell you what to say at the bank when you transferred the money?
Well, of course!
I was to ask for an urgent business fund transfer.
What kind of project could it be?
It could be a mail-order business for an official Mizunashi Rena goods shop.
She is popular enough.
Yeah, and Internet shopping is pretty widespread now.
No, that's not it.
It is something that's spreading widely, though.
Anno
Spreading widely?
This brat isn't confusing what I said with a cold or something is he?
I'm not.
That explanation she gave for the request over the phone...
I think what Sonoko-neechan said was wrong.
Why's that?
The caller is the son of this woman, and he's
a big fan of the announcer Mizunashi Rena.
If someone like that is starting a project...
Then a Mizunashi Rena goods shop
mail-order site is an obvious choice.
So, why did you say that wasn't it?
Will your son be OK?
If the project money was stolen, doesn't he
need to hurry and do something about it?
Yeah, that's why I'm going to the bank now to put up the money.
Oh my, the bank window will be closing soon.
I'm sorry, we'll talk later.
Wait a second.
Your son canceled his trip because he caught a cold, right?
Y-Yeah...
Then isn't it strange?
That he would take a vacation when he's
so busy with starting something new?
A reception, a reception.
Basically, this trip is to meet with the people vital to the project.
But, think...
He said his number changed after his old cellphone broke, right?
Huh? What does that have to do with it?
Since he had to change his cellphone out,
he went ahead and got a new number with it.
He's starting this whole new project, after all.
But wasn't it just yesterday that he called his mother about the change?
If he changed his number at such a busy time,
it would probably annoy a lot of people.
That's probably true.
Changing it means that he'll have to tell all of his
business colleagues about the new number.
Unless there was some big reason, I don't think it's likely
he would change his number at a time like this.
Then, why?
Maybe he was annoyed with prank calls?
That reminds me, he did mention he
was getting a lot of silent calls recently.
He also told me a burglar had broken in.
A burglar!?
It must've been the burglar using the phone to
check when my son would be away from home.
Well, my son takes his valuables with him when
he leaves, so nothing has was stolen then.
It was a listening device, wasn't it?
A listening device?
He must've planted the listening device to
learn your son's voice and how he speaks.
Of course, he also found out your son would be away from
his apartment this Thursday and Friday for his trip.
B-But my son caught a cold and canceled
his trip, so he's in his apartment now.
Was that really your son?
Y-Yes...
Actually...
Even though his voice was hoarse from his cold...
I know he called from his room because I heard Wan-chan barking.
He's always barking. Every time I call, I
always hear that dog going "wan, wan".
A dog's bark is even harder to identify than a human's voice, right?
He probably had a dog with a similar bark near the phone.
No, it may have even been a tape or CD playing.
Why would anyone do all that?
It was to make the person on the phone appear to be her son.
Wait a second...
Could this be...
A case of remittance fraud?
You see, maybe he's pretending to be her son
over the phone so he can steal her money.
But that's just what this brat is saying.
No, this kid may have a point.
If the criminal snuck into her son's home and called her...
The phone here would display her son's number.
Even more, by having her hear a dog barking at the same time...
She would have no reason to doubt it was
really her son on the other end, right?
Then, the one who said I had the wrong number when I called was...
Is that you again?
I told your: Wrong number!
That guy is probably waiting for you to call, right?
Y-Yes, that's right.
I'm supposed to call him as soon I transfer the money.
I'm sure that when you notify him, he'd inform a waiting partner,
who would immediately withdraw the money and escape.
If other people called in the meantime, he wouldn't waste
time trying to pretend to them that he was your son.
Furthermore, he called when the bank would be about to close.
That gives his target less time to think, making
it more likely the fraud will be successful.
Of course, he instructed you not to mention this to
anyone else, so no one would recognize the fraud.
The same applies to why he told you to make a
business fund transfer from the teller window.
With this fraud method becoming widespread, you'd have
to say that to keep the teller from being suspicious.
Or at least that's what they said on a lunchtime talk show.
As usual, you remember everything, Conan-kun.
He's like a housewife with plenty of time to watch TV over lunch.
That means when he said his cellphone broke and
he changed his number he was probably lying.
He didn't want her to call her son, who's really on his trip.
That means, if we call your son's former cellphone number right now...
We'll know if this is really a fraud or not.
Anno
The number you are attempting to reach is either outside
the service area or unreachable because it is powered off.
Oh my, I can't reach him.
Then, is it true the cellphone was really broken?
Where was your son traveling to?
To Sado via Niigata.
I think he was planning to be back by 7:00 tonight.
7:00, huh?
To get from Sado to Tokyo, you first take an hour trip by jet foil...
Then you take the Shinkansen from Niigata for two and a half hours.
If we calculate backwards...
He would be on the sea aboard the jet foil now.
His cellphone would be out of range on the ocean.
The criminal must have included this in his scheme.
There's less than ten minutes left!
It's late! I have to get to the bank!
Lady, you can't go!
Aren't you something!
If I can't get my son ten million before the end of the
day, he'll said he'd get a loan from the black market.
If he did, how could he pay them back...
BEIKA CENTRAL BANK
You missed the transfer?
Yeah...
Some visitors came by suddenly and in all the confusion...
I'm sorry.
I thought I told you to hurry.
I told you to go right away when I phoned.
Well, you said you could get a loan from the black market.
You can pay them back if you have the money
before the end of the day, right?
Y-Yeah, I guess, but...
Anno
Then, what about mother's secret savings?
Secret savings?
H-How much?
I expected something like this could happen, so I saved up two million.
I sent you the withdrawal card and accompanying PIN
yesterday; I think it should have gotten there by now.
Is that not good enough?
No, that should tide me over for the time being.
Well, I'll go ahead and withdraw it now.
Thanks for understanding, Mom.
Who are you!?
W-Well, you see...
Shit!
Move!
And so the remittance fraud criminal was quickly arrested.
Later, they caught his partner who was at the bank awaiting the transfer.
The strangely intricate remittance fraud scheme
was prevented before it did any damage.
The simplest and most effective way to avoid
being cheated by this kind of fraud is...
Not to hurry and make snap decisions on your
own, but to discuss them with somebody.
If people have to explain things verbally, they can sort out the situation.
And they can consider the circumstances calmly.
This way, if they or the person they discuss
it with are even a little bit suspicious...
This kind of fraud can be prevented.
M-Mom?
Remittance fraud!?
Y-You, Mom?
Yeah, but these kids saved me from it.
It's been awhile.
I'm Mouri Ran.
Nice to see Aina-chan as well.
Oh, I see.
I remember now, you're Mouri's daughter.
But what did you come here for?
We came to see you.
The truth is, we have a favor to ask you.
We wanted you to take a look at this picture of Mizunashi Rena.
NEXT EPISODE
Are Hondou Eisuke's sister and Mizunashi Rena the same person?
Hondou insists that his blood type still isn't a match.
Mizunashi Rena's blood type is AB.
Hondou, who got a blood transfusion from his sister, says he's type 0.
In order to confirm the facts, we head to a mansion.
A new, more mysterious case begins to unfold.
CLASH OF RED AND BLACK
BLOOD RELATIVE
Next time, on Detective Conan...
Blood Transfusion
Next Conan's HINT:
"Blood Transfusion"
Look forward to the next episode
Ran-neechan, what's your blood type?
Newtype!
What's that?