While investigating the connection between the Black Organization's member, Kir—
Mizunashi Rena
and a student who transferred to Ran's high school, Hondou Eisuke...
I discovered his father worked for some entity known as the "Company."
As for him, he's been searching for his sister who left home ten years ago that bears a remarkable resemblance to Mizunashi Rena.
Are Hondou Eisuke's sister and Mizunashi Rena really different people?
We went to visit a "big fan" of Mizunashi Rena's, Anno-san.
We came to see you.
The truth is, we have a favor to ask you.
We wanted you to take a look at this picture of Mizunashi Rena.
The tingling suspense is building.
Running in the darkness —
a red scream and a black shot.
Hondou Eisuke frantically searches for his sister.
His blood type establishes a surprising fact.
Perceiving the one and only truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan.
CLASH OF RED AND BLACK
BLOOD RELATIVE
No matter how I look at it, it seems to be Rena-chan when she was younger.
Doesn't it? Doesn't it?
Then she is Eisuke-kun's sister, after all.
You're Rena-chan's brother!?
I see it now, you have identical eyes!
Would you sign something for me?
Ah, you see...
I believe that announcer Mizunashi Rena and my sister are different people.
See, this guy is searching for his sister—the one from the photograph—who left home.
There's no doubt this is her.
As her biggest fan, I can guarantee it
B-But...
Oh, that's right, before Rena-chan first became known...
Her hairstyle was like the girl in this photograph.
You'll see what I mean after you watch this video.
This is a recording of the news program that made her popular.
Well, see for yourself.
Here's the building as it's burning.
The scene is like a battlefield.
The chemical plant suddenly exploded.
This is unconfirmed, but over one-hundred casualties have been estimated.
They are now being taken one after another to a hospital near the plant.
While covering this disaster here along with Nichiuri TV, even I have suffered a minor injury.
Excuse me!
Anyone with AB blood?
Does anyone here have AB blood?
We don't have enough.
Does anyone here have type AB blood?
Sorry, I have AB blood!
I must help.
Rena-chan!
Ah, I do!
I have AB blood!
But, aren't you injured yourself?
Yes, but my blood is very vigorous.
I understand.
In any case, let's get you inside.
You see?
Even though she was injured herself, she was kind enough to donate blood to people.
Not everyone would do that, would they?
Actually, back then during their coverage, she injured her arm seriously enough to warrant stitches.
She fainted after they drew her blood, and in the end she needed a transfusion herself.
It's a cute ending, isn't it?
I'm completely better now.
Well, Eisuke-kun?
Is she your sister?
She isn't
Why?
Come on, get a better look.
What's wrong is wrong.
From what he said his sister told him...
Your blood is the type that can be shared with anyone
If that story is true, then his blood...
Must be the type that can be transfused to anyone.
Type O.
Emergency Medical Care Center
Of course, in an ordinary situation, the same type of blood is used in the transfusion.
But when someone's badly hemorrhaging and an immediate transfusion is necessary and their life is in danger...
They use type O blood without checking the person's own type.
Just like what we saw in the video.
So, since O types can only receive from other O types...
And this guy said he received blood from his sister, she must have had O type as well.
But in the video, she declared that she had AB...
And later she was given a transfusion as well.
If her blood was actually O and she lied about it being AB for some reason...
The AB recipient could get from her, but not she from him.
In other words...
Mizunashi Rena and the girl in the picture are not one and the same.
So, the reason this guy is searching for Mizunashi Rena...
Isn't because she's really his sister...
As I thought: It's because she looks exactly like her.
So that boy's sister looks exactly like Mizunashi Rena?
It seems he's somehow figured out she was injured in that incident and was admitted to a hospital.
Now he's going around to various hospitals looking for her.
That means it's possible he'll come to that hospital as well.
He thinks he's clever enough to sneak past us, huh?
Don't worry.
Only a few doctors and nurses know that she's been admitted here.
Regardless, I'm surprised to hear Mizunashi Rena has a younger brother.
No...
Mizunashi Rena and Hondou Eisuke's sister are not the same.
Their blood types don't match.
What do you mean?
Most likely, those guys in black had the real Mizunashi Rena undergo plastic surgery...
In order for her to look just like Eisuke's sister.
Because they had some kind of objective regarding his father.
What?
That boy's father?
Who is he?
I don't have much on him yet
One thing I can say is that he might be a member of the "Company."
Could that be...
It's only a possibility, as he didn't say that himself.
But what about you?
Aren't you diving into a dangerous place?
Are you all right?
Yeah, I'm fine for now.
"For now," you say...
Can you confirm one last thing for me?
Mizunashi Rena's blood type.
Rh+ - Type AB.
Just as I thought...
Then, we'll try and look into his father for the time being, but...
Don't keep diving into dangerous areas, OK?
Thanks, Jodie-sensei.
So, how'd it go?
This Eisuke kid's sister and Mizunashi Rena really aren't the same person?
Yeah.
Mizunashi Rena has AB blood while Hondou Eisuke has O.
If his story about getting blood from his sister is true, they can't be the same.
That's because a person with O type can only receive type blood.
But he got that transfusion when he was a child, right?
He may have just misunderstood the situation.
I guess that's possible.
We should consider whether he really has O type or not
In that case, why not confirm it with him firsthand?
Or check by getting him hospitalized yourself.
Hey, hey...
Regardless, we definitely need to confirm whether it's true soon.
And we need to hurry and find out why he's looking for Mizunashi Rena and stop him...
Before those guys in black take notice.
You're right...
Those guys are looking for her as well.
Most likely...
With blood in their eyes.
Then, wouldn't it be best to let those two meet?
You know which hospital she's been admitted to.
That Eisuke guy doesn't seem to be in with them, does he?
We can't let him see her yet
It's still possible...
That Hondou Eisuke is being used by those guys without realizing it
You've regained consciousness!
Who are you?
You don't remember?
I hit you with my car.
Is that so?
I'm sorry.
It was due to my carelessness.
No, I wasn't paying attention either.
Is your head in pain?
Or the rest of your body?
I'm fine.
Thank goodness.
I'll go call the doctor now.
You —
Your name?
Miyano Akemi.
Moroboshi Dai.
Nice to meet you.
The same to you.
You know where Mizunashi Rena's apartment is?
We were asked to solve a case for her once.
Right, Dad?
Ding-dong ditch?
And you want me to catch the culprit?
I knew it was inappropriate.
As it turned out...
A-A child!
You're a boy, so be strong.
And let your mother be at peace.
And so, it was just some child's prank.
I'm home.
Welcome back, Conan-kun.
But why haven't you taken Eisuke-kun there?
Wouldn't he know right away if she were his sister or not after seeing her in person?
Because...
don't think I should be showing people where a famous announcer lives.
If I got him excited about going to meet her and they weren't related, Eisuke-kun would be disappointed.
What's wrong is wrong.
He was so insistent that she wasn't Mizunashi Rena when we saw the video.
I guess you're right.
Not going is the right choice.
When Mizunashi Rena disappeared, those guys in black likely began watching her apartment building.
If we took Hondou Eisuke, who looks so much like her, there...
That would get their attention and could get dangerous.
And?
Was Mizunashi Rena not that clumsy kid's sister who left home?
He said she wasn't
You know, back then...
Long ago, I had a little brother around that age as well.
Guess that must have been a different kid.
I guess so.
Besides, from what we heard before, I have a feeling that Eisuke-kun and Rena-san have different blood types.
You know, siblings don't always have to have the same blood type.
But remember what she said in the video?
I have AB blood!
Someone with AB can only give to others with AB, right?
Eisuke-kun said he was sure he received blood from his sister through a transfusion when he was a child.
If Mizunashi Rena was really related to him, then that clumsy boy would also have AB.
Hey, what blood type did Eisuke-niichan say he had?
It was...
T-Type O...
Hey, are you all right?
Y-Yeah...
I just tripped over something on the floor.
It's true...
That tile is sticking up a bit
As always, I'm so unlucky.
No, I'd say you're more likely possessed by something...
When did you get here, Eisuke-niichan?
He came in with us earlier.
He just went to the bathroom.
Because I'm Detective Mouri's #1 assistant
Too bad there isn't any work for you to help with.
I-Is that so?
By the way, what was that about?
What you were saying about my blood.
Ah, we were just trying to sort out what type of blood you have...
What're you doing?
Just tell him straight out
"You're not related to Mizunashi Rena because you have blood."
But he might still be hoping somewhere in his heart that she's his sister and I'd feel bad about it.
But do you really have Type O blood?
Y-Yeah.
Have you donated recently?
No, I haven't, but...
Then, have you been taken to the hospital for a serious injury lately?
That's hasn't happened, either.
When I was little, I was always going to the hospital because I was injured or sick.
Not long after I started primary school...
Bye-bye!
I was hit by a car and had to be hospitalized.
And that's when your sister gave you blood, right?
Well, even now it seems like I fall and get slight injuries almost every day.
No kidding.
Oh, that's right
If you're that interested in my blood type...
Come with me to a place I'm going tomorrow and find out
I was contacted by the people at a mansion where my mother and I used to go to.
They found some of my mother's effects, so I'm going to go pick them up.
Effects?
Your mother died?
Maternal and Child Health Handbook
Yes, from illness.
My childhood health records are among the effects.
How about it?
I'll have to pass.
I have other things to do tomorrow.
Ah, but...
But Okudaira-san's mansion is in Haido city's third district.
It's not far.
But I'm going to see Okudaira-san in Haido city's third district tomorrow...
Dad?
You have work, then?
But it's from a year ago.
The only son of the house was killed in a strange way.
The criminal's motive was never figured out
So, I, renowned detective Mouri Kogoro, have been called in to re-open the case.
By the son, do you mean Tango-san?
Yeah, I think his name was something like that.
I see, you must've known him.
Since I was really young back then, all I can remember is his name.
But how mean of you!
You just said you didn't have any cases.
That's because I don't have any cases that require clumsy brats.
How could you...
So your mother worked here as a housekeeper.
Yeah.
Since she lived-in, I was brought here.
Back then, where were your father and sister?
My father was working in Osaka.
My sister was said to be studying abroad, but...
She would come back on holidays.
But my dad would only come back for New Year's.
After my mother passed away...
My father took custody of me and took me to live with him in Osaka for awhile.
"Awhile"?
Aren't you living with him now?
No, he had to go overseas for work.
Ever since, I've lived with a friend of his.
What an irresponsible father.
He must be why your sister left home.
But my father still sends me an allowance every month.
Okudaira Eiko (56)
Okudaira's Wife
Oh, Eisuke-kun, it's been so long!
Has it already been ten years?
You've grown so big.
Yes, thankfully.
I've already got your mother's effects ready.
Well, you're all welcome to come inside.
Oh, Kikuyo-san.
Please show them inside.
Yes, ma'am.
We hired her for the housekeeping job after your mother left.
Tabata Kikuyo (39)
Okudaira Family Housekeeper
She may seem a little blunt, but she's very kind.
Um...
Oh, aren't you herewith Eisuke-kun?
Oh, no.
I'm Mouri Kogoro, here at your husband's request.
The famous detective!
I heard about you from my husband.
Yes!
In that case, I'll escort Detective Mouri to my husband's study.
Please escort Eisuke-kun and his friends to the parlor.
As you wish.
Wow, the resemblance is remarkable.
Eisuke-kun looks just like his mother.
No surprise.
He looks nothing like his father.
Found it.
The health record.
See, it's written right here.
"Hondou Eisuke, Type O."
It's true.
That proves my blood type is O, right?
I see.
Now, all that remains is whether the story about sharing blood with his sister is true or not
I'm sorry the bag is a little smashed.
When I found it, it was caught behind a drawer in my dresser.
But thankfully we came across it.
When we showed it to the mistress, she knew it belonged to the mansion's previous housekeeper and had us call you.
And yet today is the one-year anniversary of Tango-sama's death.
Anniversary?
Segawa Hatarou (48)
Okudaira Family Butler
The mistress said, "My son must be calling everyone together."
It's been a while.
Even after ten years, the butler hasn't changed.
No, the one who worked here when you were here was my older brother.
He died exactly two years ago today in an automobile accident.
So, it was like this then?
Master, with the exception of your son, everyone in the house was enjoying a home video you recorded.
During this time, your son was drowned outside in the pool...
By an unknown assailant
Yeah...
According to the police, my son presumably died between 9:00 and 10:00 PM.
Okudaira Kakuzou(63)
Head of Okudaira Family
We were watching the video in the living room all five hours from 7:00 PM to 12:00 AM.
And this is a printout from a video that was taken at the time.
Both legs bound, mouth gum taped —
how cruel.
But how did you capture it on video?
The following morning, after draining the water from the pool, the housekeeper kept screaming she found my son.
We thought he was just faking it as a joke to scare us.
But, unfortunately, it was no joke, and he was actually dead.
Do you happen to know if anyone resented your son or something?
I'm not aware of anyone on the outside...
But the inside...
You mean...
This is what I believe, Detective Mouri:
My son's life was cut off by some very crafty person who is living in this house.
One year ago, the only son of the mansion was killed in murder case.
The master declares that the still unidentified criminal is someone inside the mansion.
But is that really so?
However, before I can determine the truth...
The master himself is met with an unnatural death.
Next time, on Detective Conan...
CLASH OF RED AND BLACK
Expensive Vase
Next Conan's Hint!
Eisuke-kun, don't jostle it!
It's OK. I'm just looking.
It's because you scolded him...