While we were investigating to see if Mizunashi Rena and Hondou Eisuke's sister were the same person...
I checked to see if Mizunashi Rena's blood type was really AB.
Ah, I do!
I have AB blood!
Meanwhile, the answer to Eisuke's blood type...
Was written in the child health record left behind in the mansion where his deceased mother had been a housekeeper.
See, it's written right here.
"Hondou Eisuke, Type O."
It's true.
That proves my blood type is O, right?
Now all that remains is whether the story about sharing blood with his sister is true or not
In that same Okudaira mansion...
The son, Tango-san, had been killed by someone one year before.
And this is a printout from a video that was recorded at the time.
Both legs bound, mouth gum taped — how cruel.
Do you happen to know if anyone resented your son or something?
I'm not aware of anyone on the outside...
But the inside...
This is what I believe, Detective Mouri:
My son Tango's life was cut off by some very crafty person...
Who is living in this house.
The tingling suspense is building.
Running in the darkness — a red scream and a black shot.
A screams resounds within the mansion!
Perceiving the one and only truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
CLASH OF RED AND BLACK
EXCLAMATION
Y-Your son was killed by someone inside the house?
But, what do you mean?
You said it was while everyone in the house was watching a video in the living room...
That somebody drowned your son in your pool.
Okudaira Kakuzou (63)
Head of Okudaira Family
If I remember, your son's estimated time of death was between 9:00 and 10:00 PM...
For two hours before and after, in other words from 7:00 through 12:00,
you said everyone was watching some videos, right?
That much is true, but...
I just can't help thinking that Tango's death was...
The responsibility of someone in this house.
Is there a secret exit from the living room you can sneak out of or something?
No, there's no secret door, but people did go to the restroom during the course of the video.
I see.
Someone snuck outside during a break.
That's not it.
The restroom is connected to the living room, and its window isn't large enough for an adult to fit through.
Then, wasn't it impossible for anyone in the house?
But look more closely...
Here in the picture.
See, Tango's right hand...
He's wearing a white glove, right?
Yeah, seems so.
On this exact same day two years ago...
Our previous butler...
Fell off a cliff and died while he was driving the car.
It was the glove he always wore.
On the exact same day?
And your son was killed on this day just a year ago, right?
Right, it was today...
And three days after my son was killed, the butler's left-hand glove was found here in my study.
I get it!
You mean the criminal intended to put both gloves on your son but just happened to miss one?
No, that's not it!
Someone must be holding a grudge over the previous butler's death...
A grudge?
But wasn't the butler's death just an accident?
Well...
Basically, someone believes you and your son caused that accident
So they put the butler's glove on your son and killed him...
And then left the other glove in this room to signal that you were next
You were gonna say that, right?
What are you all doing?
Don't just come in on your own!
It's because Conan-kun said, "We're done with our other business, so let's go listen to the case."
No more "he-he-he."
If you're done, then hurry up and...
It's been a while, Uncle Kakuzou.
Is that Eisuke-kun?
I think we came across some of your mother's effects.
Yes, and thanks to you, I've gotten them safely back.
Your mother was the most wonderful housekeeper.
She was so compassionate and was always smiling.
Forgive me for not being as compassionate or friendly.
Tabata Kikuyo (39)
Okudaira Family Housekeeper
No, no, I didn't mean it that way.
That's right...
I heard Tango-san passed away.
Yeah.
I was just asking Detective Mouri here to look into it further.
Oh, Segawa-kun?
Segawa Hatarou (48)
Okudaira Family Butler
Please show Detective Mouri to the living room.
As you wish, Master.
Oh, and also, Kikuyo-san...
Please make some more coffee.
Oh, while you're at it, call my wife for me.
I want her to help me organize the study.
As soon as the two of you are available, come and help out.
I have something to talk to you about as well.
As you wish.
Oh, and Segawa-kun?
Yes?
How many times do I have to tell you?
Always knock before you come into my study!
You need to make that clear to the guests, you dimwit!
F-Forgive me.
He wants me to help him organize the books in his study?
Okudaira Eiko (56)
Okudaira's Wife
Forget it.
That man will find fault with every little detail.
But, Mistress...
Earlier, when I tried to open the cardboard box with the set of large books that was delivered today, I really got scolded.
He said, "Don't touch that until I've opened it!"
He's always changing the shelves in his bookcases around to fit those big books...
And eventually ends up having to move almost every book.
That's when he asks for my help.
B-But...
Then, how about this?
I'll escort Detective Mouri to the living room.
That will allow you go to help him.
But what about the other things, such as the repairs to Tango-sama's car.
No one has used that car in the last two years.
You can just leave it sit
But, Mistress...
All right, this way.
Since the repairs to the car can wait, I'll leave the rest up to you.
This is it
So, this is the living room that was mentioned before?
On that day all four of us, my husband and myself, the butler and the housekeeper were all here.
Last year we were watching the videos of our overseas trip on and on for five hours.
Why didn't your son watch them with you?
I'm sure it was because he was avoiding being around me...
Since I'm not his real mother.
Is that so?
Yes.
Tango-san was my husband's son with his former wife.
Didn't I tell you?
But, are you sure my husband didn't say anything about us?
With him suspecting us just because they haven't caught any culprits, my husband is becoming annoying.
The attached restroom.
An adult definitely couldn't get through this window.
And there's no way to just secretly slip out of the living room.
That means...
Since all four of them were watching those videos here, they have perfect alibis...
But, I was surprised...
When I saw that Eisuke-kun, who was such a crybaby,
brought such a cute girlfriend along with him.
It's not like that with us.
S-She isn't my girlfriend!
We came because we wanted to know Eisuke-niichan's blood type.
He said you'd found his child health records.
Isn't that right, Eisuke-niichan?
But what's this about your blood type?
When I showed a picture of my sister to Mouri-san, he said, "Isn't she that announcer, Mizunashi Rena?"
So, we came here to clear up any uncertainty.
See, that announcer has Type AB, while I have O.
And since I received a transfusion from my sister, my sister and that announcer must be different people.
Eisuke-kun already knew...
That's right, I remember that happening.
I think it was right after his mother died.
Just when Eisuke-kun was taken in by his father and moved to Osaka, that accident happened.
As soon as I heard about it, I dashed right over there and found his sister sleeping beside his bed, completely exhausted.
When I asked the nurse why, she said his sister had given him a large amount of blood.
It seems she told them, "You can draw out all of my blood for my little brother."
Is that what she said?
That settles it
His sister and Mizunashi Rena...
Are not the same person.
I don't really watch that much TV.
Are they really that much alike?
His sister and that person.
Yeah.
Judging from the photo we saw, they were two halves of a melon.
But, don't you think it's strange?
Unless they're doppelgangers...
Having two people who look so completely alike...
Maybe it's connected to my sister's disappearance?
Who knows?
I get it now.
He became suspicious of Mizunashi Rena.
He then checked Uncle out...
In order to obtain an invitation.
After that, he intended to ask her about his sister.
He likely expects she would feign ignorance if he approached her directly.
Then, why not meet her?
Actually, her...
Hey!
We might as well have them show us the pool.
We might discover something there about the son's death.
I guess that's true.
Oh, but...
It's raining outside.
Oh, Kikuyo-san?
Did you go out somewhere?
Yes, we were out of milk for the coffee, so we out to buy some in the neighborhood.
Well, forgive me, but...
Could you show everyone to the pool?
I'll take in the coffee.
Yeah, I don't mind.
Well, I'll leave it to you.
Jeez, this place is dirty.
Yeah.
It's been left this way since the incident a year ago.
This brings back memories.
This is the pool I always used to...
Hey, Eisuke-kun!
Jeez, this kid's clumsy no matter where he is.
Hey, hey...
Oh, it's the right size.
I'm sorry.
I hope my deceased son's clothes are of a size that fits you.
It's OK.
It fits well, so I guess he was also short?
It is a little baggy, though.
Yeah.
Tango-san was known as a body builder.
Your clothes are in the washer now, so wait for a bit, please.
Oh, Kikuyo-san, I didn't see any coffee in the kitchen.
Is that so?
I left it ready in the coffee maker before I went to go shopping.
Oh, Segawa-san?
Did you see the coffee in the kitchen?
The Master might have grown impatient and made it himself...
It sounded like it came from the Master's study.
I'll go check.
Please do.
Let's hope it wasn't that expensive vase.
That's not possible.
He's always treasured that vase, considering it's worth ¥50,000,000.
A blackout...
Don't open it!
What was that?
Dear!
It can't be!
Why'd this happen?
Don't go in, Mistress! On the floor...
Are you all right?
Y-Yeah...
Dear...
Anyway, let's hurry and get him down.
Ran, call for an ambulance and the police!
I got it!
Damn, what's with this rope?
It's not coming undone.
On the rim of the vase...
Is it wet?
I'm afraid it was too late by the time he made it to the hospital.
It can't be!
Mistress...
Mistress, here you are.
Thank you...
If it's all right, I have two or three questions for you.
The person who first discovered the body was?
The first ones to discover my husband were Kikuyo-san...
And Segawa-san, isn't that right?
We heard the sound of something breaking coming from the study, so we rushed here and knocked on the door, but he didn't respond.
Since he didn't answer when we called out, but when we started turning the door knob, he shouted, "Don't open it."
And, did you open it?
Yes, we did.
We thought something had happened.
And when we opened the door, we found the master's body hanging there.
That means he did it just before you opened the door, right?
Yeah, his body was still swaying then.
I'm pretty sure we're talking suicide here, since the windows were securely locked.
But why did he say, "Don't open it"?
That's obviously because he didn't want anyone to see him dying.
For some reason he had grown tired of. the world and chose death instead.
You again, huh?
Take a look at the fragments of the vase scattered on the floor, Inspector.
This must have been the source of the breaking sound we heard.
Moreover, this is a vase he cherished more than anything else and it's worth ¥50,000,000.
¥50,000,000!?
Is that true?
Yeah.
He always talked about it, saying even ¥200,000,000 couldn't make up for that vase.
He even used that vase as a footstool in order to kill himself...
Further proving he'd grown to hate this world.
However...
The autopsy results say they found coffee and sleeping pills in the corpse's stomach.
Coffee?
There?
Why are there two cups?
One of them was mine.
But why would he bother to take sleeping pills with the coffee before hanging himself?
Maybe he originally planned to take a lot of sleeping pills, but he got impatient and decided to change the plan.
And this time he applied glue to the knot of the rope to be sure it wouldn't come undone.
Glue?
Yeah.
When we were getting him down, we had a hard time getting the rope undone due to it being glued.
But what reason did he have to commit suicide?
Do any of you have any idea?
Now that you mention it...
He requested we come to the study so he could tell us something...
So maybe he was distressed about something.
But then, why did he hang himself before discussing it with you all?
He may have thought discussing it with us wouldn't help...
I don't want to say it...
But your husband didn't trust you very much, did he?
The blood running from his mouth is likely from him biting his lip in regret
He couldn't stand someone else inheriting his prize vase.
That must be why he broke it by using it as a footstool.
That means he was really greedy, right?
What?
Because if he had used the vase as a footstool and it only made the noise when it fell...
He would have already hung himself, right?
If he weren't so greedy, he wouldn't have shouted "Don't take the vase" after that
That's wrong, Conan-kun.
It wasn't "Don't take" it was "Don't open."
Note: Ageru na means 'Don't take', while Akeru na means 'Don't open'
Is that right?
Now that you mention it, that is strange.
Could someone hanging really be able to shout?
This means that when the vase broke, he hadn't hung himself yet
Then, he was so shocked after breaking the vase that he committed suicide.
No, if you rushed here immediately after hearing it break, he didn't have time to prepare the rope.
Maybe it was because of this?
The Killer from Hades
Shinmei Kaori
Look, this book is stained with blood.
He may have been upset if it were one of his important books.
"The Killer from Hades"?
It does seem to have been directly below his feet
Huh?
Could this be...
A dying message?
Don't be silly.
If it were, the murderer must be a ghost from the underworld.
Oh, no...
It could be a message.
The word "Hades" is mostly covered in blood, and the droplets below resemble the "ko" character in hiragana.
"Yomi-ko"?
(Calendar)
"Ko-yomi"?
Is it something about a date?
I'm not sure whether this is "ko" or not
If you do this and turn it horizontally, it resembles the hiragana "i" as well.
Well, if this really was a dying message...
That means the master of the house, Kakuzou-san, was...
Murdered by someone inside of this very house.
What does the message left in blood mean?
A cruel method.
The full extent of which we yet to grasp.
CLASH OF RED AND BLACK
HADES
Next time, on Detective Conan...
Footstool
Next Conan's Hint!
Detective Takagi, let me use you as a footstool!
- Ah, OK.
- Me too.
- And me.
Ah, too heavy...