In order to investigate whether Mizunashi Rena and Hondou Eisuke's sister were the same person...
We went to visit the Okudaira mansion where his mother had been a housekeeper.
From the child health records among Eisuke's mother's effects,
and from the evidence provided by Okudaira's wide, we determine that those two must be different people.
Meanwhile, at the Okudaira mansion...
The son, Tango-san, had been killed by someone one year ago.
One year later on that same day we discovered the body of the master of the house, Kakuzou-san.
Under his feet, where drops of blood had fallen, was "The Killer from Hades."
The Killer from Hades by Shinmei Kaori
Well, if this really was a dying message...
That means Kakuzou-san was...
Murdered by someone inside of this very house.
The tingling suspense is building.
Running in the darkness —
a red scream and a black shot.
At last the case is completely explained.
What is the true identity of the Killer from Hades?
Perceiving the one and only truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
CLASH OF RED AND BLACK
HADES
Just in case, let me ask you...
Before you discovered him...
Where were you...
And what were you doing?
Okudaira Eiko (56)
Okudaira's Wife
Yes...
I accompanied Detective Mouri to the living room.
And then...
Oh, right.
I was going to show them to the pool...
But it was raining outside.
So, then...
I entrusted Kikuyo-san, who had just returned from shopping, to do that...
And I would bring the coffee to my husband.
Where did you go shopping?
Tabata Kikuyo (39)
Okudaira Family Housekeeper
I went to a nearby supermarket to get milk for the coffee the master wanted.
I actually still happen to have the receipt on me.
I see.
And, in what state was the master in when you took the coffee to him?
I was going to take it to him, but when I went into the kitchen, the server wasn't there.
If the coffee server wasn't in the kitchen...
Where did it go?
I left the coffee server ready in the kitchen before I left to go shopping.
Then...
While Kikuyo-san was out shopping and the wife was with us...
Someone had to put the sleeping pills in the coffee that was left behind in the kitchen...
And then take it to the victim, right?
It wasn't me!
Segawa Hatarou (48)
Okudaira Family Butler
I was repairing Tango-sama's car.
When I finished, I came into the parlor where the mistress and the others were, only to hear the vase breaking.
remember that he was there in the parlor with us when we heard the sound.
I see.
And who is this "Tango-sama"?
He was the son of the master who was killed by someone in the pool one year ago.
That's why I was hurriedly called in, to solve his doubts about that case.
I see...
But, that old man...
It seems he was really looking forward to Uncle Kogoro's deductions.
He wrote this memo that says for today:
"4:00 PM - Sleeping Kogoro Deduction Show."
Damn you, brat.
Quit messing around.
That means he expected you to solve the case from last year by this evening...
It's becoming less and less likely that this was a suicide...
It does seem that way.
What's this?
A wet spot.
Coffee?
But the top of the table is clean.
There isn't a drop of coffee spilled anywhere.
But what's with this mountain of books?
Were you doing some major cleaning or something?
No, my husband just had some large books he ordered delivered today.
He was just taking out books to make space for them on the shelves.
I see.
And where are those big books?
Let's see...
Oh, that book over there is one.
It sure is a big book.
But, why are his new books next to the door?
Could the criminal have put them for some reason?
For some kind of trick or something?
Aren't you Hondou Eisuke-kun?
Why are you here too?
Yes, my mother worked here as a housekeeper, and they found some of her effects...
So I came to get them.
Your mother passed away?
Yes, ten years ago.
I have a photograph here...
Oh, nevermind, I changed clothes after falling by the pool.
I started your clothes in the washer earlier, but...
There wasn't a photo or anything in your pockets.
Do you really think it dropped out when you fell earlier?
My mother's picture...
Be careful.
Yeah, I will.
Jeez...
Didn't I tell you to be careful?
Here, let me hold the photo for you.
Please do.
That's how it is.
Please don't lose that photo.
Don't worry.
I've got it wrapped in a handkerchief.
There's dirt on your face.
Oh, thank you.
First of all, you need to stop being so clumsy, or else your sister will be shocked when you find her.
It's all right.
But my being unlucky one way or another hasn't just started now.
Even now, inside her head, my sister probably still thinks "hopeless brother" equals "Eisuke".
So that's what happened.
Conan-kun?
Where are you going?
To see Uncle Kogoro.
Did you figure something else out?
Yeah, I've figured it out.
The cruel methods the culprit used to commit the murders...
And the true identity of "The Killer from Hades."
The Killer From Hades by Shinmei Kaori
Are we sure there's no mistake that this is a dying message left by the master?
It's difficult to see the meaning, isn't it?
It must have just been accidental.
He simply bit his lip in regret before he died, and the drops just coincidentally seem like they mean something.
Accidental, huh?
Excuse me...
If that book is a dying message...
Then mustn't the criminal be one of us?
No, no. Your husband definitely committed suicide.
Please think about it more carefully.
When the housekeeper and the butler tried to open the door after hearing the vase break...
He shouted, "Don't open," which would mean he was still alive then.
Besides, it was obviously a suicide since the body was still swaying when they opened the door.
He broke the vase before he died because he didn't want anyone else to get their hands on it after he was dead.
Then, what did he use as a footstool?
Well, he probably piled up some of these books that are laying around here and...
Mouri-san, are you all right?
Probably.
It's about time.
Yeah, it just hit me.
Just when I said that about piling up the books...
The cruel trick performed in this room...
And...
The fact that the culprit who executed it is among you three.
So now you're saying the master didn't commit suicide, but was instead murdered by someone?
That's right, Inspector Megure.
As usual, he's saying exactly the opposite of what he said earlier.
Well then, shall we reconstruct the trick used to make it look like suicide and see what happens?
Detective Takagi...
Move the trolley to the exact spot below where the master was hanging.
All right.
Next, stack up about a meter of books on the trolley and then sit on them.
Sit on them?
Yeah, but make sure the books don't fall.
Y-Yes...
Um, I'm sitting on them now...
And now, Inspector, please close the door and line up the remaining books from beside the tires of the trolley to the door.
Like this?
Yeah, but please be sure to put that large book closest to the door.
That one?
You see, that book was closest to the door when the body was discovered.
And so our preparations are complete.
Now, this was the situation at that time, and as you know, the master had his neck suspended from a rope.
All that's left is to open the door.
It's too heavy.
However, if you force the door open...
The door pushes the books, moving them.
Then, the books push on the trolley and the master, who was on top of the trolley's books, will lose his balance...
And fa I off of the books.
And then...
His body would be hanging with the rope around his neck, which is exactly as we found him.
I see...
But no matter how many books he was forced to sit on...
Couldn't he have just used his hands to remove the rope around his neck?
That's why glue was smeared on the knot in the rope, so he couldn't undo it with ease.
But weren't you able to remove the rope when you found the body?
Yeah, if he had the time to work on it slowly, he could have got it off without losing his balance.
But that was impossible for him to do.
You see, both his hands were tied.
His hands were tied?
But, wouldn't we have seen signs on the corpse that his hands were tied?
Well, maybe I could better describe it by saying his hands were "occupied."
What do you mean?
He was forced to hold onto his precious vase behind his back.
Look at the residue on the rim of the vase.
This is evidence that he was forced to hold onto the vase until his hands became too sweaty, right?
Yeah, it's true.
But, no matter how important the vase was to him, he wouldn't let it cost him his life, would he?
And, if he dropped the vase, what would happen?
It would fall to the floor and break.
And what would happen if it broke?
I guess it would make a loud noise.
I see!
If there was a loud noise, someone would come, open the door, and that would be it, right?
Yeah, that's why, when the door was being opened, the master shouted "Don't open."
I see.
But, how did the culprit get out of the room after setting the trick up?
Well, let's demonstrate.
Hey, Conan.
Show them.
OK, got it!
First, you open the door...
And, after leaning the book against the opened door...
You carefully leave through the gap in the doorway, and slowly close the door.
I never thought of that!
With this, it would be possible to make it look like suicide, wouldn't it?
But, placing the culprit will be difficult.
That's true...
Do you know why they had to put the large book in the front of the door?
Why's that?
Because if the culprit didn't use the large book, the gap in the doorway wouldn't have been wide enough for them.
And so, the culprit who needed to do that...
The housekeeper, Kikuyo-san.
It's you, isn't it?
You're not saying Kikuyo-san is...
But wasn't Kikuyo-san at the store then, buying the milk for the coffee my husband requested?
She went to buy it after setting it up.
She anticipated that he would ask for coffee, so she probably had it prepared ahead of time.
Right, Kikuyo-san put the sleeping pills in the coffee and put the master to sleep.
She piled up the books and placed him on top of them...
And then hung the rope around his neck and applied glue to the knot.
She then gently awoke him and forced him to hold the vase behind his back.
Then she threatened that if he let the vase fall, she'd knock out the books.
And, just as I outlined before, she left the room.
Then, when she heard the sound of the vase breaking, she rushed over and forced open the door.
And at the same time, to disguise her trick...
She stopped the wife from falling and deliberately rearranged the books on the floor.
That's a really involved and cruel method to use to kill someone...
Yeah, if he got tired and dropped the vase, he'd be out
He couldn't even call to someone for help.
Yes, and that cruelty was joined by another, so to speak.
The trick the culprit used one year ago when the master's son, Tango-san, was drowned in the pool.
Hey, hey...
There was a trick in that case as well?
Yeah.
It was simple compared with this one.
The culprit just tied up both hands and feet, stuck gum tape on his mouth, and dumped him into the pool filled with water.
Dumped him?
But where's the trick there?
Since the son's clothes fit Eisuke-kun, he must have been of similar height.
The dirt level on the pool wall reached up to Eisuke-kun's eyebrows...
So if he stretched, his nose would be just above the surface of the water.
It's likely that the criminal told the son that they would drain the from the pool if he could last an hour.
If they told him that, he'd keep standing on this tiptoes in order to escape certain death while the criminal made a perfect alibi.
If they left him out there, he would eventually tire and drown.
Yeah.
Being a body builder, his heavy muscle mass would prevent him from floating after his energy was gone.
Isn't that right, Kikuyo-san?
The housekeeper was the murderer a year ago as well?
Yeah, most likely.
There's a strong similarity between both crimes, where the victim was tormented just before their deaths.
B-But, do you have any evidence that Kikuyo-san was the culprit?
Segawa-san or could have done it that way, too.
That's right, we would have used a big book as well, thinking that bigger was better.
And what about the dying message my husband left?
How do "Hades" and "ko" relate to Kikuyo-san?
Hades [YOMI]
Note: "Yomi" and "Meido" both mean "Hades" or "underworld."
The message was actually "Yomi = Meido."
Hades [MEIDO]
And so, that leads us to "Meido (maid) = Housekeeper."
Maid [MEIDO]
Housekeeper
But then, there is even more definitive evidence besides the message.
In the right pocket of Kikuyo-san's apron.
Kikuyo-san, you put the tissue the wife used in your left pocket, right?
You also pulled the supermarket receipt from the same pocket and put t back there afterwards.
Why would someone put an important paper and a dirty tissue in the same pocket together?
Everything struck me when I remembered that
Perhaps you have a reason for not touching your right pocket in view of the police.
Excuse me.
Inspector, there's a handkerchief here.
There are coffee-like stains on it.
Even though the wife was crying, she gave her tissues instead of the handkerchief.
And despite there being coffee spots under the table, the tabletop itself was clean.
The victim likely spilled the coffee with the sleeping pills in it after drinking it, and she wiped it up with the handkerchief...
Which she then put inside her right pocket
All right, turn that handkerchief over to forensics.
If there are ingredients from the sleeping pills in the coffee stain, that will be the evidence.
But...
Why would you...
It's likely related to the accident in which the former butler died two years ago...
And that's why the son was unable to drive his car since that time.
No one has driven his car for two years, right?
It's not that he couldn't drive.
It was because Tango-sama ran over and killed someone.
At that time, Tango-sama was driving the foreign car that the former butler used to escort the master in.
He took it out without permission and, while he was driving, ended up hitting someone and running.
He went crying to the master, and when the former butler suggested he surrender, he got angry at him instead.
And then two years ago on this day...
His car went over the cliff.
Could that accident...
To silence the former butler and hide the damage on the car, they got him drunk and sent him off a cliff in the car.
Just before I dumped him into the pool, Tango-sama said he did it...
With the help of his father.
Then, my brother was murdered!?
So, that's why you killed those two on the anniversaries of the former butler's death.
But how did you know it wasn't an accident?
Because when he went over the cliff, he wasn't wearing gloves.
The gloves he wore every time he drove the car were...
A gift from me to him.
Hey, Ran!
Time to go.
Damn, where'd she go?
If you mean that young lady, it seemed she and that boy were heading to the bathroom sometime earlier.
Bathroom!?
Damn!
Hey!
That bastard!
That's why he wasn't around!
Hey, stop that!
Don't do that so suddenly!
Oh, sorry...
Hey, you!
H-Hi.
What're you doing?
We came so he could change back into his normal clothes...
And then Eisuke-kun just started changing all of a sudden.
But I always used to change in front of my sister.
T-This guy...
Could it be...
Hondou Eisuke is slowly making progress.
It seems he's found a clue regarding his father —
a member of the "Company."
Next time, on Detective Conan.
CLASH OF RED AND BLACK
COMA
Nanatsu no Ko (Seven Children)
Next Conan's Hint!
When I hear Nanatsu no Ko, I think of crows!
When I hear crow, I think of black!
When I hear black, I think of the Organization!