So, how did it go?
You know, about the connection between that Eisuke kid and Mizunashi Rena.
Well, if we go by blood type, Hondou Eisuke's sister and Mizunashi Rena obviously seem to be different people.
Since according to his child health records, Eisuke's blood type is O...
Naturally, his sister, whose blood was transfused into him, must clearly have type O as well.
And, Mizunashi Rena, who's now in the hospital, has AB, so that's that.
Then, that kid and Mizunashi Rena aren't siblings after all?
Probably...
You're hiding something, aren't you?
Don't make that scary face at me; I'll tell you when I'm certain.
I'll save my scary face for next time.
As good as always...
Yoko-chan's singing voice is like little birds chirping.
Damn it, those crows are back up on the third floor railing again!
Hey, shut up!
Shut up, you bastards!
"Crow, why do you sing," eh?
The tingling suspense is building.
Running in the darkness —
a red scream and a black shot.
From Mizunashi Rena to the Black Organization...
The FBI and I make a powerful tag team that drives them against the ropes!
Perceiving the one and only truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan.
CLASH OF RED AND BLACK
COMA
No way...
It stopped at Eisuke-kun again?
That's right
No matter how many times I called, no one picked up.
I'm home.
Hey Ran, can you hear me?
What happened to Eisuke-niichan?
We can't contact him by phone and he's breaking the class call chain again.
The plans for the school event we made at the start of the break have been put on hold and we can't contact him.
"Again"?
How long has it been since you were able to reach him?
I think it was right after winter break started...
Sonoko said the call chain had stopped at Eisuke-kun then too.
Did Eisuke-niichan say anything before winter break began?
Now that you mention it, he did.
Yeah, he said he'd found a clue...
At Haido Central Hospital.
Haido Central Hospital?
That's where Mizunashi Rena is...
The place where they've hospitalized that member of the Black Organization, otherwise known as Kir.
But how did he find her?
The FBI was supposed to be hiding her there discreetly, so no one would know her whereabouts.
It couldn't have been that easy...
Conan-kun?
Did you hear what I said?
The clue wasn't about Eisuke-kun's sister.
Then, what?
His father.
He said he found a member of his father's company.
Eisuke-kun was very happy.
Maybe ever since he lost contact with him, his father and his people from his company have been looking for his sister.
One of his father's colleagues...
A member of the "Company"?
Could it be that aside from those guys in black...
The "Company" is also searching for Mizunashi Rena?
But it was after that, that we stopped being able to contact Eisuke-kun.
Maybe he and that colleague and have been searching for his sister together during the winter break.
Sorry Jodie-sensei...
For making you come here.
It's fine.
Talking on the phone near the hospital is risky, anyway.
Besides, I have something I want to tell you as well.
Well, what is it?
Whatever it is that's bothering you.
It's Hondou Eisuke.
He's gone to Haido Central Hospital.
That boy that's looking for his sister that resembles Mizunashi Rena, huh?
It's true that he visited the hospital at the end of the year.
Really?
Yeah.
He showed some nurses his sister's photo and asked about her.
But since they didn't know that Mizunashi Rena was there...
They wouldn't have been able to tell him anything.
No, I'm not talking about his sister.
He said he saw a colleague of his father's there.
You mean...
From the "Company"?
Yeah, it's become likely they are searching for Mizunashi Rena as well.
I don't know their intentions, though.
That could really be a problem.
If it's the "Company," then they may know the faces of us FBI agents...
Those guys stop at nothing, so I wouldn't put it past them to do something rough, even if it's in a hospital.
I
Then, it's likely that Mizunashi Rena's location could be exposed to those guys in black.
It would be fine if it they'd just stopped into Haido Central Hospital for a visit...
But if they're hiding inside, we have to take measures quickly.
Um, I've been wondering...
What is this "Company"?
From listening to you two, I gather that it's not the usual sort of company...
Just as the FBI is known as a "bureau," they are known as a "company."
They gather intelligence in support of the policies of the United States.
The intelligence service that carries out foreign activities under the direct control of the President.
By that, you mean...
The CIA.
T-The CIA!?
In other words, that Eisuke's father is an American spy.
Isn't that what you meant?
Yeah, but that's just one possibility.
No, there's no doubt
Be thankful.
I sounded out various places and finally got a hit.
And that is?
His real name: Ethan Hondou.
He's a second-generation Japanese-American that joined the CIA thirty years ago as a spy.
Three years after that he came to Japan, got married, and went into hiding.
I couldn't find out what he was looking for here, but...
Maybe...
Intelligence on the Black Organization?
Yeah, if you trust the story that the CIA is pursuing Mizunashi Rena's whereabouts as well.
It's almost certain.
But, isn't it strange?
If that Eisuke-kid is searching for Mizunashi Rena, a partner of those guys who got plastic surgery to look like his sister...
Wouldn't the CIA have stopped him?
That's right
Since the Organization is pursuing her whereabouts as well, he would be in danger if they noticed him.
He could hinder the CIA's operations as well.
Moreover, if he's really their operative's son, there'd be no reason not to stop him.
No, they probably did stop Hondou Eisuke from finding Mizunashi Rena.
He said he saw a colleague of his father's at Haido Central before winter break...
Which was right before we lost contact with him.
Then, the CIA stopped him?
Yeah, they're probably protecting him now as they were requested to by his father.
Unfortunately, that's not the case.
That boy's father, Ethan Hondou...
Died four years ago.
It was an abandoned warehouse in Yokohama.
The eye-witness was a homeless man who was sleeping on the second floor.
After being awoken by a gunshot, he looked to the bottom floor.
A woman was crouching near the collapsed body of a man, when two other men entered.
Both were wearing black.
One was tall, with long hair...
The other was of a solid build and wearing sunglasses.
The kneeling woman explained to the two men in a feeble tone...
"I bit into his wrist..."
"Grabbed his gun..."
"And shot him to death."
Then she said, "I didn't say anything."
"Listen to the MD the dead man is carrying and you'll know."
After a while, another man appeared.
He rushed over and began calling out...
"Hondou!"
"Hondou," he said.
Then, the man who rushed over was with the CIA also?
But if he just called out his last name, how do you know it was really Ethan Hondou?
I showed him the picture of Eisuke-kun's father you sent me.
When I showed it to him for confirmation, he said it was certain.
Akai-kun.
He found conclusive evidence that Ethan Hondou was a CIA operative.
I'm not sure how he got it, but...
His evidence has never proven wrong —
not even once.
But, I doubt they would leave a witness alive, much less two.
Luckily, they didn't realize the homeless man was there.
But, they did kill the man who rushed to the body from where they were hiding.
They burned down the warehouse as well.
They must have expected anyone alive inside to go with it
Just like with me.
Aside from that, the kneeling woman proved even more surprising.
That homeless man, though he was scared to do so, finally responded:
"That woman kneeling there was the splitting image of that announcer, Mizunashi Rena."
Then, that means...
As we thought, Mizunashi Rena's not...
Yeah, it would seem she's not that Eisuke kid's sister.
If she were, that would mean the daughter shot and killed her own father.
Thinking about it, she must have impersonated Ethan Hondou's daughter to get close to him.
She was probably sounding out Row much the CIA understood of the situation, but was then found out and captured.
I suppose that before he could make her talk, she fought back.
I guess I'm stuck now.
I was going to ask Eisuke-kun more details about his father and thought you could call him here.
And now we can't contact him.
At any rate, let's head to Haido Central Hospital.
Since CIA members may be hiding there...
I could prove useful since they don't know my face, right?
Yeah, right.
I'll be there in ten minutes.
Bye.
Just as you ordered, I have that nurse that Eisuke-kun showed the photo waiting for us, Boss.
Thanks.
Hey, hey...
Am I not your boss anymore?
Oh, Driver, did you say something?
Nevertheless, doesn't it worry you?
Why did this Eisuke boy disappear?
Yeah, that's why I'm going to listen to that nurse's story first and get on the right track.
But right now, I think the CIA is protecting him.
Although his father may be dead, I think there must be an operative who knows his colleague's son's face.
No, if Hondou Eisuke just saw a colleague of his father's at the hospital...
Hey, wait a second...
If I remember, when Hondou Eisuke was younger...
When I asked about his father taking him to that Okonomiyaki place...
Ah, isn't this the one?
Yeah, yeah. This is the photo.
Yeah, that was where his father brought his CIA colleagues, but...
When he brought his son with him, it was just the two of them.
That means he never saw the faces of his father's CIA colleagues.
But if his father never introduced him to his partners...
How would he have seen one of his partners at the hospital?
Now that you mention it, he did.
He said he found a clue...
According to what Ran said, he didn't "see" anyone, he "found a clue."
That probably means he didn't see anyone.
But then, what did he mean?
By saying he found a clue to a member of his father's company...
The father told his colleagues at the Okonomiyaki shop, "I'll dive in deeper."
Maybe he really meant, "I will finally get into the Black Organization."
What is it?
Eisuke-kun definitely said that.
He said, "I found a member of my father's company."
Would that be because he saw someone?
One of his father's business colleague's mail address...
He said someone at the Haido Central Hospital punched in the same address.
A company employee's?
How would he know the e-mail address without seeing the person?
The sound.
The sound?
When he had been overseas for work, his father would call him occasionally.
During one of these calls, he heard it.
The push tones closely resembled a melody.
Melody?
Right, right, a children's song.
(SEVEN CHILDREN)
"Nanatsu no Ko"!?
Are you sure!?
Hey, what was that tune?
He asked, and his father said he was mailing one of the guys at his company on the phone.
The person Eisuke saw at Haido Central Hospital...
The person hiding there...
One of their operatives is in this hospital, huh?
But, they may not be still hidden there.
It could have only been a brief visit.
Can we be confident in your source?
It's Edogawa Conan-kun.
A boy he knows witnessed someone at the Haido Central Hospital punching in the e-mail address of the Organization's boss.
That kid again?
You're infatuated with him, Jodie.
Regardless, I have the nurse who spoke with that boy waiting for me.
Avoid taking any conspicuous action before we arrive.
Convey that to the other agents.
If it's revealed that Mizunashi Rena is being sheltered by the FBI in that hospital...
The only line connecting us to the Organization may be cut
Our only line, huh?
If we only dangle a line in a dark sea, we won't catch anything.
To reel them in, we need a line with...
Bait that tempts them from deep in their hearts.
A hook that goes deep inside...
Oh, this boy?
He came at the end of the year.
He had a photo of a girl with him.
And did he say that it was a photo of the announcer Mizunashi Rena?
Yeah.
He asked if she was hospitalized here.
I told him she wasn't.
If she were here, everybody in the hospital would be talking about it.
As I thought: He wasn't searching for his sister.
He's after Mizunashi Rena.
But, is it true?
That this boy went missing after coming here.
Oh, he's not missing, we just lost contact.
That's why his teacher and neighbors are looking for him.
See, Mizunashi Rena has been on break from TV for a long time, right?
That's why he got the idea that she might be in a hospital somewhere.
He's a big fan of hers.
I think he's been out searching and has hardly been home since his winter break started.
Did he say anything else?
I was asked about the same thing that you're asking.
"I saw someone who looked like Mizunashi Rena in this hospital. Is it really her?"
He seemed really surprised.
I couldn't see him well?
Couldn't see him?
I ran into someone, which caused one of my contacts to fall out
That's when he came up and asked me.
And his voice?
Well...
I remember it was a man, but...
As for his voice...
Oh, but...
I think he must have been a patient hospitalized at the end of the year.
At that time, the shop got in some new sandals.
I could faintly see that those were the one's he was wearing.
What!?
When did the shop start selling those sandals?
If I remember...
It was from the 18th of December.
Then there really is a member of the Organization hiding here in this hospital.
It seems there's no doubt about it
We need to transfer Mizunashi Rena to a different place immediately.
Seeing as we know there's a member of the Organization hiding here, we'd be taking too great a risk leaving her here.
But, if we make any sudden moves, we'll be announcing to them that she's here.
However, if there is a hospital who will allow us to admit her, we could do it
Wouldn't it be better to leave her here?
"Leave her here"?
After having someone become a patient...
And seeing as they've only asked a nurse a leading question about Mizunashi Rena's whereabouts...
They must still be in the initial investigation phase.
They came here in order to get decisive evidence.
Besides, this is our chance.
Chance?
To add a second line to the one we already possess.
Well, I do think it's best that we catch him before he discovers us, but...
It seems there were more than twenty male patients admitted to this hospital at the end of the year.
Not to mention, investigating each of them without making it known we're with the FBI makes things difficult...
And, it would take too much time.
If only that nurse could remember which day that man made the inquiry...
I think it was one of the four days between December 18th and December 21st.
The winter break for Teitan High School started on December 23rd.
I heard Eisuke-niichan came here before the school's winter break, so he must have come before the 21st.
If those sandals were only introduced in the shop on the 18th,
we should focus on those hospitalized between the 18th and 21st, right?
R-Right!
Then, I'll get a list of those hospitalized during that period from the director right away.
What's left of concern to us is the whereabouts of that Eisuke boy.
Well, as an FBI agent, I say it's more convenient if he stays gone.
Having the son of a NOC hanging about would present various obstacles.
NOC?
Non-official cover.
NOC, for short
It's used for secret agents that appear as civilians and infiltrate other countries for assignments.
You know so many things; could this be your first time hearing it?
No, I have, but...
That word...
Non Official Cover
NOC, for short.
If that boy is getting close enough to know their boss's e-mail address...
Those guys have no reason to leave him alone.
You might say...
You shouldn't even bother worrying about the survival of that NOC's son.
Who is the member of the Black Organization who's searching for the location of Mizunashi Rena?
I focus my investigation directly on the three suspicious men we've narrowed it down to.
CLASH OF RED AND BLACK
INVASION
Next time, on Detective Conan...
Scar (kizuato)
Next Conan's Hint!
Children's time is over I guess.
Because "kizu-ato" means "kids ato."
"Out!"