Hondou Eisuke's been searching for the woman who's the splitting image of his sister — the Black Organization member Kir, Mizunashi Rena.
Who we hear was killed by Mizunashi Rena four years ago.
But after he visited the hospital looking for Mizunashi Rena, who had not yet regained consciousness from her injuries, we lost contact with him.
Furthermore, we've discovered that a member of the Organization is hiding inside the hospital.
If that boy is getting close enough to know their boss's e-mail address...
Those guys have no reason to leave him alone.
Well, you shouldn't even bother worrying about the survival of that NOC's son.
The tingling suspense is building.
Running in the darkness — a red scream and a black shot.
A member of the Organization lurks within the hospital.
Revealing his identity requires a dangerous strategy.
Perceiving the one and only truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan.
Detective Conan is brought to you by these sponsors.
CLASH OF RED AND BLACK
INVASION
Hold on, little boy.
I finally found it...
What you were looking for.
"Looking for"?
Did you remember something about that man?
No, I remembered something about the boy with the round glasses.
His name is Eisuke, wasn't it?
That's true, but...
I knew it!
He's the boy who had surgery that time.
I knew I'd seen his face before.
I remembered he was the boy who had that surgery at the hospital where I used to work.
Do you mean at a hospital in Osaka?
Eisuke-niichan moved to Osaka following his mother's death and I heard he was in an accident shortly thereafter.
No.
The surgery was here in Tokyo.
Of course, not here, but in another hospital.
Since his mother was with him at the time, it must have been before he moved, right?
His mother?
Then, what kind of surgery was it?
That boy, Eisuke-kun...
Had leukemia.
But to think after that complicated surgery he was in an accident and had to undergo surgery again...
He must have been unlucky.
Great news.
By only considering patients who were hospitalized between the 18th and 21st without serious injuries or illnesses...
And those who were also men...
We've narrowed it down to these three.
Now, the first one was hospitalized on the 18th after fracturing his right leg: Shinki Choutarou-san.
Forgive me for the quality of these photos, as we had to take them quickly and in secret.
The second was admitted on the 19th for a cervical sprain: Kusuda Rikumichi-san.
Lastly, the third was hospitalized on the 21st for acute pain in his lower back: Nishiya Chuugo-san.
All three requested private rooms and don't seem/to have!had any visitors.
In that case, it seems they haven't found out yet that Mizunashi Rena is here and that we're hiding her.
If we had been discovered, in order to determine the number and positions of our agents...
They would have had several people sneak in pretending to be his friends coming to visit
At any rate...
Relay this information to the agent guarding Mizunashi Rena's room for me.
Tell him to carve those three faces into his brain.
Yes.
Still unconscious.
I have some things I want to show you.
Photographs?
A member from the Organization is inside this hospital?
Yeah.
The three in those photographs are the suspicious ones.
Whether they come here on purpose or otherwise...
Do not let them in the room of our sleeping princess.
If we press firmly on the toenails like this...
We can stimulate a pain response.
If she had regained consciousness, this would cause her to awaken or grimace.
It seems we must conclude she remains in a comatose state.
I see.
Well, if we proceed with the EEG now as opposed to doing so in three days...
We'll know for certain.
No, this is sufficient, Director.
I apologize for troubling you.
I just wanted to some kind of confirmation.
Normally I would be asking a lot of questions in this situation, but...
I don't believe the friend who rescued me from those ruffians in L.A. back then would do anything questionable.
So, no questions from me.
You haven't told the director, have you?
The real circumstances.
Yeah, I only told him that we're with the FBI and that she's a material witness in a case.
How could I tell him?
That the famous announcer, Mizunashi Rena, is actually a member of a deadly organization we're hunting...
And that another member has infiltrated into the hospital as a patient to find her.
It's for the director's own safety, after all.
But there is one silver lining.
With her being in a coma...
Even if those guys did locate her hospital room...
It would be too risky to be taking an unconscious body outside.
No...
We must give 100% toward not getting discovered.
If only for the Director and other staff members cooperating with us.
Even if they didn't know the situation...
I think those known to be helping us hide her are in danger of becoming targets of the Organization.
The issue now is how will we determine which of those three is their member disguised as a patient.
Normally, I would take the three of them, transfer them to another hospital, and interrogate them at length.
This is Japan.
Since our investigation isn't sanctioned by the Japanese police...
We can't do that
And two of them are just normal patients.
Having said that, if we approach the suspects badly here, they will realize we're the FBI...
And they would know it's likely that she's being held in this hospital.
Well, then...
Why not try the good idea I've come up with?
"Good idea"?
I'll tell everyone about it after we leave here and go to another room.
If two foreigners and someone with such a mean look in his eyes were seen leaving this room at the same time...
That would be memorable and rumors would spread.
There's no one in the corridor now.
R-Right.
Let's go somewhere else.
Oh, you too, Mr. Lookout
I want you to hear it as well.
It'll be over quick.
Hey, hurry.
I forgot something.
Hold on, I'll go get it really quick.
Well, find it?
Whatever you forgot.
I guess I was wrong.
Sorry.
Mr. Lookout, you should go stay in the room after all.
It would be bad if that announcer lady woke up suddenly.
You'll question the three of them yourself?
We'll be found out if I'm not alone.
I figure the bad guy's partner will lower his guard in front of a child.
Well, it's true the probably won't realize your such a clever boy.
We can't rely on just your judgment to decide which one is their colleague.
It won't be just me.
I'll let you FBI agents think about it with me.
I'll record both the video and audio with a hidden video camera.
That you all can check later.
Actually, I think it would be better to be receiving directions from you guys when I'm asking them things, but...
You don't want to have any radio waves interfering with the medical equipment, right?
Hey, boy.
Are you truly ready?
If you do this, whether you like it or not...
Your face will become known to them.
As a dog that helped the FBI.
Afterwards, don't think the resulting sparks...
Will stop at you.
I'm just like the director.
I believe in you all.
You FBI agents.
You'll definitely capture the bad guy, and never let him go, right?
Ready?
The video camera and microphone are concealed on the right collar of your jacket
But if you're caught...
I should shout, and Sensei will come rescue me, right?
Then, first is...
Nishiya Chuugo-san.
Aren't you that kid from Mouri's place?
What're you doing in a place like this?
You know them?
No, I don't!
I came to visit a friend.
I just asked them because I got lost
But what happened to your head?
I hit my head during club practice and fainted.
I told him this was no big deal for someone like me, but...
Just in case, the doctor had me hospitalized for a few days for further examination.
I bet you tried to do an overhead.
Hey, how would you know that?
Oh, Shinichi-niichan always says that...
How else would you have hit your head like that?
By the^way, did you happen to see Eisuke-niichan?
I think he's been to this hospital, but...
I haven't seen Hondou.
I was only admitted four days ago.
If you mean Aizawa Eisuke from the soccer club, then yes he came to visit shortly thereafter.
It seems we were somehow able to record all three safely.
All thanks to you, Conan-kun.
Let's start watching now.
First is the one who was hospitalized for acute pain in his lower back: Nishiya-san.
What're you doing coming into people's rooms, boy?
Oh, sorry, I got the wrong room.
You fell down?
Just watch.
Hey, boy...
Can you pick up my phone for me?
Jeez...
It's a little bit sticky though.
I have oily skin.
Thanks.
Oh, mister, do you know how cell phones work?
That's right, their member punched in the boss's address...
Sorry, I'm not good with digital things.
I know nothing about them.
Maybe...
H-Hey, what are you doing?
Maybe it's because the curtains are closed.
If I shake them like this, then the radio waves can get into the room!
You idiot, if you do that, it'll make the dust...
Oh, I'm sorry!
Now...
Now, if you're done here, then get out before I lose my temper.
The next one was hospitalized with a cervical sprain...
Kusuda Rikumichi-san, I believe.
What are you doing bursting in here?
Who are you?
I'm sorry.
I got the wrong room.
Hey, could you pick that up for me?
If I have to.
Your cell phone, huh?
The same approach?
It's all I could come up with.
Damn, my neck hurts...
Why the hell are you scampering around anyway?
I'm sorry...
Your face reminded me of someone I know.
Oh, right.
Do you know how a cell phone works?
I keep trying but it won't connect.
I do, but...
Don't you know?
It's not good to use cell phones in hospitals.
There's no battery in this!
Oh, I see.
I dropped it on the way here, so it must have fell out then.
You really like canned coffee, don't you?
I just had a can.
What are you doing?
Sorry, I was trying to see the brand and knocked them over.
I'll put them back for you right away.
And now, lastly, we have the one with the fracture in his right leg: Shinki Choutarou-san.
Pick it up for you?
Jeez, you'd ask a man with a broken leg to do something like that.
Isn't this a cell phone!?
Pick it up yourself!
Why?
The only things I hate are insects and cell phones!
Now that you mention insects, isn't there something on your left collar?
Is that a spider?
What!?
Did you come here to spy on me for someone, boy?
He stood on his own.
Tell this to the doctor who sent you!
My leg hasn't healed yet!
X-rays damage the body and I don't intend to take them.
All I want is my medical certificate!
Now, if you understand that, get the hell out of here!
All three of them could still be faking.
I guess we'll have to watch all three for a while longer.
No, we only have to keep our eyes on one of them.
Isn't that it, boy?
Hey, Shuu...
Are you sure it's only one?
We only have to watch over one suspect?
This boy figured it out, after all...
Quite accurately showing who was their colleague.
"Figured it out"?
Sorry, but Conan-kun...
All he did was fall in front of those three, have them pick the cell phone up, and check if they could use it.
Afterwards, he messed around in their rooms until they were angry.
How could you figure something out from that?
It's true that only one of the three did admit to being able to use cell phones, but...
The member of the Organization would pretend he couldn't use them to deceive us, right?
Like the one who said he wasn't familiar with digital devices, Nishiya-san.
No, the man who was admitted for acute pain in his lower back is innocent
The one who infiltrated this hospital with the goal of finding Mizunashi Rena...
Shouldn't still have pain in his back.
You see, when this boy shook the curtains to raise the dust...
That man...
He put his fingers to his nose and attempted to control his sneeze, as if it would be painful.
In other words, afraid of putting pressure on his body and feeling pain run through him, he sneezed from his mouth.
If he sneezed in the normal way, his back, would have been considerably shaken.
True, but I sneeze like that in front of people too.
Not to mention, he could have done it on purpose to trick us.
At that time, only a child was in the hospital room.
He had no reason to worry about resisting the urge to sneeze.
If he had suspected this boy...
Before giving away his fingerprints by picking up the phone...
He would have thrown him out.
You mean to say the Organization member faked his injury to get admitted?
No matter how he was upon admission, he must have completely recovered by now.
Now that you mention it, that Shinki-san...
He stood up on his injured right leg.
Yeah, his leg fracture seems to have healed already.
As for the one with the cervical sprain, Kusada-san's neck has recovered too, hasn't it?
When Conan-kun stepped out of his sight, he turned back and forth without thinking to look for him.
If his neck was still giving him pain...
He would have turned his entire body instead.
Also, he drank all of the canned coffee completely.
Canned coffee?
See, when you drink from cans...
If you don't tilt you neck back, you can't drink it all.
But, when I knocked all of the coffee cans he'd drank from to the floor...
Nothing spilled out of the cans.
That means...
He had drunk all of them dry, right?
Since he said he'd just finished one...
It couldn't have had time to dry.
That means two of them are faking.
But, why would the one who isn't connected to the Organization be lying?
He's likely in it for the admittance insurance...
That old man.
There is an insurance bonus for staying more than twenty days.
He can pretend he hasn't recovered by refusing the X-ray's.
Simply, his motive is getting the medical certificate.
But couldn't he have said that in order to trick us?
That's true, he did accuse Conan-kun of being a spy for the doctors.
Maybe he intended to pretend he was after the insurance money if it was discovered that he'd recovered.
But that old man was the only one who wouldn't touch the cell phone.
The only things I hate are insects and cell phones!
Isn't that strange?
He couldn't touch it for good reason.
He has a pacemaker that helps his heart work.
If a cell phone or other device emitted radio waves near him, he could be at risk.
But, there was no battery in my cell phone anyway.
B-But, how do you know the old man has a pacemaker?
Remember, there was a scar and a protrusion under his left collarbone.
That's the sign of a pacemaker implant
So, the reason you lied about an insect on his collar wasn't to frighten him into standing up...
It was to confirm whether he had a pacemaker, right?
I see.
Since the old man can't use a cell phone to mail the Organization's boss, he's eliminated as a suspect.
Which means we're left...
With the one who is faking the dizziness...
And nausea of a cervical sprain.
The one who is delaying his discharge...
Kusuda Rikumichi.
At last, we've determined who the Black Organization member is.
However, the Organization's Gin starts to make his move...
And the surprising connection between the Organization and Akai becomes clear.
CLASH OF RED AND BLACK
AWAKENING
Next time, on Detective Conan...
Detective Conan was brought to you by these sponsors.
Miyano Akemi
Next Conan's Hint!
You guys, finish up and expose the Organization's true identity!
Oh, hold on!