Our only hold on the Black Organization...
Mizunashi Rena.
We lost contact with Hondou Eisuke, who was looking for her: the splitting image of his sister.
I learned he'd had surgery for leukemia when he was very young.
That boy had leukemia.
Meanwhile, a partner of the Organization slipped into the hospital where she's been admitted.
I made contact with three suspects directly...
And revealed their partner.
That means we're left...
With the one who is faking the dizziness and nausea of a cervical sprain.
The one who is delaying his discharge...
Kusuda Rikumichi.
There's only him.
Should we take him now?
We should watch him for a bit.
It shouldn't take long before his gives himself away.
Slight as it is, it's still possible that he's a patient in it for the admittance bonus.
Well, if a lot of us keep watch for any suspicious behavior...
There'll be no problem taking him down immediately.
By the way...
Please at least consider it.
Transferring Mizunashi Rena to another hospital.
Yeah.
I was planning to ask the director about it.
He may know an understanding doctor who won't ask any questions.
I'd prefer transferring her before we get Kusuda, but...
Maybe we really should take her to America...
That's not reasonable.
The tingling suspense is building.
Running in the darkness —
a red scream and a black shot.
The location where Mizunashi Rena, or Kir, is...
The Black Organization's found it at last!
Perceiving the one and only truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan.
CLASH OF RED AND BLACK
AWAKENING
Well, should I check the second floor?
Yes, thank you.
Could you check on Chikada-san for me too?
All right.
Neza-san is calling for a nurse this late again...
Is it another malfunction?
Mizunashi...
She's not in this ward either.
Hey, you!
What are you doing?
Oh, nothing...
I got lost.
Um, where is the restroom?
f you're looking for the restroom, it's near the stairs just ahead.
Sorry about this.
Hurry and use the restroom and get back to your room.
Here.
Thank you, thank you.
Say...
Don't you find it peculiar, nurse?
After seeing this camera...
You didn't think I was here to take pictures of the nurse's station?
How could you not guess that?
How could you not say anything?
Who are you?
The FBI!
Keep your hands where I can see them, put them behind your head, and get on your knees!
The FBI, you say?
Then, I guess that means the place where Mizunashi Rena was napping...
Was here, as we thought.
Yeah.
We planned to let you go free until we secured solid evidence against you, but...
That's no longer necessary.
Now, hurry and get on your knees.
Let's not wake the patients.
Then, what would you say to waking them up?
By blowing up this C4!
Plastic explosives!
Don't move now.
Unless you want me to blow this floor, I mean.
Don't move.
Don't move now.
He's probably going back to his room to remove any evidence.
From there, he'll likely escape through the window.
Get outside so he doesn't get away!
He went out the emergency room exit without stopping at his room and through the parking lot to a car?
He predicted us.
We're counting on you, Akai-kun!
Apprehend him by whatever means necessary before he can contact the Organization!
Roger.
However, if he has his cell phone with him now, I won't be able to stop him.
Don't worry.
While he was out of his room, I found his cell phone and dropped it in some water.
Shit!
It broke down at a time like this?
I thought you said you believed in us?
Better safe than sorry.
But, I believe you knew if he noticed them watching and they rushed to arrest him...
That something like this could potentially happen.
You must have predicted that, didn't you, Akai-san?
Well...
Who knows?
It's Akai...
Shuuichi!?
He stopped?
You stopped him before he could contact the Organization, didn't you?
Yeah.
Unfortunately, he found his way to the other side with his own gun.
Since he used a gun to commit suicide, the bombs must have been just a bluff, huh?
But...
At least they haven't discovered where Mizunashi Rena is, right?
No...
Now they will know for certain.
He must have used some method to contact the Organization periodically about his investigation at the hospital.
If that stops completely...
And especially if there were daily reports, well...
They'll be coming.
Tomorrow.
Them.
Haido Central Hospital...
That's where the FBI's decided to manufacture its jail cell for Kir.
Yeah.
When we lost contact with the guy we slipped into that hospital...
I sent in another guy to check it out.
Seems there's a whole swarm of them.
FBI agents, lurking under cover, watching the area.
They figure they've been found out and increased the number of lookouts.
Well, you should be thankful.
The one who got the info that Kir had been gravely injured and might be in a hospital somewhere was me, after all.
The FBI seems to be hiding that kid you got that information from.
He was only a child.
It's no big deal to leave him alone for the time being, is it?
But, how are we gonna get Kir outta there?
The FBI will have fortified that hospital.
If we cause a scene, the world will find out about the Organization's existence.
True.
Getting Kir back from the FBI without incident will be tough.
Getting her back...
What do you mean, Boss?
Don't worry, Vodka.
I have things in hand.
Still, you should be as careful as possible, Gin.
Their "Silver Bullet" has a sharp eye.
Akai Shuuichi.
That FBI agent that gouged my cheekbone with a lead bullet...
I'll take advantage of this opportunity and find a way to deal with him.
Gonna kill him?
Yeah.
I don't know why that person is worried about him...
He's just one rat, after all.
No single "Silver Bullet" can take down our cannon.
As for "Silver Bullets" that can pierce our heart...
There's one more.
We have to move her!
If the Organization knows that Mizunashi Rena is here, there's no sense remaining!
There's no room for debate, is there?
But still...
The thing is, we haven't decided on a hospital to move her to...
And we can't just parade a woman in a coma around at random.
Besides...
If we moved her now, we could find ourselves full of holes.
The agent watching the rear area said he spotted some suspicious shadows moving about on the roof of the building next door.
Then, the Organization is already...
At any rate, it's time for me to tell the hospital director the situation and come up with a plan.
It would be better if you didn't.
If you tell him the situation and their cooperation is discovered...
They could infer that the entire hospital was helping us hide Mizunashi Rena from the start.
On the other hand, if the hospital doesn't make a move in this situation...
They might think it's just a regular hospital not connected to the FBI.
You're right.
Now that this has happened, this is all we can do to protect the director and the rest of the staff.
There are a lot of patients that can't be moved from here.
How can we just wait here, knowing the Organization is coming, without alerting them?
We won't just "wait."
Well draw back.
D-Draw back?
You mean leave her here and run away?
We'll draw back our bows and wait.
Why not ambush them?
The black wolves who've come to retrieve their straying colleague?
It would seem that's the only thing we can do.
I called for several more agents earlier in the day.
Since things have become like this...
It's good that we stopped him when he was taking pictures at the nurse's station.
Even if we only stopped him from transmitting information about unrelated patients to them...
Well, we'd have been found out eventually.
Conan-kun had already made sure his cell phone was broken.
The reason the boy damaged the cell phone wasn't just to prevent him from contacting the Organization.
It was to learn how to contact them.
If he contacted them by cell phone mail when in the bathroom or in his hospital room...
We wouldn't be able to find out how.
With his cell phone broken, he would be forced to choose a different method.
I see.
If the method was something we could observe, like a payphone or a net café...
We would know what sort of words and style they used for communication.
Then we could pretend to be him and continue making contact after we've apprehended him.
Yeah.
In other words, it wasn't this boy who made a mistake.
It was us, the FBI, who did.
We couldn't think of such a method, myself included.
Regardless, let's rest in shifts and prepare for them.
If our nerves stay on the edge, they'll snap before they arrive.
Yeah, you're right.
Well, if something comes to me, I'll report in.
A good plan to attack them with, that is.
What do you think about Shuu?
About what?
Having the Organization coming here in a situation like this...
Somehow he seems happy about it.
Any other feeling would be a lie.
By being able to cross swords with them directly, he has an opportunity to take revenge for his girlfriend.
Revenge for his girlfriend?
Shuu's girlfriend was murdered...
By them several months ago.
It seems she was connected to the Organization.
Shuu said she tried to escape the Organization, so they eliminated her.
Why did Akai-san have a relationship with a woman like that?
To infiltrate the Organization.
She wasn't very high in the Organization herself, but...
Her younger sister was a scientist for them.
Younger sister?
A scientist?
Akai-kun became acquainted with the younger sister.
By using this connection with those around her, he cleverly slipped in with them.
He was a member of the Organization under the name "Moroboshi Dai."
This was five and two years ago, for three years only.
He made it well in the Organization.
At first, he didn't try to stand out too much, but he gradually distinguished himself.
The codename they gave him was "Rye."
Eventually, he was called up to work with one of the executive members, the man called: "Gin."
We expected that if we could capture him, we could take the fight all the way to the boss.
So, we had our FBI agents stake out the meeting place for the mission ahead of time, but he never showed.
We waited all through the night.
Don't tell me they found out he was with the FBI?
Yeah.
It was due to a small mistake by an agent on lookout.
Due to that, Shuu was exiled from the Organization.
Then, Akai-san's girlfriend was killed afterwards?
It seems her younger sister was a very important person to the Organization, so they couldn't lay a hand her.
Shuu realized this and stopped seeing her shortly thereafter.
Well, even if he wanted to contact her, both she and her sister were moved shortly thereafter, so they lost contact.
The Organization thought that since she'd been influenced by the FBI...
They couldn't let her go free, considering she could be contacted in the future.
They became restless and presented her with a proposition.
If she could complete an assignment, they would let both her sister and her leave the Organization.
Of course, the stipulation was that neither she nor her sister would live should she fail.
The Organization planned to use this as a pretext to get rid of them.
But she succeeded in her assignment, which was to procure one billion yen in a robbery.
They ended up killing her without a pretext anyway.
Hey...
What was his girlfriend's name?
Her real name was Miyano Akemi.
Her alias was Hirota Masami.
I never forgot them.
I knew it!
Then, that scientist is Haibara!
We only know this much because Akai-kun received an e-mail from her on his cell phone the day before her mission.
There had been no messages from her for two years, ever since it was revealed that he was with the FBI.
Perhaps, even after knowing she had been used by the FBI...
She couldn't forget about Akai-kun.
And, when she died, you could guess from Akai-kun's behavior...
Shuu probably...
Thinks of her as his girlfriend...
I'm sorry.
No, I wasn't paying attention either.
Is your head in pain?
Or the rest of your body?
I'm fine.
Thank goodness.
I'11 go call the doctor now.
Your name?
Miyano Akemi.
I'm...
Moroboshi Dai.
Nice to meet you.
The same to you.
Dai-kun...
If I'm able to escape from the Organization like this...
Will you go out with me as my real boyfriend?
Dai-kun...
If I'm able to escape from the Organization like this, as my real boyfriend?
Akemi
Hey.
Can we talk?
If it's about how we plan to attack them, I'm still thinking it over.
But, you know...
When I saw you, I was thinking...
Just maybe you were thinking...
Exactly what I am.
Time for a break.
Long night ahead of you.
Akai-san, there's an emergency meeting.
A strategy session, huh?
If the plan is worthwhile, I don't mind.
Wake up...
Mizunashi Rena.
If you don't wake up...
I can't ask you where my sister Hidemi is now.
Can't you hear me?
Hey, wake up!
Wake up!
They're going take you somewhere again, aren't they?
Before that happens, open your eyes!
Hey!
I told you...
Open your eyes!
Don't...
Ei-chan.
Hey, you.
Are you one of the additional agents?
Yes.
I'm Andre Camel.
Sorry, I have a call from my wife just now.
Then make it quick.
There's a strategy session.
Just as planned.
We finally have a plan to get Mizunashi Rena out of the hospital with us.
But those guys in black pull off a preemptive strike...
Next time, on Detective Conan...
CLASH OF RED AND BLACK
DISTURBANCE
Detective Conan was brought to you by these sponsors.
Flowerpots
Next Conan's Hint!
Flowerpots.
Next week's another development you can't take your eyes away from.
Everyone!
This channel...
That's a while...