The Black Organization member who infiltrated the hospital where Mizunashi Rena is being hospitalized...
Kusada Rikumichi...
Killed himself after the FBI agent Akai and I cornered him.
Agent Akai claimed that if Kusada was able to make contact, the Organization would single out this hospital.
The FBI needed to perfect their plan...
But...
There are a lot of patients that can't be moved from here.
How can we just wait here, knowing the Organization is coming, without alerting them?
We won't just "wait."
We'll draw back.
D-Draw back?
You mean leave her here and run away?
We'll draw back our bows and wait.
Why not ambush them?
The black wolves who've come to retrieve their straying colleague?
We discovered that Agent Akai snuck into the Black Organization in the past, and became the boyfriend of Haibara's older sister, Miyano Akemi.
If I'm able to escape from the Organization like this...
Will you go out with me as my real boyfriend?
Dai-kun...
If I'm able to escape from
the Organization like this,
as my real boyfriend?
Akemi
Can we talk?
If it's about how we plan to attack them, I'm still thinking it over.
But, you know...
When I saw you, I was thinking...
Just maybe you were thinking...
Exactly what I am.
Meanwhile, the one searching for his older sister, Hondou Eisuke...
Located Mizunashi Rena's hospital room.
Wake up...
Mizunashi Rena.
If you don't wake up...
I can't ask you where my sister Hidemi is now.
Can't you hear me?
Hey, wake up!
Wake up!
They're going take you somewhere again, aren't they?
Before that happens, open your eyes!
Hey!
I told you...
Open your eyes!
Don't...
Ei-chan.
Hey, you.
Are you one of the new agents?
I'm Andre Camel.
Sorry, I have a call from my wife right now.
Then make it quick.
There's a strategy session.
Just as planned.
You never fail to amaze, kid.
I'm just glad you're an ally, Akai-san.
Same to you.
Well then...
What now, Akai-san?
In this match...
That's live-or-die.
Are you willing to try it?
The tingling suspense is building.
Running in the darkness — a red scream and a black shot.
The victory hinges on some strange incidents.
Each of them are related to the hospital.
Perceiving the one and only truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan.
Detective Conan is brought to you by these sponsors.
CLASH OF RED AND BLACK
DISTURBANCE
We've prepared stretchers for the patients...
And three vans to transport them in.
If the worst arises, we'll confuse them and flee with Mizunashi Rena in tow.
Well, I do hope we don't have to resort to that.
Are there any questions?
May I?
About communicating...
No cell phones or wireless devices, right?
Yeah, with this being a hospital, they can affect the medical equipment...
Besides, cell phone calls are easy to tap.
Should anything happen, report it to your block leader.
Your leader will then go outside and contact James via radio, who will be waiting in the parking lot to give instructions.
But isn't this too much?
If we play the phone game with them...
They could end up taking vital tofu from us.
If we are already prepared for an escape...
Perhaps it's best we go for it now.
That is our absolute last resort.
Since they still don't know which room is Mizunashi Rena's...
Moving her now is too risky.
They definitely have their eyes on every car that comes and goes.
Now that we know their member Kusada was hiding an infrared thermographic device that detects heat...
It's likely that they'll discover which is our car from the number of people inside, thus making the FBI targets for their snipers.
Should that happen, we'll be escaping from bullets as well.
But what if we need to contact you in an emergency?
Of course, contact me on my wireless if needed.
I'll leave that call to you all.
Yes, sir!
Well, they likely won't come here wielding machine guns and handguns openly.
They don't want the world to know of their existence.
That's right.
Creeping as if a shadow, vanishing like the fog...
That's their trademark tactic.
H-Hey...
Where were you?
The strategy session is over.
It's no problem.
I already know the plan from seeing the three stretchers here and the vans in the parking lot.
I can't say it's a "good" plan.
It was expected, though.
Right, boy?
J-Just what is with you two!?
Besides, Conan-kun...
Isn't it time for you to go home already?
It's fine.
I told them I'd be staying at the Professor's.
I already took a quick nap, too.
Jeez...
At any rate...
Let's get in position.
Let us know when you decide to flee, please.
I'm confident in my driving technique.
Hey, Shuu...
Have you seen that man before?
He only joined us recently, but...
No, but I don't recognize his face.
I would never forget an enemy face.
It's natural for him to appear recognizable.
He is a fellow FBI agent, after all.
But I still have a bad feeling about him...
Hey, are you all right?
Yeah.
You aren't getting much sleep.
There are bags under your eyes.
Those are normal.
Well, I guess I'll go out for some fresh air while you patrol.
As I thought, Shuu...
He's thinking too much about his murdered girlfriend.
No, with him, all we need is him thinking.
Since he has been with them and understands their mindset...
He's an opponent whose life they've already made multiple attempts on.
He's the FBI's definitive trump card.
Has something happened?
My stomach...
It's...
Excuse me...
We're...
The Toto line train is now arriving at Platform No. 4.
Please wait behind the white line patiently.
M-My throat...
That strange smell...
Station attendant, please call for an ambulance!
If I can't get that notebook back...
Everyone's hearts will break!
A fire has broken out.
Please follow the instructions of the nearby attendant.
No way!
A fire?
James Black-san?
I'm afraid we don't have a patient by that name.
No, it's not for a patient — it's for an attendant.
That person is a friend of mine, but...
Yes!
I'm here to deliver it to him.
Who sent you and what is it?
Let's see...
The sender was...
One Kusada Rikumichi it seems.
K-Kusada Rikumichi...
Yep, you can guess what Kusada-san sent just from the outside.
Flowers?
Columbine...
It's known as "Odamaki" in Japan, I believe.
They sent this to me?
Since they used the name of their member who killed himself last night, there's no doubt.
As a precaution, we acted as security guards and checked all luggage of those entering the hospital.
We even checked delivery packages.
But why would they send this to me?
Columbine is a flower that grows in Colorado...
"Obtain without failure."
It's the language of that flower.
But, it also means "clear victory."
It's a declaration of war.
Isn't it?
Yeah, something like that.
Just hold on!
We're at the hospital!
Are they fire victims from earlier?
This is Meier at the entrance!
What's going on?
W-Well...
So many ill patients and others are flooding the hospital!
I can't check them all!
W-What?
Those coming in are claiming there were three accidents that occurred simultaneously in the area!
Three accidents at once?
Yeah!
Food poisoning, a disturbing odor, and a fire!
Is it their doing?
But while it's easy to control the timing of a disturbing odor and a fire...
Food poisoning symptoms show up at varying times from person to person.
Perhaps they used a drug that emulates the appearance of food poisoning.
Just the same, the other two accidents were set up in order to avoid killing anyone but also ensure they came here.
And, after excluding those with surface injuries such as burns or cuts...
It's still difficult to determine who is faking pain in their stomach, throat, and eyes.
In other words...
They can pretend to be victims of the accidents so as to get a large number of members into the hospital and quickly.
Their goal is, indeed, to locate the room where Mizunashi Rena is.
If they search in waves, they could find her very quickly...
That's not it.
If they're sending members in large numbers like that and having them act so suspiciously...
Then they are giving us FBI agents a chance to apprehend some of them.
These are not the types to take such risks.
Then, this uproar...
Their target may be...
Something more.
Hey, did you hear something just then?
From the flower pot.
And even worse...
It's getting louder.
Now that you mention it, there is...
Put it on the ground and step away.
A bomb...
You didn't even check the inside of the pot?
Sorry...
We thought they were only flowers, and...
Planting a bomb in a flower pot like this could only take out a few agents.
If the explosion drew the Japanese police, searching for Mizunashi Rena would be difficult.
They could gain nothing from it.
That's what you thought, right?
At any rate, we have to get rid of the bomb.
It's rigged with numerous traps, so defusing it will take too long.
The best and safest option is to take it to an unoccupied area and let it explode.
If the timer is correct...
We have 31 minutes and 14 seconds before it goes off.
Then, forgive me, but it's up to you, Akai-kun.
No, Shuu, you stay here.
I'll take it.
There's a garbage dump seven kilos from here.
I'll go by car.
Then take my car.
Will you really have the time to make it?
The main roads are backed up due to the traffic caused by the three incidents.
Making it in thirty minutes is questionable.
Well, that is, unless you had a navigator like me with knowledge of the area.
Then, it's a different story.
Hey, you...
What are you doing away from your post?
I heard of the traffic problem with so many flooding the hospital.
I came to report, since my post is nearby.
I figured it was easier to approach you all directly.
There's no time to argue.
You two get that bomb out of here.
Roger.
It's bothering me.
You mean Camel-kun?
I mean, he doesn't have the friendliest face, but...
I mean the bomb.
They were gracious enough to include a visible timer.
Then, it was made to get louder so we would notice it.
Also, isn't it strange that they gave us more than thirty minutes?
It's as if they gave the FBI enough time to take the bomb elsewhere to explode.
Then, what was the bomb meant for?
Just what are they trying to do here?
Hey...
Does this really lead to a shortcut to the dump?
How strange...
This was completely empty two years ago.
Two years ago?
At any rate, did you put a clock in the trunk?
I've been hearing this ticking sound.
You should have mentioned that earlier!
Hey!
There isn't a clock back here!
Hey, did you really hear that back there?
He's gone...
Hurry and get in before I leave you.
Why are you in the driver's seat now!?
It would be too tiring to direct you to the secret path aloud.
Besides, I'm better than you are.
Not to mention, there isn't a lot of time left.
Then what?
Did you lie about the clock sound in the trunk?
Yeah, sometimes lying is good.
Hey, what are you doing!?
Hold on to it tight.
H-Hey!
Wait, the dump is the other way!
I gave up on that idea due to time.
All we need is an unoccupied place, right?
Hurry and look at my kid!
Idiot, I was here first!
Hey, those delivery men...
Yeah, there are a lot.
What's with this?
Sorry.
Excuse me.
Damn...
Kusada Rikumichi...
Jodie-kun?
Is everything going well on your end?
The bomb should be going off soon.
W-Well...
Agent Camel took the wheel...
W-Why open the roof?
The wheel.
Please take the wheel.
Hey!
What was that noise!?
Jodie-kun!?
Yes, we've disposed of the bomb.
Great job, Jodie-kun.
No...
If anything deserves praise, it's Agent Camel's driving technique.
Without him...
And how are things on your end?
Akai-kun and Conan-kun seem to have found a clue as to what they're after.
Sorry, I'm from security.
A nurse just brought you a package, right?
This.
Is it from someone named Kusada?
But, I don't know anyone by that name.
Then, allow me.
As I thought: another bomb.
What is that thing?
It's a listening device.
They use it for a rising remittance fraud method.
B-Bomb?
So there really are bombs in those gifts?
One of these plastic explosives will only blow one room.
But, if all of them go off at once...
The entire hospital will come down without a doubt...
Four hours remain until the bombs delivered to the hospital go off.
We, after becoming aware of their aim, have come up with a risky plan...
CLASH OF RED AND BLACK
DISGUISE
Next time, on Detective Conan...
Detective Conan was brought to you by these sponsors.
Driving Technique
Next Conan's Hint!
Driving Technique.
March 3rd is "mimi no hi."
It's also called Hinamatsuri, right?
Because it's a day for chicks.
Is that so?