The ones who shrunk my body, the Black Organization...
With each move I've made toward grasping the Organization's weakness thus far...
The FBI has been a figure that supports me.
Now, the Organization is...
Repeatedly using a single strategy to take back Mizunashi Rena.
After having located the hospital she had been admitted to, the Organization...
Organized three simultaneous incidents in the vicinity of hospital.
Afterwards, bombs were sent to the FBI's James Black...
And also as gifts of consolation to many of the patients.
One of these plastic explosives will only blow one room.
But, if all of them go off at once...
The entire hospital will come down without a doubt...
The tingling suspense is building.
Running in the darkness —
a red scream and a black shot.
A mysterious strategy unfolding in the city...
The hospital is already in a huge panic!
Perceiving the one and only truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan.
CLASH OF RED AND BLACK
DISGUISE
Well, we're lucky that the bomb isn't set to go off until 5:00, giving us four more hours.
If we remove the fuses, what's left of the bombs shouldn't be able to explode.
With the final delivery, the amount of packages delivered by the delivery men was around sixty.
That must be why they wanted to flood the hospital with ill patients, huh?
Delivering so many packages at once would be too conspicuous and get too much attention, but...
By having multiple delivery men show up during the mass panic, we wouldn't expect them to be giving bombs to the patients.
But then...
How did they get the patients' names?
Kusada.
He took a picture of the bulletin board at the Nurse Station that had the patients' names and room numbers.
Most likely, after the picture was received, the orders were given.
At any rate, there are only four hours left.
Have our agents scour every room looking for the packages.
At that point, have them retrieve the bombs.
But, they're relentless with this...
I thought they were only coming to retrieve Mizunashi Rena.
Yeah.
It never occurred to me...
That their plan was to dispose of her from the beginning to seal her mouth for good.
Right, boy?
You're right.
I'm from security.
Do you have a moment?
This is a routine check.
Thanks for your help.
I wonder who this Kusuda-san is...
Excuse me.
I'm sorry, but would you let me inspect your present?
It was this stuffed toy.
May I?
I'm sorry, could you please let me see Mister Bear?
Thanks!
I'll give it right back.
It's that lady from TV!
Mizunashi Rena...
N-No way!
How!?
I'm completely better now.
To all the viewers:
I'm truly sorry for worrying you so much.
I thought she was on TV recently...
Hey, isn't that this hospital?
No way.
Thank you for watching!
Mizunashi Rena is on TV?
Is it really her?
Y-Yes!
We can see it on the TV's down here in the lobby and in the rooms.
She seems to be in her room, recovered, and still wearing her hospital clothes!
Is there a way to call up to her room from our side?
I assigned three men to her room.
I have one coming outside to report to me every five minutes.
Then, we can't call her room?
Right.
Since it could easily cause her transfusion allocation device to malfunction...
We can't allow any wirelesses or cell phones in her room.
Regardless, get up to her room to make sure.
Yes, sir!
We thought as much and are on our way!
So that's the Organization's objective?
Get this message out to the block leaders!
"Stay away from Mizunashi Rena's room!"
Well...
I guess it's too late.
T-Too late?
D-Don't tell me...
They already have her?
What's going on?
Mizunashi Rena came on TV, so I'm going to check it out.
Haven't you seen it?
There haven't been any TV's in the rooms I've visited.
Besides...
We newcomers couldn't check anyway, since we don't know where her room is.
Shall I accompany you?
Keep collecting the bombs.
There should be ten more left.
Leaving them to you!
Roger.
How...
How can it be?
Hey, move!
What the...
She's here.
Then...
What was that on TV?
You've been played.
We're toys in their hands...
Just as they planned.
We've been played?
That clip you saw on TV earlier was taken from an interview she gave following an explosion in which she was injured.
To all the viewers:
I'm truly sorry for worrying you so much.
And after they doctored the clothing and background...
As you can see, I've completely recovered from my injury.
I saw the original video of it at the house of her biggest fan.
There's no doubt.
But, what was the point of airing that video?
To make you FBI agents come here.
They knew you wouldn't use your cell phones or wirelesses.
I'm asking why they would bring us here!
You were just looking for them, weren't you?
The toys that they've scattered about the hospital.
Where are they now?
If you mean the bombs...
I put the defused ones in my pocket.
Since I had to get to another room right afterwards, I kept them.
D-Don't tell me, inside...
Yeah.
In those toys...
Were some troublesome gifts.
Just like flies to mud.
They're gathering up fast, aren't they, Boss?
That's room 307 on the 4th floor, isn't it?
Now that we have the room, it's our turn, Boss.
From the beginning, the location of Kir's cage never interested me.
What was most important was having them believe that was our goal.
Afterwards, we pierce their heads with arrows of fear.
And now, who knows...
How they'll fly?
Transmitters...
You mean they planted transmitters on every bomb?
Yeah.
Basically, they sent those bombs with transmitters inside to locate Mizunashi Rena's room.
The flower pot was to hint they would be attacking with bombs.
With the TV segment of Mizunashi Rena, they were able to get us to rush here while we were hurrying to collect the bombs they had sent.
Then, the Organization...
They're probably watching us and making their next move smiling.
W-What now?
After this, there's no reason to stay.
It's time to go with the last resort I spoke of this morning.
We'll separate into three cars and escape the hospital in the confusion.
Whichever agent is the bait will draw them as far away as possible.
As for who will ride in each car...
Talk to Jodie-kun.
Why don't we put her in a Beetle an old friend of mine drives?
We can lay her down on the back seat.
Those bad guys probably think you'll carry her in a bigger vehicle on a stretcher.
They would never guess this.
T-That's probably true, but...
Then, I'll give him a call.
He'll probably come soon.
No matter how smart you are...
This isn't an option.
This is a job for the FBI.
We can't let normal citizens get involved any further, can we?
But...
Leave the rest to us.
All right, let's destroy the transmitters in the bombs we already have.
Do so only after you've heard me out.
What is it, Akai-kun?
After hearing what this boy said, it hit me.
A clever scheme...
That will allow us to escape with Mizunashi Rena and blind them.
What'd you say?
It's true...
This could easily deceive them.
Well, that would be the objective.
Thanks again for the hint, Conan-kun.
The question now is who is to drive the car with Mizunashi Rena?
That's true.
If they discover us and find ourselves in a position in which we need to lose them...
We need someone who can take action in any situation.
Someone who knows the area and has good driving technique.
That would be you, Akai-kun.
You're the only one we have.
I'd prefer not to.
The first check they'll make is...
To see which car I'm in.
In that case...
I will.
For this...
It has to be me, right?
The one who disposed of the bomb for us, Camel-kun, huh?
I think he's the right one as well.
Fear of death is worse than death itself.
No fear.
I've been prepared for death from the start.
I have no family to mourn my passing anyway.
Well then, it's time to start the preparations.
I'm Andre Camel.
Sorry, I have a call from my wife right now.
U-Um...
What is it?
G-Good luck...
Yeah.
Don't make such a face.
This is necessary for the strategy to succeed.
Or could it be...
You're just nervous about my guarantee?
Not at all.
Well, Camel-kun...
We're counting on you.
You're the key to us failing or succeeding.
I understand.
After we make it through this, I'll buy you a drink.
Looking forward to it.
Wait!
That car...
Cannot be entrusted to you after all.
Will you switch with me?
I know the route.
I don't really mind, but...
Won't this upset the boss?
More importantly...
I have a few questions.
First Van: All ready.
Second Van: All ready.
Third Van: All ready.
The first, second, and third vans are all ready.
Everything should go as planned.
Leave your communication lines open in the event that something happens.
Roger.
By the way, Camel-kun?
Do you know where Jodie-kun has gone to?
She said she was coming to meet you, but...
Yeah.
She came by ten minutes ago.
She had some good advice on how to protect the car.
Right afterwards, she left in her own car.
Hey, hey, without even telling me?
I guess she's anxious, too.
It's no wonder that my car, the "right" car, is the one carrying Mizunashi Rena, I guess.
Here they come.
They're coming!
One dark blue van...
Two...
Three.
It looks like we're only dealing with three vans.
All right.
Chianti...
Follow the first van.
Korn, you're on the second.
Got it.
Vodka, you take the third.
Copy that.
I'll be staying near the hospital to watch over the FBI.
In the event those three are all decoys, that is.
When each of you catch your target car...
Use the planned method to survey the interior.
I'll decide which is the right car from there.
Oh yeah, Boss...
Did the informant call?
I haven't heard from them.
Well, according to that person, it's only for assurance.
I never intended to rely on that plan anyway.
Camel-kun, how is it?
No sign of anyone shadowing me yet.
Wait...
There's one.
I'm at the first car.
How does it look?
I can't see anything with the side windows tinted.
Strip it down.
Roger.
Photography complete.
Forwarding now.
The thermal graph shows...
Nine bodies.
I can see our bomb transmitters on nearly all of them.
You see that?
There's one lying down on the back seat.
Isn't that Mizunashi Rena?
That's the only one without a transmitter, right?
Mine is taken.
Forwarding it now.
I'm seeing nine bodies in the second car, but with no transmitters.
Mine's done as well.
I'm seeing two bodies in the third car that Vodka's on.
Both of them have transmitters.
Could you hurry up, Gin?
Following them for so long...
Makes me want to take out my rifle and open fire right here.
But anyway, it seems like there's no reason to follow mine.
With the transmitters and shadows, we've only got two FBI agents in there.
Besides, if this keeps up, we'll be right back at the hospital.
It'd be a perfect decoy, right?
Sorry for the wait, Gin.
I've finally found it.
Akai Shuuichi's...
Chevrolet.
You're late, Vermouth.
That person directly ordered you to do this, right?
You'll have to forgive me.
He expected this and parked a kilometer away.
And?
Where is he?
We just left Haido Park and entered the Beika City limits.
The closest van to him is Korn's.
So, he's 200 meters back?
Then our target is Korn's car...
Since that guy is following it!
Platinum blond long hair...
It's Vermouth.
We meet again.
Amazing...
He's speeding up.
He'll catch the second car in less than a minute.
They must have noticed Korn has marked it.
So it's the second one!
I'll change course and join Korn in pursuit!
Then I'll head for Korn's car as well.
Following bait like this won't help at all.
If he comes...
I'll fire.
Hold it, Korn.
Take a side road and change course.
Are you giving up and running from Akai!?
What we should be following is...
The third car that Vodka's on.
Kir is inside.
With Mizunashi Rena's whereabouts revealed, their strategy begins drawing to a close.
Now, the identity of the one this plan focuses on, Mizunashi Rena, is becoming clear...
Next time, on Detective Conan.
CLASH OF RED AND BLACK
TESTAMENT
Detective Conan was brought to you by these sponsors.
Kir
Next Conan's Hint.
"Next time, Kir's secret becomes clear," means what exactly?
That's...
To be revealed next week.