The ones who shrunk my body, the Black Organization...
With each move I've made toward grasping the Organization's weakness thus far...
The FBI has been a figure that supports me.
The Organization is...
Trying to recover their member, Mizunashi Rena.
They sprung a clever trap.
The Black Organization showed us footage of Mizunashi Rena.
As a result, the FBI revealed her hospital room.
After this, there's no reason to stay.
It's time to go with the last resort I spoke of this morning.
We'll separate into three cars and escape the hospital in the confusion.
After hearing what this boy said, it hit me.
A clever scheme...
That will allow us to escape with Mizunashi Rena and blind them.
And so, Agent Camel was chosen to drive the van with her inside.
We could only hope our strategy succeeded.
What we should be following is...
The third car that Vodka's on.
Kir is inside.
Why?
That Akai isn't going to screw up and pull out in such an obvious way, drawing our attention to the car he's escorting.
He's luring us into a trap.
A trap?
But, Boss...
The back seat of this van I'm on is empty, and there are only two FBI guys in the front.
While the driver is probably with the FBI...
The one sitting in the passenger seat must be...
They expected us to assume the unconscious Kir would placed be on a stretcher in the back of the car.
So, they put a transmitter on her and put her in the passenger seat to make her look like an FBI agent.
But isn't the third van going back to the hospital?
That's another decisive clue.
Even though they realized we had found out Kir was in that hospital...
The FBI didn't move her immediately simply because they had nowhere to take her in this situation.
Basically, they're making it seem like they're moving her, when they're brazenly returning to the same hospital.
They're guessing we won't check that hospital a second time.
The tingling suspense is building.
Running in the darkness —
a red scream and a black shot.
It's a sink-or-swim contest.
Kir's secret is revealed!
Perceiving the one and only truth.
A child with the intellect of an adult...
CLASH OF RED AND BLACK
TESTAMENT
What?
A black Porsche and four motorcycles?
Don't tell me...
They found you out?
Yeah, it's likely.
But still, they're no match for my driving.
I'll shake them off.
H-Hey!
What's happening, Camel-kun!?
Camel-kun, what happened!?
Kir...
What's the meaning of this?
Why did the car stop?
I heard on that FBI agent's radio that you were coming to rescue me.
I saw my chance and hit him with the bomb case they gave me and pulled the hand brake.
Then...
Even though the FBI had you hospitalized, you were conscious?
Yeah.
I came to two or three days ago.
The FBI thought I was in a coma the whole time, though.
I guess that means we've recovered Kir safely without getting caught.
Yeah.
They left such an important task to just one man.
Let's dispose of this foolish FBI agent.
Do it, Chianti.
Roger.
If you must blame someone, blame your FBI partners who came up with this stupid strategy...
An explosion!?
Could that guy have left a live bomb in his pocket!?
Could the fuse have been triggered from the force of the car crash?
What, an accident?
It's bad!
We need an ambulance!
Lots of curious onlookers.
Kir, you're in my car.
Let's move out.
I-It was successful...
Thanks.
Job well done.
You handed Mizunashi Rena over to the Organization on purpose!?
That's why I had Camel call attention to his driving skills.
That way, he would be the obvious choice to drive the car taking Mizunashi Rena from the hospital.
So, we led them to figure it out...
And let them recover her.
Right, we gave them the impression that they had figured out our plan and had completely outwitted us.
That's the strategy this boy and I carefully crafted.
T-Then, wait...
You mean my getting knocked out by this gorilla was also part of your scheme!?
I gave him instructions to silence anyone who got in the way.
Also, we were fortunate that we could make them the driver had been killed using their own bomb.
He had the car drift so the driver's side was facing the guardrail.
In order to escape, the door had to come to a perfect position.
If he didn't match his escape with the timing of the explosion, the plan would have failed.
I couldn't entrust that to someone with such poor driving skills as you, now could I?
B-But...
Mizunashi Rena was our only thread to them...
How could you stand by and let them take her?
I made an arrangement with her last night.
An arrangement to make her not just a thread, but a fishing line for the FBI...
And one that would make her a part of this boy's scheme.
You never fail to amaze, kid.
I'm just glad you're an ally, Akai-san.
Same to you.
Time for a break.
Long night ahead of you.
Well then...
What now, Akai-san?
In this live-or-die match...
Are you willing to try it?
Of course.
Then first...
Let's have the prince come and wake the sleeping beauty.
Akai-san, there's an emergency meeting.
A strategy session, huh?
Yeah.
If the plan is worthwhile, I don't mind.
Wake up...
Mizunashi Rena.
If you don't wake up...
I can't ask you where my sister Hidemi is now.
Can't you hear me?
Hey, wake up!
Wake up!
They're going take you somewhere else, aren't they?
Before that happens, open your eyes!
Hey!
I told you...
Open your eyes!
Don't, Ei-chan.
Haven't I told you?
Not to become a man that would hurt other people.
Now, Ei-chan...
That's reason enough for you to get out of this dangerous place without asking me anything else.
You're lying!
You have type AB blood, don't you!?
If you were my sister who gave me blood in the past...
You should have type O blood!
That's because I'm your brother who can only get blood from others with O blood!
I'm type O!
Your blood became type AB...
Due to the bone marrow transplant done to cure your leukemia.
The reason your sister's marrow was used for the transplant was the HLA.
Basically, human leukocyte antigens are easiest to match when the transplant is made between siblings.
After they destroyed the leukemia in your type O blood by exposing it to radiation...
They transplanted bone marrow from your sister, who has AB blood.
And, due to that, your blood type changed from type O to type AB.
I have type AB?
There's no doubt about it.
A nurse who was there for the operation told me it was leukemia.
And that scar in the middle of your chest...
It's likely from their multiple insertions of a needle...
To test tumor cells that were circulating in the marrow.
But...
Then...
Why didn't you tell me about that?
Why'd you change your name and become an announcer?
Ei-chan...
She had no choice.
Because your sister is...
An agent with the CIA.
The CIA?
What are you saying?
Why would my sister...
And not just your sister.
Your father was as well.
My father?
She was trying to get information by infiltrating a certain Organization.
She ended up becoming an announcer to suit their plans.
She expected you to see her on TV and try to come meet her.
She didn't dare to tell you about it...
So she pretended to be a different person.
Well, I guess that backfired, since he's come to see you like this.
Hold on a second!
I don't understand!
What do you mean?
What is this "certain Organization"
Sorry.
That's all you're permitted to know.
Camel, take care of him.
W-Wait!
I'm not done talking!
Oh, by the way, it seems that strategy session is about to start.
Then, lock the boy in an empty room and go ahead.
I'll be there when we're done talking here.
Afterwards, follow the directions I gave you over the phone.
Roger.
And now...
I wonder if you know about me?
Yeah.
I know you.
Akai Shuuichi...
The FBI agent that the Organization fears most.
That will speed things along.
We can get to the main point now.
But first...
Tell me one thing.
How did you know I was with the CIA?
First is the technique you used to see if I was lying when you interviewed Domon-san at the park.
Could you have been following me?
Oh, I wasn't...
Just a coincidence.
You were looking for irregularities in my pulse and breathing while watching the size of my pupils to determine if I was lying.
That's a frequent tactic of the CIA.
And afterwards...
I see.
Thanks a lot.
You saved me.
I truly thank you.
You knew I was lying about it being by chance, but thanked me anyway, right?
That's because you were able to get through it without Domon-san dying.
Furthermore, that phrase you used in front of Gin and the others...
Our successes won't see the light of day, but...
Our failures will become widely known.
That's a standard phrase in the CIA, isn't it?
Well, it seems Vermouth became vaguely suspicious.
Don't tell me you're...
Like this?
That "knocking" was a play on words Vermouth used for non-official cover or "NOC", wasn't it
She was saying you were a secret agent.
Actually, at that time, there was a transmitter and listening device on one of your shoes.
It was meant to catch the culprit in the door bell ringing case, but it got there by chance.
I see now.
But, how did you know about my father?
Looking into that wasn't easy, only knowing his real name was "Hondou."
But this boy...
Acquired information that led us to find out he was from the "Company."
But you didn't think I could do it, did you?
That I could kill...
Your own father, you mean?
You bit him into his wrist and shot him under the chin with a pistol.
I should say that's just what he wanted it to look like.
Your father, Ethan Hondou, did that to protect his daughter.
He prepared that MD of him questioning you in advance for that reason.
He must have thought they would find out you were with the CIA.
Right...
It was all his idea.
I was desperately trying to blend into the Organization.
I wasn't trying to reach that level.
I also didn't intend to stay in the Organization long.
My CIA assignment was to introduce a secret agent to work as a contact for my father who was already undercover.
Newspaper: Unidentifiable Corpse in Haido Bay.
The previous person had been killed and therefore communication had been cut off.
After finishing that, I was supposed to fake my death and leave the Organization for good.
However...
This is the new contact.
Barney.
You know him, right?
He should be here soon.
Aside from that, you weren't followed, right?
Yeah.
I was recording a TV segment, but...
I claimed I wasn't feeling well and needed to go take a nap for an hour, and then I left.
It wasn't very far from the station, and when I heard the Organization's next deal was here...
I figured I'd come meet you, Dad, in case it was our last chance.
Did you change clothes?
I came without changing...
Don't move.
Stop it, Dad.
I told you they didn't bug me.
There's a transmitter.
But they've never bugged me before!
These were developed for wildlife studies.
They only last twenty-four hours.
They attach them to new members to watch them.
That's a Porsche...
Gin?
Dad...
What are you...
Enough.
This is the only way to save...
You.
All right, listen up!
This is what happened.
You noticed I was behaving suspiciously.
You followed and tracked me here, but instead I caught you.
I struck you and began questioning you.
But then, you bit my wrist, grabbed my gun, and blew my head off.
Shooting under the chin makes sure they're not suspicious about the blood on my mouth.
I thought something like this might happen, so I made a tape on an MD with my voice interrogating you.
It's in my right pocket.
Tell them you didn't talk!
That's what you should say.
And now, this is...
Truth serum.
So they will believe you.
I'll give you a little bit.
It would be really bad if I gave you it all though.
Never give up, Hidemi!
An ally will come if you wait.
Complete my mission in my place!
Shortly thereafter Gin and Vodka came out of nowhere...
I told them exactly what my Dad said and they let me go without killing me.
When Barney showed up later and saw them...
He killed himself right then and there.
Then, the reason you requested Uncle Kogoro for the doorbell ringing case was because you needed a new contact?
I used that case to get that famous detective's address.
I wanted him to protect Eisuke.
That boy called the TV station a number of times, so I figured he may come by one day.
Of course, I was going to tell him my reasons honestly in an e-mail.
That I was closely connected to a dangerous Organization.
Whether he would believe my story was a gamble.
But, it looks like the one I should have confided in was you.
You noticed, didn't you?
That I had regained consciousness.
It was when I claimed I had forgotten something and came back into the room.
I noticed it then...
That the wrinkles on the sheet around your neck had moved slightly since I left the room.
Also, I knew that Eisuke-niichan was somewhere in here in the hospital as well.
A classmate of his, Nakamichi-niichan, just so happened to be hospitalized here.
When I asked him if he had seen Eisuke-niichan...
Well...
I haven't seen Hondou.
But if you mean Aizawa Eisuke from the soccer club, then he came to visit not long ago.
How did you know from that?
Eisuke
With me only saying "Eisuke-niichan"...
He somehow knew I meant Hondou Eisuke and not Aizawa Eisuke.
Aizawa Eisuke
Hondou Eisuke
That told me Nakamichi-niichan knew he was here and was trying to hide it.
And that's when I knew...
That he was hiding Eisuke-niichan in his own room.
You really are amazing.
Yeah.
To the point that we FBI are speechless.
What are you doing to do now?
The Organization is coming to get me, right?
And I have a proposal.
You aren't saying...
You want me to go back to the Organization, are you?
Of course.
That's exactly it.
Mizunashi Rena is the thread that connects us to the Black Organization.
However, that thread is still viewed with suspicion...
Next time, on Detective Conan...
CLASH OF RED AND BLACK
SUSPICION
Detective Conan was brought to you by these sponsors.
Foreign Star
Next Conan's Hint
Foreign Star.
It's our 500th broadcast!
Thank you, everyone!
We're just passing the midpoint.