The ones who shrunk my body, the Black Organization...
With each move I've made toward grasping the Organization's weakness thus far...
The FBI has been a figure that supports me.
Searching for the whereabouts of his sister and father, Hondou Eisuke finally arrived at Haido Central Hospital...
Hondou Eisuke
Where the FBI was hiding the Organization member Kir - Mizunashi Rena.
Mizunashi Rena
Jodie Starling
FBI
We had tracked down Kusada Rikumichi, a member of the Organization sent to recover her.
But when he failed to report...
Gin and the rest finally started to move, unleashing a merciless attack.
Gin
Vodka
Vermouth
James Black
FBI
During the uproar over the bombs the Organization had planted...
We attempted to put in practice a plan to move Mizunashi Rena.
Andre Camel
FBI
Gin detected our feint.
Mizunashi Rena was taken away by the Organization.
Akai Suuichi
FBI
However, that was just what Akai-san and I had planned.
In truth, Mizunashi Rena was a CIA operative...
Mizunashi Rena / Hondou Hidemi CIA
And Eisuke's sister, Hidemi.
Due to a bone marrow transplant when he was very young, Eisuke's blood type had changed.
And, according to Mizunashi Rena, Ethan Hondou's murder...
Ethan Hondou
CIA
Was to protect his daughter from the Organization.
An action he, her father, had to perform on himself.
You aren't saying...
You want me to go back to the Organization, are you?
Of course.
That's exactly it.
The tingling suspense is building.
Running in the darkness —
a red scream and a black shot.
Their rescue operation has concluded?
And the suspect in a new case is an FBI agent?
Perceiving the one and only truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan.
CLASH OF RED AND BLACK
SUSPICION
I see.
So that's why you deliberately handed Mizunashi Rena over to them?
You're having her act as a spy in their midst just as you did before.
Not as a lap-dog for us...
But as a CIA operative.
Then, the sound of her knocking you out before she got away...
That was also camouflage?
Yeah.
Akai-san had me pretend to be knocked out, lose consciousness, and then stop the car.
But, I didn't expect to actually get hit.
And I asked her to do that as well.
If by chance you had been killed then...
And there was no sign of a wound to your head...
Mizunashi Rena would be in danger.
R-Right...
But wait...
Even so, you could have at least told us about it!
Yeah, I agree.
When she escaped, we were all really shocked and depressed.
That was our intention.
They were very likely keeping tabs on we FBI's wireless communications.
If she had been retrieved and no one sounded disappointed...
Would they really be convinced?
Acting wouldn't do it.
It had to be for real.
Even so, she's just gone back to the them for her CIA job.
We didn't just send her back.
She agreed to pass along information on those guys to us after reporting to the CIA.
A condition like that...
Why would she agree to it?
Naturally, she suggested a condition of her own.
The witness protection program?
You want it for your brother?
Yeah.
I'll write a letter to Ei-chan telling him to cooperate.
You'll do that much, won't you?
You're having me go back to them as a spy when they're already suspicious, after all.
I'll make sure your brother is protected.
Also...
No matter the circumstances...
My father's mission for the CIA takes priority.
Even if I become inconvenient for the FBI, don't think badly of me.
I was about to say just that.
Right, boy?
The witness protection program?
I guess that could probably apply, since the boy knows their boss's e-mail address...
I'm worried about the people in the hospital too.
They probably think they were conspiring with the FBI hide to Mizunashi Rena all along.
We have to...
There's nothing to worry about.
Mizunashi Rena-san is probably already...
We should just leave the hospital alone?
You think we should leave all those people who helped the FBI alone?
They weren't helping them, it seems.
The FBI claimed I was Akai Shuuichi's sister to have me admitted.
But, aren't you a famous announcer?
They had to say I resembled her a number of times.
They also said that if I were really her, the media would have been all over the incident.
Of course, the FBI asked many others to help cover up my being unaccounted for.
Why, Kir?
Why do you care what becomes of that hospital?
What is it?
Is something there?
Not really.
For some reason or other, I just don't wish to kill the people who took care of me...
I wouldn't really enjoy it.
Besides, if the employees in that hospital were cooperating with the FBI and knew the Organization was coming to rescue me...
I think they would have come up with some countermeasures.
For now, we won't act.
Just as you wish.
"For now," you say?
It's difficult to swallow.
That Akai set up a plan that allowed us to retrieve Kir so easily.
There must be something behind it.
Speaking of that guy, it's a shame we weren't able to kill him.
Yeah.
I figured he would certainly interfere as soon as we recovered Kir.
Doesn't that mean this is all he can do?
She was CIA, huh?
That announcer, Mizunashi Rena...
With her now back in the Black Organization again...
At last it's in sight...
Their destruction.
Well, you're already well aware, but...
Don't underestimate them.
Especially Gin.
I understand.
Do you really understand?
Did they say if that Eisuke kid went into the witness protection program?
No, I heard he didn't like the idea.
It seems the FBI is still trying to persuade him, though.
No surprise.
I refused as well.
They give you a new name and nationality.
The system makes you someone else entirely, so I guess it can't be helped.
Actually...
I think he'll reject the program and become an ally, just as you did.
He's pretty clumsy, but he has a sharp mind.
But, you sure it's all right?
Unlike me, that guy seems to be excessively reckless.
It's fine.
He's with Jodie-sensei and Akai-san now.
This Akai person...
I want to meet him at least once.
No matter what you really are, you still look like a first year elementary school student.
A smart and capable FBI member listening to the ramblings of a child...
Doesn't that interest you?
Is there a reason I shouldn't meet him?
How can I tell you?
This is the guy who got close to your sister and became her lover to get into the Organization...
And as a result, your sister ended up getting killed because of him.
She'd probably recognize him too.
Could he be...
Could that guy be...
A loli-con by any chance!?
I was right!?
That's stupid!
You two are whispering to each other again!
(BAKA)
You just said "stupid," didn't you?
I just hope you weren't badmouthing us!
That's not it at all.
We were just talking about the smörgåsbord we're going to.
Right, right!
(BAKA) (BAKAGAI)
I didn't say "stupid," I said "surf clam"!
I was saying, "Maybe they'll have surf clam."
(BAKAGAI)
Surf clam?
Do you become stupid if you eat it!?
Is there really a terrible kind of clam like that?
No, no.
They're regular round clams.
They're known for their delicious taste...
Especially here at this hotel's buffet!
Amazing!
There's so much food!
Yeah!
There's an endless number of things to choose from!
We can all eat as much as we want?
Yeah, but don't hurt your stomach from eating too much.
This looks so good.
It really does!
This, and this, and this...
It's nice to do this sort of thing on occasion.
Yeah.
At this hotel?
Detective Takagi!
C-Conan-kun!
A murder case!?
In this hotel?
It hasn't been announced yet.
Who was murdered?
It was the president of Foreign Talent Productions that had an office setup on the 39th floor of this hotel.
The one who discovered the body was his secretary.
She came back to the office and found him sitting in his chair, covered in blood.
He had been shot a number of times in the torso.
According to the secretary, it seems the president had an appointment today with an up and coming talent star.
The new talent star is the lead suspect, but...
The secretary never saw him, since the president scouted the talent on the street.
She's never seen him and doesn't know his name.
How long has it been since the secretary reported it?
Two or three minutes.
The time of the murder was one or two minutes before that.
Luckily, I was out gathering information nearby, so I was able to get here quickly.
How did you know the time of the murder?
Well, the secretary was organizing things in a room two floors below they were using as a storeroom.
She had been asked by the president about five minutes ago to check on something...
And even though she called a minute later to report in...
She only got the machine.
That means they're still in the hotel, right?
But I think it's been more than five minutes since the crime...
But look...
Two of the three elevators here are down for maintenance.
Even though only one is running, since all those people are waiting, it probably hasn't come yet.
It's probably been full up from customers going to the rooftop restaurants.
I see.
If it's full, the culprit might not get on it.
Why?
If they shot a gun and smelled of gunpowder...
They would normally avoid boarding a full elevator.
And that means...
The culprit went up five floors via the stairs and to the roof.
They're either having a meal inside a restaurant...
Hiding in the restroom on that floor...
Or are sweating heavily from running down the stairs.
Regardless, if he's a foreign talent star that speaks Japanese...
He'll be easy to find, right?
Then, when you discovered President Sunouchi...
There wasn't anyone in the room, right?
That is right.
And, the president...
What did he have you check for him?
Irina Palmer (24)
He had asked me to pick up a file for a talent star he had hired ten years ago.
I called to say, "I am done, should I bring it to you?"
But...
But after many calls...
I could only get the machine.
Is it true you can't identify who the up and coming talent the president was meeting was?
The president would not let anyone meet potential clients before signing them officially.
It was that way with me as well.
Then, you were also a talent star?
That is right.
But, I could not write Japanese very well...
So he asked me to be his secretary in order to learn.
But, but...
Kanji is very hard.
All the messages I received from the president until now were in English.
Nonetheless, if you don't know their name or their face...
It'll be difficult to identify the culprit.
No, Inspector Megure!
Oh, Takagi-kun.
Inspector, we found two people!
Two suspicious foreigners fluent in Japanese.
Suspicious?
What's so suspicious about them?
One was loitering around the restaurants on the roof...
And the other was lurking in the bathroom on that floor.
As I said...
Why does that make them suspicious?
Because Conan-kun said they were!
Takagi...
He said since only one elevator is working, any foreigners still up there are suspects.
You went and told him about the case again?
Sorry...
It's an old habit by now...
Isn't that OK?
After all, he's produced suspects for you!
,You shouldn't be complaining!
Takagi...
Sorry...
So, were they the only two you found?
Ah, well...
Chiba and the others are checking the stairs now.
We found another one!
He's a pretty suspicious sweating foreigner that was hurrying down the stairs!
Hey, get in here!
I told you, you've got the wrong guy...
Be quiet and get in here!
C-Conan-kun!?
A-Agent Camel?
W-Why?
I see...
The fact that he's an FBI agent here in
Japan is being kept secret from the police.
Why was he here at this hotel at the time of the murder?
And why's he wearing a sweat suit?
So we have three suspects, huh?
Toby Keynes (27)
Yes.
We have the one loitering around the rooftop restaurants, Toby Keynes-san...
Hal Buckner (28)
The one lurking in the restroom on the same floor, Hal Buckner-san...
Andre Camel (27)
And then the one who was sweating and hurrying down the stairs...
Hey, hey.
Don't impugn my respectability by calling it "loitering around."
I was just evaluating what I wanted to eat.
You're fluent in Japanese, huh?
Yeah.
My father is American and my mother is Japanese.
That's why I went into modeling.
I was born with such highly chiseled features.
You don't recognize me?
I appear in the fashion magazine "Unknown" on occasion.
Confirm that later.
U-Um...
It wasn't that I was hiding in the restroom.
I was just worrying about a student...
I work as an English teacher in a cram school nearby.
I fell in love with one of the students.
I came here intending to call her to a rooftop restaurant, but...
But at the crucial moment, I just couldn't find the right words.
That's why your face was so pale in the restroom?
When I'm worried, I like to be alone.
What were you doing going downstairs, sweating, in such a hurry?
C-Can't you tell just by looking?
I was training.
The height and length of the stairs in this hotel are perfect for training.
I have to stay in shape for my work.
I used to come here when I had time, so...
"Used to"?
I discovered this place two years ago when I arrived in Japan.
Oh, they offer it in a restaurant up there, right?
That deluxe fruit juice.
I can't forget that great taste after training hard.
Today as well.
And?
What kind of job do you have?
A job that requires you to stay in shape...
A pro wrestler, right?
N-No...
There's one obvious reason he won't answer.
It's because his job... is clearly...
A professional hit man!
Hey, hey...
The reason he keeps his body in shape is to corner his targets with ease.
Those ugly scratches on your face must've been left by one of your victims!
No, these scratches are...
Those "scratches" are saying...
That your face is...
That of a professional killer!
Well, it's obvious he isn't a tourist, right?
That's true.
It isn't normal to be training while traveling...
This guy is actually...
What is it?
Do you know him?
Do you really, Conan-kun!?
Could he be an internationally wanted criminal?
He's a real bad guy, right?
If he was good, he wouldn't be hiding!
No, see...
Just as the kids said...
Unless you have something to hide...
You can tell us what your job is.
I have no choice...
C-Camel is the lead suspect in a murder case?
Yeah.
Apparently, he was using the stairway of a hotel for training where a case happened.
Training on the hotel's stairway?
That's just like that muscle training maniac.
Just like two years ago...
Speaking of which...
I heard he also came to Japan two years ago.
Did something happen then?
Nothing.
More importantly, we should focus on rescuing him quickly.
You can go now, right?
To that hotel.
Y-Yes...
Do your best to make sure they don't find out we're performing a secret investigation in Japan.
Yes, of course.
OK, Conan-kun, I'll be right there.
Well, I'll head out now.
Be careful.
I have a bad feeling about today.
Because it's Friday the 13th, right?
I don't really care about those things.
Is that so?
Detective Conan was brought to you by these sponsors.
English Pronunciation
Next Conan's Hint
The movie comes out Saturday of this week!
The title is...
Full Score of Fear!