The ones who shrunk my body, the Black Organization...
With each move I've made toward grasping the Organization's weakness thus far...
The FBI has been a figure that supported me.
Gin
Akai Suuichi
FBI
The covert plan underlying our strategy to bring an end to the Organization remains undiscovered.
Vermouth
Mizunashi Rena / Hondou Hidemi
CIA
On the condition that her brother Eisuke was admitted to the Witness Protection program...
Mizunashi Rena agreed to return to the Organization.
Several days later, when we went to a hotel buffet...
We got involved in the murder case of the president of Foreign Talent Productions.
Whereupon one of the suspects turned out to be the FBI agent Camel.
James Black
Jodie Starling
FBI
Ah, Jodie...
Be careful.
I have a bad feeling about today.
Running in the darkness — a red scream and a black shot.
Undercover in the Organization, Mizunashi Rena is given the command to rub out Akai!
Perceiving the one and only truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan.
Detective Conan is brought to you by these sponsors.
CLASH OF RED AND BLACK
INNOCENCE
The FBI?
Really?
This evil looking man is with them?
Andre Camel (27)
Yeah, when they're considering agents for the Bureau...
T-They don't judge them by their faces.
But, why is he here in Japan?
You know that I messed up a job for the FBI and came to Japan to console myself, right?
Y-Yeah...
Since I took so long to come back, he got worried about me...
You see, Andre Camel is my lover!
Right, Darling?
Darling?
Yes!
Not bad...
And so? Why are you still in Japan?
Don't you think her Japanese is getting a bit better?
Before, she was saying things like, "sou desssu."
I-It's because I've been taking a crash course from Andre, who's really good at Japanese, that I've improved so much.
And both of us have just found it difficult to leave Japan.
Right, Darling?
Y-Yes, that's exactly right...
For some reason, that seems a bit contrived.
Still, even if he is with the FBI, that doesn't exclude him as a suspect.
We need you to stay until you're cleared of suspicion.
Is that all right?
Yes, of course!
Thank you, Conan-kun, for letting me know.
Say, Jodie-sensei...
Before the FBI pulls out of the hospital, I want to see you all once more.
Inspector!
We found this paper bag in the tool storage area in the rooftop restaurant plaza restroom.
Inside was a raincoat, gloves, and a gun.
These may have been used by the culprit.
I see.
That means we probably won't find any gunpowder when we examine these three suspects clothing.
Moreover, if they had disposed of the clothes they used for the crime, the culprit could have forced their way into the crowded elevator.
I don't think so.
After the crime...
The culprit took the stairs to the roof and went into the restroom...
Then put their gloves, clothing, and gun in a paper bag and hid it in the tool storage area, right?
That means at least five minutes would have passed before they were done.
They would have looked suspicious if they did all of that in a hurry.
They also probably wouldn't have expected the police to arrive this quickly, right?
That's true...
Oh, we also checked the video from the security cameras in the elevator.
There were no foreigners on it.
What about Asian foreigners?
You wouldn't know from their appearance, would you?
No, I guess not...
Irina Palmer (24)
I do not think the president employed any Asian people.
The president always said:
"A person who doesn't look Japanese at all and yet speaks Japanese is interesting."
That means the suspicious ones are still those three people there, right?
In that case, the most suspicious person...
Would be the one who was hiding in the restroom, Hal-san.
Hal Buckner (28)
I already said I wasn't hiding, didn't I?
Besides...
Wouldn't you normally avoid hiding in the same restroom where you hid that kind of stuff?
That's true, but...
When you say the investigators and officers coming, you could have gone back in there to hide without thinking.
That's also possible.
Incidentally, the coat is fitted for slender men.
The length would exactly match Toby-san.
Toby Keynes (27)
Hey, hey...
With something that size, this FBI guy could force himself into it too, right?
Not to mention, it's not just us three men.
The secretary could have worn it as well.
As they say, "better too big than too small."
That's true.
She could have been lying up to now in order to deceive us over her own crime.
Yeah, we need to consider that.
She may have worn a man's coat to make it seem like a man was responsible.
Oh no!
I wouldn't do that!
Regardless, it seems certain that one of you four were responsible for making the president eat those bullets.
Maybe, other than the bullets, the president really was eating something.
See, look here...
At the president's right hand.
Doesn't it look like he was holding something?
Now that you mention it, it does seem that way...
But there's no food on top of the desk.
It's not like he was eating...
It's like he was holding something...
Yeah.
For example...
That pen on the desk or something.
There's only a small amount, but there are traces of blood on the shaft of the pen and on the memo paper!
There are also slight traces of writing on the memo paper!
Could the president have written something before he died?
And the culprit took it?
In that case, have a blood analysis performed and determine what was written.
Yes!
Of course, confirm it was the president's handwriting.
That's how we would investigate it, right, Darling?
Yeah.
So the blood on the memo paper belonged to President Sunouchi?
Yeah, and they say the writing on the memo was his as well.
And? What was on the memo?
W-Well...
It's written in English so I'm not sure what it means...
Or even if it's a dying message.
Bring my tux.
Bring my tux?
Watashi no tuxedo...
...tottekiitte kure?
Yeah, that's right.
Continuing with this job is becoming mentally stressful.
Yeah, it's difficult.
If possible, I want to quit.
I'm truly sorry for the trouble.
Gin...
Kir...
Who was that?
On the phone.
Don't be silly.
It was the human resources manager at the TV station.
I told them clearly that I couldn't be an announcer any longer and needed to quit.
It's troublesome to have them ineptly searching for me.
Besides, the Organization can hear every word I speak.
There are all sorts of bugs and transmitters on me right now and always two or three guards watching me.
And?
That person that even now continues to suspect me...
Has a mission for me?
I came to relay an order from that person that suspects so much...
You will eliminate someone...
To prove you can be trusted.
Eliminate...
Who, I wonder?
The FBI agent...
Akai Shuuichi.
Akai...
Shuuichi?
The FBI agent, Akai.
We've been mulling over how suspicious it was, that person and I...
How extremely easy it was to recover you from the FBI.
So, the plan is to have you kill the FBI's trump card, Akai Shuuichi...
And have you prove your innocence to us personally.
What is it, Kir?
Don't tell me you've got some reason preventing you from doing it?
Do I need a reason?
Gin, how can I approach Akai when even you don't know how to handle him?
If I approach them poorly, they'll capture me again.
You won't approach him...
You will only lure him into our firing range.
You returned to the Organization just fine...
But are now being treated like a black sheep due to your mistake and capture at the hands of the FBI.
Since you no longer have a place here...
You want to leave us and flee to a foreign country.
You can say all that, right?
Of course, you will deal only with him.
If you offer some sort of rewarding information, he'll definitely bite.
I see.
And when he comes in blindly...
You all will come forward and shoot him, right?
You'll handle that on your own.
His nose is surprisingly sharp.
If he detects our presence, he'll see through the trap and turn his heels.
You'll be letting us observe the course of events from a location where his bullets cannot reach us.
We'll place a bug on you...
And of course, a camera.
I get it.
I'll do as you've asked, but can you give me a little time?
Now.
You'll call him now, right here.
If you fail to, you'll be calling the Grim Reaper instead.
W-Wait a second.
Are you serious?
I'm not even sure the FBI will want to talk to me.
That is a possibility, but...
According to the intel from our guy, they're still holding up in that hospital.
Right now, one of their agents has somehow become involved in a case.
The FBI's eyes are all focused on him for now.
We cannot miss this opportunity.
A case?
Yeah.
Some company president found himself with extra airholes.
Just your usual murder...
You might say.
"Bring my tuxedo"?
That's what was written on the memo the president left?
Yeah.
"Bring my tux."
"Bring" is "to get"...
And "tux" is short for "tuxedo".
But, I don't get it...
The pen and paper both have the president's blood on them, and it's in his handwriting.
What's more, there's the memo paper that was torn off.
Which means...
The stricken president wrote it as he was dying...
But the culprit noticed it and took it.
It must be a "daiingu messeeji"...
No, no!
Dying message!
Oh, that's right.
Both of you are English teachers, right?
I-It's true that I teach English at a cram school, but...
Weren't these people FBI agents?
A-About that...
For various reasons, I was teaching for a while.
Right, Darling?
T-That's right, yes!
By the way, secretary Irina-san...
Do you happen to know what he meant by "bring my tuxedo"?
I think it was a message from the president to me.
He was going to a party tonight, so he asked me to bring his tuxedo by then.
Then, it's just a regular memo that has nothing to do with the case?
The president said he was going out this afternoon for a meal with an up and coming talent.
I think it was for when I returned while he was out.
Then, you're the one who tore out the memo, right?
I-I didn't!
After I saw the president was dead, I called right away!
I did not touch anything until the policemen came!
But, I did know about the tuxedo.
I left a message about it on the answering machine.
Answering machine?
Oh, this one, huh?
This is Palmer.
Are you already out, President sir?
I found the file you asked for and am bringing it there now.
Ah, I'll get the tuxedo for the party tonight later.
Friday, 1:27 P.M.
Maybe the culprit heard this and hurried away?
Or maybe the culprit recorded it after the crime to make us think that.
No way!
It's at least possible.
If "Bring my tux" has some sort of hidden meaning in it...
She may have purposely mentioned the tuxedo in the message in order to deceive us.
N-No way...
That is mean...
But, you know...
When you mention a tuxedo, the one who that points to...
Must be this man, who was working as a model, right?
Hey, hold on a second.
That's the work we models usually do, wearing all sorts of clothes stylishly...
It's not just tuxedos.
The president was going to wear one, too.
Now, now, in any case...
We'll be investigating in here.
Everyone please go wait in the next room.
Shinichi, you figured out something about the memo, right?
The president could have added something to a previous memo to make it a dying message, right?
If that were the case, forensics should have noticed the additional writing...
I can't think of anything to add or remove from these English letters to change the meaning.
Say, I'm not sure this is the best time to ask, but...
Two years ago...
What happened?
You said just the other day...
That you came to Japan two years ago.
Speaking of two years ago...
Shuu was still undercover in the Organization then, right?
Then, you must have heard...
About our failure to capture an executive member of theirs due to an agent's mistake.
The agent who made that mistake...
Was me.
Yeah, that was...
Two years ago.
Akai-san had arranged to meet that executive in a warehouse.
While we were all lying in wait...
A lone old man appeared and sat down.
Akai-san was ignoring him, but...
As for me, without thinking, I yelled:
"You should get out of here, it's dangerous!"
I see.
So the old man you drove away was one of their members checking on the arrangement?
Yeah.
Due to that, the executive never showed...
And they discovered that Akai-san was with the FBI.
I remember now...
Some undercover investigation had failed and there was an agent who returned to the office with his head held in shame.
So, when Akai-san asked if anyone was up for the plan this time...
I can handle the driving job!
I-I'll come to Japan right away!
He warned me that I could die, but...
My mistake was the cause of his girlfriend's death.
Akai-san told me not to worry about it, that his girlfriend had been aware of the consequences.
FBI?
Dai-kun is?
Yeah, I'll be putting an end to it tomorrow.
Don't be silly!
If you're trying to fool me...
Think of something better than this.
Otherwise...
I won't be surprised at all.
You knew it...
If you knew, why didn't you leave me?
You knew I was just using you!
Can you not tell without asking?
Akai-kun?
Your phone has been ringing for awhile.
Sorry.
Yes?
It's me.
Me...
Mizunashi Rena.
Is it OK to talk?
Is anyone around?
Who is...
Yeah.
I'm alone.
You're surprised, aren't you?
That I contacted you so soon after returning to the Organization.
More or less.
Explain what you mean.
Actually...
It's become difficult to stay in the Organization.
I want your help to leave and fly out of here.
Of course, I'll offer any information that the FBI wants.
Can we meet now, just the two of us?
Yeah.
It won't be a problem...
So long as you're alone.
All right, I'll mail you the time and place after this call.
Yeah.
Was that good?
Today is Friday the 13th.
I wouldn't have believed earlier...
That his fate would be sealed on such an appropriate day.
Akai-kun...
That was Mizunashi Rena on the phone, wasn't it?
She asked if we could meet now in private.
A private meeting with her could be a trap.
It would be more prudent not to go.
Yeah, except...
If it is a trap and I do not show, in 7 or 8 cases out of 9, she'll be killed.
It's fine.
I'm confident my sixth sense will work.
She may just be CIA...
But I believe she has a clever plan to get out of this.
A-At any rate, I'll call Jodie-kun so we FBI can...
Akai-kun...
W-What are you doing?
The message left behind.
The summoning call.
Do they imply a trap or a cry for help?
Should we take a risk by going on the offensive?
Should we jump in?
A glimpse of the unexpected truth hidden behind their evil ways is coming...
Next time, on Detective Conan...
CLASH OF RED AND BLACK
READY TO DIE