The ones who shrunk my body, the Black Organization...
With each move I've made toward grasping the Organization's weakness thus far...
The FBI has been a figure that supported me.
We successfully put Kir—Mizunashi Rena—in as a thread connecting us to the Organization, but...
It was a dangerous gamble.
The president of Foreign Talent Productions was killed at the New Beika Hotel.
The suspects are...
Irina Palm (24)
The secretary, Irina Palmer-san.
Hal Buckner (28)
An English teacher, Hal Buckner-san.
Toby Keynes (27)
A model, Toby Keynes-san.
Andre Camel (27)
And surprisingly, the FBI agent, Andre Camel-san is the fourth.
The memo the president Sunouchi-san wrote as he was dying...
The memo we believe the culprit took away, said this...
Jodie Starling
FBI
"Bring my tux."
Watashi no tuxedo tottekite kure.
What could this dying message have meant?
Afterwards, the FBI agent Akai received a phone call.
Yes?
Akai Shuuichi
FBI
It's me.
Mizunashi Rena.
Mizunashi Rena / Hondou Hidemi
CIA
Actually, it's become difficult to stay in the Organization.
I want your help to leave and fly out of here.
All right, I'll mail you the time and place after this call.
Yeah.
That was Mizunashi Rena on the phone, wasn't it?
She asked if we could meet now in private.
A private meeting with her could be a trap.
It would me more prudent not to go.
Yeah...
Except...
If it is a trap and I do not show, in 7 or 8 cases out of 9, she'll be killed.
The Organization must have forced her do it.
But...
It's fine.
I'm confident my sixth sense will work.
She may just be CIA...
But I believe she has a clever plan to get out of this.
At any rate, I'll call Jodie-kun so we can...
W-What are you doing?
The tingling suspense is building.
Running in the darkness — a red scream and a black shot.
The Detective Boys burst into spontaneous laughter.
A magic word identifies the culprit!
Perceiving the one and only truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan.
Detective Conan is brought to you by these sponsors.
CLASH OF RED AND BLACK
READY TO DIE
That's what the report from Chiba said.
According to our investigation...
All of the mail from the president to his secretary, Irina-san, was in English because she can't read or write Japanese well.
Irina Palmer (24)
Hal Buckner (28)
Hal-san really is working as an English teacher in a nearby cram school.
Toby Keynes (27)
Toby-san truly is working as a model for fashion magazines.
We've confirmed all of that to be true.
As for Camel-san here...
Andre Camel (27)
We believe he is with the FBI since fellow agent Jodie attests to that.
That's all we have.
But, we ask that you please wait a bit longer.
Have you solved the mystery behind that memo?
I was going to say we're still looking into that...
"Memo"?
That's the "dining message," right?
That's not how you say it, Genta-kun.
It's "dying message."
U-Um...
If we're just waiting...
I really need to leave in two hours.
The class I'm in charge of starts very soon.
May I please go to the hotel reception?
I have to cancel many appointments...
And we may find out about the people the president met today.
That's true.
I guess it won't be a problem if they're accompanied by a detective?
But, Hal-san, you'll have to give up your lesson for today.
I want to tell the principal the reason for my absence in person.
The cram school's really close, so...
You escort Irina-san.
Have him take Hal-san.
Well, let's get going.
Someone was just killed here...
And they're worried about lessons and parties?
That's some nerve, huh?
Don't you agree, Inspector?
I see...
That's how it was.
That's why the culprit took the memo...
What the hell?
What's wrong?
I thought Shuu might know the meaning of that tuxedo memo, but...
I can't reach him because my cellphone hasn't been working right since this morning.
Jodie-sensei...
Why don't you just borrow my cellphone for a while?
Really?
Aren't your friends' messages and phone numbers inside?
It's all right.
I cleared all of my mail data recently...
And if I remove my cellphone's sim card, you won't be able to see the phone numbers.
If we insert your sim card into my phone...
It'll be just like yours.
We have the same type of phone, after all.
But...
Won't it be a problem if you don't have a cellphone?
It's fine!
I have another one.
Thank you.
I'll use it, then.
But, that's strange, isn't it?
They have different shapes outside, but...
On the inside, they're the cellphones we're used to.
What are you talking about?
I'm saying...
Just like how Camel-san is really-with the FBI inside...
You can't judge him just by his appearance.
Thank you!
Because of you I figured out the mystery of the memo.
Sorry to interrupt your excitement, but...
Can you explain it simply so I can understand it?
In that case...
I'll show you something.
A perfect spell to reveal the culprit...
In a single shot.
S-Spell?
It reveals the culprit when you cast it?
It does require some preparations, though.
Preparations?
First, we'll need a chair for each person...
That's it.
That's simple, right?
Will this really reveal the culprit?
It definitely should, since I heard about this spell from Shinichi-niichan.
If Kudou-kun said so, maybe it will be all right.
Hey, Conan!
What do you mean, "a spell that will reveal the culprit"?
Will you tell us?
Tell us.
In front of the suspects...
You liar!
You're such an idiot!
If culprits could be identified like this, we'd no longer need the police!
That's what I figured they'd say...
What are you really going to say?
Tell us without the jokes.
I'm serious about what I said.
Oh, Takagi-kun.
Just watch.
Please provide four chairs for the suspects.
But, for an interrogation, wouldn't it be best to take them to the station?
No...
It's to find out who the culprit is.
We should know if we do this.
Will it really!?
Probably...
Tonight at 19:00.
The seventh left curve along the Raiha Pass.
On that pass so late, there would be few cars passing by.
It'd be the ideal place for a clandestine meeting.
B-But...
Is this really all right?
Have some faith in me.
And, of course, in her.
Akai-kun...
Well then...
As for what happens afterwards...
I'm counting on you.
Inspector Megure...
Everything's ready.
Well then, all four of our suspects need to stand in front of the chairs.
W-What are we going to be doing?
I am afraid...
Wouldn't it be more effective to question us individually?
Well, let's do as the inspector says.
It's like playing a "mystery game."
Don't sit down yet.
Is he really going to say it?
That spell?
There's no way!
They would just laugh if he did.
Now that you're all four gathered there...
Shiranpuri!
W-Why did you all sit down?
But, the inspector just said...
Sit down, please.
For foreigners who are used to hearing English, "shiranpuri" sounds like...
"Sit down, please."
This is especially true if they're already standing in front of chairs.
In other words, even though you appear to be a foreigner...
You're actually Japanese.
And, since your ears are not accustomed to hearing English, you could only understand the original meaning: "Play innocent"
Do you understand what that means...
Mr. Culprit?
Culprit?
Why?
U-Um...
Agent Jodie?
I still don't understand...
Me neither...
The case went like this...
The shooting victim was the president of a foreign talent company.
Since the president was meeting today with a new foreign talent...
And also due the police's quick arrival, there were four suspects.
The first is the secretary, Irina-san, who discovered the body.
Then, we have the foreigners who were in the hotel at the time of the murder...
English teacher, Hal Buckner-san...
The model, Toby Keynes-san...
And then we have the one who was training on the stairs...
FBI agent Andre Camel, which makes four.
The clue was a blank memo pad on the president's desk.
From the president's blood on his hand, the pen, and the edges of the memo pad...
We surmised that the culprit made off with the memo that the president wrote as he was dying.
Analysis showed that the traces left by the pen on the paper said, "Bring my tux."
That meant, "bring my tuxedo."
According to what the secretary Irina-san told us...
He had planned to go out to a party tonight.
So, the memo was likely a message the president wrote himself for his secretary.
You understand now, right?
S-So, why...
Did the culprit take such an ordinary memo?
I see!
It's because he couldn't read the English!
The culprit didn't know what it meant, so he got scared and ran off with it!
Most likely, after shooting the president, the criminal was...
Looking around for something and noticed the dead president was holding the pen and the memo pad.
The culprit thought he had written about him and took it as a result.
But, actually, the president had already stopped breathing.
That memo was just a message for his secretary, written in English so she could understand it.
Therefore, the cram school English teacher, Hal Buckner-san...
The secretary that exchanged messages with him only in English, Irina-san...
And the FBI agent Camel-san are all eliminated.
That leaves us with the one most likely to take the memo...
Someone who likely cannot read English...
Toby Keynes-san!
That's why it has to be you!
W-Where's the proof?
You aren't going to accuse me of being the culprit simply because I don't know English, are you?
Say, what would you all do?
I mean, if you picked up a piece of paper with something bad about you written on it.
I would probably just throw it away.
I'd be angry.
I wouldn't want to read it again.
But, what if it were written in a code you didn't understand?
I wouldn't throw it away, in that case;
I would want to know what it said!
I'd take it with me and try really hard to figure it out...
So, the culprit probably...
Please let me check something.
It's here.
I was going to take it home and ask my American girlfriend's younger brother what it said.
Girlfriend?
My girlfriend...
She was overworked by that president, so much that her health suffered and at the end of last year...
She died.
He wouldn't even listen to her.
"Overworked"?
That's right.
He made her sign a contract written in Japanese.
She could speak a few words of Japanese...
But she couldn't read at all.
Besides that, in case she were unable to work...
The contract made her brother responsible for her.
In order to at least save her brother, I decided to threaten him at gunpoint to get back that contract.
I made him scout me out in the city.
When he said the contract wasn't in the room and he'd have to get his secretary to bring it...
I pulled the trigger without thinking.
Then, the file the president asked me to get...
Yeah.
Her contract should be somewhere inside.
If I had known his secretary were such a slender lady...
I wouldn't have killed him.
But "shiranpuri" was a really nice one...
How did you know that I can't speak English and am really Japanese?
"Reception."
It was "reception."
When the secretary left saying she was going to the hotel's reception...
Didn't you say, Toby-san...
Someone was just killed here...
And they're worried about lessons and parties?
That's some nerve, huh?
For foreigners, a hotel's "reception" is what we Japanese call the "hotel front desk."
That's how I knew you couldn't speak English.
So, she meant the front desk?
I knew it sounded strange.
If I knew it would come to this, I'd have learned more English from my American father.
The only thing my father taught me was how to fire a gun.
How to fire a gun?
Yeah, he was with the United States Forces Japan.
Although he didn't want to, when we traveled to Guam...
I pleaded with him until he finally did.
If he planned to teach me, he should have included...
What it feels like...
To shoot someone.
That's something I never wish to go through again.
With each pull of the trigger, a bit more of your soul fades away.
It's a horrible feeling.
Both Dad and Conan-kun...
They should have been back by now.
The two of them will have to go without dinner tonight.
New York?
FBI?
That's right, back then, that person...
Long hair, Japanese...
A gun!?
I can't...
I can't move...
Hey, hurry up! Jump in!
He must be the serial killer!
B-But...
Shinichi is...
Shinichi is still in there...
Shit!
Wai...
Are you Japanese?
I just asked, "Are you Japanese"
Have you seen a suspicious man?
A Japanese man, unshaven, with long, silver-dyed hair?
No, I haven't seen anyone...
At any rate, this place is dangerous.
Take a right at that corner to get to a main street.
You can pick up a taxi from there.
But, my friend...
I'm waiting for my friend.
He's a high school student my age.
Then, I'll suggest this once more to you and your friend.
Leave!
Leave this area immediately!
He was with the FBI.
And then, that other time...
You're crying again?
You always seem to be crying.
Is that wrong?
You just remind me...
Of a woman who looked a lot like you.
She put up a brave face but cried behind my back, a stupid woman.
A woman who looked a lot like me...
I wonder who he was talking about?
Can you not tell without asking?
Has our connecting thread become a double-edged sword?
The long Friday the 13th draws to a close...
Next time, on Detective Conan...
CLASH OF RED AND BLACK
KILLED IN THE LINE OF DUTY
Detective Conan was brought to you by these sponsors.
Bullets
Next Conan's Hint
Everyone, I hope you don't forget FBI agent Akai Shuuichi.
What do you mean?