The ones who shrunk my body, the Black Organization...
With each move I've made toward grasping the Organization's weakness thus far...
The FBI has been a figure that supported me.
In accordance with the plan, Kir returned to the Organization.
But Gin was suspicious...
And gave her the order to eliminate Akai.
As for the murder that occurred at the New Beika Hotel...
Will this really reveal the culprit?
It definitely should, since I heard about this spell from Shin'ichi-niichan.
Try it and see!
Now that you're all four gathered there...
First...
Shiranpuri!
Casting the magic spell safely resolved the case.
At that time, FBI agent Akai had been called out...
By the one who had returned to the Organization, Kir...
The CIA operative: Mizunashi Rena-san.
She had set the meeting place...
At the Raiha Pass.
The tingling suspense is building.
Running in the darkness —
a red scream and a black shot.
As the final gunshot echoes along the mountain pass...
What will be the fate of FBI agent Akai Shuuichi?
Perceiving the one and only truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan.
Detective Conan is brought to you by these sponsors.
CLASH OF RED AND BLACK
KILLED IN THE LINE OF DUTY
The CIA?
What are you saying?
Why would my sister...
Hold on a second!
I don't understand!
W-Wait!
I'm not done talking!
Dad...
Never give up, Hidemi!
An ally will come if you wait.
Complete my mission in my place!
Is something wrong?
You came from the opposite direction.
I arrived ahead of you...
So I could scout out the area.
I see.
And?
Were the results correct?
That I...
Really did...
Come alone.
Yeah.
It seems so.
So, as for your offer in exchange for help escaping...
Let me hear what information you have.
Yeah.
As for what I can offer you...
A Porsche 356A...
So that's how it is...
What's wrong, Kir?
Hurry and finish him off.
But...
I shot out his lung.
Even if we leave him, he won't last thirty minutes.
The head.
Drive a bullet right into his head.
That way we can be sure that his life...
Has come to a final end.
Roger.
To think you'd go this far...
I'm surprised myself...
That it's worked out...
This well.
The police...
Seems there was an accident nearby.
Clean up and get away.
Don't...
Don't think badly of me.
What!?
H-Hurry!
Call the station!
Right!
What the...
Why isn't he answering?
I even went to the trouble of borrowing Conan-kun's cell phone to call him.
He isn't picking up, that damn Shuu.
Maybe he's taking a nap.
It seems he didn't sleep much during that case.
Jeez...
What do you want to do, Conan-kun?
You said you wanted to come by the hospital one more time before we withdrew, right?
Do you want to come with us now?
I had been planning on it, but...
I decided I'd better not.
Having a child hanging around might cause you problems.
Besides, today is Friday the 13th.
I should just go quietly home and go to sleep, right?
See you later, Jodie-sensei.
Friday...
The 13th?
Be careful.
I have a bad feeling about today.
I don't really care about those things.
Really?
Shuu went...
Shuu went to see Mizunashi Rena after she called for him?
Yeah...
After you left, Akai-kun received a call from her...
Asking for a private meeting.
A private meeting?
That's obviously a trap!
Why!?
Why didn't you stop him!?
No, I did try to stop him...
He said her life would be in danger if he didn't go, and talked me out of it.
But this is Akai-kun we're talking about.
There's no reason to be worried.
U-Um...
The place they were going to meet was the Raiha Pass, right?
Y-Yeah...
There was this news segment on the TV just now.
A car exploded at the Raiha Pass...
And a burned body was found inside.
What'd you say!?
The car that exploded was a black Chevrolet.
The person found inside was a man between twenty and thirty years of age.
The discovery was made by police officers in a patrol car that happened to be en route to a different accident.
According to the officers...
The car exploded suddenly right in front of their eyes.
From the fact that there were indications of bullet wounds on the body...
The police will continue their investigation as a murder case.
The person's identity was determined from the car numbers and the body's right hand, which narrowly escaped being burned.
No way! That isn't Shuu!
He must have substituted in someone from the Organization!
He must have done that!
That's what I believe as well!
Raiha Pass
Car Fire / Mysterious Gunshot
If we go to the police...
We can check and make sure!
But, how can we check if the body was burned?
I guess if the right hand of the body remains, we'd know if we compared it with Akai-kun's fingerprints, but...
Then, if we compare it with Akai-san's fingerprints from the FBI registry...
"Please loan us that right hand so we can compare fingerprints."
"That corpse might have been an FBI agent"
Is that what we should say?
It's the same with Akai-kun's Chevrolet.
Raiha Pass
Car Fire / Mysterious Gunshot
There's no doubt his fingerprints are on it, but not only has it been burned, it's in police custody.
We can't just ask them to give it to us without a reason.
If only there was some way we could compare his fingerprints with the fingerprints of the body without making them suspicious...
If we use a cell phone with his fingerprints on it...
I think we could check without raising suspicion.
But, his cell phone...
This one: The cell phone I borrowed from Conan-kun.
Then, I'll give him a call.
He'll probably come soon.
No matter how smart you are...
This isn't an option.
This is a job for the FBI.
We can't let normal citizens get involved any further, can we?
Leave the rest to us.
So, Akai-kun's fingerprints...
I'll take this to the police to confirm it.
Wait.
I'll take you in my car.
I may be belaboring this, but the fact that the body might be someone connected to the FBI...
I won't let them find out.
I'll do this right.
He may be the man who picked up your cell phone?
You mean the man whose burnt corpse was just discovered a while ago?
Yeah.
I just happened to be driving by Raiha Pass this morning...
And had a meal at a roadside drive-in.
He was driving a black Chevrolet, so if that was him...
I remember his face and clothes, so I thought this may be useful for the investigation.
I see.
that case, I'll take charge of this.
Since I actually borrowed that cell phone from Conan-kun...
My and his fingerprints may be on there as well.
I understand.
I'll have it checked out now, so just wait here for a moment.
The results of the investigation are in.
A-And?
Just as I thought...
I was wrong.
Right?
I'm sorry for all the trouble.
I'm the one who should be saying sorry.
I can't really remember much about what he looked like.
However, there are a lot of inexplicable things about that body.
Please contact us if you remember anything else.
Yeah, of course.
Well, thank you for all you've done today.
According to the report...
Both your and Conan-kun's prints are there, just as you told me.
We also found the fingerprints...
Of the man whose burnt corpse was found just a while ago.
Judging from your expression...
I guess that body really was Akai-kun's.
Still, we can't blame Mizunashi Rena for this turn of events.
She would likely have been killed if she hadn't done it.
She did tell Akai-kun...
No matter the circumstances.
My father's mission for the CIA takes priority.
Even if I become inconvenient for the FBI, don't think badly of me.
Right?
Nevertheless, with this...
We can drive a wedge right into the Organization.
One they can never free themselves from, a wedge of steel.
Maybe Akai-kun...
Sacrificed himself on purpose in order to drive in that wedge.
Though, the price for this was far too...
Far too big...
Shuu...
W-What?
The rifle...
Can't reach me here.
When did you...
Drop your gun.
I told you to drop your gun...
Or else the next shot will be at your head.
A pump...
Shotgun?
OK, Calvados.
We'll take her from both sides.
He's conning from there...
Now, Calvados...
What do you say about using your beloved Remington...
To blow away this little FBI kitty cat?
That man...
Was "Calvados," you say?
He was carrying a rifle, shotgun, and three handguns.
I thought he was an arms dealer from somewhere.
Akai Shuuichi?
Shuu I
Don't, Shuu...
You'll be killed.
She was able to shoot out the gasoline tank through the mirror in her condition.
Impressive.
Shuu...
Why are you admiring her?
She's escaping and with a hostage!
She's taken the key to your car.
Well...
I'll leave the rest to you.
It isn't time for that girl with the brown hair to see me yet.
Don't you...
Don't you still have things left undone?
Shuu!
They don't need two...
Silver Bullets.
That one will be sufficient.
Here you go.
It's the cell phone I borrowed from you.
Huh?
You're done with it already?
Yeah.
About that cell phone...
We I need to hold onto it for a while.
As for Conan-kun, could you give him this same model cell phone for me?
So long as he has his sim card, he shouldn't have a problem using it.
Well...
Thanks a lot, Conan-kun.
The serial number is different...
Jodie-sensei?
What?
Just saying...
Good luck.
Hey, Conan-kun!
What are you doing?
We're gonna be late.
What that?
We just heard a strange noise, didn't we?
LAWYER KISAKI ERI'S TESTIMONY
(PART ONE)
Hair
Next Conan's Hint
"High side!"
Next time the case is at a beauty parlor.
"High cut!"
That's a nice cut.
Isn't it?