Waiting gets us nowhere.
Take a step forward into the future...
Begin the deduction and love countdown!
A case at a beauty salon...
Will the suspect gain a powerful edge through the testimony of a lawyer?
Perceiving the one and only truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
I left it to the wind.
Detective Conan is brought to you by the following sponsors.
Well then, onto the next item.
The fighter Nagasaku Shirou is preparing for the championship bout next month, and...
It looks like his wedding is rapidly approaching too.
Young people are always at their best before they get married.
What? Stop being such a grouch.
On the other hand, Dad, you need to be getting ready.
Didn't we agree to have dinner at 10:00?
It's only 6:30!
We need to leave early so we can go and pick up Mom.
Pick up?
At her office?
At the beauty salon.
The beauty salon!?
Hold it!
The reason we're having dinner so late at 10:00 is...
So she can have her hair cut!?
What's wrong with that?
She's getting all dressed up for you, Dad.
That's stupid.
Just so she can look cute.
You should dress nicely too, Dad.
I'm home.
Conan-kun, you get washed up too.
We're getting dressed up.
LAWYER KISAKI ERI'S TESTIMONY
(PART ONE)
This was the last thing I expected to be doing.
Hasaka Minayo (29)
Beautician
Hey, hey...
I still plan to have you cut my hair even after I'm married.
Nagasaku Shirou (28)
Fighter
If she knew you were frequenting the beauty salon of your former girlfriend...
Your beautiful TV star wife would get angry.
So that's why we're cutting my hair here in the bathroom rather than in sight out in the salon, huh?
I'm just being considerate to a popular fighter who's about to get married.
But look...
It's already 8:00.
Customers aren't going to...
Please excuse me!
Yes!
I'm coming!
You're kidding.
It's already closing time, isn't it?
I'm sorry.
The thing is, someone made a special appointment for tonight.
Well, I don't mind coming back some other day.
I don't really need to have this done by today.
Today's the last time...
The last time I cut your hair.
Welcome, Kisaki-san.
Forgive me.
I'm always having to come in at such a late hour.
It's no problem.
You're alone tonight?
Yeah, the rest of the staff had things to do.
Just so you don't feel lonely, I'll raise the volume of the BGM for you.
It's all right.
You don't have to go to all that fuss.
You want the usual color, cut, and perm, right?
As for the cut, you only need to straighten out the ends a bit.
All right, to start with we'll wash your hair over at the shampoo stand.
Jeez...
Why am I, the renowned detective, Mouri Kogorou...
Being forced to go to a beauty salon at a time like this and pick up some old woman who's leisurely getting her hair cut?
It's no problem, is it?
After all, we have the spare time.
Mom said she got an appointment for 8:00.
So we might get to see Mom with her hair down for the first time in a long while.
I was already tired of seeing that when we were young.
Yet despite that, you agreed pretty quickly to go pick her up, Uncle.
OK, the coloring's done!
Now, I'll leave you here for about ten minutes while the color sets.
Please remain like you are for a bit.
You're going out somewhere?
Yeah.
Just to the convenience store to put out the garbage.
I see.
I was thinking we could exchange gossip like usual.
That's too bad.
Oh, I've always looked forward to that each time too.
Like the stories of your defense trials...
And the ones about your famous detective husband.
Well, I have plans to see that famous detective for the first time in a while after this.
I'll be sure to stock up on some of his good stories for you.
Wow! I'll have to put more effort than usual into your setting!
I can hear your fond stories about your husband while I'm cutting.
It's not fondness, just idle complaints...
If I remember correctly, the beauty salon is somewhere at the top of this hill.
Since this is your first time seeing her in a while, please talk nicely, Dad.
Yeah, today especially I'll be giving that woman a whacking...
What was that sound just now?
We just heard the sound of something being hit and then falling, didn't we?
But, I don't see anything around that's fallen...
I don't think we hit anything with the car.
Could that be it?
Look, down there on top of the garbage collection point.
What?
Wait, that's...
A person!
J-Just in case, I'll call for an ambulance and the police!
What's...
This sound?
What do you think?
Thanks, it's perfect.
Thanks for being a good customer.
Say, isn't it a little bit noisy outside?
It looks like something happened.
I heard the sound of a patrol car as well.
Should we go have a look?
Yeah, why not?
Well, if it's a case, that's more my husband's department.
Isn't it?
What's most important to me is...
Your defense...
Lawyer Kisaki.
Stay back!
According to his driver's license...
The deceased is Nagasaku Shirou-san, age 28.
The cause of death is blood loss due to the severing of his carotid artery.
Based on Mouri-kun's story about happening to hear the sound of something falling...
After someone sliced open his neck...
They tossed him over the guardrail of the road above and into here.
But, when we heard the sound on the road above...
We didn't see anyone else around.
Really?
Yes.
Then...
We should consider that they could have carried the body on a tall vehicle, like a truck, and threw it from atop the trailer.
But, I don't think we heard the sound of a truck or anything...
I guess not...
What we heard was...
The sound of a "whack," from something being hit...
A "thud," from something falling...
And a "klink klink," like something rolling. Those three sounds.
A "whack," a "thud," and "klink klink?"
Well, leaving the sounds aside, if we assume the body was thrown...
It's highly probable that the culprit is a man.
And not just an ordinary one, but a reasonably skilled hand-to-hand fighter.
Fighter?
You don't recognize him, Inspector?
The victim is a fighter scheduled to compete in the next championship: Nagasaku Shirou.
He's a fighter known for not letting his opponent get behind him.
His weight class is 90 kg.
To slice the neck of a guy like this and to throw him easily...
They must have been considerably quick-witted and strongly muscled.
If it's only slicing his neck, couldn't a woman have done it too?
Depending on the situation at the time of this man's murder, that is.
Eri!?
Why are you here?
That's my line.
The café we're having dinner at isn't near here, is it?
Well...
It's just coincidence.
Well, at any rate...
If the victim was a fighter...
Let's check to see if there's some fellow fighter that had a grudge against him.
Stupid police...
Sniff around his colleagues all you want.
No matter how hard you look...
You'll never arrive at an ordinary beautician like me.
Miss, you're from this neighborhood, aren't you?
Well...
Is there a barber shop or beauty salon nearby?
Conan-kun...
Why are you asking her something like that?
Because...
If you look at that dead man's neck...
You'll see a lot of small cut-off pieces of hair mixed in with the blood.
Really?
It's true...
I was thinking that maybe he was getting his hair cut before he was killed.
I see.
And also...
Isn't the blood that flowed along his neck strangely broken in places?
Now that you mention it...
Isn't that because his neck was cut when he was wearing a cape or towel from when you get a haircut?
I see!
If it was a barber or beautician, even if the victim were a seasoned fighter...
That means they could bring a blade against their open neck from behind without raising suspicion.
What is it, Takagi-kun?
Actually, just now...
Conan-kun noticed something strange.
I see...
So that means it's quite likely that the culprit is a some macho barber or beautician, right?
Yeah...
Then they could easily carry this man.
Then, I'll go find out if there's any person to answer that description in the neighborhood...
In that case, why not ask her?
She might know...
Because I'm sure that woman is a barber or beautician.
Isn't that right?
Miss?
What?
What's this?
This kid...
What the hell is he?
Because I'm sure that woman is a barber or beautician.
Isn't that right?
Miss?
Is that so?
Yes...
That's right.
She was cutting my hair until just a moment ago.
Then, the beauty salon you had an appointment at today was...
It was Hasaka-san's salon.
It seems it was originally founded by her late father.
But it's remarkable that you noticed, Conan-kun.
That she was a beautician, that is.
It was her hands.
There's a callus on the second joint of the ring finger on that lady's right hand.
Excuse me...
Could you please show me your right hand?
Please excuse me.
It's true...
That's known as a scissors callus, which develops from always placing your right finger through the loop of the scissors.
Also, if you look closely, you'll see her nails are turning a light brownish color.
That's from the chemicals she's always using to dye and shampoo her customer's hair.
How do you know all that?
They did that on a TV program about beauticians!
Again with the TV?
You watch that too much.
It's a lot better than your listening to horse racing.
Horse racing is like romance for men!
Is that right?
Then, let me ask you, do you know how many barber shops and beauty salons are in the area?
You see...
The victim, Nagasaku Shirou-san, was a 90 kg fighter.
As Mouri-kun and his family just happened to be passing by, they heard the sound of a "thud" from something falling.
Furthermore, since there are a lot of small hairs of his same blond color clinging to the blood around his neck...
And based on how the blood is strangely broken up...
The culprit cut open Nagasaku-san's neck with a blade while in the middle of cutting his hair.
And then we have to assume he was thrown from somewhere.
If you don't mind, we hope you can tell us if there are any barbers or beauticians in the area who have the strength to have carried him.
Yes...
There are two or three other shops besides ours, but...
I'm not sure if they have anyone who has that kind of strength.
You were mean, Miss.
Because when I asked earlier if there were any barbers or beauty salons nearby...
You didn't answer me!
Why didn't you tell me then that you had your own beauty salon?
That's because...
Wasn't it you who was mean? Asking that when you already knew the answer.
But...
"But" nothing!
Here, watch this brat properly so he doesn't wander around.
Yes...
I couldn't answer immediately because I was agitated.
Agitated?
Because when I arrived, I recognized the dead man.
Y-You knew him?
The victim, Nagasaku-san?
I'm sure you'll learn about it later, so I'll tell you about it now.
He and I were classmates in high school and we dated for a time.
Then, Nagasaku-san had been to your shop?
Yeah...
Before he got engaged, he used to come a lotto get his hair cut.
Engaged?
Come to think of it, that was reported in a sports newspaper.
Well then, that makes it even more likely.
Hasaka-san...
You had a motive to kill Nagasaku-san as well, did you not?
Hold on a second.
How did you pull that one out of the bushes?
His estranged former girlfriend lives near the area where the body was discovered.
Obviously she's the one to suspect.
I'm amazed at your hasty thinking.
Detective Takagi?
What was the presumed time of death?
Let me see...
Mouri-san discovered the body at...
Sometime around 8:30 PM.
So it would have to be around twenty minutes before that, right?
In that case, it was impossible for her to be the culprit.
Because she was caring for my hair the whole time from 8:00 PM until after 9:00.
She was really with you the whole time?
She was somewhere near me.
Well, midway through she went out to do something, but...
It only took ten minutes.
Then, she must have cleverly used those ten minutes...
Impossible.
Her beauty salon is on the top of that hill, way up there.
It's too far to for her to have carried an adult man with a sliced neck.
B-But still...
What's this "but still?"
Mom and Dad are glaring at each other again.
But if what Kisaki-sensei just said is true...
U-Um...
If you like, why don't you come check my shop?
Well, I guess this is OK once in a while.
Take a left turn at the next intersection.
Hey, what are you doing!?
When you going to turn at an intersection, you need signal ahead of time and check both ways!
Can't you follow the rules properly?
Jeez...
This is why I told you not to ride in my car!
My shop is right there.
What!?
Conan-kun!
Jeez, such reckless driving.
I should have just walked here.
Are you all right?
I see.
So, Kisaki-san, you were sitting in this chair...
And Hasaka-san was cutting your hair, correct?
Yeah.
She always cuts my hair after work.
I made an appointment for 8:00 P.M. today as usual.
I came to the shop at 8:00.
From there we started with a shampoo for ten minutes...
Coloring for twenty minutes...
Another shampoo for ten minutes...
Then a perm for ten minutes...
Yet one more shampoo for ten minutes...
And then fifteen minutes for the cut...
And the last shampoo for ten minutes.
With ten more minutes for blow drying and setting...
That makes it about an hour and a half, doesn't it?
Yes.
You remember things extremely well...
That's what I've always done.
I was supposed to have dinner with someone tonight after this, so I looked at my watch a lot.
When she went out to do something midway through, when was it and where did she go?
It was while we were waiting until the coloring had set.
I'm sure she left for about ten minutes between 8:20 and 8:30, right?
Ten minutes between 8:20 and 8:30, huh?
Then she must have used that time to kill him!
It wouldn't take three minutes to get back here from the scene by car.
But see...
I don't have a driver's license.
I only went to the convenience store to throw out the trash.
The trash?
To the collection point that's just across from the convenience store where go to I buy things.
Convenience store?
It's really close, so would you like to go check it out?
Please, this way.
Is this a back road?
This route is shorter than going down the main street.
And this scooter?
It's something my father left me, I use it now.
I use it sometimes when I go to that convenience store...
Like when I buy rice.
Then, you put the body on the back of the scooter and...
You idiot!
What now!?
Even putting a 90 kg man on the back would be difficult...
But how could she drive around with him set up like that without anyone noticing?
And how do you explain her throwing him like that in the first place?
I was just speaking hypothetically...
And so, which way is the convenience store?
Right...
If you go down that side street, it comes out right in front of the convenience store.
Does this way maybe lead to the garbage collection point where the body was?
Yeah...
Wait, Conan-kun...
Just as I thought...
The garbage collection point where the body was is two levels directly below here.
But, to toss a person from here to the garbage point would be impossible without using a crane...
The popular fighter Nagasaku Shirou-san was killed...
And his body was found at the garbage collection point.
At that time, we heard three sounds.
What on earth could those sounds have been?
Nagasaku-san was killed while he was having his hair cut at a barber shop or beauty salon.
Therefore the most suspicious person is...
The one who runs a beauty salon in the neighborhood, Hasaka Minayo-san.
Minayo-san was Nagasaku-san's former girlfriend.
But, between 8:00 and 9:00, Minayo-san was...
Cutting Kisaki-sensei's hair.
She was only away from Kisaki-sensei's side...
For only ten minutes starting at 8:20.
If we assume Minayo-san was the culprit.
How did she move Nagasaku-san's 90 kg corpse to the garbage collection point in a mere 10 minutes?
Is Minayo-san really the culprit?
And...
The origins of those three sounds we heard...
The dust on the pole of this road sign...
Has been rubbed off, and there's a thin stripe.
Where'd this stripe come from?
You were hurt, I knew it.
Hurt?
We refuse...
Unless you can provide us with an arrest warrant issued by the court?
Well, what if I show you proof?
Proof that she was capable of performing the crime.
LAWYER KISAKI ERI'S TESTIMONY
(PART TWO)
Next Conan's Hint
Scooter
I'm clueless.
Did you try the barber?
Why?
It's always refreshing.
Hey!