Waiting gets us nowhere.
Take a step forward into the future...
Begin the deduction and love countdown!
The lawyer Kisaki Eri and the great detective Mouri Kogoro...
A fateful confrontation between a separated couple!
Perceiving the one and only truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
We had a dinner appointment with Ran's mother, the lawyer Kisaki Eri-sensei...
On the way to get her, we discovered the body of the popular fighter Nagasaku Shirou-san.
From the condition of the body...
It seemed that Nagasaku-san had been killed as he was getting his hair cut at a barber shop or beauty salon.
The one who ran a beauty parlor in the neighborhood, Hasaka Minayo-san...
Hasaka Minayo (29)
Beautician
Confirmed that she had been a former girlfriend of the victim.
Suspicion turned towards her, but...
During the time it seemed that the crime was committed...
She had been caring for Kisaki-sensei's hair.
If we presume Minayo-san was the culprit...
How could she have moved the 90 kg corpse to the garbage collection point?
When we discovered the body...
We heard them:
A "whack," a "thud," and "klink klink."
What caused those three sounds?
LAWYER KISAKI ERI'S TESTIMONY
(PART TWO)
Conan-kun!
Everyone's going.
Shall we go too?
Why are those there?
That table and chair.
Maybe she collected the things she wasn't using...
And put them out for the next bulk garbage collection.
But Minayo-san's really well-organized, don't you think?
Because look...
The newspapers and magazines have been properly separated.
And the cardboard has been folded up in small pieces and tied too.
Come, let's go.
Why?
You ride your scooter in this narrow alley?
Yes.
Normally there's no one here.
Why does that guy keep calling?
Don't want to answer it?
After all, it could be from that cute young lady at your favorite store.
What's wrong with that?
Geez...
Why does it always end up this way?
It's that convenience store over there.
So the garbage collection point where the body was opposite direction, tail.
The dust on the pole of this road sign.
Has been rubbed off, and there's a thin stripe.
Where'd this stripe come from?
Cigarette butts other rubbish have been collected into a circle...
Why is that?
Is this the place?
This is the garbage collection point next to the convenience store where you went to throw out the garbage?
Yes.
Did you people want something?
You're in charge of this convenience store?
Yes.
We're with the police.
The police?
Oh, earlier...
I heard there had been an incident in the neighborhood, but...
Yeah, it pertains to that.
Do you know what time she came here tonight?
Minayo-chan, you're under suspicion?
Yeah...
No, we're only checking just in case.
Let's see...
If I remember correctly, I think it was around 8:30 PM.
I think we'd know if we looked at the shop's receipts...
Since Minayo-chan was the only who bought rice tonight.
8:28 PM, eh?
Do you know how long she was in the store at that time?
I believe it was four or five minutes.
We could find out for sure by checking the security camera.
If that's so, then isn't it totally impossible for her to be the culprit?
When she left me and stepped out for an errand, it was 8:20.
When she came back after finishing her errand, it was 8:30.
She arrived at this convenience store sometime between 8:23 and 8:24.
If she finished shopping and headed back at 8:28, then...
The time available for the crime was either the three or four minutes before coming to the convenience store...
Or the fewer than two minutes after she headed home.
That's too little time to murder him and transport his body to the garbage collection point.
When she came to this store tonight, she was carrying a garbage bag, right?
Yeah, two or three of them...
And what if one of them didn't contain garbage, but a corpse instead?
Eh?! A corpse?
Dear...
Well...
Even though she could have been carrying a corpse on her scooter...
That'd have been impossible.
Impossible?
That's because...
The engine on Minayo-chan's scooter sort of stalled and broke down before she got here.
Stalled?
Yeah, just when I had gone outside the store to put out the trash...
Just as Minayo-chan came out of the back alley that leads to her place...
I noticed it sputtered and stopped.
After that...
She got off the scooter and pushed it by hand up to the store.
It fixed itself after I left it there for a while.
I then rode it home.
Do you get it now?
She's innocent.
Given that she's my treasured beautician...
Could you please stop making accusations against her?
That's the way.
Keep on defending me...
Lawyer Kisaki.
There are some blond hairs sticking to your stomach.
T-That can't be!
I changed clothes properly.
Now that I look closer, they're brown.
They must be Kisaki-sensei's.
R-Right...
That reaction...
She must be the culprit.
But I don't get it...
The trip from Minayo-san's beauty salon...
To the garbage collection point where the body was found is in a direct line and they're in close proximity.
Bit she went from there in the exact opposite direction to shop at this convenience store.
That means...
The remaining time that made it possible to commit the crime was short...
How could she have moved the body of a 90 kg man in that time?
You were hurt, I knew it.
Hurt?
Where did this happen?
Remember?
That time in the ear when Dad braked suddenly.
That's it!
Sudden braking!
If my reasoning to correct...
There should be something left behind here.
Yes, it's just as I thought...
I understand almost everything now.
How a man was dropped into the depths of the Abyss.
That terrible trick.
This guy again?
Haven't I been saying it the entire time?
It's impossible for Hasaka-san to have committed the crime.
But, you see, Kisaki-san...
The presumed time of death was between 8:10 PM and 8:30 PM.
That time when Hasaka-san had left your side, that's still really bugging me.
Right, right.
Not to mention that Hasaka-san was Nagasaku-san's former girlfriend.
That doesn't have any bearing now.
We checked the video of the security camera.
For the four minutes between 8:24 and 8:28...
She was definitely inside the store.
The time available for her to commit the crime was the four minutes between 8:20 and 8:24 and...
The two minutes between 8:28 and 8:30.
In that short amount of time, how could she...
Have moved the body of a 90 kg man...
To that garbage collection point on the street two levels below?
Or is there something else?
Is the reason you're suspicious of her because she's the beautician that I use?
What kind of talk is that?
Hey, Mom!
You're being too harsh.
The reason Dad came here today was...
Actually to pick you up.
I figured that out a long time ago.
In that case, why?
Because he's been playing dumb about it and hasn't said a single word to me.
I'm doing it just to irritate him.
Then...
Shouldn't you ask him about it?
You could say, "Did you come to pick me up?"
What's this?
You want me to flirt with that mustached old man?
Absolutely...
Hasaka-san...
Yes?
Just to make sure...
Will you allow us to search inside your place?
We refuse.
Article 35 of the Constitution.
Everyone has the right to refuse access to their homes, official documents, as well as their personal belongings...
As well as the any investigatory search or seizure thereof.
And, except in the case of arrest, that right can be asserted on the basis of any legitimate reason.
Moreover, it cannot be violated unless there's a warrant that explicitly states the places to be searched and the items to be seized.
If you really must search...
Can you please provide us with an arrest warrant or one that permits search and seizure issued by the court?
B-But, you see...
Well, since she couldn't have committed the crime, I suppose that would be impossible.
That's good.
Nicely done, Lawyer Kisaki.
I was definitely right...
To choose you to be the witness for my alibi.
Well, what if I show you proof?
Proof that she was capable of performing the crime.
You're talking like you could really prove it.
No, just now...
It wasn't me...
He's appeared!
Sleeping Kogoro!
I'm glad that Professor Agasa made me this spare voice-changing necktie.
Wait a moment!
Didn't you just say, "It wasn't me" or something?
Ah, that's because...
I was saying it's not just me who can explain a trick that's this simple.
The trick Hasaka-san used when she murdered Nagasaku-san...
In order to toss him to the garbage collection point two levels below.
Inspector...
Could you prepare some strong fishing line, like that used for big game fishing...
And some cement bags to stand in for the victim?
Takagi-kun, go ahead.
Yes!
Oh, before you do that, please take some photographs.
Photographs?
Of the thing right above the garbage collection point where we discovered the body...
The post of that guardrail.
As well as what's at the turn to the convenience store...
The thin strip on the post of the road sign.
And what is on the road near that sign...
The small pile of rubbish that's been collected into a circle.
Mouri-kun...
The preparations are complete.
In that case, shall we begin?
Please take down the chair that's been placed on the table over there.
That chair was the first thing that I found suspicious.
On that chair...
The seat's been extended to the highest point, right?
It's true...
Minayo-san is a well-organized person.
The old newspapers and old magazines have been carefully separated...
And the cardboard has been folded up and tied.
Despite that, there was that chair...
With its seat left like that extended to the highest point that caught my notice.
I just happened to carelessly leave it that way.
In order to successfully perform this trick...
It was necessary for that chair to be left extended.
Shall we begin to reproduce that trick now?
Detective Takagi?
Yes?
To start with, tie the fishing line you prepared onto the shaft of the chair.
Knot if firmly so that it won't come undone.
Next, take the end of that line...
You see the garbage collection point where the body was discovered?
Loop it around the back of the post of the guardrail directly that's directly in front of it...
And then come back.
Now, for the length of the line running from the chair to the guardrail...
Adjust it so that it's roughly the same as the distance from the back of the beauty salon to the road with the convenience store.
Then, tie it to the rear of the scooter that's parked at the back door.
It's all done.
Well then...
Tie another section of line to the rear of the scooter.
For the length this time...
Make it a bit longer than the distance from the guardrail to the street with the convenience store...
And tie it to the shaft of the chair.
Finally...
Place the cement bags we're using as a substitute for the body and the setup is complete.
Then, all you have to do is head to the convenience store on the scooter.
Are the preparations all ready on your end?
Yes.
Just as you instructed, we've cleared out all the onlookers.
Good, got it.
Takagi-kun...
Go for it.
Start off slowly at first so that the cement bags don't fall...
Then begin accelerating little by little.
Understood.
Inspector Megure!
The cement bags really did fall into the garbage collection point!
Got it!
When the chair collided forcibly with the guardrail...
According to the law of inertia...
The body that was placed on the chair went flying...
And it fell down into the garbage collection point two levels below.
Also, the thread we tied on at first snapped due to the shock of the collision.
If you keep going on the scooter up to the convenience store...
The line we tied on later pulls the chair, and that's how it was returned to the alley.
The law of inertia, huh?
Then, the origin of the "whack", "thud" and "klink klink" sounds we heard...
Was from this, right?
So, those thin stripes on the guardrail and the road sign...
Were left by the rubbing of the line then.
But...
If the body was sitting on the chair...
I think the legs would have gotten caught in the guardrail and it wouldn't have flown over like that.
To ensure that didn't happen...
The victim was likely placed with his legs crossed.
The reason the chair was extended to the highest point was so that the body could clear the guardrail.
Then, what caused the rubbish to collect in a circle on the road?
When Minayo-san was returning from the convenience store...
The dangling string swept up rubbish from the road.
The reason the scooter's engine stalled was...
Due to the sudden braking from when the chair collided with the guardrail.
Where's the proof?
The proof that I killed him?
Aren't you being awfully mean treating, me like a criminal without any proof?
Isn't that right, Kisaki-san?
That proof is, perhaps...
Damn!
He's waking up at the most crucial part!
What's the proof?
Proof?
Provision 239 of the civil code.
If you gain possession of unowned property with the purpose of establishing ownership...
Then your ownership is established.
In other words...
Once garbage has been thrown away at the garbage collection point...
If there is someone in need of it, then it can become that person's property.
If we check the garbage that you took with you to the convenience store, then we'll know, won't we?
If you were the culprit...
Then the bloodstained cape and towel that the victim was wearing at the time of the crime...
You would have wanted to dispose of them immediately by way of the garbage.
Your reaction tells me that we don't even need to bother checking.
It's disappointing.
That you would use me in order to create your alibi.
Most likely...
You asked Nagasaku-san to come to your place before I arrived...
And then you used the ten minutes when my coloring was setting...
To murder Nagasaku-san.
Then, you used the trick we just saw to toss away the body.
But...
When you collected the string...
You were in a hurry and forgot to lower the height of the chair.
The reason you threw the body onto the garbage collection point was...
So someone would discover it quickly for you.
Since you didn't want a wide window for the estimated time of death.
Did you really resent Nagasaku-san that much?
I didn't really resent him that much.
The one I hated was...
That talent he was engaged to.
He and I had a fight.
During the short time when we weren't seeing each other...
She approached him...
And then she got engaged to him instead!
Then...
Why him?
You don't understand?
When he debuted as a fighter, he had short black hair.
The one who made him change to medium length blond hair was her.
It was completely unbearable!
His entire appearance had been changed in accordance with that woman's orders!
And then...
That look of satisfaction on his face...
But, couldn't you have just left him alone?
I had to cut his hair for the rest of his life.
That's what I promised him when I became a beautician.
I didn't want anyone else to cut it...
And I didn't want to cut it.
So, this is all I could do...
Well, we can discuss the rest at the station.
Takagi-kun...
You should be careful too, Kisaki-san.
Fighting with him for silly reasons...
Your petty competition...
There are some things that can't be mended.
Come, let's go.
But it's really too bad!
Now I won't be able to listen to Kisaki-san telling fond stories about her husband any more.
Fond stories?
You're wrong!
Those weren't fond stories.
Is that true?
Don't be silly.
How could it be...
Is that true?
Yes, it is.
Does that bother you?
You really made 1200 thousand yen betting on a dark horse?
Wow, congratulations!
We'll raise a toast tonight!
You're already drinking?
Wait for me!
That phone call?
That call was from my horse-racing buddy who's been calling me the whole time.
He's been pestering me to go drinking because he made a killing!
W-Why?
No idea.
How did the case turn out?
I have no idea either.
Eisuke-niichan...
You came back to school?
Yep.
He was reinstated today.
I still don't know who it is, but...
What I think about this situation is that...
There's an FBI agent observing Hondou Eisuke.
Could it be...
Him...
BLIND SPOT IN THE KARAOKE BOX
(PART ONE)
Next Conan's Hint
Hondou Eisuke
Next time the scene is at a karaoke box.
Even if I'm off key...
My reasoning is pitched right!