Waiting gets us nowhere.
Take a step forward into the future...
Begin the deduction and love countdown!
Everyone's gone to the karaoke box.
The surveillance video can't show the truth?
Perceiving the one and only truth,
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
BLIND SPOT IN THE KARAOKE BOX
(PART ONE)
Look at this guy! Isn't he stupid?
I just can't help laughing!
He's kinda like Genta-kun!
They're on those shelves over there.
You are looking for mysteries, right?
Thanks.
There it is! Shinmei Kaori's new mystery.
Line-Up in the Dead of Night.
And there's only one left!
H-Hondou Eisuke?
Hi, Conan-kun.
It's been a while.
Wow.
It's Conan-kun.
And the rest of the brats.
Hanging around the bookstore reading manga on the way back from school, huh?
Yeah. If you mean these guys...
Didn't you girls come here to read manga too?
I hate to disappoint you, but...
We came to buy a reference book to help us prepare for exams.
The test must be real soon...
So they rushed over here to buy the book.
They're just trying to apply a thin veneer of respectability.
Dang, they guessed right.
You sure know some difficult words.
More importantly, Eisuke-niichan...
You came back to school?
I heard you were gone for a real long time.
Yeah.
Yep.
He was reinstated today.
You were recuperating from an illness the whole time, weren't you?
Sure was. I bet he was sick over love.
It wasn't love! It was just a regular illness!
Geez...
So this is the Hondou Eisuke I've heard so much about?
Yeah.
He's the high school student who came here to find both his sister and the announcer Mizunashi Rena who looked just like her.
But it turned out that Mizunashi Rena was actually his sister...
A CIA agent who had infiltrated that certain Organization.
Yes...
The ones who shrank my body with their drug...
The Black Organization.
Since he found out about his sister...
It looked like the FBI was going to hide him, but...
The fact that he's strolling around openly like this means...
He refused entry into the witness protection program.
What?
Now that I look more closely, this book is only the first volume.
I'll let you have this since both parts aren't together.
But the second volume is scheduled to come out next month.
I won't wait like that.
It's because I hate being restricted by anything.
Even by time.
Ah, is this it?
This is the reference book the teacher recommended, right?
And it's even super cheap!
You should buy one too, Eisuke-kun.
The questions on the next test might be from it.
It's OK if just you two buy it.
Because I think I probably...
Won't really need it.
I guess so.
You always get good grades, Eisuke-kun.
Suit yourself.
But when you come crying to us before the test, we won't let you look at it!
See you, Conan-kun! Ai-chan!
See you tomorrow.
Don't forget your homework!
You either!
Fifty meters behind us...
In the shadows behind the vending machine in front of the convenience store.
And he's been following...
He started just as we came out of that bookstore.
I don't know who it is yet, but...
I'm sure he's not a member of the Black Organization.
That's true.
They wouldn't be trailing us so conspicuously.
In that case, what I think about this situation is that...
He's an FBI agent who's observing Hondou Eisuke.
Most likely.
If he's both observing and guarding at the same...
Then that distance makes sense, huh?
Well, if we ever want to get back to a normal life, we need to smack down those guys soon.
That gang of crows, I mean.
Oh, right!
Since Eisuke-kun's finally come back, we should do something to celebrate.
Ah, good idea! Let's, let's!
It's OK.
We don't need to celebrate.
What's that?!
You won't let me offer a cup of sake to you?
"Offer a cup of sake"?
Well then, why don't we go check out the new cake store in front of the station?
Ah, I don't really like sweets.
Well then, the hamburger shop in the fourth district should be safe enough.
Let's go, let's go! They're super famous for their spicy chicken.
Ah, but I don't like things that are too spicy either.
You're being annoyingly picky.
In this case, there's only one place left!
A place where everyone can have an exciting party time...
Karaoke, eh?
Heh, Haibara gave this a pass.
Eh? The high-school students who just came in with a child?
Yeah.
Could you let me know when those girls leave?
When I was here earlier, I forgot something in the room those girls are using.
But no one's reported any lost item as of yet.
It seems my friend hid it as a practical joke, so it wouldn't be that easy to spot.
Anyway, I'll go sing in another room while I'm waiting.
So I'll be counting on you.
Conan-kun, that was great.
Just like always, he can't hold a tune in a bucket.
Huh?
Where'd Eisuke-niichan go?
He went to the restroom a bit ago.
Ah, we were just talking about you.
Geez, the next song was the one you picked—
Huh?
What is it?
Excuse me...
Ah, is this room #3? I got the wrong room.
Sorry, everyone.
Ouch...
You all right, bro?
E-Excuse me.
Sorry, I wasn't paying attention...
Be careful.
He's being really slow, that clumsy kid.
Just yourself?
Conning to sing karaoke after going fishing...
That's unusual.
Hey!
He's been to the bathroom twice now!
What's the star of our celebration think he's doing?
Maybe he's not feeling well.
He is just back from being sick.
That's likely it.
Ah, you're back.
Are you OK?
You're face is really pale.
It's nothing.
If you're not feeling well, do you want head home?
T-That's right.
We should hurry and escape...
No, I mean, we should go home!
Yes?
You only have five minutes of time left.
Would you like an extension?
For real?
It's that late already?
Ah, we're leaving.
All right.
Didn't you just look at the time on your cellphone?
Conan-kun...
Make sure you didn't forget anything.
Despite the fact that all! brought was this backpack.
Huh? What is it?
N-No way!
Is this for real?
The police and an ambulance.
Call them immediately!
What's that I heard?
Did something happen?
Hello.
Is this the police?
Did you say the police?
It's no use.
He's no longer breathing.
It's been 30 minutes or so since he died.
Y-Yes...
This is the karaoke box in the third district One of our customers has collapsed.
This room is past the place where the corridor turns.
From the register, this is a blind spot.
And beyond the turn...
Are the men's restroom and a cigarette vending machine.
Come to think of it, that guy...
Went to the restroom.
I knew it, it's that person.
The man who was following us earlier.
If this man is really an FBI agent...
It's because I hate being restricted by anything.
Could it be?
Because I think I probably...
Won't really need it.
Could it be that...
He did it?
According to the license the victim was carrying...
The murder victim is...
Moniwa Tatsumi-san, 46 years of age.
Tome-san?
He was hit over and over on the head with some kind of blunt weapon.
So he was beaten to death.
In that case, what's with that suit?
Most likely the criminal hung that on him to avoid being covered by the blood spurts.
As for any other articles left here...
This item was in the victim's suit.
What's this?
A miniature camera?
Why would he have this?
Since it's a film camera, we'd have to develop it to see.
Chiba-kun!
Go and get the film in this camera developed for me right away.
I got it.
By the way, the person who discovered the body...
You're the one who's in charge of the reception desk at this karaoke box, right?
Ah, that's right.
When the victim arrived...
Was there anybody with him?
He arrived alone, but...
At the time, he asked me for something strange.
Asked you for something strange?
When those high-school students with the child left their room...
He asked me to let him know.
When Ran-san and the others left their room?
Why did he ask that?
He said that when he was in here earlier.
Something like he'd forgotten something in the room the girls were using...
And that he'd search for it after they left.
What was the thing he forgot?
Dunno.
When I came to tell him the girls were leaving, he was like that.
No. He didn't forget something.
When we left the karaoke box...
He was going to start tailing us again.
Just like he was doing before we came here.
And I think the reason he was following us was...
That he was observing as well as guarding a certain person.
If that man was an FBI agent...
And he was doing this as part of his duty...
The most suspicious person...
Would be the person who it appeared that this man was following:
Hondou Eisuke.
He said he hated to be restricted by anything...
And more importantly...
After he returned from going to the restroom here, he was acting strangely.
possible he might just have witnessed some important thing related to Be case.
And then...
After the victim went into his room...
How many customers left the karaoke box?
I don't think anyone did.
There were some customers who came in though.
Those high-school students and the child arrived.
They went into room #3.
Immediately thereafter, the customer who passed away arrived.
He went into room #5.
And after that, if I remember correctly...
That dark-skinned customer and his companion went to room #4.
That long-faced customer went to room #2.
And the elderly customer went into room #1. I think that's the order in which they arrived.
If that's so, that means the culprit has daringly remained here after the crime.
You guys don't mean...
That you're suspecting us?
Ah, well. Please excuse us, but...
Just in case, could you please tell us your names?
Honma Kyouta (32)
Room #2 Customer
Well...
I'm Honma Kyouta.
Arimoto Konji (34)
Room #4 Customer
My name is Arimoto Konji.
Tamai Kunio (63)
Room #1 Customer
Ah, I'm Tamai Kunio.
In short, the arrangement...
Was like this, right?
Ah, w-wait a minute please.
Earlier you said the dark-skinned customer and his companion, didn't you?
Ah, yes.
That customer had someone with him.
Yeah, there is.
Right now, that person is lying down on the sofa in our room.
Hey, hey.
Haven't you woken up yet?
Sorry.
That voice is pretty hoarse, isn't it?
Yeah.
It's been trashed from singing too much while fighting a slight cold.
Well...
Since this person was in our room the whole time...
There's no connection to the incident.
Well, you see, since there's nothing that proves that...
There's proof!
Are you OK, Eisuke-kun?
Your face has turned pale again.
Wait a sec.
You didn't...
Kill him, did you?
I didn't kill anyone!
I just saw something!
Saw something? What?
When I was coming back from the restroom the second time, I got the wrong room.
I went into that dark-skinned person's room and then...
And then?
H-He and that person from before...
THEY WERE KISSING!
I guess that was too stimulating for a kid.
Ah, no. I don't think the issue is that he was a kid...
We're not allowed to smooch in a karaoke box?
No, it'd be no big deal if it were a normal couple, but one can't help being surprised when it's between two men.
Ah, I completely understand!
How rude!
I'm a woman!
Is that so?
We beg your pardon.
Well, she's a bodybuilder, so it's not unreasonable for you to have made a mistake.
Ah, so that's what it was...
But thank goodness.
You were looking so strange.
You had me worried.
It's really good.
Yeah, thank goodness.
This doesn't mean you've been cleared of suspicion yet.
any case...
Would you like to see the video recorded by the security camera at the reception desk?
It won't show the deceased customer's room, but...
You can find out who left the other rooms and when.
People did come out.
The first was Honma-san from room #2.
But we can't see you anymore after you started heading towards the victim's room.
The restroom!
You saw it, didn't you?
The restroom is that way.
Next was Eisuke-kun.
I-I went to the restroom too.
I went just as Honma-san was coming out of the restroom.
That's right That's right.
Ah, he's returning.
Ah, after that it was Arimoto-san from room #4?
Yeah, I went to the restroom too.
Next is Tamai-san from room #1.
Did you go to the restroom too?
I went to buy some cigarettes.
I was annoyed because it didn't have the brand I liked, but since there was nothing I could do, I returned without buying any.
It's true you returned around two minutes later.
Arimoto-san returned then too.
Eisuke-kun hasn't returned yet.
You're right.
Let's fast-forward a bit to check.
Ah, he's returning.
And just like he said...
He made a mistake and went in to the neighboring room #4.
And after Eisuke-kun returned to room #3...
It's showing the clerk.
That's just like I told you earlier, right?
I went to tell the deceased customer that the high-school students were leaving.
However...
Even if it might look like that, but it's still possible that you killed him.
I don't think it is.
Even though I rushed right over there when I heard him yelling...
The blood from the man lying there was mostly all dried.
I see.
It's true.
After the clerk went to the victim's room...
Before even a minute had passed...
Conan-kun came running out of his room.
That means, the suspects are...
Eisuke-kun and you three.
Well, everyone...
Could you please wait in front of your rooms and we'll speak to each of you.
We need to look for something too.
Look for something?
The murder weapon.
Moniwa-san was beaten to death...
And were were unable to find anything that could be used as a blunt weapon in the area.
The suspects are the four people who where photographed by the security camera leaving and returning to their respective rooms.
Tamai-san from room #1.
Honma-san from room #2.
Arimoto-san from room #4.
And...
Eisuke.
The victim, Moniwa-san, was...
Killed by being beaten repeatedly with a some kind of blunt weapon.
However, nothing like that was discovered at the scene of the crime.
Did the culprit carry it away?
Moniwa-san was definitely shadowing us.
If I assume he's an FBI agent that's observing and guarding Eisuke...
Eisuke might have been mad about that...
Was he really an FBI agent in the first place?
Who the heck was it?
The one who killed Moniwa-san...
W-Wait, what's this!?
There all of us! Eww!
It's not here...
The murder weapon.
It's somewhere in this karaoke box.
It absolutely must be!
Isn't the culprit...
That boy with the round glasses?
It's here, the murder weapon.
Sonoko, it happened! Just like always!
BLIND SPOT IN THE KARAOKE BOX
(PART TWO)
Next Conan's Hint
The Suspects' Shoes
That hint sounds like it's Cinderella.
It's not Cinderella.
True enough.