Waiting gets us nowhere.
Take a step forward into the future.
It's a deduction and love countdown!
Standing in for Kogorou is the high-school detective girl, Sonoko!
Let's resolve the mystery of the vanished murder weapon!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
In the Mizunashi Rena case...
Hondou Eisuke had been protected by the FBI, but he's returned.
When we went to a karaoke box to celebrate his return...
We were shadowed by a suspicious man.
Could he be an FBI agent observing and guarding Eisuke?
However, that man was murdered in a room at the karaoke box.
The culprit is one of the customers who came to sing karaoke.
Could it be Eisuke?
Well then, first of all...
We'll start with Tamai Kunio-san from room #1.
Y-Yes.
Tamai Kunio (63)
Room #1 Customer
I came here today on the way back from fishing.
Oh? You came to sing, karaoke alone after fishing?
Is that bad?
You sure caught a lot.
To tell the truth, those are mostly fish I bought at the supermarket.
I carelessly let my fishing rod drift away...
But I'd promised my family that I'd bring back a lot.
So I had no choice but to buy the fish.
True enough, there's no rod inside this case.
Since they'd be suspicious if I came home too early...
I was just wasting time here.
Next is Honma Kyouta-san from room #2.
OK.
Honma Kyouta (32)
Room #2 Customer
As for me, my company is having a karaoke
tournament soon, so I came here to practice.
Is your company in this area?
No.
I'd be embarrassed if my co-workers knew about this, so...
I deliberately came here where it was far away.
You buy cigarettes by the carton?
Yeah, it's because I'm a heavy smoker.
Please excuse me.
Well, I suppose you can't use cigarettes to bludgeon someone.
Oh, so you came to sing karaoke on the way home from school?
Hondou Eisuke (17)
Room #3 Customer
Yes.
Young people these days...
Oh, maracas!
I like these a lot myself.
I guess it couldn't have been maracas either.
Aromoto Konji (34)
Room #4 Customer
Next we have Arimoto Konji-san from room #4.
I came to sing karaoke with my girlfriend
on the way back from the gym.
That's not a problem, is it?
Huh?
Isn't this that carbonated beverage that came out a bit ago?
Yeah, she wanted to try it, so I bought some.
It tasted awful, so she only had one sip.
It would have been impossible with a PET bottle also.
We've checked out everyone's rooms, but...
It's not here...
The murder weapon.
Yeah.
I checked the restrooms too...
That shouldn't be.
It absolutely must be somewhere in this karaoke box...
Some weapon, like a bludgeon.
Besides, I need to check if the
murdered man was an FBI agent or not.
Why would Jodie-sensei's phone not be connecting?
Inspector!
They've just finished developing the film that the victim had.
It shows something we didn't expect.
Something we didn't expect?
W-Wait, what's this!?
There all of us! Eww!
You mean he was a stalker?
It sure looks that way. Icky!
So it looks like it doesn't have anything to do with us.
You're right.
I didn't even see the victim.
Then, you all didn't even pass by the victim in the corridor?
Yeah.
If we had met, it would have been either
in the corridor or in the restroom.
But I didn't see anyone except for these people here.
I didn't see any of the other customers until the incident occurred.
Well, if you consider it normally...
Isn't the culprit that boy with the round glasses?
That's right.
He was being followed by the stalker and
lost control and killed him or something.
N-No way!
Hold on, look carefully.
Don't each of these pictures have me in the center?
That means I was the target, not this geeky glasses boy!
Geez.
Can't you let us go home already, Mr. Detective?
That's right, Mr. Detective.
It's true that Sonoko is the focus of every picture...
Then, perhaps the murdered man wasn't with the FBI?
Wait a second!
If I remember correctly, just now...
It's already 7:30!
No, I can't let you leave yet.
I don't mind hanging around here until I'm cleared of suspicion.
Please do that, definitely.
I just happened to bring some cards with me.
I can kill time playing poker or blackjack with my girlfriend.
Blackjack!
I had forgotten about that!
In any case...
Based on the presumed time of death of Moniwa Tatsumi-san,
who was beaten to death in room #5 of this karaoke box...
The crime was committed in an approximate thirty minute
window, likely between 6:00 and 6:20 this evening.
According to the recording made by the security camera, the people
who passed by the victim's room in those 30 minutes were:
Honma Kyouta-san who came out of room #2 at 5:50.
Hondou Eisuke-kun, who came out of room #3 at 6:03.
Arimoto Konji-san, who came out of room #4 at 6:05.
And Tamai Kunio-san, who came out of
room #1 at 6:07, making 4 people in total.
The culprit is definitely one of you four.
And that's why I can't let you leave yet.
But, the murder weapon hasn't been found anywhere, right?
I think you said it was some kind of blunt weapon, didn't you?
I'm pretty sure that if you can't find it, you might
be overstepping by making us remain here.
It's here, the murder weapon.
Although it's something that wouldn't appear to be a weapon at all.
Sonoko, it happened! Just like always!
Ah, no. That wasn't me...
Wasn't you?
Yeah.
For a case this simple, I thought it wasn't me who would solve it.
But if you all really don't understand, then I'll explain it to you.
The trick that, after the crime, changed the shape
of the murder weapon and made it vanish...
And the culprit who used it.
Yes, if it's OK with you, could you please tell us about it, young lady?
Ah, wait a minute!
You 're saying there was a blunt weapon at the time of the crime...
But now it's disappeared, right?
Yeah.
Then I know what it was.
The murderer weapon was probably...
A gigantic block of ice!
And so the culprit is the one who had a cooler that
could preserve it for a long period of time...
Tamai Kunio san!
It was you!
Bzzz. Wrong.
It's true that if ice was used, it could be melted
after the crime and would disappear, but...
If it was used to strike with, there should be pieces of ice, scattered
water droplets, and a water stain left behind at the crime scene.
But there weren't any stains like that.
And since we can still see the splattered blood from the corpse,
there's no evidence that the culprit wiped the floor after the crime.
Instead, the culprit placed something
hard inside a certain thing to strike with.
That was so it wouldn't splatter.
That's it, the PET bottle!
If they struck when the contents had been
frozen solid, then the liquid wouldn't splatter!
In other words, the culprit is the one who had a
carbonated drink in a PET bottle, Arimoto-san!
That means it was you!
Bzz. Bzz. Wrong.
Arimoto-san came out of his room after 6:00.
And you, Inspector, and the other detectives
examined the PET bottle before 7:30.
With the air-conditioning in there, an hour
and a half wouldn't be enough time...
For the ice in a 500ml container to completely dissolve.
So then what was it? That hard thing?
Ah, I think even you have some of them with you, Inspector.
What?
Yes, it's something that everyone has with them.
It was a coin. Coins.
And they were probably ten yen coins.
T-Ten yen coins?
Young lady, how would you be able to strike someone a ten yen coin?
You're right: with a single ten yen coin, the best
you could do would be to bruise someone.
But if you had something like 300 of them?
That would become a mass of copper
weighing approximately 1.5 kilograms.
W-Well, that's certainly true, but...
No one had such a large amount of change with them.
They disposed of them after the crime.
Disposed of them?
They put them in that machine behind you, Inspector.
T-That's it!
The cigarette vending machine!
So, they put 300 ten yen coins in a PET bottle and
used it as a bludgeon to beat the victim to death!
And after the crime, they used the ten yen coins in the
vending machine and that's how they vanished.
Bzz. Bzz. Bzz.
The mouth of a PET soda bottle is too small to fit ten yen coins in.
And if you struck someone with something like that in it, both
the interior and exterior of the PET bottle would be scratched.
You'd know right away if you look at it.
Then what the heck did they put them in?
Yes, it was something just like ten yen coins that everyone uses...
And furthermore, when you stuff a large
number of ten yen coins inside them...
They become a weapon that is commonly called a "blackjack."
Socks!
Socks?
Isn't that right?
Honma Kyouta-san?
Why would it be him?
Both Tamai-san and Eisuke-kun are wearing socks.
Honma-san's shoes are kind of stretched tightly, aren't they?
Excuse me.
It's true.
When he mistakenly came into our room...
He bumped into Arimoto-san and fell down.
At that time, rather than being stretched
tight, his shoes were almost falling off.
Now he's wearing the second pair he used as the murder weapon.
That was probably done to hide the sock he used at the
time of the crime that has the victims blood on it.
Come to think of it, Honma-san had that carton of cigarettes.
If he had the box for the carton with him beforehand...
Then the pile of cigarettes he got when he disposed
of the ten yen coins in the vending machine...
Could have been placed in the box in order to deceive us.
If you check the pile of ten yen coins in the cigarette
vending machine, you will have your conclusive evidence.
If any blood got on the sock, then some
should be on the ten yen coins inside.
I'm sure they will have his fingerprints on them as well.
For a culprit wanting to leave the scene
and use up the ten yen coins quickly...
I don't think he'd be wearing gloves or anything.
Then when you told us you hadn't seen
the culprit, that was a lie, wasn't it?
It's not that you just saw him, you knew him well, didn't you?
What?
The victim's name was Tatsumi. If you just hear that,
you can't really tell if it was a man or a woman.
However...
Honma-san said that if he had met the victim, it would
have been either in the corridor or in the restroom.
I wonder if you would say that if you
didn't know the victim was a man.
You couldn't have met a woman inside the
separated men's and woman's restrooms.
Yeah...
I knew him.
How could I forget?
That man's face!
That kidnapper's face!
Kidnapper?
Exactly.
That man kidnapped my son.
And when he learned that I'd reported it to the police...
He killed him.
My son, who was only four years old, and that, in retaliation...
Papa!
No way...
Mr. Detective, do you remember a kidnapping
case a year ago from Okuho city?
I think I heard that they'd arrested a suspect
but couldn't prosecute for lack of evidence.
Yeah, they never found the murder weapon.
It seems that man used the same trick that I did.
Therefore, you kept watching him, looking to
meet in a place where you could use that trick.
In other words, a place with a cigarette vending machine and private
rooms, like this karaoke box, so you could exact your revenge.
Yeah.
Well, you should be grateful to me.
From those pictures that man was taking, it
looks like you would have been the next victim.
But then, with someone as perceptive as you,
you probably wouldn't have been kidnapped.
And your parents wouldn't have had
to do something as stupid as this.
That turned into a lousy celebration for your return, didn't it?
Still, I was really impressed.
By Sonoko-san's deduction show.
It was just like Sleeping Kogorou-san's.
Your great deductions put even Shinichi to shame.
You think so?
Yet I don't remember a thing.
Shinichi?
You mean that high-school detective, Kudou Shinichi?
Yep, he's Ran's long distance husband!
Sonoko!
You got married as high-school students?
Of course I haven't! Not with a guy like him!
He's been away for a long time, wrapped up in some case.
It's just like a lengthy separation.
No, we're actually living together...
There's another book I want to buy, so you head home before me.
Now?
It's fine.
I'll go with him and make sure he gets back to the detective office.
And?
What is it?
The reason you're deliberately coming with me.
There's something you want to discuss with me, isn't there?
Yeah.
I've been thinking about it and...
I've decided to go to America.
So you're going to enter the witness protection program?
No, as you figured, I turned that down.
Just like I said before...
I hate being restricted by anything.
And, luckily, it looks like I have yet to draw the attention of
the people from that evil organization you told me about.
Then, why are you going to America?
Just like my father and sister, I want to join the CIA!
I'll dig up and expose bad people and
their evil deeds out of every nook and cranny.
And someday, my sister and I will bring down that evil Organization!
First of all you better fix that "clumsy kid"
problem or you won't get into the CIA.
I guess you're right.
Moreover, the CIA is an organization that acts
on behalf of American national interests.
Does this guy understand that?
But, you know...
If you're going, why did you come back to school?
Even if was just for a short time, I wanted to
see my close friends before I went and...
Confess my love to Ran-san.
I fell in love with her from the first time I met her.
I'd never met someone as pretty and kind as her.
But, it seems that's she's in love with Shinichi-san.
I don't know what Shinichi-san thinks about her, but...
Oh, right!
Do you know how to contact Shinichi-san?
Then, could you ask him for me?
If it would be all right to confess my love for Ran-san.
Unlike Shinichi-san, I'll never keep Ran-san waiting.
My plan is to bring her with me to America
someday so we can both live happily together.
You can't.
No, I wasn't asking for your opinion.
I wanted you to ask Shinichi-san...
And I'm saying you can't!
Then...
You aren't saying you're...
Yeah.
That's what I'm saying.
That solves that mystery!
The reason I went to see Detective Mouri in the first place was...
Because I heard he'd met with Mizunashi
Rena just before she disappeared.
At that time, I didn't know she was my sister and a CIA agent.
I thought for sure that Detective Mouri was one of
the bad guys and was sheltering her somewhere.
That's why I was looking into Detective Mouri on my own.
And then, I figured something out.
His deduction power before and after he started
"Sleeping Kogorou" was completely different.
And at Sleeping Kogorou's side, there was always you.
Though I couldn't think how you could have gotten smaller...
As I thought, you really are Kudou Shinichi, aren't you?
As you thought?
You talk like you already knew.
Yeah, I'd guessed it.
Around the time Sleeping Kogorou first appeared,
you had taken an absence from school...
And there was one time that I fell down
not from clumsiness, but on purpose.
You remember, it was the first time we met.
It's great to meet you, Detective Mouri.
It's such an honor.
Then, you did that just to grab on to me?
Yeah, but I really did fall in love with Ran-san.
Please make her happy for my sake.
Oh, that's right.
Did you hear?
Something seems to have happened with the FBI.
Something happened?
Yeah...
Based on their mood, it seems that someone might have died.
But, if they haven't told you about it...
I'm sure it's all right.
Yeah.
It's all right.
So there are zero requests today as well, huh?
Who would be calling me at this time?
Codename...
Bourbon.
It's got to be one of those three who set the fire, doesn't it?
They're here...
Somewhere nearby...
A member of the Organization!
Next Conan's Hint
DIARY
Look forward to the next episode
Next time it's red, white and yellow.
What's that about?
An athletic meet.
A bean-paste bun!