Waiting gets us nowhere.
Take a step forward into the future.
It's a deduction and love countdown!
The words "red, white and yellow" written in a diary...
Are an important hint to solving the riddle of a case.
Perceiving the one and only truth...
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Bye-bye!
What? There's nothing in here.
So there are zero requests today as well, huh?
How boring!
Well...
That means it's good that things are peaceful, doesn't it?
Exactly.
Who would be calling me at this time?
That's weird though.
It's the same as always.
Hello.
Hi, Cool Kid.
Your classes just got finished, right?
Jodie-sensei!
What's up?
I called your cellphone several times but it wouldn't connect.
Yeah.
After that "Shiranpuri" case, my cellphone broke
down for good and I had to buy a replacement.
With all that's happened, I decided to
start anew and got a new number also.
Of course, as appropriate, I informed that girl who's
infiltrating the Organization about the new number.
That girl?
Mizunashi Rena-san?
Yeah.
And then I got a call from her.
It seems they were off guard for a bit, so it was a fairly short call, but...
She was able to tell me this quite clearly.
The Organization has activated a new member.
An agent who is frighteningly skilled at intelligence
gathering as well as observation and discernment.
Codename:
Bourbon!
Be careful!
That's all she could tell me in our short conversation.
Judging from her harsh tone, that agent is pretty sharp.
And most likely their target is...
That girl with the brown-dyed hair,
known to the Organization as Sherry.
Let's wait and see.
I expect so.
As far as the FBI is concerned, we'd like to assign a bodyguard to her.
But, if we do that now, we would be in danger of
letting them know her whereabouts instead.
In the short term, it seems it'd be better to
avoid that risk and put our trust in you.
So, be vigilant and protect her closely for us.
Well, if anything happens, be sure and contact us.
Codename...
Bourbon.
By the way, what should we do now?
Yeah, with this rain...
In that case...
How about a game at the Professor's house?
Yeah, let's go, let's go!
So?
I wonder what you're going to discuss
with the Professor when you see him.
Mr. Great Detective.
That phone call just now.
That was from Jodie-sensei and the FBI, wasn't it?
Ah, no...
It's all right.
It was nothing for you to worry about.
"For me?"
You're hiding something again.
Ah, I mean it's not like another case occurred or anything.
It's a case!
A case between Conan-kun and Ai-chan?!
No, behind them!
I see.
So, to summarize your story, first year
student from class A, Sugiura Kaito-kun...
Your father is the landlord of a small apartment building.
That apartment building has three residents.
And one of those three has been behaving suspiciously.
And you want us Detective Boys
to find out what he's been doing, right?
Yeah.
Well then, let's stay over at this guy's place
tonight and we can all keep watch on that guy.
Yeah, that sounds good. Tomorrow is Saturday, so there's no school.
That's right!
Ah, today is no good.
Because tonight's...
The night I play Othello with my dad.
So that's why earlier you put your request in the shoe
box after we had all left for home, wasn't it?
So you wouldn't miss your chance to play with your father today.
Ah, yeah.
But, in that case, we wouldn't have gotten
your letter until next week Monday.
Ah, that's right.
And so? What kind of suspicious things is that person doing at night?
As for that, come over and stay at my house tomorrow.
It would be better if you could see for yourself, Kuroshi—
Edogawa-kun.
Oh, yeah! If it's all right, why don't you come during the day?
I want to show you my room and the inside of the apartment building.
Well, shall we all go at noon tomorrow?
Yeah!
My house is in the apartment building called
"Mokubasou" at Beika City, 2nd district, number 23.
I'll see you tomorrow, Kuroshi—
Oh...
Edogawa-kun.
Later!
How come it's just Conan?
And what's that "Kuroshi" thing about?
Maybe he was just trying to say "yoroshiku" (thanks).
"Mokubasou" at Beika City, 2nd district, number 23...
Huh? Do you recognize it? That apartment building?
Ah, no.
I think it's somewhere near the Professor's house though.
Yeah.
I pass in front of that apartment building a lot on my way home.
It's old and small, but it's a nice agreeable building.
Beika City...
2nd district...
Number 23...
"Mokubasou."
This is it, isn't it?
Is this for real?
It's been completely burned down!
No way!
Come to think of it, I did hear the sounds of sirens during the night.
But what about that boy?
What happened to Kaito-kun?!
Maybe he was caught in the fire and...
It can't be!
No, that boy Kaito is safe.
He got a few burns, but he was rescued by one of the firemen.
Inspector Yuminaga
Police HQ Division One Investigations
Chief Arson Investigator
He's asleep at the hospital now.
Is that true?!
Thank goodness!
Inspector Yuminaga!
Oh! You're the boy from Mouri's place!
I haven't seen you since that "Red Horse" case.
Exactly.
That happened a while ago when Hattori Heiji had come to Tokyo.
The person in charge of that murder/arson
case was this guy, Inspector Yuminaga.
So, did anyone die in this fire?
Happily, there were no fatalities.
But Kaito-kun's father was badly burned and is in the ICU now.
Then the rest of that boy's family and the other residents of this
apartment building were all able to get away during the fire?
The boy's mother happened to be away on a trip.
When I called her at her hotel earlier, she was
astonished and said she was coming back immediately.
As for the three other residents, all three of them
happened to be out at around the time of the fire.
It seems they didn't come back until morning.
They were out?
Didn't the fire happen in the middle of the night?
Yeah.
Around 2:30 in the morning.
Well, the three of them aren't kids, so there's nothing suspicious
about them going out in the evening and staying out all night.
It's got to be one of those three who set the fire, doesn't it?
What?
Yesterday Kaito-kun told us that one of those three
people was doing suspicious things at night!
But when we came here to investigate,
we found that this had happened!
I see.
Inspector Yuminaga.
We found this in the remains of the fire.
What's this?
It's...
This must be Kaito-kun's diary.
Let's see. The last page says July 4th. That's yesterday.
"The weather has been bad since this morning. I have to get up
early or I'll miss school, but I bet the red guy can sleep in late."
What does this "red guy" mean?
"When I got back from school, I fell down in the entryway."
"I'm glad the white guy was just coming out."
"Tonight the red guy and the white guy
and the yellow guy are all going out."
"My dad and I are alone together. I want to play some more but the
detective club is coming tomorrow, so I should go to bed early."
"Who is it? Someone came home in the middle of the night."
"He's arguing with my father."
"It's the yellow guy."
"I wonder if my dad found out about the suspicious things he's doing."
"It's scary, so I'll cover my ears and go to bed. When
I wake up I'll have to tell Edogawa-kun about this."
Well, it's obvious that the yellow guy set the fire.
Inspector Yuminaga.
What kind of people are those three residents?
Yeah.
Say, sorry about this, but could you
bring those three over here for me?
Yes, sir.
This feeling...
A glare that impales its prey...
A pressure that's eating into my guts...
What's wrong?
They're here...
Somewhere nearby...
A member of the Organization!
They're here...
There's no doubt.
A member of the Organization...
How?
How could they be here?
No.
There's no time to think.
I've got to escape!
I've got to get away from here quickly!
Or else everyone will...
It went away.
Hey, are you OK?
Yeah.
Are you feeling sick?
Are you all right?
Well, would you mind answering a
few more questions from my officers?
This way, please.
And so?
Which one of those three was the suspicious person?
We don't know!
We came to see Kaito-kun to ask him that.
What? Couldn't you have mentioned that earlier?
Say...
What do those three people do?
Yeah.
From the right:
Hosoi Ryuuhei (25)
Carpenter
The one with the band-aid is a carpenter, Hosoi Ryuuhei-san.
The one with the glasses is a graduate student, Okiya Subaru-san.
Okiya Subaru (27)
Graduate Student
And the heavy one is a part-time worker, Makabe Ginya-san.
Makabe Ginya (29)
Part-Timer
I suppose one of those three is the yellow guy.
Inspector, what's that? The "yellow guy"?
Yeah.
Read this for a bit.
It's a diary that the landlord's son wrote.
According to that, for some reason, on the
day before the fire it seems Kaito-kun...
Asked these kids to investigate one of the
residents who was behaving questionably.
We're not just kids!
We're the highly-respected...
Detective Boys!
Oh yeah, he referred to them that way in his diary.
I'm inclined to think he's using colors to stand
for the residents of this apartment building.
According to what's written here, it seems certain that whichever
resident is the "yellow guy" is the culprit, doesn't it?
Yeah, however, we don't know which of them is the "yellow guy".
None of the three have a color in their names.
Nobody is wearing yellow clothing either.
Their jobs are carpenter, student, and temp.
Nothing there that's associated with a color.
Red, white, and yellow?
That's like the colors of flowers.
There's a black guy though.
A black person?
Look, that dark-skinned man.
Ah, if it's the color of their skin, then that
guy with the glasses is white, right?
In any case...
Let's ask them a bit more detailed
questions and see what we find out.
Such as who is the certain "yellow" person in question.
Geez.
How many times do I have to say the same thing?
On the night of the fire...
I was out drinking with my boss and my
superiors from the carpentry trade.
But earlier when we were confirming that, it seems
you left sometime after 1 o'clock in the morning.
Yeah.
I haven't been drinking in a long time, so I got really drunk.
To try to sober up, I went off by myself and
laid down on a bench and fell asleep.
And so, when I came to, it was already morning.
Then at the time of the fire, around 2:30 in the morning...
That means there was nobody with you.
Ah, yeah.
Say, why do you have that?
That band-aid on your face. Did you get in a fight?
What's with this kid?
It's OK, just answer.
I got hit by a board while I was working.
I'm still a beginner, so I keep getting injured.
Look.
These are all from work.
By the way, what's your favorite color?
Color?
The blue of the ocean.
It's cause I like to go surfing occasionally.
No.
I was driving by myself that night.
I do that frequently whenever I start going crazy
trying to prepare my thesis for my professor.
Whereabouts did you go driving?
I drove down that tree-lined street by the Teimuzu River.
When I'm looking at the greenery, my heart
feels at ease, so I end up along there.
I water the plants in the garden at
this apartment building every day too.
That's because the landlord doesn't seem
very interested in maintaining the garden.
Oh, then your favorite color is green or something then?
No.
If you force me to pick one...
It'd be black.
It covers up the things inside of me
that I don't want to be know about.
Well, for the same reason...
Black is the color I hate too.
Last night I went to see a movie in Haido City.
It was an all-night showing from
10PM at night until 5AM in the morning.
It was a triple feature from the "Monster Gomera" series.
Were you alone?
Yeah.
My net friend was supposed to go with
me, but he suddenly couldn't come.
What's a "net friend"?
Ah, as a side-line, I work as a day trader.
I have some friends who exchange information
with me about that on the internet.
A day trader? So you deal with stocks and such?
Well, it's just sort of a hobby, so I only make
a ridiculously small amount of profit from it.
Your only a part-time worker, but you earn enough
to cover your living expenses from that?
Yeah.
Because I'm registered with a temp agency for daily work.
Say, about that.
Do you do public construction work?
See, there's a lot of mud under your finger nails.
No, that's...
That's mud from the time I played a survival game a while ago.
It's because I was running around in the mountains.
But since they got covered in that bright color
from paint gun shells, I ruined my clothes.
Then your favorite color is the color that camouflage
clothing is usually made from, navy...
Yeah.
It's navy green.
Hey, Mr. Detective.
Do our favorite colors have something to do with the fire?
No.
Well, you never know.
Hey, Tsuburaya-kun.
Could you help me with a little something?
Ah, sure.
Stay like that and walk backwards.
That's all I need.
Walk backwards?
Is there something behind me?
Don't look back.
You need to keep looking at me.
Can you do it?
Y-Yes.
They're here.
It's definitely one of them.
The one I sensed that pressure from earlier.
A member of the Organization.
I have to figure out who it is right away.
I have to do something.
Or else these kids will get mixed up in it!
Haibara-san, this hurts.
I'm sorry!
Are you all right?
Ah, sure.
It's cool.
I only scraped a little skin off my elbow.
Here.
Use this.
This band-aid.
Thank you.
You don't mind?
Don't worry about it.
My boss told me that since I keep getting
injured I should always carry some.
If we assume it doesn't mean their favorite color,
what does it mean? This "yellow guy".
Excuse me, Inspector.
Isn't it dangerous to keep on concentrating on a kid's diary like this?
It might possibly just be an imaginary person.
That's not true!
He told us!
There was a guy who was doing suspicious things at night.
I really don't think it sounded like he made it up!
Exactly.
Moreover, whenever you police...
Have a child who's done something bad...
Don't you start by asking the adults around him...
If they know what kind of child he is?
In that case...
Isn't the converse true also?
Even if he's a child, Kaito-kun has observed the residents
closely, even going so far as to give them nicknames.
The Adventure of the Copper Beeches, isn't it?
During the case of the Adventure of the Copper Beeches...
It was one of the lines that Holmes said to Dr. Watson.
"My dear Watson, you as a medical man are continually gaining
light as to the tendencies of a child by the study of the parents."
"Don't you see that the converse is equally valid."
Was that it?
You like Holmes too?
Yeah.
I used to have all of it.
But they've all burned up now, eh?
Well, speaking of Holmes...
He wouldn't have ignored this diary.
Hey!
Could I look at that diary?
Sure, take a look.
Thanks!
Inspector!
Yeah?
Have you found something else?
Yes.
They were in the area near Kaito-kun's room.
A pile of mini-cars.
Mini-cars?
It's not strange for there to be some miniature cars in a child's room.
But, there were quite a number.
Easily more than 100 of them.
Huh?
What's this?
Where? Where?
What's up?
Look. Here.
The characters for "Edogawa" have been erased and
rewritten several times. The paper's even gotten a bit dark.
Could he have been trying to write it in kanji?
No, you can faintly see what looks like katakana underneath.
Could it be "Kuroshi"?
Kuroshi?
Kuroshiro-kun?
Earlier when I called the hospital...
Kaito-kun's mother said something.
"The really smart boy who solved a case that happened at
school instantly is coming over to our house tomorrow."
Kaito-kun seemed really happy when he told her that over the phone.
He said he was called Kuroshiro-kun.
Then when Kaito-kun said "Kuroshi" yesterday...
He was talking about Conan-kun, right?
But why would he call him "Kuroshiro"?
Dunno.
I guess we'll have to wait until Kaito-kun gets better...
And ask him in person.
No.
That won't be necessary.
Shall I be Kuroshiro-kun...
And make plain what's black and white right here?
I'll tell you which one among them is...
The yellow arsonist.
The three of you said...
You'd gone out the night of the fire...
And returned home in the morning, didn't you?
If that's so, then somebody must be lying!
Which of these three people is the yellow arsonist?
I already know who.
Wh-What did you say?
Uh-oh! Over there now is...
Shin'ichi?
Shin'ichi came home?
Next Conan's Hint
Mini-car
Look forward to the next episode
A dish made from the skin of pigs' ears?
[mimi no kawa (ear skin) is a pun on mini-car]
That's mimigaa.
[Okinawa cuisine]
Is that for your father?