Waiting gets us nowhere.
Take a step forward into the future.
It's a deduction and love countdown!
Today's episode is in two parts.
That's twice the reasoning as usual!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
A child with the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
A new member of the Black Organization has been activated.
Codename: Bourbon.
Is Haibara their target?
According to Sugiura Kaito-kun, a resident of his apartment building
was behaving strangely night after night and he wanted it investigated.
So he commissioned us Detective Boys, however...
The apartment building had been completely burned down in a fire.
In his diary, which escaped unburnt, Kaito-kun had assigned the
nicknames "red guy, white guy and yellow guy" to the three residents.
He wrote that the one behaving suspiciously was the yellow guy.
And it seems the one who set fire to the
apartment building was also the yellow guy.
Shall I be Kuroshiro-kun...
And make plain what's black and white right here?
I'll tell you which one among them is...
The yellow arsonist.
What does that mean, "the yellow arsonist"?
I thought I heard something like a diary or something.
Ah, well...
It's the diary belonging to Kaito-kun, the son of the landlord
of the apartment building here that caught on fire.
It was written right there in that diary.
That the yellow guy suddenly came
back home in the middle of the night.
And had a quarrel with Kaito-kun's father.
Hosoi Ryuuhei (25)
Carpenter
The three of you said...
That you'd gone out on the night of the fire...
Okiya Subaru (27)
Graduate Student
And returned home in the morning, didn't you?
Makabe Ginya (29)
Part-Timer
If that's so, then somebody must be lying!
The one who's lying is the yellow guy, and he's the
criminal who set fire to the apartment building.
It's true that I do know the landlord's son.
Was that boy calling somebody things like "yellow guy"?
I don't know.
Well now, it's just something a child said, so don't worry about it.
It's a bad idea to be talking about the "yellow guy".
Huh? Why?
If they know that he's the arsonist, won't all three
of them insist they aren't the "yellow guy"?
Ah, I see.
That's right.
No, it's OK.
Huh?
Which of these three people is the
yellow arsonist? I already know who.
Wh-What did you say?
Hey, kid. Is that true?
Yeah.
Ayumi-chan, let me borrow the diary for a sec.
OK.
Kaito-kun's diary also mentions a "red guy" and a "white guy".
I've figured out who the "red guy" and the "white guy" are,
so that's how I figured out who the "yellow guy" is.
T-There's a "red guy" and a "white guy" too?
Yeah.
This is what's written in the diary.
"The weather has been bad since this morning"
"I have to get up early or I'll miss school,
but I bet the red guy can sleep in late."
That must mean the red guy does something every morning...
But since it was raining that day, it wasn't
necessary to do that something.
What do you think it could have been?
Maybe taking out the laundry to dry?
A sports day festival would be postponed in the rain.
Adults don't have sports days.
Watering.
Watering the flowers.
Ah, that's right!
Yeah.
So the "red guy" is the one who gives the plants
at the apartment building water every day.
Therefore it's Okiya-san.
But, kid, why is this young fellow called "red guy"?
Remember, didn't you find a lot of mini-cars in Kaito-kun's room?
Kaito-kun definitely loves cars.
If you think about cars and "red", what's
the first thing that comes to your mind?
Ah! A fire engine!
I see, Kaito-kun watched this young fellow sprinkling
water from a hose, like a human fire engine.
That's why he gave him the nickname "red guy".
If that's the case, then "white guy" also
refers to the color of a car, doesn't it?
But there are a whole bunch of white cars.
An ambulance.
In Japan, under the Road Trucking Vehicle Law,
the body of the vehicle is required to be white.
That's it!
But, who could that be?
The "ambulance"
What does an ambulance do for you?
It transports injured people.
They give you medical care inside the vehicle.
Ah, that's it!
Band-aids!
The white guy is the one who gets injured a
lot and therefore always carries band-aids.
That must be Hosoi-san, right?
Oh yeah, the diary also says, "When I got back from school, I fell down
in the entryway. I'm glad the white guy was just coming out."
Yeah, his knee was bleeding.
I gave the boy one of the band-aids I was carrying.
That sort of thing has happened several times earlier, but...
A dark-skinned guy like me is the "white guy", eh?
Then we're left with the yellow guy.
Taxis are yellow.
But there are white and green ones too.
What about construction vehicles...
Exactly. In short, it's the person who has dirt under his fingernails.
Makabe-san, that means you're the yellow guy.
Wh-What are you saying?
This dirt under my fingernails is from running around
in the mountains playing a survival game.
If I remember, you said you clothes were ruined
because they got stained by paint from a paint gun.
Uh, yeah.
In japan, what they use for a survival game is...
Are air soft guns that shoot BBs.
Paint guns are used in a different game called "paint ball".
Oh?
Th-Those are mostly the same thing, aren't they?
But paint guns use a water-soluble ink
that comes out clean when you wash it.
Oh-oh!
Ah, well...
Moreover, Makabe-san, you said your favorite color
was the "navy green" used in camouflage clothing.
But I think what's usually used in camouflage
clothes is a green called "olive drab".
Have you really played that whatever-it-was ball?
T-The thing is. I'm still just a beginner.
Well, shouldn't we just check around where
the garden was in the apartment building?
According to what Kaito-kun wrote, the yellow guy
was doing something suspicious night after night.
And if we add in that Makabe-san is deceiving us
by telling lies about the dirt in his fingernails...
We might conclude that Makabe-san was digging
in the garden at night to avoid being seen.
He must have been burying something. Something
important he didn't want anyone else to see.
And most likely that was...
Money you earned as a day trader, correct?
What about it?
Two attache cases...
With money I earned as a day trader.
There's roughly two hundred million yen.
That much?!
Why would you bury it in the garden?
So I wouldn't have to pay the taxes.
But last night, when I got back from the movies...
The landlord questioned me insistently.
I got irritated and try to push him away,
but the landlord fell down the stairs.
He wasn't moving anymore, and I got real scared.
And then I figured, if I burned it all, just about
everything would just be reset, and...
"Reset"?!
Don't you get it?! What you did was completely different
from turning off the power because you lose a game!
You turned the decades of memories created in this
apartment building into ash in a single night.
You're not allowed to just reset this.
Your game of life isn't over yet!
You better be prepared to make up for this in full.
Including to Kaito-kun and his father who you got mixed up in this.
Inspector! I just got word from the hospital.
They said the landlord's operation was successful,
and that Kaito-kun has regained consciousness.
Oh, is that so?
Thank goodness!
Well, now you can rebuild this apartment building with
the pile of cash you saved from that money game.
Yes, sir.
Well, let's go.
But there's still one mystery remaining.
Yeah, why is Conan's nickname "Kuroshiro-kun"?
What kind of car is black and white?
I bet that's the car we police use, a patrol car.
Since that's the most suitable nickname for
the boy who puts the police to shame.
See you again, boy.
Yeah.
Well, how about we all go now to visit Kaito-kun?
Agreed!
Since it far away, we should have the professor drive us in his car.
Professor?
You guys know a professor?
Yeah, we do.
But he's always coming up with stupid games.
Oh, I'd like to meet that professor.
That's fine, I'll introduce you.
I'd appreciate it.
Oh, so you're an engineering graduate student.
So someday you'll earn your doctorate
and become my professional rival, eh?
No, nothing like that...
But, what a big house you have.
It's just the two of you here, you and the child?
Yeah?
Well, it doesn't seem there would be any problem adding another.
Eh?
The thing is, the apartment building where I was living burned down.
If it's all right, could you let me stay
here until I find another place to live?
Of course, when I have free time, I'll do
anything to help you with your research.
Ah, well, I don't mind. As long as it's OK with this kid.
Say, how about using Shinichi-niichan's house?
Shinichi-niichan's house?
Yeah, there's nobody living there right now.
Look, it's that house next door.
He's left the keys with me.
Oh, what a splendid western-style house. It's OK?
Yeah.
Hold on.
What are you thinking?
You're renting your house to a person
whose background we don't know well.
What will you do if he finds out your secret?
It's all right.
There's no way a Holmes fan could be a bad person!
Huh?
Here, these are the keys to the house.
Are you sure this is OK? That "Shinichi-niichan" won't mind?
Yeah, I'll e-mail him later.
Thank you. You've really helped me.
In exchange, guard the house while he's away.
Yeah, of course.
Geez...
An arson, a kidnapping, and a hit-and-run.
How come so many different cases happen every day like this.
Such a carefree person.
Huh?
That man who's living for free at your house.
Are you sure it's OK have such simple faith in him?
Oh, you mean Okiya Subaru-san?
It's all right!
I sure hope so.
It's cool, it's cool.
Ah, Conan-kun!
Huh?
It's gonna hit you!
Sorry, sorry.
Geez.
A paper plane?
Not that it matters, but what's with this pattern?
The Japanese flag?
What? You don't know.
The public's in an uproar over the paper plane prankster right now.
During the last two days...
Something like 100 paper airplanes have
been recovered in the metropolitan area.
And something that this was drawn on those paper planes.
That pattern.
Come to think of it, that was on the cellphone news too.
Well, it's probably just some rank.
They've only been seen flying at night, so...
It's probably just the act of some person who's stressed out at work.
Speaking of stress, today's the rebroadcast, isn't it?
"The Stress Murder Case."
Ah, that's from Shinmei Kaori's "Detective Samonji" series, isn't it?
I want to watch that again.
But we won't be in time for it today.
The rebroadcast was today?!
Uncle was watching Okino Youko's special during
the original broadcast so I missed it then.
Wait a sec.
I'm pretty sure Ran had a test today, and
was only at school during the morning.
I'll ask her to record it.
Huh? Ran hasn't come home yet.
She said she'd be back late today.
Eh? Why?
For some reason she's gone to clean that detective boy's house again.
Geez, that Ran, doing things she doesn't need to again.
Ah, if it's OK with you, can I ask you for something?
Heh? If it's pocket money, I'm not doing it.
No, it's nothing like that.
Ah, wait a minute.
Uh-oh! Over there now is...
So? If it's not that, was is it?
Hey! Are you listening?!
Why did he call me then?
You know, that really surprised me.
That clumsy kid deciding go study abroad in America.
Yeah, and so suddenly after he went to so
much trouble to come back to school.
Still I wonder how Eisuke-kun is doing these days.
Speaking of how someone is doing...
Huh?
How's Shinichi-kun doing?
He still hasn't come back yet?
No.
And while she waits for Shinichi-kun, who's never coming back...
Ran sets out all willingly yet again today to clean.
I'm not doing it "all willingly".
But, still...
Hasn't this become a monthly event?
Cleaning Shinichi-kun's house, that is.
Now, don't say it like that.
Didn't I tell you where they had that delicious sandwich?
That was definitely delicious, still...
Why would you do this for free for that
deduction guy who hardly ever contacts you.
Oh, c'mon.
It seems he has his troubles too.
Huh?
Mmm? What's wrong?
Isn't it awfully cool inside the house?
It's like the air-conditioning is on.
Now that you mention it, it is.
Shinichi?
Shinichi came home?
Shinichi!
Where are you?
You're here, aren't you? Answer me!
Shinichi!
He's there.
The bathroom!
Geez, if you were coming home, you should have told me.
Who are you?
Ah, well...
Wait! It can't be! A thief!
Sonoko, stay back!
Ah, you see...
Heh. Serves you right!
Ran, hurry and call the police.
Ran?
He didn't resist.
Who is this person?
Eh? A graduate student has been staying
here since last week? Really, Conan-kun?
Yeah, remember? I told you earlier. My friend's
father's apartment building burned down?
That guy was living there. His name is Okiya Subaru-san.
Does Shinichi know about this?
Yeah, I sent him some e-mail and he replied.
He wrote that it would be fine to lend him the house, but we
shouldn't talk too much about Shinichi-niichan in front of him.
Eh? Why not?
He might take some strange interest and go
looking around Shinichi's room or something.
Oh, I see.
The teacher's here, so talk to you later.
Ah, wait...
And so that means...
We're very sorry!
For kicking you so suddenly without thinking.
Exactly, Ran. There's no way a good-looking
guy like this would be a thief.
What's that?
Weren't you the one who said "Serves you right!"?
Ah, yeah, well, it's really my fault too for
not managing to explain right away.
By the way, Okiya-san, which graduate school are you going to?
Touto University's engineering department.
Good-looking and elite!
Say, would it be OK if I took a cellphone picture?
And could you tell me your e-mail address too?
I don't mind.
I should tell Kyougoku-san.
Well, just a photo then.
Would it be OK to go out and buy something before that?
I haven't had anything to eat since I woke up.
Well then let us, in apology for what happened earlier.
Well in that case, if you're sure it's all right.
How about that "Welcome Burger" place you ate at earlier.
Huh?
Did we mention we'd gone to Welcome Burger?
No, but it was simple enough.
I noticed you with the brown-dyed hair.
Back then when you suspected I was a thief...
You were cursing at me with defiant words.
But just as you figured out that wasn't the case...
Then you kept your distance from me...
And tried to hide behind your long-haired friend.
Normally it would be the opposite.
This is most likely because you felt considerably favorably
impressed by me as a member of the opposite sex...
And you were concerned about me smelling your bad breath.
In short, that's why I thought that you might have
eaten that new garlic sandwich product.
T-That's amazing!
But there are other foods that have garlic.
I figured it out from the way you handled your cellphone earlier.
Huh?
The reason you were using your ring finger,
even though it's difficult to do so...
Was that when you were eating French fries...
You picked them up with the tip of your right thumb and middle
finger and you felt the oil that was still stuck to them.
And besides, you with the long hair, you have
a little bit of salt sticking to your mouth.
Excuse us.
We need to use the washroom.
Wow, who is he? Who is that good-looking guy?
I dunno.
I think I may have met that person somewhere before.
I have the feeling he resembles someone.
Ah, in that case, isn't it your husband, Shinichi-kun?
Subaru-san sort of acts just like a detective.
Eh? He doesn't look like him.
And he's not my husband.
Well, from what I see, I think
Subaru-san is one cut better as a detective.
You think so?
Shinichi wouldn't have done any worse.
Well, why don't we have them compete
and see? Subaru-san and Shinichi-kun.
Today let's study the names of flowers.
E-mail? From Ran?
"Can Shinichi solve the case that's got everyone upset?"
For the time being, the information
I have is this picture I'm sending you.
What's this?
Isn't this the paper airplane Genta was flying this morning?
Huh? The pattern is slightly different from Genta's, however.
There's a picture of the other side too.
Hey!
Could it be?
This was in the garden at your house?
I'd like to know what reason that annoying prankster
has for spreading these around, whoever they are.
I see.
This is a very interesting code.
Does that mean you've already figured it out?
Something came.
Shinichi's reply. That was fast!
Most likely the meaning of this paper plane is an SOS.
An SOS?
Then someone needs to be rescued?
Yes, and what's more, the circumstances are
such that immediate attention is required.
If there's a different kind of paper plane...
A paper plane with a different pattern...
I'd like you to show it to me at once.
Ah, you don't know? He's a detective
who's a high-school student, Shin-
It's Kinichi.
Something made me stop.
I have an uneasy feeling that I shouldn't
talk about Shinichi to that person.
Someone's life is probably at stake!
I can't wait for you at a time like this!
Tell me, Shinichi! Tell me how!
Ran!
Next Conan's Hint
Squid
Look forward to the next episode
I knew it wasn't an octopus!
How so?
I can't say.