Waiting gets us nowhere.
Take a step forward into the future.
It's a deduction and love countdown!
Has another rival to Shinichi appeared?
It's a contest to solve the paper plane puzzle!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
A new member of the Black Organization has been activated.
An agent who is killed at intelligence gathering
as well as observation and discernment.
Codename: Bourbon.
I need to be careful.
I solved the arson case over Sugiura
Kaito-kun's apartment building, but...
One of the residents of the apartment building who
lost his home in the fire, Okiya Subaru-san...
Is now staying for free at my,
that is to say, Kudou Shinichi's, house.
Ran and Sonoko, who didn't know about it, mistook him for a burglar.
I wonder, is Subaru-san all right after being kicked by Ran?
Recently a paper plane prankster has been annoying the public.
Night after night hundreds of paper planes
have been scattered around the city.
Those planes had been detailed with unusual markings.
When I saw one of the planes in an image
attached to an e-mail Ran sent me...
I realized that a serious message was hidden on them.
And that was.
A different kind of paper airplane?
Yeah. I remember from the news that close to 100 had been
recovered in the city area yesterday morning and the before.
And so, if the message drawn on the paper planes was
different between yesterday and the day before...
Then I think might be able to narrow down the
location of the person who's sending this SOS.
By the way, when was this found in the garden at your house?
I found it the morning of the day before yesterday.
But, before that, won't you tell me?
Why is that paper plane an SOS?
It's the pattern drawn on the body.
The size of the circles on the top and bottom are roughly the same...
And the lengths of the three lines are three times width of the circles.
Also, the distance from circle to circle...
Is exactly the width of a single circle.
And thus, these are...
The symbols of Morse code, which is frequently
used as a means of communication.
Morse code? That thing that's always in those old movies?
Yeah, that's right.
The circles are the short sounds, or dots.
The lines are the long sounds, or dashes.
In Morse code, three dots are an 'S'.
Three dashes are an 'O'.
In other words...
An SOS.
"That means it's a signal from someone asking to be rescued."
That's what he wrote in the e-mail.
You're kidding!
Shinichi-kun figured it out too?
Yeah.
And then he asked, if there was a different kind
of paper plane, for me to send him a picture.
Shinichi-kun?
Come to think of it, the name of the owner
of this house was Shinichi too, wasn't it?
Ah, you don't know? He's a detective
who's a high-school student, Shin-
It's Kinichi.
K-Kinichi's this boy in my class who's a real mystery lover.
It's not "Shinichi-kun", but "Kinichi-kun" instead?
Ah, yeah. The Shinichi who's the owner of this house is just
a regular high-school student with no special abilities.
Just a regular high-school student?
That's not what I think at all.
Eh? What do you mean?
For some reason, even though I'm told he lived
here, there's no trace of him left at all.
There are no clothes, or a diary, or even
anything like a photo album here at all.
Well, I'm just saying what I've noticed.
Is that so?
Perhaps he cleaned everything up because he'd be
embarrassed if we saw them when we came to clean?
Speaking of cleaning things up...
Earlier, when we were at Welcome Burger...
Wasn't the manager asking an employee to clean up
the paper plane that had gotten caught in the sign?
Let's hurry and get it!
Ah, wait a sec! Ran!
Hey, what was with that "Kinichi-kun" stuff?
You see, earlier Shinichi told me not to talk about him to that person.
Shinichi-kun did?
He said he might take some strange interest and
he didn't want him looking through his room.
Conan kun told me something like that in an e-mail.
You know, that's just like a detective.
They love to investigate other people,
but the reverse is "no good" eh?
Guess so.
Besides...
Something made me stop.
I have an uneasy feeling that I shouldn't
talk about Shinichi to that person.
So next, why don't you all try writing the
names of the flowers in katakana?
That Ran sure is slow...
Could it be there was only that one kind of paper airplane?
She finally sent it.
Let's see...
It looks like yesterday's paper planes were different
from the ones the day before yesterday.
I'll send you a picture, OK?
Eh? What's this?
There's no pattern on this one.
If I look closely though...
There are five lines on the fold of the plane.
In Morse code, five dashes means zero.
But what on earth could zero mean?
There's a pattern on the opposite side too.
But it looks like the lines are just drawn alongside the folds.
C-Could this be?
An antenna mark?
Like on a cellphone?
It's true! They're the same!
And so, if we add that together with
the five dashes on the body, we get:
Zero radio waves.
Furthermore, considering the initial SOS...
"I'm being held captive in a location where
radio waves don't reach. Please rescue me."
That's what it would mean, right?
Amazing! Subaru-san, you're a great detective!
Still...
Even with this, as of yet all we know is
it's a place outside reception range.
A place outside reception range? Like a cave
deep within the mountains or something?
But the paper planes have only been found inside the city.
Then what about below ground?
How would it be able to fly from below
ground into the garden at your house?
Ah, that's right.
Oh, wait a minute.
They were found yesterday and the day before, but what about today?
That's it! The TV news!
The identity of the kidnapper who, whiles escaping, committed suicide
by leaping from a building early this morning has yet to be established.
The whereabouts of the kidnapped naval construction
company president, Daita Ikou-san, is also still unknown.
The police are also considering following
up on any grudges against Daita-san.
The kidnapper may have planned...
That's all that's on this channel too.
That man, President Daita, used his experience as a former sailor
to bring his company, with great effort, though lots of hardships.
That's what they said on the news this morning.
Could it be?
Could what be, Subaru-san?
This kidnapping case.
It might be related to the paper airplanes.
If he was kidnapped and is still being confined somewhere...
It makes sense that he could be throwing out these SOS
paper planes every night without the culprit seeing.
Then this President Daita is the paper plane prankster?
Yeah, there's a high probability.
Since he was a former sailor...
It wouldn't be strange for him to know Morse code, since they
use it as a means of communication during emergencies.
Most likely, still not knowing that the kidnapper committed
suicide, he's trying to get help without the culprit realizing.
I see. That way, even if the culprit happened to pick one
of these up, it would look to him like some kid's prank.
It seems that the paper planes found yesterday and the day before...
Were made from single pages ripped out of a magazine.
President Daita's might be restricted from moving very much.
And so he can't reach anything except that magazine.
That's terrible.
And now moving on, we're following up on
the story of the paper plane prankster.
Ah, here it is!
Right now I'm at the park near the Beika Tower Apartments where
one of the controversial paper planes was found this morning.
And so, first of all, regarding the patterns on the plane this time...
There aren't any on this side, but...
One the opposite side, there's one circle and four
partial circles drawn in a symmetrical pattern.
However, looking closely, there are also some strange creases.
This only serves to deepen the mystery.
Creases?
You can't see it very well on the TV.
Hey now, we're in the middle of class.
But Conan-kun's working really hard making paper airplanes.
Hey, Conan-kun!
You can do that during the break.
I'm sorry, teacher, but can you leave me alone?
Now look here...
Someone's life is probably at stake!
Is that so?
Exactly.
The person releasing these things could possibly be...
The kidnapped President Daita.
And he's being confined in a location
where there's no cellphone reception.
Considering the fact that he's made and released
such a large number of paper planes...
It's highly likely he's been abandoned there while still confined.
And if he’s without food or drink..
He'll be in danger soon.
Using the paper plane that was found this morning...
I should be able to narrow down his location further.
But what's with these?
What's with the four partial circles and the strange creases?
Wait a sec.
If I assume this is also Morse code...
These half circles probably combine to make one.
So four half circles make two full circles...
Plus there's the original full circle.
A full circle would be 'E'.
Two would be 'I'.
In romaji, that would be "El" or... "IE"? (house)
What "house" could he be talking about?
Excuse me, Subaru-san...
You know, speaking of paper planes,
there are lots of ways to fold them.
There are, you know. Lots of kinds.
Like an cicada! Or like a swallow!
There are even ones that resemble animals you'd
definitely never think you'd see flying through the sky.
I get it!
It's like this!
Hey, Conan!
What's that supposed to be?
Is that a paper plane?
That sort of looks like a squid.
But, if that's it, shouldn't you fold the head part one more time?
Nope, this is good enough.
The person who's been throwing these wanted the
people who find them to make a squid this way.
Could it be that person you're talking about is the paper
plane prankster who's causing all this commotion?
Yeah, if you spread this squid open once more...
Turn the paper over and make a paper airplane.
Look.
It looks exactly the same as the paper plane
that was collected today, doesn't it?
Now I see.
So the strange creases and the partial
black circles come from making a squid.
That's the real message that's being sent
to the people who pick them up.
Wait a minute!
That paper plane guy, he's not just pulling some prank?
Yesterday, the day before, and today...
Each day seemed to have a different pattern.
Don't you see there has to be some kind of message?
But who's doing it? And why?
If we want to know that...
We'll have to have Conan-kun solve the code.
He's gone!
Conan-kun?
"Be"?
Those three circles mean "be"?
Yes, probably.
This is Morse code written in a Japanese way.
A single circle is "he".
The other two indicate a consonant marker, and if we join them up...
"Be".
But where's the message in that?
Do you recognize this shape?
The shape?
A squid?
And so, if we join the two of them together?
Be...
Ika...
Beika!
In other words, Beika City.
Ha-ha. It's a pun.
Well, a code is sort of like a pun.
And if these are being thrown out by President Daita,
who's been kidnapped and held captive...
Then if the culprit picked one up, he might not guess the meaning.
So it's OK that he used a pun.
Then where could President Daita be?
If I remember right, the first paper plane said "SOS" and the next
one said "A location with no cellphone reception," right?
Putting all three together would be: "Rescue me from the location in
Beika City that has no cellphone reception where I'm held captive."
Is there a place like that in Beika City except underground?
A high-rise building.
Eh?
The base station antennas for the cellphone network are targeted
towards the ground, where the population density is high.
Therefore it's difficult to connect from high places.
Even if you can connect, as a consequence of the height,
you pick up radio waves from several base stations.
You often get roaming mode, and eventually you go outside the range.
There are two high-rise buildings in Beika City.
In a hotel, people are coming and going to make the bed
and such, so, it's difficult to confine someone there.
Therefore...
The place where President Daita is being held captive
could possibly be the Beika Tower Apartments.
No way! That's really close by!
Now, the message about being out of range is
likely only a hint about where he's being confined.
Because in reality the culprit would probably have taken his cellphone.
In any case, we should tell the police about this right away.
The phone?
Ran! It's me!
Shinichi?
Where are you right now?
I'm still at Shinichi's house.
That's perfect. Can you head over to the
Beika Tower Apartments near you?
That's where the kidnapped President Daita is being confined!
Then you solved the paper plane code?
Yeah. But I'll explain later.
There are some binoculars in the
second drawer of the desk in my room.
Take those and get on the observation elevator
at the New Beika Hotel for me.
Ask Sonoko to call the police and get there as fast as you can!
Ah, I should have gone with Ran.
Well, let's trust that she and he can handle things at the scene.
He?
The mystery lover, Kinichi-kun.
Right?
But, Shinichi, I can only see one side
of the apartment complex from here.
Yeah if it's on the side you can't see then we're
wasting time, but there's nothing we can do about it.
Did you find it?
Yeah. It's the apartment on the far end
of the east side on the 36th floor.
The window is open a little and there's
a pile of paper planes on the veranda.
Ran, even if you've found the place where he's
confined, don't try going in there on your own.
The possibility is close to zero, but an accomplice
of the kidnapper might still be in there!
OK. In that case, I'll inform Sonoko by e-mail
and she can take this all to the police.
What's happened? Ran!
No way!
A paper plane just flew by now.
And it's been made from a 10,000 yen bill!
What?
There's nothing written on it, but...
Did President Daita send this too?
Yeah, probably.
Even with nothing written on it, if money comes raining down...
It will get everyone excited and they'll search for where it's
coming from, and it'll get reported to the police too.
That's his aim.
But him doing something like that during the day, taking on the risk
that the culprit will notice, means it's come down to life-or-death.
In other words, that means President Daita's condition is really bad!
The paper planes were initially found on
the morning of the day before yesterday.
So it's been nearly three days since he started throwing them out!
Furthermore, the culprit committed suicide.
If he's been left alone without being provided food and water...
It's possible that he's extremely dehydrated.
Anyway, I'll call the police and an
ambulance, so, Ran, you stay there!
Say, what would you do, Shinichi?
Huh?
You wouldn't wait at a time like this, would you?
Ah, hey!
Then I'm going too!
Wait!
There's still a chance that the culprit had an accomplice!
But didn't you say the probability was almost zero?
If it was you, you'd rush into the room to help right away.
Tell me, Shinichi!
Tell me how!
Shinichi!
This is Yamakawa from the insurance company.
Please come in.
Yes, coming. Who is it?
Uhm, I was just riding the elevator at the hotel and...
There was a suspicious person on the veranda of this apartment!
Please call the police right away!
OK.
It's here.
In a high-rise apartment complex, they are
required by law to install escape ladders.
You can reach him from the apartment just above.
Who are you?
You're the kidnapped man, President Daita, right?
I saw your paper airplanes and I've come to rescue you.
Listen up.
If you find him, first lay him down on his side,
and don't forget to cushion his head.
Then wet a handkerchief with lukewarm water and apply it to his mouth.
That's the best emergency treatment you can give him.
Th-The ransom.
Has it been paid?
It's all right. It's all been taken care of, so don't worry.
No way! So there really was an accomplice!
Ah, I'm...
All right, leave the rest to us.
I've already heard the story.
You're Mouri Ran-san, right?
Yes.
That high-school student who called, is he your boyfriend?
Ah, no. Nothing like that.
Pass along something to him.
The situation was easy enough to understand in brief.
I can understand him being impatient, but
there's no point to just ranting on and on.
Well, he sure expressed his desperation well enough.
In the end, it turned out that apartment belonged
to the culprit and there never was an accomplice.
He committed the crime because he was pressed by debts.
President Daita recovered from his confinement shortly thereafter.
And the uproar over the strange paper airplanes came to an end.
Really? Shinichi-kun got all upset and started ranting?
To the emergency personnel and to the police?
Yeah. Even after he was really calm when he was
directing me. That's not like Shinichi, is it?
That was because his beloved wife was in a crisis.
It can't be! That would be out of character for that guy.
And I'm not his wife!
Well, to be blunt, it could have been.
Because I honestly don't remember what I said then.
My tension flared up.
And I only had a single thought in my head...
I couldn't let this tomboyish rescue squad member die.
Come to think of it, that deduction showdown
between Shinichi-kun and Subaru-san. Who won?
I dunno.
Deduction showdown?
Well, President Daita's been rescued safely, so I wonder if
Subaru-san is having a celebratory drink just about now.
A celebratory drink?
It was on the shelf in the kitchen.
A bottle of alcohol that wasn't there when I was cleaning before.
I'd like to have you tell my fortune.
I want to know no matter what.
Oh! A red-flanked blue tail.
Reika-sensei...
The door's locked.
That means this was...
A sealed room murder!
Next Conan's Hint
Bluebird
Look forward to the next episode
Oh, where is my 'bluebird of happiness'?
There, Sonoko-neechan, there!
Oh, there it goes.