Waiting gets us nowhere.
Take a step forward into the future.
It's a deduction and love countdown!
Astrology can't solve it itself.
Let's solve the case quickly!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
It's essential for a detective...
To capture objective leads in a case.
And, by not allowing subjective feelings to get in the way...
Systematic deductions can be carried out.
Don't you think so?
Say, Mouri-san, the astrology that I practice...
Shijou Reika (38)
Astrologist
You don't believe in it, do you?
That's not it at all.
Although it's different from fortune-telling...
Solving a case also requires a sixth sense.
One of which often comes in a flash of light...
A flash of light that can see through the intuitive truth of a case.
Have you ever looked into this line of fortune-telling?
Well, I guess I should say "some"
Because of a curious publisher...
The widely famous astrologist, Shijou Reika...
And the famous detective Mouri Kogoro
were brought together for a discussion.
Katsuragi Kensuke (45)
"Starry Sky Weekly" President
That's how we've ended up here at Shijou Reika's home.
Tamura Machio (32)
Editor
Perhaps I have a natural ability for detection...
As many times, I have solved them while unconscious.
You really know how to tell jokes!
Sensei, Nakame-sama from Tohto TV is on the phone.
Shiraishi Yuuka (26)
Reika's Apprentice
He said it's important that he speaks with you.
I'm working right now.
I'll call later.
Yes...
I'm about to take the shot.
Mouri-san, no need for that—just be natural.
This is a really nice house.
It was originally a very wealthy person's
villa, before Reika bought it for herself.
Reika?
No...
I meant Reika-sensei.
That's stained glass, right?
Yeah.
It's a personal design by Reika-sensei.
You can see ones like it all around the villa.
Above it is her profile, as well as her astrological sign—Scorpio.
I'll get it.
Too strong.
When you make coffee this strong...
It doesn't even have a nice aroma!
My apologies!
I'll prepare another batch.
Aren't you...
Aren't you actress, Midorikawa Kurara-san?
Midorikawa Kurara (28)
Actress
Is this a customer?
This is the famous detective, Mouri Kogoro.
We're having a discussion to be included as a special in the magazine.
Nice to meet you.
To behold you with my own eyes is an honor!
Reika-sensei, can I have a moment?
Hey, I already paid!
That's all you wanted!
Should you really be saying that?
If I released even a bit of information on you...
You'd be finished.
Then, there's nothing I can do but quit!
If you want to escape me...
You must find a replacement immediately.
Replacement?
Yes, a replacement for you.
Anyone will do.
So long as it's someone with money and privacy.
Find someone along those lines, and you're free to go.
Who's that handsome guy?
What're you talking about?
Mouri-san, I will tell your fortune next.
Please wait here for an hour.
Have some wine with the others in the meantime.
Kurara-san, please come to my room around 5:00.
Reika-sensei!
Oh, Ran-san.
Is there anything I can do for you?
I'd like to have you tell my fortune.
Actually, that's why I forced my father to come here...
I have to know, no matter what.
It seems it's really troubling you.
Very well.
I'll read your fortune.
Will you really?
Yes.
But, I don't quite have the time right now.
There are many people waiting.
Is that so?
As consolation, take this.
It's a charm.
I can't accept something so precious!
Then, I'll let you hold it.
Just return it on the day I read your fortune, all right?
Yes!
I will do my best to find time for you.
Thank you so much!
That can't be!
Didn't you promise you would let me take over that column?
Although I originally intended to do just that...
Reika strongly opposed it...
Unless you can tell fortunes by some other means.
It's not that you aren't good at it.
This is just a front...
This is the proof that she hates me!
Tres bien!
Yuuka-san, what's wrong?
Did sensei scold you?
Sensei is always taking out her anger on her.
Yuuka-san is her niece as well as her apprentice...
But she treats her more like a servant.
Well, I guess that's just another aspect of fortune telling.
Excellent!
Yeah, it's me.
About that special matter...
Which way is the restroom?
The door on the left, all the way at the end.
Thanks.
To the left, to the left...
Instead of playing soccer with Genta and the others, I'm stuck here.
Oh! A red-flanked blue tail.
It actually made it all the way out here.
That's rare.
Sensei, dinner is ready.
Reika-sensei?
I called for her several times but she didn't answer.
Could she be asleep?
She isn't the type to make her guests wait for extended periods of time.
Let's go look.
Mouri-san, will you accompany me?
Yeah, if you insist.
Sensei?
Reika, what's wrong?
The door's locked.
That's strange. Something could be wrong.
Let's look from the veranda.
What!?
Reika, what's wrong!?
Reika!
It's no use.
That's right, we can break in through the window on the roof.
I'll climb up and see!
Tamura-kun, open the door so I'll have some footing.
Right!
After you get inside, go unlock the door!
Hold on, Reika!
Reika!
Open your eyes, Reika!
The entrance and exit doors are both locked...
Moreover, the window is covered with bars...
Which means this is...
A sealed room murder!
The murder victim is a fortune-telling astrologer, Shijou Reika-san.
She has likely been dead between three and three and a half hours.
That puts the crime at about 5:00.
Since the door was locked...
You all broke the window to get in, right?
And where was the key then?
It was in that pile there.
It was Katsuragi-san that opened the door.
Are there any spare keys?
Her apprentice, Yuuka-san, may have one.
Oh, a bird's feather fell in here, too!
It's from a red-flanked blue tail.
At around 5:30...
I saw one fly to the roof up there.
If the feather fell in from the broken window...
Isn't it strange that the feather is under the glass?
Brat!
Stop rummaging through the scene!
Shiraishi-san...
Did you have a spare key to Reika-san's room?
No, only she had a key to her room.
Yuuka-san, as the one closest to her...
It would be easy to make a copy of that key, right?
Why would I?
Would you not be against her, since she halted
you from writing the astrology column?
That's not it!
With sensei dead...
You serve to inherit her legacy, as the closest relative.
I see.
Yuuka-san...
The culprit is you.
You used a spare key.
Inspector, we've already heard back on duplicates of the key.
What was their conclusion?
Yes, sir.
This is a special hollow-point key.
Only the manufacturer can duplicate this key.
Duplicates can only be requested with the original credit card.
That way, the chance of anyone but the owner getting one...
Is near zero.
I called the manufacturer...
And was told this is the only one.
No way...
This case has become much more complex...
Yeah, and since the key was inside the room...
A sealed room murder...
That's right!
When Katsuragi-san opened the door at the time...
Couldn't he have hidden the real key?
What are you saying?
No, I saw it from beginning to end...
And he didn't do anything like that.
Right...
I saw it as well...
Shiraishi-san...
When was the last time you saw Reika-san alive?
When sensei left the living room for her office.
And where did you go afterwards?
I talked with Katsuragi-san for a few minutes...
And was in the kitchen the rest of the time.
Uhm, I was also in the kitchen helping
with dinner and can confirm that.
Tamura-san, what about you?
The same as Yuuka-san.
I was in the living room with Mouri-san.
And you, Katsuragi-san?
Same for me.
I was discussing business on the phone at reception...
And after 5:00, I was here with Tamura-kun and Mouri-san.
What about you, Midorikawa-san?
I... Just like the others.
Now that you mention it, when I went to the bathroom around 5:00...
You were coming down from the 2nd floor, weren't you?
That was... My fortune-telling appointment.
Could Kurara-san have killed sensei?
Don't say such foolish things!
Why would I do that?
Kurara-san...
I saw it when I came here last month for work.
You were coming out of her room...
Stupid bitch... I'll take care of you sooner or later.
You did it?
Why did you do it?
Reika was a dispicable woman.
She would have such an inviting face at first...
And by using fortune-telling as a front...
She had me tell her my deepest secrets and betrayed me.
She used astrology to extort large sums of money from me.
I wanted to stand my ground...
But she threatened to leak my private information to the press.
I see.
Extortion.
And that's why you went to Reika-san and...
That's not it!
I went to her room, but...
I'm working right now.
I'll call later.
That's why I came back.
Can you prove that?
How do you expect me to?
Conan-kun...
Ran-neechan?
I once thought she was such a good person...
But now this extortion...
Before, I went to Reika-sensei to have my fortune told...
But she said she didn't have time.
She gave me this...
And said it was a charm.
It used to be on her room's key.
When was that?
Before she went in for Dad's reading.
That means...
That means the, "I'm working right now, I'll call later"...
Where have I heard that before?
The design here is the same as the one on the roof.
This is...
I see...
I've got it!
At any rate, we'd like for everyone to go the station...
And answer just a few questions.
It's all that wine getting to me...
Hold on just one moment, Inspector-dono
You could settle for just taking the culprit.
What? You mean you know who the culprit is?
Of course.
The trick in this case isn't a complicated one.
After they killed Reika-san...
The culprit walked out of the room with the key and locked the door.
And then, went up on the roof...
Cracked the stained glass by making a hole...
And dropped the key from there.
The red-flanked blue tail that Conan saw around 5:30...
Went over the hole the culprit made.
That's why its feather was under the glass.
Speaking of glass...
In what shards of the stained glass, there aren't any red pieces.
It was in the middle of the scorpio's image on the glass.
But why would the culprit go to so
much effort to create a sealed room?
To ensure that Yuuka-san becomes the scapegoat.
The culprit was likely convinced Yuuka-san had a spare of the key.
But, since there isn't one...
This simple murder became a sealed room one.
I see.
Doesn't that mean Midorikawa-san is the culprit, then?
No way...
No.
When Kurara-san went to the door...
Reika-san had already been murdered.
What'd you say?
But I heard her voice!
Tamura-san...
The conversation between Reika-san and I was recorded, wasn't it?
Yes.
There was a call in the middle of it, right?
Could you please play that back for us?
Got it.
He said it's important that he speaks with you.
I'm working right now.
I'll call later.
Reika-sensei, it's me, Midorikawa.
I'm working right now.
Wait until I call.
Then, it's the one with the recording, Tamura-san!
That's not it!
A tape recorder can be concealed in a pocket by anyone.
Isn't that right, Katsuragi-san?
What?
The murderer who took the life of Reika-san...
Katsuragi-san...
It was you.
What the hell do you mean!?
Earlier, it was you who suggested Yuuka-san would have a spare key.
I want to ask: Why didn't you ask Yuuka-san
when you couldn't get the door open?
That's because I was in a bit of a panic and hurrying!
No.
In order to prevent the hole from being found...
You had to break the glass.
No!
Then, let me ask...
When you broke the glass and jumped down...
There were a number of keys lying around.
You picked up this room's key without any hesitation, didn't you?
How did you know that key went to the room?
It's the key holder!
I know that she always keeps a sapphire pendant on her key holder!
That is strange.
Because, before this incident, what was
on the key holder was changed slightly.
Beforehand...
Reika-san removed it from the keyring and gave it to my daughter...
As a charm.
Isn't that right?
Yes.
That sapphire key holder...
She removed it just before she went into her office.
So, if you did not see or talk to Reika-san after that...
How would you know?
That the key with the sapphire pendant is the one in this room.
Other than Reika-san...
The only other would be the culprit who created the sealed room...
Katsuragi-san!
That woman was worthless!
She demanded I repay all of her investments.
She said that if I couldn't...
She would get insider trading information from the publishing house...
And sell it to the weekly magazines!
Say, Ran-neechan...
What did you want to learn from the fortune-telling?
I wanted to know where Shin'ichi is right now.
Right here, actually...
Really...
I don't know how he's doing...
Rather than worrying about Shin'ichi-niichan...
Wouldn't it be best to start thinking of how we'll get Uncle home?
This isn't a "dream vision," right?
"24 Hours in the Life of Mouri Kogoro"?
I'd be happy to accept!
You came into this sealed room first to hide some evidence
that you weren't able to remove earlier, didn't you?
I was wrong, this isn't an ordinary murder.
It's an impossible crime!
Next Conan's Hint
Soaked Jacket
The playboy, Officer Takagi!
It's a jacket!
Next Conan: Secret Love is brought to light.