Waiting gets us nowhere.
Take a step forward into the future.
It's a deduction and love countdown!
A white cup has a lingering scent of black.
A miraculous secret room and an unseen culprit.
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
"24 Hours in the Life of Mouri Kogorou"?
Yes, Monday at 9:00, during golden time.
We often have programs like that where we
follow the daily lives of policemen, but...
This time we'd like to try a spot with a private detective.
Usually detectives don't want their faces exposed,
Somei Shougo (35)
TV Program Production
Company President
or their investigation methods known....
Since that can become a hindrance to their work.
So they often refuse.
But, you're extremely famous, Mouri-san.
And can really draw an audience.
If it's possible, we'd really like you to do it.
Still, being followed the whole time for 24 hours...
Of course, when it's a bad time, tell us and we'll turn the camera off.
Kuzumi Maiko (29)
TV Program Production
Company Employee
You can check it before it goes on air.
And we'll cut any parts that are NG (no good).
But, still...
He hasn't had any clients recently.
That's true.
He spends the day drinking beer and listening
to horse-racing and plays mahjong every night.
Having them follow him might be a problem.
Y-You don't have any work?
Ah, no, it only happens that's the case now.
Hey!
If you like, why don't you just prepare something?
Make up an unsolved murder case or something.
Wait a sec, Dad!
Make it up?
Staged events aren't well received.
Still, for now, why don't we check with the staff?
Even if it's not a murder case...
They might have some case or problem which would draw interest.
That's no good.
Even if we didn't stage it...
If we depend on the staff to do it...
People would suspect it was staged anyway.
And it might hurt Detective Mouri's name.
Also, considering the time before it would go on-air...
There isn't time to make those kinds of arrangements.
I guess you're right.
Excuse me...
Yes?
Could it be you two are seeing each other?
You're wearing paired watches.
Ah, no.
This is something she gave me as a present for my birthday.
Since I liked the design, I bought another for myself too.
Well, ever since I first established the company...
She's been taking care of me.
So she is sort of like a wife.
Still, it's disappointing.
I thought you'd say OK for sure, Mouri-san.
We already setup plans to meet with Nakame-san.
Nakame-san?
He's a producer from Touto TV.
The truth is, I arranged a meeting about
the program together with Nakame-san.
I said I'd invite both you and the staff together to his house, but...
What? You decided that on your own without
first asking about my availability?
I figured that, when you saw the name of the program
narrator, you'd respond with a favorable reply.
The narrator?
It was written on the proposal I gave you a while ago...
YOUKO-CHAN!
And?
Will Youko-chan be coming to this business meeting too?
Yes, of course.
I'd be happy to accept!
The old man is so easy to manipulate.
Detective Mouri accepted?
Just like I thought, Okino Youko made very effective bait.
Yeah, I heard he was a fan, but...
That was something else.
Well, you were extra careful so he didn't realize...
Nakame Raisaku (52)
Touto TV Producer
That this special is just filler to replace a drama
we canceled because of low ratings.
Yeah, I'm certain it's fine.
Mouri-san was really excited.
It's such a catchy program, he's got no idea it's just filler.
Now, please take care of that matter we discussed earlier.
Matter we discussed?
The kickback!
Request an increase in the budget for the program...
And turn the extra money over to me.
That's all profit.
Ah, but, I already refused to do that earlier.
Is that so?
What a shame, and here you thought, you'd finally
gotten some work after such a long time.
W-Wait a minute, please!
Well, if you turn her over to me...
Then I won't insist on it.
Her?
Your company's Maiko-san!
You still don't get it?
The reason I turned the work over to a puny
production company in the first place...
Was because she's my favorite.
I want to keep her next to me.
I can have a working woman like her act as my secretary.
Even better, she's pretty and has a good figure.
Ah, that's kind of a problem too.
Well, we can talk more about it when you bring
Detective Mouri over to my house, can't we?
Is something wrong?
No, it's nothing.
Hello, this is Somei Planning.
Ah, yes.
Ah, thank you.
Don't mention it.
Geez, he's late. It's been more than 30 minutes.
Youko-chan. Yo-o-ko-chan!
Well, there's one person who doesn't mind.
Please forgive me for making you wait, Mouri-san.
No, no!
Well then, I'll just go take the car to the parking lot real quick.
Huh? Where's Youko-chan?
Wouldn't she already be at the producer's apartment?
His jacket was extremely wet...
Youko-chan couldn't come?!
It seems she had something come up suddenly.
So we'll have to have the full meeting another day.
The staff didn't come today either.
Pardon me, but are you all right?
You've seemed tired ever since we met up earlier.
Well, various difficulties kept coming up.
There's no answer.
Maybe he went out and is late getting back or something.
T-That shouldn't be.
Nothing we can do but come back later.
Youko-chan isn't here either.
W-Wait a second, please.
Maybe something happened.
Huh? Something?
T-The thing is, the producer, Nakame,
has been acting strange recently.
Oh yeah, it was on the news a little while ago.
That issue with Touto TV's prearranged TV show.
Ah, that TV travel program where they caused a ruckus.
Yeah.
Nakame-san wasn't part of the staging, but...
Since Nakame-san was the one who started the program...
He felt it was his responsibility.
And so, lately, he's been drinking and complaining a lot...
Saying he wanted to die.
Hey, now.
So, it's possible, that while he was waiting...
He was feeling like that.
Then go right now and tell the apartment manager the situation!
And bring back the key!
Immediately!
R-Right!
Thank you very much.
No, no, no.
A chain lock.
Like we thought, it looks like someone's here.
Nakame-san!
Is anything wrong?
It can't be helped.
We have to cut the chain and go in.
Please.
Ah, right.
Nakame-san?!
We're coming in!
Let's see, where are the slippers?
Ah, it's OK to wear shoes in here.
It seems Nakame-san lived overseas for a long time.
Well, I'll go check in the living room over here.
Mouri-san, could you check the study over that way, please?
Nakame-san!
What should we do, Conan-kun?
Should we go in and check too?
Ran-neechan, you stay here in the entryway.
Nakame-san!
What happened?
Stay there!
Wait!
Nakame-san!
Please don't be dead!
Hey, what's happened?!
When I came into the living room, I saw
Nakame-san had collapsed and wasn't moving!
What did you say?
There's an almond smell coming from his mouth.
A poison containing hydrocyanic acid?
It must have been,mixed in with the coffee when he drank it.
It-It's my fault!
It's because I was late that Nakame-san...
If you have time to sputter that kind of nonsense...
Go call the police and an ambulance!
Right.
Hello, is this the police?
Somebody... Somebody has died!
Hurry! Please come quickly!
The location?
The location is...
The Touto Sky Apartments. The 20th floor.
Just as I thought.
This wasn't suicide.
It was murder.
And the one who planned it...
Is probably...
Probably...
Oh, so he was producing a 24 hours in the life of a detective special?
Yes.
So you came for a meeting concerning it...
To the TV producer's home.
You rang the bell, but there was no answer.
You went into the apartment to check, and that's when
you found the producer, Nakame Raisaku-san...
Had drank poisoned coffee and died.
Ah, yes. When there was no reply...
We asked the apartment manager for the key.
We cut the chain lock, and when we came
into the apartment, this is what we found.
And so, the one who accepted the offer to be in the special...
Who came to this meeting with the president of
a TV program production company, Somei...
The detective who happened to come upon this case...
Once again, completely by coincidence, would
unfortunately be you, wouldn't it, Mouri-kun?
Yes, Inspector-dono!
But don't you think it's pretty strange?
Isn't the ongoing mystery why you're
conveniently there each and every time?
Nah, I'll should just let it drop.
It's becoming silly.
Gu-Guess so.
So, as I suspected, the cause of death was
hydrocyanic acid poisoning, wasn't it?
In regards to that...
How's it going, Tome-san?
The details will have to wait until the autopsy, so it's hard to say...
However, there's probably not much doubt.
The presumed time of death appears to
have been sometime after 6:30 PM.
But, don't you think you broke into the apartment rather soon?
Even cutting the chain lock.
It was something President Somei here said.
Nakame-san had recently been saying things
frequently about committing suicide.
So I felt there might be an emergency.
I see.
Still, Inspector, we shouldn't discard the possibility of murder.
Eh? What's that?
Wasn't this a suicide?
The entryway door was locked and the chain lock was on.
No, I do think this was a sealed room.
But since he drank poison, we can't be sure it was suicide.
I-Is that so?
The culprit might have come to visit
Nakame-san in his apartment, bringing the cake...
And after poisoning the coffee...
Got up to leave, claiming they had urgent business.
While leaving, they could have said, "It's been unsafe recently."
Making him set the chain lock.
So this situation could have been easily created.
And so, after the culprit left...
Nakame-san could have returned to his
seat and drank the poisoned coffee.
I see.
Incidentally...
Where were you at the presumed time of death, around 6:30 PM?
A-Am I under suspicion?
No, you were the one who discovered the body first, right?
I'm just asking to make sure.
I haven't been feeling well recently.
After work was over, I went home to lie down.
Then, at 6:30 exactly, I received a phone call from Mouri-san.
He reminded me that we had an appointment
to meet Nakame-san tonight at 7:00.
And we came here.
I slept the whole day, so I was feeling better.
Wait a minute! Do you mean you'd forgotten
about the appointment for our meeting?
Yes. Please forgive me.
That call, did you take it on the phone at your house?
No.
I took it on this cellphone.
Then, is there anyone who can confirm you
were sleeping at home the whole day?
No, there isn't.
But, proof? I knew it, you are suspecting me.
No, no. Were just making sure.
Ah-re-re?
What's so "ah-re-re"?
This is strange. Underneath the saucer for this coffee cup.
Don't go touching things at random!
Can't you remember to stop fooling around?
Look, see the stain from when the coffee spilled?
Usually when it spills while it's still on the saucer...
There should be a circular stain from the bottom of the plate.
But on this table there isn't a circular stain.
Instead there are these two weird thin lines.
And there's no coffee sticking to the underside of the plate either.
Hmm. That's true.
Could those two thin lines possibly be marks
from the coffee cup and its handle?
If the cup was left after the coffee inside it spilled...
Then the place on the table where the coffee cup
and handle were resting wouldn't get wet.
If that was the case, it would have fallen
down after Nakame-san drank the poison.
That means someone placed the coffee
cup on its saucer on purpose...
And set them back on top of the table...
After the coffee had dried.
But who would do that, and for what reason?
I don't know the reason they did it, but...
I do know who did it.
The one who could do this after the coffee had dried...
Was the one who came into the apartment
first and found Nakame-san's body.
It had to be the one who first discovered
the body, President Somei, doesn't it?
Wait, Conan-kun, what are you saying?
Children say the oddest things.
Nope, it definitely couldn't have been anyone but you.
Spilled coffee would normally take an hour to dry.
If the presumed time of the crime was around 6:30 PM...
We got the key and went into the apartment after 7:30 PM.
No, no, no. It was sometime before 8:00 PM, so...
The spilled coffee must have dried.
You came into this sealed room first to hide some evidence
that you weren't able to remove earlier, didn't you?
With the saucer for the coffee cup!
Am I wrong?!
Like I said, what evidence?
All that's under the saucer for the coffee
cup is the stain from the spilled coffee!
Why would I want to hide something like that?
The stain of spilled coffee?
L-Let me go for a second!
Ran-neechan, let me go!
Hey, Conan-kun!
I was wrong, this isn't an ordinary murder.
It's an impossible crime!
What wrong, Conan-kun?
You've got such a grim face.
Say, this stain from the spilled coffee...
Isn't there something strange?
Like we said, the saucer was placed there afterwards.
On the floor. The floor.
Heh? Something strange?
The spilled coffee dropped from the table onto the chair.
Then, furthermore, it just dripped down the
chair leg onto the carpet on the floor.
That was along the front left leg of the chair.
Look just a bit before the right front leg.
Isn't there a circular spot missing from the stain?
That means that when the coffee spilled...
The chair's front leg on the right side was there, right?
Yeah.
Why was it moved? This chair?
Then, when this guy came into the room...
For some reason, he moved that too.
Could you please stop it with the nonsense?
But, isn't this strange?
The place where the stain is if he moved it after the coffee had dried.
Just like I said.
Look more closely.
The chair was placed like this at first...
Look!
If you join up the right front leg with
the stain, the left side won't reach.
Oh?
Therefore when the coffee was spilled the chair was like this.
Then before the coffee dripped along the left front leg
onto the floor, it had to have moved like this, right?
That's true, but there's no way the chair could have moved on its own.
It's not like someone else was sitting in it.
Exactly. When the coffee spilled...
This is clear proof that someone was sitting here.
Isn't that right, Uncle?
Huh? Oh, yeah.
W-Wait a second here.
If that's the case...
The entryway door was locked and the chain lock was attached.
And the fact that no one except the corpse was in this room means...
It couldn't be...
An impossible crime.
That means, it's a sealed room murder.
No, it could also be that when we came into the
apartment, the culprit was still lurking inside this room.
And in the confusion, they slipped out and made their escape.
I don't think that's possible.
That's because I stayed at the entryway
the whole time, like Conan told me to.
Nobody came out of the room until the police arrived.
What did you say?
Exactly. This was an impossible crime. A sealed room murder.
The TV producer, Nakame Raisaku-san, was killed by poisoned coffee.
A saucer was deceptively placed under the coffee cup
after the coffee spilled on top of the table had dried.
I suppose that was because the culprit had already left the
room when Nakame-san drank the poisoned coffee.
The person who could have performed the deception could only
have been the one who first discovered the body, Somei-san.
However, the coffee stain on the floor was
from it running down the leg of the chair.
I realized that someone was sitting in
that chair when the coffee spilled.
If that person was the culprit, how
did they escape from this apartment?
When we got to the apartment, the entry door
was locked and the chain lock attached.
A sealed room murder.
What kind of trick did the culprit use?
Another of your trademark "Ah-re-re"s?
That's the third time today.
This boy is hungry, so...
He'd like to eat the cake that's on top of the table.
The aroma of coffee. It's just as I thought.
In that case, there's only one answer.
The sad truth is the only one.
Next ﻿Conan's Hint
Cake
Look forward to the next episode
I wanna eat cake!
- Yeah, that's the hint.
- Cake! Cake!
Try saying it backwards.
'eake eat'?