Waiting gets us nowhere.
Take a step forward into the future.
It's a deduction and love countdown!
The coffee cups and cake reveal the real culprit and the sad truth.
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
A special TV program, "24 Hours in the Life
of Mouri Kogoro," was planned for production.
To attend business meeting concerning it, we went, along with a
T program production company president, Somei Shougo-san...
Kazumi Maiko (29)
TV Program Production
Company Employee
Somei Shougo (35)
TV Program Production
Company Employee
To pay a visit to the apartment building of the
Tohto TV Producer, Nakame Raisaku-san.
Nakame Raisaku (52)
Tohto TV Producer
However, the entryway door was locked.
And there was no reply from the intercom.
When we heard from President Somei that nakame-san had made hints about committing suicide...
We called the manager and went into the apartment.
Nakame-san!
There we found the body of Nakame-san, who
had been killed by drinking poisoned coffee.
Since there were signs that the spilled
coffee on the table top had been manipulated...
It became likely that this was murder.
Moreover, the marks of the spilled coffee on the floor indicated that...
When Nakame-san had died...
Somebody else had been in the apartment.
And so the case became more mysterious.
How did that person escape from the apartment
while leaving the entryway door locked?
And who is the culprit who poisoned Nakame-san?
So that means...
It's possible that the culprit is still
hiding somewhere in this apartment.
Check the place from top to bottom!
Yes, sir!
Ah, as for you, Takagi-kun, come here a sec.
Ah, yes?
This sealed room murder has me thinking.
That President Somei...
I'm worried that, since he was the first one to enter
the room, he might have destroyed any signs of a trick.
Confirm whether he's really been sick and
whether he was absent from work or not.
Right.
Has President Somei been sick?
He has.
Seems he's been feeling bad for the last 2 or 3 days.
He didn't come into the office today either.
Ah, I see.
As for his poor health, did he mention
specifically what he was sick from?
No, he didn't, but...
I think it's about his work.
His work?
It's probably because the special
we were working on was scrapped.
By special do you perhaps mean
the one that was to cover Mouri-san?
Oh, you know about it?
Yeah, that "24 Hours in the Life of Mouri Kogoro".
Then, the business meeting with the producer, Nakame?
It was canceled.
The president said he would apologize to Mouri-san himself.
I hope he managed to tell him.
Ah, no, he hasn't mentioned that at all.
Oh, right!
Speaking of the president...
I saw him at a nearby drugstore earlier this evening.
About what time was that?
I think it was around 6:30.
6... 6.30?
6:30.
If that's true, then he has a perfect alibi.
Since his company's location is quite a distance from here.
Nevertheless, why didn't he say anything about it?
Yeah, Somei-san came here around 6:30.
He came to buy some stomach medicine.
But why would the police need to know something like that?
Ah, no.
It's just that Somei-san has gotten involved in a trivial case.
Ah, would that have anything to do with
that famous detective, Mouri Kogoro?
He got a phone call while he was at the store.
And Somei-san answered "Detective Mouri?"
Ah, well...
Ah, wait a second.
Before that, Somei-san got another call on his cellphone.
Do you know who it was from?
I'm sure it was a woman.
A woman?
He called her "Maiko".
Maiko?
She was the one who came earlier with
President Somei to the detective office.
So she telephoned President Somei at that time...
What's this?
Could it be?
Then the reason President Somei went into this room first was...
His real objective was...
The aroma of coffee.
It's just as I thought.
So there's no body here.
Say, was that window locked?
Yeah.
Just to be sure we opened it and checked the veranda.
It's really raining hard.
So don't open the window.
The window was closed.
Yet despite that, the lace curtain underneath is damp.
Come to think of it...
When President Somei stopped in front of the apartment building...
His jacket was wet.
So what was it like? That veranda?
Could they have reached the next apartment or jumped down from it?
No way, no way.
The next door veranda is blocked off by a wall.
And there was no evidence that the emergency
ladder was used to descend to the veranda below.
And most importantly, this is the 20th floor.
And no matter how few people might
be in the parking lot directly below...
Using a rope or something to descend would be slow,
and somebody would notice them coming down.
Well, they could have jumped off using
a hang glider like Kaitou Kid, but...
This rain seems too intense for that.
In that case, there's only one answer.
The sad truth is the only one.
Excuse me.
So would it be OK to let me leave soon?
It's getting late after all.
And I'm still not feeling very well.
Ah, no, wait a bit longer please.
Hey, did you get confirmation about his health?
Yeah, I phoned President Somei's office.
It seems his stomach was bothering him...
And he took 2 or 3 days off of work also.
The employee said that today around 6:30...
He saw the president in a nearby drugstore.
Around 6:30?
But wasn't that the presumed time of death?
Yes.
So I called the store too.
The president was definitely there
buying stomach medicine at that time.
Well, then he's got an alibi, doesn't he?
Yeah.
However, that "24 Hours in the Life of Mouri
Kogoro" special has already been dropped.
Why didn't he mention that?
He tricked Mouri-san into coming with him to a business
meeting about that program to Nakame-san's apartment.
As we suspected, he came to destroy some kind of
evidence pointing to the sealed room murder trick.
If we assume that to be true...
First of all, we have to reveal that trick.
In this kind of situation...
Ordinarily that guy comes up with something.
When he goes "Nyo-hyo" or whatever.
You're right.
Well, sometimes Conan-kun unintentionally says some
word that becomes a clue for solving the case too.
Why not?!
Why can't!?
No means no.
Don't say such strange things.
What was it? What strange thing did he say?
Could it have been something important related to the case?
Ah, no.
This boy is hungry, so...
He'd like to eat the cake that's on top of the table.
But nobody else is going to eat that cake, are they?
So why isn't it OK?
Now, now, Conan-kun.
That cake is an important piece of evidence.
We still have to do various tests on it.
You're lying!
Detective Takagi, you and the inspector
just want to eat it later, don't you?
Ah, no, no.
We wouldn't do something like that.
But, isn't it just the right size for two portions?
Two portions?
Yeah, look carefully at the cake.
There's a gap where it was cut down the middle.
It-It's true.
But why?
That's because...
Isn't is because he suddenly decided to eat a bigger piece?
There's the remainder of whole cake in the refrigerator.
So he could change the size however he liked.
When did the old man go looking inside the refrigerator?
Ran does that a lot too.
When she buys cake for our customers, she buys extra.
And then eats two portions by herself.
It's all thanks to the weird ideas she grew up with.
That has nothing to do with this!
Speaking about growing up...
If you give coffee to a tree, will it grow up bigger?
Give coffee to a tree?
He's just saying meaningless things again.
But I can smell coffee from that flowerpot.
Let me see.
Hmm, it's true.
It does look like it's grown big.
Ah-re-re?
There's the smell of coffee from this pen stand too.
He must have really liked coffee.
That Nakame-ojisan.
That's it!
Perhaps...
The arrangement of the coffee cups and cake on the table...
Wasn't actually like this
But in reality...
Could have been like this.
Now there are two portions.
I see.
Shift the cake onto a single plate...
And place the now empty plate under the
coffee cup to make it look like a saucer.
Pour your own coffee into the pot for the decorative plant...
Put writing implements into the empty cup...
And then it's disguised as a pen stand.
When Nakame-san drank the poison...
This was done to make it seem nobody was with him.
But, who could have done this?
The culprit.
The culprit did this to make us think Nakame-san committed suicide.
What I was asking was who that culprit was.
That was...
Ah-re-re. That's strange.
Another of your trademark "Ah-re-re"s?
That's the third time today.
But there's aren't enough items on the table.
As for the cake, plates, and coffee cups, there are two each.
Isn't that enough?
Forks.
There's only one fork to eat the cake with.
Hmm, that's true.
There's no fork beside the other saucer.
Well, maybe that's been hidden somewhere in this room too.
Or in the kitchen.
No, if I'd had the time to hide it in the kitchen cupboard...
I'd have put the coffee cup in the sink too.
But there wasn't enough time, so unthinkingly I put it in my pocket.
Once I saw Nakame-san's body...
If I didn't cry out right away, I'd be suspicious.
Then it was you who killed Nakame-san.
Yeah, he really put me through a bad time at work.
I killed him the way you said at the beginning, Inspector.
I came to visit bringing the cake,
and after putting poison in the coffee...
I got up from my seat saying I suddenly remembered something.
And after having him attach the
chain lock as a safety precaution, I left.
At the time, it bothered me to leave my
coffee and cake behind on top of the table.
Before I left, I said I would clean up, but...
Nakame-san said that since I had urgent business, it would
be best to leave right away, and he'd clean up himself.
Therefore I came here with Mouri-san in
order to conceal that coffee and cake.
I guess I did something I didn't need to.
But you were seen by witnesses at the drugstore near
your office at around 6:30, the time of the crime.
Who by?
An employee of your company and the shop assistant.
It's true that I did go to buy medicine
today, but it was sometime after 5:00.
Couldn't they have been mistaken?
Well then, what about the coffee stains?
Looking at the stains from where the coffee dripped onto the floor...
Makes us think that someone must have been
sitting in that chair when the coffee spilled.
I spilled it to make those stains on purpose.
On purpose?
When Mouri-san and I came into the apartment...
I took the opportunity before I spilled my coffee into the flowerpot.
Putting those there made this look like an impossible crime, didn't it?
But when Conan-kun mentioned them, I felt
the stains right away, but they weren't wet.
Can you remember when you felt them?
Well, not the exact time...
But I think probably about 30 to 40 minutes after we got the report.
Probably, right? You're not certain.
Enough time had passed and they were already dry.
More importantly, if I didn't make those
stains, then who are you saying did?
How would such a person lock the apartment from the
inside and where would you say they vanished to?
Yes, they vanished.
Into the other world.
What do you mean, "the other world"?
Ah, no, I wanted to ask that too...
Dad, could it be...
It finally happened.
Exactly, that's the mystery everyone wants to ask about.
How did the culprit leave this sealed
apartment and where did they vanish too?
The answer is, the other world.
What I mean is they escaped into a place we
can't reach, into the realm of the dead.
Hey, hey, I don't really get what you mean.
C-Could you be meaning that Nakame-san
sealed himself in before drinking the poison?
What?
No, it wasn't Nakame-san.
Please think about it for a moment.
Even though the window in this room was closed...
Why are the curtains wet?
And when he came to the apartment building...
Why was President Somei's jacket wet despite
the fact that he was riding inside a car?
At the time of the crime, around 6:30 in the evening...
President Somei got a call on his cellphone
from one other person besides me.
And so that means the culprit is someone that President Somei
wanted to protect, even if he had to pin the crime onto himself.
Wait, you're not saying...
Yes. The culprit who killed Nakame-san is...
An employee at President Somei's company.
Kuzumi Maiko-san.
She probably came here to visit, bringing the cake along...
Had Nakame-san drink the poisoned coffee...
And, after confirming that he was dead, went out onto the veranda...
Threw herself over, and thus ended her own life.
No way...
Then the call Somei-san got on his cellphone
at the time of the crime was from her?
Probably she called to tell him she was about to commit suicide.
Since President Somei was the one
she trusted and cared for the most.
Y-You're wrong! She didn't do anything!
I planned the whole crime! She didn't...
You came here so that she wouldn't
be thought a murderer, didn't you?
To erase all traces that she had been here...
And to make it look like Nakame-san had committed suicide.
And if necessary, you were prepared to take the guilt onto yourself.
Then, the reason the curtains were wet was because she left the
door open behind her when she went out onto the veranda.
Yes. President Somei closed and locked the window as well.
And then he cried out in a loud voice
to let me know he'd found the body.
You're wrong! It wasn't her!
It was me! It was me!
Please arrest me, Inspector!
Are you sure it's OK? To leave it like this?
If you're taken in for questioning at this point...
It will remain shut up in this cold hearted rain.
After it had fallen the twenty stories
from the veranda to the parking lot...
You laid it down in the trunk of your car,
becoming dripping wet in the process...
Maiko-san's body.
Maiko...
Go check the trunk right away.
Right.
Afterwards, Maiko-san's body was discovered
in the trunk of President Somei's car...
And the mystery behind this uncanny
sealed room murder was brought to light.
According to the final phone call she made to President Somei...
Because the producer Nakame's demand for a kickback
was refused, he scrapped the special program.
And he threatened to work covertly to dry up any further business.
It seems she committed the crime because she couldn't stand
seeing President Somei looking so worn out day after day.
She kept those murderous intentions to herself.
She said nothing to President Somei, even
quitting the company the day before the murder.
But, it seems that right before she threw
herself over, she phoned and finally told him...
About her feelings for him...
In a frail voice, as if it had been drowned out by the sound of the rain.
Next Day
What's this?
The cake in the refrigerator's been eaten?
Ah, I just ate my portion.
That's funny.
Even though Mom told me she bought three pieces of cake
and put them in the refrigerator while you were out...
There's only one in here.
Look more carefully, there are two pieces there.
It's true! Er...
Isn't this one piece cut into two?
The cellophane wrapping on the cake look like it's been used...
Almost like it's been reapplied.
Is-Is that so?
There's cream on the kitchen knife.
You ate them! You ate two
pieces by yourself, didn't you?!
Hey, don't fool with the knife!
Cake, eh?
Well, I'll just let Ran-neechan have my piece.
I'm not hungry.
Conan-kun?
In that case, I'll give this to you too, Dad.
Are you sure?
I don't think I'll be eating cake for a while.
At least, not before this rain is over...
By teleportation.
He'll escape using teleportation?
Well now, in the next 10 seconds, I'll pass through space and time.
Broadcast is October 20th (Monday) at 7.00 PM
Next Conan's Hint
White & Black
Next time it's a special showdown with Kid!
Let's go!
1, 2, 3, gah!