He's in poor health?
That old man, Jirokichi-san, is?
That's right.
Even though he seems like the type who would never die...
Recently, he hasn't even been able to swallow food.
Is it a serious illness?
An illness? Maybe it could be be called an illness...
Of the heart.
The heart?
He's been leaping up from nightmares every night, covered in sweat...
After seeing his smile in all his dreams.
His?
Him, him.
Who else could it be?
Who do you mean?
He must be planning another extensive and daring theft...
She must mean that scoundrel.
The curtain opens on a new mysterious era...
The Monday 7:00 reasoning show.
Utilizing an impossible teleportation technique...
Kid aims to take the jewels!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Suzuki Jirokichi (72)
Suzuki Financial
Group Senior Advisor
Wrong, wrong!
A plan this bad isn't worth discussing!
Our opponent is the one who uses the
alias, "Magician Under the Moonlight"!
Do you really think such an immature scheme would...
Actually work?
Senior Advisor, you really should rest for a moment.
If you keep straining like this...
And, while I'm resting...
Can you come up with a plan to actually catch this guy?
Ah, no...
I don't need you to teach me what to do.
This time, I've acquired these as bait...
The legendary heels, Purple Nail...
To keep them from the hands of the demon, Kaitou Kid!
Even Maria Theresa of the Roman Empire's
monarch were captivated by these!
The glitter coming from the shoes...
They're 100-carat amethysts, aren't they?
However much they're worth is beside the point.
All we need is to just lure that guy in.
He sets his sights on only the biggest of jewels.
However, simply having this as bait does not mean he will be caught.
We have to be a step ahead of him.
Uhm, even though you say that...
The plan to have the heels inside a large block of ice...
I think it's a good one.
Even if it's Kid, he won't be able to take them easily.
Tell me this...
Where do you plan to display it, exactly?
Of course, it would be in a refrigerator that's completely sealed...
That's the problem!
If you go with this, the onlookers won't be able to see it!
I want to get my hands on him with everyone watching!
Not to mention that you would ruin the
legendary heels by putting them in ice!
You idiot!
Then, how about this plan?
We put the heels at the top of Touto Tower...
Surrounded by Suzuki Financial Group helicopters.
This way, even the onlookers can see what's going on at the scene.
Did you forget?
He has a set of white wings: his hang-glider.
The sky is his playground, making the
chances of us prevailing there too slim.
He'll win the game, take the heels...
And disappear into the moonlight once again.
Wait, wait...
Why does he always go with this back to the moon?
That's because it's night, right?
Thieves only work at nights.
No, that's not it.
Every time, he always seems to emerge when a full moon is at his back.
Perhaps he calculated it that way.
Maybe to be stylish.
Not to mention that his targets are usually on
the top floors of buildings and museums.
That puts him closer to the moon.
Kid is well-suited for high places.
I get it!
You still have it hidden!
To think it's being displayed in the middle of Ginza...
Isn't this just like telling Kid, "Come and take it"?
That's true.
Are you all right with this, Sonoko?
As for me, I'll be content so long as Kid-sama can appear and see me.
Sonoko...
Well, it seems Uncle Jirokichi is thinking about something, doesn't it?
Hey, you...
What are you planning?
Nakamori Ginzou (41)
Metropolitan Police Investigation
Division 2 Inspector
Is there a problem,
Inspector Nakamori?
There are problems
everywhere!
Having only these four guards protecting
the jewel in the middle of the street...
Kid will get this in the blink of an eye!
Then, what do you propose, Inspector?
How about we put it somewhere high, to make it harder to steal?
And that! That is a foolish idea!
I once thought that way as well, but that's
just how he has us play into his hands.
Each time we confront his white wings...
But he seems to be at his best when he takes to the sky.
And every time, every time he ends up
escaping because we can't combat that.
Then, the reason you're displaying it on the ground...
That's right!
It's to clip his wings!
He's not a bird —the second he hits the ground...
His hang-glider becomes impossible to use.
But...
While it's true he can't fly to safety...
If he were to mingle in this crowd...
We will diligently check every single one of them.
You knew that Kid is going to come
and called for a riot squad and fences, but they aren't here yet.
I sent him a challenge of my own in the morning newspaper.
It's likely that he's still deciding whether or not to show.
He'll come.
I know he'll come.
He'll come in the name of the "Magician Under the Moonlight."
And now, I'm going.
I have to adjust a few things for the plan with the staff.
Wait...
Hey, what do you mean by "plan"?
The hell is this?
It's a daring feat!
Kaitou Kid has appeared with his mysterious
white visage in the sky above Ginza plaza!
Kid-sama!
I'm here!
At the back of the hang-glider...
A propeller?
No way!
Kid-sama?
Where?
Kaitou...
Kid!
Amazing! He flew down from so high up!
Just like Superman!
No, he only blew up a dummy.
With that diverting everyone's attention, he snuck in from the crowd...
And hopped onto the exhibit's podium.
Kid-san, please comment for us!
Give us one line!
Kid-san!
Then, please relay this to Senior Advisor Suzuki Jirokichi for me.
"This time, it was a shot from the sea."
"My impoliteness was due to not having sufficient
time to prepare a notice, so please excuse me."
All right! Now!
It's a net!
The square is now sealed by a large net!
Uncle Jirokichi really went all out this time.
Around 20m high...
Since a balloon wouldn't take you that high, it's impossible to get out.
And now, even if he had a balloon...
The helicopters above would get him!
Naturally, it's impossible for him to mingle back into the crowd.
In the very second he crosses the net,
the staff will be able to root him out.
If you have the prize with you then, you're out.
If you drop them now, your theft has failed.
I'll be the victor either way!
Kid-sama, become me to escape!
You can also become me, Kid!
Your concern is unwarranted.
Something along these lines was expected.
And, what will you do now?
Well, you see, with my work done...
I'll be going home.
That —how will you do it?
By teleportation.
What'd he say!?
Teleportation!?
He'll use instant movement to escape?
By teleportation.
What'd he say!?
Teleportation!?
"Teleportation," right?
Amazing!
Kid-sama is great!
Are you really going to use teleportation, Kid-sama?
He said he'd use instant movement to escape?
This bastard is messing around again!
The situation has become more complex!
Kaitou Kid suddenly appeared and has
declared he will use teleportation!
Even with this encircling net, can Kid really escape?
What do we do, Senior Advisor?
What should we do?
Stop overreacting and look at this carefully!
He's surrounded on all four sides.
It'll be impossible for him to escape
with his hang-glider from the ground.
He's stuck on the ground!
What's this "teleportation"?
It's a lie!
The legendary heels, Purple Nail...
As you can see, I have laid my hands on them.
Damn you, Kid!
Don't move from that spot!
And, in ten seconds...
I'll travel through space and time.
Kid!
He vanished?
He's really vanished...
Is it really teleportation!?
No...
He used the smoke to slip into the crowd.
That hardly qualifies as instant movement...
The transmitter!
How is the transmitter attached to the heel?
Still in the intersection, heading toward the third district...
All right, get security over to the third district!
No, have them surround the net from all sides!
He's now a mouse in my trap.
Using such small-time tricks to beat me, you'll be caught in no time!
And where is he now?
Actually, he suddenly switched directions...
And is just running around in the intersection!
Kamaitachi was a trio of mythic monster
resembling weasals that encircled prey.
He's cutting through space like kamaitachi!
That's impossible!
How can he do that in the middle of such a crowd!?
Where has Kaitou Kid gone?
This is Kaitou Kid's mark.
Where'd it come from?
There's a transmitter on the upper left corner...
And on the back is...
Three...
I got Kid's card!
Hey, isn't there something written on the back?
Really?
Two...
One...
No way...
Impossible!
On the roof!?
It's Kid!
Kaitou Kid actually appeared on the roof we're on!
Amazing!
Amazing, Kid-sama!
Seriously...
He teleported all the way up there...
He's merely a substitute.
This one must have hid on the roof and waited to appear.
The true kid must still be in the crowd!
Don't let up until we have him!
I kindly ask that you relay this message to Suzuki Jirokichi.
"I have received your gift for safekeeping, but...
"Regrettably...
"This one is but an imitation.
"I will now return this one to you.
"Should it be convenient, I would be grateful if you
would meet me here once more tomorrow night.
"To share with her only one shoe would
serve only to hurt the fair lady's heart."
Then...
What?
He's aiming to steal it again tomorrow night?
Did Kid actually say that?
He proclaimed it in front of a TV camera.
Since he returned the fake...
I'll be displaying the real one at the same place tomorrow.
But, Uncle, why didn't you just make two fakes?
If I had done that, he'd have tossed
both away and escaped into the crowd.
It wouldn't be my victory then, would it?
Well, at least put a transmitter on it.
That way...
We'll know the route he took to get to the roof.
Of course, I did that...
But it fell off somewhere.
Is this that transmitter?
Uncle Kogorou picked it up in the intersection.
It was stuck in place with tape.
This really is the transmitter that was on the heel.
When did you find this?
About five or six seconds before he
teleported, it came down from above.
There were two other cards as well, right?
Going by what was on the back...
Three...
Two...
One—in that order.
As soon as the "one" card came, Kid appeared on the roof!
In other words...
He prepared the cards beforehand...
And quickly attached the transmitter that he found.
Which would mean Kid was already on
the roof when the cards appeared...
Someone would have noticed if he had
thrown out three cards while down there.
And all of that was done before he teleported to the roof...
Couldn't he have used one of the buildings' elevators?
Impossible.
I borrowed all four buildings in the intersection for the day...
And sealed every last exit to them all.
You "borrowed" them!?
Not to mention, even if he had found
his way into one of the buildings...
It would take at least a minute to get to the roof via elevator.
But see...
If we're only talking about the heel...
It would be possible to get that to the roof, right?
Kid has an accomplice, right?
With the accomplice on the roof and Kid on the ground, it can be done!
I see.
With a line extended to the ground...
The one on the ground can tie the line to the heel...
And the one on the roof just has to pull it up.
That would make people think it was teleportation!
With only the heel...
It would just take a few seconds to reel it in.
No, it wasn't solely the heel.
Hey, announce yourself as you come in!
Yes, sir.
I was one of the four security personnel chosen to guard the heels.
I believe you're aware that when Kid appeared...
The crowd swarmed us.
One of them had a hamburger.
When I tried to stop that person...
Unfortunately...
I got ketchup on my hand.
And, with the ketchup on my hand still...
I grabbed at Kid's cape when he was about to disappear.
And? Are you saying he escaped because the
ketchup on your hand made it hard to hold on?
No, actually...
Just look at this.
This one is but an imitation.
Isn't this the tape where he proclaimed
he'd be back for the other real one?
Right here!
Get it yet?
On the left side of the screen.
His cape was blown up by the wind.
A red handprint!
That's the mark the guard left when he grabbed him!
This isn't something even he could have anticipated.
In other words, the one on the ground...
And the Kaitou Kid on the roof are one in the same.
He actually teleported...
In 20 seconds, he scaled a building 30 meters high!
Did you see Kaitou Kid last night?
I saw it, I saw it!
It was on TV!
It was awesome, wasn't it?
Kid's instant movement.
Kid is gonna teleport again tonight, isn't he?
I'm really excited for it!
That's true!
After he disappeared from the intersection...
Who expected him to reappear on the roof of the next building?
You think that Kid might have psychic powers?
He doesn't have psychic powers.
He's nothing but a thief that uses magic.
Oh, you're saying you've solved his trick?
You were there, weren't you, Conan-kun?
At the intersection where Kid was.
I was there, but I don't know the trick...
There could have been two Kid's, right?
On the ground, there was one who disappeared after taking the heel...
And another one was waiting on the roof waiting to appear!
Amazing, Mitsuhiko-kun!
That's not it.
One of the guards protecting the treasure...
Left a handprint on Kid's cape before he disappeared...
That appeared when he was on the roof later.
He also gave the fake heel to the TV announcer...
Which was the exact one that Suzuki Jirokichi had made.
Maybe Kid...
Actually has a twin!
Maybe!
That would be awesome!
This is like talking to cows...
Well, he did create a miracle there.
In that intersection enclosed by a net...
He vanished in front of everyone.
And, within 20 seconds, appeared on the rooftop of a nearby building.
Yeah, it doesn't seem possible for a human...
But then again...
It proves you can't do it without taking 20 seconds.
I'll solve the 20 second mystery...
And unveil the instant movement trick this time.
You sound excited.
Like a child who's about to open a present they know is a toy.
But, you should be careful.
Your opponent is the famed moonlight magician, Kaitou Kid.
At night, when he appears in his conspicuous white costume...
He's prepared for anything.
Yeah.
I know.
Hey, hey, hey...
Why is the net already up before Kid has come along?
They won't even let the crowd in.
Now that you mention it, the TV crews' staff
were asked by Uncle Jirokichi to leave.
This old guy is doing what he wants now...
I appreciate your cooperation, Inspector Nakamori.
No, no.
With my staff teaming up with the police...
We'll take down this demon together!
That's how it should've been from the start...
Hey, Kaitou Kid!
If you can truly teleport, come on.
In this open situation, I will have the pleasure
of getting my hands around your neck.
It will be my honor to include my victory here
as the final chapter of my autobiography.
And make sure this will be on the front
page of every newspaper tomorrow!
Is this old guy still hung up on that?
I will now return this one to you.
Should it be convenient, I would be grateful if you
would meet me here once more tomorrow night.
Kid-sama!
Oh, isn't that the TV airing from last night?
Yeah, to pass time while we wait, I'm watching him from last night...
Kid-sama in his white suit!
Hey, there's something I've always wondered.
Why does Kid wear white?
As always, he appeared at night.
It's better if he wears black, to make him harder to see.
That's easy, isn't it?
It's because Kid is daring, and gorgeous!
Speaking of him, do you really think he'll show?
You idiot—Kid-sama has never failed to show after sending a notice.
What's that?
A parachute?
Good evening, everyone.
This is Kaitou Kid.
I regretfully have to say that, despite everyone gathering today...
I must cancel tonight's magic show.
What'd he say!?
Although I would love to display my magic...
The absence of an audience or TV camera gives
us only the most lonely of circumstances.
There's just no tension right now.
Then, everyone...
Have fun.
No way!
Kid isn't coming?
What the hell?
I even left my office early!
I'll get through the net myself!
That's it! Let us in!
Let us in! Let us in! Let us in! Let us in!
Let us in!
Inspector!
Someone saw a person with a strange gun.
What?
Then, Kid is in the crowd?
Search!
He's in there somewhere!
Right, just like last night...
He shot those cards before appearing on the roof.
Since he appeared 5 or 6 seconds afterward...
He must have shot them just before.
Since no one saw him...
He must have left the ground about 10 seconds after disappearing.
But, in 10 seconds, he can only cut through the crowd...
And hurry over to the designated building.
But, he was able to shoot three cards...
If he had gone into a building, he wouldn't
have been able to launch the cards.
Could he actually get to the roof while not being seen, without hiding?
Is that really possible?
Let us in! Let us in! Let us in! Let us in! Let us in!
Hey!
Didn't Kid say he wanted an audience?
Let's give him one!
Wait!
Inspector...
Are you OK?
Jeez...
Inspector, the TV crew on the roof are urging for us to let them film.
Ignore them! Ignore them all!
No, we have no choice here.
The most important person isn't here.
Who is there to catch?
To everyone watching:
We've just been given permsision to begin the broadcast again.
Right now, we, the Nichiuri TV staff...
Will station ourselves here on the rooftop where
Kaitou Kid teleported, just like last night.
We're broadcasting to you live.
No way, the TV program is going again.
Huh?
Where's Conan-kun?
He purposely gathered everyone inside the
net and got the TV broadcast going again...
Which means...
Without them, his trick doesn't work?
Don't move.
Move, and you're dead.
Kaitou Kid!
Don't move.
Move, and you're dead.
Kaitou Kid!
Fool.
Who would be scared of a toy?
I see you still have no sense of humor.
Who cares?
Say, Meitantei...
Do you know them?
Thurston's three principles.
Yeah.
The magician who prospered at the onset of the 20th century...
Howard Thurston.
He was also known for his three principles.
They are the three taboos that cannot be used in magic, right?
Exactly.
The first: A magician cannot give away the secrets of the trade.
I shouldn't have to say much on that.
The second: Prior to performing magic...
You must not reveal what is to happen next.
If the shock factor is lessened, so is the excitement.
And, the third:
You cannot perform the same trick twice with one audience.
If performed only once...
The magic leaves a strong impression.
It will then blossom into a beautiful miracle in their hearts.
But, when used twice, rather than the audience enjoying the magic...
They focus on unravelling the trick.
As such, the chance of it being unveiled is high.
I see.
In other words...
You're willing to risk the taboo, and so long as it goes unrevealed...
It will remain the greatest trick of all, right?
That's right.
There you are, Conan-kun.
You can't keep straying off.
He escaped into the crowd...
My, it seems the audience has become quite lively.
The curtain on the show will raise soon!
Please enjoy it!
Kid is coming!
This atmosphere makes it seem like he's already taken it.
Well, if I, Detective Mouri Kogorou, directly advise them...
I could catch a thief or two myself.
ino naka no kawazu
Uncle, you're one of the people that gets called a "frog in a well."
"Frog in a well"?
ino naka no
"in a well"...
Now, before Kid arrives...
Let's review the VTR from last night when he teleported.
Kaitou Kid used his hang-glider to get to us at Ginza...
And, in a puff of smoke, appeared.
It's so exciting!
In a flash, he was atop the display.
And then, the legendary heels, Purple
Nail, were in the hands of Kaitou Kid.
But, Suzuki Jirokichi wasn't done.
The junction he had made into a square...
Had suddenly been sealed off by a net.
Osaka
Even though escaping seemed impossible...
Kaitou Kid's facial expression remained unchanged.
He proclaimed he would escape via teleportation.
That is, moving from one place to another instantly.
Hey, Hattori here.
Oh, it's Ohtaki-han.
How's it going?
We're just watching TV.
You need my help for a case?
Centipede?
Among the smoke, Kaitou Kid disappeared from the display.
- About 20 seconds later, and 30 feet up...
- Let me see that for a second!
He appeared on the roof of a department store.
It's a miracle!
This is...
But, where will Kid teleport tonight?
Well, it's hard to say, since he might
avoid the building from yesterday...
Maybe up in that helicopter!
How could he?
So, should we go?
I know where Kaitou Kid will teleport.
For real?
Where is it, Conan-kun?
Didn't Sonoko-neechan just say it?
He must be on one of those helicopters.
No way!
Remember, there was a case when he was walking in mid-air, right?
The trick then was that Kid had an accomplice
piloting the helicopter he was hanging from, right?
That's why it's the same as last night's instant movement.
They have Kid hanging in the middle of the sky...
And then drop him off on the roof of the department store.
That's how it looks like teleporting, right?
You're stupid! That's impossible!
After what happened last time, Uncle Jirokichi
personally checked everyone piloting the helicopters.
Not to mention that the helicopters up there
today are with the police, unlike yesterday.
Kid's accomplice would have a hard time getting in with them.
Get a good look over there!
There's a huge crowd around the heel display!
This square has been surrounded by more than 200 people.
If Kid were to be hanging in the air...
Everyone on the ground would see him!
Well, brats have such shallow intelligence.
Sorry, but I agree with Sonoko's reasoning.
I see...
I thought this was a great idea.
I guess I'll have to think it through again.
Now, night has finally come!
The calls for Kid are rising!
Kid will be returning tonight...
To take what is on display in the middle of the
intersection, the other of the legendary heels...
Purple Nail!
Will he be able to perform his miraculous
instant movement trick again tonight?
It's Kaitou Kid!
Kaitou Kid has appeared!
Kid-sama really came!
Damn you, Kid! I'll get you...
Hold it, Inspector Nakamori.
Look at the propeller carefully.
It's a dummy!
It's the same as last night, with the exploding dummy...
Before he lands on the display.
He must be waiting in the crowd for
the perfect moment to jump up there!
Kaitou Kid!
I apologize for the delay.
Now, just as before...
My body will pass through space and time...
With absolute skill.
Hey, what are you doing?
Get him now!
I invite you to take hold!
However...
Do make sure you don't let go.
That's because, when I do teleport, I may shake you loose...
And leave you to wander between the void of time and space.
What's there to fear? He just got in the crowd!
He's still here!
Start looking!
Hey, did Kid teleport?
I can't see—we'll have to get closer.
All right, it's OK here.
Get moving.
Where will Kid-sama teleport to tonight?
Huh?
Where did Conan-kun go?
And now, the first shot...
Kid's card?
No way!
Three...
Two...
One...
Zero.
Unfortunately, the magic show tonight is a free one.
The reward is zero...
Magician Under the Moonlight.
Unfortunately, the magic show tonight is a free one.
The reward is zero...
Magician Under the Moonlight.
Drop the weight! Hurry!
What's that?
It looks like a sand bag, but...
Where'd it come from?
The trick behind the instant movement is simple.
It's nothing more than utilizing the pulley concept.
First, your accomplice sneaks in with the TV staff...
And attaches two pulleys to the railing here.
You then take the lowered wire and
link up through the prepared hooks...
That goes from the roof to the bottom.
This completely connects the two of you.
Next, you disappear from the display, clear the crowd...
Run up to the building...
And attach the hook to yourself.
Then you just have to wait for your accomplice to take the jump.
A weight is used to ensure your accomplice is heavier than you...
Which allows you to use the pulley to quickly reach the roof...
And appear as if you teleported.
Since the TV staff are engaged with their broadcast...
They wouldn't notice if one of them quietly slipped over the railing.
Naturally, the cheering from the crowd
easily masks the sound of the pulley.
The main issue here is ensuring that two people
going up and down isn't seen by the crowd.
Even though your accomplice can easily
get down by going under the banner...
You need to direct everyone's attention away from
the building, which is why you fire off the cards.
This prevents you from getting behind it.
What told me this was the news ticker.
So long as you match the words from bottom to top...
The crowd's eyes can be deceived.
I see.
So your deduction that I overheard through the
bug was a fake, meant to take me by surprise...
Since you had already discovered the trick via the news ticker.
It was only when I saw it on last night's news.
You luckily appeared in front of the ticker when it said...
daisuki na josei dai boshuu
"Recruiting women that you like the most."
But, with just "you like" to go on, it isn't easy to understand.
That's why the trick is in the reading.
daisuki inu suki
It's not "you like" but "like dogs."
inu
You were covering up the accent in the word "dog".
Right —the black clothes.
I finally understand...
Why you always appear in that eye-catching white costume.
It isn't to exhibit your fearlessness.
It's just easier to hide.
No matter who, if something white disappears before their eyes...
They'll keep looking for something white.
Switching from white to black...
Serves only to deceive the eyes.
All the same, imagine if something
white were to appear in a dark place.
It's mysterious, isn't it?
Hey, isn't that Kid!?
Amazing! He's standing on the side of that building!
The site of Kaitou Kid's teleportation...
Is this display screen!
Ignoring gravity, he's standing straight up on the wall!
No way!
For real?
Kid-sama is amazing!
Well, you should give up.
If you come up, you may make it out...
But you would be delivering your accomplice to the police.
If it's the opposite, you'll be the one that's out.
Kid!
Don't think about escaping!
Then, how about the middle?
The middle?
Grab on!
He was able to get over the net...
Given that these aren't quite
the jewels I was after,
I relinquish them to you.
- Kaitou Kid
That guy...
You did well last night, Conan-kun.
It's impressive that you got into that building.
I'm a kid—I just snuck in.
Oh, and I may have used a tranquilizer on the guard...
It's in the morning news, huh?
"Suzuki Jirokichi's Great Victory."
I guess even this old man can finally
fluff his pillows and sleep well for once.
They even put a huge picture of him in here.
That's up for debate...
My face is almost not in it...