Torada House
Death bu massive hemorrhaging resulting
from trauma along the whole body.
Did he die from a fall?
That's right, my only heir and son, Yoshirou was...
Torada Naonobu (61)
Head of the Torada Family
Struck by the ruthless hand of the demons who
bear resentment against our Torada family.
You mean somebody shoved him off from some high place?
No, it was a tornado.
My son got caught in a tornado.
He was sucked up into the air and thrown
down to his death in a rocky area.
A tornado?
Then he wasn't murdered by someone?
Look closely, Mouri-dono.
Don't you see something in the pool of blood?
You can see it if you look very carefully.
Something that shouldn't be there.
A centipede!
That centipede corpse appears to have been placed there
after it had been stepped on, but before the blood was dry.
In other words, that means some person...
Despite finding my son in that condition...
Didn't call for help, but, as if saying he deserved what he got...
Torada Tatsue (58)
Naonobu's Wife
Put that repulsive insect next to to him and left him to die.
But maybe it was a centipede corpse that somebody had stepped on...
And the wind of the tornado blew it there by coincidence.
Shigetsugu, who was the one who found the body, said this to us:
"There aren't any centipedes like that in the area.
"My brother was left here to die."
Brother?
Didn't you say earlier that the deceased was your only heir?
A moron like him who spends all his time
on some imaginary buried treasure.
I no longer consider him to be my son.
And so, you have an idea who the culprit was, don't you?
You said someone resented you.
Conan-kun!
Yes, the ones who have been feuding with our Torada
family for countless years —
the Tatsuo family.
The fiend who left my son to die must be one of them.
The curtain rises on a mysterious new era.
The Monday 7:00 reasoning show.
Shingen's treasure! The riddle of the Fuurinkazan!
The sound of Ran and Kazuha's screams!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Tatsuo House
So your son Koiji-san was not only tied up but buried in the ground.
And then he was beaten to death by being
repeatedly stuck in the head with a blunt weapon.
On top of that, before his blood had dried...
Someone placed the corpse of a centipede
next to him and made their escape.
Jeez, this was really cruel.
So, what did the police say?
As for them, all they do is repeat the same response.
Tatsuo Tamefumi (56)
Head of the Tatsuo Family
We're still investigating, we're still investigating,
That's why I called for you, Hattori-kun.
I had my old friend Otaki-kun from the Osaka police ask you.
But, Otaki-han told me it seems you've
already figured out the culprit's motive.
Ah, well, as for the motive...
It was revenge!
Thinking that the death of their own son
was the fault of our Tatsuo family...
They murdered Kouji in thoughtless retaliation.
Tatsuo Shigeyo (78)
Tamefumi's Mother
Someone from the Torada family, that is.
Mother, we still don't know if that's true.
The way he was murdered was so malicious, how
can there be any doubt it was them who did it!
And, who was it that found the body?
It was my other son, Akira.
He discovered it on the way home
from this horseback archery practice.
Horseback archery is where you shoot with a
bow and arrow while riding on a horse, isn't it?
Yeah, Akira is the top practitioner of it in our village.
Whenever we have our festival, he always demonstrates the technique.
Where is Akira-san now?
Every one a bullseye! I knew you could do it, Akira-san.
Tatsuo Akira (32)
Tamefumi's Son
Yeah, I guess with this I'll get to be the horseback
archery bowman at the next festival too.
Tatsuo Ayaka (27)
Akira's Wife
If that happens, it will be the 6th year in a row.
They should just declare you to be the
horseback archery bowman already.
No, no. I haven't reached my senpai's level yet.
Excuse me. Are you Akira-san?
Ah, yes.
I'm Mouri Kogoro, a detective from Tokyo.
If it's all right with you, I'd like to ask you about the
situation when you discovered Kouji-san's body.
Uh, I guess I don't mind.
Is there a reason that would make it difficult to answer?
Ah, no, it's just that someone asked
me the exact same thing a bit ago.
A boy detective with an Osaka accent.
An Osaka accent?
Boy detective?
It couldn't be!
Yeah, I was the one who found my brother Yoshirou's body.
Torada Shigetsugu (31)
Naonobu's Son
It's true that there was the corpse of a centipede next to the body.
But why a centipede?
I don't know.
Does either your Torada family or the Tatsuo family...
Have any sort of connection with centipedes?
There's no real connection, but...
I do remember seeing a drawing of a centipede at the festival.
Festival?
At that festival where they have the horseback archery...
The men of the village have a make-believe battle.
That's when they put on that armor.
Well, you can call it armor, but it's just a fairly lightweight
thing made out of plastic that the village provides.
I have the feeling that I've seen it somewhere
at that festival, the picture of a centipede.
Where was it? Was it drawn on a chest protector or something?
If it was a dragonfly, I think there was a warlord
during the Sengoku who had one on his helmet.
Speaking of warlords, there was a detective who
came by and asked the same questions as you two.
A detective?
Yeah, he was a detective from Tokyo...
His family name was the same as one of those warlords.
Could it have been Mouri?
Right! Mouri like in Mouri Motonari.
Ran-chan's father!
In that case, was there a little boy with glasses there too?
Yeah, he was asking about the incident
more diligently than the detective.
Heh, it's Kudo.
That reminds me, Akira-san was telling us that a
person died six years ago from a strange accident.
Is that true?
Yeah, the deceased was the one selected to be our horseback
archery bowman at the festival up until that year, Kai Kuroto-san.
What I heard was that he fell off a cliff while practicing.
Who would know more information about that?
Maybe my late brother's wife, Yui-san.
She was the one who found the body.
Where would she be now?
Do you see those stables behind the fence?
She might be taking care of the horses around this time.
It's Kudo.
Kudo's been seduced here by the scent of this case too.
This shows what I've always thought, that you and I
are two of a kind, like badgers from the same hole.
C'mon, give me a break!
I'm still trying to get over the death of my husband!
I don't want to try to remember
something that happened six years ago!
Oh? Now you're
cooking!
Please leave already!
Hey! You'll have to forgive me for being so...
What is it, kid?
Ah, well...
Do you know a detective with swept-back hair,
a tiny mustache, and a stupid-looking face?
By swept-back hair, tiny mustache, and stupid-looking face...
Do you mean mine?
Ah, no, not at all...
Kazuha-chan! Hattori-kun! It's been a longtime!
Ran-chan! Have you been doing good?
Yeah.
Heh, I knew it'd be him.
And?
Who's this evil-looking man?
Well, I don't know.
I'm the one in charge of this case...
Yamato Kansuke (35)
Nagano Prefectural
Police Detective
Yamato Kansuke of the Nagano prefectural police.
A police detective.
I was just asking this lady some questions.
OK, ma'am, I'll ask you one more time.
Was that thing there six years ago?
Or wasn't it?
Didn't I just say I wasn't in the mood to answer you now?
People's lives are at stake!
You'll answer me without any arguments!
I got it.
Torada Yui (29)
Yoshirou's Wife
There wasn't any centipede corpse near the body.
There was just the dead horse in a pile along with his emaciated body.
I see.
Sorry to have bothered you.
Hey, wait a second.
What's the meaning behind those centipedes?
I still can't say for sure.
But if we don't figure out this critical point soon...
It's inevitable that we'll find ourselves rolling in dead bodies.
Just like on the battlefields of the Sengoku wars.
Now for what these two successive cases share in common...
The people who discovered the bodies
were both related to victims and...
For some unknown reason, the corpses of
centipedes were placed next to the bodies.
The thing that's bothering me is the incident six years
ago where, while practicing his horseback archery...
Kai Kuroto-san fell to his death from a cliff along with his horse.
I'd say that was just an accident.
It probably doesn't have anything to do with these two incidents.
Yeah, since there were no centipedes or anything next to his corpse.
That is if we believe Torada Yui-san's story.
Yeah.
There wasn't anything there like a centipede, but...
As for the issue of someone leaving him there to die...
It might just be the same as the first incident where my husband died.
Someone left him to die?
Didn't you say he died instantly when he fell from the cliff?
I did mention it' didn't I? That his corpse was emaciated?
It's true that when he fell from the cliff...
He sustained serious injuries when his
body struck the trees and the rocks.
His white undershirt became covered in blood.
It even became pitch black due to oxidation, but...
He starved to death.
Starved to death?
Exactly.
His hip had been broken and he couldn't stand up.
On that day, the sun didn't strike the place where he fell.
It was right below the cliff, where people wouldn't normally pass by.
When I discovered him, almost a week had passed.
A week?
Even though it wasn't just him and his horse had fallen there too...
Nobody found them?
Was there a proper search?
We searched!
Both the police and the villagers even gave up their sleeping time!
Officer Kai was loved by everyone in the village!
Officer?
He was a policeman?
Yeah. He worked at the village police box.
He had a strong sense of justice, and he was kind and gentle.
You couldn't find anyone in the village
who had anything bad to say about him.
That's why, when he disappeared, the
whole village looked for him frantically!
Despite that, how could it take a week to find him?
It was the leaves.
The leaves?
Unfortunately, he'd been buried in leaves.
He was hidden under them until the wind blew them off.
My brother Yoshirou's body had fallen in a
rocky area where the visibility was good...
So he was discovered easily.
Did everyone in the village look for him right away then too?
No...
We started searching when it was almost dawn
and we realized my brother hadn't come back home.
Started searching?
You mean you didn't discover my husband's body
by chance on the way to that hole of yours?
Is that what happened?
That hole?
It's just a hobby.
I pretend I'm hunting for treasure.
You call that a hobby?
As if it wasn't enough that you don't work,
you're obsessed over something like that.
You bring shame on the Torada family!
Please be practical, Shigetsugu-san.
You're the only heir left to our family.
And so, have you discovered anything, Mouri-dono?
No, I've only found that next to the body
of Kouji-san from the Tatsuo family...
The corpse of a centipede had been placed, just like with Yoshirou-san.
Speaking of Kouji-san...
He used to have a lot of private conversations
with my husband before he died.
Private conversations?
I think he would say "Let's go"
or "Let's not go" or something.
Yeah, I heard him say that too.
He said they should go together and see that
one-eyed detective, Yamato, before too long.
And that since it might be a big deal,
would he please resolve himself to it.
What's that?
Did you ask what they were going to him for?
No, he just said he couldn't say yet.
Well, we should go check with the Tatsuo
family; they might know something.
Yeah, let's strike while the iron is hot.
In that case, we'll head over there for a bit and come back.
Kazuha, you and she can stay and mind the store.
We can come with you.
Idiot, if you come you'll just be in the way.
They planned to go to the police?
My son Kouji-kun along with Yoshirou-kun from the Torada family?
Yes. You didn't hear anything about this from your son?
That's right, nothing at all.
It's just that, when Yoshirou kun died, it seemed
like he became frightened of something.
Frightened?
That's right. Even during meals he would
be withdrawn and mutter to himself.
"Next time it might be my turn to be killed."
"To killed by the curse."
C-Curse?
Don't you know?
The curse of the Torada family who have
hated our Tatsuo family for generations!
Say, why are their family and yours on such bad terms?
That's because...
A long time ago...
Wait, what was it again?
Hey...
Old lady...
Ever since I was a child I've heard that the Torada family hates us...
But I've forgotten why.
I'm sure that's what the people from the Torada family think too.
But now those chains are falling away.
Ayaka and I have gotten along well with
Yoshirou and Shigetsugu from the Torada family.
But, before they died, those two said
they were going to go to the police.
Could that have been in connection
with that policeman, Kai's, accident?
That was just an accident.
After practicing his horse archery...
He must have been exhausted and fallen from the cliff.
He missed a target at the festival that year and was upset about it.
Hey, haven't you given that up yet, Ayaka?
But that's what everyone said.
Maybe due to the shock of having missed...
He jumped off the cliff on his own.
Don't people miss sometimes?
Yes, on occasion.
But Kai-san never missed, not even once.
At least not until the last shot at that year's festival.
That man would never have committed suicide.
A minor embarrassment at the festival...
He wasn't some fool who would abandon the villagers
and escape into the other world over something like that.
What? You're staying over there tonight?
Then you're not coming back, Heiji?
Yeah, the rain's becoming really nasty.
And it's dangerous to take the mountain roads at night.
And so, that's how it is.
Don't sleep with your belly button showing.
Hey, watch it, Heiji!
He hung up.
What do you think, Kudo?
Did you figure something out?
No, nothing yet.
I'm still stuck on what Kouji-san was muttering before he was killed.
"Next time it might be my turn—"
It that was true, then these are serial murders.
And what's more, there may be more victims to come.
Hey, Ran-chan.
Ran-chan!
Did you hear a strange noise?
I can't hear anything except the rain and the thunder.
Listen, you can hear that noise alongside them.
It sounds like the floor creaking.
I said I'm telling you the truth!
Right? Ran-chan saw it too!
Yeah, it wasn't a dream!
But still...
Kazuha, what's going on?
Ah, Heiji! I really saw it!
Saw what?
I thought I saw it during the lightning flashes last night...
It was standing right there on the other side of the shoji screen!
It was an armored...
Fugitive warrior!
A fugitive warrior?
Could it possibly have been the armor from
Shigetsugu's room that's used for the festival?
It wasn't!
That's because there was a long
fringe of hair attached to the helmet.
That's like the Suwa-style helmets used by Takeda Shingen.
If it's Takeda, it could be one of
Takeda's "Akazomae." (red armored warriors)
Say, that armor, was it red?
I don't know. I could only see the silhouette.
NO!
What? Ayaka locked herself in the restroom and won't come out?
Just after someone mentioned the red armor of Takeda Shingen?
Hey, Aya-chan!
Hurry and come get her, she's being a bother!
Aya-chan! Aya-chan!
What's the meaning of this?
She's not here, is she? My daughter-in-law isn't here!
That's strange.
I'm sure she was here until just a moment ago.
She asked us to leave her alone for a while, so we went away.
She ought to still be in the area, so let's all split up and search for her.
OK, I'll use my scooter.
I'll go in my car.
Akira-san, Yui-san, and I can ride the horses.
Everyone else will go by foot!
Aya-chan!
Where are you?
Ayaka-san!
Are you here?
Ayaka! Ayaka!
Answer us!
Aya-chan!
Ayaka!
Where are you?
If only I had been faster...
This wouldn't have happened.
Conan-kun, you shouldn't be—
What is it?
Has something happened?
Ayaka-san's... Ayaka-san's...
Ayaka?
Ayaka!
Stay back!
From here on, this place is under police jurisdiction!
You all need to stay back!
What's this?
Hey, you there, woman on the black horse...
Didn't you hear me?
Ah, yes.
Hey!
What on earth?
What's happened?
It's no good.
Hey, Uehara, tell me the time.
Ah, right.
8:59.
Sorry, it's an old habit.
No problem.
An old...
Habit?
It's me.
There's been an incident in the woods near the Torada mansion.
Bring the forensics team here immediately.
Yeah, that's right. There's been another serial murder.
Serial murder?
Exactly. The time Torada Yoshirou was left to die
after bring seriously injured by the tornado...
That was the first incident!
The time Tatsuo Kouji was tied up, buried
in the ground, and beaten to death...
That was the second incident.
Just like what happened in those two incidents...
Just underneath where Tatsuo Ayaka is suspended...
Is the corpse of a centipede!
What?
Moreover...
In the area around the body, on top of
the ground that's muddy from the rain...
Right now, there are only my footprints and the marks of my cane.
Furthermore, on this tree she was hung from after it rained...
There is absolutely no trace of anyone having climbed it.
This is an...
Impossible...
An impossible crime, huh?
An impossible crime?
Well, it could also be the case that your footprints
where here already before you brought down the body.
Is that right? Mr. Detective who arrived here awfully quickly?
When I went to the Torada house, they told me everyone
had gone to the woods to search for Tatsuo Ayaka.
So I just came here.
But wasn't your timing a little too good?
Almost like you invited Ayaka san out here by calling
her cellphone while she was in the restroom...
Put her to sleep, and after making it look like a suicide...
Went on to the Torada house, acting all innocent.
I don't think that's it.
I saw the ground before the detective took Ayaka-san down, but...
There were no footprints or cane marks.
Putting that aside, I heard that before she locked
herself in the restroom, she'd been acting strangely.
Did something happen?
Last night, on the other side of the shoji screen
from the room where we were sleeping...
We saw the silhouette of an armored warrior.
When we said it looked like it was wearing a Suwa-style helmet...
Suddenly Ayaka-san got all scared.
It's the curse.
The murderous curse caused by provoking Lord Shingen's wrath.
That centipede corpse is the clear evidence.
What does a centipede have to do with Takeda Shingen?
You don't know?
Lord Shingen called the people who worked as
runners on the battlefield "The Centipedes."
They would carry centipede flags at their backs.
That's it!
I knew I'd seen a picture of a centipede somewhere before.
I saw someone wearing that flag during the festival competition.
How can you be going treasure hunting
without even knowing something like that?
Then you mean that treasure you
mentioned is really Takeda Shingen's?
Yeah, Shingen's hidden gold mine.
Even since he found some books and maps
in our cellar that seemed to refer to it...
Shigetsugu-san's been crazy about it.
Those two who died earlier along with Ayaka-san...
And even Tatsuo Akira-san here all got dragged into it.
We weren't doing it for selfish reasons.
We thought if we really found it, it would help revitalize the village.
But still, why did Ayaka have to be cursed too?
All she did was bring refreshments for us at the mine.
It's not a curse.
This is a full-fledged murder case.
It's just like the detective with the mustache said.
Tatsuo Ayaka had her cellphone here in her waist pouch.
While she was secluding herself in the restroom...
She was fooled into coming out by the serial murderer.
So, if you don't want to us to be finding your corpse...
Don't go wandering around alone.
Especially you two who have been searching for buried gold.
Really? That armored warrior was really standing right here?
Yeah, but he left right away though.
Why didn't you just open up the shoji
screen and flatten him with your karate?
Because! I thought it was a ghost so it wouldn't have a real body!
When you're opponent is a ghost, stuff like karate
and aikido will just pass right through them.
Idiot, there's no such thing as ghosts in this—
You know what this is, don't you?
It's looks like unraveled threads of the vinyl cord that
you sometimes use on packages, but so what?
Several pieces of it had fallen along the corridor and on the ground.
I see.
If these thin vinyl strings were bunched
together and attached to the helmet...
Then the silhouette as seen through the shoji screen would
look like the Suwa-style helmets of Takeda Shingen.
Then Shigetsugu san, who has that armor used
in the festival in his room, is the culprit?
No. Look over there.
Those are the footprints from an unusual sandal.
They continue right up to the back gate.
Then some outsider must have sneaked in and taken the
armor and used it to make that silhouette of Shingen.
Or, someone from this house made those sandal
prints on purpose to make it look that way.
Come to think of it, Shigetsugu-san said something earlier.
He said, "Speaking of armor, they
have one at Akira-san's house too."
There's some armor at the other house too?
Yeah.
He said the Tatsuo family had a really magnificent one.
In that case, we'll go over to the Tatsuo house.
Kazuha, you two stay here with the old man.
I'm sure you already know this, but...
Keep your eyes on Shigetsugu-san, since he
was one of those looking for the buried gold.
I'd do that without you telling me.
Later.
Jeez!
We've been left behind again.
I'm sure it's because he doesn't want to put you at risk, Kazuha-chan.
You know, how we're always experiencing dangerous
situations and being targeted by criminals.
Is that so?
Yeah, and after keeping you in suspense, he's going to
tell you the real story with a prideful look on his face.
Shin'ichi does that too.
Ah, but in Shin'ichi's case, it's not because he likes me or anything.
"Be as swift as the wind."
You like him, don't you? That dark-skinned boy?
Ah, well...
It's OK to sit yourself down like a mountain and wait patiently.
But while your feelings are hot, another
way is to act swiftly, like the wind.
If you grow careless, before you can tell him your feelings,
the other person might vanish right before your eyes.
Because there are some things that can't be brought back.
Just like in my case.
It's strange. It's strange, Kudo.
Yeah, that thing in Ayaka-san's mouth.
That gag.
It was probably put on her to block her voice, but...
If you wanted to make it seem like she committed
suicide because she was afraid of Shingen's curse...
You'd normally take it off.
That means there was some reason it couldn't be taken off...
Or possibly it was left there on purpose.
But if it was on purpose, why would the
culprit have done something like that?
After all, she couldn't talk after she was dead, right?
Maybe it was a threat directed at someone.
Meaning don't say anything and keep quiet.
This is a really impressive suit of armor.
Does the fact that it's red mean is from
Takeda's "Akazonae"? (red armored warriors)
Yeah.
Is your family related to Takeda or something?
No, my mother and I were big fans of Lord Shingen, you see.
We spent a lot of money to get this.
Both my late son Kouji-kun and Yoshirou-kun from the Torada family...
They really liked Shingen too.
They would come here often to look at it.
My other son, Akira, wasn't like that though.
Say, even though they're both your sons, why do say "kun" when you
mention Kouji-san, but you refer to Akira san without an honorific?
Kouji-kun was the husband of my daughter, who was born after Akira.
He took our family name.
You see, my daughter died in a traffic accident quite a long time ago...
And before they got married, Kouji-kun was Akira's classmate.
He used to come over to our house a lot, and
so just like in those days, I still use "kun."
Speaking of classmates...
Both Yoshirou-kun and Shigetsugu-kun from
the Torada family were Akira's classmates too.
Yoshirou-san and Shigetsugu-san were
classmates even though they were brothers?
Ah, no. Yoshirou-kun was the son of the elder sister
of Naonobu-san, the head of the Torada family.
I heard that his sister and her husband both died at an early age,
so he adopted him and raised them just like natural brothers.
Then that means that the three people who've died...
Aren't related by blood to either the
Torada family or to the Tatsuo family?
Yeah, and Ayaka-san was Akira's wife also.
Say, that banner behind the armor...
Yeah.
That's a replica.
Can you read it, little boy?
Be as quiet as the wind.
Be as quiet as the forest.
Attack as fiercely as the fire.
Be immovable like the mountain.
That's the art of war as advocated a long time ago by Sun Tzu.
That's it!
Yoshirou-san, who as seriously injured
by the tornado and left to die was...
The wind.
Kouji-san, who was tied up, buried in dirt piled
up like a mountain, and beaten to death was...
The mountain.
Ayaka-san, who was left gagged in the middle
of the woods suspended from a tree was...
The forest.
You don't mean...
Yeah, our culprit is patterning himself after Takeda Shingen.
Making use of the strategy that he preferred...
The Fuurinkazan.
Fuurinkazan?
The culprit is patterning their crimes based on that?
That's right.
Try and think back carefully about those three incidents in succession.
Start with the first case, where Torada Yoshirou-san
was seriously injured by the tornado and left to die.
The tornado is the "wind."
In order words, the "wind" from "Be as swift as the wind."
Next is the second case where Tatsuo Kouji-san was
tied up, buried in the ground, and beaten to death.
That he was tied up and unable to move after being
buried in dirt piled like a mountain refers to...
The "mountain" from "Be immovable like the mountain."
And earlier, the third case where Tatsuo Ayaka-san
was killed in the middle of the woods.
The meaning behind the gag preventing her
from speaking and keeping her quiet was...
I see now. The "forest" from "Be as quiet as the forest."
Yeah, it looks like our serial murderer is
pretty obsessed with Takeda Shingen.
But why Takeda Shingen?
Is it to prevent them from digging up Shingen's buried gold after all?
Who knows.
There is one thing we do know now though.
There is still the "fire" (ka) character remaining in "Fuurinkazan."
That means we can be certain that the culprit
is planning to take one other person's life.
Then, it could be the next target was one of those searching
for the buried gold along with the three people who've died.
Shigetsugu-san or Akira-san?
Yeah, there's a high probability.
Still, it's possible that it just looks like that
and they may be targeting someone else.
Well, at any rate, we'll be keeping watch here.
You keep your eyes on the people
over there, particularly Shigetsugu-san.
Uh, right.
Say, Ran-chan. What does that mean, that "Fuurinkazan?"
I don't know. I've seen it used on TV and in the movies though.
What? You don't know?
Be as swift as the wind, be as silent as the forest, attack
as fiercely as the fire, be immovable like the mountain.
It's one of the strategies that the great
military strategist Sun Tzu conceived.
When an army moves, they are as swift as the wind.
When they wait, they are as silent as the forest.
When they attack, they are as fierce as fire.
When they decide to defend, they are immovable like a mountain.
That's what Takeda Shingen, reputed to be the strongest
leader during the Sengoku, had written on his banners.
Then earlier...
That's what Yui-san was saying.
It's OK to sit yourself down like a mountain and wait patiently.
But while your feelings are hot, another
way is to act swiftly, like the wind.
Ah, I see. The "Fuurinkazan" strategy can be applied to love too.
So you're here.
If you practice when you're upset over your wife's death...
You won't be able to concentrate.
No, it's just that the festival is approaching,
and I can't neglect my training.
I'm putting all of my effort into being the horseback archery bowman.
That's what I swore to do at the grave of my senpai, Kai.
That's what my wife, Ayaka, would have wanted too.
However, the reason I missed the target wasn't because I'm upset.
Look, that shows the target was shifted a bit, doesn't it?
It's true.
Who would so something strange like that?
There's some people there behind the trees.
Hey, what are you doing? Wait!
Hey!
They were probably guys from the neighboring village.
They were trying to make me lose my self confidence.
Why so?
Because the honor of their village is at stake.
The festival is an event that the two villages
have conducted together for generations.
Only one person becomes the bowman for the horseback archery
contest, which is the number one highlight of the festival.
That is to say, if they can ruin Akira san, the representative
of our village who won in the preliminary contest...
The bowman from the other village will become the star of the festival.
They could brag about it for a whole year.
If you count starting with Kai-san, for more than 10 years the
bowman for the festival has been someone from our village.
What happens during the preliminary contest?
Ten targets are setup at even intervals on the
grounds of the shrine, and we compete by hit ratio.
We keep on doing it until a winner is decided.
Exactly.
Six years ago, you and Kai-san had both hit all the targets.
Since it was getting dark, the match was suspended until the next day.
That's how it was left when Kai-san disappeared.
And one week later I discovered his body.
Yeah.
If we had held the match on the following day, I would have lost.
When compared to my senpai, who after that tie match, said
he was going to sweat it out a bit more at practice, I was...
So exhausted that I couldn't move.
He went to practice even though it was already getting dark?
Yeah.
As long as he knew the positions of the targets.
he could have done it with his eyes closed.
But he missed the target at his last festival, didn't he?
That was an underhanded trick perpetrated
by the people from the neighboring town.
They shifted the position of the target
on purpose in order to embarrass him.
Not knowing that, my father-in-law
Naonobu got blazing mad at Kai-san.
You've sullied my honor!
What did he mean, sullied?
It seems my father in law Naonobu was the one
who taught Officer Kai horseback archery.
Also, my grandmother Shigeyo happened to be there...
And quarreled with him then.
Someone like you who's never once been chosen as the
bowman for the festival shouldn't act like you're a master.
In some way or another, everyone seems
to have some connection to that Kai guy.
Exactly.
And that makes all of them suspects in these serial murders.
I examined the area surrounding the place where Tatsuo
Ayaka-san's body was discovered carefully, but...
Except for the footprints of those who came
rushing there, the hoof marks from the horses...
And the tracks of the tires from the
scooter and the car, there was nothing.
In short, if we exclude you guys from the outside, the
only ones who could feasibly be the culprit are...
Those from the Torada family: Naonobu, Tatsue, Shigetsugu, and Yui.
Or those from the Tatsuo family: Shigeyo,
Tamefumi, and Akira. Only those seven people.
There are eight people.
Your footprints and the marks from your
cane were there too, right, Detective?
Yeah, you can include me if you want.
Madam, you came here to get that horse, didn't you?
In that case, lead your dark bay back to the Torada house right away.
As for you, take these kids with you and return to the Tatsuo house.
When you return, tell this to the people in the house:
"The culprit is one of you.
"Until I, Kansuke, arrive to take them away, they should stay
quietly in their houses and recite a prayer to the Buddha."
Why don't you call me by my name like you did in the old days...
Kan-chan.
Sorry, but as for now, you're no longer my childhood friend Yui.
Or my junior officer Uehara either.
You're just the wife of a victim.
Just one of my suspects.
What did he mean by "junior officer?"
She's a former police officer?
That's what I'm telling you!
I have no memory of anyone who might be intending to kill me.
Excuse me, but what is it that you've been doing?
I figure with all that's happened that I won't be
able to hunt for the treasure for a while...
So I came here to get various documents and such.
But it's not here! The memo pad where I was
recording the progress of the treasure hunt.
Well, then Akira-san must have it, right?
After all, you and he are the only treasure hunters still left alive.
Maybe he's planning on keeping all the treasure for himself?
Akira isn't the kind of person who would do something like that.
He's been my hero since we were classmates.
But people's hearts can change, Shigetsugu-san.
After all, how can you know what someone bearing
the blood of the Tatsuo family might be thinking.
Nonsense! Don't confuse him with your
own Torada family's prodigal son.
Akira's been the bowman for the festival
five years in a row! He's a samurai!
Why are you here!?
We came looking for Akira.
We thought he might be here.
As for Akira-san, Heiji told me over the phone that he finished
his horseback archery practice and is on his way home.
Well now, at any rate, let's all go back to our respective houses
for the present and remain alert until this case has been settled.
You too, Shigetsugu-san...
All right.
OK, I guess we'll be heading off this way.
Please be careful on the way home.
Nobody's going to attack a horrible old mountain hag like her.
Those words fit you perfectly too, you bald raccoon.
Oops, now now. Didn't Shingen say this too?
"Compassion is your ally; resentment is your enemy."
Wouldn't it be better here if both families put aside their
disagreements and cooperate to resolve this case?
That's not for someone like you to say.
What you just said was Officer Kai's favorite phrase.
He often used those words to bring quarrels
between both families to a close.
That silly fool was a big fan of Shingen.
Oh, so you'll be my wife when you grow up?
You'll have to let me off the hook on that,
or else Kansuke will be mad at me.
Hey, hey, please stop calling me "sensei"
Despite the difference in age, you're my rival.
I don't mind if you call me Kai-senpai.
Say, Hattori...
Why would the culprit be patterning
their crimes after "Fuurinkazan?"
Maybe it has something to do with how the three
victims were all searching for Shingen's buried gold.
Or possibly they might be trying to make us
think that in order to hide their true motive.
But, you know, Yoshirou-san's being swallowed
up by that tornado was completely by chance.
Nevertheless, the fact that they had the corpse of
the centipede already prepared would mean...
The culprit had been planning to kill
those three for some time before that.
Still, the thing that bothers me is that matter about Yoshirou-san and
Kouji-san saying they were going to see that Detective Yamato.
What has me is how Ayaka san suddenly was so startled
when she heard about Shingen's armored helmet.
Speaking of being bothered, there's one more thing.
Yeah.
Officer Kai's death by falling.
In any case, we still have the remaining
character "fire" from "Fuurinkazan."
Will the next target be Akira-san or—
What was that sound?
It sounded like thunder.
Heiji! Something terrible has happened!
What's is it, Kazuha?
What happened?
There was a huge noise, and when I turned around...
Shigetsugu-san had gone...
And when we went back to the railroad crossing
to look for him, the train had stopped...
And in front of the train...
There was a collapsed person on fire!
There was a person on fire?
Yeah, I think it could be Shigetsugu-san.
Wait right there! I'll be there as soon as possible!
"As fierce as the fife," huh?
Next Conan's Hint
Eye Shadow
Next time we start at 7:00 PM too.
Conan keeps on confronting puzzling cases. Hooray!