The curtain rises on a mysterious new era...
The Monday 7:00 reasoning show.
It's the puzzling case of the "Fuurinkazan."
Conan and Heiji bring it to its final conclusion!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
The feuding Torada and Tatsuo families
are involved in a serial murder case.
The crimes are being patterned
after Takeda Shingen's "Fuurinkazan."
Why is the culprit so obsessed with Shingen?
And what's the connection with the falling
death of Officer Kai Kuroto six years ago?
As the mystery deepens, eventually there's a new victim.
He's been burnt black from top to bottom.
But looking at the shape, there's no doubt it was Torada Shigetsugu.
The Tatsuo family must have done this!
Torada Naonobu (61)
Head of the Torada Family
What kind of foolish talk is that?
Come to think of it, where
did that fishing pole go?
Fishing pole?
Yeah. It was in a case, but I think it was probably a fishing pole.
Hey, a fishing pole? Could it be...
That's right.
Shigetsugu-san touched the train's aerial electrical wiring
with this long fishing pole and was electrocuted.
Torada Yui (29)
Yoshirou's Wife
Where did you find that pole?
Right there in the woods.
The case for the pole had been
dropped over by the railroad crossing.
So he must have taken it out there, and
after he was hit by the electrical shock...
I figure it must have been struck by the train and hurled there.
And next to the case, someone has placed the corpse of a centipede.
This is another serial murder.
Torada Yoshirou-san, who was killed by a tornado, is "wind".
Tatsuo Kouji-san, who was buried in the
ground and beaten to death, is "mountain".
Tatsuo Ayaka-san, who was hanged in the woods, is "forest".
And Torada Shigetsugu-san, who received an electrical
shock and was burned completely black, is "fire".
The "Fuurinkazan" has been successfully completed.
Tatsuo Akira (32)
Tamefumi's Son
But, why did my wife and my friends
have to be killed in this horrible way?
Yamato Kansuke (35)
Nagano Prefectural
Police Detective
Inspector Yamato, there's
a strange notebook.
This seems to be...
A record of their progress in searching for the buried gold.
Ah, could that possibly be the memo pad
that Shigetsugu-san was looking for?
Yeah, but this was also used as a shared diary.
In summary, what's written in the diary says...
That six years ago they accidentally caused a certain person's death.
They fought with the idea of going to the police
or not, but in the end, they didn't say anything...
And they've remained silent ever since.
Tatsuo Akira, they did it for your sake.
Wait a second. Six years ago? That means the dead person was...
Yeah.
It was Kai Kuroto-san.
So that you would win at the preliminary contest
and be chosen as the horseback archery bowman...
They wanted to cause Kai-san to be injured.
They used fireworks to frighten Kai-san's horse
while he was practicing, hoping he'd be thrown.
However, the horse became more frightened
that they thought, and it started running.
And when they followed...
It says they found that Kai-san, along
with his horse, had fallen off the cliff.
N-No way!
Judging from the handwriting, I'd say four
people were writing in this shared diary.
I'd dare say it's those who've recently died:
Yoshirou and Shigetsugu from the Torada family...
And Kouji and Ayaka from the Tatsuo family, those four people.
But why would that notebook be here?
In order to send it to hell, and keep all of this hidden.
Shigetsugu made a show of looking for this note-
book, but in truth he had it concealed on him.
He kept hold of it as he burned.
I think that was his way of apologizing to Kai-san.
Then, you're not saying, this series of murders was...
Yeah.
After consigning his partners in the crime six years ago to oblivion...
As his last act, he killed himself...
In order to bury the truth in darkness.
Torada Shigetsugu was the serial murderer.
The reason he attempted to destroy this notebook...
Was so Tatsuo Akira would never know the truth.
Well, unfortunately for him, since it got hurled
away without being burned, it remains.
Still, if it was done in some part for Akira's sake...
Tatsuo Tamefumi (56)
Head of the Tatsuo Family
Tatsuo Shigeyo (78)
Tamefumi's Mother
I'm sure that, in the other world, he'll acknowledge him for that.
Kai-san will.
At any rate, this case is over.
In this situation, I'd like to tell you all to
return peacefully to your homes, but...
To complete my checking on this case, I need to
search your houses, so wait here for a while.
Say, did Shigetsugu-san actually find that notebook?
I don't know. I didn't see him find it.
But Shigetsugu-san stopped searching and
started reading his cellphone e-mail...
So maybe he did find it.
E-mail?
Oh yeah, I saw him.
Just when we were about to leave.
E-mail...
Heiji-niichan!
What is it? Did you find something?
Look at this.
A rock with a string attached to it.
Come to think of it, there was a string attached to that notebook too.
Bah, what does it matter? The case is already over.
When Shigetsugu-san burned, that was "fire", right?
The lightning.
Lightning? Does that mean it's going to rain?
Lightning?
Was it "lightning?
This is annoying, to think we're being made
to wait here in the middle of the rain.
Torada Tatsue (58)
Naonobu's Wife
Come to think of it, it was raining on the day my
husband and the others killed Kai-san, wasn't it?
My husband started having a lot of nightmares.
He would mutter, "The sound... the flash..."
He meant the lightning, didn't he?
No, it was sunny that day.
Yeah, all day long.
My poor Shigetsugu will get rained on.
Hey, Heiji, can't you do something about this?
He's gone.
Conan-kun too.
Those guys went off on their own again!
Here below the place where Ayaka-san was hanged...
There are no one else's footprints.
Exactly.
There are just the footprints and the marks of his cane that
detective Yamato made when he brought the body down.
When could the culprit have hanged Ayaka-san?
Until Ayaka-san disappeared from the restroom...
Both us and the members of the Torada family were there together.
And the people from the Tatsuo family were
being driven over by Tamefumi in his car.
Hey!
What the heck are you doing?
Ah, it's the police detective we met earlier.
What's the matter?
Since it looks like it's going to rain, Inspector
Yamato told us to come cover the crime scene.
Huh? Whose coat is that?
I found this earlier, caught in a tree branch.
Say, that coat...
Is it wet?
Oh, no. The inspector asked me the same thing.
But it's not wet.
In any case, please keep out of the way.
Ever since the inspector came back, he's kept us
working hard without even letting us have a day off.
"Came back"? Where did he go?
We went up into the mountains to find a man who had
skipped on his parole and got caught in an avalanche.
The man was someone Kai-san had arrested for stealing...
But he'd vanished six years ago.
Inspector Yamato thought he might be
connected to Kai-san's accidental death.
Thanks to that, the inspector's left eye and left leg were injured...
And he was unconscious the whole time that he was in the hospital.
And did that man have any connection to Kai-san's accident?
No, it turned out they were unrelated.
But fate sure is cruel.
The person who was his junior officer before he left, Uehara-san...
The next time they met, she was the wife of a victim.
Even though Uehara-san said they had to be absolutely
sure about what really happened when Kai-san died...
And despite both she and the inspector being so enthusiastic about it...
She suddenly quit her job as a detective and got married.
I heard that those two became police detectives
in the first place because they admired Kai-san.
If that's so, then when she found Kai-san's
body six years ago, she was a police detective?
Yeah, since she was still new, it was a terrible
experience for her and she cried over it.
Speaking of crying, there's one thing that's strange.
Huh? What is it?
Tatsuo Ayaka-san. Even though she must have
wiped away some tears before she died...
There's no other trace of her having cried.
How do you know she wiped tears away?
The eye shadow in her left eye had been rubbed,
and some of it was still on her right index finger.
Doesn't that make you think she wiped tears away?
What color was it?
What color?
Uh, well...
It was just common blue eye shadow.
In that case, lead your dark bay back to the Torada house right away.
That's it.
So that's what it means.
It appears that this war...
Isn't over yet.
Torada House
What? The police are coming to search the house again?
Yes, Inspector Yamato along with some of his junior officers will be coming tomorrow and staying over while they investigate.
Of course, they'll be searching the Tatsuo
house in the same way starting tomorrow.
How long will they be staying?
It will be three or four days, I'm afraid.
Three or four days?
If I remember right, the festival is three days from now.
It'll have started.
I see now.
The festival, eh?
Tatsuo House
Yoshirou.
Kouji.
Ayaka.
Shigetsugu.
Why did you do that to Kai-senpai just to help me?
Why?
So it was you, just as I thought.
Torada Yui-san.
Oh? So you knew?
That I'd be coming.
Yeah.
That's because of what you said to yourself
when Shigetsugu died: "lightning."
While it's true that Shigetsugu san's body was
burned, the cause of his death was electrocution.
That wasn't "fire", it was the "lightning"
from "Move like the lightning."
That's right. There's more to the "Fuurinkazan"
strategy that Sun Tzu advocated.
The "Move like the lightning" that you just mentioned.
"Be as impenetrable as a shadow."
The "lightning" comes from "When you appear,
appear unexpectedly like the lightning."
"Shadow" is from "When you hide, hide as still as a shadow."
That's right.
It was the same way with Kai-san beneath the cliff where the sun didn't reach throughout the day, his breath growing still.
To those four who caused Kai-san's death six years ago...
His blood soaked undershirt must have looked deep red.
Just like the calvary troops wore in Takeda's "Akazonae".
That's why this was all patterned after Shingen.
Yeah, it was to flush out those four who caused Kai-san's death.
Just as expected, Kouji-san reacted to it almost instantly.
But Ayaka-san and Shigetsugu-san weren't that interested in Shingen...
So they didn't respond to the corpses of the centipedes.
And so, it was with all that uproar that
occurred over the Suwa-style helmet...
That Ayaka-san was finally smoked out.
And then Ayaka was forced to revealed Shigetsugu's name!
Have you come to deal with me just like you did those four!?
To wipe out Kai-senpai's rival!?
Deal with you?
You idiot.
I came here to protect you.
From the person who's behind these serial murders.
From that person there.
It was you...
I should have expected it from a former policewoman.
How did you figure it out, I wonder.
It was the blue eye shadow on Ayaka-san's hand.
"Ao" (blue) from "aokage" (dark bay), meaning a black horse.
In other words...
The person riding a black horse at the time, which was you.
What a clever little girl.
Then, you forced Shigetsugu-san's name
out of Ayaka-san, and dealt with him.
Yeah, Shigetsugu-san was the child of my husband's former wife.
He wasn't related to me by blood.
But why, Tatsue-san!?
It's because she's the one who really killed Kai-san.
I mentioned it earlier, that my husband would say, "The
sound, the flash..." while he was having nightmares.
That's what lead me to realize there was another
person at the crime scene six years ago.
Tatsue-san, it was you, wasn't it?
Yeah, I wanted him injured as well.
So I fired one shot from this gun at his horse's legs.
That's when he plunged head over heels off the cliff.
But, wouldn't you know, some people
came and started making a big fuss.
As if they were the ones who caused his death.
That just made me laugh.
It would have been best if they continued
to think that and kept quiet, but...
Later on, he started talking about going to tell the police
about the gunshot he'd heard and the flash he'd seen...
But then the gods punished Yoshirou by sending him that tornado.
And you left my severely injured husband there to die.
Leaving the centipede corpse you had already prepared there too.
Yeah, by that time, I'd already hit upon the idea of
patterning everything after the "Fuu-rin-ka-zan-in-rai".
So, that means one of your targets right from the start was Akira-san.
Yeah, Akira-san is the final one—
"fire."
Since you've become a hindrance to the gambling
that we sponsor, you'll be burned to a crisp.
We'll cook you with these flames.
Gambling?
They gamble on the festival horseback archery demonstration,
betting how many of the ten shots will be missed.
But Kai-san never missed a single one...
Until you shifted one of the targets.
There's no point in gambling if he never misses.
And since you've hit them all for five years
straight as well, you'll need to die too.
The story will be that you took revenge for
your Kai-senpai, whom you loved dearly...
And then to atone for those crimes, you took your own life.
But considering the current circumstances...
Having this stupid woman who, to solve the mystery of Officer Kai's death, went so far as to marry Yoshirou, a man she didn't love...
It might look better if we change our story to
one where she kills you out of resentment.
Well, will you tell this stupid woman something?
Why were there no marks beneath the place
where Ayaka-san was hanged on the tree?
Why waste words on someone about to die?
It was the horse.
Back then, you put Ayaka-san on your horse, didn't you?
You used a rope you had already attached to the branch beforehand.
Allowing you to hook it to her neck from the other side of the tree.
Afterwards, you rode your horse up behind the tree...
So no one would know when the hoof marks had gotten there.
How long have you been here?
"Be as swift as the wind."
I've been waiting here for two hours before you came.
Incidentally, the reason no one noticed
that Ayaka-san was on your horse was...
You had put a black coat on her.
When Ayaka san was secluded in the restroom, you called
her by cellphone and secretly lured her out to the stables.
After Akira-san and the others left on the horses...
You placed her, with that black coat on her,
onto your black horse and went into the forest.
Kid!
You too!?
"Be as quiet as the forest."
I've been waiting here, holding my breath.
Well, it looks like an earlier visitor got here before us.
An earlier visitor?
If you know your target...
Be cool and level...
Sit yourself down and observe.
"Be immovable like the mountain."
You planned this, didn't you?
Yeah, with the police sticking around here until
the festival, tonight was your only chance.
Heh, compared to your plan of swiping that note-
book, hanging it from the electric train wires...
And thereby electrocuting Shigetsugu, my plan was no big deal.
The way you used a string to tie the notebook to a rock...
Made it simple to throw up and catch it on the aerial train wires.
Shigetsugu-san learned where it was from an e-mail you sent...
And when he used the pole to get it, he was electrocuted.
Anyway, if you want to start a fire, go ahead.
I've already called the fire department
and have them waiting on standby.
Get them!
Don't worry, I'm striking with the blunt side.
You bastard!
Kan-chan!
Eat this!
Saved the best for yourself again, eh?
An thus, the final murder was prevented before it happened.
As for the war that had lasted for six years...
It was over at last, with the enemy
general sporting a bruise on her left eye.
What? You fought a battle with the culprit and her gang last night?
Why didn't you invite us?
Even after all the support we've given you.
Idiots, how could I get you involved in such a dangerous situation?
All right, please come in for a formal interview later.
Very well.
You need to come to the police as well.
See you.
"Be as swift as the wind."
I...
It was because I thought you were dead, Kan-chan!
That's why I thought I had to do something...
That's why I married Yoshirou-san.
Sorry, when I say it like that, it makes me feel sorry for my husband.
Idiot, didn't I just say it?
"Come to the police."
When you free yourself from your obligations,
and when you're ready —
come back.
The chief detective has been waiting too —
to taste that awful coffee you make again.
Wow, somehow those two...
Are getting along!
Say, what did those two say?
You were standing next to them, right?
She said, "Be as swift as the wind" or something...
The strategy of love!
Fuurinkazan!
Heiji!
What's wrong, Kazuha?
It's fine, just c'mon!
What's going on?
It's from Ran.
Ah, hello, Shin'ichi?
Ah, Ran. What's up?
What the heck is it?
Today! Today's when I'm going to tell you!
Couldn't we talk later?
No! It's no good if we don't talk now!
"Be as swift as the wind."
Ah, sorry. I gotta go to the bathroom.
Idiot! Don't try and run away, Heiji!
"Attack as fiercely as the fire."
"Be as quiet as the forest."
You're right. It might be better to talk later.
Well, why don't we leave it there for today.
Hey! Wait a second!
What's with them?
No idea.
You think they're getting irritable because they're hungry?
"Be immovable like the mountain."
Next Conan's Hint
FOX
(kitsune)
The setting next time is Yamaguchi Prefecture.
Will I be going to?
You're not needed.
The broadcast is on Dec 1st.