The curtain rises on a mysterious new era...
The Monday 7:00 reasoning show.
A puzzling code written in her grandfather's diary.
Yamaguchi prefecture is the stage for a treasure hunt!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
This is all, you see, dedicated to Yoshida Shouin...
The man who trained the people that would become
the leaders behind the Meiji Restoration.
The great teacher has been enshrined in this place.
Shouin?
He lived 150 years ago, during the last
years of the shogunate (bakumatsu).
The Meiji "mishin"? (sewing machine)
Not "mishin" (sewing machine), the Meiji "isshin" (restoration).
(Meiji is a common sewing machine brand in Japan.)
Shouin was a studious man who broadened his
knowledge by traveling throughout Japan.
Because he wanted to change the country,
he studied foreign works as well.
That was when Japan excluded foreigners.
He poured his heart into studying western culture...
At the risk of his life, he even tried to stowaway to America.
But, before his plans had come to fruition...
Translator's Note: Shouin's final words, "Even if my body shall, in this
Musashi field, rot away, I will at least retain the spirit of Yamato."
Shouin was executed.
Even so, Shouin's intentions were adopted by others.
And the pupils who listened to his
teachings went on to change society.
Did you get all that?
Why did we have to bring a bunch of brats
along for our Japanese history homework?
C'mon, it's OK.
Having to come along is a real nuisance for us too.
That was my line.
What's happening?
Hand it over!
Please stop!
Hey, you!
What do you think you're doing?
Wait!
Are you all right?
So you're being threatened?
Yes.
He said if I didn't hand over this diary,
something horrible would happen to me.
And that if I told the police, he couldn't guarantee my life.
That's what he told me several times over the phone.
Do you have any idea who it was?
No, no idea.
This diary is a little worn-out, isn't it?
My late grandpa left it to me.
Kobayakawa Kimiko (21)
College Student
But the contents are just some puzzles.
Puzzles?
My grandpa loved word games.
He would always be writing down puzzles in here.
But, before he could write out all the solutions, my grandpa...
Five years ago today, he passed away.
My grandpa was really fond of Master Shouin.
That's why I went to visit the Shouin shrine.
But why would that guy be after something like this diary?
I don't know either.
Mouri-san, could I possibly ask you to investigate?
I understand. I'd be happy to accept.
Huh?
Huh? There's something stuck inside where it was torn earlier.
What is it?
"November 30th...
"Only by the twilight will the true treasure be illuminated.
"Solve the puzzle of the fox."
Treasure?
Kimiko-san! Do you have any idea what this is about?
Treasure? That reminds me...
Kimiko, I have a magnificent treasure
that could buy the whole country.
Wh-What did you say?
A treasure that could buy the country!?
How many bowls of eel over rice (unajuu) would that be?
Why would anyone know the conversion rate to unajuu?
But what could "The puzzle of the fox" mean?
Maybe this is it.
There's a picture of a fox here.
"Feed the carp to the fox." What could that mean?
A moat with carp. That might possibly refer
to a scenic spot that's near my family home.
Where is your family home?
In Tsuwano in Shimane prefecture.
Then we need to go to your family home!
We do?
November 30th is tomorrow!
We can't miss this chance! We leave first thing in the morning!
But can we get a ticket now for tomorrow morning?
It's no problem.
Leave that task to Suzuki Sonoko-sama!
If I use my family's connections...
No matter if it's the bullet train (shinkansen) or an express sleeper...
It'll be a piece of cake!
I guess that's to be expected from the daughter of Suzuki Financial.
Yeah.
With the great detective Mouri Kogorou on the job,
that treasure will be discovered before dinnertime!
There's been a complication.
That's woman's gone to see the detective, Mouri Kogorou.
All right, I understand. Keep on watching her.
I really have to thank you for undertaking this.
No, it's no big deal.
What on earth could this stand for?
"Feed the carp to the fox."
Do carp taste good?
Huh?
Why are you guys doing that?
We're doing what we can for now.
After all, we were the ones Kimiko-neechan
asked for help from in the first place.
Jeez.
That diary of puzzles...
Your grandpa must have been a really fun person, Kimiko-san.
Yeah, he was always coming up with interesting things.
Kimiko, if you were going to send a letter to the
future, how much postage would you need?
Kobayakawa Shigetoshi
Kimiko's Grandpa
A letter to the future?
What was it? What was the answer?
He didn't tell me that.
Shin-Yamaguchi! Shin-Yamaguchi!
To reach Tsuwano from here, we
need to transfer to the Yamaguchi line.
Kimiko!
Kimiko, are you all right?
Eh? Yeah.
Kimiko-san, who is this?
Kawaguchi Shigeru, I'm a pal of Kimiko's.
I heard that Kimiko had a close call while in Tokyo.
We're the ones who protected Kimiko-neechan.
Yes, for we are...
The Detective Boys!
Hey, that's cool.
Kawaguchi Shigeru (21)
Kimiko's Friend
As her friend, thanks from me too.
So, Kimiko, are you heading back to Tsuwano from here?
Huh? Yeah.
Kimiko-san?
Yeah, it's me. Nine tickets will be
enough. Cancel the rest for me.
Awesome!
It's gotten hot coming here.
It smells really awesome too.
Hey! Hurry up and get on!
Right!
They're only running this steam locomotive for a limited time.
It's really full. It must be hard to get tickets.
Heh, if you have connections, it's easy.
Is there a hot spring here?
If you want a hot spring, the Yuda onsen is popular.
That person said his name was Kawaguchi Shigeru, didn't he?
So you noticed it.
Kimiko-san's cellphone strap matches that guy's pendant.
There are initials on the back.
Kimiko-san's has "K.K." for "Kobayakawa Kimiko"
That person had "A.T." But if his name is Kawaguchi
Shigeru, it should be "S.K.", shouldn't it?
Why would he be trying to hide his real name?
Heh, if you have connections, it's easy.
If I use my family's connections...
No matter if it's the bullet train (shinkansen) or an express sleeper...
It'll be a piece of cake!
So that means he has a connection who
is an influential person in this area
What the heck are you intending?
Listen to me!
What's the matter?
I thought this was the way to the toilet.
It's that way.
Thanks.
Tsuwano! Tsuwano!
Might you be Mouri-san?
Huh? Yeah.
Thank you for coming so far.
Kikkawa Tsuneo (60)
Kobayakawa Family Employee
I work for the Kobayakawa family. My name is Kikkawa.
Sorry to put you to any bother.
Wasn't the daughter of the house with you?
Huh? She was just here.
Oh no! Could she have been kidnapped!?
Sorry!
I forgot to buy a souvenir for my mother.
So I just bought this.
What a relief.
I go all the way to Tokyo and I buy a souvenir here, isn't that funny?
What happened to your friend?
It looks like he already left.
Well, shall we go?
Development is our home town's future!
Everyone is already aware
of my past record.
Who's that?
His name's Takahashi Hisamichi.
He's involved in real estate and construction
along the hub of the San'in region (SW Honshu).
He has an extensive business developing resorts and such things.
Now he's announcing his candidacy as
a member of the prefectural assembly.
So this area will be invigorated and everyone's lives will be enriched.
The one who can do it is me, Takahashi!
And only me, Takahashi Hisamichi!
Takahashi-san makes me feel reassured.
He's the one who loves this town the most.
To think such a splendid father could have a son like that.
Yeah, Atsushi-kun, eh? How long will he keep acting like a delinquent?
This is Tonomachi street.
This is where old-time samurai houses are still standing.
Wow! What huge carp!
In the old days, they were raised for emergency food.
Is the fox going to eat all of these carp?
What are you talking about? This is a code.
You're not supposed to think he will really eat them.
I know that!
Thank you for taking the trip here.
No, no. I'm just happy your daughter is safe.
The thing is, recently we just had a thief break into this house too.
Could they have been after the diary?
Kobayakawa Hideko (48)
Kimiko's Mother
That might be the case.
Mouri-san, please, find the culprit any way you can.
Please leave it to me.
So, Kimiko-san said she had heard something
about a treasure from her grandpa.
What about you?
I've heard things about a treasure too.
After the war, the Kobayakawa house was the first
to be rebuilt, supposedly thanks to the treasure...
But I know how much effort my father put into it.
And I know it wasn't thanks to any treasure.
But there are a lot of people who don't think that.
Especially some people who rose to power
in the turmoil after the Second World War.
Since historically we've been deeply trusted by the local people,
they've been hostile to the Kobayakawa family at every opportunity.
I see, those people might be the ones after the diary.
We can't let the bad guys find the treasure before us.
Yeah.
Excuse me, can I eat this now?
I'm sorry, please go ahead and eat up.
OK!
These rice-powder sweets are a Yamaguchi specialty.
They're a little different than the ones
from Nagoya, you can wiggle them.
Yummy.
Wiggly!
Mine's already gone.
Eating the carp means the carp would disappear.
Mitsuhiko, can I borrow your copy of this page?
Sure.
Conan-kun?
What are you doing?
How about this way?
The carp have disappeared!
It's true.
I'm pretty sure that "Feed the carp to the fox" meant this.
What? All you did was fold it.
Ah! There are characters at the fold.
What?
Characters appeared when the ends
of the canal were joined together.
"Below the top of the hidden Inari."
If it says "Inari", the Taikodani Inari shrine is in this area.
That's it! The treasure is at the Taikodani Inari shrine!
All right, let's go!
There are a mind-bogglingly large number of Torii arches here.
Yeah, they say there are around 1000 of them.
1,000!?
We have to climb this?
That's what it looks like.
I can't go on!
Genta-kun, you can do it!
It's just a bit further.
It's a long way!
So lift up your leg!
I made it.
It's pretty!
This is a terrific view, isn't it?
Still, what does "Below the top of the hidden Inari" mean?
Wow, what's that?
Is it food?
Fried tofu?
That's not for eating, it's an offering.
Fried tofu is the Great Fox's favorite food.
Say, say, say, what do they do with the offerings?
Are you thinking about stealing them?
The gods will punish you.
I was just asking.
The offerings are made at the main shrine over there.
Or at the shrine in the back, either one.
Could that maybe be it?
That "Hidden Inari"?
Here?
It doesn't seem there's anything here.
There's fried tofu in there.
That way you can't steal it.
I told you, I'm not going to take it!
Wow!
Hey, look at this!
There are a whole lot of foxes!
There really are!
That's awesome.
I got it! That "Hidden Inari" is referring to this.
No, not there. Over here.
The "Hidden Inari" is here.
Now we just have "Below the top" remaining.
They're using a stone to signify fried tofu.
Eh? Fried tofu?
That's it!
"Ue" (top) as kanji can be read "a-ge" (up, but also fried tofu).
Therefore the treasure is under that stone fried tofu!
You're so smart!
Awesome, Mitsuhiko!
No, not really.
A bottle?
What's that in there?
Let's see. There's some kind of paper in it.
This is...
It's a map, isn't it?
Something's written at the top.
Hey, what does it say?
"Reflect the castle in the eye of the cat and look under the mouse."
What's that?
Cat, huh...
This is it.
That hole looks like it was made on purpose.
But there's no page with a picture of a mouse.
Another code?
This looks like it was drawn based on an old map of Hagi city.
Hagi? That's in Yamaguchi prefecture, isn't it?
Yes, and it's related to the person
that my grandpa liked, Master Shouin.
I get it. So the treasure's in Hagi then?
I see. So they're going to Hagi?
Don't lose them! Understand?
Huh? Kimiko-san?
Sorry, I'm here.
For some reason this really looks like an old town.
In Hagi, the old-time street patterns still remain today.
Therefore, if you're looking at a map from the Edo period...
You could walk through the town now and still find your way.
That's great.
So we're seeing the same street fronts as the
patriots from the Meiji Restoration then, eh?
That's right, this was the birthplace of the Meiji Restoration.
There it is again, the Meiji sewing machine.
It's Meiji Restoration.
That's the reform that gave Japan its chance
to become a modern country like it is today.
A lot of the people who accomplished the Meiji.
Restoration were from this town of Hagi.
Nekonocho? (Cat St.)
Could this have something to do with that code?
Hagi has roughly 250 streets with names like that one.
Here in the old days, among the retainers of Mouri Terumoto...
Some people who really loved cats lived
here, so they called it Nekonocho.
A real cat!
Cat? That's it, I've got it!
You've solved the code?
Exactly.
"Shiro" didn't mean a castle (shiro); it meant a white (shiroi) wall.
In other words, somewhere near this white
plaster wall where we can see this cat sitting...
Is the hidden treasure!
Look, exactly like now, that cat...
Wait, kitty!
That's completely wrong.
Mouri-san, you're having a joke on us.
I'm worried that it wasn't a joke.
That was the guy who called himself Kawaguchi Shigeru.
Didn't you hear what I told you?
But...
So it was Shigeru-san.
That man?
That was the man who attacked Kimiko-san.
This is the house where the doctor, Aoki
Shuusuke, lived during the Edo period.
I've heard that a treasure was found here a long time ago.
You're very familiar with it.
Was there really a treasure?
Yes, there was gold buried in the cellar.
Buried gold!?
There definitely must be a treasure!
I think so too!
I'm getting all excited!
I am too!
Shall we go see the remains of the Hagi castle next?
What's the relationship between Shigeru-san and those men?
And who is Shigeru-san for real?
Hurry and get in! Settle down!
You there! What are you doing?!
The key!
Officer! Hurry, this way!
Quick, let's get going!
Mitsuhiko!
What the...
I'm borrowing this.
You're not getting away!
Damn...
I didn't think those guys would go this far.
I wasn't paying enough attention.
Could there really be treasure big enough to buy the country?
And those men who are after it, who the hell are they?
And that voice from that time.
Officer! Hurry, this way!
I'm sure that voice was...
Next Conan's Hint:
CAT
(neko)
Look forward to the next episode
Meow! Next time we find the treasure!
I can eat lots of unajuu, meow!
That's meow-meow stupid.