The curtain rises on a mysterious new era...
The Monday 7:00 reasoning show.
Something terrible happens while searching for the treasure.
What will happen to the kidnapped Haibara and Mitsuhiko?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
At the Shouin shrine in Tokyo, we rescued Kobayakawa
Kimiko-san when she was attacked by a man.
Kobayakawa Kimiko (21)
Collage Student
In order to search for "A treasure that could buy the country"
that her deceased grandfather was said to possess...
We went to Tsuwano, where Kimiko-san's family home was located.
On the way, at Shin-Tamaguchi station, we ran into
Kimiko-san's friend, Kawaguchi Shigeru-san.
Kawaguchi Shigeru (21)
Kimiko's Friend
However, Haibara and I noticed that he was using a false name.
At Tsuwano, we discovered a new riddle and an old map of the town of Hagi.
As well as a picture of a cat drawn in the diary.
When, in a search for clues, we went to visit Hagi...
I witnessed Shigeru-san meeting up with
the man who had attacked Kimiko-san.
And, in the end, those mysterious men...
What horrible people.
What should we do?
"What should we do?" Of course, we should call the police.
Hey, that's right. Didn't someone already call for the police?
The voice from that time...
Officer! Hurry, this way!
Kawaguchi Shigeru, I'm a pal of Kimiko's.
Is was definitely him.
It's from the young mistress's cellphone!
Put it on speaker!
Uh, right...
Just press this one more time.
Can you hear me?
We have the woman and the children.
Find that treasure as quickly as you can.
If you delay, the three of them will...
You know what.
You bastard!
Don't inform the police.
I'll contact you again.
Oh, hello? Young mistress!
Young mistress!
We should notify the police.
We can't! What if we do that,
and by some chance...
Kikkawa Tsuneo (60)
Kobayaka Family Employee
But even if we obey the culprit, there's
no guarantee they'll be rescued.
I understand.
Conan-kun.
Mitsuhiko-kun managed to drop this before they grabbed him.
Mitsuhiko...
That's it! I figured it out!
This picture of a cat and the map of Hagi...
If we turn the map over and put it on top...
They're the same shape.
It's true!
This picture of a cat represents the layout of Hagi.
And "Reflect the castle in the eye of the cat" means...
Line up the castle on the map exactly with the eye of the cat.
And then the place corresponding to the
hole in the picture of the cat is revealed!
I see!
If we go there...
We should be able to solve the other part
of the code, "Look under the mouse."
Mouri-san, I've alerted the police!
Kikkawa-san...
Where is the place that corresponds
to this hole in the picture of the cat?
Look here!
Um, that's...
The Enseiji temple.
All right! Let's go to the Enseiji temple!
There's no time to spare.
"November 30th.
"Only by the twilight will the true treasure be illuminated."
This evening is the time limit.
You can unfasten them.
Luckily, no matter no much noise you
make here, it won't do you any good.
So act mature and keep quiet.
He might say act mature and keep quiet, but
we're not children who would try and act mature.
Heh, that's true.
He'll be sorry he underestimated us.
Conan-kun!
Mitsuhiko!
Thank goodness. You can hear me, right?
Is everyone all right?
Did they do anything horrible to you?
No, we're all OK.
Right now we're in some basement.
What are you hiding there?
Show me!
Mitsuhiko!
Hey, what's happening!?
Mitsuhiko-kun!
You wanna get hurt!?
Mitsuhiko?
Mitsuhiko!
It's no good.
The police are on the job, right?
Yeah...
This is the Enseiji temple.
Itou Hirobumi, Takasugi Shinsaku, and the others studied here.
"Look under the mouse."
What could that mean?
Wow, what a huge Tengu!
It's scary.
What is it this time?
I found it!
That's it!
Mice!
It's been decorated with all 12 of the Chinese zodiac signs.
I see now.
This is what "Below the mouse" meant.
But is there anything underneath it?
There's nothing here.
Still, it was something her grandpa who loved puns came up with.
So it might not mean mouse exactly.
In English, it's "mouse."
That's it!
"Mouse" (mausu) is pronounced like "mouth."
In other words, the treasure is somewhere in this mouth.
No, it's was below the mouth...
Could this be it?
I see.
It could be this too.
What's that?
That's the largest stone lantern in the prefecture.
What's particularly interesting is that some of the
stones supporting the lantern can be moved.
I see now.
Found it.
Conan-kun, that's amazing!
But how did you know it would be here?
That opening in the lantern is called the "fire mouth" (hi guchi).
I see.
This is "below the mouth" too then, huh?
So? What is it this time?
It's...
What's that?
Another code?
Wait a second.
I think the same thing was in the diary.
Here it is.
There's no mistake.
It matches the place where the page was torn.
That means the picture spanning these two pages is the next riddle?
"You must construct a map from the cave where the kappa dwell."
Well, if it says, "The cave where the kappa dwell,"
then there's only one place like that in this area.
There are kappa there!?
Akiyoshi Cave.
So you know where the treasure is?
Are those three people safe?
What's your next destination?
First, you let us hear those three's voices!
How would you like to be unable to hear their voices for good?
It's Akiyoshi cave.
Let's hurry!
There's no time!
I've heard it said that the Akiyoshi cave is
the largest limestone cave in the Orient.
It's close to sunset.
Hurry up!
"You must construct a map from the cave."
Hidden somewhere in here the Akiyoshi
cave must be a hint about making a map.
This place is called Aotenjou (blue ceiling)
The light from outside is reflected off
the water, coloring the ceiling blue.
What about here?
The sign says "Nagabuchi" (long abyss).
One hundred plates?
They really do look like plates.
Limestone caves are marvelous.
Hyakumaizara, Nagabuchi, Aotenjou.
Hyaku?
That's it!
Did you figure something out?
Yeah.
If I rip this here...
What are you doing!?
It's better this way.
Look closely at each of the papers.
There's a character in the upper left, right?
Yeah.
They are the first characters of the names of
the famous places here in Akiyoshi cave.
"Ao" is the "Ao" from "Aotenjou."
"Naga" is from "Nagabuchi."
This one is for the Hyakumaizara.
The rest are the same, right?
You're right, it's true.
After this comes Donaifuji (Mt Fuji Inside the Cave).
Kabochaiwa (Pumpkin Rock).
Oomatsutake (Giant Matsutake Mushroom).
Subogaki (The Mother of Persimmons).
And Chirimeniwa (Crepe Paper Rock).
Those are the famous places in order.
So that means we need to line up these cut-up pieces of
paper in the same order, starting from the entrance...
If we do that, what do we get?
We get this.
Isn't this a map of a cave?
Oh, this X mark! That's where the treasure is, isn't it?
The hint is this sentence.
So if we read it in order it says, "Wa inori..."
No, it's read from the right.
Ah, I see.
Kuroka radetefu tagonori yuuki tsunei wanokuchi sakihika rinoiwa?
Come out of the black, a pair of dragons.
kuro kara dete, futago no ryuu
The snout of the Fox Rock, the Light Rock.
kitsune iwa no kuchisaki, hikari no iwa
If it says "Come out of the black"...
AKIYOSHI CAVE KUROTANI EXIT
The Kurotani (Black Valley) exit.
"Come out of the black" meant come out of the Black Valley exit, then?
Then the "pair of dragons".
What could that be?
Say...
Isn't there a place in this area where there are two waterfalls in a row?
Two waterfalls?
Oh, if I remember right, there's a place
like that halfway up the mountain.
Those are the pair of dragons!
Then, somewhere near there is...
Where the Fox Rock is!
Let's hurry!
Kikkawa-san!
Could I borrow your cellphone for a moment?
Ah, sure, but...
Who would you be calling at a time like this?
Oh, you're right.
It's better to wait.
Sorry about that, thank you.
No, it's no problem.
The pair of dragons.
This is it!
So, we're supposed to find a rock in the
shape of a fox somewhere near here?
But there's nothing that's shaped like that.
I wonder where it could be.
That's the Fox Rock there.
Where?
That rock?
But it's not shaped like a fox.
It's the shadow.
The shadow?
Ah, a fox!
I see, the rock didn't make the shape of a fox—the shadow did.
And, right there just ahead of its mouth. That rock is the Light Rock.
There's a crevice where someone's affixed a mirror.
If it wasn't for the angle of today's evening sun...
The light wouldn't be reflected from the crevice.
Let's move this rock and see what's there!
Is the treasure inside that?
Yeah, it has to be.
Genta kun, Ayumi-chan, be careful.
Don't worry, we're OK.
The path breaks off in two directions.
It's the right path.
Right at the next fork too.
Another right after that.
And then left and another left.
Right, right, right, left, left, right?
Right, right, right, left, left, correct?
Why are you shouting?
I'm sorry, I just got excited.
Next is this way, right?
We'll be there soon.
And after the final left...
Where is this?
Pretty!
This is where the treasure is.
This light is probably...
The light of the moon shining through
the gaps in the rocks on the ceiling.
It looks so romantic.
So, Conan, where's the treasure?
Over there.
Here, eh?
Let's open it.
It's here!
That's far enough!
Good work.
Ai-chan!
Mitsuhiko-kun!
Are you both all right?
We're fine.
Hand that over to us.
If you do, we'll return the woman and the children.
Young mistress!
Do it quickly!
Dad?
In such an uncanny location as this, wouldn't it be
best to put an end to any more disgraceful pretenses?
Mouri-san?
Why don't you come out too, Shigeru-san?
You? What are you doing here?
Shigeru-san?
Shigeru-san, your name isn't really Kawaguchi Shigeru, is it?
Shigeru san's pendant and Kimiko-san's cellphone
strap both have the same kind of initials on them.
Kimiko-san's strap says "K.K."
However, Shigeru-san's pendant says "A.T. "
And in addition...
Even though tickets for the steam train were
difficult to get, you were able to obtain them easily.
Could that mean you have a connection
to some influential person in the area?
Come to think of it, that person giving a speech in
front of the station, Takahashi Hisamichi-san...
He was an influential person in the area, announcing
his candidacy for the prefectural assembly.
And also...
To think such a splendid father could have a son like that.
Yeah, Atsushi-kun, isn't it?
Takahashi Hisamichi's son's name was "Atsushi".
Takahashi Atsushi.
His initials would be "A.T."
Just what I should expect from a great detective.
I am Takahashi Atsushi.
You've been trying to stop the culprits the whole time, haven't you?
When Kimiko-san and the others were taken captive...
Officer! Hurry, this way!
That was your voice.
Just like you said, we should have everything out in the open now.
Isn't that right, old man?
Idiot!
That person!
He was the one speaking in front of the station!
Atsushi-san knew his father was
after Kimiko-san and tried to stop him.
Yeah, I learned that yesterday.
I don't care if you need to be a bit rough,
but we absolutely must get that thing.
I went to Shin-Yamaguchi station so I could tell her that.
Why would you do something like that?
Isn't it obvious? He did it to protect
the person he cares for, Kimiko-san.
What did you say?
At the station, Kimiko-san seemed to be acting unusually worried.
As if she was concerned that someone might see her with him.
Our relationship...
We knew he'd be completely opposed to it.
Of course!
That family has kept our area's treasure for themselves!
But I think different from the Kobayakawa's.
That money should be used for public projects!
So our area could prosper!
Don't be ridiculous!
To go so far as to take children hostage!
Let them go.
All right, you can go now.
Old man...
Atsushi-san.
Kimiko.
Kikkawa-san, where are you going?
Kikkawa-san?
Just as I thought, it was you, wasn't it?
You were the one told Takahashi-san about the treasure.
Conan took a look at your cellphone...
And he told me there was no record of a call to the police.
And here, in this cave...
The reason you shouted out the route...
Was to inform Hisamichi-san and the
others who were following us from behind.
It can't be.
I'm sorry, young mistress.
My son had heavy losses in the stock market.
And the company he took out a huge loan from
was a credit company owned by Takahashi.
He told me he would cancel the debt in exchange
I'm truly...
Truly sorry.
Kikkawa-san.
What kind of joke is this?
This thing.
What is this thing?
This is the treasure?
Are you trying to make a fool of me?
This is...
A letter written by one of the
ancestors of the Kobayakawa house.
Please read it.
"I am studying here under Yoshida Shouin-sensei.
"No matter what kind of age may be approaching
us, I know a treasure that will never change."
"The sensei says, 'It is the goals we have in
life that are the fountainhead of all things.'
"It is having a purpose in one's life that gives rise to everything.
"According to his teachings, we students
with the will to make the country better...
"Shall come to see how we can make things different in the real world."
"From here on, no matter how bitter the winds that may
sweep over our world, our greatest assets will be our wills.
"That's what can change the people, and
give them the power to change the country."
"I must rely on my ability with my writing brush in
order to communicate this to the generations to come."
The power to change the country.
That's it.
KAERU - BUY
It wasn't a treasure that could buy (kaeru) the country.
CHANCE
It was a treasure that could change (kaeru) the country.
Those who are unable to solve my riddle...
Do not meet the requirements to inherit the words of my ancestor.
Shut up!
Takahashi Hisamichi!
What value does your will have?
I asked you what price it carries.
If money is enough, is your will for sale?
A will that can be bought with money...
What's the meaning of that?
If your will can be bought with money...
Then it will vanish along with that money.
Am I wrong?
So this is the Shouka Sonjuku? (Village School
under the Pines, where Yoshida Shouin taught)
The people behind the Meiji Restoration
studied many different things here.
He turned himself in?
Yeah.
Takahashi Hisamichi-san did kidnap you and the others.
However, it seems Kimiko-san is denying that it was a kidnapping.
How naive of her.
At any rate, what a waste.
Yeah, that stamp you mean?
As for the old stamp her grandfather had affixed to the letter...
That stamp had a printing error—the
characters on it were printed upside down.
It seems it's something that collectors
have paid tens of millions of yen for.
Kimiko, if you were going to send a letter to the
future, how much postage would you need?
That stamp was his answer to that riddle.
And, for his descendants who find that letter...
It would provide the funds to try and accomplish
whatever great things they have the will to do.
I will definitely get these pasted together.
I'll find the will!
Uncle...
Is that the price of your will?
Next Conan's Hint:
TASTING