The curtain rises on a mysterious new era...
The Monday 7:00 reasoning show.
Included in the high-priced wine is...
An important and enigmatic message.
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
My my, if it isn't Shiratori-san.
Welcome to my mountain retreat.
Honjou Murozou (42)
Apparel Company President
Please enjoy yourself to your heart's content this evening.
I should be saying that. It was very kind of you to have invited me.
By the way, what about Mouri-san?
Here's Mouri with some "grand vin"!
Dad!
Hey, hey...
It's not good to shake that wine!
Why not?
There won't be enough time for the dregs to settle back out.
Dregs?
The tannins and the pigmentation agents that collect at
the bottom of the bottle will make the wine taste bad.
Heh, it's all right.
More importantly, I'm honored that you agreed to come.
I'm sure Hirose-sensei will be very pleased as well.
It's an honor for me as well.
Considering he's the president of the national wine association...
And the recipient of a prestigious French medal...
It's an honor to be invited to participate in
Hirose-sensei's 70th birthday celebration.
Ah, you there.
Yes?
Could you please explain to Mouri sensei
the arrangements for this evening?
The truth is, I was thinking of asking Mouri sensei
if he would mind performing in a short skit.
How about it?
That will be no problem.
Excuse me for a moment.
Let's see, this is the scenario.
Dad, are you sure this will be OK?
Leave it to me.
Indeed.
You hid it in the trunk of the car.
The culprit is you!
That's wrong.
You should have another line before that.
Ah, that's true.
Oh, brother.
Why does it have to be me?
The ropeway goes all the way up to the summit.
There's a great view, so why don't you check it out?
We'll do that.
Let's go, Conan-kun.
Why are you here when you weren't invited?
Did you come to pick a fight with me?
Well, Akamaru?
I heard that it was a magnum of 1959 Pétrus.
Akamaru Gorou (50)
Translator
Yeah, it's the best quality product that you
will probably drink in your entire life.
Oh, you think you can appreciate the taste?
And yet, the other day, you weren't able to
detect the unusual taste of that Neuf du Pape.
At any rate, I feel sorry for Hirose-sensei.
What, with this being his long-awaited 70th birthday celebration.
Just as I thought, I should have been the presenter.
Screw you!
Conan-kun, let's go.
Today will be a memorable day, when your true
abilities as a wine connoisseur will be revealed.
I'll be happy seeing you embarrassed before such a large crowd.
Conan-kun.
What.
There!
I don't see anything...
You were worried about where to conceal the body...
So you hid the body in the trunk of the car.
Oh, and then your wife, who wasn't aware of its presence...
Drove the car.
You've underestimated me, haven't you?
Me, the great detective, Mouri Kogorou.
Could you move over a bit?
Ah, excuse me.
Oh, you're back awfully early.
The truth is, I wanted to spend more time looking...
But Conan-kun suddenly said he had a stomachache.
What are you doing?
Ah, see...
I'm looking for something I lost.
I guess it must be inside the house.
Excuse me, what about—?
Oh, just put it over there.
Say, do you happen to know what happened to that man?
The man in the mustard-colored suit.
You were talking to him about something, right?
Yeah, we were having a serious conversation, weren't we?
But he's already gone home.
I see.
Of course, I can't accuse you of being the culprit
based solely on circumstantial evidence.
Let's see, er...
"Material evidence."
Material evidence is required.
Did you find it?
Nope.
By the way, when did you guys get here?
At 4 o'clock.
Huh?
I lost something...
You again?
This thing you lost wouldn't happen to be
a hamster or something like that, would it?
And you're thinking it might have slipped in here?
That's not it. It's a ball.
The key requires a fingerprint comparison...
So no one except Honjou-san could have come in, you see.
Is that right?
Wait there!
Koike-san...
Don't worry about the preparations for the party.
Could I ask you to find this boy's ball instead?
Until then, why don't you watch TV or something up on the 2nd floor?
KAMEN...
YAIBA!
Do you like Yaiba, little boy?
My grandson likes it too.
He's just started kindergarten this year though.
Yeah, I love it.
It's useless. There's no way I can remember these long lines.
That's why I asked you if this would be OK.
Why don't you ask Honda san if it's all
right for you to just do a regular speech?
If I can.
Conan-kun!
Did your stomachache get better?
Yeah, somehow.
Gotta go to the restroom!
Conan-kun?
Ah, Honjou-san.
Is it all right if we convert Mouri-san's skit into a regular speech?
It seems he can't remember the lines.
I guess it can't be helped.
But, before that, may I have the privilege
of a few words with Mouri-sensei?
Is this...
I see!
He must have concealed Akamaru-san here temporarily.
And while I was going around searching inside the house...
He moved him somewhere else, in
case he was unfortunately discovered.
It must be in a completely secure location.
The wine storeroom!
Thank you so much for coming such a long way, Hirose-sensei.
The gratitude is all mine.
For hosting such a grand party on my behalf...
Hiroso Shinya (70)
Wine Critic
Honjou-kun, everyone—my sincere thanks.
That person is today's guest of honor.
The president of the national wine association, Hirose Shinya-sensei.
So that's the French medal.
In celebration of Hirose sensei's 70th birthday and in hopes
that he will continue to play an active role hereafter...
Cheers!
It's delicious!
Mouri-san, please hurry up and memorize this copy of your speech!
Well then, everyone...
Let's now savor the highest-quality Bordeaux
wines that I have chosen for this evening.
Our initial selection...
A 1985 Chateau Haut-Brion.
Is that one expensive?
Yeah, it's more than 100,000 yen per bottle.
Oooh! I'm looking forward to that!
The value of a wine shouldn't be judged solely by its cost.
Please take one.
It has a mellow but elegant character.
Delicious!
Mouri-san, it's not just the flavor of the wine...
It's important to enjoy the aroma and the coloring as well.
Next, we have a Chateau Mouton Rothschild.
This one is a 1982.
There's a pretty picture on the label.
That's called "Etiquette."
Etiquette?
Yes, for Mouton's etiquette...
Each year a different well-known painter or artist draws one.
It's famous for its artistic taste.
The etiquette for 1970 was drawn by Chagall.
Wow!
This is a 1992 Chateau Le Pin.
A 1986 Chateau Lafite Rothschild.
And a 1990 Chateau Margaux.
Hirose-sensei...
And so, congratulations!
Tell me about the incident that
occurred in Kusaka Shouhei's wine cellar.
Yeah! If I hadn't been there, that might have gone unsolved, huh?
Sensei, excuse me for a moment.
Ah, Honjou-kun.
What is it?
I haven't seen Akamaru-kun.
Akamaru-san?
A translator of French literature.
He's also famous for being a wine critic.
It seems he got here around 3 o'clock.
Why would you know something like that?
I just happened to see him.
Isn't that right?
Ah, yeah.
He's terribly sorry he couldn't come to your long-awaited celebration.
He said to give you his regards, Hirose-sensei.
I see. In that case, it can't be helped.
Well then, I have some preparations to make.
So, about that case...
Yes, yes.
Ah, Conan-kun!
Huh?
Conan-kun's stomach is bothering him.
He's probably been drinking too many cold beverages.
Dad, are you all right?
That was close.
I'm fine, I'm fine.
No problem!
Little boy!
Was this your ball?
It was in the corner of the parking lot.
That's it.
Thank you very much.
For half a century...
It has been waiting patiently until it has come to us now.
A gem in a bottle...
This!
A 1959...
A magnum bottle of Chateau Petrus.
1959!?
And a magnum!?
Let me offer this now to Hirose-sensei.
Thank you, Honjou-kun.
This makes me extremely happy.
To tell the truth, this should have been
uncorked and decanted a few hours ago.
But when it comes to a wine of this caliber, it should
be fully enjoyable even if we uncork it now.
What's this?
Dad, it must have been from that time!
Excuse me!
I was unintentionally careless.
Ah, it's all right.
After half a century, even if I pour it directly into the glasses...
I contend that we will find it just as satisfactory.
Will that be OK?
Wine should be treated like a woman.
Well now, sensei...
What's wrong?
The dregs have been mixed.
The flavor is off too.
That shouldn't be.
May I try also?
Go ahead.
Very well.
It's true.
How?
Someone must have shook it.
Someone shook it? We're not amateurs here!
Perhaps the temperature in the storeroom got too high.
That's also impossible.
The temperature in the storeroom is kept
perfectly regulated through computer control.
Well, it's a mystery then.
Could this be...
By some chance...
When Akamaru-san made fun of him over something,
Honjou-san flew into a rage and killed him.
He then hid Akamaru-san in the wine barrel by the tennis court.
However...
Since I was loitering around...
In order to conceal it to a more secure location...
He moved the body from the tennis court into the wine storeroom.
Even so...
Akamaru-san, who he thought was dead, regained consciousness.
And he noticed the Petrus had been placed
upright so that the dregs would settle.
Pétrus...
This will teach you...
Honjou!
Since Akamaru-san hasn't yet made an appearance...
He may have lost consciousness again.
Or in the worst case...
How can I get into the wine storeroom?
Honjou-san is the only one who can open the door.
That's it!
What the heck could have happened?
The wine is suddenly making me drunk.
Dad?
This is the famous Sleeping Kogorou!
That's Sleeping...
Honjou-san, you've fallen into a trap, haven't you?
Trap?
That's right.
Someone who is jealous of you, Honjou-san,
must have come to this party to embarrass you.
They secretly snuck into your wine storeroom...
In order to ruin that wine.
T-That's right!
That must be it!
Who did it?
Ah, but that's impossible.
In order to get into the wine storeroom...
It makes a comparison with my fingerprint.
Most likely the culprit is someone who's
familiar with your security system.
And it's possible they might still be hiding in
there, which is where the remaining wine is.
That's terrible!
We need to stop them!
That's a sacrilege against the wine!
Let's all go to the storeroom together.
Ah, no. I'll go by myself.
It's dangerous.
You don't know what the culprit will do if you back them into a corner.
And when you encounter them, they might have a broken wine bottle.
Ah, no...
I'll go as well!
Me too.
Let's hurry!
Save the wine!
Hurry to the storeroom!
Me too!
Akamaru-san!
Please wake up!
Hurry!
Call for an ambulance!
Ah, right!
What does this mean, Honjou-kun?
It's...
Honjou-san...
I'm going to call the police.
That guy was ridiculing me!
He said I didn't have the proper refinement or quality of character.
And that I didn't have the qualifications to call myself a wine lover.
Honjou-san...
Are you truly a wine lover?
I love it!
I don't think so.
A wine storeroom.
That's a sacred place for a wine lover.
For one to use it in order to conceal a crime...
That's unreasonable.
Happily, Akamaru-san was still alive.
And the case was closed.
Perhaps...
The true victim in this case might be...
The thing whose taste was ruined when it got involved
in the dirty fighting between human beings...
That bottle of wine.
The sweetness is very mellow...
Just as you would expect, a vintage wine is exceptional.
How much did that cost?
It was 10,000 yen, but...
Without Dad knowing, I asked the person at the store to switch it...
With a 1,000 yen one.
Tres bien!
It's lucky for us that you can't recognize the taste.
Next Conan's Hint:
Kudo Shinichi