Say are you all right, Conan-kun?
I'm fine...
I took some cold medicine that Professor Agasa gave me.
But, your voice sounds awful...
We should head back so you can look after the house with me.
It'll be OK.
With the miracle drug this kid took earlier,
a little cold like that will clear up in no time.
What was it, this "miracle drug"?
Hey, it better not be that stuff you brought over
when we first met you back at the detective office.
It was that Chinese liquor Baigar, wasn't it?
No, no!
This medicine will be much more
effective than something like that alcohol.
Right, kid?
Still, are you sure this is all right?
The person we're going to meet wrote in the
letter that they had something to tell Kudo-kun.
Won't they be disappointed if we come without Kudo-kun?
Is that so?
They claimed to have found a mistake in the deduction
behind a murder case Kudo-kun solved a year ago...
And wanted to meet to discuss it.
And, based on that mistake with his deduction...
They reinvestigated from scratch and are planning
to disclose the real truth behind the case to us.
Well, I e-mailed Kudo about it.
Maybe he'll show as well.
Shin'ichi might?
But, why would the letter be sent to your place?
That might be because I'm Kudo's best buddy.
Well, even if they tried to get in contact with me by letter or phone...
The person living in my house right now isn't me.
In frustration, they sent a letter to Hattori, since
he's a high-school detective like me, but...
What was it? The mistake in my deduction.
If I'm not mistaken, the sender was...
The letter's from Okuda Makoto-san, whose address
is in East Okuho village on the outskirts of Okuho city.
You know him?
Yeah...
When I investigated a murder case that happened in that village...
I think he was the young guy from the village who helped me out.
What's that? Have you caught a cold?
Well, a letter addressed to you was enclosed,
so I'll bring it along when I come see you.
You can read it properly then.
In any case, if he's written bad things about your reasoning,
that'll be the perfect thing to make you shake that cold.
I only had that one case in East Okuho village, but...
A reasoning mistake?
That has me worried...
A desperate crisis...
A splendid revival reverses the conclusion to a case!
When Shin'ichi strangely loses his memory...
He can no longer assist Heiji with his reasoning abilities!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
What?
He's gone missing?
Is that true?
Yeah, the search request was issued half a year ago.
Well, since Makoto-kun was always attracted by the big city...
The people of the village say he must have left home
and found a part-time job or something in the city.
Okuda Makato (19)
So, what did you need Okuda Makoto-kun for?
I got a letter from him last week.
He said when Kudo investigated a murder case that occurred
in this village a year ago, he made a mistake in his deduction.
He wanted to meet and discuss it.
Who did you say?
Like I said, he told us to bring Kudo Shin'ichi with...
What's going on?
That liar!
Are you guys friends with that liar!?
Liar?
Here now, young master.
In any case!
If it's about that ordeal, go to the village police box.
We have nothing to say to you people.
Jeez, what the hell did that detective kid do?
Ran-chan, did Kudo-kun tell you anything about it?
No...
Where's Conan-kun?
Ah, that brat said he was heading back to the inn ahead of us.
His cold must be getting worse or something.
Then, I'll head back to the inn as well.
I'm worried about him being alone.
Well, I bet he just didn't want me to go to the crime scene and
point out the mistake in his deduction in front of everyone.
Dear Kudo Shin'ichi-sama...
I've uncovered proof that you were mistaken in your deduction.
In order to avoid wounding your pride as a detective...
Can you come see me alone?
The place will be the mountain hut where you and I first met.
- Okuda Makoto.
Hello...
Excuse me!
The cold medicine the professor gave me isn't having any effect all.
Is that Kudo Shin'ichi?
He's disguising his voice...
Who is this?
It's been locked!
Hey!
Wait!
Damn it!
This cold is hurting my throat and I can't yell...
The window...
And the door...
How do I get out of here?
This feeling...
It couldn't be...
Hey, Professor...
Do you know where the bottle of
medicine I put in this drawer went to?
Ah, you mean that cold medicine?
Well, that's what the container said, but...
The contents were a drug that I created.
You didn't take one, did you?
No, you see...
Shit...
If I can't get out of here quickly...
A prototype antidote for Apotoxin 4869!?
Yeah, that's right!
I created it to secretly test on Kudo-kun
the next time he came to stay over.
A miracle cure that would restore his body, once
reverted to that of a child by Apotoxin 4869...
Back to that of a high-school student!
Hurry and call him!
If he happens to change back to normal in front of the others...
Tha'll be no joke!
No way...
Conan-kun hasn't returned to the inn yet?
Yeah, and when I asked the people in the village, they said
they saw a boy wearing glasses go into the forest by himself.
Well, why don't you just call his cellphone?
It's no good.
We're out of range here.
What's that guy up to?
And Conan-kun even has that terrible cold...
That brat's always causing trouble.
Sorry, Officer, we'll put off going to the crime scene until later.
Yeah.
Later then.
Conan-kun!
Where are you?
Come out!
Don't tell me there was something in that letter addressed
to him that asked him to go to some strange location...
Hey!
Did you hear?
What about?
There was a guy floating stark naked in the lake.
Ah, I sure did.
My mom is bringing him a blanket right now.
Hey!
It wasn't an elementary-school student, was it?
No...
It was a young man, probably a high-school student.
A high...
A high-school student?
There, there!
That guy with the blanket.
Shin'ichi?
Shin'ichi!
What?
Why are you here, Shin'ichi?
Shin'ichi?
Is that my name?
What kind of nonsense are you saying?
You're the high-school detective of the East, Kudo Shin'ichi.
No one's going to laugh at a stupid joke like that.
Detective?
Don't tell me that Kudo-kun...
Lost his memory?
I don't know...
Who I am...
Or where this is...
Shin'ichi.
Hey, now that I look closer, isn't this guy that Kudo Shin'ichi?
If that's so, we shouldn't have bothered rescuing him.
Hey, what did you say?
Could you lend me something to wear?
It seems I'm not wearing anything.
That's cool.
I'll lend you my extra set of clothes.
Wow, his voice is awfully hoarse...
Just like Conan-kun.
That's right!
We have to hurry and find Conan-kun.
No, we don't have to worry about that any—
No, because, the thing is, you see...
He took a train and went home before us?
All alone?
Y-Yeah!
That kid told me about it before we went to
the village office, but I completely forgot.
He said it would be bad if his cold got
any worse, so he decided to head home.
But, even if he goes back home to the
detective office, there's nobody there!
I think he mentioned that he'd be staying
with that old man Agasa, or something...
Why didn't you tell us that earlier?
Didn't I just tell you I forgot?
In any case, this location is out of cellphone reception range.
If we're going to verify where that brat is, we'll have
to head back to the inn where they have a land line.
And since he can't remember anything, we'll have
to take this bothersome detective kid with us.
You might as well give up trying to return his memory.
I bet he met up with that thing in the forest.
Forest?
You'd better hope not.
Hey!
Wait a minute!
What did they mean by the "thing in the forest"?
Wow!
Heiji's clothes look pretty good on you.
Don't you think, Ran-chan?
Where did Ran-chan go?
As for Ran, it looks like she's more concerned
with that four-eyed brat than this detective kid.
What!?
You gave him the wrong medicine?
It wouldn't happen to be what that little
girl made at the festival that time?
Yeah, that's right.
The antidote for that Apotoxin 4869 that turned Shin'ichi into a child.
In other words, that drug will turn
him back into a high-school student.
I mistook the drugs that Ai-kun made for cold
medicine and inadvertently gave it to him.
It wasn't exactly "inadvertent," old man!
More importantly, is it really true that Shin'ichi has lost his memory?
Yeah, it seems he can't remember anything.
It may be best that he's like that for the time being.
It'll be easier for him to handle various
things that come up in his original form.
Idiot!
That drug is just a prototype.
Though I may have made a small measurement error...
The range of its effectiveness will be 24 hours at most.
24 hours?
If he doesn't regain his memory before then, it'll turn bad.
Why?
As for his memory, he'll have plenty of time after he shrinks again...
What kind of brain-dead things are you saying?
If someone else with memory loss appears,
someone's definitely going to discover...
That the two of them are one in the same.
Especially her.
Guess so.
If that happens, she's going to force him to explain no matter what.
Who forced him to take that sort of drug, and for what reason...
And when she knows the truth of what happened...
Do you think she can keep it to herself?
At any rate, for now, in order to avoid
putting her in such a dangerous position...
Can you get him back here before he transforms into a child again?
After that, I'll do what I can.
Yeah, leave it to me.
Say, Hattori-kun...
Why are you whispering?
Let me see the phone.
Ah, they hung up.
Well, it seems he took some medicine and is
sound asleep in bed, so they said not to worry.
That's good, I guess...
In that case, let's have dinner and get to sleep early ourselves.
We should get back to Beika tomorrow.
Weren't we going to hang around here for a couple of days?
Change of plans.
We need to get Kudo examined by a doctor soon.
In that case, shouldn't we take Kudo-kun along to the crime scene?
That might help him remember something.
What kind of moronic idea...
Wait, that's a good idea as well...
This is nasty.
The interior of the house is really messy.
The young master insisted that the room
be left as it was at the time of the crime.
Shiroyama Kazuma (46)
Police Officer
Young master?
Young master Daiki, who was staying over at a relative's house
on the night of the incident a year ago, escaped from the trouble.
That's the brat we met at the village office.
Who are these people on either side of him in the photograph?
Young master Daiki's parents, who both lost their lives in the incident.
Hinohara Takinori san, who was the village
mayor at the time, and his wife, Shouko-san.
Mayor Hinohara was a very easygoing person
and was popular with the people in the village.
He served as the village mayor for roughly 20 years.
That's why the tragedy from one year ago
has so distressed all those in the village.
Then, these black footprints were from the case?
Yeah.
The criminal stabbed the wife in the middle of
the stairs and got her blood on their shoes.
The marks here are from them walking around the room.
How awful...
These footprints go on for quite a while.
To that veranda, huh?
What a remarkably spacious veranda.
The bloody footprints turn back here.
I see why.
The mayor was forced to fall from here to his death.
Was the murder weapon found? Or was anything taken?
There were no bladed weapons found inside the house.
Some jewelry and antiques were found to be missing, though.
All that remained were the bloody footprints in the room and matching
prints making a round trip from the back door to the asphalt roadway.
Were those really the only footprints that were found?
Yes.
Leading up to the day of the incident, it had been
raining, which made the ground soft and muddy.
That means that, after killing the mayor and his wife, they returned
to their car with the murder weapon and the stolen valuables.
It must have been a robbery-murder.
So, who did Kudo say was the culprit?
Don't tell me he named some innocent
person as the robbery-murder culprit?
No, he said...
Double suicide!
This person, Kudo Shin'ichi, deduced that it was a
forced double suicide instigated by Mayor Hinohara.
Forced double suicide?
Say, who are you?
A classmate of Makoto—the boy who was being
cared for in this house after his parents passed away.
Look, Makoto is there in the picture too.
Behind the mayor.
Wait a minute.
This Makoto wouldn't be Okuda Makoto?
Yes, that's right.
Hikawa Moegi (19)
Makato's Classmate
Since he was the first to discover the bodies,
Okuda Makoto was the primary suspect.
However, because he was taking a university entrance exam
and was staying at a city hotel at the time of the crime...
He was instantly cleared of suspicion.
In that case, let me ask you this: Where is Makoto-san now?
Despite sending a letter stating he had discovered a mistake in
Kudo's deduction and even after telling us to bring him here...
Why are they still saying that he's gone missing?
It's not that he's gone missing...
Makoto has probably been killed.
What did you say?
What do you mean?
The villagers are saying that Makoto is
working part-time jobs in the city, but...
The inheritance he received as an adopted
child of this family was considerable.
Then, you're saying someone killed him in order
to get their hands on the inheritance money?
Yeah...
If that somehow weren't the case, there's no way
I wouldn't have heard from Makoto for half a year.
And the one who killed him was probably...
The forest...
"The forest"...?
In that case, who sent me that letter, and for what reason?
And, what was the mistake in Kudo's deduction?
The motive behind Mayor Hinohara's forced double suicide was...
The desperation he felt after his
doctor diagnosed him with cancer.
That's what Kudo kun said a year ago,
but the real situation poses a problem.
Who are you?
I'm a reporter for the Touto Shinbun, Kawauchi Misato.
Kawauchi Misato (36)
Newspaper Reporter
Excuse me, but the door was open, so I came on in.
So, what was the problem in that?
Later, a nurse at the hospital let slip some information to me.
It was cancer, but the tumor was benign.
The mayor had been pleased to hear it
could be completely resolved via surgery.
What did you say?
Hey, Kudo, what does this mean?
Explain yourself!
Hey, I'm talking to you!
I don't know.
I can't remember...
Anything.
Kudo...
I see!
I finally get it.
That's why the people in this village hate this detective kid.
Yeah.
He's the dreadful person who sullied
the name of everyone's beloved mayor.
But that's frightening...
If that's true, doesn't that mean the real
criminal is still around here somewhere?
The rumor among the villagers is that it was
done by the thing that lives in the forest.
Hey, I heard someone else mention that earlier—what is it?
What is it that lives in the forest?
It's a legend that's been handed down in this area.
Legend?
I've heard it many times since I was a child.
If you encounter him in the forest, don't look in his eyes.
If you do, you'll be cursed...
And you'll be enslaved by the Shiragami-sama.
Sh-Shiragami-sama?
What is it, Ran-chan?
Nothing, I just had a strange feeling.
But isn't that just some ordinary folklore tale?
It's true that the story of the Shiragami-sama is...
A legend that's been handed down in this area about a local
guardian deity who punishes those who lay waste to the land.
Nine years ago, at this lake, a young woman...
Lost her life.
No way...
Is there really something in the forest?
Yes.
That girl went into the forest and never came home...
And on the evening of the third day that
the entire village spent looking for her...
The exhausted villagers started spreading a rumor.
She had defied the ancient law.
By venturing into the forest on a dark night, the girl...
Roused the anger of the guardian of the forest, the
Shiragami-sama, and received her punishment.
And then...
When the girl's father heard the rumor...
He shook off those who tried to stop him, and
ran into the forest as the day drew to a close.
He was to never be seen again.
Two days passed.
Someone who was walking in the forest lost their
footing, fell into the lake, and nearly drowned...
But they found the girl's body there.
If I remember correctly, I think her name was Okuda Tamako.
Okuda?
That's right.
She was the little sister of Okuda Makoto, who sent you that letter.
Then, the father who went into the forest to search...
Yes, that was Makoto's father.
He has never been found.
It could be that the Shiragami-sama got Makoto's father as well...
But, come on, there's no reason to decide some fictional thing did it.
I didn't believe it either.
But...
But I saw it!
Up in a tree, dyed crimson by the evening sun,
sitting silently, sneering, baring its teeth...
That white-haired monster!
What are you saying?
Couldn't you have just mistaken a monkey or something?
It wasn't a monkey!
A person from the town hall saw it last week also!
But, isn't that strange?
Why would that creature need to kill the mayor and his wife?
Did they go into the forest at night?
The village redevelopment.
Mayor Hinohara was planning to build
a large tourist facility in the forest.
I see.
That's how he earned the wrath of the Shiragami-sama.
Yes, and thanks to that, the plans were withdrawn.
That's despite the plans being proposed by the village hero, Mayor
Hinohara, in order to counter the continuing village depopulation.
Hero?
What, you didn't know?
When he was young, he was an athlete who was even nominated to
be the Japanese representative in track and field at the Olympics.
I can't remember which event it was though.
If you're interested, why don't you go check?
Look in his room on the second floor.
It's true.
It looks like he took the championship in several events.
But they don't say which events they were, do they?
Why are only the medals here?
Did he remove the ribbons?
Huh?
A statue of Niou-sama...
Let me see.
It's pretty heavy.
That was really well made, with lots of intricate detail.
But, where's the other one?
When you talk about Niou-sama (two kings),
there should be a pair of guardian kings.
This one with its mouth closed is Unzou.
Usually Azou, with his mouth open, is placed alongside.
On the night of the incident a year ago, the Azou Niou...
Disappeared from this house along with the wife's jewelry.
I see, so the culprit must have taken it, huh?
Say, were they expensive?
Yeah.
They're the work of a famous sculptor from the Edo period—
nowadays, neither would go for under five million yen.
Five million!?
Wait a minute, isn't that odd?
Why would they only take one?
Wouldn't they be worth more if they were together?
I don't know. However, he was concerned about this point as well...
The one who came to this crime scene a year ago, Kudo Shin'ichi-kun.
Say, Kudo, are you sure you can't remember anything?
Huh? Hey, Kudo!
Ran-chan!
Where are you?
Over here.
Come and see this room.
You'll be surprised.
A picture of Shin'ichi!
This is the photograph from the first time
Shin'ichi was covered in a magazine...
How nostalgic.
They had it enlarged.
Wow, that's really huge.
There are files here on all of the cases that Shin'ichi has solved.
Whose room is this?
It's Makoto's room.
Makoto really worshipped this high-school
detective Kudo Shin'ichi here, you see.
That's why, when he heard that Kudo-kun was to join
the investigation into this case, Makoto was ecstatic.
He said he was sure he'd catch the culprit.
But the conclusion this guy came up with was that
the mayor instigated a forced double suicide.
As you might expect, Makoto was devastated.
He'd lost his mother to an illness when he was little.
And when Makoto was left orphaned, Mayor
Hinohara was the one who adopted him.
They were a typical type-0 family - Mayor Hinohara, his
wife, and young master Daiki were all very generous.
He always said he was very fortunate to be made to feel so at-home.
That's why he couldn't believe the
mayor would ever lay a hand on his wife.
Still, he told himself time and time again that he had to accept it...
Because Makoto still believed that you were a great detective.
However, it's been proven that the great detective was
incorrect in his presentation of the true facts behind the case.
His, conclusion that Mayor Hinohara's motive for murder was his
desperation after his doctor told him he had cancer was wrong.
That's right, and Makoto tried to contact you
multiple times through letters and phone calls...
He was worried that he couldn't get a hold of you.
That's why he went to visit and ask you to
reinvestigate directly, but you weren't home!
Well, that's obvious.
He'd been shrunk and wasn't home.
And now that you're here, you've lost your memory?
What are you playing at?
Leave me alone.
Could you leave me alone in this room for a bit?
I have a feeling that I might remember something.
If that's so...
We'll leave you alone for a while.
Take your time and recall what you can.
Then, you're taking care of the mayor's son,
Daiki-kun, at your house now, Shiroyama-san?
Yes, and Makoto-kun as well until half a year ago.
Say, there was something bothering me earlier.
Why is he still called Okuda Makoto?
If Mayor Hinohara adopted him, should
he not be called Hinohara Makoto?
Yes...
That's how he's referred to in the family registry, but...
He said it would be presumptuous to call
himself by the mayor's family name.
So, Makoto always used his former name, Okuda.
Ah, Kudo-kun's come out.
So? Did you remember anything?
Well, don't lose heart.
I'm sure you'll get your memory back eventually.
I was wondering what kind of ploy you'd come up with.
But it seems that you haven't thought of anything.
Ploy?
Yes, I know all about it, Kudo-kun. About your ulterior motive.
Huh, what's with that face?
Did you think I hadn't found you out?
Well, if you come around and want to confess it all to me,
come and see me at the Kotou Inn where I'm staying.
If you do, I can write more favorably about you in my article...
About the truth that you've tried to keep
hidden—the truth that must not be said.
You can never tell anyone about this.
The truth that must not be said.
What an unpleasant old lady that newspaper reporter is.
What was it? Kudo's ulterior motive?
Well, what we know now is, no matter how we look at it, the
incident couldn't have been anything other than a robbery-murder.
But this detective kid deduced it was a forced double suicide...
And missed the mark on the motive.
And there's one more problem...
In this forest, something of an unknown nature is lurking even now.
Say, Kazuha-chan...
For example, and this is just speaking hypothetically, all right?
Yeah?
If someone you liked suddenly reappeared after
you've waited so long, but had lost their memory...
If it were you, Kazuha-chan, what would you do?
Well...
I'd be crying like mad!
The joy of seeing him after so long and the sadness over his
forgetting all about himself would come welling up together.
If you didn't feel that strongly about it, it wouldn't be
someone you love, but maybe just a normal friend.
I guess you're right.
No, no! What I just said was for someone stupid like me.
I don't feel anything.
I just...
I just feel like Shin'ichi is as far away as always.
It's all right!
When he gets his memory back, everything will be back to normal.
What's the matter with me?
Really?
It's started raining.
This is bad.
Let's run to the inn.
Hurry! Hurry!
Kudo-kun's not in his room?
No, I got up early and his futon was left empty.
It can't be!
Hey!
I just asked the people from the village, and they said they saw
him go into Mayor Hinohara's house early in the morning.
Could it be?
His memory has returned?
Hey! Kudo!
Kudo's shoes and a woman's shoes?
Are you here? Kudo!
Oh, found you.
Did your memory come back?
That's why you came here.
Right, Kudo?
Blood...
What happened?
There's so much blood...
Hey, Kudo!
What is this?
What happened?
I don't know.
I fell unconscious...
And when I came to, I was here.
Was it me?
That person...
Did I do this?
This lady's still breathing.
Jeez, so this is where you went, detective kid...
That's the newspaper reporter!
What happened?
There's blood everywhere!
We'll look for explanations later!
Hurry and call for an ambulance and the police!
Ah, no, no!
It's best if you just call the ambulance.
Why?
This lady's wound...
Didn't someone do this?
Can't you tell by looking?
If we call the police with the situation as it is,
Kudo-covered in blood-will be made the culprit!
No way!
Don't tell me you...
Idiot!
There's no way Kudo would stab someone!
He's been framed.
Someone tried to make it look like Kudo did it.
It seems there are plenty of people in this
village who bear a grudge against him.
More importantly, if Kudo is taken in by the police now...
No matter how innocent he is, there will be
a lengthy investigation and this'll go bad.
There's a possibility that the drug returned
Kudo to his normal state will wear off then.
In any case, Kazuha, call the ambulance.
Uncle, you bring the car over here and we'll hide Kudo in it.
I understand.
Right.
An ambulance siren...
Yeah...
And the sound of a patrol car, too...
They're getting closer.
Who could have called them?
Oh, so that's how it is.
You all had questions about how the murder
case that occurred here a year ago was settled.
And, despite having visited this place last
night, you came here again this morning.
That's when you discovered the newspaper reporter, Kawauchi
Misato-san, who had been stabbed in the abdomen, is that right?
Famous detective Mouri Kogoro-san.
Ah, yeah, well...
And? When you got here, there really was
no one else here except the victim, right?
Y-Yeah!
Right?
Yeah!
Well, they left the murder weapon, and once we check the "gesokon"
in the entryway, we'll know who the culprit was soon enough.
"Gesokon"?
It's a police term for footprints.
But, how will you know from that?
They were left behind in the muddy
ground due to the rain that fell last night.
Both the victim's and the culprit's footprints are deep and distinct.
But, Detective, those may have been our footprints.
No, when you came here, the sun had
come up and the ground was fairly dry.
Your footprints are shallow.
We will know when we compare them
with your shoes that are in the entryway.
What bothers me are the footprints left by the culprit when they
came here while the ground was still muddy this morning...
Why did they leave out the back of the
house after the ground had dried?
Considering the tracks coming after the ground had dried, there
should be four people here, but there only seem to be three.
Furthermore, for some reason, the footprints
of the 4th person leave from the back door.
I wonder if Sleeping Kogoro-san can solve this mystery.
Ah, no...
Still nothing.
All right, Kudo? I know it's a little tight, but be patient.
As soon as I find the real criminal,
you can get out, but you need to wait.
That little girl said the medicine would only
remain effective for approximately 24 hours.
I definitely have to settle this case before night falls without fail.
Ah, Heiji!
I don't want to lie anymore.
She's right, Hattori-kun.
Wouldn't it be better to tell the police the truth
like we should and help them investigate?
These two don't know anything.
Well, we're in a pretty bad situation.
It seems that, before the police came, the only
ones who went to the house were the four of us...
Along with the victim, Kawauchi-san, and that detective kid.
Is that really true?
Yeah.
They searched the perimeter of the house carefully...
But only the footprints from we six were found.
You know, you bought Kudo-kun's shoes
last night at a store in the village, Heiji.
No matter how well you are able to hide
him, won't they figure it out soon?
It was a trick.
Someone asked the two of them to come to that house...
Put Kudo to sleep with some sort of drug, put on his
clothes, and stabbed Kawauchi-san in the stomach.
But, you know, if that's what happened, that someone's
footprints should have been left there too, shouldn't they?
That's why I said it was a trick.
What method could they have used?
Wait a minute...
Since that house should have been locked, how did the culprit get in?
Neither Kudo nor Kawauchi-san had the key on them, did they?
That's right.
When we went last night, that policeman, Shiroyama-san, opened it.
Oh, yeah...
Why would Shiroyama-san have the key to that house?
Young master Daiki entrusted it to me.
Say, does anyone other than you have a key to that house?
As for the keys from the former owners of
the house, Mayor Hinohara and his wife...
I have custody of them.
If anyone else has one, it would only be the adopted
son of the household, Makoto-kun, who's gone missing.
Ah, come to think of it, while Makoto kun was off
in the city taking his university entrance exams...
The person who was helping with the chores at the Hinohara house,
his classmate Hikawa-san, was temporarily given a key as well.
If I remember correctly, the incident occurred on the day
that Makoto-kun was taking his university exam, right?
Ah, yes.
As far as that goes, that girl, Hikawa, could be suspect.
Well, when she was entrusted with the key,
she could have had a duplicate made.
In both the case where Kudo made his deduction mistake
and in the incident today, could it have been that girl?
But what was his deduction mistake?
Certainly enough the inside of that house was completely trashed...
But according to Kudo-kun's deduction,
after Mayor Hinohara killed his wife...
He may have done that himself to
make it look like a robbery-murder.
Idiot—it seems that, like today, at the time of the incident
a year ago, the ground was muddy from the rain, but...
Unlike this time, there was only one set of footprints around the
house making a round trip from the back door to the roadway.
The culprit had walked around inside the house wearing their shoes.
If Mayor Hinohara was planning to make it look like a robbery...
And he left the house wearing those shoes and
then returned to the house still wearing them...
Shouldn't those shoes be somewhere in the house?
I guess so.
If he had thrown the shoes outside the house,
the police would have discovered them already.
Since the distance from the veranda of the house to the
lake is around 30 meters, he couldn't have reached it.
But, wouldn't Kudo-kun have realized all of that also?
Yeah, that's what I've been thinking about since last night...
Ah, no-no-no-no!
I should be thinking about the case today, not the one a year ago.
Even if the culprit had a key and ambushed them in that house...
It would have been impossible for the culprit to have gone
in and out of that house without leaving footprints.
An impossible crime...
A baffling murder trick...
But...
If it were Shin'ichi...
If it were Shin'ichi, I'm sure he'd...
Damn it!
If only Kudo were in his right mind, we could
combine wits and have the answer in no time.
He must have really encountered the Shiragami-sama.
What's this have to do with the Shiragami-sama?
It's what the people from the village said yesterday.
He lost his memory because he met the Shiragami-sama in the forest.
And last night before we went to sleep,
Ran-chan and I asked someone at the inn.
We asked what we should do if someone
had been cursed by the Shiragami-sama.
And they said...
Go into the forest while the sun still shines.
When you see the Shiragami-sama,
call out to him at the top of your voice.
If you continue praying to him with a clear and unclouded heart...
His curse will be lifted.
Although, basically no one has ever put that to an actual test.
But the person at the inn said that
lady newspaper reporter had done it!
Is that so?
Yeah.
They said that a year ago, when she came to
collect information about the incident...
She brought her daughter along and the
girl went into the forest to not return.
Hey!
Ran's gone!
Don't tell me!
She took what we were just saying
seriously and went off into the forest?
Shiragami-sama...
Shiragami-sama!
I beg you, please restore Shin'ichi to the way he was.
If my clouded heart is good enough, I'll give it to you.
Therefore, Shin'ichi...
Make him the real Shin'ichi.
Please, Shiragami-sama!
I found him...
I actually found him...
Wait...
It's no use... I'm too frightened to speak.
Hey! Just now!
Wasn't that Ran-chan's voice?
Something's happened!
It's no good...
My body hurts all over and I can't move
What in the world have I done?
Rushing of into to forest and then carelessly falling...
Such an idiot.
Shiragami-sama...
Please...
Shin'ichi...
Make Shin'ichi the way he was...
Hey!
It's completely covered with pictures and articles of that detective kid!
Huh?
My wounds have been dressed.
Who on earth...
The victim's blood is on his clothes and his
fingerprints are on the murder weapon...
No matter how you look at it, he has to be the culprit, but...
That's it exactly.
This guy is the culprit!
Next Conan's Hint
Shiragami-sama's Curse
Look forward to the next episode
Next time, we'll resolve Shin'ichi's memory!
And the truth behind the case!
Please look forward to it!