One year ago, in East Okuho Village...
I, Kudo Shin'ichi, solved a murder case.
A letter that said I'd made a mistake in my reasoning...
Had been sent to me by way of Hattori Heiji.
Okuda Makato (19)
In order to meet the sender, Okuda Makoto-san...
We went to visit East Okuho Village, but...
Makoto-san's whereabouts were currently unknown.
And, for some reason, it seemed the people of the village...
Harbored a sense of hatred towards Kudo Shin'ichi.
I went alone to the mountain cabin where
Makoto-san had arranged to meet me - however...
Excuse me!
This feeling...
It couldn't be!
I created it to secretly test on Kudo kun
the next time he came to stay over.
A miracle cure that would restore his body,
transformed into that of a child by Apotoxin 4869...
Back to that of a high-school student!
Shin'ichi?
Shin'ichi!
"Shin'ichi"?
Is that my name?
Don't tell me that Kudo-kun...
Lost his memory?
That drug is just a prototype.
Though there may be a slight calculation
error, the range of its effectiveness...
Will be 24 hours at most.
24 hours?
If he doesn't regain his memory before then, that'll be bad.
In that case, shouldn't we take Kudo-kun along to the crime scene?
That might help him remember something.
This person, Kudo Shin'ichi, deduced that it was a
forced double suicide instigated by Mayor Hinohara.
What was the mistake in Kudo's deduction?
The motive behind Mayor Hinohara's forced double suicide was...
The desperation he felt after his doctor diagnosed him with cancer.
That's what Kudo-kun said a year ago,
but the real situation poses a problem.
Kawauchi Misato (36)
Newspaper Reporter
It was cancer, but the tumor was benign.
The mayor had been pleased to hear it
could be completely cured through surgery.
What did you say?
Hey, Kudo, what does this mean?
I know all about it, Kudo-kun.
About your ulterior motive.
About the truth that must not be said.
Was it me?
That person...
Did I do this?
As soon as I find the real criminal,
you can get out, but you need to wait.
I definitely have to settle this case before night falls without fail.
An impossible crime...
A baffling murder trick...
But...
If it were Shin'ichi...
If it were Shin'ichi, I'm sure he'd...
Shiragami-sama! Shiragami-sama!
I beg you, please restore Shin'ichi to the way he was.
Shiragami-sama...
A desperate crisis...
A splendid revival reverses the conclusion to a case!
As Heiji discloses the astounding truth...
Ran can't stop crying for Shin'ichi.
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Sorry, Ran, could you head home before me?
Wait...
I'll catch up with you right away!
Shin'ichi!
He's leaving.
Shin'ichi's...
Shin'ichi's leaving me.
No! Don't go!
SHIN'ICHI!
Where am I?
That's right.
When I found the Shiragami-sama in the forest and ran after him...
I lost my footing.
Huh? My wounds have been dressed.
Who on earth...
Ran-chan!
I've found Ran-chan.
What'd you say!?
Kazuha-chan.
Ah, you're safe!
What's with these bandages?
I fell down in the forest and lost consciousness.
It looks like someone carried me here and treated my injuries.
I bet it must have been the owner of this cabin.
We need to give them our thanks when they return.
No, it looks like the owner of this cabin isn't a good person.
A transceiver?
Heiji! Where are you?
In the room next door.
Come and look. It's quite impressive.
Come over there? But the door's been boarded up.
You can go back outside and come in through the window, can't you?
Ah, I guess we could.
Hey!
What the hell is this?
It's completely covered with pictures and articles of that detective kid!
Yeah, it seems they've really taken a fancy to that "Kudo" guy...
To the point of wanting to kill him.
His photo's been chopped to shreds!
Ran...
Are you sure you didn't see them?
The person who carried you here?
Right.
I did see the Shiragami-sama in the forest, though.
The Shiragami-sama?
Really?
It appears that the owner of this cabin is
none other than the Shiragami-sama.
Look at this.
A white hair from a wig made of polyester.
The Shiragami-sama you met had white hair, right?
Yeah, but he didn't seem to be that bad of a person.
He was scary, though...
That's right.
It seems he was the one who gave Ran-chan medical treatment.
Maybe he was being kind in order to lower your guard,
so that he could do bad things to you afterwards.
Well...
One thing's for certain, he's a dangerous guy.
An empty box of bullets for a handgun...
And the scattered remains of mirrors.
Five or six of them have been smashed.
And the real clincher is...
The nasty words carved into this table.
"Failure means death."
Hey!
If there's an empty box of bullets...
Yeah.
It looks like the Shiragami sama is walking
around with a dangerous object in his possession.
In that case...
That lady newspaper reporter...
When it looked like she'd been stabbed by Kudo-kun...
Could that have been the Shiragami-sama?
Yeah, probably.
It seems he has a grudge against Kudo.
But...
If that were the case, he must have called Kudo and
the woman over to that house and ambushed them.
How did the culprit not leave any footprints near the house?
The ground was even muddy from the rain during the night.
Could he have been lying in wait inside
the house prior to it starting to rain?
Moron.
Even if that were so, he couldn't have left
the house without leaving footprints.
Because of the case that happened there a year ago...
I decided to check around the house last night, but...
It would be impossible to get into or out of the
house without stepping on the ground somewhere.
Furthermore, this morning, before
the ambulance and the police arrived...
I looked around inside the house just in case...
But there was nobody there.
That's true enough...
Oh, yeah...
The ambulance and the police.
Who called them?
Did you hear?
Yes.
It was the same both times.
They said it was a young man with an awfully hoarse voice.
What?
Wouldn't that mean it was Kudo-kun?
The truth is...
The call to the inn where the newspaper reporter,
Kawauchi-san, was staying was just the same...
A young man with a rough voice.
The people there told me that he said he was Kudo Shin'ichi.
You mean Kudo was the one who called out that woman?
And also called the ambulance and the police?
Maybe that guy faked his memory loss and was planning something...
Kawauchi-san said something like that as well.
What?
There's one thing she said last night that bothered me...
Huh, what's with that face?
Did you think I hadn't found you out?
Later, when I went to the inn where she
was staying to ask her about it, she said...
"Kudo-kun's memory loss is fake."
"He's definitely up to something."
I see...
What that woman said last night...
Was she just trying to trick him into revealing himself?
At any rate...
We can be sure that the owner of this house is someone dangerous.
Have the police come here immediately.
Yes.
I think I can find the way out of the forest, but...
As for finding my way back here again...
Then, what if we get the bonfire going again?
You can use the smoke as a landmark.
Bonfire?
Yeah.
Next to that rock that looks like a tombstone...
Those ashes are from a bonfire.
It was burning from before.
He must have been planning to eat dinner...
But when we came here, he got scared and ran away.
Do you think he might have escaped through
the small window in the room next door?
Ah, that window?
But, wouldn't that be too small for an adult to escape through?
A child's footprints.
It was Kudo.
They might have used that letter to call
him here so they could lock him in...
But then, he escaped through that window.
But who could have locked him in
The person who sent the letter, Okuda Makoto,
has been missing for the last half year.
Makoto has probably been killed.
Could Okuda Makoto still be alive?
Or is he dead?
No, wait a minute...
I need to think this through again from the beginning.
That photo of Kudo that's been chopped to shreds...
It seems the culprit has a big-time grudge against Kudo.
And the words on the table.
What would the culprit be doing that would risk his life?
Revenge on Kudo?
The empty box of bullet in the next room.
Most likely the culprit has a handgun.
Even though they must have had plenty of chances to shoot Kudo...
Why haven't they done it?
They used a kitchen knife when they stabbed that old lady, Kawauchi.
Why didn't they want to use the gun?
And the one other thing that's bothering me is...
The mirrors that have been shattered to bits.
Why did they need to break them into so many pieces like that?
Could it be?
Could it be, he...
Say, while you're off calling for the police, there's
a little something I want you to check for me.
But how can I check something like that?
Don't worry.
You can find it just fine using this.
Is this good enough?
I suppose so.
This way, the smoke can be seen even from a distance.
He won't get lost spinning in circles in the forest.
Speaking of spinning in circles, what do you think it was?
The sport that Mayor Hinohara played?
I think it was a track and field event.
Remember when I told you that we asked the people
at the inn about the Shiragami-sama last night?
At the same time, we asked them what
event Mayor Hinohara competed in, but...
They said they didn't remember the name,
but it was one where you spin around.
Spin around?
A track-and-field event where you spin around in circles?
It could be the hammer throw or the discus or something, maybe.
That's right, they said he was good at the ring toss too.
Ring toss?
It seems Mayor Hinohara's son, Daiki-kun,
would brag about it to everyone.
He'd say his father was really good at the ring toss,
and he always got a perfect score of 100 points.
He said 100 points?
Wasn't that the policeman's voice?
Shit!
Hey!
What happened? What's wrong? Hey!
The Shiragami-sama...
The Shiragami-sama suddenly...
I think I saw him...
And all of a sudden I lost consciousness.
Hey!
Your gun holster is open!
It's all right.
They didn't take the pistol.
But why the gun?
Maybe he only bought the bullets but hadn't acquired a gun yet.
Who knows.
I still haven't figured that guy out yet, but...
I've more-or-less figured out the rest of the case.
Let's forget the cabin for now.
Shall we gather everyone together at Mayor
Hinohara's house and solve the mystery?
A high-school detective from Osaka? Hattori Heiji?
You're saying that detective will explain to us police...
The truth behind the incident where
Kawauchi-san was stabbed here this morning?
Yes, that's it exactly.
Before that...
If you're ready to do so, I'd like you to bring forth the person whose
unidentified footprints left with yours through the back door.
Of course, I brought him along...
The owner of those footprints.
Isn't this Kudo-kun?
Why does he have blood on his clothes?
Hey, hey.
You're not going to tell me that Kudo-kun was the culprit?
Among the footprints that were left in front of this house...
If you exclude the footprints of those who were at the inn and
have an alibi, as well as the stabbing victim, Kawauchi-san...
All that remains...
Are this guy's footprints.
The victim's blood is on his clothes and his
fingerprints are on the murder weapon...
No matter how you look at it, he has to be the culprit, but...
That's it exactly.
This guy is the culprit!
In other words...
I mean there was no trick used in this crime at all.
H-Heiji!
What the heck is this?
Some kind of tactic?
It's no tactic.
Like I said, this guy called Kawauchi-san over here on the phone...
And this guy was the one who stabbed her!
Wait a minute!
Wasn't it just this morning that you were so insistent about it?
You said this guy would never stab anyone.
I was scared.
That newspaper reporter...
She said she'd expose the error I made a year ago.
All the prestige and pride I'd built up to this point...
She threatened to rip it all to shreds.
Though I really didn't understand exactly what she meant...
I was scared, scared. And without thinking...
Who is this person?
It's all wrong. He's not Shin'ichi.
The Shin'ichi that I've waited for...
The one who fills my heart...
That's the Shin'ichi I've been longing for.
Wow, it's just like Kazuha-chan said.
My tears...
My tears just won't stop.
Are you actually saying you called that newspaper
reporter, Kawauchi-san, here and stabbed her?
Yes. There's no mistake.
My God, I can hardly believe it.
Your deduction a year ago was magnificent.
You saw through the trick in an instant...
And showed us how to settle the case as fast as lightning.
How could you have done something like this?
You've overestimated me.
I'm not a god. I can hate people, and I can make mistakes.
Just like in that case a year ago...
When I called Mayor Hinohara a criminal
even though he hadn't committed a crime...
Ah, no, it seems you've lost your
memory and can't remember it, but...
As for that incident, we have concrete proof.
Excuse me.
The results of the analysis have arrived,
so I've come to inform you just in case.
Analysis?
The one that boy from Osaka ask me to have done.
To see if the knife that was the murder weapon and
the bits of chain inside the charm the boy had...
Matched or not.
And? How did it go?
Just like you said, they didn't match.
Great! It's just like I deduced!
Charm? You mean that charm?
How could that be connected with the knife?
What was it that you said didn't match?
It was something that we are all born with.
Bequeathed to us by heaven above.
An emblem that never changes throughout our lives.
And in a criminal investigation, because everyone's are different...
They're a mark that provides an extremely
dependable and high degree of proof.
Fingerprints, right?
Yeah.
Who is this?
The Shi...
The Shiragami-sama!
Stay back.
A gun!
It's no use.
Give it up.
It's time for the curtain to close on this costume ball.
Costume ball?
What are you talking about?
Yes, if we want to call it that, the trick in this case would be...
This guy's face.
Really now, how could anyone think the high-school
detective, Kudo Shin'ichi, would ever stab someone.
The first thing I noticed was...
The behavior of that girl there - old man Mouri's daughter.
Even though Kudo, who she has waited so long for, had
appeared, why was she being so cold and distant to him?
Normally she'd stick to him and not let go -
and all the more so if he'd lost his memory.
At the start, I thought she was just trying
to hide her embarrassment, but...
But when I was investigating the culprit's cabin in the forest...
I figured out the reason.
The culprit's cabin?
Yeah, the place with chopped up pictures of Kudo affixed to the wall...
And where mirrors had been smashed into
little pieces and scattered on the floor.
The guy chopped up the photos because he hates Kudo, but as for the
mirrors, there's only one reason for them to be smashed to pieces.
It was something he couldn't stand at all.
His face, Kudo's face, reflected in those mirrors.
Then, you don't mean...
Exactly, he's had plastic surgery.
To become this great detective...
To have this stupid high-school student's face.
Hey, they're...
Identical!
But why Kudo-kun's face?
He requested that I come to that cabin and locked me in.
I think probably so that he could pretend
to be me and commit some sort of crime.
Most likely one that, for me, Kudo Shin'ichi...
Would obliterate me personally and socially.
Obliterate you?
The reason he pretended to have lost his memory was...
In order to get by without answering any questions
put to him by those who might have come with me.
And the reason he got into the lake without clothes was...
For the same reason - so he could pretend to have a hoarse voice.
Even though he could mimic my face...
It wouldn't be possible to have my voice.
And he couldn't predict what sort of clothes I would be wearing.
Heh, I fell in that lake as well, when I escaped from the cabin.
Looks like I've developed a bit of a hoarse voice myself, huh?
Then, the one who called the police and an
ambulance this morning just after the incident?
That was me.
I'd seen him and Kawauchi-san go into this house...
I then considered what the worst possible outcome would be.
In that case, why didn't you go in and stop him?
That's because I couldn't make myself known.
When he was coming out of the house last night,
I noticed a bulge on the back of his clothing.
I was convinced from then that he was carrying a gun.
Well, it couldn't be helped, I guess...
With the words "Failure means death"
carved onto the desk in that cabin.
Yeah.
If he was planning to kill a specific person with that gun...
I could have tried to stop him, but...
If, at the moment he realized his plan had
failed, he was resolved to kill himself...
I would only have a very short interval
where I could try to prevent that.
That's why I took the bullets from Officer Shiroyama's revolver.
And dropped them in front of him.
In order to make him hesitate.
At the point when I appeared before him...
That was probably when he intended to do it.
Isn't that right, Okuda...
No...
Hinohara Makoto-san?
Ma... Makoto-kun?
Are you really Makoto-kun?
Exactly.
It takes time and money to have plastic surgery like this.
For Makoto-san, who had money from his
inheritance and has been missing for half a year...
It would be possible.
In that case...
He must have concealed the gun inside his own room, right?
We brought him here with us, thinking
that would help him recover his memory.
He must have retrieved it when he asked us to leave him alone.
But why?
Why did he have to stab the lady newspaper reporter?
He thought she'd found him out...
When she said that stuff last night.
Huh, what's with that face?
Did you think I hadn't found you out?
He thought she was talking about the
plastic surgery to make him into Kudo.
But I still don't understand.
This morning when we came running over to this house...
Why didn't you say that you had stabbed Kawauchi-san yourself?
If you wanted to pin the crime on Kudo, would
it not have been easier to tell us right away?
It was a test.
Of you guys. As detectives.
If the circumstances all pointed to this
guy, Kudo Shin'ichi, as the culprit...
I wanted to see what kind of deduction you would come up with.
Well, it seems we've seen through that quite splendidly.
Then, what happened in the case a year ago!?
Mayor Hinohara killed his wife?
It was a robbery murder where things were stolen!
A stupid deduction that Mayor Hinohara
committed a forced double suicide?
How could this guy, Kudo Shin'ichi, have said that!?
Kudo wasn't wrong.
It was a forced double suicide.
The culprit's shoes, the murder weapon, his wife's jewelry...
Even one of the expensive Niou statues! None of those were there!
Isn't it obvious that the culprit took those and got away!?
The lake.
After Mayor Hinohara stabbed his wife...
He collected the murder weapon, the jewelry and
the rest together and sank them in the lake.
What are you saying?
It's at least 30 meters from this house to the lake.
How could he throw them in the lake without leaving any footprints?
It wasn't just the murder weapon and the jewelry.
The ribbons from the medals and the ring
from the ring toss game were also gone.
Ring toss?
Isn't it what Mayor Hinohara's son, Daiki-kun, had said?
His father was really good at the ring toss, and
he always got a perfect score of 100 points.
The point values as written on the ring toss
game are 10 points, 5 points, and 2 points.
If you think about getting a perfect score of
100 points, you can't do it without 10 rings.
But here, there are only 9 rings.
And moreover, based on the fact that only
one of the Niou statues was taken...
Plus the fact that Mayor Hinohara was a
former competitor in track and field events...
The answer becomes clear.
The hammer throw.
He used the Niou statue as a weight after stuffing the
murder weapon, the shoes, and the jewelry in a sack...
Then, he used the ring in the place of a handle, affixing the
ribbons from the gold medals to it, and then to the bag itself...
In order to fling it from the veranda to
the lake, similar to the hammer throw.
I see now.
The reason he left one of the Niou statues behind was...
If he'd put both of them in the sack...
It would become too heavy and wouldn't reach all the way to the lake.
T-That's stupid.
Something like that would never make it because of the air resistance.
No, it made it.
The bag, the ribbons, and the ring were all recovered from the lake.
Of course, the wife's blood was found
on the knife's blade inside the sack.
And Mayor Hinohara's fingerprints were detected on the handle.
There's no doubt that Mayor Hinohara
committed a forced double suicide.
It-It's a lie.
In order to keep this all from his son, Daiki-kun...
He tried to make it look like a robbery-murder.
It's a lie!
The mayor, that generous and good mayor...
There's no way he'd kill his wife in a forced double suicide.
Besides, the mayor's cancer was benign.
The claim that he was in despair over learning he had cancer...
That was a downright lie!
After he learned he had cancer...
That's when it came to light.
A different issue.
Mayor Hinohara's blood type...
As a consequence of being examined,
he was told it was actually type-AB.
Wait a second.
If I remember right, we were told the mayor
and his family were a generous type-0 family.
Yeah.
According to Mendel's laws of heredity...
A type-AB person and a type-0 cannot give birth to another type-0.
In other words...
That meant Daiki-kun wasn't Mayor Hinohara's son.
No way...
It can't be.
That's bullshit!
I see.
It would be bad to tell people that was
the true motive behind the murder.
Yeah, that's why the official announcement
said it was because he learned he had cancer.
But...
If that was the case, why didn't anyone tell me!?
I was a member of the family too!
I'm sure I told you.
Kudo-kun asked me to do so.
You must never tell anyone
However, please do explain it to Makoto-san.
When?
Where was it you told me?
The evening after Kudo-kun finished
his investigation and left. Right here.
But, when I think back now...
You'd just been told the truth about Mayor
Hinohara's forced double suicide...
You might have been too far into shock...
And not been paying attention to me.
No way.
If that's true...
Why did I...
For what reason? Even my face...
What was it for!?
Another tragedy caused by unfortunate coincidence.
Seeing my own face covered in tears right in front of me...
I thought...
I would never forget that face.
It would be carved into my heart forever.
So that guy, Makoto, was the Shiragami-sama?
Yeah, he was the second generation one.
The second generation?
The first was his father.
After his own daughter died when she got lost in the forest...
So the other children in the village wouldn't suffer the same fate...
He built that cabin in the forest and lived there as the Shiragami-sama.
That way, he could frighten people from going into the forest.
Three years ago, he died from an injury.
Could it be that stone by the cabin is...
Yeah, Makoto-san's father's grave.
You seem to know an awful lot about it.
When I came here a year ago...
There was another problem in addition to the case.
Kawauchi-san was here to cover the story, and her daughter...
Had gone into the forest and hadn't come back.
We heard about that from the people at the inn.
They said Kawauchi-san went into the forest to look for her.
Yeah, and just when I was thinking of going in to search myself...
Her daughter made it out of the forest on her own.
She said she'd encountered the Shiragami-sama in the forest...
And she'd run frantically from place to place with him chasing her...
Before she knew it, she'd come out of the forest.
I wanted to figure that mystery out before
the murder case, so I went into the forest.
When I saw the Shiragami-sama, I chased after him...
And I came to that cabin.
That's when I came across Makoto-san
in the guise of the Shiragami-sama.
I see now.
So this time you borrowed the costume
from where it was left in that cabin.
Yeah.
My clothes got wet when I fell into
the lake, so that's all I was left with.
Well, looking like this made everyone run away
from me, so it helped me stay concealed I guess.
Still, I feel sorry for Makoto-san.
It'll be all right.
It seems Kawauchi-san wasn't as badly injured as we thought.
If he explains the situation to her later, I think she might forgive him.
She was extremely grateful to the Shiragami-sama
for rescuing her daughter a year ago, after all.
Shin'ichi?
Is something wrong, Kudo-kun?
It's...
Shin'ichi, what's wrong?
Shit! It's coming...
Oh no, it's been almost 24 hours.
I've got to get Kudo away from them quickly!
Ah, that's right!
Since he wanted to ask us some more details about the case...
The inspector invited me and Kudo to go see him.
So, you guys go on to the car ahead of us.
No!
I'm going with you.
Because I...
Because I have to ask Shin'ichi...
I have a lot of things to ask him!
Ran!
Shin'ichi!
Kudo!
Are you OK?
My body...
My body's on fire!
Oh no, you've got a terrible fever.
If this keeps up, I'll return...
I'll return to being Conan again!
If I turn back now in front of her...
It's a cold! A cold!
Remember Kudo said he'd fallen into the lake.
The cold he got then has just come back.
Well, that's probably it, but...
This much pain is definitely not normal.
What's that?
You're saying you need to go to the toilet?
Ah, that's fine, that's fine!
In that case, I'll take Kudo with me to the restroom at the inn.
Kazuha, can you go get my bag for me?
Why do I need to bring your bag?
A change of clothes!
Kudo's really sweating here.
We can't have him wearing this Shiragami-sama costume forever.
Well then, I'm counting on you.
T-Twenty four hours?
Are you serious?
Yeah, that's what the professor's little girl said.
"The range of effectiveness of the drug is around 24 hours."
"Can you please bring Kudo-kun back here before that?"
It's almost that time.
Anyway, if you shrink again, get inside this bag.
Then, I'll make up some clever story and you can come back out.
Leave it to me.
Hey, Heiji!
Kazuha!
Why are you being so sneaky?
Don't come in here, idiot!
This is the men's restroom!
That's true, but we're worried about Kudo-kun.
I even asked a doctor who lived nearby to come.
Ah, it's all fine. Fine.
He just took some cold medicine.
What kind of medicine was it?
Ah well, it was a formula that's been handed down in my family.
Shit!
It's like this every time.
Why is it always like this?
Am I going to change back without
being able to tell her anything again?
Am I going right back to square one again!?
Oh no...
I turned back.
Shin'ichi? What's happening?
Wait, you can't!
Shin'ichi!
Hey, Shin'ichi?
I gotta hurry and hide in this bag...
Shin'ichi, I'm calling you!
Ah, you see...
Ran's going to find out my secret identity!
Shin'ichi?
Shin'ichi!
Oh, no!
In the next stall...
Who?
Shin'ichi, answer me!
Hey now, didn't I already say he was all right?
There's no way he's all right when he's screaming so loud like that!
Step aside!
Please, Hattori-kun!
Ah, you can't! Wait, no, you can't!
Moron!
K-Kudo?
Shin'ichi!
Why are you all being so noisy?
Can't you be more quiet when I'm on the toilet?
Are you feeling better?
Yeah, I feel much better now that that's over.
It does seem that your fever's gone down.
Does it?
Thank goodness, I was worried.
Well now, let's hurry and head home.
Weren't you going to tell the detective the details of the case?
Ah, no, I'll do that after we get home.
That's good. Just in case, maybe you should go to the hospital too.
Yeah.
Well, let's go.
Please excuse us for asking you to come here.
No problem.
Kudo! What the hell happened?
Ah, I'll explain later.
Hey!
Later?
Wait, Kudo!
We got him out of trouble somehow.
It seems he's got his memory back too.
Yep, we saved him.
It was thanks to your remembering the name
of the inn they were staying at, professor.
It stood to reason that he'd come running to the
restroom at the inn if he'd gotten cornered like that.
Haibara?
Why are you here?
There's no time to explain.
In any case, swallow this quickly.
This, could it be?
Yeah, the prototype antidote for that drug
that turned you into a child, Apotoxin 4869.
The same drug that you took yesterday.
Then, I have another 24 hours?
Idiot.
Taking the same drug frequently makes it lose its effectiveness.
Your body is building up a resistance to that drug.
As you continue to take it, its active duration gets shorter.
If you want to keep hiding your true identity...
Get away from those people and return to being...
Edogawa Conan.
So, what was it?
The thing you needed to ask me.
Nothing in particular. I just wanted to say thank you.
You were the one who took care of my injuries, weren't you?
Luckily there was a first-aid kit there in that mountain cabin.
You didn't see them, did you?
I mean, when you were treating my wounds.
When I was wrapping the bandage around your
thigh, I did catch a glimpse of something white.
You did see them! You're the worst!
Idiot! I didn't look on purpose!
They just happened to come into view.
Well, excuse me!
For letting you see something you didn't want to see.
Idiot!
Say, Ran-chan...
Would you like to change seats?
It'll be easier for you two to talk that way.
It's OK! You stay there, Kazuha-chan!
When we get home, I'm giving that guy a judo throw.
Moron.
No. This isn't what I wanted.
What I wanted to ask Shin'ichi was...
What I truly need to ask him is...
Hey!
Is that you, Ran-chan?
Detective Sato and Detective Takagi!
What are you doing?
We just had some business with the Kanagawa prefectural police.
Since that's over with now, I'm having my Mr. Chauffeur drive me home.
Mr. Chauffeur?
What about you guys?
Did you have a case or something?
Sleeping Kogoro-san?
Yeah, more-or-less.
I see. Well, we're in a hurry to get home.
You can tell me about the case some other time!
Well, with an awesome case like that, even if we
don't tell her, she'll see it in tomorrow's paper.
No, I think it probably won't be in the newspapers.
After all, nobody died.
And the culprit is still a minor...
So they can't reveal his name or show a photograph.
And as for the lady newspaper reporter who was stabbed...
It seems she's not going to write about it either.
Lucky, weren't you, Kudo?
What's with that car?
They keep scraping the side of their car against the guardrail.
Maybe they fell asleep?
If they keep it up, there's gonna be a bad accident!
Hey! Wake up!
Hey, you!
Hey! There's something strange about the way he looks!
Get the car out in front of his!
Hey, "in front"? You're not saying...
Now that we're in front, lower your speed bit by bit.
Idiot! I can't do that with a rental car!
Just do it! Hurry!
Hey, Gunpei! Gunpei!
Wait! Don't touch him!
Please step back.
What's with you two?
It's bad.
He's no longer breathing.
Look, Kudo.
There's been hemorrhaging in his eyelids.
Could that mean...
Line marks!
Kudo, this guy was...
Hey!
What's happened?
Ran, there's a tollbooth one kilometer ahead of us.
Call Detective Sato and ask her to setup a blockade there.
Why?
He's dead. The driver of this car.
He's been strangled.
Strangled?
Yeah, while he was driving...
Inside the closed environment of this car.