I set up a blockade at the tollgate just like you said, but...
Are you really saying someone died in their car while driving?
Yeah, and it looks like he was strangled.
Then, wouldn't the culprit have to be someone riding with him?
No, that's the funny thing. The driver was the only one on board.
How could that be?
How do you go about strangling a driver while they're driving?
Beats me.
But, Heiji said that...
Since the body was still warm...
The culprit must be in the area.
That's why Shinichi suggested that, if we block the tollgate
1KM ahead of the scene, we could capture them for sure.
Hattori-kun and Kudou-kun, you say?
And?
Where are those two?
They said they'd narrow down the suspects
and disappeared into the line of cars.
Narrow down?
How can we do that with nearly a hundred cars?
Well, this way we'll get to see them in action, won't we?
The famous high-school detectives.
Three of them.
There are only three cars that are suspicious.
A desperate crisis...
A splendid revival reverses the conclusion to a case!
The two of us reason our way through both the case and love.
What is it that Ran truly wants to ask Shinichi?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Three of them.
There are only three cars that are suspicious.
The rest of the cars will get in the way, so it's OK to let them go.
"Three of them"?
What we learned from the condition of the body was...
It's quite clear that the victim was strangled while driving.
In other words...
The culprit must have brought their car near the
victim's while it was moving and done something.
It's natural to think along these lines, isn't it?
No matter what method the culprit used...
They must have prepared it in advance and gotten on
the highway at roughly the same time as the victim.
I see.
What you're saying is there were only three cars that got on
the highway from the same interchange as the victim, right?
But, are you sure about that?
You could ask them to show you the tickets
they received at the interchange, but...
These days, with ETC (electronic toll collection), they have systems
that let you through the tollgate without getting a ticket.
The victim got on the highway from the same interchange we did.
The ETC machine there has been
out of order since just before noon...
We had to use the general gate and get a ticket.
I see!
That means you could narrow it down to only the
people who had tickets from that interchange, right?
What's more, when we checked the victim's ticket...
We discovered he'd got on the highway an hour before us.
An hour before?
He likely stopped to eat or something
at one of the rest stops along the way.
In other words...
While many cars got onto the highway at the
same time and from the same interchange...
For those that parked at the rest stop for an hour and
were, for some reason, driving near the victim's car...
There were only three.
I see.
Incidentally...
The car with the victim's body in it is stopped
a kilometer back with its hazard lights on.
Call forensics and have them examine it in detail.
So, why don't we go over to the suspects' cars and question them?
All right.
Satou-san, let's have our dinner date some another time.
Satou-san?
Who...
Who are they?
Who on earth are these kids?PP
Say, Heiji, why is Kudou-kun wearing your hat?
Oh...
He asked if he could borrow it.
Do you like hats, Shinichi?
It seems weird, somehow.
What's wrong with it?
Shut up.
Just a change of image, a change of image.
Well, it's because the bad guys Kudou is after think he's dead.
I figured it'd at least help to hide his face, but...
How long will his body stay like this?
Kudou said he'd probably last for half a day or so...
Was he right?
These are the drivers of the three suspicious cars I mentioned earlier.
Mizuhashi Riko (35)
All I was doing was going on a drive on the highway with Gunpei.
You see, the one that died, Gunpei, was my boyfriend...
"Going on a drive?"
You were driving your own car, weren't you?
Yeah.
Gunpei and I both loved to drive our cars. Is that wrong?
You and the victim arranged to visit the rest stop before you left?
That's not right.
Gunpei said he was suddenly feeling tired
and asked if he could rest for an hour.
With no other choice, I killed some time at the
rest stop restaurant and then woke him up.
I see.
And, what were you two doing at the rest stop?
Chuuda Atsuo (34)
I got hungry, so I went into the rest stop to have a bite.
What about you?
I, well...
Shimodori Futoshi (48)
I suddenly had a stomachache hit me while driving.
So I went to the bathroom at the rest stop.
I heard someone died in their car, but...
It's got nothing to do with me whatsoever.
And me, too - it's likely not someone I know.
You liars!
Both of you knew Gunpei very well!
You're the leader of Gunpei's rival team, the Black Stars!
And you're the father of Akira - one of Gunpei's team
members that died in a road accident not long ago.
Hold on a second.
Are you saying the victim was Furuki Gunpei?
Furuki Gunpei (32)
The former leader of that street racing gang that
hangs out it western Tokyo, the Red Comets?
Yeah.
He stopped dyeing his hair and shaved off his beard.
Now that you mention the Red Comets...
I heard their leader took responsibility for
some accident and ended up resigning.
This was to be his last drive.
He was just taking the car out for a spin.
But nevertheless, this man came up behind Gunpei's
car and started insistently flashing his passing lights.
After all, he could never beat Gunpei in a real
race, so he was probably doing it out of spite!
Shut up!
With that bastard going and talking shit like he's going
to quit after his winning streak, I tried to piss him off.
But, when he didn't get into it, I just ended up passing him.
Well, it looks like he was enjoying his friendly drive
with the woman I thought broke up with him.
This guy sounded his horn a whole bunch of times!
That's because, after that guy passed him...
I was right behind Gunpei-san's car, and...
When he suddenly reduced speed, I sounded
the horn instinctively to prevent a collision.
And then, thinking he was going into the passing lane to
chase the car that passed him, I sounded my horn again.
On the day of my son's funeral...
Gunpei-san swore to me he'd retire from street racing, so I was upset.
It was immediately after that.
Gunpei-san's driving became really erratic.
He was in the passing lane but didn't try to pass.
He was moving sluggishly, and he started
scraping the car against the guardrail...
That's what triggered my quick reflexes,
and using my exceptional judgment...
I moved in front of his car...
In order to slow it to a stop.
That's when I discovered the strangled body of the victim!
You know, I seem to recall that being Kudou-kun's idea.
Then, you guys were the first to find the body?
No...
It was this woman.
I thought Gunpei was driving strangely also!
That's why, at the time, I immediately
stopped behind him and rushed over.
Gunpei!
But, if what the three of them just said is true...
It doesn't seem they had the chance to strangle him.
Well, for the next step, could you show me where
the victim's car was, my young detectives?
Yeah.
Of course.
And me too, right?
As for you, Takagi-kun...
Have the blockade on the tollbooth taken down.
And then stay here with these three.
Yes!
Kazuha, you stay here with her for now, too.
We'll be back in a bit.
He's leaving...
Shinichi's leaving me again!
See you.
You aren't the only one.
I have things to ask you and tell you as well.
So wait for me, will you?
Shinichi...
But, if my deduction's correct...
I suspect...
That what we would like to ask each other is one in the same.
Hey, buddy!
What's all this sweet talk?
Idiot!
It's not like that!
Let's get going.
Wait up.
Listen, Ran-chan...
When Kudou-kun comes back, don't let him go again.
You're kidding, aren't you?
He was really like this while the car was going?
Yeah.
Hard to believe, isn't it?
What caught my eye...
Are these thin scratches on the window molding.
It almost looks like something was pulling on it from outside...
Hey, hey...
Don't tell me you're saying someone fastened
something like a cord around the victim's neck...
And pulled it while driving in a different car?
No way, that's impossible. Impossible.
Yeah.
If they used the strength of the car to pull the cord...
His neck would be broken before he had been asphyxiated.
That's what has me puzzled.
Not to mention...
Why is the window all the way down?
Isn't it because he's a heavy smoker?
Look.
The ashtray is full of spent cigarettes.
Don't you open the window to let the smoke out?
But see...
At high speed, the wind is pretty strong.
You'd only be able to keep the window down just a bit out here.
And how much is "a bit"?
All I'm saying is...
Just enough to let the smoke out.
Holes...
There are two holes drilled into bottom of the window glass...
I see now.
So that's how it was.
I think I have it, Kudou!
The trick the culprit used!
Hey!
What's the matter, Kudou?
You're sweating.
What did you say?
The drug may not be effective for much longer?
Yeah.
I can't give you an exact figure...
But guessing based on my previous data
from giving the drug to Kudou-kun...
It wouldn't be unusual for him to be having those spasms soon.
Hey, Kudou!
It can't be...
Seriously?
It's happening...
Even though she said I'd build up resistance to the drug...
It hasn't even been 4 hours yet!
Well, since it's Shinichi, he'll come up with something.
Once the spasms start, he'll have around
30 minutes before he changes back.
Think before you speak.
With the efficacy of the drug shortened...
The time between when spasms start and
when he turns into a child is also shortened.
I can't even say with certainty that he has ten minutes!
Ten minutes!?
If he hasn't realized that...
His secret will be out.
Hey, Kudou-kun! Are you all right?
I heard you had a slight cold, but...
I think it's best if we have you examined by a doctor.
Let that...
Be after we solve the case.
Please bring those three people here.
He knows who the criminal is!?
Yes, I'll bring these three right over!
I'll take you in my car, so come please come with me.
Hey, Ran-chan - let's go, too!
I'm going to wait here.
Shinichi said he'd be right back.
Don't talk like that!
Doesn't he always try to run away?
But, we don't want to get in the way of their deductions...
Run!
Wait!
What?
He was strangled?
While he was driving?
Yeah.
Then, wouldn't it have been impossible for us?
It is possible...
So long as you ensured Gunpei-san did something while driving.
Hey, Kudou!
Don't try to talk!
Ensure he does something?
What, exactly?
This is nonsense.
With him driving so fast, what are you proposing we could have done?
Didn't we just say that it was possible?
Those openings at the bottom of the driver's side window...
If you use those two small holes, you can manage it.
Holes?
The mechanism is simple.
First, you take both ends of a thin, strong fishing line and
pass them inside through the two holes in the window.
Then, after passing both ends from
behind through the gap in the headrest...
You slip one end through the back of Gunpei-san's
necktie, and tie the other end to the first one.
Then, if you make him open the power window...
The line will be automatically pulled - effectively strangling him.
Due to the auto button on the driver's side, the
window won't stop until it's completely open.
But, kid, how did we make him open the window?
All I did was come up behind his car
and overtake him in the passing lane.
After that, all I did was sound my horn on two occasions.
First was when Gunpei-san's car suddenly slowed down...
And the second time was when he started chasing Chuuda-san's car.
This doesn't have anything to do with me, does it?
I didn't do anything.
No...
You slowed down, didn't you?
When you were driving in front of him and reduced your speed...
Gunpei-san was forced to as well.
Then, thinking something was wrong, he got into the passing lane...
And came up alongside your car.
Hold on a second!
Are you saying I yelled at him to lower the window or something?
Did you hear me say anything?
No.
It wasn't that you said something.
All that was required was that you face him...
And, with an anxious look, feign crying for help.
I see!
He'd lower the window to catch what you were saying.
The one who used this trick on him was his girlfriend here.
You were able to setup this trick while he was asleep at the rest stop.
Since he told you to wake him, he'd already
given you the key to his car, didn't he?
I see now...
She got him to take a sleeping pill beforehand.
You probably made the holes before you and he started driving.
If Gunpei-san habitually left the window slightly open in order to let
his cigarette smoke out, the holes would be hidden from view.
And the proof?
Where's your proof that I did this?
After we discovered the body, you went by yourself...
And you drove directly to the tollbooth inside your own car.
Therefore, if we investigate your car, I'm sure that we'll find it.
You rushed over to the body before we got there...
That's when you severed and removed the fishing line.
Perhaps you also made sure Gunpei san was sound
asleep during his nap by using chloroform on him.
Then, you woke him with the scent of ammonia or something.
All of this could be stored in your car.
The fishing line...
The chloroform, the ammonia...
It's all in my car.
Well, I expected the police to question me, but...
You cute little detective boys...
Who would have thought you'd see through my trick in an instant?
It's just as these young detectives said.
I was the one sent Gunpei to the grave...
While he was still holding the steering wheel.
Exactly...
He died with his hands clinched to the steering wheel...
Just like Akira did!
Akira?
Do you mean my son, Akira?
That's right!
I ditched Gunpei and started dating Akira!
That was just after Gunpei lost a crucial battle against Akira...
It's because I like whoever's the fastest.
I get it.
With his reputation trashed and then getting dumped...
He had to arrange for that battle in the rain.
It wasn't just rain!
It was a storm!
Those were no kind of conditions for a battle!
But even so, Gunpei challenged Akira...
As might be expected, Akira's car lost traction on
the wet road and fell to the depths of the valley.
But, weren't they both taking an equal risk?
When he took up the challenge, he accepted that risk as well.
The challenger too, he accepted the
responsibility and did the decent thing.
This guy? Decent?
Don't give me that nonsense!
That was just a pose!
That's what I think as well.
Once you start racing...
You can't stop until you die.
That's why I had to stop him!
This cold-hearted red devil!
No...
I believe he truly regretted what he had done.
How...
How can you possibly know that?
Up above the instrument panel in front of the driver's seat.
There are cigarettes and a lighter, right?
Given the dampness of the cigarette filters in the ashtray...
It's clear he was smoking before he was strangled.
If he leaned forward to get the cigarettes...
Wouldn't he have noticed?
That something strange was around his neck.
Then, why?
Why didn't he just cut the line?
I think he had already resolved himself...
That his crimes could only be atoned for with his own life.
You mean...
He already... knew?
Nonetheless, I would never consider sympathizing with his decision.
Just as you had killed him...
He made you into a murderer.
That's something I cannot accept.
No matter what...
No matter what the reason...
He shouldn't have made that choice...
It was the wrong... answer...
Hey, Kudou!
Takagi-kun, get an ambulance!
Right!
No...
He can't go to the hospital!
Let's go, to the hospital!
Ran!
Let's get you to the hospital so they
can treat you and you can get better.
You promised to tell me, didn't you?
The answer to your deduction!
Ran...