Let's go, to the hospital!
Ran!
Let's go to the hospital so they can treat you and you can get better.
You promised to tell me, didn't you?
The answer to your deduction!
Ran...
Because maybe I have a feeling that...
I agree with your reasoning...
That's why...
That's why, until you go to the hospital...
I'm not letting go of your hand, never!
Shin'ichi...
A desperate crisis...
A splendid revival reverses the conclusion to a case!
The terms of the engagement are "No Smoking!"...
And yet, for reasons unknown, there's a huge explosion.
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Ran-neechan...
Wake up, Ran-neechan!
Conan-kun?
How?
Is your cold all right now?
Heiji-kun and the others headed to the airport in
Mouri-kun's car so they could get back to Osaka.
I see.
By the way, Ran-neechan...
Could you let go of my hand sometime soon?
Ah, I'm sorry. Did it hurt?
Not at all.
But that's funny...
I thought I was holding onto Shin'ichi's hand...
Then I suddenly felt faint...
That's because I shot you with the spare tranquilizer gun.
I guess it's because you were really tired.
You kept holding onto his hand the entire time.
Even when Shin'ichi was carrying you and putting you in the car.
Where's Shin'ichi? Did he go in my dad's car also?
No, he rested in my car for a bit until he was feeling better.
He left saying he had some unfinished case to tidy up.
Then, he shook himself free of my hand and left?
That mystery-loving prince of fools.
Prince of fools?
But that's too bad...
I was so determined not to let go of his hand...
Idiot.
Take a good look at the left side of Kudo-kun's sweater.
See how it's been cut from the cuff all the way
to the hem and sealed with safety pins?
That proves he put on the sweater while
you were still holding his left hand...
As such, you really have nothing to regret.
Oh no. Is your cold coming back?
I'm fine. I'm fine...
So it was thanks to that little girl putting the girl from
the detective agency to sleep with the tranquilizer gun...
That you weren't found out in the end, even though
you shrank in the car while still holding hands.
Holding hands? Who told you that?
That old man, Agasa, told me over the phone.
Professor... Keep your mouth shut...
So, you did get some of it, didn't you?
The drug that changes you back?
It'd be better if you had that drug with
you, just in case it becomes necessary.
Yeah, that's what I thought, too.
Hey, didn't I just tell you guys not to eavesdrop?
Hey, Kudo...
Ah, sorry. Ignore that.
We're all on the way to go camping.
So then, how did it go?
I asked Haibara to give me a hundred tablets of that drug to start with.
A hundred?
Yeah.
I don't think even that much will be enough though.
I'm warning you now.
Each time you take the drug, your body builds up more resistance to it...
And it grows less effective.
I truly don't know if you'll be able to return to your former body.
Well, since you want to act cool for that girl at the detective agency...
You might not even last a week, even with a hundred.
Like she needed to tell me that.
You know, Kudo...
Even though the little girl tells you not to...
Wouldn't it be better if you tell the girl at
the detective agency the whole story?
That way you can confess your love sooner.
I-Idiot!
It's not like that!
That's exactly why I can't do it!
What can't you do (ika-nai)?
You can't go (ika-nee) camping with us?
Ah, no... it's...
Idiot! We're going camping in the mountains.
There's no way there'll be a squid (ika) there.
That's what you're talking about on the phone?
Ah, no, I've already finished talking.
Hey, hey! Wait a second!
He hung up.
Geez.
This is going to be fun!
The campground we're going to, that is.
Yeah!
I heard it has really beautiful scenery.
By the way, what should we have for dinner tonight?
I bought lots of ingredients.
Then, I want a barbecue!
You always want that, Genta-kun!
What would you like, Conan-kun?
The usual - curry.
How about you, Ai-chan?
Doesn't matter. If I were in the mood to eat, anything would be fine.
Ah, don't pay attention to her.
It seems she's been like this since this morning.
I bet she's worrying about something silly again.
Don't tell me the engine died again!
Didn't you have it checked before we left?
Yeah, and thanks to that, the engine's running perfectly...
But, as for the gasoline, we're out.
You know, it's getting dark.
We'd better hurry and call someone to bring us some gas.
Yeah.
I think so too. That's why I'm calling him.
Him?
Remember, the person who's been living next door to
me since that incident with the fire - Okiya Subaru-kun.
Since he said he'd be relaxing at home all day today...
He wouldn't mind spending two hours coming out here.
What? We're out of the cellphone service range here?
What'll we do!?
Here in the middle of the mountains!
We're still pretty far from the campground, aren't we?
For now, we have three choices.
Walk back to the gasoline stand we passed by
around thirty minutes ago, and buy some gas.
Stay here and wait until a car happens by, and
then ask them to take us to the gasoline stand.
Otherwise...
We go to that villa viewable on the mountain
above and ask to borrow their phone.
Well, it'd take us more than two hours
to get back to the gas stand on foot.
And since we haven't seen many cars pass by
on this mountain road, it'd be tough to wait.
Therefore, I think the safest bet is to
head to that villa while it's still light out.
What a beautiful house.
It's like a princess lives there.
I wonder if they'll serve us food when we get there?
We may get a full course of French cooking!
I want Italian!
I thought you came to go camping.
Stop, stop, stop!
Is something wrong?
I'm terribly sorry, but could you take us to a nearby gasoline stand?
Sudou Gouki (34)
IT Company President
I don't mind, but...
Could you give me a few more details?
The thing is, we were on our way to a campground...
And happened to run out of gas.
Since we're out of cellphone range, we're in a quandary.
I see, so that's how it is.
Then...
Wait here until you die!
You old goat!
What's with him?
What an unpleasant person!
He's the worst!
Well, we may well have to beg for help
from that unpleasant fellow once again.
Why?
That car was one that has ridiculously high maintenance costs...
A classic car that rich people prefer.
The person driving a car like that around here...
Might just be the same rich person who built
this luxury villa in the middle of these mountains.
No way!
Then, let's not ask him!
That's right!
I'd rather wait here until another car
comes than ask someone like him!
Well, there's a chance that guy wasn't going to
the villa, but to a completely different place.
It wouldn't be a bad idea to go and check, would it?
Yeah, you're right.
Let's leave the luggage in the car and go together to see.
Yeah, if we all ask together...
In that case, we should at least take a flashlight.
It is getting dark, after all.
It's in the pocket beneath the driver's seat.
Could you get it for me?
Yes, yes.
What's with you? You're acting like a queen.
Oh, is that what it looks like?
I don't know what's gotten into you, but...
While we're camping...
An explosion?
That's...
The emblem from that guy's car!
H-Hey!
Conan-kun!
If it was the same car as before...
Why did it explode?
Was the bomb planted on it from the beginning?
Then, was the reason he didn't give us a ride because
he didn't want us to be caught in the explosion?
It can't be. It didn't seem that way at all.
Gouki-san!
Stop, Ena! It's dangerous!
But... But...
I called for a fire truck and an ambulance!
Say, did that Gouki-san...
Did he have dyed brown hair, a beard, and wear
a black fleece jacket over a wool sweatshirt?
Who... are you?
A man like that, driving a classic car, passed us on the road a bit ago.
The deceased was Sudou Gouki-san, age 34.
It seems he was a company president who made a ton of money
from his IT business, which let him build this gorgeous villa.
The cause of the fire was a cigarette he was smoking.
A cigarette he was smoking?
Yeah, a plastic container in the garage with
gasoline inside had accidentally tipped over...
Which ended up filling the garage with gasoline fumes.
And then, Sudou-san arrived in his car
and opened the door of the garage...
He was smoking inside the stopped car, and in
the moment he stepped out, the fire erupted.
The fire completely engulfed the car.
We found a burnt cigarette butt, so...
That can't be!
Ginbayashi Ena (31)
Sudou's Fiancee
Gouki-san said he had quit smoking!
I hate cigarettes, so he did it for me!
Uhm - who are you?
She's Sudou's fiancee, Ginbayashi Ena-san.
On the weekends, everyone usually gets together here for parties.
Tonight, Sudou was supposed to announce something.
Our wedding.
We'd finally decided on the day for our wedding.
So he was planning to announce it to everyone...
And then... and then... why did this have to happen?
Ah, since we found a burnt marriage license...
What you're saying appears to be true.
But as for giving up smoking, it looks like that was a lie, doesn't it?
The ashtray in that car had a large number of cigarette butts in it.
And next to the body, in addition to the burnt cigarette...
He'd dropped a bag that contained a
sealed carton of cigarettes and a lighter.
N-No way!
And I was just telling him to stop smoking a little while ago!
A little while ago?
I got a phone call from Gouki-san about
an hour ago that said he was on his way.
During that call, Ena told him...
"If you don't quit smoking, then our engagement is off!"
Was that phone call really from Sudou-san?
Yes.
I was the one who answered the phone...
And I talked with him before hanging up.
So not only did Sudou-san not quit smoking...
He ignored the recommended way to store
gasoline, and used a plastic container.
I guess Sudou-san suffered the consequences...
And died in an accident.
No, we can't say that for sure.
What?
Because, if Sudou-san got out of the
car with a cigarette in his mouth...
That means he took the cigarette out and
lit it shortly before he got out, right?
Yet it isn't here anywhere...
The open cigarette pack, I mean.
Isn't that right, Mr. Forensics guy?
l-ls that true?
Yeah, we couldn't find it in the car, the garage, or anywhere...
But why isn't it here?
That cigarette butt might have been thrown in the
garage before Sudou-san arrived, might it not?
Say, Conan-kun...
What do you mean?
Please explain!
I mean this wasn't just an accident, but
was probably planned by someone.
It may have been murder.
Are you sure, Conan?
Yeah, the polyethylene tank placed in the garage had tipped over...
The gasoline vaporized and filled the garage.
Whereupon Sudou Gouki-san brought his car inside the garage.
He stopped the car and the instance he got out
with a cigarette in his mouth, it exploded.
They even found the cigarette butt
that caused the fire inside the garage.
At first glance, it appears to just be an accident, but...
If they can't find the open cigarette pack the victim
supposedly took the cigarette from anywhere...
Then that means the cigarette butt had already
been in the garage before Sudou-san arrived.
That means it may be a fake piece of evidence that the culprit
left in order to make it look like an accidental death.
Amazing, Conan-kun!
Well done!
However, boy...
We've been investigating the garage for some time, but...
We haven't found anything that looked like a detonator.
But, Sudou-san didn't have a cigarette case or anything either, did he?
Yeah...
That's definitely strange.
I bet if you search more, you'll find something.
It was the last one.
That cigarette was the last one.
So couldn't he have thrown the empty pack out
the car window before he went into the garage?
Gouki-san always used to crumple empty
cigarette packs into a ball and do that.
Then, are you saying that if we search around
the villa, we'll find that empty pack?
Yeah.
Ah, but he may have thrown the empty pack out a long time ago!
If Gouki-san had lied about quitting smoking...
Don't you think he'd avoid throwing it out around the villa?
If that's true, it would expand the field of
search greatly, making it difficult to find.
Not to mention the deep valley along the road.
But that's all I can think of...
Say, Miss...
Did you really believe that Sudou-san had quit smoking?
If you had found out that he was secretly smoking...
You would have only had to drop the plastic
gasoline tanks inside the garage and...
What are you saying?
Nobody's noticed Sudou-san secretly smoking!
That's right.
He never smoked a single cigarette since said he was quitting!
But that was just in front of you guys, right?
We met Sudou-san a little while ago, and...
He was a brazen liar.
So I thought his fiancee might know about that!
Brazen liar?
Yeah.
We had run out of gas on our way to a campground...
So we stopped Sudou-san, who happened
to be passing by on the same road.
We asked him to take us to the gasoline stand, but...
That's when he was real mean!
When we went over by the driver's seat and explained the situation...
At first that guy said "Get on in," but then...
He swore at us and drove away.
Wait here until you die, you old goat!
Hey, hey, that's terrible!
I don't want to speak ill of the dead, but...
He didn't seem like the kind of person who
would keep a promise to quit smoking.
That does sound like something he would say.
But I thought he'd keep his promise to quit smoking.
Yeah, Sudou-kun was madly in love with Ena.
Let's assume - and this is just an assumption...
Even if I knew that Gouki-san was secretly smoking...
On the way here, he called me on the phone...
And I said in front of everyone that if he didn't
stop smoking our engagement was off.
Do you think I could predict that he'd go against that
and get out of the car with a cigarette in his mouth?
Even after I told him not to smoke?
It's just as she said.
Seeing that she told him not to smoke in front of everyone...
It will be hard to prove that she's the murderer.
No, the cigarette didn't start the fire.
Whether he stopped smoking or not, I can't tell...
But, for today at least, I don't think he was smoking inside his car.
When the Professor stopped him...
I went up to the driver's side too, and there was no smell of cigarettes.
Then, how did the fire in the garage start?
I'm still not sure about that, but...
I am sure that Ena-san is the one who set it up.
Try to remember...
At the start, when Inspector Yuminaga said the cause of the
fire was his smoking, Ena-san flared up at him while crying.
Gouki-san said he had quit smoking!
Yet, only a little while after those
words came out of her mouth...
As a response to me pointing out how it was strange
that there were no opened cigarette packs around...
Couldn't he have thrown it out the car
window before he went into the garage?
If she had really believed that he'd quit smoking...
Wouldn't she normally have agreed with what I said?
"It's just like I thought. He did quit smoking."
T-That's true.
However...
Her inconsistent words all add up if they're from the culprit.
Her flare up at Inspector Yuminaga was saying.
"I didn't know he was secretly smoking!"
While her objection to me was.
"The cause of the fire was most definitely the lit cigarette."
It seems that Ena-san...
Wants, at all costs, for this to look like
an accidental death due to smoking.
Then, it wasn't an accident?
The fire was set up on purpose?
But, don't they say, "There can't be smoke without fire"?
That's what I'm thinking about right now.
There's got to be something here.
Some trick to starting that fire in the garage without using a detonator.
Next Conan's Hint
Wool Sweater
Ah, there's a fuzzball on your sweater.
That's because it's wool.
Ah, there's a price tag on your sweater.
That's because it's on sale.