We were on our way to go camping in Professor Agasa's car...
However, the car ran out of gas and we were stranded.
We asked the driver of a classic car that passed by...
Sudou Gouki-san, to help us, but...
He just swore at us and drove off.
Immediately afterward, there was an
explosion at the villa atop the mountain.
When we came running, what we saw was...
Sudou-san's classic car on fire in the garage and...
A person in tears calling out his name.
It was his fiancee - Ginbayashi Ena-san.
Although at first she appeared to be miserable about the
accident, I felt Ena-san's behavior to be suspicious...
Could it be that Ena-san still somehow arranged a murder?
No sort of detonator was found at the scene of the incident, but...
There has to be something here...
Some trick to starting that fire in the garage without using a detonator.
A desperate crisis...
A splendid revival reverses the conclusion to a case!
The secret behind the hateful trick
that caused an explosion without a fire.
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Well, leaving the cigarette matter aside for now...
Ginbayashi Ena (31)
Sudou's Fiancee
I'll ask you all where were you and what were you
doing at the time Sudou-san arrived at this villa.
"What"?
We were all together in a room, playing a game.
A game?
The game of "King."
Are you familiar with it?
Lots are chosen using numbers and a king symbol.
The person who draws the king card...
Issues commands like, "Number 4, kiss Number 13."
Then, was there anyone who wasn't
in the room when Sudou-san arrived?
I think everyone was there.
And if someone got up to go to the bathroom, we paused
the game and everyone waited for them to come back.
But wouldn't you normally expect someone to greet the
owner of the house, Sudou-san, when he arrived?
No, we didn't realize he'd come in.
Not to mention that he opens the garage
door with the remote control inside his car.
And the background music was playing really loudly.
And then, in the middle of the game,
we heard a bang and went outside...
We found the garage burning!
Then, that means that even if we assumed there was
a detonator, no one would be able to operate it...
Nor could they estimate the proper timing.
Yeah.
That'd be impossible.
Still, why did that polyethylene tank tip over?
It was probably because of this little guy.
It's a golden retriever my late father bought for me.
It's naughty and has a habit of knocking things over.
That's why we told him to stop storing
the gasoline in a plastic container.
But, to think that this has happened three times before...
It's happened before?
Yeah, we had parties last week and the week before, and...
The polyethylene tank was on the ground when Sudou arrived.
He yelled out, "Who was it? Which of
you bastards did this?" really angrily.
When he found out it was Ena's dog, he and Ena had a big fight.
And then the fight expanded to other
things, like Sudou's car and his clothes.
The party was even broken up over it — two weeks ago, I think it was.
Yeah, and, if I recall, before he arrived last week,
Sudou-kun had an argument with Ena on the way.
That's enough already!
Sorry...
He lost his life because he didn't listen to my request.
In the end, that's the degree to which he loved me...
Only that much.
Here you go.
I had my assistant bring this gasoline.
Oh, thank you for this.
Well, if we find anything else we need to ask about, we'll contact you.
Yeah.
Where's the boy with the glasses?
Over there.
Come on, tell me!
Tell me about the fight last week and the week before.
Geez, you've got awful manners!
I already told you, the week before last
their fight was about cars and clothes.
I'm asking why they fought over something like that.
I don't know.
Maybe it was because Ena-chan told Sudou to drive
here in his classic car, but he came in his new car.
Later it was because Sudou didn't come wearing
the clothes Ena bought him for the party.
What kind of clothes?
What kind?
Remember?
I think Sudou-kun was wearing them when you met him earlier.
A fleece jacket over a wool sweater.
As for the sweater, Ena gave it to him.
As for fleece, Sudou has liked it ever since he
started the company and has worn it often, but...
He didn't much like wool.
But he came wearing a wool sweater last week, didn't he?
He even drove that classic car, too.
And yet, when Ena saw Sudou kun holding a
plastic bottle of mineral water, she got really angry.
Yeah.
She said, "You were loitering at some gasoline stand
on the way even though everyone was waiting."
Sudou irritably replied, "No one tells me where to go."
Then, Ena spilled the wine she was holding on Sudou-kun's sweater.
Ena started to cry and said, "I'm sorry!
I'll buy you a new one. I'm sorry."
The party last week was ruined as well.
But, that's strange...
Ena said before that she hates classic cars.
Classic car...
Wool sweater...
Stopping on the way...
Wait a second, could it be?
The investigation is over.
Well, leave the rest to the police and enjoy your camping.
Ah, right.
Later.
Even if he tells us to enjoy it...
We're thinking about the case...
So we couldn't enjoy it, could we?
Hey, Shinichi, haven't you solved it yet?
No...
I'm still stuck.
Whatever you want to do is fine, but
can't we talk about it in the car?
That's true, it's getting a little chilly.
Geez, in that case, why don't you just get in yourself?
Sorry, but will you open the door for me?
Stop this nonsense already!
Who on earth do you think you are?
Open it... please.
Could it be, you're...
Please.
I'll teach you a good way to do it.
If it's just before getting into a car, use the asphalt.
If it's a doorknob, then use a wall.
Nobody asked you about that!
I told you to open the door!
C'mon, try it for yourself.
Be brave and use your palm...
Rock-Paper-Scissors?
I see...
That's why...
The classic car...
That's why Ena-san...
Didn't want him to stop on the way.
It was to make Sudou-san himself...
A detonator.
Didn't you already ask us this before, detective?
The plastic tank in the garage containing gasoline accidentally
tipped over, and the gasoline vaporized, filling the garage.
When Sudou-kun arrived, he got out of
his car with a cigarette in his mouth.
The gasoline caught fire and exploded, right?
Isn't this a complete accident?
Knowing all this, why do you find it necessary to question us again?
No, the person the police want to question...
Is the fiancee of the fire-victim, Sudou Gouki-san.
Ginbayashi Ena-san...
Just you.
The plastic gasoline tanks in the garage have
fallen over for three consecutive weeks now.
Like this boy told us, that's a real sticking point,
so we ought to ask you some questions.
This brat again?
What's with you?
I just told the detective he should ask and make sure.
Since it's possible that someone might have
knocked over the plastic tanks on purpose.
Well, it's only a few questions.
I guess I must.
Seeing as there's no culprit in this case, it looks
like I'll have to be the one to talk to the police.
But, only on the condition that we don't go in a patrol car.
It would feel bad to be treated like a suspect.
I'll use my car.
Ah, that's right.
Since we were the last people to see
Sudou-san, the police invited us too.
If it's OK with you, why don't you come in our car?
I don't mind, but...
Aren't there a lot of people in your car?
I wonder if there'd be room for me...
It's fine, because, as for them...
They're completely entranced by that car.
We can really ride in a patrol car?
What an honor!
But, I still think I'll pass.
I'll just go in my own car.
I see...
That's too bad.
I had something I wanted you to see, but...
Something you want me to see?
Yeah, something belonging to Sudou-san
that I picked up on the way to this villa.
I haven't shown it to the police yet, though.
Don't you want to see it?
Sure.
I guess...
What do you think of this car, pretty cool, isn't it?
Yeah, it's comfortable and also has a cute shape.
What do you call this kind of car?
Its nickname is "Beetle," since it's just like a beetle.
Yeah, now that you mention it, it does resemble one.
Huh, e-mail?
To a friend, since we're finally in the cell phone's service area.
Then, will you show it to me after you're done with your e-mail?
That thing that belonged to him...
Oh, yeah.
Here, this is it.
Ah, that's the emblem from Gouki-san's car.
You recognize it?
Y-Yeah...
This was attached to the front of Gouki-san's classic car...
Is this really from his car?
When the explosion happened, we were on the
road below the villa and it came flying down to us.
But, you know...
I heard that you hated classic cars.
So, why did you ask Sudou-san to come in that car?
I'd started to like it...
Because of him...
And even though Sudou-san hates wool...
Why did you specifically have him come wearing a wool sweater?
I just thought it looked good on him...
Since he was always wearing nothing but fleece, you see?
Speaking of which, Haibara, you're also wearing
fleece over a wool sweater today, aren't you?
And? What of it?
Ah, no...
I was just asking...
Then, was this all you found, little boy?
Yeah, that's right.
Did you think I'd found something else?
No, not really.
We're running out of gas again!
Geez, you just got gas from the detective earlier.
Yeah...
But we're really stuck now.
There's no gasoline stand around here...
Then, why don't we go to your house, professor?
You have some gasoline in a can in the garage, right?
Ah, that's right.
I bought some for the camping trip and forgot to bring it along.
Sorry, but we're going to stop by the professor's house, all right?
Sure...
Sorry about this.
Please wait a moment.
Ah, found it.
Yeah, this is it.
Hey, what are you doing?
To think that that gasoline tank fell over in the garage...
It's just like in the garage at the villa that caught fire earlier.
Y-Yeah...
But it's all right, nobody here smokes cigarettes.
R-Right.
Excuse me, Ai-kun...
Could you bring me the towel from the trunk?
You can open it with the key in the car.
Geez, guess there's no helping it.
Wait...
Don't...
Don't! Don't put the key in!
Static electricity will cause a spark!
So, static electricity was the detonator after all.
What you just said has made it clear.
You had Sudou-san wear the fleece and wool
combination, which gather static electricity easily.
After filling the garage at the villa with gasoline vapor...
When Sudou-san, who had been in his car for a long time, got out...
The moment he put the key in the keyhole in order to
lock the door, the static electricity caused a spark...
That's how you manipulated him into being
burned to death by the exploding gasoline.
While driving, he would unconsciously rub his back against
the seat, making it easy for static electricity to build up.
And the reason you had him come in the classic car was...
Nowadays, most cars come with keyless remotes...
So it isn't necessary to put the key in the keyhole to lock the door.
To make it likely for the static electricity to discharge, you
didn't want to lose the chance of metal to metal contact.
But, aren't there times when you only
feel a shock from static electricity?
You couldn't be sure that a spark would be emitted.
It's true that it's unlikely to happen with just one try, but...
If you're determined to do it until there's a spark...
It's sure to happen eventually.
And, in actuality, it looks as if you've tried it for the last three weeks.
The reason, the week before last, that there was no spark...
Was because Sudou-san didn't wear the wool
sweater and came with the new model car.
As for last week, Sudou-san stopped on his
way to the villa and bought some drinks.
Once he got out of the car and touched something...
The static electricity he'd built up to that point was lost.
Even if he later put the key in the keyhole while in the garage...
No spark was going to be generated.
Also, the reason you spilled wine on
Sudou-san's sweater during an argument...
Was because you wanted him to change it quickly.
If he continued to wear that sweater and felt a shock somewhere...
He might have bought some anti static items,
and your plan would be out the window.
Of course, you didn't want Sudou-san to talk with
anyone about how to avoid static electricity.
Right, for example, reaching your arm out and
touching the roof of the car before getting out.
When getting in a car, touching the ground before touching the door.
And for the doorknob in a room, if you touch the wall with your hand...
The static charge you've built up will be dissipated.
Among those people who get shocked with static frequently, it seems
some nervously try and touch things with one finger, however...
If they're brave and use their whole palm...
The static discharge will be dispersed and they won't feel the shock.
Sudou-san hates wool, and wouldn't usually wear it...
So he didn't encounter static electricity very often.
Coordinating the fleece and wool, a combination
that makes collecting static electricity easy...
Having him put the key in the keyhole would, I think,
create a high probability of an electrostatic discharge.
And since he hadn't had a bad experience
with static electricity, he wasn't being careful.
But, why did she keep trying this method?
It wasn't just Sudou-san...
You wanted to destroy that car as well, didn't you?
Yeah, that's right.
I wanted to eradicate him and that car from this world.
That man! That ruthless devil who only wore the skin of a man!
My father had heart problems.
While he was driving with my mother, who didn't
know how to drive herself, he had a heart attack.
It was on a mountain road, where few people passed...
He couldn't get to a hospital and he died.
But that just seems like bad luck.
That's right, he was unlucky.
Just after he had the heart attack and stopped his car...
By coincidence, whose car do you think happened to pass by?
My mother begged him to take them to the hospital...
But that devil just swore at them.
Just wait here until you die, you old bag!
My mother was in deep shock because of
the incident and laid up for a long time...
Then, as if she was chasing after my father, she passed away.
That devil's words, the car he drove...
And the fact that a silver figure with
its wings spread was attached to it...
She left all of this information to me in a note.
That's why I devoted myself to finding him.
The owner of the classic car with the winged figure on it.
But boy, you were reckless.
It would have been terrible if that little girl put
the key in the keyhole before I stopped her.
It was all right.
There's no keyhole for the Beetle's trunk.
And that e-mail earlier was me asking a certain person a favor...
To replace the contents of the tank with water.
This is a really fun racing game!
Even the professor can do a good job sometimes, can't he?
Huh?
Where's Ai-chan?
Well now, I think she's already gotten up...
Don't tell me she still isn't over her bad mood?
Now, now, don't say that.
Ai-kun's been getting static shocks ever since that morning.
And to make matters worse, it seems she
lost her anti-static items somewhere.
Be brave and use your palm.
Ai-chan, come and play this game with us!
It's fun!
Oh, that's fine.
I'm really good at that game.
Oh, Haibara! How'd you do that?
She's way out in front!
You're great!
It's eerie when she's in a good mood...
Next Conan's Hint
Package Ribbon
Look forward to the next episode
Below the office is the Poirot coffee shop.
I am Poirot.
No, you're not.