A securities trader was killed in his apartment.
The murder weapon was a hunting rifle.
The police are looking for someone with a grudge against him.
That's kinda scary.
That apartment building is in our neighborhood, isn't it?
That means the culprit might live somewhere around here, doesn't it?
Azusa-chan!
Enomoto Azusa (23)
Poirot Coffeeshop Waitress
Please excuse me...
I'll make another of the same plate right away and bring it to you.
Are you all right?
You look so pale.
I do?
Come to think it...
Your brother Sugihito-san goes shooting, doesn't he, Azusa-neechan?
Enomoto Sugihito (28)
Azusa's Older Brother
What's that got to do with it?
Sugihito-san shoots clay pigeons.
That's not hunting.
But, you know...
It seems there are a lot of stern-looking people
here who suspect there could be a connection.
Now that you mention it, there are a lot of guys
in this shop with a mean look in their eyes.
Including some guys I have a feeling I've seen somewhere before...
Like that guy sitting at the counter.
He looks exactly like someone we know.
Huh?
Aren't you...
Detective Takagi!
What are you doing here?
A desperate crisis...
A splendid resurgence changes the solution to the case!
The Poirot coffeehouse is full of cops...
A package arrives full of mystery!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
What?
You're considering Sugihito-san as a suspect?
In the case of this securities trader?
Yeah, the victim, Torihira Tagafumi-san, was...
The boss of Azusa-san's brother, Sugihito-san.
Sugihito-san's fingerprints were on a rifle found at the scene.
Moreover, we found some spent shells at his apartment...
And it seems he's been absent from work without permission.
We're thinking he might contact his
little sister, so we're on stakeout here.
I see.
And so?
Has your brother tried to contact you?
Like I told the policemen, he has only once.
"Don't worry," he said.
And then my brother said, "I'm innocent. I didn't do anything."
Yes, that's exactly right.
I'm sure there's been some mistake.
Uhm...
Who are you?
Kawase Touji (28)
Securities company Employee
He's a co-worker at my brother's company, Kawase-san.
I had an errand near here for work, so I thought I'd stop in.
Say, those fingerprints on the rifle that
was used as the murder weapon...
Are you sure they were Sugihito-san's?
Yeah, we're sure.
In that case, some time ago, after he joined the company, he and
four or five co-workers went to visit Torihira-san at his apartment.
Perhaps his fingerprints got on it when he asked to see the rifle.
At the time, he was intensely interested and held it...
He even looked down the barrel.
Are you sure he was that interested?
He shoots clay pigeons himself.
No, he said he used a shotgun to shoot clay pigeons.
He was excited to hold a hunting rifle for the first time.
Excited?
But, if he went over to visit him at his house...
It doesn't seem like your brother was mad at Torihira-san, does it?
Yes, my brother told me that even though
he was a strict boss, he was a good person.
Strict?
Torihira-san considered Enomoto-san to be a capable person, so...
It seems he took a special interest in him.
He frequently scolded him harshly in front of everyone.
Well, he was the type who believed in tough love.
Still, if his fingerprints just got there coincidentally...
Why has he run away?
Moreover, it seems he left his apartment in considerable haste.
In haste?
Yeah, he left the front door unlocked...
And he left his ATM card and wallet behind.
What's more, those aren't the only
things he left behind when he ran away.
We found something at the garbage
collection point near his apartment.
It was one of his dress shirts, covered in quite a lot of blood.
N-No way!
And that blood was?
Yes, the DNA analysis showed it was Torihira-san's blood.
But, how do you know it was Sugihito-san's dress shirt?
They were left on the buttons - his fingerprints.
I brought along a photo of it just in case.
Do you recognize it?
Well...
You can find dress shirts everywhere.
Let me see it too!
Conan-kun...
What's this?
Well, I'm going to head back to work.
It takes an hour to drive there...
So I should go now.
Right, the company is in Kanagawa, isn't it?
If he happens to contact you...
Could you send me an e-mail right away?
I'll try and persuade him to go to the
police instead of staying on the run.
If he's caught while still trying to escape...
I wouldn't put it past them to force him into being the culprit.
Yeah...
Later.
Thank you for everything you've done.
Say...
Was that man a good friend of your brother?
Yeah.
It seems they became friends not long after they were
assigned to the same unit within the company last month.
He's been staying over at my brother's apartment a lot recently...
Because my brother's apartment is close to work, you see?
Is that so...
Please excuse us police for intruding on you.
No...
If I'm going to be watched regardless, it
doesn't matter if you're inside or outside.
I just want to prove that my brother isn't a criminal.
This is just what I expected Azusa-chan's apartment to look like.
It's pretty isn't it?
You think so?
You have lots of gifts here.
Are these from your regular customers at Poirot?
No, those are all from my brother.
He's always sending me weird souvenirs he buys on his business trips.
Speaking of sending things, my brother's also
always sending me weird photo e-mails.
Just last night...
He e-mailed me this funny picture.
Snow?
Did it snow last night?
It seems there was a lot...
Near my brother's apartment.
My brother sent this one to Kawase-san as well.
Who could believe that a person that'd send
an e-mail like this could be a murderer?
That's true...
Besides, my brother told me this morning over the phone...
"The gun I always use is a sports shotgun."
"There's no way I could easily wield something like a hunting rifle."
No, as for wielding it or not...
A guest?
Did someone have plans to visit you?
No one.
That might mean...
It couldn't be...
Ta-da! I've brought you a delivery!
Ah, what's wrong?
Nothing.
Who sent it?
Let's see...
The person's name is Enomoto Sugihito-san.
My brother!
Is it all right if we look at the contents?
Sure.
Here.
Thank you.
A cookie assortment.
Hey...
Is there a letter or anything inside?
Let me see...
It doesn't seem like there's anything like that.
Azusa-chan, do these cookies bring anything to mind?
Azusa-chan?
Cookies, you say?
They're my favorite food, so maybe that's why he sent them.
Now, doesn't that make him seem less-and-less like a murderer?
Yeah...
That's right! I need to go out shopping now.
I'll just go out to the nearby supermarket
and get some food and a few other things.
I'll be right back.
Yes, certainly.
So the first person to find the body was...
Torihira-san's wife, when she got back from a trip this morning.
Yeah.
I was told the crime likely occurred last night between 10 and 11 PM.
Oh yeah, I had a problem last night at exactly the same time.
Problem?
I had to go to see the Kanagawa prefectural police...
But the highway was closed.
The trains were running late, too.
Was there an accident or something?
No, it wasn't an accident...
This is Chiba.
Ah, Takagi-san, what's wrong?
You let Azusa-san get away?
Yeah!
Those cookies must have told her where to meet!
How could they?
There was no message or anything...
No, there must have been a message written there...
In an unexpected place that only Azusa-san would notice.
However, the person who sent it wasn't Sugihito-san.
Most likely, it was from the true culprit...
He called Azusa-san out in order to destroy all the evidence.
The one who let slip from his own mouth that he was the murderer.
That man...
You idiot!
How could you let the suspect's sister
get away while you were escorting her?
I'm sorry!
Enomoto Azusa-san gave us help in solving that case before.
I never thought she'd run away...
You know, the person we suspect murdered Torihira-san...
Is none other than that Azusa-san's brother, Sugihito.
If she's a good sister...
Don't you think that, at heart, she'd feel she should do
everything possible to help her brother get out of trouble?
Well, what would you have done, Inspector?
What if, while you were shopping, she said, "Please wait
for a moment, I need to go to the underwear counter."
If it were me, that wouldn't be a problem and I'd go right along.
Then, what if she said, "You can come along if you want,
but please don't watch me while I pick one out!"
And what if, when she said that, she
was blushing and looking worried?
What about that!?
Well, I guess it couldn't be helped.
Good job, Azusa-chan.
None of that matters now!
The problem is that we've completely lost all
means of finding out where the suspect is!
But, Inspector-dono...
Was Sugihito-san really the culprit?
His fingerprints were on the rifle used as the murder weapon.
Not to mention that he's on the run even now!
What's more, we found that bloodstained
dress shirt at the garbage collection point.
The bloodstains on it are Torihira-san's blood.
We also found Enomoto Sugihito-san's
fingerprints on the dress shirt's buttons.
Nine times out often, that'd mean he's the culprit...
Yuck!
Hey now, Conan-kun - What are you doing?
I was thirsty, so I thought I'd get a cola from the refrigerator...
But then it gushed out!
What's this?
My elbow and underarm didn't really get wet.
You must have closed your arm when you opened the lid.
I see.
"Closed your arm"...
Inspector-dono, there's something strange about this dress shirt.
Where at?
Here, by the underarm and elbow...
There's blood all over this area as well.
For there to be this much blood...
He must have fired the rifle at nearly point-blank range.
In other words he'd have shot it while holding it
under his arm and not looking through the scope.
If that were the case, the underarm and elbow should
have been blocked off from the spurts of blood.
As such, this dress shirt may have been concocted by someone.
No, it's not unnatural for the shirt to have been covered in blood.
Torihira-san wasn't shot to death by the rifle...
He was beaten to death by the butt of the rifle.
Is that so?
I was sure he'd been shot with the rifle as well.
But, you know, there was someone who
guessed that exactly right, wasn't there?
Remember?
It was Sughito-san's co-worker at his company, Kawase-san.
Didn't he say Sughito-san had been really intersted
in the rifle, and even looked into the muzzle?
And with that, he also said that Sugihito-san's
fingerprints got on the rifle barrel.
It's true that the culprit probably held the
barrel to make it easier to strike with, but...
Why would Kawase-san say that?
The press release only said that the murder weapon was a rifle.
That's because Kawase-san was the actual perpetrator of the beating.
It was as the culprit that he unintentionally made that slip.
But didn't Kawase-san try to cover for Sugihito-san?
He was letting us know that the reason the fingerprints were
on the rifle was because he had touched it earlier, wasn't he?
But, at the same time...
He told us that Sugihito-san was really excited.
But he then said Torihira-san considered
Sugihito-san to be a capable worker...
Didn't he also say Torihira-san often
scolded Sugihito-san at the company?
I see...
He seemed to be covering for him, but
in fact, it was the exactly the opposite.
But, still...
Enomoto Sugihito-san's fingerprints were
on the buttons of this dress shirt —
That reminds me, Kawase-san said he'd often
stayed over at Sugihito-san's apartment...
Because Sugihito-san's apartment was near the company.
I see!
If he stayed over and then went directly to work the next day...
He might have borrowed a dress shirt.
In other words, he kept one of the dress shirts he'd borrowed...
So that he'd have it to wear before he committed the crime.
Yeah.
And then, after the crime...
He threw it away at the garbage collection
point near Sugihito-san's apartment building.
If that's true, why did he run away?
Maybe Kawase-san could have told him to run.
Saying, "You touched that rifle."
"If you're caught now, they'll make you out to be the culprit"
Perhaps Kawase-san was also the one who called out Azusa-san.
Why would he call out Azusa-san?
Well, for some reason or other...
Wasn't it the e-mail picture?
Remember?
Last night, Sugihito-san sent her an amusing picture.
That's what Azusa-neechan said, didn't she?
Since it seems he sent it to Kawase-san as well...
I'd bet Kawase-san wants to have all the copies of it.
Are you an idiot?
Why would he want all the copies of that lousy pun and picture?
Snow?
That picture showed it snowing.
Detective Chiba, could it be that the difficulty you
had last night was because it was snowing?
Yeah.
At the time of the crime, between 10 and 11 PM...
I was returning from the Kanagawa department where
snow had closed the highway, and even delayed the trains.
Hey, if I remember, Sugihito-san's apartment was
near the company location in Kanagawa, right?
Yeah, and it would take an hour to get here from there.
And if the crime occurred at ah apartment building nearby...
Doesn't that picture amount to an alibi?
If the traffic was paralyzed by the snow...
That's true...
But a digital image is difficult to use as proof...
And if the culprit realized that as well, it'd become
the most likely reason to call out Enomoto-san.
He'd then instruct her to bring along the cellphone with the picture...
In order to destroy it.
But how could he have called her out?
All that was suspicious was an assortment of cookies
from Sugihito-san that arrived some time ago, but...
Say, is today Azusa-neechan's birthday?
I don't think so.
Why?
Because there's a ribbon on that package.
That's why I thought it had to be a present for something special.
See?
The other packages from Sugihito-san have no ribbons on them.
So wouldn't Azusa-neechan think, "What's this?"
Hey, that ribbon!
Where did she put it?
I think she put it in the trash bin with the wrapping paper.
The empty warehouse at #4, Okuho City, 3rd District!
Contact the local jurisdiction right away and send them there!
Yes, sir!
Will they be in time if they leave now?
Yeah, they probably won't make it in time...
If they leave now, that is.
Brother?
Where are you?
Are you here?
Brother?
Azusa!
Brother...
Why are you here?
"Why..."?
Didn't you call me here by writing the location on that package ribbon?
That's why I sent Kawase-san an e-mail asking him to come too.
To persuade you that, since you're innocent...
You should go to the police instead of staying on the run.
Persuade me?
He was the one who told me to run and hide here!
He was?
What does that mean?
K-Kawase!
This is what it means.
I've been waiting here for two hours, Azusa-chan...
Waiting for you to come along.
You've been waiting here?
Yeah.
Waiting for her to bring your stupid e-mail photo.
Good...
You brought your cellphone, just as instructed.
E-mail photo?
You mean the one I sent last night?
Yeah.
The photo that provides an alibi for you despite all the
pain I went through to make you out to be a murderer.
T-Then...
You're the one who killed Mr. Torihira?
Yeah, that's right.
I lost a pile buying stocks with the company's money.
A hundred million yen leaves one big hole, you know.
That's what led old-man Torihira to find me out.
He gave me some rot about making me
spend the rest of my life paying it back.
I went ahead and shut him up.
It was just afterward...
That the photo e-mail from you arrived.
If only you hadn't sent that photo...
Azusa-chan wouldn't have to die.
Wait!
If you don't wish for your sister to die,
write out a final confession right here.
And then, use that rope...
You follow me, don't you?
You bastard!
Make it a good one and you'll save your sister.
Fortunately, she didn't hear my voice...
And it appears she still trusts me.
Make it clever.
About Torihira abusing you, maybe?
Or even that you felt running away was hopeless?
Something clever enough to have the
witless police weeping when they collect it.
That's no good.
We wouldn't weep over something like that.
But then again, a farce like that may make us laugh...
Laugh to the point of tears, that is.
If it were up to me, I'd rewrite the script this way...
At the last moment...
A daring female police detective rushed onto the scene...
And masterfully arrested the suspect.
Don't you like how this one has a happy ending?
How did you police get here?
You shouldn't have been able to trail Azusa-chan.
We came here directly along a different route.
Don't tell me...
You discovered the message on the ribbon?
Is that it?
I got an e-mail from a certain someone.
It said the true culprit would be coming here.
MAIL: I know the true culprit!
So please hurry and go there!
Ah, keep it a secret from every-
one that I happened to figure
out the location by coincidence!
If Uncle Kogorou knew, he'd
burn up with jealousy!
Well, as for who that certain person is...
As per their request, I won't be telling you that.
Please forgive me for all the trouble I've put you through!
The police gave me a bit of a scolding,
and I embarrassed that detective...
Well, that's all right, isn't it?
At least your brother was proven innocent.
And so, you're free from those detectives with the mean looks in their...
Hey now!
You detectives are still here!
The detectives who ate my special pasta when they came
here on their stakeout all said it was really delicious.
Yeah!
So they've been coming here a lot recently.
Does that bother you?
No, that's great.
Geez...
The way this feels like a detective squadroom is giving me the creeps...
Next Conan's Hint
Stone Coffin
Look forward to the next episode
An "ishi" is a "stone," right?
You got it, Takagi.