The moment of vengeance is upon us!
The curtain will draw...
The masque of death is ready to commence!
A desperate crisis...
A splendid resurgence changes the solution to the case!
Actors are frightening with their faces veiled...
All in this tragic masquerade!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
"Masques."
Basically, they were plays featuring masks before Shakespeare's time.
They were a popular type of play in England until then.
The play that's being performed right now
is John Benson's "The Triumph of Folly."
Shimizu Kinuko (26)
Troupe Company Manager
In Japanese, it would be, "Oroka sa no Shouri."
You know, this performance is really something.
In order to achieve that effect...
We borrowed actual rapiers to practice with
Tabuchi Manabu (50)
Stage Art Director
Huh?
No script?
There's no call for a script.
This is a silent play.
I see.
He vanished!
There's a landing under the veranda.
He just has to jump down.
And, this scene is...
This is a pivotal scene in which the king raises his cup in celebration...
Following the deaths of the prince and minister.
Of course, it was the king who orchestrated the feud between the two.
The wine the king was just drinking...
Was poisoned by the minister beforehand.
It seems like quite a bloody story.
The story is indeed an intricate one.
This play has encountered a number of problems in the past.
What you're saying is...
They say that ever since the first performance in the 17th century...
This play has been cursed, and leads to the death of a cast member.
The guy playing the prince really looks like a prince, doesn't he?
Banno Robert (21)
Stage Actor (Role of Prince)
Yeah.
That is our star actor, by the name of Banno Robert.
It's Komazuka Hiroshi!
Dad, you've heard of him?
Yeah.
Komazuka Hiroshi (50)
Stage Actor (Role of King)
Back when I was a student, I watched his movies all the time.
The one playing the minister is Yabuki Atsushi.
Yabuki Atsushi (28)
Stage Actor (Role of Minister)
As for the lift I'm jumping on...
Think you could raise the platform a bit?
In reality, during practice...
Suspicious happenings have come one after the other.
That's why we asked you, Detective Mouri...
Leave it to me!
It shall be as easy as relaxing on a boat—no, I mean, a cruise liner!
No problem at all.
There aren't any suspicious places, are there?
Hey, where's the brat?
Conan-kun!
It's such a big place, he could have gotten lost.
I'll go find him.
That kid is such a pain...
By switching this rapier with the real one...
Robert will...
Kyoko...
Although I may not know where you are now...
I only hope you will see tomorrow's news.
Because the news will be about the accidental
death of the man that's having a secret affair on you!
Robert...
Come tomorrow, the sword of justice...
Shall pierce right through your sinful heart.
Who are you!?
Hello...
Bye!
Hold it!
You...
You're Detective Mouri's...
Me? I didn't hear a thing!
There's no way you didn't hear anything!
Now that you've heard, there's no way I can let you go!
Until the show is finished, at the earliest.
To be honest, staying here...
Damn...
My alcoholism is acting up again.
Uhm...
What?
Have you seen a child about this tall?
Haven't seen him.
Is that so?
Sorry for the trouble.
There we go.
Is that so?
The real rapier is missing?
Rapier?
Could it be...
How dangerous!
Damn it, I'm filing a complaint.
No...
Wait a second...
Shocking him to death on the stage lift...
That doesn't sound like a bad idea either.
It isn't like I was the one messing with the rapiers.
I can still claim it was an accident.
Now, the problem...
How do I switch roles before the real performance begins?
He'll definitely take the bait.
All right, I'll talk him into it.
What?
You don't have the money to pay me
back, so you're handing me your role?
My apologies.
There's just no way for me to ready the money.
As such, I'm giving you my role.
Don't be stupid.
The actual performance is soon, anyway.
Hold on...
This is a silent play.
Since there's no script, it should be fine.
Actually...
I'll take it.
That should be fine.
Well, hurry and tell the manager.
What if we kept it a surprise until we got on stage?
From an acting standpoint, I think it would be interesting to try.
I guess so.
Let's go with that.
I'll just leave this here.
The trap I was going to remove...
No...
So long as I fall to the side, I should be fine.
Conan-kun, where are you?
Even an elephant can be poisoned to death.
That old man—he's about to see...
This is a gift from your fans?
Yes.
But, sake is...
Well, I'll accept it for now...
Komazuka-san?
Is everything going OK?
Yeah!
Please...
Although Robert-kun and Yabuki-san are
doing well, these are their first starring roles.
Komazuka-san, please show them your guidance.
Yeah, got it.
Bye!
Just don't do anything foolish that would
embarrass me like you did during rehearsal.
I'll pay closer attention.
Such a nice-sounding response...
Too bad you have zero acting talent.
I'm not even sure how someone like you is allowed on the stage.
Put this away.
I've stopped drinking.
I understand.
Geez...
He just keeps going on and on and on.
The main role was supposed to belong to me, originally.
But because of you, everything has been ruined.
You must know by now that the audience is growing
tired of watching you only act like you've been poisoned.
Well, for the next performance, I'll be the one in the spotlight.
What's wrong? Everything will be just fine.
I suppose, but...
Where's Conan?
I've looked everywhere, but I can't find him.
Could it be that something happened?
Nah, no worries.
It's always like this.
The moment of vengeance has come.
The curtain will draw...
The masque of death is ready to commence!
You don't have the slightest clue that this
performance is about to become your last...
Nothing suspicious.
Same here.
Geez...
Where has Conan-kun gone off to?
How did a guy like him...
You said it, didn't you?
"My dream is to see out the remainder of my life on the stage."
I'm merely obliging by fulfilling your wish.
We're almost to the climax.
In the end...
It seems everything will work out without a hitch.
That Yabuki seems to really be into it today.
Could it be that he performs better during showtime?
No matter, it'll be in this state that you put a sword right through him!
I won't be showing mercy.
Whatever happens, don't blame me!
It's an accident!
The scene with those two looks completely different?
Yeah...
I'm just seeing things, right?
That must be it.
Your pleas for mercy will be in vain.
What?
A sound?
Finally!
Robert is gone!
My bad...
But it is just an accident, right?
What was that sound just now?
What goes around comes around.
It would be fantastic if this were actual wine.
Just to be safe, I'll go have a look at the stage lift.
Could it be...
Dad...
Ran!
He's still alive.
Call an ambulance!
It's too late...
The poison's already coursing through his body.
This is the punishment for making me look like a fool.
But, more importantly...
Who switched the rapier for a real one?
I was the one who did...
That's punishment for making my daughter suffer...
Robert...
What did you say?
Robert-san!
Yabuki-san...
How did this happen?
Once I knew the rapier had been switched for a real one...
I decided to switch roles with him...
To repay the money I owed him...
Everything was going fine...
Until I ended up falling into my own trap...
Tabuchi-san!
Hurry and shut off the power to the lift!
Yes!
Just what is going on here!?
Robert-san...
Am I going to die?
A shock that small won't kill you.
Still, we'll need an ambulance!
But, when was the rapier switched out?
The last time I checked, it was definitely the fake that was there.
It is the fake!
Then...
Of course it's the fake.
I was the one who secretly switched them.
And it wasn't just that...
To make it a poor conductor...
I also switched the wine inside the decanter.
But, at that point, I was really worried...
Damn!
After escaping from the coffin...
I used the genuine rapier to cut the rope...
And then...
Is that so?
The real rapier is missing?
How dangerous!
Damn it, I'm going to file a complaint.
I believed everything was all right at that point...
No...
Wait a second...
Shocking him to death on the stage lift...
That doesn't sound like a bad idea either.
It isn't like I was the one messing with the rapiers.
I can still claim it was an accident.
Could it be that even Robert-san...
In a rush to swap the rapier with the fake one being used in the play...
And to stop him from going to Yabuki-san's dressing room just in case...
The result was...
Even an elephant can be poisoned to death.
That old man—he's about to see...
Dealing with one criminal is relatively simple...
But three is too many to handle.
And even if they were stopped now...
There will be a next time.
So...
I have to save him, even though he's a criminal.
Well, I'll accept it for now...
Komazuka-san?
Is everything going OK?
Yeah!
Please...
Although Robert-kun and Yabuki-san are
doing well, these are their first starring roles.
Komazuka-san, please show them your guidance.
Afterwards, the show began.
A bottle cap should be enough...
First, make Yabuki-san lose consciousness.
Next would Robert-san...
Shit!
And then, we have Komazuka-san...
The evidence is all there.
The three of them can't deny it now.
Well...
If they would just realize the error of their ways
and not do something this mindless, then...
Conan-kun!
Where were you this whole time?
Well...
The bathroom.
Geez!
I've been looking everywhere for you.
Because, I...
You'd better smarten up!
Yes...
I'm sorry.
You want to be in a masque, Dad?
Can you pull it off?
Of course I can.
STRANGE ATTEMPTED MURDER
SCENARIO PLAYS OUT AT THE THEATER
Well, let's give it a try.
That —is it supposed to be a masque?
Yes! Yes!
Next Conan's Hint
Ring Impression
Look forward to the next episode
Next time, Mom and Dad get along with one another!
Really?
Yes, really!