You promised to meet someone for work?
Right now?
Yes, that's right.
You called for us to come...
Because you said we were going out to have dinner.
And on a night when Dad is having drinks
with the master and the others at Poirot...
Well, it can't be helped.
There's someone I wanted you to meet.
All right, looks like it's time to go out...
A fax?
What's this about?
No way!
A desperate crisis...
A splendid resurgence changes the solution to the case!
A female judo champion...
Enters a three-way battle with Kogoro and Eri!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Troubled by a stalker?
Is it someone you know, Mom?
Yeah.
Her husband was taken to court in the
past, in order to settle a traffic accident.
Oh, it's the judo fighter, Arisawa Yuuko-san.
You know her, don't you?
I do, I do!
They say that, if she hadn't got injured, she
would have won a gold medal at the Olympics!
She's the former All-Japan champion for the 70kg class, right?
But if it's her, wouldn't the stalker be the one running away?
No...
Even though she was the one who approached
me, it was her husband that was concerned.
He was suddenly on edge, and noted that, ever since the traffic
accident, it "seemed like someone was always watching" him.
It seems he isn't sleeping at night, either.
Then, shouldn't the "stalker" be the victim from that accident?
I'm not convinced that's the case.
The victim came to a mutual understanding that
it had been his own fault, and settled privately.
Also, it seems the victim has completely recovered from his injuries.
Then, who is the stalker?
She tried to convince him otherwise, and even
told him, "It's probably your imagination," but...
He isn't willing to listen to her.
That's why I'll be looking into it.
Should there not be any listening devices or
cameras, we can prove there isn't a stalker.
But, say, why is Kisaki-sensei going?
Well...
The husband seemed very appreciative during
the settlement proceedings before, so...
If I'm the one telling him, don't you think he'll believe me?
Ah, no...
That's not what I mean.
I mean, why didn't you ask Uncle Kogoro?
That's right, that's right!
Mom is a lawyer!
Dad is a detective!
If it's a stalker case, a detective is...
I didn't want to.
Isn't that reason enough?
Of course that's not "enough"!
Well, considering what that old guy is usually up to...
Strike!
Oh, no!
Jackpot!
Might not be able to ask him.
What's this?
While you have no problem coming to another's defense...
You won't intercede when it comes to your personal affairs, huh?
Arisawa Yuuko (37)
Judo Martial Artist
Don't you think it's time you forgave your husband?
Kisaki-sensei...
Arisawa Yuuko...
It's really her!
I'm afraid that's impossible for the time being.
Before I do, I'll wait for him to demonstrate his sincerity.
Then, why not get moving on the divorce?
No, that's...
Well, at least he was able to give you a lovely daughter.
Oh?
Was there a son as well?
Ah, no...
We're only caring for him at our house.
Well, at any rate...
Shall we head over to your house?
I'm sure your husband is waiting, too.
Yeah, you're right.
Since it's about time for him to return from the office...
I'll give him a quick call.
That's strange...
No answer.
Could he be taking a bath?
Ah, dear?
Where are you?
I'm at a wake.
A wake?
Yeah.
Someone I know passed away not long ago, so I came to their wake.
Can't you hear it?
The chanting.
Speaker...
So yeah, I'll be getting in late.
Get to bed ahead of me.
Ahead of you?
Tonight?
Kisaki-sensei is coming over now to discuss the stalker situation.
Was that today?
I'm at Kisaki-sensei's office right now.
I'll put her on.
Yes, this is Kisaki speaking.
No...
If it's truly an inconvenience, we can
meet on a more suitable day, but...
Yes.
Is that so?
We will review the situation then.
How was he?
He said he'll be arriving home at 9:25, so...
I'll meet with him then.
25 minutes after?
That's really peculiar, isn't it?
Normally, wouldn't you say 9:00 or 9:30?
He's just really punctual.
He's rarely late for anything without a reason.
Well...
It does seem like he completely forgot about
Kisaki-sensei coming over tonight, though.
Furthermore, we still have another two hours until 9:30.
Then...
How about we have dinner at the nearby hotel restaurant?
Actually, we can spend some time in the parking
lot's drive-in cafe until it's time for the meeting.
Not to mention, the parking fee there is cheap.
In that case, is it all right if these two come along?
Why, of course!
You won the karate tournament championship?
That's amazing, Ran-chan.
Thank you very much.
But, didn't you do that as well?
No...
My talent developed later on.
I was first crowned a champion in university.
Given the comparatively high injury rate...
My peak lasted two, three years.
And, after retiring, I married.
I still wasn't able to achieve my dream of earning the
gold medal in front of the senpai I admired so much.
The senpai you admired?
He's currently the coach for the All-Japan team, Kajimoto Hajime.
At one time, he was an unrivaled gold medalist in the 81kg class.
I took up judo after seeing him on TV.
It's the same with me, then!
I admire the karate champion of Japan, Maeda-san.
But...
Admiration is admiration.
It's the same as viewing flowers from afar.
When you get too close...
It becomes like Icarus, who lost his wings and plunged
to the earth after flying too close to the sun...
Disaster befalls oneself...
I'm sorry!
I started saying such strange things...
No...
But I'm glad that Ran came along.
The reason I called you to my office was to meet her.
Since you're both women interested in this, I didn't
know if it would help stimulate the conversation or not.
Actually, until this meal, I wasn't sure
if you two would get along or not.
Then, why didn't you call Dad as well?
Dad actually practiced judo!
Now that you mention it, I suppose he did.
The truth is, I was worried.
I wasn't sure whether or not he was on a case, so I decided
against using the hand of such a renowned detective.
Is that so?
If that's the case, you should have mentioned it from the start!
Oh, didn't I mention it?
Say...
Isn't it about time to go?
You said it would take ten minutes to get to your house by car, right?
That's true...
But before we go, I need to visit the bathroom...
Wasn't it delicious?
That western-style food.
Yes, absolutely.
Do you come here often?
Yeah, always once a week.
With your husband, right?
Nope.
I come alone.
My husband has zero tolerance for new food.
Let's see...
Where did I park?
Oh!
Isn't it that white car?
Ah...
When I saw you with your husband before...
That's the car you were driving, right?
Yep, yep.
That's it.
Then, I'll give Ran-chan and the boy a ride as well.
We'll pass right by the detective agency on the way home.
Thank you very much.
Oh, do you know how to adjust the seat?
There's a lever on the right side of the seat, and if you pull it...
See, like this...
The seat will move.
No need to worry.
My car has the same thing.
Well, boy...
It's not far, so be sure to behave yourself.
Huh?
That parking ticket...
Where did I put it?
In that case, I'm afraid you'll have to
pay the daily maximum of 3,000 yen.
Guess it can't be helped.
If you don't mind, I'll gladly pay half.
It's fine, it was my mistake.
I apologize...
The children are truly being an inconvenience.
No, no.
Geez...
Why are you being so selfish, Conan-kun?
Because, if she's the former All-Japan champion...
She must have a lot of trophies and plaques, right?
Doesn't Ran-neechan wanna see them too?
Well, I suppose, but...
I'm home!
My husband's shoes...
It is just before 9:30.
I guess he really doesn't lose any time.
Well, I'll go get my husband.
You can wait in our living room here.
Dear?
Kisaki-sensei is here.
No matter how you look at it, this is amazing.
The number of trophies and plaques...
That's right, that's right!
When she was in her prime, she never lost.
Legends began to circulate that she was invincible, even.
Say, this picture...
Do you see the tall man standing to the far right?
I think that's the gold medalist that she mentioned earlier.
Right, right.
That's Kajimoto Hajime of the 81kg class.
Oh, and the other one...
The man standing to her left—that's Yuuko-san's husband...
Arisawa Shirou-san.
Then, the boy making the peace sign...
Is that Yuuko-san and Shirou-san's son?
No...
That would be Kajimoto-senpai's son, Kouta-kun.
He would come along to the judo dojo with the coach.
He was really adorable.
And, your husband?
The thing is, I can't find him anywhere.
He's not in the bath or the bathroom.
He might have gone out for cigarettes after getting home.
I'll try to get him on his cell.
A ringtone?
You hear it too?
Don't cut off the phone!
Conan-kun?
The closet?
Dear...
Dear!
The victim is Arisawa Shirou-san, age 37.
He was a businessman that worked for Haidou Shouji...
As well as the homeowner here.
And...
Arisawa Yuuko-san...
There is no doubt that this is your husband?
Yes...
It appears that some sort of rope was used to strangle him to death.
Yeah.
Although we haven't found the weapon yet...
It was likely something along the lines of a thin cloth.
Like a necktie, right?
Because before, on the phone...
He said, "I'm at a wake," so shouldn't he have a necktie?
Usually, when men go to a wake, don't
they wear suits with black neckties?
That's true...
This raises the possibility of the culprit taking
the victim's necktie and using it as a weapon.
And, do you know whose wake it was?
Well...
All my husband said on the phone was that
someone he knew had passed away recently.
But I think I heard chanting in the background.
Ran-san spoke with the victim on the phone as well?
No...
While I was speaking with my husband on the phone, I...
Accidentally hit the speaker button.
That's why we could hear it as well.
Why were you and the children with her
while she was speaking to the victim?
Ah, actually...
The victim was her husband, Shirou-san, who had
consulted with me on settling a traffic accident in the past.
Ever since the accident...
He had been plagued by a stalker, which
led to her consulting with me again.
The husband had been saying that it felt as
if "someone was always watching" him.
But, personally, I never felt there was any indication of that.
As such, we had our old lawyer, Kisaki, visit the house.
Since my husband had such great faith in Kisaki-san...
I thought that, if she could prove there weren't
any listening devices or cameras anywhere...
It might put his mind at rest.
Also...
Prior to leaving Kisaki-san's office via car...
As this boy said earlier...
My husband said he would return home to meet with her.
Over the phone, her husband said he would be back around 9:30.
We ate at a nearby hotel restaurant until then...
And then she, the children, and myself
all came here in her car afterwards.
Would you happen to know how long that was?
Let's see, it was...
She called her husband at around 7:30 in the evening...
And we ventured to the hotel immediately.
By the time we finished our meal and left, it was around 9:00.
When we made it here, it was almost exactly 9:30.
And then, somehow, you came across the body in the closet?
Yeah.
Since I couldn't find him...
I called his cell, and...
We heard ringing from the closet.
Which amounts to...
Your husband claimed he wouldn't be home until
9:30, but actually arrived a full thirty minutes early.
His estimated time of death is around 9:00 tonight.
So, at that time, he must have already been home.
That means there's a chance that the stalker is still somewhere nearby.
The culprit had been lying in wait, waiting for the husband to return...
And when he did, he killed him and fled.
About your husband's stalker...
Did you really have some knowledge of the situation?
Yes, I did...
Without being a fan of hers, it's unlikely you could understand.
A fan of hers?
Oh?
Did you not recognize her?
She is the former All-Japan champion in judo for the 70kg class...
This is Arisawa Yuuko-san.
It really is her!
I thought I'd seen her face somewhere!
Thanks...
But, for a guy to be so worried about a stalker when
he has such an able-bodied bodyguard is strange...
That's true...
After thinking about it, this could have
been the victim from that traffic accident...
I'm not so sure that's the case.
They might have just been after money.
Conan-kun?
Cause look down here!
At this person's left ring finger.
It looks like one was there before...
But now there's no ring!
It's true...
Isn't the left ring finger for wedding bands?
Did your husband always wear his wedding ring?
Yeah...
Now that's weird!
Even though the ring is gone...
This fancy-looking watch is still here!
Why is that?
I'm so sorry, I should be keeping a better eye on him!
Since it's still here, their motive wasn't money after all, huh?
Guess not.
At any rate...
For the time being, we'll concentrate on inspecting the house.
While we do, if you all would please wait in another room.
To think all of this started while looking into a stalker...
I feel sorry for Yuuko-san.
Yeah.
As do I.
I don't want to conclude that she planned the murder already, but...
Are you trying to say Yuuko-san is the culprit?
Yeah.
It's certainly a possibility, isn't it?
But, her husband was killed around 9:00 tonight...
That's the same time we left the hotel restaurant.
Wasn't Yuuko-san with us the entire time?
But, did she not excuse herself to the bathroom once?
Just before we left the restaurant...
But that—it was only for around ten minutes...
Wasn't he coming back from someone's wake then?
Are you saying he was called to the hotel?
No, that's not it.
When Detective Takagi...
Checked the history on her phone...
It said the last call she made was at 7:30, which was from my office.
Then, how could Yuuko-san be the culprit?
The call from my office could have been fabricated.
By then, shouldn't he have already been home, normally?
But this time, when she called her husband...
She went for his cell instead of the home phone.
Isn't that suspicious?
What's more, I think she purposely put
it on speaker, just so we could hear.
A wake?
Yeah.
Someone I know recently passed away...
You're thinking about it too much...
Because after that, didn't she let you speak to him?
The voice on the phone was that of the husband, right?
Yeah, I doubt there was a trick involved there, but...
That's true...
If his voice had been recorded beforehand...
And it was just played back over the phone...
She could easily fake a conversation that way.
But afterwards, it would've be 100% impossible
to hold a conversation with Kisaki-sensei.
Someone could have imitated his voice over the phone, but...
After meeting with her so many times
during the settlement proceedings...
She would be hard to fool.
If that really was the husband we heard on the phone...
So I came to their wake.
Can't you hear it?
The chanting.
Without knowing where the wake was being held...
Could Arisawa-san really have planned to murder him?