While we were waiting at the office of Ran's mom...
We met the former All-Japan women's
judo champion in the 70kg class...
Arisawa Yuuko (37)
Judo Martial Artist
Her name was Arisawa Yuuko-san.
When her husband, Shirou-san, requested a
consultation over a recent stalker problem...
A meeting was set to meet with them, but...
When Shirou-san revealed he had suddenly been called to a wake...
It was planned that he would meet them at 9:30.
But...
When we arrived at the set time, we discovered...
The strangled body of Shirou-san.
Lawyer Kisaki began to find Yuuko san's behavior suspicious...
But her alibi was solid in that she had
shared a meal with us at the time.
There was only the ten minute period
where she went to the bathroom...
In such a short time frame, is it possible for her to have
killed Shirou-san, who had been at a wake previously?
A desperate crisis...
A splendid resurgence changes the solution to the case!
Kogorou and Eri's combined deduction...
Makes a tag-team move on the case!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Maybe they have call forwarding?
That way, if Yuuko-san called here from
your office, it would forward to his cell.
See, since no one answered, the service would have done that.
Unfortunately, that's not the case.
The truth is, before you two made it to the office...
I called here.
It was in order to confirm the appointment for tonight.
But the call wasn't forwarded...
It went to the answering machine after ten rings.
Then, maybe the husband hadn't come home yet, so his cell was...
It wasn't just that phone.
We were deceived.
Near the closet where the body was
discovered is the door to the garage, but...
The trash there was strange.
How so?
Isn't it easier to take it out if it's left there?
No...
It wasn't the position, but the contents.
A large amount of match books from the western-
style restaurant we ate at earlier had accumulated there.
Since she doesn't smoke...
Her husband, a heavy smoker, was likely
responsible for bringing them back.
In other words, he's a regular customer at that same restaurant.
But if so...
Why did she say he had zero tolerance for their
food, which caused her to always go alone?
If that's the case...
Why don't we have Dad investigate?
Maybe he can find a hint?
I'd rather sell my soul to the devil.
Geez...
The devil, huh?
What?
You found a listening device?
Five of them?
Yes, sir.
This makes it more likely that the victim was the target of a stalker.
Also, we found two items in the victim's clothing.
Two?
Yeah.
The first was found in the inside the pocket of his suit...
This wedding ring.
Then, the victim's missing ring wasn't taken after all...
Which makes the question why he removed it to his pocket, right?
Oh, and the other?
Ah, yes.
In his coat pocket...
We found this black necktie.
Could this be the murder weapon?
No, because...
There aren't any wrinkles.
It doesn't even look like it's been opened.
Which means it's brand new?
Yeah...
So...
Should I give Dad a call?
Dad did say he was going drinking with
the master of Poirot and the others, but...
I doubt he'll be drunk just yet.
Hey, Mom!
Say something!
Hey!
Geez, be quiet!
Just quiet down a little!
Hello, Dad?
Mom has something she wants to ask you.
What?
Eri does?
Here.
Hey!
Well, I doubt he'll be able to look into much.
I...
It's not really anything important, but...
If it's not anything important, then don't call.
Idiot!
Stop, don't hang up!
Yeah, yeah, I see.
So, you see the former All-Japan champion as suspicious, but...
When the crime occurred, she was with you.
And since you don't even know where the victim went to a wake...
That makes it impossible to solve.
Yeah...
Then, the answer is simple...
That woman is innocent.
That's it, isn't it?
Her alibi is solid.
The best evidence is that you talked to the victim yourself.
But, still...
It could have been some sort of deceit...
Ron!
Ron?
Ah, sorry!
I'm at the table practicing with some of the neighbors!
Well, if that's all, you'll need to find someone else to be the culprit.
What did Dad say?
He was busy playing mahjong, so we'll have to find someone else.
And, even then, he wasn't really playing mahjong...
It was a tape, a tape!
I know he used it a number of times in the past.
You'll get nearly the same sound by using one.
What?
What do you mean by sound?
It's because...
Even if you don't know their whereabouts at that time...
The culprit can decide where to cut it...
That's it...
The husband didn't want it to be known...
That was the reason for the underhanded trick...
Could it be that his trick was seen through...
Without him realizing just how it would come back?
Despite the few unexplained points that remain...
We can assume, from Arisawa Shirou-san's
recent claims about being troubled by a stalker...
That someone came to this house, confronted
Shirou-san as he was returning from the wake...
And ended it by taking his necktie and strangling him.
Isn't it possible that the reason Shirou-san
removed his wedding ring and necktie...
Was because he was readying to bathe?
I see!
The stalker must've been hiding in the bathroom, right?
After he was discovered by Shirou-san, he took the necktie, and...
The only remaining question is just why...
Shirou-san had a sealed necktie in his coat pocket.
Perhaps someone asked him to buy it for them?
Wakes are generally quite urgent.
It's possible someone may have been required to go
directly from work, and had to ask him to buy it for them.
And, in the end, they were unable to make it.
I see.
If that's the case, it wouldn't be unusual
at all for him to have an extra necktie.
At any rate...
When 9:00 came around earlier, we were just leaving.
The drive from the hotel restaurant to here takes at least ten minutes.
Shirou-san's wife Yuuko-san was just
leaving the restaurant with us at the time.
As such, we have no connection to this case.
May we leave now?
That's true...
For the time being...
We need to find out whether or not anyone
suspicious was seen leaving the house.
Go look into that.
Yes, sir.
Yuuko-san?
May I speak to you in the living room?
Do you have a moment?
Sure...
So?
What did you want to discuss?
Article 42, sub-paragraph 01 of the penal code.
Criminal offenders that voluntarily surrender before being properly
suspected by authorities may reduce the severity of their sentence.
Yes...
That is why the one I am advising to surrender...
Is the very Yuuko-san that strangled her husband.
It was you, was it not?
Wait...
Is this some sort of joke?
Didn't you say so earlier?
At the approximate time of the murder...
We had only just finished eating and were
leaving the hotel restaurant together.
But, before that, did you not make a trip to the restroom?
That was for ten minutes, no?
In so little time, how could I...
If you only pretended to visit the restroom
and instead went to strangle your husband...
Returning after just ten minutes is more than possible, isn't it?
For the former All-Japan judo champion for the 70kg class...
And for someone who is currently a dojo's coach...
You could do it, right?
What are you saying?
Since I had no clue where my husband went for the wake...
How could I get there from the hotel?
There was no call for visting the wake...
Considering your husband was already at the hotel.
"Already" there?
You heard it too, didn't you?
That was his voice on the phone saying he was at a wake.
So I came to their wake.
Can't you hear it?
The chanting.
Don't tell me you're denying hearing that!
The chanting was from a tape.
It was to hide his affair, wasn't it?
Affair?
My husband was guilty of using that trick
constantly when he was with the police.
He would play a recording of patrol
car sirens next to the phone and say...
"A sudden case has come up, so I'll be
home late — go to bed without me."
In actuality, he was drinking at the bar until dawn!
That man!
M-Mom...
This is probably not the best time...
But...
That was just your husband...
My husband would never do that.
Prior to taking a bath, do you normally remove
your wedding band and store it in your pocket?
Now, if he were going out to meet someone else...
It would make a lot of sense, would it not?
And, as for that unopened black necktie...
He planned to put it on before returning home...
In order to make it appear he had been to a wake.
However...
Before he could do that, you strangled
him with a different necktie, didn't you?
And, further evidence is the restaurant matchbooks
that have collected in the garbage by the garage door.
Your heavy smoker of a husband brought them back, right?
You also mentioned that you go to the restaurant on a weekly basis.
This would mean you both visit that restaurant often.
Then, why did you say you only ever go alone?
I come alone.
My husband has zero tolerance for new food.
Yes...
Even though you always went alone...
Your husband did not.
You saw it in that restaurant, didn't you?
Your husband was there happily enjoying a meal with another woman.
That restaurant is where they usually frequent...
But you had only discovered it that night.
You proceeded to scatter listening devices around the house,
and fabricated the story of the stalker to meet with me.
And, as we waited, you invited us to that hotel restaurant for dinner.
When you contacted your husband on the phone from my office...
You expected him to play something in the
background that he'd prepared as an alibi...
And also predicted he would say he'd be
home late and not to wait up for him.
Also, you timed when he would be leaving the
hotel, and pretended to go to the restroom.
You then caught your husband in the parking lot...
Where you proceeded to drag him to your car, and strangled him.
Next, you placed him in the trunk of your car
And came back as if nothing had happened.
Afterward, you drove your car with us
and the body inside to your home.
You instructed us to wait here in the living room while you
transported his body from the trunk to the nearby closet.
And lastly, you called him so we would discover the body...
Well?
Was anything I said in the wrong?
That story sure sounds like a plausible one!
Do you have proof?
We can probably find out by checking the hotel parking lot.
Keeping in mind that your husband was punctual...
He must have been alone in the lot at the time of his death.
As such, it should still be there...
The car that your husband drove to the hotel.
Because, should he have been in the car of another woman...
You wouldn't dare risk having her see your face...
Which means you couldn't have killed him in the parking lot.
The garage here only has space for one car.
Most likely, your husband rented a car behind your back.
Then, why not investigate it?
That hotel parking lot.
And, should you riot find a car like that...
Even you, Kisaki-san, can't get out of this!
Say...
Arisawa-san is really good at judo, right?
Wait, Conan-kun...
Could you teach me the inner thigh throw?
That's when you use your opponent's attacking
power to your advantage and throw them, right?
You use their power to throw them
to the ground and gain points, right?
Using your opponent's power to your advantage...
Gaining points...
Geez, what are you up to?
But, back then, didn't Arisawa-san teach us how to adjust our seats?
Oh, do you know how to move the seat?
There's a lever on the right side of the seat, and if you pull it...
See, like this...
The seat will move.
I see.
The car that you ended up driving us back in...
That was the car your husband drove to the hotel, was it not?
That's why you demonstrated how to adjust the seats, right?
Your husband is smaller and shorter than you.
It's natural for his seat to be in a different position.
Should you adjust it on a whim, it would seem suspicious.
That's right...
That would also explain your adjusting of the rear-view mirror.
Which means...
It should come as no surprise why you
couldn't find the car in the parking lot.
Most likely, you trailed him closely and
avoided letting him take notice of you...
After he got inside the car, you proceeded to strangle him.
Afterward, you likely rushed back at full speed to the restaurant.
And, due to this, you did not have enough
time to remember the car's position, right?
It really was a strange story.
Your reason for inviting us to that hotel...
Was because of the cheap parking.
But when you were expected to pay for the parking ticket...
Despite not having gone anywhere else,
the ticket was suspiciously missing.
This is peculiar, isn't it?
When you said you had "lost the ticket," what you really meant
was that you weren't sure where your husband put it, right?
If your husband were the type to put things away at random...
It could be behind the sunvisor, or even in the ashtray.
With a proper search of the car, I imagine we'll find it...
The hotel parking ticket with your husband's fingerprints on it.
That would be the proof that your
husband was also at the hotel tonight.
Well...
If we check the trunk, we should find
evidence that he was moved from there.
Maybe his hair...
And possibly even the necktie used as a weapon, as well as his shoes.
And, as for the shoes that we saw at the entryway tonight...
Those were likely prepared by you.
Now...
Before the police come across this evidence...
Hurry and surrender.
In his left sock.
I just remembered...
That's where my husband usually puts his parking tickets.
So, if they check there, they should find it.
Then...
Yuuko-san really did...
But, why?
How could someone like you resort to murder over a mere affair?
If it were only an affair, a divorce would have sufficed, but...
The other woman was Kajimoto san's wife.
I just couldn't allow it.
"Kajimoto-san"?
That's the gold medalist you mentioned before, right?
But, wouldn't that give you even more reason to work it out?
It isn't like you weren't acquainted with his wife...
Yeah.
My husband and I visited Kajimoto-san's house often in the past.
Such a good wife, such a cute child...
They were the ideal family you see in pictures...
But, my husband—he ruined that.
When I considered the suffering to come, I couldn't live on that way.
Not even a divorce would've been enough.
Only by killing him would it be over.
Right...
You really never should grow close.
If we had never visited Kajimoto-san's house...
My husband and his wife wouldn't have met.
If only I had kept my admiration to myself,
none of this would have come to be.
This is merely an assumption, but...
Could your husband have just wanted more attention from you?
The tape trick for an alibi would have only worked
two, maybe three times before he was found out.
And, when it comes to those matches from the restaurant...
He may as well have told you directly that he went there often.
Are you saying my husband wanted me to discover his affair?
Yes.
He was jealous that you still thought of
Kajimoto-san, despite being married.
That can't be...
But...
He crossed the line and angered you,
caught on fire, and fell to the ground.
Just maybe...
The sun that burned Icarus' wings...
Was actually you.
It was all thanks to Dad, huh?
You know, the alibi tapes!
A coincidence, just a coincidence.
Definitely an accidental hit.
Was it really a coincidence?
What if...
It was a deliberate hint, just for Mom?
No way...
It couldn't be.
He was probably too embarassed to say anything!
Is that so...
If you want to find out, here's the phone!
Well...
I should at least inform him that the case is over.
It's me.
About the case...
Oh, sorry, I'm still playing mahjong
Silly, still using those tapes...
Kogorou-san!
Hurry!
Damn, I...
This...
This is...
As I thought, it was just a coincidence.
How do you know?
Mom!
Wait up!
It looks like Uncle's back already.
Oh, really?
Don't mind him.
Perverted old man...
Tonight drinking party has been canceled!
Sorry about that, Kogorou-kun~!
-Poirot Master
I see.
Since he'd used this strategy so often
before, he saw through it instantly.
And he was able to find his own alibi tapes so
quickly because he skipped on the party...
Then, he tried to play it one more time over the last call, but...
Kogorou-san!
Hurry!
Next, we'll have a friend of the groom, Mouri
Kogorou-san, give a congratulatory speech.
Thank you!
What bad luck, recording that part and accidentally playing it as well.
Yep, quite a pity.
Eri...
Don't be fooled...
Do your best...
You too, Uncle.