Love is eternal, labyrinths are mysterious.
Saturday nights are for mystery!
An urban legend has everyone on edge.
Long-haired girls need to be cautious!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
What's up, bro?
You lookin' for sumthin'?
Hey...
Hold up now...
No need to be runnin'...
Hey, Ran...
Did you hear?
About the Hammer Man.
I did, I did!
They mentioned it on the morning news.
I heard he appeared in the park nearby last night.
Yeah.
They say he's at least 180 cm tall and that...
All four of his targets have been women with long hair.
Right...
Just like Ran!
Come on...
Stop scaring me, Sonoko.
But, if it were you, you'd give this Hammer
Man a taste of your superb karate skills, right?
I'm not sure.
If he were to ambush me from some dark corner...
Jeez.
He's the nemesis of all womankind.
I'm sure the police will catch him eventually.
Just when you mention them...
There's Detective Takagi and Detective Sato.
You're right!
Let's go ask how the Hammer Man investigation is going!
Wait a second!
Uhm...
I don't think I heard that very clearly...
Then...
I'll repeat it.
Kiss me.
Right now.
A hot one.
Come on!
Hurry!
Don't stall!
Yes.
In that case...
Pardon me.
A stakeout?
Right?
Why did you have to interrupt? It was getting to the good part!
But...
Both of them were glaring at that apartment
with such concerned looks on their faces.
If you look closely, you can see someone's shadow
beyond the slit in the curtains on the third floor...
And then, Detective Sato suddenly put her
arms around Detective Takagi's neck, so...
I thought maybe they were trying to appear as lovers...
So that it wouldn't be so obvious they were on a stakeout.
Am I wrong?
That's right.
You're observant!
That's how it was?
Oh?
What else did you have in mind?
Nothing...
If this was really a stakeout, we're truly sorry for interrupting.
Conan-kun was a real hindrance...
It's fine, it's fine.
He actually saved us.
Saved?
Because no one would expect high school girls and an
elementary student to accompany us on a stakeout.
Not even the Hammer Man.
The Hammer Man!?
Didn't you see it in the news?
The Hammer Man was spotted in this neighborhood last night.
Yes.
On TV this morning.
Actually, the witness...
Happened to follow the Hammer Man...
And watched him...
He watched the Hammer Man enter this very apartment building.
And so...
We came over immediately after receiving the report.
After checking each apartment one by one...
We found that most residents had alibis, except...
There was one room that...
Even though they were inside and we rang the doorbell...
The occupant chose not to open the door
of their central, third floor apartment.
Then, why not just force your way in?
Just get the key from the landlord!
No, we can't!
That requires a warrant...
But is the one in that apartment really the Hammer Man?
Maybe he just imitated the Hammer Man and...
This isn't a copycat crime.
Last night, when the witness called out to him...
What's up, bro?
You lookin' for sumthin'?
When he panicked and ran away,
He left it behind...
That blood-stained hammer.
On it were traces of blood that corresponded
to the three previous victims as well.
But, isn't it remarkable that the witness managed to follow him?
I heard the Hammer Man can cover 100 meters in just 11 seconds!
Oh, that—
it's just an urban legend.
He doesn't appear to be that fast.
Let's keep in mind that the witness, a drunkard,
was able to keep up with the Hammer Man easily.
But, say...
If you know the apartment, you can find out who lives there, right?
Well, about that...
The usual resident of that apartment is a
backpacker currently wandering overseas.
He ended up lending it to his male friend temporarily.
Or so, that's what his parents said over the phone.
Don't they know who that man's friend is?
No.
According to his next door neighbors...
His girlfriend used to stay over and live there with him, but...
As of late, she no longer seems to stop by.
Now, he seems to usually spend the entire
day inside and only ventures out at night.
Since he's always wearing a hat or hood...
No one seems to remember what he looks like.
Sato-san!
Takagi-san!
Chiba!
They came and went from the apartment?
These three did?
Yeah.
I was staking out the apartment entrance from a distance, when...
I noticed these three coming and going from the room.
At ten minute intervals, one at a time.
Of course, you've already informed Inspector Megure, right?
Yes.
So, just what were you three doing in the apartment?
"What"?
The only reason I went there was because an order
was placed by phone to come collect a package.
I went to collect luggage from the resident, but for bike delivery.
I was just delivering a pizza that was ordered.
Then, I suppose all three of you met the resident?
No.
I didn't meet him.
There was a piece of paper taped below the front door.
It read, "I'm bedridden with a cold, so let yourself in...
"And help yourself to the cardboard box on the table."
The express delivery slip was filled out...
And the money was waiting in an envelope on top of the box.
I see.
And you?
I didn't meet the guy either.
The note there also mentioned what to do for the bike delivery.
"The luggage to be delivered is the bag on the table —
please take it."
I already knew the destination since
he had mentioned it with his order.
There were also instructions regarding
pizza delivery on the paper as well.
"The payment is in the envelope on the table.
"Leave the pizza in its place and go..."
I think, anyway.
"Bedridden with a cold," huh?
Yeah.
When I took the order over the phone, the
voice on the other end was extremely hoarse.
I thought so too.
Same with me.
But why did he call people to the apartment in succession...
Say...
Aside from you, Chiba-kun, there were two
other officers watching the entrance, right?
Yes.
The home delivery courier and the bike delivery
woman were stopped by the two of them...
And I stopped the pizza man, who arrived last.
Then...
Doesn't that mean no policemen are watching the entrance now?
Chiba-kun, I'll leave those people to you!
Yes!
If he called various people to the apartment...
The officers would have no choice but to stop and question them...
And inquire as to why they entered the room.
Moreover, it's the police officers who
have to approach each of them directly...
Which means his goal was to reduce the number of
officers keeping watch and use the opportunity to escape.
The memo beneath the door...
The pizza is untouched...
As I expected, he ordered it to make his escape.
Sato-san!
Just after Chiba-kun stopped the pizza delivery man...
The first officer who went after the home delivery courier came back.
He made it just in time to take over Chiba's watch, but...
He didn't see anyone come out of the apartment.
No way...
Then...
The Hammer Man is still in this apartment.
Could it be...
He's waiting to ambush us?
No.
It seems he didn't plan...
To ambush anyone.
Suicide?
It's all right.
His breathing is steady.
Takagi-kun! Call for an ambulance!
Ah, yes!
I see.
He had donned his coat and hat, ready to escape, but...
When he discovered there was no way out...
He opted to commit suicide instead.
But...
Before he stopped breathing...
The rope gave way and he fell onto the floor unconscious, I suppose.
I don't think this was suicide.
Look, on that man's neck.
You can't really see any rope marks, can you?
You're right...
Moreover, that hat...
I don't think someone about to commit suicide by
rope would wear a hat that would be so obstructive.
Then...
This hat...
This is...
What is this about?
It seems the one struck this time was the Hammer Man himself.
And the one responsible is...
Among the three that entered this apartment.
Chiba-kun?
There were three people who came and went
from the Hammer Man's apartment, correct?
Yes.
Could you bring those three up here?
I have some questions for them.
Ah, but...
All three seemed really busy, so...
When they asked if we could finish the questioning after work...
I just let them go.
Hey, hey...
So, it was like this, then?
While you were staking out the Hammer Man's apartment...
Three people came and went from it.
You assumed the Hammer Man called those
three in order to divert your attention...
As part of his plan to escape.
And when you came inside, you found the Hammer Man...
On the ground, unconscious.
Taking all of this into account, you concluded
the culprit was likely among those three.
But, not expecting the matter to take this sort of turn...
You politely let those three go on their way.
Well, am I right?
Yeah.
Right.
Mostly.
You...
Idiots!
How many years have you been working as police officers!?
We truly deserve only shame.
And?
What sort of people were they?
Yes, sir.
Let's see, they were...
A home delivery courier, a bike
delivery lady, and a pizza carrier.
Conan-kun?
Ah, no...
He just happened to be around...
I seem to remember...
The express home courier guy was really big and over 180 cm tall...
The bike delivery lady was a small woman under 160 cm...
And the one delivering pizza was thin and about 170 cm in height.
It's starting to look like Conan-kun is more reliable.
This sure isn't the first time, is it?
Really?
But...
Why did they end up hitting the Hammer Man?
Most likely...
The suspect here is somehow related to one
of the Hammer Man's four previous victims.
That would make it revenge, no?
While none of them have died...
All four have suffered serious injuries.
In other words...
The culprit learned from the news that another
incident had occurred in this neighborhood...
So they kept their eyes on this apartment,
which had been encircled by police...
Disguised in a way that wouldn't draw suspicion
should they go inside, entered the room...
And struck him.
That should be it.
But, why did you let them go without even getting their names?
No...
All three claimed they left receipts in this room, so I thought...
We could get their names and employers from those...
Only the pizza receipt was here.
No way!
Hey...
Chiba...
But...
We do have the pizza receipt, so...
That means...
We can check if it was him by just calling his shop, right?
He isn't back yet?
The one who went out for delivery hasn't returned yet?
Yeah.
He took that apartment order, and...
Left the shop about forty minutes ago, so...
I guess he'll be back any time now.
Has something happened to our employee, Officer!?
No.
All that comes to mind here is that...
The culprit called the pizza shop and made the
order as if he were the resident of this apartment.
After intercepting and seizing the delivery
man while he was en route here...
He stole his uniform and proceeded to
gain entry to the apartment secretly.
Right?
If that's so...
Were the appearances of the home
and bike couriers just a coincidence?
It's possible it was just camouflage, right?
Should just a pizza carrier appear, he'd draw attention.
All three did mention that he had a hoarse voice, so...
It's possible he did it on purpose in
order to make his voice unrecognizable.
And let's keep in mind that, since he arrived last...
The pizza carrier could throw the bike and home delivery receipts away.
But, don't you think it's strange?
Because the express home delivery man, who came first...
He saw the memo beneath the door that said,
"I'm bedridden with a cold, so let yourself in."
Afterwards, he went inside and got the package, right?
I don't think the pizza man that came last could have left any memo.
That's true...
The only one who could have left a message is the one
who arrived first —
the express home delivery courier.
Which means...
The reason he came wasn't for a package.
He instead lied about a delivery, forced his way into the room...
And knocked the Hammer Man unconscious.
As he was leaving...
He left the note under the door to ensure both the bike
courier and the pizza carrier would enter the apartment.
That way, he wouldn't be the only suspicious party.
But...
If that were so, the bike courier's receipt should still be here.
The only ones with an opportunity to toss away the receipts are...
The bike courier and the pizza carrier.
But...
Why would the pizza carrier leave a receipt behind?
The only one who could have gotten rid of
the pizza receipt is the pizza man himself.
As such, he likely planned to leave it.
I see.
Now, which of these three is the culprit?
Hey, how about we leave finding those three to the other policemen...
And investigate the rest of this apartment in the meantime?
The definitive proof that shows the one
staying here really was the Hammer Man...
You still haven't come across it, have you?
That's true...
All right!
Sweep this place thoroughly, from corner to corner!
Yes, sir!
Hey, Takagi-kun.
Find anything yet?
Ah, no...
Nothing of note except...
They seem to have kept this bathroom especially clean.
Is it maybe too clean?
Because, there...
Look.
The dining area is actually really messy...
Which makes it strange that only the bathroom is sparkling clean.
And also...
The electric razor on the washstand.
Electric razor?
Despite being chargeable, it isn't even plugged in.
Isn't it also strange how there is shampoo, soap,
and toothpaste, yet there's no toothbrush?
You're right...
This is starting to feel off.
Now this is really strange!
Down in the bathtub drain...
There's not a single hair to be seen.
No way!
Seriously!?
Sorry...
I think I tripped over your foot...
N-No...
I wasn't watching out...
You mentioned the drain, right?
Let's have a look.
This is definitely strange.
I wonder why just the bathroom is this clean...
Kiss me.
Right now.
A hot one.
Come on, hurry!
Don't stall!
Inspector Megure!
There's a blood-stained glove here!
Where was it?
Right here.
While I was sifting through the washing machine and dryer...
I found this glove mixed in with the clothes.
Then, does that really make the collapsed guy the Hammer Man?
And...
Did one of the three who came here attack him?
The one they thought was the Hammer Man...
You can never forget it...
That soft feeling...
What!?
There was no such thing to begin with.
Nothing like a "Hammer Man," that is.
Next Conan's Hint
Shift Pad
Look forward to the next episode
Next time, with Sato-san...
Don't get in the way, Conan-kun!
I dunno about that