Targeting only long-haired women...
Attacking with a hammer...
His name...
The Hammer Man.
With information from a witness...
His apparent residence and apartment was identified.
The detectives underwent a covert stakeout.
To avoid being exposed, they arranged a love scene, and then...
It was reported by Detective Chiba that three people had
successively entered and exited the staked out apartment.
The first: A male express home delivery
courier that came for a package.
The second: A bike delivery woman who
came to fulfill a luggage shipment request.
The third: A pizza man delivering a pizza.
However...
All three claimed to have not met the resident.
A memo that instructed, "I'm bedridden with a cold,
so let yourself in and complete your business..."
Was waiting under the door.
This could have been a diversionary tactic utilized
by the Hammer Man to escape the apartment.
Operating under that assumption, we forced our way inside...
But instead...
We discovered a man who had taken a serious blow to the head.
Is this guy the "Hammer Man"?
And was it one of the three who visited the apartment...
That struck him?
Among those three...
There may have been someone related to
one of the hammer Man's four victims.
However, when we tried to confirm their identities...
We learned that all three had already been released.
While investigating the room alongside the police...
I came across several points of doubt.
While the pizza receipt was found inside...
Those for the bike and express service
deliveries were nowhere to be found.
The chargeable razor wasn't even plugged in.
Even the bathtub was remarkably clean...
This is strange...
There's certainly something more to this case...
Something beyond our imagination...
Love is eternal, labyrinths are mysterious.
Saturday nights are for mystery!
The Hammer Man unexpected identity!
The captivating Deduction Queen, Sonoko, stages her entrance!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
While I was inspecting the washing machine and dryer...
I found this glove mixed in with the clothes.
Should forensics be able to link these blood
stains with those of the victim from last night...
We can conclude that the man found collapsed here is...
Indeed the Hammer Man.
Now, if we could just find something left
behind by the Hammer Man's attacker...
It'd be a great clue.
They're not here!
These clothes were in the washing machine and dryer, weren't they?
Yeah.
Then, why aren't there any here?
Any underwear or socks.
You're right.
There are T-shirts, sweatshirts, towels and the like, but...
Perhaps he threw them out after one use?
I once wore the same underwear for a week while on a stakeout.
Instead of washing them, I just threw them out...
Stakeout...
You were trying to appear as lovers...
So it wouldn't be so obvious you were on a stakeout, right?
Oh?
What else did you have in mind?
Nothing...
Uhm...
Is there something wrong?
Chiba, you've been on a stakeout with Satou-san before, haven't you?
Yeah.
Two or three times.
And during those times... Did anything happen?
Like what?
Ah, no...
If there wasn't, nevermind...
Do you mean...
The time I was pretending to be Satou-san's boyfriend?
Satou-san seems to do it quite often, so
her identity as an officer remains secret.
In my case, after she made me do that...
I couldn't concentrate on the stakeout anymore.
Don't tell me — you too!?
Yeah...
I will never forget it...
That soft feeling...
That soft feeling!?
Kiss me.
Right now.
A hot one.
What!?
Did you find something?
No...
Uhm...
We would like to take Conan-kun home soon, so...
Oh, right.
Thank you, Conan-kun.
Leave the Hammer Man to us police.
Ah, but...
Then, that man carried out on a stretcher
was also attacked by the Hammer Man?
No...
The one carried out was the Hammer Man himself.
It was likely revenge carried out by
someone related to one of the victims...
What?
No way!
I thought the Hammer Man was over 180 cm in height?
The man that was just carried out...
He didn't even look as tall as 170 cm!
That's an urban legend as well.
The victims were all struck from behind...
And only saw the culprit from behind, as he was running away.
They wouldn't be able to properly estimate his height.
The witness from last night was standing upright, but...
It seems he was drunk.
An urban legend...
Wait a minute...
The unusually clean bathroom...
The unplugged electric razor...
The absent toothbrush...
No underwear or socks...
And...
The note leading to the apartment...
The missing receipts for the express and bike deliveries...
Could it be...
There's a patch of leather attached to the tip of the left shoe.
The other shoes...
This is the only shoe with a patch.
Hey!
Look here!
Is there something wrong with the Hammer Man's shoe?
No...
This isn't the Hammer Man's shoe.
There was no such thing to begin with.
Nothing like a "Hammer Man," that is.
What do you mean?
"There was no such thing as a 'Hammer Man' to begin with."
See...
Things like the "Mouth-tearing Woman"...
And the "Human-faced Dog"...
They're merely embellished rumors that
end up as really scary stories, aren't they?
And in the same vein...
The Hammer Man running 100 meters in 11 seconds...
And being over 180 cm tall...
All I'm saying is...
These are just exaggerated to scare everyone.
The "Mouth-tearing Woman" and "Human-faced Dog"...
You really know some pretty old stories, you know.
I heard it from my school teacher!
But see, Conan-kun...
Unlike the "Mouth-tearing Woman" and the "Human-faced Dog"...
The Hammer Man...
Has four confirmed victims.
You can't say he's fictitious...
That only tells you there's a bad person that is
attacking long-haired women with a hammer!
But you don't know if it's really the Hammer Man, do you?
He's called the Hammer Man precisely because he uses a hammer!
Do you mean to say he didn't actually use a hammer?
What I mean is...
What is it?
Speak up if you have something to...
Sonoko?
That strange dance...
Could it be...
That's right.
Dance.
After hearing that keyword from Conan-kun, it finally hit me.
The fact that we have been artfully manipulated to dance...
By the urban legend of the Hammer Man.
She's here!
Deduction Queen Sonoko!
But, why does she seem exactly like Sleeping Kogorou?
What do you expect?
No...
Compared to Mouri-san, the extent of her leaning is different...
Really?
Wouldn't say that...
But, say, Sonoko-chan...
If the Hammer Man is merely an urban legend...
How do you explain the guy that was knocked out in this apartment?
I can only reason that one of those three who visited this apartment...
Decided to exact their revenge on the Hammer Man.
Try recalling and considering carefully...
The order in which those three entered, and...
The purpose for which they did.
Let's see...
It was...
A stout express home delivery man who was about 180 cm tall...
A short bike delivery woman who was about 160 cm tall...
And a thin pizza delivery man about 170 cm tall, in that order.
The reason all three came inside was...
A memo under the door read...
"I'm bedridden with a cold, so let
yourself in and complete your business."
And when it comes to the memo...
You should already be aware that only the home
delivery courier that came first could place it, right?
Then...
You should also be aware that the only ones able to
dispose of the bike and express delivery receipts...
Would be the two who appeared after the first
man — the bike courier and pizza carrier, no?
Yeah.
That's why we've been troubled until now...
Well, maybe it will become consistent should
we consider it from this perspective...
What if we suppose the one who placed
the memo and disposed of the receipts...
Was the Hammer Man in this apartment?
Sure, he might have been the one to put the memo there.
But what reason would the Hammer Man
have for throwing away the receipts?
It was to prevent us from promptly contacting
their employers to confirm their identity...
Considering they planned to switch
places with him from that point onward.
What!?
"Switch places"? Don't tell me...
You mean to say the Hammer Man
switched places with one of those three?
Yes.
In order to switch places...
He called for express home delivery, bike delivery, and a pizza delivery.
In other words...
The man found unconscious in the apartment...
Is actually one of those three.
I see.
The people called over here by phone...
Followed the instructions on the memo under the door...
And, when they consequently entered the apartment...
He would strike them...
Help exchange their clothes for his uniform, pose it as a suicide...
And then boldly exit out the front door of the apartment.
If that's the case...
The express home delivery man that arrived
first can be eliminated as a suspect.
His physique is clearly far different from
the man knocked out in the apartment.
He's also unable to dispose of the
bike delivery receipt that came later.
Which means...
The pizza carrier is without a doubt the Hammer Man.
And the fact that he hasn't returned to the shop further supports this.
All right!
Cordon off the area immediately!
We have to apprehend the pizza delivery man—
My, my...
Haven't you had enough dancing?
What!?
Just now, when I heard about the state of the
apartment from Conan-kun, I instantly knew...
The true face of the Hammer Man.
The state of the apartment?
The unusually clean bathroom...
The chargeable electric razor that was unplugged...
And the missing toothbrush.
I also mentioned that there were no
underwear or socks among the clothes.
What did you draw from that?
Isn't it obvious?
Cleaning the bathroom and removing the toothbrush...
Were both acts to erase all traces that
they had been living here all along.
The chargeable electric razor remained unplugged because...
It wasn't in use.
And the reason there were no underwear or socks in the laundry...
Was to hide their gender.
You should understand now, no?
Don't tell me...
Don't tell me, the Hammer Man is...
The Hammer Man is...
A woman?
That bike courier woman!?
Right.
Underwear is obvious, of course...
But even for the socks, which are usually small, they had to be hidden.
This was all to conceal the fact that a woman was living here.
While it's true the attacker has always
been referred to as the "Hammer Man"...
None of the victims ever identified the culprit as male.
It was probably the media that assigned that name to her...
After all, the weapon being a hammer does have a violent precedent.
And any moniker ending with "man" is always memorable.
Now that you mention it...
Even though they said the one living here was male...
They also said he brought his girlfriend to live here as well...
In other words...
The one who actually stopped coming was the man...
While the woman continued to stay in the apartment, right?
Well...
Once you look at the shoe Conan-kun found
that had a strip of leather attached to it...
It all becomes clear.
What it is is a shift pad, used for protecting
the toe from the motorcycle's shift pedal.
That shoe was the only one of its kind in the shoe cabinet...
And judging from the fact there were none others like it inside...
The shoe doesn't belong to the bike delivery
woman that's staying here, but instead...
It belongs to the true delivery man that was attacked here.
It's likely that she decided to take her feminine
clothes and shoes along with her underwear.
They were probably put in the daypack she used for the delivery.
Chances are, you'll find the pair of thick-soled boots inside
that she used to gain the height of a male for her attacks.
I see.
If she weren't wearing those boots that were popular in the past...
The drunk witness wouldn't have been able to keep up with her.
But...
If that's so, why didn't the pizza carrier return to the shop?
It's highly probable he was knocked unconscious
by the culprit and locked away somewhere.
Should he not return, the police would naturally suspect him.
All right!
Organize a cordon immediately!
For now, I'm not sure it's necessary.
But if we don't hurry, she'll get the bike and...
If her intent was to use a motorcycle...
She wouldn't have left this shoe equipped with a shift pad here.
Which means...
She planned to waste no time getting out of her jumpsuit.
After all, it wouldn't be easy to ride in a taxi with it on.
While it's true that changing in a bathroom would be ideal...
She would garner too much attention in a family restaurant...
And make it more likely someone would remember
her normal clothes and face without cosmetics.
As for a bathroom that would make that avoidable...
A park bathroom!
If it's a nearby park...
It'd have to be where the incident happened last night, Beika Park!
As for there...
It's being investigated as we speak.
Stupid man...
Believing such a lie.
Say...
In that park back there...
There was a bathroom stall that wouldn't open,
so would you mind coming along with me?
I'm just concerned because this was
the site of a Hammer Man attack.
Ah, I guess...
I'm not seeing that stall.
How strange...
It was just locked!
Now, I just have to get out of this jumpsuit...
Get out of this park...
And find myself in a place where the
eyes of the stupid police can't reach.
Did something happen?
I'm with the police.
You are aware an incident occurred here just last night, right?
Y-Yes...
Is there something in the bathroom?
Well...
I'm not sure if it has anything to do with the case, but...
Back in the inner stall, there's a collapsed man lying there.
It's true...
I'll go ahead and call for my subordinates.
If you will cooperate, please come along and answer some questions.
Yeah...
It'd be my pleasure!
I've heard all about you...
Miss "Hammer Man."
Isn't that it?
And with that, the Hammer Man...
No...
The Hammer Woman, was safely apprehended.
The peculiar urban legend that spread so suddenly...
Came to an end before greeting the next generation.
Her motive for the crimes was unwarranted
resentment for the man who left her.
As for targeting long-haired women...
That was simply the type her boyfriend starting seeing after her.
After the witness found out where she lived...
She decided not just to run but to make
that man out to be the real culprit.
She was surrounded by the police much faster than she expected...
And resorted to foolish decisions.
You were a huge help back there, Sonoko-chan.
It was as remarkable as a Sleeping Kogorou deduction!
Especially when you said, "Haven't you had enough dancing?"
You were like a real Deduction Queen!
You don't remember?
Oh, no...
Not the details...
None, actually.
And you too, Conan-kun—thank you.
Well?
How far did it get?
How "far" did what get?
Isn't it obvious?
With Satou-san!
Hasn't it been a while since you started dating her?
I don't want to discuss it with you...
Could it be...
Because I pretended to be Satou-san's
boyfriend on that one stakeout?
I'm not upset or anything...
Come on, we just held hands.
But wait, I remember you saying something about a "soft feeling"...
It was the feeling of her squeezing my hand so tightly!
Well, right after that...
I was scared by the look she was using to glare at the suspect.
But, just a little, you know...
And that was all?
Yeah.
Didn't she do the same with you, Takagi-san?
It was a stakeout, you know.
Well, in my case...
Kiss me.
Right now.
A hot one.
I see...
Because it was me...
Because it was me, Satou-san...
We've finally located the home of the suspect's
younger brother in the murder case.
It's in Okucho-cho, District 3, second floor of the pachinko parlor.
According to our intel, the chances of him
meeting with the suspect soon are high.
We'll need some of you on stakeout, of course.
I'm going with Satou, who has followed this one...
Yes, yes!
Please select me, sir!
It's so unlike you to volunteer for a stakeout.
You weren't aware?
I actually really love stakeouts.
Keep your guard up.
He may just be the brother, but they say he's merciless all the same.
Yes!
Be careful.
Yes?
"Be careful"?
Looks like there's...
No movement, huh?
Inspector Satou...
Uh-huh.
The name "Satou" is a pretty common one, isn't it?
At least it's a good name, right?
This is Matsumoto.
I'm currently at Enba Harbor in pursuit of the serial killer suspect.
What?
Really?
Yes.
The stolen car's model and color match the report.
He's proceeding to park now, and is the only one inside.
Confirming plate number now...
Shinjuku 5—
What's wrong, Matsumoto?
What's the rest?
Whistling?
There's no doubt about it!
This is him!
He's whistling right now!
That tune!
He saw me?
Hey!
Respond, Matsumoto!
Matsumoto!
Superintendent Matsumoto!
Are you all right?
You seemed to be out of it there.
Ah, excuse me.
Seems I dozed off for a moment.
Why not go home and get some rest when you get a chance?
As of late, you've been staying overnight
and not getting any rest, haven't you?
There's nothing that can be done.
The expiration on the serial murder case is in one week.
Even now, the hands on the clock are ticking.
And?
Where are those two people who came forward right now?
It's the one who left this scar on my face...
The suspect from back then.
Next Conan's Hint
Nickname
Look forward to the next episode
The amazing Deduction Queen, Sonoko-san!
And the Dance Queen as well, you know.