There, they've rounded the final corner...
We're down to the last 200 meters!
Come on!
Which horse will win?
Will it be the favorite, Iron Blade, in Lane 4?
Come on, come on, come on!
Or, maybe even the trump in lane 2, Devil Typhoon?
Come on, just a bit more...
The outcome will depend on the fighting spirit of each horse!
For the sake of the Mouri Detective Agency's future!
Love is eternal, labyrinths are mysterious.
Saturday nights are for mystery!
The clue is a large scar!
Differentiate between the first love and the suspect!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Iron Blade in Lane 4 leads by a half-length...
Masked Yaiba in Lane isn't far behind...
Come on...
And Black Chaser in Lane 8 is close!
And there!
We have one coming from behind!
Come on!
Devil Typhoon! Devil Typhoon! It's Devil Typhoon!
Come on, come on, come on!
It's over!
The winner is Devil Typhoon!
What an unexpected outcome!
Finally!
The crowd is in an uproar!
No way!
You won?
Yeah!
The three million jackpot!
Three million!?
Dear, God!
Thank you for watching over this detective agency!
Especially during this particularly difficult month!
That's because we practically had no cases this month...
Please hold on...
The judge's deliberation lamp has been lit.
Was there a problem in the scramble to the finish?
Look at that!
Devil Typhoon in Lane 2 has been disqualified for stepping out of lane.
And now, the new order has the winner as Iron Blade from Lane 4!
God!
Haven't you always been on my side, buddy!?
Come to think of it, recently...
There was a rich lady...
Who bought a lottery ticket on a whim and won 100 million yen.
It was all over the news.
What!?
Moreover, she said she plans to give the winning ticket to someone.
It seems that, when she met with a traffic accident in her childhood...
A boy was seriously injured trying to protect her...
So she wanted to express her gratitude by giving
him the 100 million, if he would come forward.
And?
Has this lucky boy appeared?
Well...
In the course of the accident, her eyes
were damaged and she lost her sight.
Since the boy was also a child then...
She wouldn't be able to identify him by his face or voice anyway.
Then...
How does she intend to find that boy?
From the injury he sustained during the accident.
It was a huge wound...
So even after growing into an adult, the scar would still be there.
Wow, I have a scar as well!
Two years ago —
it's the scar from when I slid headfirst
on the baseball field and injured the top of my shoulder!
Do you think there's any chance I can fake it!?
"Fake it"?
Hey, hey, this old guy...
It wasn't on the shoulder.
There was a straight tear across his T-shirt.
I clearly recall the blood seeping from it.
Afterwards, my eyesight began to deteriorate.
That is the only image I cannot forget.
It's this person—the 100 million yen...
In that case, are you here to ask me to find
that boy by using only the scar as a clue?
Yeah.
There are people who have come forward claiming they are the one.
In fact...
There are two of them.
Two?
I see.
You'd like for me to determine which of these two is the real one?
Yes.
Shoudou Kurumi (39)
Head of the Shoudou Family
The boy who saved me was just one person, after all.
Which means...
One of them is a fake.
Someone who would pretend to be the one from
this kind lady's memory for the sake of money...
What a shameless bastard!
You're one to talk...
And?
Did you observe the scars on the two of them?
Houya Taisuke (40)
Butler
Yes.
Although I did see them...
Well...
The brown-haired man has it on his back, while...
The man with the dark complexion has one on his chest...
Both of them have very large scars.
On the back and chest?
Miss, do you not know the location of the wound?
No.
I only remember that it was severe and nearly went from side to side.
By the way, where did the accident occur?
That was...
During the summer holidays, some thirty years ago.
It happened while I was on vacation with my parents in Izu.
I met a boy around my age at the beach, and we became good friends.
During the vacation, we played together every day.
He was very familiar with the sea and the types of fish.
And he always drank ginger ale.
He looked so cute when I could see his white teeth
gleaming alongside his tanned face from time to time...
My, it was love at first sight.
But, those dream-like days couldn't last for eternity...
On the last day of the vacation...
When I cried and told him, "I don't want to go home..."
"Then, stay here..."
"I'll protect you," is what he said at the time.
And, how old were you at the time?
I think I was in my second year of elementary school.
This lovey-dovey even in the second year of elementary?
And, how did the accident happen?
I selfishly petitioned for my parents to stay in Izu for one more day.
When I saw him walking on the road near
the coastline, I tried to run up and tell him...
But just when I caught him...
A drowsy driver ended up veering toward the sidewalk.
Afterwards, I was unconscious for three days.
When I came to, I was already in a hospital bed.
And...
You don't know what became of that boy after that, right?
Yes.
I was told later that that boy...
Had carried me to the hospital with a large wound of his own.
He told the hospital staff that he would call for his parents and left...
But was never seen there again.
But...
You must have asked for his name, right?
I mean, you had been playing together for a while...
Gari-kun!
"My classmates refer to me as Gari, so
that's what you can call me as well."
That was the answer you gave on TV, right?
Yes.
"Gari" should be able to count as a name...
And?
Where are those two who came forward right now?
They've been staying at my house for the past two days.
What a luxurious home!
I bet a place this big sure takes a while to get clean, huh?
Yes.
It's all due to the limitless effort of Houya-san and the two maids.
But, since there are only four of us living here, including myself...
There are rarely many places that need cleaning.
No, I bet the dusting is more than enough...
Uhm...
When you say "four" people, does that mean your parents...
My mother passed away from illness some time ago.
My father, who had taken care of me until his
death, fell ill and passed on three years ago.
Just prior to my father's passing...
He decided to hire this butler.
This is the one who took on the burden of caring for me, Houya-san.
Not at all.
It's certainly no burden.
Well, it seems we've added two more recently...
And, with you, that will bring us to nine.
I suppose we'll have quite a feast tonight.
So good, so good!
As they say, the more the merrier when meals are concerned.
Is that so?
One of us here doesn't belong, and yet is getting a free meal.
Kasumoto Ryuuhei (42)
Don't you think it's best if you admit it already?
Impostor-kun.
Banba Sougo (41)
I think I'm the one who should be saying just that!
Well, we'll sort this out later.
Detective Mouri will ascertain the truth.
Is that not so, Mouri-san?
Well...
I'll question them in the next room, individually, for the time being.
Well then, Detective-san.
Until later.
Yeah.
Please do your best to differentiate between them.
The possibility remains that both of them are impostors.
Yeah...
After all, it has been thirty years now...
It's possible the boy has already passed away.
No!
He is here.
I have no doubt that he is in this house!
I refuse to think that way.
That's why I specially requested the great
detective, Mouri-san, to investigate.
It seems that I've grown a little tired...
I'll retreat to my room for some rest.
Once you have reached your conclusion...
Please come and reveal it to me.
Yes.
Could that lady...
Already know which one is him?
Say...
Conan-kun...
Conan-kun?
What's wrong?
Did you see something outside?
You don't feel it?
As if we were being watched...
That feeling.
I'm not really feeling anything.
Afterward...
Uncle inquired with the two of them
over the boy from thirty years ago, but...
The two of them only repeated the same answers.
But, that was to be expected...
What!?
She mentioned everything about the situation in her TV interview?
The date of the accident, the model of the car, and
even the name of the facility she was hospitalized in.
That would explain why they answered
all the questions exactly the same...
How can I identify which is which, then?
As I thought, there is someone out there!
And...
There's not just one or two of them!
Uncle!
Come over here!
The hell are we doing outside?
Who's there!?
Detective Takagi, and Detective Chiba?
What are you two doing here?
No...
We're on a stakeout...
For the suspect from fifteen years ago.
Fifteen years ago?
Have you forgotten, Mouri?
It's the one who left this scar on my face...
The suspect from back then.
Superintendent Matsumoto...
But, superintendent...
Fifteen years ago, Mouri-kun had just been promoted to detective...
And wasn't involved in that case.
Oh, is that so?
But, superintendent...
By the time I was assigned to the metropolitan
police, I'm pretty sure you already had that scar...
Yeah.
Five years prior to that...
That same suspect gave me this scar with a katana.
Could you mean...
Twenty years ago?
I cornered him at the docks.
I took the katana from his hand and paid him a strike of my own.
On his body...
There's a 1-shaped scar.
A 1-shaped scar...
It can't be...
Yeah.
After seeing this woman's story on the news a few days ago...
I figured that guy would take notice.
That's why I'm here.
And...
Was the scar from the katana on his chest or his back?
I'm afraid I don't quite remember.
He was certainly a worthy adversary, though.
Is that so?
You neither...
Well, at the time, the superintendent...
Had just been cut across his left eye, so it wasn't easy for him to see.
But it seems I was right in coming here.
This scar on my left eye...
It's starting to ache.
It's telling me that our man is in that house.
There's a serial killer from fifteen years ago is in this house!?
We still aren't sure if he's actually in here.
Then, what Conan-kun said earlier about us being watched...
It was the police.
Superintendent Matsumoto has been
looking for this criminal for a long time.
It seems this was the one who gave him the scar on his face.
Well, at the same time, the superintendent...
He used that guy's katana in retaliation
and left a 1-shaped wound on him.
A 1-shaped wound—does that mean...
Yeah...
It would seem the serial killer has it as well.
From one side to the other, there should
be a large wound from the katana.
But, why has a serial killer come to this house?
It's likely he has his sights set on the 100 million yen lottery ticket.
After all, he can use the scar he got from the superintendent.
In other words...
The boy from her memories could be either the brown-
haired Kusumoto-san or the dark-skinned Banba-san...
But the one that isn't could be the serial killer.
And...
Where is the serial killer's scar?
I think Kusumoto-san's scar is on his back...
While Banba-san's is on his chest, right?
About that...
It seems the superintendent doesn't remember...
But it did happen just after his eye was injured.
Then, do you mean to say there aren't
any other clues aside from the scar?
Well, the culprit then was wearing gloves...
Which meant they couldn't lift any fingerprints
from the katana that was taken from him.
And since the katana had been the
murder weapon in multiple cases...
The blood of the criminal and that of his victims had
mixed together, which made it difficult to pinpoint.
And he didn't see his face?
Right.
With a hat, long hair, and beard...
It was clearly a disguise.
That's obviously not going to be enough!
What about the whistling?
Whistling?
Since the murderer was always whistling a certain melody...
Superintendent Matsumoto said, "Casually keep
watch over those two and find out who is who."
And, what kind of melody is it?
Not sure.
He was reluctant to share any further information
with me, and when I tried to get it out of him...
He said it's possible that I would make it "obvious" a
police investigation was ongoing, so he didn't tell me.
But...
If there's such a dangerous person in here, there's
no reason to have sent Conan-kun back inside.
I actually had no choice but to come back.
If I suddenly disappeared, the murderer might suspect something...
And then discover the police watching over the house outside.
About that...
As I said before...
We can't be 100% sure that one of those two is the murderer.
That's true, but...
Yes?
The bath has been prepared, so...
Should you like...
Offering a bath, even after treating us to that feast...
Well, if you would be so kind!
But there's only one washroom here, so should you wish to use it...
Perhaps the young lady should go first.
Hurry up.
You won't be able to use a washroom at
a place like this for a long time to come.
I guess so...
Then, Conan-kun...
Why don't we go in together?
It's been a while...
Since we washed each other's backs, hasn't it?
N-No, I...
I don't have any clothes to change into...
And I was just in one yesterday, so...
Oh?
But...
If you really want to do it, Ran-neechan...
Enjoy!
I thought you probably wouldn't want
to go, so I decided not to enter either.
Right...
Well, I can focus on the murderer instead of the bath now...
But, so long as we don't know which melody he
whistled so often, there isn't much to go on.
First, we'll need to see through those two
and find out which is the boy from the past.
Say...
Uncle Kogoro talked with Kusumoto-san and Banba-san, didn't he?
Yeah.
They mentioned the day of the accident and
the name of the hospital she was taken to...
It seems they both relayed the same story.
Were they really identical?
Not even a small difference between them?
You know, that's strange...
You were there and didn't listen this one time?
Blame the police outside for getting my attention instead...
That's true...
If only their stories differed...
Kusumoto-san claimed he was was thin as a child...
While Banba-san said he was always studying hard when he was young.
Is that it?
Would you like to ask that lady yourself?
But...
I have a feeling that she...
Already knows exactly which one is the one she's looking for.
You know...
I've seen these in dramas and movies, but...
To think this sort of luxurious bath exists...
Oh, if it isn't Mr. Detective!
We thought we'd join you if you didn't mind.
You two entering together, huh?
Must be well acquainted!
Nah, just a coincidence.
I heard you were coming into the bath, so I thought I'd join you...
And maybe see how your case is going.
Well?
How is it?
You already know which of us is real, right?
It's a trade secret, you know...
This is perfect!
Now I can ask about the melody just as the superintendent
requested, but without approaching these two directly...
Oh, isn't that the butler?
You joining us as well?
Oh, no...
I am only here to see to the detective's back...
Per request of the madam.
My, I believe you're suspecting too much.
If I had already known which it was...
I would have had no reason for calling Detective Mouri here.
I guess not, huh?
Say...
Is there anything from the past you omitted during the TV interview?
Well, I believe I included it all.
You see, he was a perfectly honest person by nature.
I figured it would be simple for Detective Mouri to solve.
Perfectly honest?
Yes.
He bought packed sushi for lunch, and when he later
realized he'd received 100 extra yen in change...
He went really far out of his way to return it to the shop, right?
Yes.
He said it was because it didn't belong to him.
That person liked sushi, then?
Yeah.
When we ate fried noodles in a house by the sea...
I was surprised to see him heap such a
large amount of red ginger onto his plate.
That may be the first time I've heard that story...
Oh, really?
Well, please relay that to Mouri-san for me.
Sorry for the trouble.
No, please do not bother.
You know...
Whenever I enter a bath...
I feel like reciting "Hana Uta," or another great tune!
How about you two?
Yeah.
I guess so.
Happen to have any favorite songs?
Well, not really.
There is a melody I find myself humming a lot, yeah.
Superintendent!
I've received a mail from Mouri-san.
Well?
"The brown-haired guy chooses jazz...
"While the dark-skinned guy prefers soul."
That's all.
Return a mail to him.
Just say...
"Continue the investigation," huh?
Really now...
To order me around just when I send news...
Butler, you doing all right?
You have a pretty heavy sweat going.
Yeah, well...
The air conditioning in the bathroom went out not long ago.
Due to the sweat, I can see...
A scar!?
That...
That means that, now...
The number of people with a 1-shaped scar in this house...
Is now up to a total of three...
You're wondering whether it's natural or manufactured?
That doesn't matter!
A letter on the bodies of the victims, huh?
Next Conan's Hint
Sushi
Order any sushi you want.
Look forward to the next episode
All righty, let's have sea urchin,
abalone, tuna belly, salmon roe...
Ah, two eggs.