Thirty years ago...
Shoudou Kurumi (39)
Head of the Shoudou Family
Shoudou Kurumi-san befriended a boy by the sea.
Ultimately, that boy saved her life in a traffic incident.
When Kurumi-san won 100 million yen on a chance lottery ticket...
She decided to give it to that boy instead...
And announced it in magazines and on TV.
The clues were: Her memories of those summer days...
As well as the large scar the boy received while rescuing her.
Two men came forward claiming to be the boy.
Kusumoto Ryuuhei (42)
Kusumoto Ryuuhei-san had a scar on his back...
While Banba Sougo-san's was on his chest.
Banba Sougo (41)
Both were shaped like the number 1.
In order to ascertain which was truly the one...
We decided to go along to the Shoudou estate.
But there...
Outside that very house, investigating a
serial murderer from many years ago...
Were detectives from the first division, watching secretly.
The criminal from that time also has a 1-shaped scar on his body.
Houya Taisuke (40)
Butler
However...
It was soon discovered that the butler of the estate,
Houya Taisuke-san, also has a scar on his back.
Of them, which is truly the "Boy of Memory"?
Love is eternal, labyrinths are mysterious.
Saturday nights are for mystery!
With the deadline approaching, it's time to identify the first love!
The scar case takes an unexpected turn!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Really?
There's a scar on the butler's back as well?
Yeah.
Compared to those of Kusumoto-san and Banba-san...
It's short and only about 15 cm in length.
This also suggests that the butler,
Houya-san, could be the serial murderer.
Why?
Wasn't the serial killer's scar a big one?
Well, the superintendent couldn't exactly see well
at the time, after just being injured by the culprit.
He wasn't in a position to accurately estimate the length of the scar.
Not to mention, it seems the murderer is quite a cautious person.
After the superintendent cut him,
the culprit did escape by car, but...
When the police discovered the car later, there
were absolutely no signs of fingerprints or blood.
Since the driver's side seat cover had been peeled off...
His blood had probably gotten on it.
That's why he must have wiped away the fingerprints afterwards.
But, why are you already suspecting the butler is the murderer?
If someone were that cautious, it isn't like they could
be lured in with money—even if the scars were similar.
Even though they could tell the blood had been wiped
away, there was no reaction at all from luminol testing.
Those three scars...
Kusumoto-san's is on his back.
Banba-san has one on his chest.
Then, there's the small one on Houya-san's back.
As children...
Kusomoto-san was thin, and Banba-san loved to study.
The boy of memory was familiar with both the sea and fish...
His favorite drink was ginger ale.
He loved to eat sushi and fried noodles...
As for his character, he was honest.
He was known to his classmates as...
Gari?
Yes?
How is it going?
The investigation.
Ah, no...
I'm not quite sure yet.
Is that so?
Well, there is still time.
A midnight snack has been prepared, so, should you like...
Midnight snack?
Could that be...
Sushi maybe?
Yes.
That's impressive, you know.
Then, how about this?
This is a secret, though, so...
A little lower.
What's he saying?
Then, I can count on you for the rest?
But, I'm surprised...
I was under the impression you were a short
high schooler whose voice hadn't changed yet.
But to think you're just a little boy...
It's as if Sherlock Holmes were imitating a child.
Really?
I'm able to see that which others cannot.
Well, I'll be waiting in my room.
I'll leave the rest to you...
Mr. Detective.
Yes!
As delicious as expected!
Mr. Butler, do you want to join us?
That lady said you should eat, too.
Well, then...
Natural ingredients really do taste the best.
No, this is manufactured.
What're you saying?
Of course it's natural!
You agree with me, don't you, Detective?
Ah, well...
If you ask me...
Dad?
You're wondering whether it's natural or manufactured?
That doesn't matter!
"Doesn't matter"?
Well, I'd say it's important...
Now, now—you see, the boy of memory...
It's been said he knew the sea and fish well, and loved sushi.
That's why you thought you could appeal to me with this, no?
No...
Well, it wouldn't be impossible.
That 100 million yen would be enticing enough to try anything.
Speaking of sushi...
What happened when the boy bought the packed sushi?
I received 100 yen in excess change,
so I went back to the shop to return it.
It's in my nature to not keep what isn't mine, you know.
That's pretty strange.
What is?
Well, that honest boy that returns
everything that doesn't belong to him...
If the chance arose for him to get
100 million yen from someone else...
Do you think he'd take it?
What're you talking about?
It was all because of the help I gave her after
what happened in that accident back then.
She wanted to express her appreciation with the 100 million yen!
What's wrong with coming and accepting it?
You saw it yourself in the bath, didn't you?
The big scar I got from that accident!
No...
I owe the scar on my back to that accident.
It's true that you both have large scars of around 30 cm in length.
But, what brings questions of doubt to my mind is exactly that.
Didn't the lady say it in the interview?
"The scar reached from one side to the other," were her words.
She didn't say much else, but she was certain it was a big scar.
And, about how old were you at the time?
I was in around my second or third year of school...
Oh?
If you were in your second or third year at the time...
The scar would have only been around 15 cm long.
Well, see...
When I first got the scar, it was about that size.
As I grew up, the scar got bigger as I did...
Oh?
You didn't know?
That scar wouldn't increase in size no matter how much you grew.
What!?
If a scar is 15 cm at the time...
It should stay 15 cm until death.
Ah, well...
I just had a big physique is all.
Same with me!
Oh, Kusumoto-san?
I recall you mentioning being thin in your childhood.
That's...
I bet that, when you heard the boy of memory's
name was Gari, you mistook what it meant.
You took it as garigari, for "skin and bones."
Gari is actually for gariben, "someone who studies hard."
Gari from gariben, huh?
Did you know?
When the boy from her memories ate fried noodles by the sea...
He heaped a pile of red ginger on top of it.
What do you mean?
I've never heard that before!
It should come as no surprise that you haven't.
This is a new story that she only just told me today.
You still don't see it?
The boy of memory that loved ginger ale...
Bought packed sushi often...
And heaped red ginger on his fried noodles...
I see!
That boy liked ginger, right?
Ginger is one of the key ingredients in ginger ale...
And the Gari that goes with sushi is pickled
ginger that results from soaking it in vinegar!
Then, does that mean that boy got the Gari from...
Yeah, that's right.
The boy with a fondness for ginger was known as Gari.
Isn't that right?
The one who didn't eye any other sushi...
But went straight for the ginger...
The butler, Houya Taisuke-san.
No way!
The real guy was here!?
Yeah.
There's a scar on his back about 15 cm in length.
I'm not mistaken, am I!?
Then, why didn't you say something!?
You could have got 100 million!
That money is something I could never accept.
If I had not told her, "Stay here," back then...
She wouldn't have been involved in that accident.
Therefore, I decided to support in secret...
Well, it seems you weren't able to do it in secret, after all.
Don't you see?
Given that she clearly knew you wouldn't
accept something that wasn't your own...
Isn't it obvious as to why she announced
she'd give you 100 million on TV?
She wanted the one by her side to come out and tell her.
She wanted you to tell her before any impersonators appeared!
Then, that lady really did already...
Yeah, she'd already discovered it.
She knew that the butler, Houya-san, was the boy from her memory.
The reason she had you see to my back in the
bath, even with the broken air conditioning...
And her reason for withholding the red ginger story...
As well as why she had sushi prepared for a midnight snack...
They were all just hints for me to follow.
Well?
What will you do now, Houya-san?
The lady is waiting in her room.
No...
But...
I...
It's all right!
I'll go tell her in your place if you want!
Or would you like for me to tell her?
I know she wouldn't want these two that came
just for the money to use her precious memory.
I...
I understand!
I'll tell her myself.
Seems we were able to push him well, huh?
Yep.
Geez...
With my situation as it is, I couldn't tell the truth even if I wanted...
Were you saying something?
It's Kamen Yaiba!
It'd be terrible if his identity were revealed!
Well, I'll just...
You know...
Please wait just a moment longer.
The police?
We were just joking!
I got this scar on my chest while surfing a long time ago, so...
No.
Our business is with the one with the big scar on his back...
You.
As for that scar...
Some twenty years ago, there was a serial killer...
Who, after being cornered by Superintendent Matsumoto...
Ended up with a 1-shaped scar on his back from a katana.
I couldn't remember whether it was on the back or the front at first.
But, with the mail from Mouri, it all became clear.
Mail?
Oh, man...
I forgot to return Uncle's phone.
Normally, when someone is injured,
they'll cover the wound with their hand.
However, there was no reaction on the steering
wheel when we tried the luminol test, because...
His hand couldn't reach the wound.
In other words, it was on his back.
You pulled off the cover on the driver's
seat to get rid of the blood, did you not?
No...
That's not it!
I met a guy a long time ago that had a scar
on his back, and I thought it was cool...
So, I just copied him!
Enough with the random excuses!
It's true!
Please, believe me!
And, did this man happen to be whistling?
Did he?
Yeah!
I think it was...
A song that was popular like, twenty years ago!
Is this the truth?
Yes!
Superintendent...
A song that was popular twenty years ago...
The song of the serial killer...
His name is Kusumoto Ryuuhei, 42 years old.
The incident dates back to fifteen years
ago, when he was homestaying abroad.
We were able to verify it, so...
He can be removed from the list of possible suspects.
I see.
He came across the man in question at a
sauna, just before leaving for his homestay.
There was a towel covering his face, so he wasn't entirely visible.
"The scar on my back is a badge of courage
a cop gave me some five years back."
"You want one too, by any chance?"
That's what he said, with a laugh.
And that sauna?
Sato and Takagi have just gone to make inquiries.
Tell them to be on their guard.
Yeah...
Two victims twenty years ago...
One victim fifteen years ago...
That's three victims he's claimed...
He's a ruthless criminal.
No, there's one more.
Have you forgotten?
How could I forget?
Superintendent Morimura, who was
killed in the line of the duty on that case.
He was the man who taught me the
fundamentals of being a police officer.
Superintendent Morimura...
Even after being promoted two classes
ahead after you died in the line of duty...
I still don't understand...
What you meant back then.
Matsumoto...
There's something...
His whistling...
There's definitely something to it!
Just what did you mean, Morimura?
And we ended up with nothing for our effort.
There's nothing that can be done.
The case was fifteen years ago, after all.
That's true.
The building's been renovated, and
the class of customers have changed.
Hey, there's a large remodeled spa on 5th
street that everyone is saying is great!
Really now?
Why don't you head over there with Chiba-kun?
I'd rather go alone...
Oh?
Were you inviting me?
Of course I was!
Then, how about this?
If we catch the serial killer before the deadline...
The two of us will go to the hot spring.
But, there's only three days...
Take me to the hot spring!
Hey, wait...
Is this really all right?
Police officers being so lovey-dovey while on duty.
We weren't being lovey-dovey...
We're here asking about...
Don't reveal too much to the children!
You're right...
Hey...
To summarize the case from what's been on TV...
Along with the story I heard from Superintendent Matsumoto...
The first case occurred twenty years ago.
The victim was a 50 year-old doctor: Boukawa Tsuguharu-san.
The murder weapon was the Japanese sword from his house.
Just two days later, the next victim was...
An associate professor of science and engineering at Tohto University...
The 42 year-old Mugita Atsunori-san.
The weapon was the same sword.
Then, while a detective was questioning him...
There was a driver that appeared suspicious
that ended up suddenly driving off.
The detective on duty was struck by the car, and died.
After he caught up with the car, Superintendent
Matsumoto was attacked by the culprit...
And even though his left eye was injured...
He took the katana from his attacker and cut him across his back.
As a result, a 1-shaped scar was left behind.
And five years later...
Nabei Susumu-san, a 34 year-old lawyer, was
killed with a kitchen knife from his own home.
His method.
Render them unconscious with a stun gun...
And then cruelly slice at their bodies with swords and bladed weapons.
In all three home cases, there were no signs of break-ins...
Which led police to believe it was an acquaintance, but...
The case went cold because no common points
could be found to connect the three victims.
Well, I'm right, aren't!?
Yeah...
But, I still don't get it.
The first and second victims died by the same weapon,
which is why it's assumed they share a perpetrator, but...
That's true.
The case five years later involved a kitchen knife.
How do you know it was the same offender?
Ah, no, that's...
That's because...
All of the victims had the same letter cut into...
Wait, Sato-san!
Weren't you the one who told me to stay quiet about it?
Sorry...
Every time these kids ask...
With under three days remaining before the
deadline is upon us, do you think he can caught?
They're broadcasting about it now!
That case!
Criminal Psychologist, Hiramune-san.
With the conditions as they are, let's say that it's highly unlikely.
The culprit has probably drawn the curtains...
Hiramune Douji (41)
Criminal Psychologist
Unplugged his phone.
And isolated himself from the outside.
The suspect is likely trembling in bed,
waiting for the deadline to pass.
To remain inconspicuous, he'll keep disposing of his safe tiles...
Just waiting for this round to end.
In the event that isn't the case, come kill me.
If you're prepared to throw away the hardships you've
endured while hiding for fifteen years, I mean.
I know that man!
He lives in the same apartment building as I do.
Then, since we're going over to Ayumi's to play today...
We might get to see him, huh?
That man there.
Perhaps.
Well...
We might come across the serial killer as well.
Oh no!
Don't come!
Ai-chan, you're scary!
Well, have a safe walk home.
Don't hesitate to call us if the murderer appears!
Yes!
A letter on the bodies of the victims, huh?
Awesome!
You can totally see the buildings way out there!
The scenery at night must be really great, huh?
We're home!
We bought juice!
And quite a few snacks as well.
You bought Yaiba chocolate too?
Of course!
By the way...
We happened to pass a strange man near the entrance.
A strange man?
It was a man who was whistling and wearing an off-season long coat.
What!?
What kind of person was this!?
Did you see his face!?
No...
He had a beard, and a hat drawn over his face...
Listen, all of you!
Until I get back, don't take a single step out of this room!
Is it possible that guy heard Hiramune-san speaking on TV...
And really came after him!?
The serial killer!
Hiramune-san...
The suspect was whistling at the time...
While tears poured down his face.
Next Conan's Hint
Letter Z
I'll protect you, Ayumi-chan!
Oh? And what about me?
What now, Mitsuhiko?