Two of them twenty years ago...
And one fifteen years ago, became victims of the serial murderer.
It was then that that the criminal...
Ran down Superintendent Morimura with his car and killed him.
Superintendent Matsumoto in turn followed him,
and ended up with a scar over his left eye.
For the cases twenty years ago, their respective statutes have passed.
But for the case from 15 years ago...
There are still three days until the time runs out.
There are two clues that connect the criminal.
The first: A scar on the culprit's back
courtesy of Superintendent Matsumoto.
The other: Whistling.
A song that was popular twenty years ago...
He was always whistling it.
As Detective Takagi and the others carried out their investigation...
Hiramune Douji (41)
Criminal Psychologist
A criminologist by the name of Hiramune Douji-san...
Appeared on TV and repeatedly provoked the
criminal as he had in magazines before.
And then...
We happened to pass a strange man near the entrance.
It was a man who was whistling and wearing an off-season long coat.
Could it be...
He actually came here!?
The serial killer!
Love is eternal, labyrinths are mysterious.
Saturday nights are for mystery!
Something is different about Detective Takagi!
Will it be a straight line to arrest the culprit!?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult.
His name is: Detective Conan!
Seriously, Conan-kun!?
You're saying that, at that apartment building...
It's highly likely that the serial killer appeared!?
Right!
That criminal psychologist, Hiramune-san,
just ridiculed the serial killer on TV...
Hiramune
So he may have come to his apartment!
Regardless, I'm going to check out his room!
Wait, Conan-kun!
Conan-kun!?
Chiba-kun, ready the car!
Yes!
Hiramune
That's strange...
It's unlocked...
Hiramune-san?
Are you here?
Hiramune-sa—
Hiramune-san!
It's no use.
This is...
Could this be...
It's a Z...
The victim is the criminal psychologist, Hiramune Douji-san...
Age 41.
The murder weapon was a fruit knife from the kitchen.
Judging by the stun-gun markings on his neck...
As well as the alphabet letter carved into his back...
Most likely, this was...
The work of the serial killer.
But this time, the letter is a Z.
I completely expected an N this time.
Judging by the investigation reports...
The letters carved on the previous victims were...
E S W —
in that order.
Should it have been an N this time, we
would have east/west and south/north.
Touzai (East/West)
Nanboku (South/North)
Huh?
If it's Touzai Nanboku...
That's East, West, South, North...
E W S N, huh?
Well, we can be sure it wasn't a copycat.
That is, since the culprit cutting letters into the
bodies of his victims was never made public.
And it seems Conan-kun's friends passed by the
man as he was whistling near the entrance, right?
But, with only knowing this much...
After you heard your friends mention a man that was whistling...
You remembered him ridiculing the culprit on TV...
And then thought Hiramune-san might be in danger...
Which caused you to rush over here.
You're as attentive as a police detective...
Conan-kun.
But, what he said...
Was it really that provoking?
Yes.
"The suspect is likely trembling in bed,
waiting for the deadline to pass."
"In the event that isn't the case, come kill me."
Isn't that a challenge?
Yeah.
Hiramune-san was known for this style
of writing in newspapers and weeklies.
It seems Hiramune-san immediately left the TV studio
after his appearance at 4:00, and hurried home.
In fact, he said he was going to meet an acquaintance.
It's very likely that this acquaintance is the suspect.
Maybe...
That certain someone is related to a copy machine?
Look, underneath Hiramune-san's left hand.
The Ctrl and C keys are stained with blood.
When you press those two keys together, don't you get "copy"?
That's true, but...
It could have been left deliberately by the criminal.
But still, there's no blood on his left hand, right?
True...
Why is there just blood on his right hand that's grasping the mouse?
That makes me think...
He stained the keyboard with his bloody right hand...
And then specially covered it with his left hand, you know?
If the suspect had planned this, would he have done that as well?
You're right.
He would focus on making it more noticeable, huh?
Since his left hand wasn't covered in blood...
We know he didn't end up staining the keys by chance while typing.
I guess that means he used his left hand to cover it...
Simply because he didn't want the suspect to notice?
In other words, this—which was left by
Hiramune-san just as he was dying...
Amounts to a dying message.
There also seems to be a copy machine in this room.
I inspected it earlier, but I didn't find anything out of the ordinary.
Could it be a copy band?
The suspect was always whistling a song that
was popular some twenty years ago, right?
Doesn't that mean he could know people from a copy band?
There are many such bands.
Superintendent Matsumoto.
Superintendent!
That means it could be a song that's popular all over the world, no?
Well, as for the serial killer...
This melody holds some sort of deeper meaning.
Deeper meaning?
Immediately after that incident twenty years ago...
Morimura was questioning drivers of suspicious
cars that frequented the area of the crime scene.
It was during the questioning that he was struck
by a car and killed in the line of duty, right?
Yes...
When Morimura approached the car, he noticed that...
The suspect was whistling at the time...
While tears poured down his face.
Tears?
All right!
Sato, Chiba —
inquire around the neighborhood.
Yes, sir!
Shiratori, look into everyone related to Hiramune-san
again, but with the clue of the copy machine in mind.
That was my intention.
Takagi, just in case, visit the relatives of the previous three victims.
See if they have any connection at all to Hiramune-san.
Understood?
Yes, sir!
I understand!
Well, he's enthusiastic.
Looks like my medicine has been more than effective, huh?
Only three days remain before the
statute on the murder case is reached.
But, if the criminal has committed a new offense,
the statute will last another fifteen years!
Ah, no...
The Code of Criminal Procedure was amended...
The statute of limitations on murder cases
was extended to twenty-five years!
So long as I can catch the serial killer
within the next twenty-five years...
Sato-san and I can go to...
The hot spring!
I see now.
That would explain why you were more enthusiastic than usual.
Your motives are impure.
A hot spring, that's great!
You should take us with you!
What are you all doing in my car!?
You were the one who let us in back there.
You asked us, "Where do you want to go?" in the parking lot...
And opened the door without saying anything else.
It didn't seem like you were really paying attention, though.
I was thinking about the hot sprin—I mean, I had the case in mind.
Well?
What will you do?
Will you permit us to stay?
Or will we be dropped off?
Of course I'll be dropping you off!
But, Ayumi-chan and Haibara-san saw the culprit, didn't they?
But, see...
I'm just going to the homes of the relatives of the
victims fifteen and twenty years ago right now.
But you know...
The family of the victims were all considered suspects as well.
Or so, that's what they said on TV.
That's true, but...
Well, if this continues for another twenty-five years...
And assuming Detective Sato is still waiting for you
as a 50 year-old woman with wrinkles on her face...
I guess you can try to do it all alone.
So hollow...
It will be fine if you do it now!
She's still really beautiful!
Don't you think it's worth it?
All right?
Only Conan-kun is conning with me.
The rest of you need to wait patiently in the car, all right?
Yes!
Say...
The one we're here to see...
She's the widow of the doctor that was murdered
twenty years ago, Boukawa Tsuguharu-san, right?
Yeah.
Boukawa-san was the clinic head of a large hospital.
Because his wife, Maiko-san, inherited a large fortune with his death...
She became suspect and was called in for a number of line-ups.
Anyway, we had no proof, and since there was no
connection to the second victim, Mugita-san...
She remained only a suspect.
Yes...
I know this man.
This is the criminal psychologist that seems
to always be on TV—Hiramune-san, right?
Boukawa Maiko (62)
Wife of Boukawa Tsuguharu
What about him?
He was found murdered in his apartment earlier.
The one responsible is most likely the very same
person that killed your husband twenty years ago.
My, that's upsetting...
As such, we've come to ask if your husband had
any sort of connection with Hiramune-san.
Well...
Just how old was this Hiramune-san?
He was 41 years old.
Then, when my husband was killed twenty
years ago, he would have only been 21.
My husband was 50 years old when he died.
I can't imagine there's any link between them...
Is that so...
Are you sure he never met anyone in secret?
Who is this child?
I'm here to observe how policemen work for my social studies class!
Oh, is that so?
But, it is true that he would often go out for
drinks with someone on Saturday nights...
Do you have any idea who that was!?
No...
But once, when he returned home especially drunk, he said...
"Damn! Wouldn't stop with the 'crybaby,
crybaby,' making me out to be an idiot!"
He said something along those lines.
It was probably an old friend my husband knew from his childhood.
I told all of this to the police twenty years ago, though...
The relative we're visiting next is for
the second victim twenty years ago.
Murdered just two days after Boukawa-san...
We'll see the younger brother of that associate professor
of science and engineering, Mugita Atsunori-san.
As beneficiary in his brother's sizable life insurance
policy, he was also considered a suspect, but...
Just like with the wife of the first victim,
there was no connection between them.
What about the third victim, Nabei-san?
Of course, there was no connection found there either.
This is a criminal psychologist named Hiramune Douji-san, you say?
No matter how many talk shows the guy has been on...
Mugita Hidekuni (56)
Younger Brother Of Mugita Atsunori
It doesn't change the fact that I dislike TV, you understand.
Well, Hiramune-san has been murdered.
We're confident it was the same one who
murdered your brother, Atsunori-san.
Aren't you surprised?
Yeah, well...
After the statute on his case expired five years ago...
I'm afraid I decided to forget about it.
Then, well...
Is it possible your brother and Hiramune-san knew one another?
Who knows...
I don't think so.
Saturday nights...
Did your brother happen to meet with anyone on Saturday nights?
Yeah...
He would often venture out on Saturday
nights and not return until morning.
My brother's wife, who died the
year before last, told me about it.
She was worried he was using Saturday nights for an affair,
and would always call his pager to keep tabs on him.
It seems my brother would grow angry as he called back.
"I'm going to the Doctor's now!"
"Quit nagging!"
Like that.
Could that doctor be...
The first victim in the case, Doctor Boukawa!?
Yeah.
I told the police about it twenty years
ago, and it seems they looked into it.
Apparently my brother's name wasn't on his patient list, right?
That does seem to be the case, huh?
What is it, Detective Takagi?
Did you come across something?
Nothing at all.
And you, Ayumi-chan and Haibara?
Did either seem similar to the culprit?
I didn't notice any similarities.
And I don't think it was the old lady.
Well, if they had been wearing a wig and synthetic
facial hair when we passed by them earlier...
It's possible our impression could change, isn't it?
That's true.
Where are we headed next?
Ah, the last one is...
Related to the murder case that occurred
five years after the cases twenty years ago.
We'll be meeting Eika-san, who is the son
of the murdered lawyer, Nabei Susumu.
Eiki-san was just 10 years old at the time.
He was sleeping in his room and was awoken by his father's moaning.
Between when the culprit left and his
mother returned home from shopping...
He was too scared to even leave his room.
His mother went into shock after seeing her
husband's body, and ended up bedridden...
She is still hospitalized to this day, and
Eiki-san continues to live alone in the house.
Enough is enough, Detective!
Have I not discussed this case with the police enough!?
Nabei Eiki (25)
Son of Nabei Susumu
With this deadline coming up...
The news people are all over me!
I'm tired of this shit!
So what if this criminal that killed my father got someone else!
How does that concern me!?
Well...
We just want to know if your father was
acquainted with this man, Hiramune-san...
Who knows!?
Idiot!
Idiot?
It seems he wasn't always like this.
Really?
Yeah.
According to the inspector, when the boy
was questioned about the incident...
He claimed that, before the murder, his
father had said something strange.
It seems every time he remembered something, he
would come to the police to report it immediately.
Something strange?
He usually slept until noon on Sundays, and it seems
he was mumbling something after waking up...
"Had some parents run over last night as well, too bad."
Like that.
Someone's parents were probably run over by a car.
I see!
It's because he was a lawyer.
He probably decided to defend the ones
responsible or the victims involved.
And?
Why is that considered strange?
The murder victim, Nabei-san, specialized in corporate cases.
It appears he never took on a traffic case.
Then, why?
It seems Eiki-san found it strange and didn't
understand it either, so he reported it to the police.
Crybaby...
Going to the Doctor's...
And parents being run over, huh?
I see.
I finally get it...
The connection between the four victims.
Mahjong?
The connection between the four serial murder victims...
It's really just mahjong?
Hiramune-san said it when he was on the talk show, right?
It was when he said, "He'll keep disposing of his
safe tiles, just waiting for this round to end."
That's all mahjong terminology, right?
Hiramune-san must have truly liked mahjong.
That may be true, but...
What about the other three?
The first victim that was killed, the doctor, Boukawa-san...
He came home drunk one Saturday night...
And apparently said, "Wouldn't stop with the
'crybaby, crybaby,' making me out to be an idiot"
As for the associate professor of
science and engineering, Mugita-san...
Also on Saturday nights, his wife would call
his pager, and when he called back...
"I'm going to the Doctor's now, stop nagging," he said angrily.
The lawyer who was killed five years
later, Nabei-san, got up one Sunday...
And the first thing he said...
Was something like,"Had some parents run
over last night as well, too bad," right?
The crybaby Boukawa-san mentioned was actually
misheard for what's known as opening doors in mahjong.
Why would he want to cry?
Isn't mahjong just a game?
It's when you try to hurry and win early...
By collecting tiles discarded by other
players, to form groups of 3's and 4's.
That's opening doors.
Then...
"Had some parents run over last night as well, too bad" means...
It could have been, "Had oya ni run over last night as well, too bad."
His son Eiki-san could have misheard that, right?
The parent in mahjong refers to the dealer,
who can capitalize for extra points.
To personally be run over is to be overtaken by
someone who has more points, thereby losing.
So...
What he really meant was, "Had the dealer
run me over last night as well, too bad."
But, what about Mugita-san saying, "I'm going to the Doctor's now"?
That was probably...
"I'm listening to the tiles now, stop nagging," or...
Something like that.
It's true!
It does sound like "going to the Doctor's."
But what does that mean, "listening to the tiles"?
When you're just one tile away from a
win, it's called "listening to the tiles."
"One more" tile is what you need.
That's why he angrily said, "I'm listening to the tiles, stop nagging."
Well...
Since everything they said involved mahjong terminology,
it shouldn't be surprising that non-players misheard them.
That's true...
Those who heard these statements were
Boukawa-san and Mugita-san's wives...
As well as Nabei-san's son, Eiki-san, who was still a child.
What the suspect said when Eiki-san was
a child was also related to mahjong.
What the suspect said?
After the suspect killed his father and was
on his way out, Eiki-san apparently heard...
"Don't think I'm cruel."
"I'm having you pay your dues."
"Because you had to talk like that, I had to ready my hand."
"And as a result, I ended up with this long scar from the cops."
That's it.
Paying your dues and readying your hand are both part of mahjong.
And?
What do we do now?
Do you have to ask?
The probability of those four meeting for
mahjong on Saturday nights is high.
Now is the time to narrow our search to the mahjong parlors...
That those four could have accessed easily from their homes and jobs.
When it comes to mahjong parlors, even complete strangers
will play together, with no mind for differences in age.
All right!
Detective Boys...
Let's go!
For you all, is the time all right?
It's already 9:00.
Don't worry.
We told our moms we would be staying at the Professor's tonight!
"No problem."
Oh, really...
All right, let's do this!
Yeah!
Just wait, Whistling Man...
I'll uncover your true face without a doubt.
It's our man on the line!
Take absolute caution!
When it comes to hostages, I guess it'll just be me, huh?
Next Conan's Hint
Mouse
Why is it called a mouse?
You'll know next week!
Genta's talking strangely...