With just three days remaining before the serial murder case expired...
A criminal psychologist by the name of Hiramune
Douji-san repeatedly provoked the serial killer...
And was later found murdered at home.
On his back was...
A wound in the form of a Z.
On the bodies of the serial killer's three previous victims...
Were the letters E S W in that order.
When Haibara and Ayumi-chan saw someone suspicious...
And mentioned that he had been whistling...
The police concluded the serial killer had struck again.
In order to visit the bereaved families of the victims...
We accompanied Detective Takagi as he interviewed them.
It was then that we discovered that the
connection between the four victims...
Was actually just mahjong.
The serial murderer...
I'll uncover your true face without a doubt.
Love is eternal, labyrinths are mysterious.
Saturday nights are for mystery!
Detective Takagi has enthusiastically gone into a pitfall!
An emergency development of love and mystery!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
I do recognize these gentlemen!
They were frequent customers that would
always share a table, quite a while ago.
Brings back memories...
But who's this?
That's the criminal psychologist, Hiramune-san.
This picture is from twenty years later, though.
This must be the student that would always play with those three.
Then, you're saying those four did play mahjong here?
Every Saturday night at 10:00 PM, always these four.
There was the doctor...
The associate professor of science and engineering...
The beginning lawyer...
And the criminal psychology university student.
There was a gap in their ages, but they had things in common.
They would often discuss and reason
through cases over games of mahjong.
"The culprit was the husband that was interviewed."
"The trick utilized his expert medical knowledge."
The crazy thing was that they were usually right!
And?
Why are you asking about them?
They were murdered.
And, by the same criminal...
What'd you say!?
All four at once!?
No, the first was twenty years ago...
You didn't know about it?
I haven't kept an eye on the news for a long time...
I only checked the cases that those four mentioned in the newspaper.
Actually, I only bought the paper for those two years they were here.
When they stopped coming, I no longer bought them.
Stopped coming?
Yeah.
I couldn't hear it very well, but they mentioned a "complete crime."
After that, the student was the only one who would come.
He would sit down at a table alone and polish tiles all by his lonesome.
If they were killed, the culprit was likely that man.
Are you saying you have a lead!?
There was a customer that was always
annoyed at the deductions of those four.
After everyone else stopped coming, that one man
would always tease the lonesome student...
It even resulted in a big fight between them.
I remember him yelling at one point...
"I'm gonna do something about all of you!"
And could you please tell us who that was?
Who knows...
He had a reputation as being bad, but...
As for his name...
Oh, there was that incident where that gun disappeared.
When a police officer left his police box open...
His handgun ended up disappearing.
Even though it caused quite a stir,
it was returned within two days.
There were rumors that that customer was responsible.
And back during their fight, this case of tiles was scattered about.
Due to the damage, they couldn't be used anymore, though.
And those mahjong tiles were thrown by that customer as well?
Yeah...
Who cleaned up the tiles?
I did.
When the police came to stop the fight and took those two
away, I picked them up and collected them all in this case.
Then, you're saying that the only fingerprints on those tiles...
Belong to you, Hiramune-san...
And that one other customer, right?
Who is this boy?
He's just observing for a social studies class...
Not to mention, if those two were hauled in by the police...
There should still be records of it somewhere, no?
That's true...
Then...
We'll take these damaged mahjong tiles along with us.
And your fingerprints as well.
Say, now that you mention it, I got a weird call last week.
A guy asked if a doctor, an associate professor, a lawyer,
and a criminal psychology student all used to play here.
What?
You've found a lead to the suspect in the serial killer case?
Yes!
Twenty years ago, the suspect got in an argument with
Hiramune-san and was restrained in a police box!
Address and occupation unknown...
His name is...
Kibo Dokurou!
Kibo...
Did you say Kibo Dokurou!?
"Kibo"?
You mean that burglar-murderer?
I'm fairly certain he was just discharged from prison a
few days ago after a fifteen year prison stint, but...
Then...
The reason the serial murders stopped during those fifteen years...
He was incarcerated for that period and was unable to continue.
Yes.
It's probable.
All right!
We must find this man at once!
Bring him before me!
Yes, sir!
It seems he's really enthusiastic about this case...
Takagi, I mean.
Maybe he found a woman?
Yeah.
I've heard some occasional rumors to that effect...
Be sure that he's on his guard.
Don't you see it in movies and dramas?
He'll make a careful promise to his wife or lover...
And then end up taking a bullet of misfortune
from a suspect, dying in the line of duty.
But, those—they're just stories, after all...
Morimura fell victim to it as well.
He had planned to marry the very next month...
So, to impress the woman, he acted on a whim of haste...
And was run over by the suspect's car.
Satou-san!
We're going!
Age has brought my time on as well.
This scar...
It reacted when I heard someone had met the suspect in a sauna.
And there was even more pain when I walked
into the crime scene of the fourth victim.
Now, with only a few hours behind us,
it's as if it has all come to an end...
And the pain is long gone.
It could be heaven signaling to me, saying that my work here is done.
Geez...
I was just thinking you had investigated quickly, but...
Conan-kun was helping from the shadows, wasn't he?
Nah...
I guess that means the hot springs trip is off, huh?
It's all right!
Go with him to the hot springs!
He still found the culprit, didn't he?
Don't be so narrow-minded!
I cannot!
Personal feelings are not permitted in investigations!
I had almost forgot...
Just one mistake in this line of work can mean death.
Well, I'll take these kids home in my car.
You go accompany Chiba-kun and the others in the search for Kibo.
Yes!
Yes, Satou speaking.
We already got Kibo!?
It seems he was found in his apartment.
He decided to come along voluntarily...
So we need to get the son of the first
victim Nabei-san, Eiki-san, down here.
It's to identify his voice, right?
He heard the voice of the suspect as a child.
That's it.
We'll leave it to you.
Then, Takagi-kun, you get Eiki-san.
Yes, understood!
It's hard to believe he was captured so easily, isn't it?
The serial killer...
I thought we would be out on an exciting chase after him...
At least a gun fight, you know.
You only see that in movies and dramas!
In reality, it's pretty plain.
You're looking bleak.
The Z on Hiramune-san's back is what's bothering me.
As for as the three previous victims...
Their bodies had...
E S W  carved into them.
The last letter should be N, but...
It's possible that there was no pattern at all, right?
Touzai (East/West)
Nanboku (South/North)
If it's Touzai Nanboku...
It shouldn't be E S W N...
But instead E W S N.
No...
If it were mahjong, ton nan shaa pei would work, but...
All we can cover right now E S W.
Why would the last letter be a Z?
The killer could have just planned to
position the body sideways, right?
If you rotate a Z, you get an N.
But, if that's so, it makes you wonder
why he didn't leave it sideways, no?
Guess you're right...
Another point of concern...
Would be the Ctrl key being covered with Hiramune-san's blood...
That is, the control key, along with the C key.
Even though pressing those two keys results in the copy function...
Why would he need to grasp onto the mouse cord?
"Mouse"?
In order to operate a PC, you need to
have that round device plugged in, right?
The cord running from it resembles a mouse tail.
That's why it's known as a mouse!
Then...
Because he caught the tail of a mouse...
That person must be a cat, right?
Geez, you don't have to say it in such a cute way...
Ayumi-chan.
It's true, isn't it?
There's no need to be laughing about it!
A cat?
I see.
So that's how it was...
The serial murders came to an end...
Fifteen years ago.
You gotta help me here, Officer!
I've been behind bars for fifteen years and just now finally got out...
I have no desire to kill anyone again.
You think this is our man?
Since the one who heard the suspect's
voice back then was Nabei Eiki-san...
We should wait until he can confirm it for us.
Say, Megure...
How would you handle it?
If the officer that put a big scar on your
back long ago appeared in front of you.
I'd be surprised...
When that guy passed by me just a minute ago...
He didn't even raise an eyebrow.
It's possible that this Kibo Dokurou...
Kibo Dokurou...
Isn't the serial killer?
Why not?
Since the victim today was that criminal psychologist, Hiramune-san...
It's likely that he was acquainted with the real suspect.
But, since those two had been involved in a fight long ago...
I can't imagine they would agree to meet in that room together.
Not to mention...
Hiramune-san left a dying message.
A message that said his killer was not actually the serial killer.
With the blood on the Ctrl and C keys, he meant "copy."
And by holding onto the mouse cord...
He was referring to the cat holding the mouse's tail.
If we combine them...
"Copycat."
In other words, the one who killed him trying to
be the serial killer was just that—an imitator.
mouhou han
An imitator!?
What is that?
Is it like mixed boiled rice?
maze gohan
It's like a blue birthmark on a baby's bottom.
That's not an imitator.
What they mean by imitator...
Is an offender that copies another criminal's methods.
But why is it a cat?
It's simply because a kitten always tries to imitate the mother cat.
But how did Hiramune-san know that it was an imitator?
That's simply because...
The murdered Hiramune-san...
Happens to be the original serial killer.
If you consider that, it makes perfect sense
as to why a Z was carved into his back.
Due to Superintendent Matsumoto, the serial killer
had a big 1-shaped scar on his back from a katana.
To cover that scar...
And to not let anyone discover that Hiramune-san was the serial killer...
He had to come up with a letter of the alphabet that would fit.
I see.
By doing this, he is able to camouflage the murder
as one committed by the serial killer, right?
If all went well, the police would continue
chasing an already deceased serial killer...
While the real murderer would never be suspected.
And?
Which one is it?
That copycat.
Since they knew about the whistling habit...
It was someone close to one of the victims.
That's strange...
Even the light is still on.
It's open...
Nabei-san?
This is the police officer that was here earlier!
Nabei-san!
Would you come to the station with me?
Nabei-san?
All of the victims' family members knew about
the letters being cut into the bodies, but...
As for those that knew about the whistling and mahjong references...
There was only one.
Are you saying...
It's the one who heard the crime in
his house as a child, Nabei Eiki-san!?
Right.
He also knew the voice of the criminal.
It's likely that he heard the voice and tone of
Hiramune-san on TV, and remembered it by chance.
That made him go searching for the
mahjong parlor his father had visited...
Which is how he found out how the other
three had been connected to Hiramune-san.
After that, he was convinced Hiramune-san was the serial murderer.
Since it took him fifteen years to come to that conclusion...
That could mean Eiki-san did not become familiar
with mahjong terminology until adulthood.
Wait a second!
This Eiki-san is the really angry person we went to visit earlier, right?
That person—just now, Detective Takagi went to...
So you're the cop they've got looking into the serial murder case.
Looks like you brought a gun along, too.
I guess the reason you came alone...
Is because no one realized I was the culprit, right?
The "culprit"?
Then...
It can't be that you killed your father fifteen years ago!
Idiot...
That was all Hiramune's doing.
I was just taking out vengeance for my father today.
I called that bastard.
"I just remembered something about my father's murder."
"I wanted to run it by a criminal psychologist
such as yourself before going to the police."
Right over the phone, the meeting was set.
He never expected I was coming for revenge.
With just a little convincing, he felt like talking.
The motive for murdering my father was apparently
the "complete crime" that came up during mahjong.
Something about whether it would be possible to steal
a gun from the police without anyone taking notice.
They had differing opinions, so...
Hiramune decided to prove to them he
could really pull off a complete crime.
He expected them to praise him, but instead, the doctor
and professor said that the crime stops at mahjong.
He grew afraid that they would reveal the truth and
ruin his future, so he did something about them.
My father stayed quiet, since he knew it was his
joking around that encouraged him to try it.
Some five years later...
My father suggested that they turn themselves into
the police, so his mouth had to be silenced as well.
And now...
What should we do here?
Even if we take off in your patrol car, they'll get me sooner or later.
That's...
My cellphone...
Lookie here...
Is this a call from your girlfriend, Cop?
Terrific.
Have her come here.
She can be my hostage.
Oh, don't you worry.
If I do manage to get away, I'll set her free.
Come on, hurry and answer it!
Not that I need to tell you, but...
If you say anything fishy, I'll use the gun and...
Look at that...
Seems I broke my cellphone.
When it comes to hostages, I guess it'll just be me, huh?
Bastard!
What?
The culprit is Nabei Eiki?
Yes.
If nothing else, he's at least responsible for killing Hiramune-san today.
Takagi was en route to pick him up, but I can't seem to contact him.
Hurry and send back-up, now!
This is to all investigators!
Move to the house of Nabei Eiki immediately!
It's highly likely he is now in possession of Takagi's handgun!
Take absolute caution there's little time!
Listen up!
Any minute could cost our man his life!
Takagi-kun...
Son of a bitch...
Do I look like a moron to you!?
That's it!
You're done for!
Damn it, they must have...
Figured it all out!
It can't be...
Satou-san...
No choice...
If I rush him now...
Satou-san...
No way!
Takagi-kun was...
Shot...
What!?
It seems...
This is a common pattern in movies and dramas.
It can't be!
Just because of the hot springs promise...
Why did Takagi-kun have to die for it!?
Hot springs?
Detective Takagi!
Ah, no...
It's all right, see?
He happened to put this material evidence in his chest pocket...
And, following the pattern, the criminal's bullet landed there.
That mahjong tile...
That's right...
He put it in his chest pocket.
Thanks to Takagi-kun rushing at Nabei Eiki and getting shot...
All of the other officers came out just fine.
Because of him, this case only had one victim in the end.
Then, Takagi-kun is...
Ever since they finished treatment, he's been in the ward...
Sound asleep.
In that song he was whistling...
The author had written, "This is how it has
to be," which had always reminded him.
So, in order to remember those Saturday night deduction battles...
Hiramune Douji would reminisce while whistling that tune.
That's what Superintendent Matsumoto said.
I see...
But, oh well...
Since you're injured, I guess we have to cancel the hot springs trip.
Do you mean the deal was still valid!?
Yep.
It looked like you really gave it your all, Takagi-kun.
But, I guess...
It's too bad, huh?
It always ends like this...
For me.
The time during the bombing case...
And the time during the Hammer Man case...
It's always so close...
Which room is Takagi's?
I believe it's 304.
Hot springs...
Hot springs?
And what do you mean by "so close"?
No...
Just interruptions...
Wait!
Conan-kun?
Detective Takagi just took his medicine.
He's fast asleep in there!
That's why it's best...
To not wake him!
You would like him to recover, no?
I see.
I guess we can come back later, right?
Guess so.
They'll definitely take us to the hot springs with them now, right?
Definitely!
No, I don't think that's likely...
You mean that spooky house?
Apparently there's some strange guy living in there.
It seems we need to scout out that house, like the police would.
After all, we are the Detective Boys!
But, what about the nameplate on the house?
But, that person...
Why would they move into such a spooky house?
Let's investigate.
Every mystery deserves to be solved.
Next Conan's Hint
Nameplate
Look forward to the next episode
The nameplate at my house says "Yoshida"!
What about you, Conan-kun?
Ah, I guess it's Mouri.
He's a freeloader.