Hey, hey, hey...
There's a spooky chateau on 3rd street, right?
You mean that abandoned house that no one lives in anymore?
Last night, I heard my mom say...
Some strange man came out of nowhere and started living there.
In that haunted house?
Since it looks so spooky, no one wants to go near it.
It seems we need to scout out that house, like the police would.
It's our duty as the Detective Boys!
Roger!
Love is eternal, labyrinths are mysterious.
Saturday nights are for mystery!
Hidden in the famous painter's masterpiece...
What's this astonishing mystery you think you can see but can't!?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
It's really strange to think someone would
purposely move into that kind of house.
I'll say, I'll say.
I'm actually more interested in the one residing in your
house, rather than whoever's in this haunted house.
You mean Okiya Subaru-san?
That guy's nothing to worry about.
After all, he's a Holmes fan.
You're choosing to be illogical, aren't you?
It's none of your business.
I can lend my house to whoever I want.
I suppose, but...
Huh?
It's become really pretty here.
Looks like the one who moved in took good care of the landscape, huh?
I'm telling you, you're giving me a hard time...
We agreed it was only valid until today, didn't we?
Two or three more days won't hurt anything.
But we have our own schedules!
At any rate, I can only give you until tomorrow...
I have my own concerns here!
Now, leave!
You can't...
You had better keep your promise, please!
Beika Mortgage Company...
Who are you kids?
What do you want from me?
No...
Well...
Say, Uncle...
What's with your nameplate?
It's blank.
It's true—there's no name.
I haven't placed a name on it yet.
I couldn't.
Not yet.
To think you wouldn't put your own nameplate, it sure is weird.
Yeah.
What could he be up to?
In such a house...
However, the next day...
That guy died!?
What happened?
It seems he wasn't in good health.
He collapsed at home last night and managed
to call for an ambulance himself, but...
Although he was acting strange...
I feel sorry for him.
That's true...
But I wonder what he was planning to do
after moving into that haunted house.
Let's check it out.
Our minds won't be at ease, right?
With an unsolved mystery lingering.
The neighbors said they don't know much about that man.
Yeah.
Even though he moved in three months before...
He didn't acquaint himself with the neighbors.
He seldom left the house, too!
Everyone said he would always either stay inside to
fix up the house or go out to maintain the landscape.
Maybe he didn't have a job?
It's here, it's here!
No doubt it's here.
Say, Uncle...
Are you an acquaintance of the man who lived here?
You mean, you all knew Wada-sensei?
Sensei?
He was a sensei of some kind?
Yes.
Master Wada Rokurou was a famous
Western-style painter representing Japan.
So that guy was a painter, huh?
Then, you are too?
Oh, no.
Yagami Keiichi (50)
Art Dealer
I'm an art dealer that has been handling
Wada-sensei's masterpieces for a long while.
Sensei said he borrowed this chateau to use as an
art studio for painting a new masterpiece, so...
Hayashi Kaoru (25)
Yagami's Secretary
There's no time for that, President.
Let's hurry and find the painting.
You're right.
If someone were to steal them, it would be tragic.
Looks like this was a mystery easily solved.
About who that person was...
And what he was doing here, at least.
If he was painting all the time, it would make
sense as to why he didn't go out often.
But, I wonder what kind of picture he was painting...
We really wanna see, right?
That's true...
Right?
Sorry to drop by...
This way!
Yes!
There's nothing here...
It's because it was only borrowed as an art studio.
This house.
Huh?
Hey, hey, Conan-kun!
Could this kid be that man from childhood?
Sure looks like it.
What's going on, children?
Ah, no...
We just wanted to see that guy's paintings.
About that...
We didn't find any, even after searching the other rooms and upstairs.
Could it be that someone stole them?
Ah, no, we didn't see any art supplies at all.
No easels, canvases, paint, or brushes.
Are you sure this really is his art studio?
Yes.
There's no doubt about it.
I finally found it!
The perfect chateau!
Wada Rokurou (55)
Western-style Painter
At that place, I'll create a once-in-a-lifetime masterpiece!
Sensei absolutely said that.
Couldn't it be that he simply put his art
supplies away after he finished painting?
That's true.
Let's give it one more careful search!
Excuse me?
Wada-san?
We're about to commence the deconstruction!
What is the meaning of this?
"What"?
This is the guy who was arguing with Wada-san yesterday!
He was arguing with Sensei?
Uhm...
Where is Wada-san?
He passed away.
Late last night.
Lucky!
Wait, what did you say.
Someone has died and you feel lucky?
Ah, forgive me, my mistake.
Shishikura Yasuo (31)
Beika Mortgage Company Staff
See, I'm...
With the Beika Mortgage Company, Shishikura is my name.
In fact...
Our company purchased this land three months ago.
We decided to demolish this chateau for other use, but...
That's when Wada-san came around.
He requested to borrow the house from us for three months.
And we agreed to let him for just three months, but...
You "won't leave"?
Why is that?
Something has come up and changed my plans.
Allow me two or three more days!
But that's causing us problems, you know!
We already sold this land to another customer,
and agreed to demolish this house immediately!
Just two or three more days!
That's what he said.
It really put me in a pickle.
So, that's why those two were fighting...
But, if he's no longer with us, that means the problem is gone, right?
All right, everyone...
Carry out the belongings and start the demolition.
Just hold on!
Until we've located the painting Wada-sensei mentioned, can you wait?
But...
Don't worry, we'll be quick.
You must be kidding...
What do we do now, Shishikura-san?
We'll just have to wait.
Let's help them find the painting as well.
This sounds fun, like a treasure hunt!
Let's do it, let's do it!
But...
Let's go!
So, you're not going to find it?
It's Wada-sensei's final masterpiece.
Just think of the aesthetic value!
I'd say it's futile, searching for that painting.
Futile?
Conan-kun!
Where on earth did Sensei put his painting?
Conan-kun?
But, it's strange as well—this place.
If painting had been done here, there
should at least be a scent of paint...
But I can't smell anything like it.
Now that you mention it...
It's true—just like the boy says...
Perhaps Sensei didn't paint anything here after all...
No painting?
If that's it...
The remaining mystery revolves around why he borrowed the house...
Geez!
You're just too soft, you can't even firmly refuse!
So it looks like nothing came out.
There was no painting to begin with, I suppose.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Now, let's get started!
Finally, we can get to work!
Yeah, let's get this done quick.
Uhm...
Where is Wada-san?
He's no longer with us.
Last night.
Why are you looking for Sensei?
We received a message from Wada-san a few days ago...
"It will be complete today, so please come see the painting," he said.
"Come see the painting..."
Wada-sensei actually said that?
Yes.
Four or five days ago, he mailed this...
"Due to the weather, it took longer than expected, but..."
I believe it will be complete by this weekend.
Please be sure to bring Auntie here to see it.
-Rokurou.
There's no doubt...
This is Sensei's handwriting!
Addressed To
Tohto Beika City, Beika Town
15-7 Kafuuen
"Eguchi-san."
That's your name, isn't it, Miss?
What's "Kafuuen"?
Eguchi Mina (24)
Private Health Care Provider
It's a retirement home.
It's the place I work at.
A retirement home?
Could it be...
That you're Takatoo Saeko-san?
Do you know her?
As I suspected...
It's actually something I heard about from Sensei.
He said he often visited a chateau as a child...
And an auntie of his always took care of him.
Takatoo Saeko (71)
Wada's Aunt
He said that auntie was now in a retirement home.
I was always taken care of by Sensei, you see.
Ever since Takatoo-san's injury a year ago...
She's been suffering from amnesia.
She doesn't even remember who she is anymore.
Amnesia...
I'm sorry to hear that.
But, even still, Wada-san would take
time out of his busy schedule to visit.
Listen, dear auntie...
I'm now working on a masterpiece that's just for you.
How exciting is that, Takatoo-san!
Please do bring it here when you're done.
Well, it'd be impossible to bring it here.
You'll have to come by.
Does that mean it's a big project?
If you feast your eyes on it...
I think even you will regain your memories, Auntie!
The gate guarding your memories will swing right open.
I'm certain!
That means Sensei actually did work on his final piece in this house!
Let's hurry and tear this house apart to make up for our lost time!
Hold on!
Once more!
Let's search thoroughly!
Yes!
Wait, please!
Didn't you say you couldn't find it?
There were no paintings?
There must be!
Please wait!
I said you're giving me a hard time!
What do we do now, Shishikura-san?
We wait!
We can't proceed if there are people inside!
We have other construction sites to get to!
I can't keep going with this.
Let's go grab some lunch.
Yeah!
No point arguing with a wimp like him!
Dammit...
That good-for-nothing guy.
And I thought we could finally get started...
Then, Takatoo-san...
How about we wait here for a while?
Don't just stay and sit around!
What do you think?
The painting?
Nothing was found in the search.
I doubt he actually painted one.
What do you mean?
Do you mean...
He lied to his favorite auntie who cared for him when he was little?
I don't want to think that.
If it wasn't for working on a painting...
What reason did he have for borrowing this haunted house?
It would seem we're back to the same mystery.
As for what he did, looks like he only fixed
the house and took care of the landscape.
That's right...
Just ahead of this house, there's that!
Mitsuhiko!
The kids finally went home!
It's time for us to go.
But, the painting...
It's bright and sunny today.
Let's walk our way to the train station.
The heck is this?
Beika Bank.
That guy was trying to dig a tunnel from that house to here!
A tunnel?
He tried to steal his way into the underground deposit vault!
I expected something like an underground tunnel.
From the house to this bank, the direct distance is only about 50 meters.
If he were to dig 60 centimeters per day...
Three months would be enough!
He dug away during the night...
And then, during the day, he would bring up the dirt and deposit it.
By doing that, he could make it appear he was gardening.
And what about him fixing up the house?
Merely camouflage.
It wouldn't look natural if he only worked on the landscape.
But, wait...
Not only that.
Well, it'd be impossible to bring it here.
You'll have to come by.
If he were stealing billions of yen, it sure
would be impossible to carry around.
If you feast your eyes on it...
I think even you will regain your memories, Auntie!
There's no one out there who wouldn't be
shocked to feast their eyes on billions of yen!
He was referring to shocking her out of her amnesia.
That's what he meant!
Perfect, Mitsuhiko!
Really...
It made my head spin.
Let's find the entrance to the tunnel!
Yeah!
The kids... are back...
So, that man went as far as to fight the mortgage
company staff in order to keep staying here...
Please don't go back in...
Not again...
This is the storage cabinet.
But, it's not connected to the basement...
That means he could have torn up some of the
wooden flooring and dug under there, right?
We should go check if there's a void under the floor, then.
Not in this room, it looks like.
Let's try elsewhere!
Boy, they sure are noisy...
At Aunt Saeko's House
And stop making messes...
Huh?
"At Aunt Saeko's House"?
Could it be...
No, if I consider it like this, it all...
Chief!
Something strange has come up.
And because of it, we couldn't...
All right! All right! All right!
Time's up.
We've gotta move to the next site.
But, what about the demolition of this house!?
Why don't you do it yourself?
Sheesh.
Why is it always like this...
Everything...
Is the fault of...
This house!
So, this house really was...
I think it was where Auntie lived, but...
I guess I might have, huh?
In such a beautiful house?
I did?
When Auntie lost her husband...
She apparently had a pretty rough time, but...
Before that, she was very wealthy and happy.
That's what I heard before.
Oh?
Memories from the past when she was fortunate...
So that's how it was...
I'll just have to burn it down completely!
The hell are you doing!?
Stop doing foolish things!
What if the fire were to spread to the rest of the neighborhood!?
I'm sorry...
But please understand, I have my own duty!
Just one more day!
Wait until tomorrow!
Please!
What happened to him?
It seems like he's willing to wait one more day to tear down the house.
He could have just done it, and tore it down now.
In the end, the painting wasn't here.
And no underground tunnels...
Figures.
Because the reason that man borrowed this house was...
So he could work on something for his auntie, Takatoo-san:
A once-in-a-lifetime masterpiece made just for her.
Did you find it?
Sensei's masterpiece...
It's still in progress, but...
I think it'll be complete tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
It'll be complete?
Because it's bright and sunny... Today.
The Next Day
As I thought...
It really is entirely complete.
What is this?
It's beautiful!
It wasn't a painting.
A gorgeous sea of flowers flooding around the chateau...
This is the masterpiece Wada-san had worked toward for three months.
The masterpiece...
Is this view!
Due to the bad weather, it took extra time to complete.
So that's why he asked for more days...
Takatoo-san?
I...
Know this place!
Flowers blooming around the garden...
And swaying in the wind...
Over there was this chateau...
My husband stood beside me...
And I was always smiling.
The always-cute Roku-chan, my nephew, often came over to play.
Roku-chan lost his mother when he was still young.
He viewed me as his mother after that...
Takatoo-san, could it be...
I remember!
Everything!
The gate to her memories opened!
So that's why it had to be here...
The chateau that looks so much like her house...
It couldn't be anywhere else.
I see!
The nameplate was meant to be signed.
Sign?
That's why he couldn't place a nameplate.
Not until the flowers bloomed!
Because, as with any art project, you only put it on after it's complete.
That's what a signature is for!
I guess it's all gone...
The haunted house, and the garden.
Such a waste, huh?
But...
That man's wish finally reached his auntie, so it's all right.
You're right!
That's true!
Well!
We're gonna be late!
Yes!
Hey, hold on a second!
Don't just leave me here, you guys!