This is to all investigators!
Move to the house of Nabei Eiki immediately!
It's highly likely that he is now in possession of Takagi's handgun!
Take absolute caution, there's little time!
Listen up!
Any minute could cost our man his life!
That's it!
You're done for!
Damn it, they must have...
Figured it all out!
Could it be...
Satou-san?
Satou-san...
Takagi-kun was...
Shot...
Just because of the hot springs promise...
Why did Takagi-kun have to die for it!?
Hot spring?
Detective Takagi!
Ah. no...
It's all right, see?
He happened to put this material evidence in his pocket...
And, following the pattern, the criminal's bullet landed there.
Then, Takagi-kun is...
Ever since they finished the treatment, he's been in the ward...
Sound asleep.
Love is eternal, labyrinths are mysterious.
Saturday nights are for mystery!
Kaitou Kid's challenge notice...
His target this time is the world's strongest safe!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
"A Life and Death Decision."
"A lone police officer...
"Was able to fight off a hail of gunfire and single-handedly
arrest the suspect, we learned the following day."
It's this one!
The article about Detective Takagi.
Well, mostly...
The only reason it happened at all is because he was able to get my gun.
You should be grateful.
The only reason anyone realized the scar was
actually on the serial murderer's back...
Was due to my brilliant deduction.
And once again, I don't remember a thing...
But it was good to solve the case, wasn't it?
Yeah.
It's great.
For a few reasons...
Detective Takagi?
You're...
Blushing.
Did something good happen?
Ah, no...
Nothing!
I know!
I saw it!
What, what?
What'd you see?
In the ward, with Detective Satou...
Hold it, Conan-kun!
Such optimism...
That guy just keeps on winning...
Inspector Nakamori!
Time after time, that arrogant thief has evaded capture...
He keeps defeating me every single time.
My apologies!
Was it too hot?
No, it's fine.
On occasion, it's a perfect match for my cold heart...
Your cold heart?
Because there hasn't been any news from Kid lately...
I haven't had the chance to compete with him.
You didn't see it?
In the newspaper...
The newspaper?
It's being reported everywhere!
"Kaitou Kid has sent a challenge notice
to his old rival Suzuki Jirokichi," it says.
Advisor Suzuki!
What's going on here?
Please, elaborate on the details!
What is Kid coming to steal?
Who knows.
"Who knows"?
The following was written on his notice...
"It came to me, Senior Advisor Suzuki...
"That we should stop these senseless bouts of ours
and take on the compliant nature of a newborn.
"When darkness next consumes the moon...
"Await me at the grand safe kept precious in your family home...
"And look forward to my surpassing it."
Signed, "Kaitou Kid."
The grand safe...
Could he mean, that...
That's right!
It was constructed during the Tokugawa shogunate period by
the master of traps, Samizu Kichiemon, just prior to his death.
It's the grand and impregnable safe...
The Iron Tanuki!
This is the challenge notice.
While it seems that guy's interest has nothing to
do with the contents but instead the safe itself...
The Iron Tanuki's door has never failed to repel even the most famous
of thieves, and I'm sure it will gladly challenge the one to come next.
As for whether that guy can really get it open...
It'll be a pleasure to witness.
To hell with this "pleasure" business!
You decided, even after receiving a notice...
That it was best to go to the press first instead of the police!
There's nothing pleasurable about that!
It's Inspector Nakamori from the Tokyo Metropolitan Police!
What measures are in place for repelling Kid this time?
Inspector Nakamori, please comment!
Inspector!
What's there to say — I just heard about it...
Well, I suggest you take a careful look at the challenge notice first.
This isn't his normal drawing!
That's why I deemed it unnecessary to notify the police.
I believe it's merely an impostor.
Then, why the hell didn't you tell that to the press?
Should I come out victorious and the world still believes it's authentic...
I can add it to my memoirs of bravery, no?
How can this old guy still be thinking about that...
At any rate, the aid of the police won't be necessary.
This isn't actually Kaitou Kid, after all.
Three Days Later
It could be a fake?
The challenge notice sent by Kaitou Kid, that is.
Yeah, that's what Uncle Jirokichi has been saying.
We did send it to you, right?
A photo-copy of that notice.
Something was off, wasn't it?
His symbol did seem different from how it usually is...
Not to mention, all of his notices have featured horizontal writing...
But, for the first time, this one was written vertically.
The composition itself also seemed dated...
Then, why'd you bother calling us here as well?
A lady's intuition!
After all, I still have the feeling Kid-sama will appear!
Well, it seems I'm not the only one that feels that way, though...
All right!
Don't let your guard down just because it might be an impostor!
"When darkness next consumes the moon"
refers to the next new moon, which is tonight!
Surround the safe room and secure it as tight as possible!
Inspector Nakamori...
Of course he's here...
But, what's the point in surrounding the room?
It seems more natural to position everyone just outside of the safe.
That would be pointless, Detective Mouri.
Why not come see my prized Iron Tanuki?
The safe of Samizu Kichiemon, huh?
Yeah, from back then...
Kichiemon is the one who designed that mansion full of traps.
Episodes 394-396 Big Adventure in the Eccentric Mansion
So this is that impenetrable vault, huh?
Just from looking, it seems you'd end up
breaking a bone or two trying to pry it open.
There's no furniture in here at all...
But putting it in the wall makes it look
more like an actual vault than a safe...
That's right.
It's four meters short of a six-tatami mat room in size.
The walls around it are covered in 50 centimeters of steel.
Back during the war, when I was still just a child...
My parents and I would seek refuge inside to wait out the air-raids.
Then, that means there are holes for air, right?
Yeah.
There's a small gap for ventilation under the door.
The opening is only about three centimeters in all.
But, to get out, didn't someone have to open it for you?
It's a simple matter to open it from the inside...
But I may well be the only one still alive
that knows how to open it from out here.
Well, how about we take a closer look?
Hold it!
I believe you're a smoker, isn't that right?
Yeah...
May I borrow a cigarette?
Yeah, here's one.
This is a bodyguard I employed a few days ago.
Gotou Zengo (38)
Bodyguard
Not much of a talker, but he's dependable.
Is that so...
Now, if you'll excuse me...
What is that!?
That sound!
Well, just wait and see.
It became a complete prison just like that...
And it's all thanks to a weight sensor.
Even the weight of just one cigarette can set it off.
I guess that's why there's no furniture.
Surely you understand now.
That guy won't even be able to get close to the safe!
This old guy sure is fond of enclosures...
Akitsu-kun!
Get in there and dispose of that cigarette that's rolling around.
But...
Akitsu Masuhiko (32)
Assistant
If i go in there now, I'll end up locked in the cage ass well...
You fool!
I've switched it off!
Now take this time to get in there and clean it up!
Yes, sir!
Geez...
That's another new one I hired a few days ago...
But he's proven to be mostly useless.
Uhm...
As for this cigarette...
Should I return it to Mouri-san?
You moron!
Why would he smoke something that's been on the floor!?
Throw that in the trash right now!
Yes, sir!
When you're done with that, I'd appreciate
it if you'd move away from the door.
You're getting in our way.
Didn't I already tell you it was a waste of time?
This is just a fake.
Detective Mouri, you may go now as well.
I'm sure nothing will happen tonight.
Yeah.
Of course, that includes this little guy
that's regarded as his natural enemy.
Guess it's time to go.
You're leaving?
After all, it doesn't look like Kid's coming.
That's about it.
But can't you wait just a little longer?
I'm so sorry!
Are you all right, little boy?
I was looking for that doggie, and...
Seto Mizuki (23)
Maid
I accidentally hit you.
Oh, do you mean the doggie of my uncle's?
Yes...
Uncle's dog, Lupin-kun, was looking ill earlier, so apparently
he sent him off to the clinic—or so, that's what Uncle said.
You didn't know, even being the maid?
Right...
I just came today.
But that's really too bad...
I was looking forward to this, because I
heard there was a really cute doggie here.
See, my own doggie passed away last month...
Is that so...
Well, I had raised it since I was young, so...
It was already growing pretty old.
Oh, this is bad!
I'm doing this during work hours!
I'm sorry.
Please excuse me.
Inspector!
Superintendent Chaki has issued a removal order.
What?
It seems it was due to pressure from Advisor Suzuki...
That's true, the superintendent and that old guy were
alumni of the same university and got along well.
Well, the safe is already outfitted with extraordinary security measures...
Yeah, even without our help, it should be all right.
Old man!
Hurry and turn off the anti-theft device!
There's something in the middle of the floor!
It looks like a card!
This is...
"As stated in the notice, I will appear before the
moon's face greets us from beyond the darkness...
"And take that which lies in the stomach of the Iron Tanuki."
Kaitou Kid!
This is the real one!
But, how did the card get in here?
Why wouldn't the sensor go off?
First, let's find the reason...
Look at this!
The police task force has surrounded the Suzuki residence!
Kaitou Kid's offensive is moments away!
More and more members of the riot squad are joining the effort!
Given that Kid is up against such a massive police assembly...
Will he still appear as he claimed in his notice!?
He's coming...
No matter what, that guy will come.
I'll do something about that daring grin of his.
All of you, take notice!
Today is the day we catch that guy and
wipe that damn smirk off his face!
This is some fuss you're making over a mere impostor.
He's the real one.
Although the composition and mark on the first smelled of a fake...
That was most likely meant to serve as a taunt to we police.
But, the notice that showed up inside the room with the vault...
There's no doubt that this was the real deal!
Isn't it strange for you to keep insisting that even this points to a fake?
Well, even if that is the case...
This sort of excessive security force is unnecessary.
Have you forgotten?
That guy's target is...
The legendary and impregnable safe crafted by
the trap master, Samizu Kichiemon, himself!
He's out to open the door of the Iron Tanuki!
The multitude of mechanisms and gears in the door make it so
intricate that no thief will be able to force their way inside.
Given that I'm the only one who knows how to open it, anyone else
who tries and fails may end up losing their life in the process...
I told you no one else can open it!
You need to keep in mind that we're dealing with
the "Magician Under the Moonlight," Kaitou Kid!
It doesn't matter what kind of safe it is, that
guy will be in there before you know it!
Even should he have the ability to crack it, he can't even get near it!
Didn't I show you?
That defensive mechanism protecting it.
If that guy takes even one step into the room...
The weight sensor on the floor will ensure that he finds
himself trapped in the iron prison, like a rat in a sack!
Hold on a second...
Hasn't Kid already gotten into the room...
Since he delivered this notice there?
It's obvious that he already has a way to bypass the security setup!
About that...
When Kaitou Kid put the notice there, he must
have been one of the people near us, right?
Because when the door was first opened, there was nothing there...
But after it was opened the next time, the notice was inside, right?
That whole time, we were near the room, right?
If something were to be placed there while the weight sensor
was disabled, wouldn't it pick it up when it was reactivated?
Well, the design is such that it only registers
new weight after it's switched back on.
Which means he could have placed it there while it was switched off...
Now that you mention it...
Uncle switched it off earlier, didn't he?
Right, right.
To demonstrate how the weight sensor
worked, he threw the cigarette into the room.
What is it!?
That sound!
Well, just wait and see.
He then turned off the switch to collect the cigarette.
Akitsu-kun!
Get in there and dispose of that cigarette that's rolling around.
But...
If I go in there how, I'll end up locked up in the cage as well...
You fool!
I've switched it off!
Now take this time to get in there and clean it up!
Yes, sir!
Geez...
That's another new one I hired a few days ago...
But he's proven to be mostly useless.
That assistant —he was the one who went in to get it!
That means he could've been Kid!
While feigning to get the cigarette, he might have put the notice there!
But, I don't think that assistant is the
only one who could have put it there.
The bodyguard for Uncle Jirokichi could have, too...
Since he could have tossed it in while Uncle had the door open.
That maid that just came today could have done it as well, right?
She was on her knees looking for the doggie, after all.
But, while the switch was off, the maid wasn't near the door, was she?
The security device was demonstrated from this door, wasn't it?
But, the room housing the safe...
Look, another door leads to it over here!
If Kid really were the maid, while he was searching for the dog...
He could have slid the notice under the door
while the guards weren't watching, right?
That's true...
Uncle was talking in a really loud voice at the time.
His voice may have carried over there, right?
I see...
Even if we were on this side, she would know the switch was off.
Not to mention, these three were ones he just hired recently, right?
Which means the chances of Kid being in disguise are fairly high...
All right!
Bring that Akitsu guy and the maid here immediately!
I'll tug at his face and find out...
Just who he's really disguised as!
Which means the first is...
Bodyguard-san—your turn.
Enough!
I consider my staff part of my family from the day they're hired!
I won't permit the police to come and do what they please!
No, see...
If you're sure that it has to be Kid, make me believe it!
In the meantime, I'll be having a meal in my room.
Keep the disturbances to a minimum out here.
Damn it...
We'd know immediately if we could just have a pull at their faces...
Something's different about Uncle today.
Because, usually...
He would be glaring and saying, "I need to see that
thief with my own eyes" with such excitement.
But this time...
He's more like, "This has to be an impersonator."
And even, "Make me believe that it's him."
Maybe Kid-sama has come as Uncle this time!
No way.
Something's definitely off...
When Kid's notice arrived...
He could have already been in the house...
But does that make it normal to hire three all-new employees at once?
Also, Kid's behavior from the first notice was strange...
Even if the dated writing on the first
notice was meant to taunt the police...
What reason did he have for returning
to his usual style in the second one?
There's something...
There's something behind this case...
But what is it?
But he could be disguised as any of them, right?
It's as the brat said earlier.
There's the bodyguard with the dark complexion, Gotou...
That mostly useless assistant, Akitsu...
And the clumsy maid, Mizuki—that's all three.
Could this really be Kid?
The rest is on you, little guy.
Next Conan's Hint
Suzuki Jirokichi
Look forward to the next episode
Oh, Kid-sama!
But wasn't Uncle the hint?
Oh, Hint-sama!