Inside Advisor Suzuki's home...
Resides the Iron Tanuki.
Designed by the master of traps, Samizu Kichiemon, in the final days of the Tokugawa shogunate...
It's the strongest and most impregnable safe.
Kaitou Kid sent a notice challenging the Iron Tanuki.
Its strong door had repelled many a thief...
But he vowed to open it himself.
However, the Iron Tanuki...
Had been outfitted with an anti-theft security
device that relied on a motion sensor...
Which made it difficult to even approach.
After hearing of the notice, Inspector Nakamori
assembled a massive police force, but...
Despite that, in the safe room that was equipped with the sensor...
A second notice from Kid appeared.
Just how was he able to bypass the weight sensor?
Does that mean Kid has already infiltrated the house?
And...
How does he plan to open the door to the Iron Tanuki?
Love is eternal, labyrinths are mysterious.
Saturday nights are for mystery!
The unexpected contents of the safe...
Kid finally shows his true face!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Well?
Seto Mizuki (23)
Maid
Kaitou Kid—have you found him?
No, not yet...
It'd probably be best if you didn't pass through this corridor.
Why is that?
Maid-san...
It's because they suspect you of being Kid.
And it's all this brat's fault.
That's troubling...
The master just ordered me to bring this food to his room.
Uncle did?
Yes.
I didn't know since I just started, but...
As of late, it seems he's been taking his dinner alone in his room.
Actually...
When the tableware is collected...
It seems there are always two plates missing.
Plates?
Why?
Dunno...
It's not just the food and plates that are strange.
After each meal...
Akitsu Masuhiko (32)
Assistant
He always goes into the room to check on the safe, but...
When he does, it seems he never forgets to take along his cane...
The uncle that is always full of such vigor does?
Yes.
Maybe it's because plates and a cane...
Happen to be essential to opening the safe?
Even if the security device protecting the safe
reacts to the weight of a single cigarette...
That won't help much if the safe is really that easy to open.
Guess I'm out of cigarettes...
Seto-san...
Yes?
Earlier, when the master called over on his extension...
Akitsu-san...
Yes?
Sorry to bother you, but...
Any chance you could get some cigarettes for me?
Got it.
Earlier, when the master called over on his extension...
He was wondering why dinner still hadn't been...
I'll get right on it!
Right away!
I'm so sorry.
Forgive me!
It's...
Hey, what do you think you're doing!?
Get my food to my room immediately!
Yes, sir, right away!
My apologies for getting you so wet...
No, no.
Whether it's the maid or the assistant, both have proven worthless.
Thank you.
The only one of any worth
is this bodyguard here.
Gotou Zengo (38)
Bodyguard
Uhm...
What was it you wanted earlier?
Want?
Huh?
Didn't you say it?
That, once I was finished with dinner...
I should come "lend you a hand."
Oh, that's right!
Well, let's go to my room first.
Yes.
What?
You want to turn off the security system!?
Even though Kid could show up at any time!?
Yeah, that's right.
Checking the safe has become part of my daily routine.
Could this really be Kid?
Well, just two, three minutes will be fine.
And during that time, don't peek in here.
By saying that I shouldn't...
Don't.
Yeah, no problem...
Also, would you mind keeping it down out here?
Otherwise, you may disturb the advisor while he's on the phone.
The phone?
He always speaks to someone while inside.
I suppose it's possible he's just talking to himself, though.
Could it be that he forgot how to open the safe...
And has to call someone for help?
Who knows.
Advisor Suzuki has been having dinner
in his room lately, and eats it alone...
For some reason, afterwards, two plates always disappear...
Then, as he checks the safe afterward...
He has reason to bring a cane...
And always talks to someone while he checks.
And...
There's also the peculiar notice...
Could it be...
Conan-kun?
They said that dinner's ready now.
All right, the check is complete.
Do as you please now.
Before you go back to your room, your body...
Along with your bag—do you mind if we check them?
Fine.
I don't see a problem with that.
And what's in the bag.
Nothing of consequence.
Some old albums...
Some writings and pictures from my childhood...
I sometimes take them back to my room to look over in secret.
It's true that there only seem to be albums here...
Ah, right, right.
I hope it won't be a problem if I go out now.
I almost forgot that I promised to meet
up with Chaki-kun for dinner tonight.
Superintendent Chaki!?
Here.
There are the car keys.
Get it ready on the other side.
Absolutely, sir.
Well, I'm sure everything will be fine here.
After all, that guy's natural enemy is here, in this boy.
The rest is on you, little guy.
This is an announcement to all those guarding the Suzuki residence!
The time of Kaitou Kid's arrival could be any moment now!
As a precaution, neglect nothing!
Don't think knowing someone's face is enough!
The officer next to you could be Kid!
This guy is a master of disguise!
But he could be disguised as any of them, right?
Kaitou Kid.
It's as the brat said earlier.
When the anti-theft device was first disabled earlier...
Those that could have placed the notice were...
The bodyguard with the dark complexion, Gotou...
That mostly useless assistant, Akitsu...
And the clumsy maid, Mizuki—that's all three.
Well, I guess we don't have to worry about that bodyguard.
He just left with Uncle Jirokichi.
Then, it must be either Akitsu-san or the maid...
Then it's Akitsu, huh?
I asked him to fetch me some cigarettes, and haven't seen him since.
But, the maid could have just been pretending, right?
There's one more...
Suspicious person.
I mean, Uncle Jirokichi!
If Kid was acting as Uncle...
He would already have the switch for turning off the security device...
And could put the notice there easily, right?
Even if he could...
You should've mentioned that earlier!
I just thought of it.
And besides...
When the change fell out earlier...
It was Uncle Jirokichi that picked one up and threw it to you, right?
And, what hand did he use then?
I think it was his right, but...
Then, when Uncle Jirokichi threw the car keys to the bodyguard...
What hand did he use that time?
Let's see...
I think it was...
His left!
Wait, is that true!?
At that time...
He took it out of his coat pocket with his right hand...
But specially changed it over to his left...
And got it to the bodyguard that way.
That's definitely strange, don't you think?
Doesn't that mean he's Kid!?
Then, shouldn't we hurry and tell Inspector Nakamori?
If we went after them now, we might be able to catch them.
That's true!
That old man might be Kid?
How can that be!?
But...
Advisor Suzuki just deactivated the security
system to get inside a minute ago...
And then went into the safe room, right?
Yeah.
Checking the safe is part of his daily routine.
I even had a body check performed on him and
personally inspected the bag he brought out.
I didn't see anything unusual in there.
Not to mention, right now...
That old guy is on his way to meet up
with Superintendent Chaki for dinner!
There's no way that guy could be Kid!
Did you mention me?
Superintendent Chaki!?
But...
Weren't you set to meet with Advisor Suzuki over dinner tonight?
You fool!
Why would I consent to something so easy-going at a time like this?
Uhm—
I went to collect the tableware from the master's room, but...
The door was slightly open and, when I looked in the closet...
I saw...
The master tied up inside, sleeping!
Then, the old man who just left was...
Inspector!
I was just there to confirm it, and...
There are countless wires stretched over the closet and...
There's a sign that reads, "Danger, do not touch" attached...
Which means it won't be easy to get our hands on him.
How can that be?
When that old guy went in earlier...
It was only for two or three minutes...
It's...
Kaitou Kid!
"I've already seen that which lies inside
the stomach of the Iron Tanuki," huh?
I see!
His objective from the beginning was to just open the safe.
I guess he's already met his goal then, hasn't he?
That bastard...
I think it's better if you don't go in there.
Since Kid was the one with the switch, he probably left it on.
All right!
I want Team A cooperating with the bomb
squad to rescue Advisor Suzuki immediately!
As for the rest of you...
Chase after him!
Seems we have a bit of commotion behind us.
Forget it and just lose them.
The fact that it's like this...
Means it's all going as expected.
Just a minute ago, there were so many riot squad members here...
Quote from Oku no Hosomichi, a haibun work by Matsuo Bashou
"All that remains of brave soldiers' dreams," I'd imagine.
Well, it seems they're still trying to rescue Uncle in his room, but...
To think Kid-sama was actually Uncle...
I should have been more friendly around him...
Even if that's true, isn't something strange about it?
When the device was first switched off...
That Jirokichi who put the notice there...
Must've been Kid, right?
But the Jirokichi who picked up the change was the real one.
And then the Jirokichi that tossed the car keys...
That was Kid again, right?
It's definitely odd.
So only the first instance and the last instance
were Kid, with the real one in the middle?
When was the switch made?
Say, wasn't Conan-kun acting strange as... well...
Has he already disappeared again?
Well, our opposition here is the "Magician
Under the Moonlight," Kaitou Kid.
The brat has probably moved onto something else.
Hey...
After we find that brat, we're heading home.
What a disappointment...
You must love it...
Disguising as a woman.
Yeah.
It's just so much more cute this way.
When did you get it?
When he said to hurry and bring his food...
You resumed the role of the clumsy maid and hurried
over, hitting Uncle with the dining cart in the process.
But you didn't expect Uncle to drop his wallet...
And scatter around coins in the process.
You weren't about to be careless by
picking them up and leaving fingerprints...
Since you only had your bare hands.
That said, it would have also been
unnatural to stand there and do nothing.
That's why you spilled the water, right?
Since the change had become wet...
It would no longer be strange to wipe them down
with a handkerchief as you collected them.
You discovered I was Kid just from that?
The real telling moment was when you said...
Huh?
Didn't you say it?
That, once I was finished with dinner...
I should come "lend you a hand."
That's when it all unraveled...
The mystery behind the dated writing in the first notice.
If you take the final letters of each line starting from the left...
It reads, "Lend me a hand."
In other words...
The first notice was written by the advisor himself...
As a request for aid from him to Kaitou Kid.
After he heard you say that, he realized who you were...
And took you to his room to plan how to get rid of the riot squad, right?
The tossing of the key with his left hand...
And the lie about having the dinner...
Along with the placing of the card on the safe...
It was all to make everyone think Kid was the advisor.
As for the one tied up in the closet...
That's probably Akitsu-san who you disguised as the advisor, right?
That looks complicated.
Need my help?
On that door back there...
There are a number of indentations, as if something had hit it, right?
That probably means...
If this dial isn't turned just right...
That will happen.
Well, leave it to a pro.
Hey...
This tile over here...
Isn't it oddly new?
Look, that one.
As expected...
A truly great safe by the master of traps, Kichiemon...
You Lose
This guy's really too much...
Then...
I guess you already know why I was called here, right?
You did help by having the police fall
into the plan and chase him, after all.
Yeah.
Only because of Advisor Suzuki's strange behavior lately.
He had been having dinner alone in his room...
In order to get fresh water.
The reason two plates would disappear each time...
Was because one was to hold the water...
While the other carried the food.
And then, those two plates were fed under the door of the safe...
By using his cane to push them inside.
He was always talking while inside, and saying
something like, "Hold on just a bit longer," right?
Yeah.
All for the one swallowed by the Iron Tanuki...
This little guy.
Hey, come on now!
As the old guy said...
It should be on the underside of the bandanna...
The guide to opening the Iron Tanuki.
He had to use this to open it every time.
Then, that was why...
Yeah.
He only realized after the door was closed...
That his dog Lupin wasn't with him.
That's why he had to come to me crying for help.
Because the only one who can open such
a masterful safe in such short time...
Would be the one and only Kaitou Kid.
Haven't I already told you!?
That I'm the real Suzuki Jirokichi!
Liar!
Superintendent Chaki said you never scheduled a dinner with him!
It's not Chaki!
The one I was to meet was an old friend by the name of Chiaki!
You idiot!
Chiaki?
Then, that means Kid is still...
In that house?
Looks like they've already discovered that old guy
was the real deal and are on their way back.
But, this is a real risk, you know.
This could have all been a trap.
Yeah.
I considered that at first too, but...
After visiting in secret and seeing the reason, I decided to help.
After all, I'm a big fan of the real "gentleman thief."
To see Lupin completely shut away in that dark cage...
I couldn't just stand by, could I?
Don't try to get too friendly.
Hey, hey, don't you get too friendly either.
By name, we're meant to be enemies.
Lupin-kun was trapped in the safe?
And he had to ask Kid to open it for him?
It's a secret from society, though.
But, he didn't give Kid anything for helping, did he?
That old man.
Yeah.
He said that would have to wait...
Until there are handcuffs around both of his hands!
That's what he said.
Really?
That's right...