Kamakura
10:10 AM
If we keep going up this hill...
We'll get to see a famous temple that's surrounded by hydrangeas.
Really, it's a beautiful sight to see!
What the...
There aren't any flowers here.
That's weird...
Did I get it wrong?
Hey, hey...
Love is eternal, labyrinths are mysterious.
Saturday nights are for mystery!
Three brothers, unable to understand their parent's love...
Fight over an inheritance, resulting in an unfortunate case!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Hey, what happened!?
Is everything all right?
Over there!
Hey, you!
The hell are you doing over there!?
Damn!
Tell me what that gunshot was about!
Shut up!
Fuck off!
Hey, wait!
That's strange...
The blood's already dried.
It's still warm...
Then, why...
What's this?
It looks like some sort of crystalline substance...
Damn, that guy was quick.
He got away.
Hey, brat!
What'd you find?
Hey!
The hell is this?
Yaguchi Hisaemon (70)
Property Investor
The victim is Yaguchi Hisaemon-san, 70 years old.
He was the owner of this house and was quite a property investor.
He was shot directly in the chest and died soon thereafter.
It was the fatal shot.
The weapon was that rifle over there.
And?
You all happen to be the witnesses, right?
Yeah.
Geez...
What're you doing back in Kamakura again?
Just sightseeing—sightseeing!
These kids said they wanted to watch the hydrangeas.
Inspector Yokomizo, one moment.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Is it true that my dad's dead?
Yes.
Sorry, and you are?
Yaguchi Rokurou (42)
First-Born Son
I'm his oldest son, Rokurou.
What's your occupation?
I'm a film director.
Film director?
Never heard of one by that name.
Regardless, have you figured out whodunit?
Before that, at 6:00 this morning...
Where were you?
But it was almost 10:00 when we heard the gunshot...
He was killed long before that.
Really?
Yeah.
According to autopsy, his time of death is around...
Hey!
Shut up about that.
Yes, sir!
So, the time of death is around 6:00?
Then, the gunshot we heard...
Was that to throw us off the scent of the real time of death?
But, even that...
I was in Tokushima.
I went to Tokushima seeking inspiration for my new film.
I checked out of the hotel at about half-past 6:00...
And by the time I made it back to Tokyo, it was already after 10:30.
Oh, that's right.
I also kept the stub to my boarding pass.
Here you are.
I see.
Check this out.
Roger.
By the way, did Hisaemon-san live here alone?
Yeah...
He used to have servants here looking after him, but...
He laid them off a half-year ago.
Jeez...
To think he'd go this far just to save money...
What a stingy father he was.
He decided not to keep servants, despite owning a large house?
Do you have any other family members?
Two younger brothers.
That's right—they may know something about this incident.
Well, of course, I wouldn't know if they'd tell the truth.
Hey, we know you're in there!
Get out here right now!
Return the money or else!
Who're you guys?
Some punks looking for trouble!?
Hey!
Our apologies, Big Boss Yokomizo.
You guys are still doing that?
Let's get home.
Just go!
Yaguchi-san!
Yaguchi Akehiko-san!
This is the police!
We have things to ask you.
Yaguchi Akihiko (37)
Second-Born Son
The police?
What for?
Around 6:00, huh?
I was at this family restaurant.
To get to my dad's house from there,
it'd take about an hour even by car.
The money it took to open this shop...
Your father was the one who covered it, wasn't he?
And even beyond that, you still received money from him...
Until he recently refused to give you any more, isn't that right?
Who told you that!?
Your elder brother, Rokurou-san.
That bastard...
Give me a break.
My brother's the one who relied on Dad to fund his movies!
But since he didn't give him much, he still had to take out loans.
Actually, the company I ran went bankrupt recently...
And my father, who had always supported me
financially, refused to bail me out just like that...
And, let's talk about what you did at 6:00 this morning.
Yaguchi Kimio (32)
Third-Born Son
That... That early?
Of course, I was still asleep around 6:00.
Really?
Really...
Actually, prior to the incident...
There was someone who witnessed you at the scene.
Care to explain that?
No, I didn't...
Now!
Yes, sir!
I went to... my father's house...
What for?
For... the money...
With good intentions?
That early in the morning?
No, I tried to steal some...
But...
It isn't like I heard...
I can't get this safe open...
Damn...
Don't move!
Who the hell are you!?
Kimio!?
What a pathetic man you are!
To think you would act like a thief!
I was told by Akihiko that...
Akihiko, you say?
Dammit, you freeloaders never take responsibility and grow up!
No, I'm not a freeloader!
It's the truth.
Please believe me!
After that, I went to see my brother Akihiko...
Well?
How'd it go?
Dad caught me stealing...
You moron!
I even taught you step-by-step how to do it!
"Step-by-step"?
What I saw wasn't what we expected at all!
Dad's safe was so sturdy there was no way to...
Safe?
You didn't know?
Dad, that bastard...
When'd he buy a safe?
Fine.
I'll do it.
You still want to steal it?
Of course!
I'll give you a portion of the green to shut you up.
All right...
If that safe is really that sturdy, I've gotta prepare some tools...
That was at 6:00 this morning...
Damn...
To think you two were going to rob from Dad!
It's Akihiko who told me to.
Don't blame me!
But you really did!
What, disbanding right now?
Be quiet!
Akihiko-san...
Until 5:45 this morning, you claimed you were in a restaurant.
This has since been confirmed by the waitress and several customers.
Yeah, of course.
Afterward, you went to a discount shop nearby to buy some items.
A crowbar, an electric drill...
A number of witnesses confirmed this for us.
I remembered, too.
Look at your right hand.
This is...
Fine, I did come to steal.
But I didn't kill Dad!
When I arrived, Dad was already...
What the...
Who did this?
But, this is my chance...
It really was a strong safe, though.
I tried my best and still couldn't get it open.
And...
How's this!?
Then, the gunshot we heard at that time was...
Yeah, it was me, but the rifle couldn't beat that safe either.
The time of death was around 6:00 this morning...
At that time...
The eldest brother, Rokurou-san, was in Tokushima...
While Akihiko-san, the second youngest
brother, and Kimio-san, the youngest...
Were at a family restaurant an hour's drive away by car.
Hisaemon-san was shot at close range...
After seeing the culprit wielding a rifle right before his eyes...
Why didn't he try to escape?
And then...
The white crystalline substance...
Just what was that, anyway?
Now then...
Aside from the body...
What else do you notice?
Or, not notice?
Now that you mention it...
Dad's antique collections are gone!
I'd bet it was our older brother that snatched them, right?
What'd you say!?
I bet you stole them when you came to break into the safe!
The victim recently discontinued financial aid for his sons...
He also dismissed his servants six months ago...
And then his antiques were gone...
Could it be...
Then, that safe...
By the way, we found this item in this room.
It appears to be a webcam.
Who planted that thing?
You're a pro when it comes to cameras, big bro!
What's this!?
Are you saying I did that!?
Inspector...
I see.
Everyone, we've come across further information.
So please, come back over to the other room again.
By the way, Detective...
Can you open that safe for us?
This...
In this position...
Say, Mr. Detective...
Where was that stuffed eagle originally?
Let's see...
Ah, right over there.
See that dust mark?
I think the eagle was placed here...
And fell off while the victim was struggling with the culprit.
Rokurou-san, I have received a report
from the Tokushima Police Department.
How was it?
I was in Tokushima staying at a hotel, right?
Well, it was witnessed...
That a man wearing a hat and sunglasses like yours was there.
You mean me...
Well, how should I know?
I heard the guest refused to remove his hat
and sunglasses even while inside his room.
That's because this is my trademark style...
I don't take these off in front of people.
But, since no one saw your face...
We can't say that guest was you, can we?
No way...
Also, that guest's checkout time wasn't until tomorrow...
But he suddenly decided to leave this morning, I heard.
Perhaps he already knew that Hisaemon-san...
Was dead at that time?
This morning in a haste, that must be it...
The loans you borrowed were huge.
However, you said you had already
secured a way to pay off all those debts.
That's...
So big bro really did kill Dad?
No!
So, the person who went to Tokushima was a double that you hired?
And then you used that online webcam to monitor this study...
In order to obtain the code for the safe!
I see.
You saw Kimio-san attempt his robbery over that camera...
And decided to kill Hisaemon-san and frame Kimio-san for it.
Because even if you couldn't open the safe,
you could inherit more money this way.
Big bro!
I knew it.
That's complete nonsense!
You broke into the house this morning...
And killed Hisaemon-san in his study.
Since there aren't any neighboring houses nearby...
There was no one around to hear the gunshot.
Then, you ordered your double to return
and hand over the ticket stub to you.
That way, you could appear here as if nothing happened!
Am I wrong!?
Wrong, wrong!
You're wrong!
Where the hell are we wrong?
Spit it out already!
Dad?
Rokurou-san...
I advise you to tell the truth for your own sake.
If you don't, you'll be made the culprit by mistake.
What'd you say!?
Hisaemon-san's death was actually an unfortunate accident.
Isn't that right?
Hey!
What do you mean by "accident"?
Recall the position where the body fell.
Judging from that position...
When Hisaemon-san was shot...
He would be standing about a foot away from the cabinet, facing the wall.
It isn't possible to stand in front of him
and shoot him in the chest like that.
Also, consider the stuffed eagle that fell next to the victim's foot.
And that branch the eagle was perched on—it was broken.
So it was, but what does that mean?
Rokurou-san...
You actually witnessed the entire scene, didn't you?
On that webcam of yours.
Yes, it's true...
I saw everything.
Seeing is believing.
Look.
This is the truth.
After Kimio fled, Dad sat there like that.
What's this?
Is it a heart attack?
So the trigger got tangled on the eagle's
branch and caused the gun to misfire.
That's correct.
The way Dad died wasn't by murder.
It was an accident.
Hey, you!
If you had this on video all along, why didn't you show us earlier!?
He tried to make Akihiko-san and Kimio-san...
Appear to be murderers...
In order to keep them from getting the inheritance.
What?
That was why Rokurou-san hurriedly returned from Tokushima.
Before the body was discovered..
He planned to recover the webcam and plant fake evidence
that made it seem the crime was committed by his brothers.
But, before he could, we discovered the body.
You bastard, how could you!?
At least I proved you two innocent.
You should thank me!
For what!?
By the way, what becomes of our share of the inheritance?
That's right.
Regardless, just get that safe open!
For the two that act like robbers...
I don't think you have the right to inherit anything!
What'd you say?
Mr. "Spy Camera" Bastard!
You can't just keep everything yourself!
Knock it off already!
Have you still not figured out Hisaemon-san's feelings!?
Dad's feelings?
After Kimio-san fled...
He sat in front of the safe...
And Hisaemon-san...
Wept in sorrow!
"Wept"?
Dad did?
How could you know such a thing?
On Hisaemon-san's collar and chest...
Traces of a white, crystalline substance can be found.
That is most likely...
Salt.
The tears ended up drying out on his clothes...
And left traces of salt!
To have left salt crystals after his tears dried,
he must have shed a lot of them, right?
Yes.
He must have cried in deep sorrow, and out of great embarrassment.
He loved and pampered you all so much...
And yet you still cannot take care of yourselves or take responsibility!
It was due to the pampering that he
felt he had lead you to a life of crime.
And, finally, he felt hopeless...
Because he could no longer financially support you.
What do you mean?
Chances are...
There's nothing left in this house that can be considered valuable.
That can't be!
Think about it for a moment!
In a house as large as this one on such a steep hill...
Would a senile 70 year-old man live all alone,
and not hire any servants to help him!?
Why do you think that is!?
That means he had no money left to hire anyone?
He likely sold all his antiques, and had to
mortgage his house along with the land.
No way!
What the hell is the safe for, then!?
Tell me what could possibly be in there!
Uhm, Inspector...
We have opened the safe.
Understood.
Why not go see for yourselves?
It can't be...
Why...
They're loan contracts...
You guys mooched him off, that's why.
Not to mention your movie production costs,
surf shop costs, and company operation costs.
Shit!
What do we do now?
It's all over...
This...
Could this be of you three?
Yeah...
That's...
From when Mom was still alive...
That's right...
It's so nostalgic...
This photo...
This is what Hisaemon-san left behind...
His final inheritance.
The happy memories you shared as a family...
They're all present in that one photo.
However, none of you were able to inherit that.
Guess so...
Sorry, Dad...
I'm glad about our family, since we don't have
to worry about fighting over inheritance.
Guess you're right.
This is it, this is it!
Dad?
Hey, pretty lady!
Please grab me all these sake bottles!
Yes, sir...
Hold it, Dad!
What're you doing?
What am I doing?
I'm buying sake for souvenirs!
If it's just for a souvenir, just buy one bottle—one bottle!
Don't be so stingy!
There won't be any inheritance left at this rate...
Kamou-san!?
He was innocent, but I suspected him.
By pressuring him...
I caused his death.
Next Conant's Hint
Flashlight
Look forward to the next episode
Dad's probably going to give up being a detective!
What'd you say!?
Mouri-san is!?
Don't yell...