That day, I woke up from a nightmare very unpleasantly.
Come to think of it...
That was likely a premonition signaling
something terrible was to happen.
Well, what do you say?
Tokomae Sayuri (40)
Client
Mouri-san, pretty please!
If you're so afraid of getting robbed...
You could just leave your expensive
accessories at home before going out...
But I want everyone to see them!
Please, just an hour a day.
Jog with me as part of my weight-loss program!
Kogoro-san!
She said her deceased husband looked just like Uncle.
But, being a bodyguard...
That's not part of detective work!
She's totally into Dad.
Come on...
Join me!
No...
Coming!
Hello, this is Mouri Detective Agency!
My name is Gamou Ryouzou.
I want to find a witness who can confirm my alibi.
All right, now this is what I'm talking about—some real detective work!
Yes, tomorrow at 7:00 in the evening!
General Pufferfish
Meeting at "Fugu-Taishou" right?
Got it!
Well, we'll talk about it more then.
Oh, I'm so sorry, Tokomae-san, but
I've suddenly had a request come in.
But I came first!
Scary...
She doesn't need a bodyguard...
See, something terrible has happened...
Love is eternal, labyrinths are mysterious.
Saturday nights are for mystery!
A wrong deduction leads to tragedy.
Is this the end for Detective Kogoro!?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
He's running late because something came up?
Yes.
Gamou-san called and said so.
As an apology, he wanted you to enjoy those first.
Pufferfish!
Delicious!
Sir, a visitor for you.
There he is.
Take this.
Thank you for everything, Gamou-san.
Gamou Ryouzou (70)
Finance Company Owner
My apologies for being late.
I am Gamou Ryouzou.
Ah, I'm Mouri.
About this...
Of course, I know of the case.
About half a month ago, at an antique store in Tsukimi City...
The owner, Kinugasa Sakae-san, was killed by someone.
The police suspected that I was the murderer.
They said I had a motive.
Five years ago, I was scammed out of a large amount of money.
Then, when the detectives came to check my alibi...
I couldn't help but answer that I was at home on the day of murder.
But, in actuality...
I was in Akebono City hanging out here and there.
But I was alone and there were no witnesses...
I thought if I said I went out they would
suspect me, so I couldn't help but lie...
If they expose my lies, I bet the police will
suspect me and make me the murderer.
So please, Mouri-kun...
On the day of the murder, in Akebono city, I know
this person saw me there —
please find them!
A search for your alibi witness, huh?
Let me take care of it!
That's easy!
You're so reliable, just like they all say!
Since I go out often and don't carry a cellphone...
I'll personally call you when I need your results.
Well then, eat, drink and be merry!
Thanks for coming!
Gamou-san, please come again!
Hey, Gamou-san, thanks for the meal the other day.
Oh, Gamou-san, please come in!
My, you're a popular guy, Gamou-san!
Nah...
Shall we go to another bar?
Yes! Let's go, let's go!
To our hearts' content!
I started investigating first thing the next morning.
But the investigation didn't go as smoothly as expected...
And I've been getting calls from Gamou-san every night.
Give me a break...
And then, on the sixth day—Friday night...
Did you find something, Dad?
Okino Yoko-chan's on TV starting at 8:00!
I bet it's a love call from that lady.
Not now...
Hello?
It's Gamou.
I've been working on it all of today as well, but...
You still couldn't find my witness?
I thought I could trust a famous detective like you...
But now, I've lost hope!
What's he mean by "I've lost hope"?
What a drama-king.
Geez...
The time of death was estimated to be from 7:00 to 9:00 last night.
In addition, there's no indication of the body being moved post-death.
Inspector Megure, I've fetched Mouri-san.
Thanks for coming.
What is it, Inspector?
What can I do for you?
Well...
Although it appears to be a suicide...
We found this tightly crushed piece of paper near his feet.
My office phone number is on it...
Please allow me a look at the face of the deceased.
Gamou-san!?
Then, when he told you, "I've lost hope" over the phone last night...
Was that for real?
What do you mean?
By that...
He's come to confirm the identity of the victim.
Arai Kyousuke (42)
Gamou's Nephew
This is Gamou-shi's nephew, Arai Kyousuke-san.
What do you mean?
With "I've lost hope."
I see.
So that's how it was.
We finally understand Gamou-shi's actions from last night.
The one suspected of murdering antique
merchant Kinugasa Sakai, Gamou-shi...
Called Mouri-kun last night at eight o'clock.
After realizing the investigation had grown
futile, Gamou-shi lost hope, got in his car...
And came here to commit suicide.
From Gamou's house to here takes around an hour by car...
Which puts his suicide at 9:00 PM.
That matches our estimate as to the time of death.
But, Inspector...
If he was actually innocent...
He shouldn't have lost all hope just because
his alibi witness couldn't be found.
Hisamoto Kango (50)
Jousai Police Department Detective
Gamou-shi had experienced the pain of
being arrested despite being innocent.
A false arrest?
This case occurred five years ago.
Kinugasa Sakae, who died recently,
was attacked from behind by someone.
After hearing witness testimony, we detectives
from the Jousai police arrested Gamou-shi.
But, a few days later, we learned of Gamou-shi's alibi.
I remember that.
"Being made the culprit by the police; it was really frightening."
That's what my uncle told me.
So he thought he was going through that traumatic
ordeal all over again, felt helpless, and lost all hope.
We vowed to investigate more thoroughly this time, though.
We didn't want to repeat Takeoka's failure again, either.
"Takeoka"?
Do you mean Takeoka Isao?
Yes.
He felt the false arrest was his responsibility
and decided to leave his job with the police.
That Takeoka-san?
You knew him?
A long time ago, he would come to visit Dad's place on occasion.
So that's Takeoka-kun—your colleague
from way back in the police academy?
It's me.
Understood.
I'll be right there.
The one suspected of murdering Kinugasa-shi is now in custody.
What?
I'll report back once I've obtained more information.
If only they could have arrested the suspect earlier...
Uncle wouldn't have jumped to such conclusions.
This place is gonna be scary after dark.
There aren't any lights around, after all.
You're right.
It should be pitch dark around here at night.
Yeah.
That must be why we also found a flashlight near Gamou-san's body.
Then, why did he take the trouble to prepare
that in order to come here to commit suicide?
He could've done it at home.
That's true.
I believe there must've been a reason Gamou-san needed to die here...
One that was planned by his murderer.
The "murderer"?
Inspector, this is a homicide!
Homicide?
In my final phone call with Gamou-shi...
He said the words: "I've lost hope."
And it's precisely that that was used by the murderer...
In order to make us believe this was a suicide.
There's no reason for you to come here and do all this.
But still—we cannot omit the possibility of a homicide.
If Mouri-kun's deduction is correct...
The culprit would have been here last night.
Say...
About Gamou-san...
I think he directed a complaint to a bread company.
A complaint?
"Regarding the Nico-nico Red Bean Bread
manufactured by our company..."
"We have received your constructive
criticism from your call just days ago."
Even if he did file a complaint with that bread company,
it couldn't be considered a useful motive for murder!
Mouri-san, to what extent will you insist this is a homicide!?
Until it makes sense to me.
I know my uncle killed himself!
Of course, I can't be sure of that...
Inspector Megure!
It seems you have been having quarrels with Gamou-shi recently, no?
No, it wasn't that big of a deal...
You tried to borrow money from him,
but he refused without even blinking.
Here he comes!
Mouri-san!
We've heard that you've seen through a suicide
that was actually a murder case, is that right?
Does that mean you already know who the culprit is?
Not so fast—even someone of my caliber couldn't be that quick.
Yamane Yasushi (30)
Touyou Sports Reporter
But isn't it a shift in responsibility for you to
insist that a suicide is actually a murder?
He requested of you to find his alibi witness...
Yet you found no one...
And disappointed your client.
Where'd you hear such a thing!?
I'm not sure that's our primary concern.
That guy—how did he know that?
I doubt the police would tell him that...
Please do answer.
Just how will you take responsibility for your client's death?
Mouri-san!
Gamou-shi did not commit suicide!
This is a homicide!
I will absolutely seek out the perpetrator!
Detective Mouri Kogoro
"I will absolutely seek out the perpetrator!"
Fabulous Job!
Mouri Kogorou does it again!
"Leave it to me!"
Pathetic! Running Away
from Responsibility
Mouri Kogoro Leads His Client to Death
The "Famous Detective," just a glory of the past···?!
Mom?
I've seen them.
So what?
Dad's the hero of the day!
So, just get back together already.
Go tell him that if he pushes his luck too much, he'll fall into a trap.
Jeez...
Ran!
We'll get many, many clients at this rate!
Before that, please allow me to watch some horse-racing!
Mom's probably right.
The rider has fallen from his horse!
And now, the first ones to cross the finish
line: Ooana, number 4, and number 18!
It's over...
Amazing, Ooana won!
I won, I won!
Amazing!
Mouri?
Welcome back, Dad.
I just ran into him.
Takeoka-san!
Takeoka Isao (40)
Former Detective
Ran-chan!
You've grown so big.
Here, a gift.
This person must be...
The detective who falsely arrested Gamou-shi five years ago...
And left the police...
As I thought.
When he said "gift," he had to mean this.
Animal cookies...
What do you think, Takeoka?
This can't be suicide.
Not Gamou.
I questioned him five years ago and know he isn't the suicidal type.
I'll help you.
It wouldn't be like you to do nothing when one
of your clients was killed by someone, would it?
I think his death might involve a grudge or a conflict of interest.
If you're thinking grudges, I know one suspect.
Who?
Right in front of you.
It wasn't a major grudge, but I did have one.
It counts as a motive.
Where were you the night before yesterday?
What's the estimated time of death?
Around 9:00 PM.
Not me, then.
I met up with a friend at 8:30, and we stayed together until midnight.
So his alibi's as firm as steel...
All right, let's go, Takeoka.
Just like the old days.
Kogoro-san!
Looks like it's over—your commitment to your previous client.
Nothing's over yet; nothing...
We're investigating!
So, Gamou being out of the way still isn't enough, huh?
What've you been doing these past five years?
Not a peep from you at all.
Consider me dead.
Detective work was what I did best, but I threw that away.
There's still the career path of private detective.
You could be one in no time.
I'll think about it.
I was with the central police and he was with district.
Despite the difference, we teamed up
numerous times during our investigations.
It's true that some clients have held unreasonable grudges against us...
But the owner, Gamou-san...
Tsuchida Reiji (43)
Haraiso Finance Co. CEO
Already made me CEO and left all responsibility to me.
So was he hated outside of work?
I'm not familiar with his private matters.
How about asking his nephew?
He's the only one that's related to him.
Are you trying to make me the culprit by force?
We're just trying to confirm something.
The night before yesterday, I was drawing an illustration
for a serial novel that runs in a weekly magazine.
And, any witnesses?
None...
I live alone.
You've been borrowing money here and there, haven't you?
We've obtained some interesting information from a nearby bar.
After getting yourself drunk...
You grumbled over your drink, saying, "If only uncle
were dead, I could have that inheritance right now."
But, I was just drunk...
Arai-san, I'll say this one thing.
The number of culprits that have successfully escaped
from me, the famous detective, Mouri Kogoro...
Amount to absolutely zero!
Go home!
And then?
There were no results in the end?
Yeah, only for today.
Say, about that Arai-san...
It seems he'd like this to be a suicide case no matter what.
Yeah.
There'll be a full-blow investigation if this is deemed a homicide case.
He doesn't want his dirty little secrets to be discovered.
Hello?
Ah, Takeoka?
You've thought of something?
There's no reason I'd tell you that.
Why should I tell you who it was that
told me Gamou-shi had hired you?
So you won't leak your news source, huh?
Well, I can figure that out.
If it weren't from the police...
It could only come from his nephew, Arai Kyousuke.
If you already knew that, you didn't have to come!
I came for this!
Print an apology for this stupid report!
So, it was just as you thought.
Arai was the one who told the reporter.
Since he would get the entire inheritance...
And there were zero witnesses to the alibi...
Not to mention using the media to throw you off...
I'll make him spit everything out!
Don't tell me he ran away!
Arai!
The estimated time of death for Arai-san...
Happens to be around 9:00 and 10:00 last night.
This was suicide.
And also...
I believe this is the best evidence indicating he had killed Gamou-shi.
I agree to that.
Inspector, this is the neighbor living next door.
She said that, on the night Gamou-shi died...
Arai-san was in his room.
What do you mean!?
Because he was so noisy, I thought about complaining to him.
So, I looked over to his room from the veranda...
And saw him walking to and fro, shouting something...
But he soon went quiet, so I didn't have to say anything.
When was that?
A little before 8:00.
8:00?
To get to that forest from here, it would take an hour and a half by car.
If he were in his room at 8:00...
No matter how much he hurried, he couldn't
make it in time for Gamou-shi's time of death.
So, Arai-san was innocent.
Which means there was only one reason he would commit suicide.
He was innocent but I suspected him.
By pressuring him, I caused his death...
It looks like you brought us some serious
trouble with your suspicions, Mouri-kun.
No excuses from me.
No, I was the one who insisted on
inviting Mouri to find the real culprit.
I will take responsibility for this incident my way.
Mouri...
As usual, lots of them have shown up again.
I'm sorry, Mouri...
Don't you worry!
I was glad to team up with you again, like the old days.
Well, I'll see you someday.
Here he comes!
Did you not falsely accuse Arai-san!?
And to prove his innocence, he took his
own life to detest you, isn't that right!?
How will you answer to that!?
You made an innocent person die, Mouri-san!
Say, Uncle...
Did Arai-san really commit...
Inspector, this is Mouri.
Starting today...
I will...
Close up my detective agency.
Dad...
Dad!
Mouri-san is...
Giving up his practice?
He's giving up being a detective?
Please, Dad!
Reconsider!
Dad!
It all began with this request...
Could it be...
Looks like I'm a detective to the bone...
Next Conan's Hint
Voice
Is Mouri-san giving up being a detective?
Then, who's going to solve the cases!?
Hey, hey...