My name is Mouri Kogorou.
It goes without saying that I'm a famous detective.
My job this time was to help a client suspected of murder...
Gamou Ryouzou—I was to find his alibi witness.
It was a request I once thought easy, but it didn't go very well...
I even received phone calls from Gamou-shi every night.
I've lost hope!
The next morning...
Gamou-shi's body was found.
Because Gamou-shi had once been falsely arrested five years prior...
The assumption was he feared he would go
through that traumatic ordeal once again...
And opted for suicide.
However, I wasn't having any of that.
This was a murder disguised as a suicide!
The one who had falsely arrested Gamou-shi was...
Takeoka Isao (40)
Former Detective
An old friend of mine, Takeoka.
He took responsibility then and left his job with the police...
And after I met up with Takeoka again...
We decided to team up and investigate the case together.
One that appeared fairly suspicious was
Gamou-shi's nephew, Arai Kyousuke.
He was in debt, and had been arguing with Gamou-shi.
I had no doubt he was our culprit.
However...
Arai committed suicide.
Soon after, his alibi witness appeared.
That ensured Arai wasn't the culprit.
And then...
By pressuring him, I caused his death...
Starting today...
I will...
Close up my agency by removing my sign.
Love is eternal, labyrinths are mysterious.
Saturday nights are for mystery!
Is this famous Detective Kogorou's final case?
The real culprit is beyond prediction!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Looks like he's totally in a down mood.
But is Arai Kyousuke-san really not the culprit?
His neighbor attested to that.
She came home at 8:00 PM, and just
when she went to turn on her TV...
Time machine!?
The readers will bombard us!
Then, when she peered over into his room to complain...
She saw Arai-san furiously shouting at a piece of faxed paper.
Arai-san was drawing illustrations for this
particular mystery novel, but to his dismay...
The culprit used a time machine for his alibi trick.
The readers will definitely bombard them...
From Arai-san's apartment to Gamou-shi's
home would take thirty minutes by car.
From Gamou's house to the forest, that's another hour.
Which won't fit the estimate as to the time
of death, which was from 7:00 to 9:00 PM.
So he really couldn't be the one...
But if the neighbor actually heard his voice after
8:30, Arai-san still could have done it, right?
Because if the had killed Gamou-san in the forest at 7:00...
He could have made it to his room by 8:30.
That's still impossible.
Gamou-shi called Mouri-san from his house at 8:00.
What if he changed voice?
No way...
The police call I received didn't have an altered voice.
But Gamou-san talked in a hoarse voice, didn't he?
Anyone could've used a hoarse voice to impersonate him.
There's no way I'd mishear my own client's voice!
But...
Shut up!
I've been working as a detective for ten years!
But then, who did it?
The Real Culprit X in this case.
The real culprit?
"X"?
The real culprit that killed both Gamou-san and
Arai-san and made them appear to be suicides.
If the neighbor hadn't come forward as his alibi witness...
We would've assumed Arai-san was the one who killed Gamou-shi.
And after thinking he killed himself, we'd say, "Ah, as we thought."
So that was X's intention...
Mouri-san...
We're going to look over this case one more time.
Excuse us.
If there had been a real culprit, Dad
wouldn't be held accountable whatsoever!
You wouldn't have to give up being a detective!
What?
What "Real Culprit X"?
Dad...
His condition's worse than I thought.
Jeez, come on, only you can encourage him right now, Mom!
Is he that depressed?
It's all right, dear.
You've been running around for ten years.
You must be tired.
Mom...
KO-GO-ROU-SAN!
As was agreed, starting today...
You're mine!
Dad...
Wow, animal cookies.
How nostalgic.
Yeah, Takeoka-san came the other day...
He said these were his wife's favorite.
Regardless, has your father...
Developed an interest in that kind of woman?
No! And definitely not her!
Talk about misunderstanding...
My bodyguard!
My weight-loss program!
Please enjoy your jogging, Kogorou-san!
What was that!?
To make him feel better...
I'll have to let Uncle solve this case on his own...
Everything started from this request...
It would've been nice if you could've just taken
me as a client in the first place, Kogorou-san!
Tokomae Sayuri (40)
Client
In the end, it all comes down to this.
Looks like this person benefited from Gamou-shi's death, too...
How enjoyable!
Because I detected the truth...
They think they have to silence me!?
It was this trio!
They're the ones who tried to steal my jewelry!
Excessive self-defense!?
I merely defeated the robbers!
What do you mean by excessive!?
It's a shocker that he committed suicide.
There weren't any abnormalities in his check-up, that Gamou-san.
That—Do you mean Gamou Ryouzou-san?
Yeah.
We happened to be together during our health check-ups.
It was about ten days ago.
The Sunday of last week.
Sunday of last week?
I accepted his request on Saturday night—the day before that...
Did you administer a barium examination?
Yes.
He had no food or drink since the day
before, and everything went smoothly.
But, that night, Gamou-san...
This isn't making sense.
Come to think of it, that brat...
What if he changed voice?
Could it be...
But, if that's true...
Wait...
There's no way I'd mishear my own client's voice!
I see!
Conan-kun?
Looks like I'm a detective to the bone...
And I'm...
As determined as ever!
What are you doing here now?
Maybe we just go along very well.
Yeah, right!
Uncle may have noticed it too.
Although he's a regular customer, he
was fairly new here, that Gamou-san.
First time I saw him was half a month before the day you came.
About half a month ago.
Two weeks ago, I think?
Around fifteen days ago.
There's no doubt.
It seems Uncle's detected culprit X's trick as well.
There are a lot of shoeprints here, all from the same pair.
Gamou's bathroom, huh?
So the culprit snuck in here every night looking for a chance.
Looks that way.
But, Detective...
How would you confirm your hypothesis?
A recording of Gamou-san's voice?
His speeches to the staff or whatever!
Anything with his voice recorded would be fine!
Tsuchida Reiji (43)
Haraiso Finance Co. CEO
What about this answering machine at home?
It goes, "This is Gamou speaking. I'm not available right now."
He recorded it himself.
Dial his number!
Yes, yes.
Hello, we are currently unavailable.
Please leave a message after the beep.
When'd he change it?
It was deleted.
Someone got to it first.
Anything else!?
I remember now!
He made a speech at our New Year's party last year.
The video tape is...
Found it!
Play it now!
But we don't have a player nor a video camera...
You don't?
Find an electronics or camera store!
Go that way!
Uncle, there's one over here!
Uncle, are you all right?
Who just...
The tape's gone!
Someone snatched it!
That may be our most crucial evidence!
Screw that son of a bitch!
Oh yeah...
Nico-Nico red bean bread!
Why are you talking about food right now!?
Not that.
Gamou-san filed a complaint by phone, didn't he?
I see.
Nico-Nico Bread Company
To avoid future troubles, we keep a recording of every complaint.
So it's just as I thought!
Bingo.
Now I know the trick...
But just who the hell did it!?
Who killed those two and tried to frame me!?
Don't tell me...
About that case five years ago?
As I said the other day...
Kinugasa Sakae-shi was attacked from behind on his way home.
Fortunately it wasn't fatal.
But the culprit escaped in a car they'd arranged.
However, that attack was witnessed by a female pedestrian.
It's this person!
The driver was a long-haired man in his thirties.
Gamou has a nephew that he's supporting financially.
His name is Arai Kyousuke, a long-haired illustrator!
Ignoring the advice that having only a motive
and a witness's testimony wasn't enough...
Takeoka went ahead and arrested Gamou-shi.
However, a few days later...
When other witnesses appeared and
corroborated Gamou-shi's alibi...
The whole thing became a false arrest.
But, no matter how rash Takeoka was, he still
acted on that woman's testimony, so quitting was...
Hisamoto Kango (50)
Jousai Police Department Detective
The woman who gave that testimony...
Was Takeoka's own wife!
Hey, Takeoka!
It's me, baby, Mouri-kun!
Are you drunk?
As drunk as a skunk!
I'd like to meet up tomorrow, though, all righty?
C'mon, c'mon, c'mon!
Dad looks so drunk.
Is he going to be all right?
He didn't drink even a drop.
Well, it's true you have to feign drunkness to make certain calls.
Remember this place?
For sure.
During summer ten years ago, on this very beach, two
couples on vacation bumped into each other unexpectedly.
Takeoka!
Mouri?
Despite being in the same class at the police academy...
We didn't hang out at all...
And didn't even have time to talk.
At that time, we spoke at last.
You got married while still a student?
Well, yeah...
We're childhood friends, so I'm hopelessly tied to him.
What do you mean by "hopelessly"?
We met each other in college.
At a performance circle.
This clumsy guy can perform!?
Shut up!
I'm not clumsy!
I can act!
So, ten years have passed, huh?
We were both young.
Are you sure the culprit will show up here?
That's what uncle said, so...
So it still isn't enough, huh?
Guess I'll have to help.
He's a detective again.
My prayers worked!
I get it.
This has to be Uncle's case.
About the case this time...
The murderer knew who attacked
Kinugasa-shi and planned the whole thing.
They first killed Gamou-shi and made it out to be a suicide...
And then sought a way to make
Arai-san our suspect only to kill him too.
That was their plan.
However, if the plan were to kill
Gamou and pin it on Arai Kyousuke...
Why would they go through the hassle of moving Gamou
out of his house to a faraway place to stage a suicide?
For alibi manipulation.
At 7:00 PM...
The culprit transported Gamou-shi to the forest by car and killed him.
Then, they hid their car in an empty garage near Gamou-shi's house.
At 8:00 PM, they disguised as Gamou-shi and gave me a call.
Next, they drove Gamou-shi's car away
from his home and hid it in the garage.
They then walked to meet a friend at 8:30 PM and stayed until midnight.
Lastly, they walked back to the garage and this
time drove Gamou-shi's car to the forest area.
If I had testified that I received a phone call from him at 8:00...
It'd be logical to conclude Gamou-shi had died no sooner than 9:00.
And with that, the culprit...
Would have the alibi of meeting with a friend at that time.
So, you're saying the last phone call you received...
Was actually from Gamou's killer who had mimicked his voice?
Correct.
But Dad said he would never mishear his client's voice...
But still, Mouri...
You were a police detective—would your ears deceive you?
If it had only been that time, I wouldn't have been deceived.
However, the culprit, aiming to deceive me, had
already started the impersonation half a month ago.
The first call that I received...
My name is Gamou Ryouzou.
I want you to find a witness who can confirm my alibi.
Along with the ones I received night after night...
Weren't from the real Gamou-shi.
The actual Gamou-shi had not met nor called me even once.
Isn't that right?
Mr. "Performance Art," Takeoka.
The way Gamou-shi looks and talks...
They weren't hard for you to impersonate, were they?
But, you were afraid that I might see through
you, since I'd spent so much time with you.
As such, that night, you purposely showed up late to the restaurant.
As an apology, he wanted you to enjoy those first.
You had me get drunk in order to break my concentration.
Not only that...
Gamou-san, please come again!
Hey, Gamou-san!
You made yourself known in public so no one would be suspicious.
And of course the search for the alibi witness didn't go well...
Because the request itself was a fluke anyway.
To avoid raising suspicions from the call records, you also...
It's Gamou!
You still haven't found my witness?
You waited for the real Gamou-shi to take a bath...
And used an additional handset you installed to call me every night.
So you've seen through it all...
Looks like I've been wasting my effort.
And it wasn't a coincidence that we met at the horse racetrack?
Yeah.
Why?
I am sorry for using you.
Why did you have to kill those two!?
Especially after five years!
She died...
A month ago, my wife did.
After two long years of fighting her disease.
My sweetheart, when she drew her last breath...
She apologized to me.
I'm... sorry...
What for?
Five... years... ago...
I was shocked.
She had been feeling guilty the entire time.
She thought her testimony made me lose my job.
But I never stopped believing in her testimony.
What alibi witness?
Hell, Gamou could've just hired someone as his fake witness!
Then, on the day her funeral was over...
I learned of that Kinugasa Sakai's recent homicide...
And called Gamou immediately.
You killed him, didn't you?
Just like you jumped him five years ago!
It wasn't me this time!
Talk about a slip of the tongue.
"It wasn't me this time," meaning it was last time.
Natsuko's testimony was right!
She gave them the truth and wasn't
believed, only to die apologizing to me.
I wanted to avenge my poor sweetheart...
Mouri...
Get back together already, with Eri-san.
What's this nonsense all of a sudden!?
Takeoka!
Takeoka-san!
Where are you!?
Takeoka!
There!
Don't tell me...
Hold it!
I don't think so!
Not gonna let you die!
I'll make you...
Pay for your crimes, so stay alive!
I'm not letting you go!
Takeoka!
Mouri!
Takeoka-san...
Mouri...
Takeoka...
Dad, you don't have to take down your sign, especially right now.
Uncle...
I'm a man of words.
Awesome, our new sign!
So you really aren't giving up being a detective?
Since when did I say that?
He did only say he'd take down the sign and close up, temporarily...
A private detective is a lonely and fairly misunderstood organism.
Lipstick?
Next Conan's Hint
Names of Fish
Look forward to the next episode
Whole eel, eel rice, eel pie, eel paste, eel gut soup, charred eel rice!
Those are names of dishes...