Awesome!
We caught a bunch!
If we count everyone's together, we'll have almost twenty!
We'll have a big fish dinner at the professor's tonight!
Well, the one preparing it will be the professor.
That's reason to worry a little.
That's really something, Genta.
You caught sea bream again.
You're an expert now, huh?
Maybe...
Actually, I was trying to get eel, but...
I missed it.
In that head of yours...
There's probably only eel-on-rice.
Let's eat!
All right, go ahead and pack away your equipment.
It's time to get ready to head back.
That ship's coming to get you.
It's true!
Professor!
Thank you, Uncle Ejiri.
You did great watching over us.
No, no.
You and Agasa-san did save my life once, after all.
It was nothing to watch over you kids
while he rushed home for some business.
As for this guy, Eijiri Futoshi-san...
We met him on a past fishing trip when he got involved in a case.
He ended up being poisoned while fishing...
But due to help from Professor Agasa and the rest of us...
His life was saved.
After some rest, it seems he's as energetic as ever.
Professor!
We got a huge catch!
Pro... fess... or?
That isn't the professor...
Isn't he the man who lives next door to the professor?
I think he was a post graduate student named Okiya Subaru-san...
Love is eternal, labyrinths are mysterious.
Saturday nights are for mystery!
Left on the rock of the dragon legend...
Remains a message full of fish!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
The professor couldn't make it back?
Seriously!?
Yeah.
That invention he made and distributed to the neighbors...
The "Automatic Ham & Egg Maker," seems to have malfunctioned.
The complaints have poured in.
He thought it'd be an instant repair, but...
It's taking longer than expected.
That's why he left it to me to pick you guys up.
That machine —
I knew it was a bad idea...
All right, resume chatting once you're all on the ship.
Make it quick or we'll get caught out here while the sun sets.
Yes, sir!
Hey, next!
That's you.
Yes.
Be sure to watch your step.
What's with you?
You've been acting weird lately.
I can feel it...
From that guy.
"That guy"?
Okiya Subaru-san, you mean?
What kind of feeling could you be getting from him?
He just...
Smells like someone from the Black Organization.
You can still feel it?
No...
I only felt it when I first met him...
Back during that arson case.
The source of that peculiar pressure
must have been him, no matter what.
The ones who changed you back into a child...
This is definitely the sign of their presence!
You sure you aren't just over thinking this.
My, my, what's keeping you?
You guys need to get on too.
Yes.
We can't have that.
Keep an eye out.
Yeah...
Well, I'll see you later, Ida-kun!
This is too bad, huh?
We've caught so many but won't get to eat them.
The professor is busy, after all.
Well then...
How about I prepare it for you?
You can cook?
Yeah, a little bit.
I'm not up there with first-class chefs, but...
I can manage home dishes.
Then...
If the professor will let me use his kitchen...
I'll treat you to it.
All right!
A treat!
Hey, kids, look at this!
It's a beautiful sunset, right?
Awesome!
It's like a postcard picture.
Huh?
What's that?
There's something pointy coming from under the sun.
That's Ikkaku Rock.
Ikkaku Rock?
A long time ago, there was a sea dragon with a big horn on
its head, which is why it was known as the Ikkaku Dragon.
After fishermen caught its young, the Ikkaku Dragon grew angry.
It then placed its horn above the water to
protect its home, or so the legend goes.
Since fishing boats are cautioned that any
that approach it will end up sinking...
Fishermen only worship Ikkaku Rock from a distance.
Well, you wanna see it?
It's easy to come to a stop near the rock.
But, if the ship ends up sinking...
It's fine!
The Ikkaku Dragon loves kids.
They also say that if kids visit, the dragon will grant them
the power of the sea and make them perfect swimmers.
For real!?
Come on, let's go, let's go!
It's really big...
Yeah.
It's just that, thinking of a huge dragon under there...
It's a little eerie.
Hey!
The hell are you doing!?
That's Ikkaku Rock!
You're gonna get cursed by the dragon and sink!
It's fine.
Look, they're kids.
That's right.
Hey, Kaita.
Looks like this isn't the place.
Nothing we can do then.
Let's head to another point.
Who were those guys?
It seemed like they were looking for something.
They started diving around here recently.
They're divers that are colleagues of
some company president's daughter.
They've really been disturbing our fishing.
The sea does belong to everyone, sure, but...
I just wish they'd be a bit more thoughtful toward us fishermen.
Anyway, this Ikkaku Rock is also the children's rock!
Enjoy it to your heart's content!
Yes!
After getting here and seeing it up close...
It's really just a bunch of rocks with potholes in them.
Yeah.
It looks like sea water has caused it to deteriorate over time.
Look, look!
The sunset!
Why don't we all take a picture together before it sets?
Well, maybe the camera on my cell will do.
Let's do it!
Yes!
Everybody in a row, in a row!
That rock behind you...
Something's written on it.
saba koi tai hirame
Mackerel, carp, sea bream, flounder?
Did someone carve the names of fish they
caught here to commemorate the occasion?
It's bad, to do something like that...
Hey, look at this!
There's something stuck between the rocks here.
What is it?
It's in there really tight, I can't get it out...
That's a fin you wear on your foot while diving, right?
A new fin and freshly carved words...
If the fin had been left as a prank...
They couldn't use it on the return trip.
And the writing...
Could it be some kind of message?
Is someone here?
Conan-kun!
A tank and regulator...
A diver, huh?
What happened to that person?
Is she asleep?
No...
She's dead.
Judging from the rigor...
She likely died only a few hours ago.
Given the plenteously dry mouth...
As well as the tense skin...
It must be dehydration.
Lipstick?
Huh?
Hold on...
The regulator I just saw...
It's likely she ran into trouble during her dive
and as a result was unable to swim properly...
So she struggled her way here...
But unfortunately wasn't discovered in time.
Yeah.
This is Ikkaku Rock, where ships are known
to sink, so it's likely no one even came close.
Still, we should all help carry her to the boat.
It would be pitiful to leave her here...
No.
We should wait to move her...
Until the police arrive, since it's possible we aren't too late.
The police!?
Then, could it be —
she was...
Yeah.
It's possible she was left here deliberately.
Look at this.
The regulator here that's used for breathing air from the tank...
It's not dirty, is it?
If this person that's wearing lipstick had used it...
There would be some trace of her lipstick on the regulator.
What are you saying?
Someone substituted this one for another, and for a specific reason.
It's likely that, in the past few hours...
The one who stopped by here twice...
Is the culprit.
I see.
You were here at Ikkaku Rock posing for a
picture with the sun in the background...
When you found the remains of this young woman.
Looks like this wasn't the best time to check out the sunset.
Yes.
I can't be sure before we get her back
on land for a proper examination, but...
Judging from the extent of the rigor and the cloudy corneas...
I'd say she's been dead five to six hours.
Due to the exceedingly dry mouth and stiffened skin...
It must be death by dehydration.
In other words, this woman must have been on
this rock for three days without food nor drink.
Take into account the wet suit, oxygen
tank, and regulator, and we have...
A diver.
The average detective would conclude
some trouble befell her while diving...
Which lead to her struggling to this
rock where she was never seen.
Well, that would be the ordinary deduction...
But it's wrong.
Take a look at that.
This woman is wearing lipstick...
Yet there isn't any on the regulator!
As such!
Someone calculated the time it would take for her to die...
And returned to switch the regulator.
From there, they made the switch and left the body behind.
While I'm not sure what lead to it...
I am sure that this is a case of murder.
That's amazing!
Nah, it's nothing.
Just a detective's work.
No, I mean Conan-kun!
We already heard everything you just said
from Conan-kun, before you got here!
Right?
But really...
This kid always seems to be involved in cases.
Don't tell me you already knew there
was a body here before you landed?
I had no way of knowing!
I only thought someone may be here after we arrived.
And why would you have thought that?
Because of a fin stuck in the rocks.
It's on the opposite side of here...
There's a diving fin tightly wedged between the rocks.
It must have come to the boy's mind after seeing that.
A fin wedged between the rocks?
Yeah.
Almost no one would bring along
an extra fin for the sake of a prank.
In other words, it's best to assume it
was left there as a message instead.
That's the natural path of deduction.
Then, let's just pull the fin out and see what's written on it.
No...
We found the other fin as well and pulled both of them out.
But there was nothing written on them.
Now that you brought it up...
There was something written on the
rock next to the fin, wasn't there?
They were fish names!
There were four of them.
Did you say fish names?
Yes, sir.
They were...
Mackerel...
saba mackarel
Carp...
koi carp
Sea bream...
saba mackarel
koi carp
tai sea bream
And flounder, right?
saba mackarel
koi carp
tai sea bream
hirame flounder
What's that about?
Couldn't those just be the names of
some fish someone had caught here?
That's not it, Juugo-chan.
Is that Ida-chan?
You may find mackerel, sea bream, and flounder...
But there aren't any carp out in the sea.
Guess so...
I guess you were the one who brought them here?
Yeah.
You and the detective know each other?
We've been friends since we were young.
We wanted to become better swimmers, so
we'd come out here on my father's boat.
This guy—he would always be totally
scared and have to hide behind me.
That's right.
How's that older brother of yours
that came along doing now?
He was so scared he couldn't get off the boat.
Yeah, after all that, Sango's still a worthless swimmer.
Talk about being no help at all...
But what do they mean?
Sea bream, flounder and all those.
This isn't like the legend of the dragon palace.
Isn't it a dying message?
Look over here...
At this woman's left arm.
There's a tan line from wearing a watch, right?
So, I thought about that before you came...
And searched all over this rock for it.
That's when I found this.
A diver's watch that's a perfect
match for the mark on her wrist.
What!?
The edge here seems to be fairly roughed up...
I see.
The size of the damaged area on the watch
is close to that of the writing on the rock.
She most likely used it to carve in her dying message, right?
That's what you thought, no?
But the criminal came here once, didn't he?
That person may have written the words
in order to implicate someone else.
But if that were actually true...
They would have opted to leave the watch
in a more visible spot for us to find.
If we consider that she hid it away deliberately...
We can say she did so in order to prevent the culprit from realizing...
That she had left those words as her dying message.
Even though it's true few ships pass by this rock...
It's possible she would've been seen by someone.
The woman knew the culprit would not be able to stay long...
So she hid the watch.
She left the message for the police to
decipher after her body had been discovered.
There.
Because there are initials on the back of the watch...
Even if we had found it much later, we
would still know whose watch it was.
It looks like "H.A." is engraved here.
"Akamine Angel—"
"Club"?
The engraving after "Angel" has been
scratched off so badly that I can't read it...
But, boy, it looks like your deductions are as great as ever!
He's been trained by that stingy detective, Kogoro.
This kid just likes to play detective.
This is a police investigation starting now.
No matter how smart this kid may be, there's
no way he can know who this woman is.
She's the only daughter of a chairman to a finance
company that recently branched out to Kanagawa.
His name is Akamine.
Isn't that right, Uncle?
She was always diving around here with a group of young guys.
I think her name was...
Lady Hikari!?
Hey...
That wet suit...
Isn't that the same as hers!?
What's going on and who're they?
At any rate, get closer to that rock!
If that's really her...
It's no laughing matter!
What?
She disappeared three days ago?
It's true, right?
Yeah.
The four of us went diving during the day three days ago.
After not surfacing for quite a while...
We went back down to look for her.
Ohto Rokusuke (23)
Diver
She sent an e-mail to my phone after that.
It said, "Please handle the rest."
Are you saying you stopped looking right
then and there without confirmation?
Aosato Shuuhei (25)
Diver
That isn't out fault.
A similar incident happened in the past.
A similar incident?
We were diving at the beginning of summer, too...
And like this time, she didn't resurface.
We looked everywhere for her.
Actually, didn't we put out a missing person's search request?
That time, she unexpectedly came back the next day.
When we asked about it, she said some attractive
guys picked her up on their cruiser...
And she went back and drank at their place until morning.
But, I don't recall hearing about any search
requests in the past two or three days...
No, we didn't ask for one this time.
Kaita Yasuji (24)
Driver
Last time, she was angry with us over that.
Didn't I send you an e-mail saying, "Please handle the rest"?
Don't make such a fuss over it!
That was it.
That's why we decided to just wait for her this time.
But after getting to the third day and still not hearing from her...
We decided to come out and search for her.
The three of us went back and visited
the point from three days ago.
We stopped and asked all of the cruisers we came across as well.
But we never thought...
We'd find her on Ikkaku Rock...
And definitely not in this shape.
Akamine Hikari-san...
Because of someone...
She was left deserted here on Ikkaku Rock.
A planned death by dehydration.
Who on earth could have done this?
And...
saba mackarel
The words she carved into that rock...
koi carp
tai sea bream
hirame flounder
Mackerel, carp, sea bream, and flounder.
Just what is it they mean?
The culprit actually identified himself from the beginning.
It was as if he said, "The one who left this lady at Ikkaku Rock...
"Was me."
Next Conan's Hint
Diver's Watch
All right, I'm putting the mask on!
Kamen Diver!
You mean Yaiba.