After we finished fishing...
We were expecting to go back with Professor
Agasa, but he sent Okiya Subaru-san instead.
Due to the legend of the one-horned dragon...
We stopped by Ikkaku Rock.
Then, carved in a rock, we found...
"Mackerel, carp, sea bream, flounder," along with...
The body of a female in a wet suit.
After running into trouble during a dive...
It seemed she had died of dehydration
while waiting for help to arrive.
But I wasn't fooled.
Even though the woman was wearing lipstick...
There were no signs of any lipstick on the regulator near her.
It had been a murder staged as an accident.
In addition, it seems she carved words into the rock side...
With the diver's watch she had on her.
Of note was one word being leveled off from the back.
The name of the deceased woman...
Akamine Hikari-san.
According to the three men known to be her diving companions...
Hikari-san had disappeared on a dive three days earlier.
Just who was it that left Hikari-san on Ikkaku Rock...
To die of dehydration...
And...
The words engraved on the rock...
Mackerel, carp, sea bream, and flounder...
What is it they're supposed to mean?
Love is eternal, labyrinths are mysterious.
Saturday nights are for mystery!
Mackerel, carp, sea bream, flounder...
It's time to catch the truth behind the case!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Geez...
To think she never learned how to swim...
You can go diving without knowing how to swim?
Yeah.
There are plenty of divers that do.
They just have to rely on the air in their tank and their fins.
And, just how are the three of you related to her?
She was just our diving partner.
It started out with just us, but...
Ohto Rokusuke (23)
Diver
When she said she wanted to join a group...
Well all started going together.
Aosato Shuuhei (25)
Diver
And with the use of her cruiser, we could
get to any point we wanted easily.
By hanging around with her...
Kaita Yasuji (24)
Diver
We could also always have the most exquisite meals.
But, say...
While scuba diving...
You usually go out with two or more people, right?
Did you just lose sight of her?
That woman was always swimming off on her own.
She always said she wanted to be alone with the sea.
Due to that, she ended up being taken by the current half a year ago.
That was definitely a really bad situation...
Yeah.
If that hadn't happened...
Yoshirou likely wouldn't have died.
Yoshirou?
Ah, no...
Stop, don't mention Yoshirou.
That's unrelated.
By the way, Kaita-san...
That eye there...
What happened?
Well...
This guy hit me last night.
It was after I suggested the lady...
May have just be staying at some guy's
house and we should just let her be.
"And what if this turns into a real emergency" was what he said.
Then, what's with Ohto-san's mask?
Despite not feeling well, the lady forced me to go diving with her.
I ended up with a cold, and a prolonged one at that.
Well, I've been diving without worrying about it for now.
Aosato-san...
Were you injured, under your lip?
Just acne.
While I was at a net cafe surfing the net last night...
I accidentally burst it open while leaning on it.
What were you looking for on the net?
What else but looking for signs of the lady?
I looked around at numerous blogs...
To see if anyone had picked her up on their boat.
I thought it was best to check.
Say, you misters!
What kind of fish do you like?
And could you answer one at a time?
Tell us already!
I really like eel!
What is it with these kids?
No, no...
Hey!
What're you guys doing!?
Asking this strange stuff out of nowhere...
It isn't strange!
Because that dying message mentioned sea bream and flounder...
saba mackarel
koi carp
tai sea bream
hirame flounder
Those might actually be the favorite fish of the culprit!
How absurd...
No...
The point they're aiming for isn't a bad one.
Innocent conceptions unbound by that of common sense...
It may, at times, be the one key that's instrumental
in wading through to the sole truth of a puzzle.
In addition, have the words and hints from that boy...
Not already led to the solving of a great number of cases?
Well, yeah, but there haven't been that many...
Hey, you lot.
What're your favorite fish dishes?
The three of us love practically all fish.
We don't really dislike any, either.
Satisfied?
Hey, hey...
How much longer must we stay here?
You're right.
The day's already growing dark.
Huh?
That watch you're wearing, mister...
It's a diver's watch just like that lady's, isn't it?
Yeah...
The lady had these custom-made for us.
She said that, as a diving team, we
should have a common link between us.
"Akamine Angelfish Club."
That's the name she selected.
Angel...
Fish...
At any rate...
We can continue this down at the station.
I still have some questions as to the identity of the culprit.
"Culprit"?
Hey!
Wasn't this just an accident!?
Right...
There is a culprit...
And most likely, he's among these three.
But, what was with that?
The fish message...
Mackerel, carp, sea bream, and flounder...
saba mackarel
koi carp
tai sea bream
hirame flounder
Just what is it supposed to mean?
And then...
There's the word on the diver's watch that was scratched off...
Why was only "FISH" missing?
That's it!
I know what those fish names mean now!
If you add a character and then connect them...
It becomes a sentence!
"Add"?
If [ku] is added to [saba], it becomes [sabaku].
saba
mackarel
sabaku desert
If we add [ai] before [tai], we get [aitai]
tai
sea bream
aitai want to
meet
As such...
Mitsuhiko inserts the word [koi]
(originally written for carp) as [come]
in order to better fit his deduction.
"I want to meet, come to the desert."
That's the message that was left behind.
flounder
And, hirame?
With the name of that fish...
hirame → hirame-ke
flounder → flash
We're meant to know it will serve as a flash of inspiration.
That's its meaning.
But, wait...
Who's waiting on who in the desert?
And that lady, she's already dead, isn't she?
Guess you're right...
Beyond that...
Even if you're meant to conveniently add
characters, and therefore force sentences...
Would we really ever be able to solve it?
Adding or subtracting won't matter.
Without a keyword, none of it will matter.
Well done, you guys!
What'd we do?
Indeed, it seems innocent conceptions should not be taken lightly.
Could it be, the culprit...
You know who it is?
Yeah.
And it's all thanks to you.
What is it?
The culprit actually identified himself from the beginning.
It was as if he said, "The one who left this lady at Ikkaku Rock...
"Was me."
Hey, hey...
It's already getting dark!
Shouldn't we be hurrying to get the lady's body to shore?
Don't you think so?
If you still have things you want to ask us...
We'll come to the station and answer them later.
Well, let's get her body onto the ship...
Hold on!
What now?
Both of you together?
No...
I think this boy had something to say.
But, I think Subaru-san wanted to
talk as well, so he should go ahead...
I said we're done!
We'll continue the talking down at the station!
But, actually...
Actually...
Key evidence may be destroyed in the process.
That's what you wanted to say, right?
More or less...
"Evidence"?
What kind of evidence?
You don't get it?
That is, of course...
Regarding this woman who was left here
at Ikkaku Rock to die of dehydration.
Evidence pointing to the culprit!
Hey, hey...
Being able to destroy evidence—does that mean...
Yeah.
He's here, isn't he?
The criminal we're looking for.
Hold on a second!
How can you just say that!?
While it's true she did go missing
while we were diving three days ago...
She could have just been picked up on the ship of some bad guy!
He could have been the one who left her here!
No...
That's not it.
At the time that she disappeared...
You claimed she sent an e-mail stating,
"Please handle the rest," right?
Actually...
What proves that the culprit is among you...
Is that evidence.
Most likely, the culprit...
After stranding her here...
Sent that mail himself, to ensure the search was delayed.
To manage that...
He had to abort his dive and hurry
back to the boat before anyone else.
After locating the lady's phone...
He hurriedly typed and sent the message.
Please handle the rest
Akamine
Unlike with telephones, e-mails have solid addresses attached.
If it had not been directly from her phone...
It would have been doubted.
I see.
Only you guys know it wouldn't be strange
for her to send an e-mail like that.
That means only one of you three could have sent it.
But, wait...
The lady's cell phone...
Where is it right now?
Well, if I had sent the e-mail...
I would have tossed it deep into the vastness of the ocean.
Then, where's your evidence!?
No...
The evidence is here...
Where this lady neatly left behind the name of her assailant.
Isn't that so...
Aosato...
Shuuhei-san?
Hey...
That's a weird thing to just come out and say.
Am I really that much like the culprit?
Actually, boy...
How did you know?
Shuuhei's first name.
We only gave our family names, right?
Because the lady stranded at Ikkaku Rock...
Carved the name of the culprit here.
Their full name...
Was Aosato Shuuhei.
Where was that done?
"Carved" it?
Do you mean the names of the fish?
But, that was just mackerel, carp, sea bream, and flounder.
saba mackarel
koi carp
tai sea bream
hirame flounder
While it's true they just appear to be the names of fish...
When she used it to carve in those words...
On the back of that lady's watch...
One word ended up being leveled down.
Do you see it now?
Leveled down?
Yeah.
The word between "AKAMINE ANGEL" and "CLUB."
"AKAMINE ANGEL FISH CLUB."
The word that was marked off...
"FISH."
In other words...
Cancel out the "FISH," right?
Yeah.
Please hold on a minute!
sakana fish
"FISH" is written as sakana, right?
Mackerel, carp, sea bream, and flounder...
Those are all fish, aren't they?
If you canceled out the fish...
There wouldn't be anything left!
I see!
It's the kanji!
Think of those four names in kanji...
And then remove the sakana from them.
Kanji?
But, mackerel...
Is there even a kanji for it?
Yeah.
The kanji for mackerel is the kanji for fish and AO written together.
The kanji for carp is the kanji for fish and SATO written together.
The kanji for sea bream is the kanji for fish and SHUU written together.
And...
The kanji for flounder is the kanji for fish and HEI written together.
And now, what do we get when we
read it with the fish kanji removed?
AO SATO SHUU HEI
aosato shuuhei
It's Aosato Shuuhei!
Hey!
You...
Idiots!
Don't take him so seriously!
With just this little riddle theory...
Am I really going to be called the culprit?
But!
It's a little too convenient how well it fits.
But, come on...
If I were the criminal, why didn't she just write my name?
That's because she believed you may erase it afterwards.
It was natural for her to assume you
would return to make sure she died.
The hell're you saying...
You saw it, didn't you?
When I came here?
I didn't see you, but...
I know another reason that led to you coming here today.
What?
The switching of the regulator.
Most likely...
You started by severing her regulator pipe with a knife...
In order to create the appearance of trouble with an air leak.
You then brought her here to Ikkaku Rock...
And left her under the pretense you'd
come back for her, but you never did.
Since no one comes near Ikkaku Rock...
And you knew she couldn't swim, she wouldn't be able to escape.
In other words, he replaced the damaged regulator...
With his own regulator that he normally uses?
That's due to the fact if a damaged regulator had
been found, it wouldn't be seen as an accident.
By covering the slice in it with some vinyl tape...
You would be able to make it back.
But none of you saw anything, did you?
The bandage under your mouth.
You claimed that, while at a net cafe...
You were surfing the net...
And accidentally burst something while leaning on your chin, right?
The mice you'll find in net cafes are
generally for those that are right-handed.
In other words, you would have been leaning on your left hand.
By that logic, one would expect the burst acne to be on the left side.
But, judging from the position of the bandage...
It does not appear to be on the left side.
It ended up coming off there, didn't it?
When you used her regulator on your way back to the ship...
No!
Her lipstick got on you.
I see.
You didn't realize until after you returned to the boat and
removed the regulator that her lipstick had gotten on you.
That's when you decided to move your
bandage to just under your lip to conceal it.
When it comes to wiping away lipstick...
It isn't easy to do with just your hands.
But, she is a strange woman...
Even if she is a beginner...
Divers with even a little experience aren't likely to dive with lipstick on.
It was on purpose.
When she first started...
I put on her regulator by mistake...
And got lipstick on me.
She found it so funny that she felt the need to wear it every time.
Well, thanks to that...
I discovered that she left Yoshirou out to die.
Left him out to die?
Do you remember?
That accident from half a year ago.
She ended up being carried away with the tide during a dive...
And then, Yoshirou went out to save her.
She managed to find her way back...
And got back on the boat, but...
Yoshirou was found dead not long afterwards.
Hey...
Does that mean, at that time...
Yoshirou was with her?
Yeah, it's likely.
But, that isn't what she said back then.
There's just me!
Hurry and let me back on the boat!
It's so cold I feel like I'm gonna die!
That's what she said then...
I assumed she never saw Yoshirou.
There's no way for her to have missed him!
When they found Yoshirou's regulator...
Her lipstick had been stuck to it.
When I asked her about it...
As for Yoshirou...
She said she assumed he had returned to land.
There's something wrong with it all, right?
If someone had gone to rescue you...
You would ask how they were doing after being swallowed by the tide.
But all that woman thought about was how
to get back to land as soon as possible...
So she could sleep in a warm bed!
Whether Yoshirou ended up dead or not...
She didn't care!
That's why...
That woman...
That's why I chose to leave her on Ikkaku Rock.
Well...
I'll let you all have that same experience!
Shuuhei!
Don't do anything stupid!
Don't you worry.
I'm just using this temporarily, until I get away.
I'll leave you here for a while!
Hey, cop!
Go talk with your colleagues over there!
Tell them you're coming back on our cruiser to question us.
Order them to leave and head back!
And then, as the police disappear...
Fisherman!
You'll cut the rope that has your boat docked near this rock...
And we'll let yours go as well!
Then, when the fishermen's boat is out of sight...
I'll take this little child...
And make my escape on the cruiser!
Damn it!
My tranquilizer watch is on the boat...
There's some risk involved, but if I use my power kick shoes...
These are my boots!
Hey, Haibara!
Do you have anything on you that can serve as a weapon?
How could I have something so convenient right...
0.12%.
What?
That's the probability an offender's flight will end in success.
That gives us 1 in every 1000.
But...
Of those that fall under the devil's influence...
Many grow tired of leading a false life and living in fear.
If we exclude those that eventually surrender
to the police and those that opt for suicide...
The amount that do successfully escape...
Amounts to nearly zero.
Are you prepared...
To endure the loneliness and pressure as a result of your actions?
Shut up!
There.
Now you're all right.
Thank you...
Awesome!
Well, then...
How about we escape to the police station, buddy?
Yes, sir...
So strong!
You were so cool!
It was nothing.
Thank you, Mr. Subaru!
But, was it true?
That figure of 0.12%.
Of course...
It was random.
In that situation...
To get the knife and free this little one,
I thought it would be best to provoke him.
You really are amazing!
As I thought...
That person...
Choke marks around the neck...
Manual strangulation.
Say, on Yukiko-san's shoulders...
There are greenish smears on them, aren't there?
Yukiko-san climbed down the stairs to B1F.
Why didn't she take the elevator?
The culprit who killed Yukiko-san...
Is among them!
Next Conan's Hint
Crayon
Shin-chan...
Your name is Shin'ichi, isn't it?
You can't say it with that kind of timing...