Thank you for listening.
Now, onto our next great performance...
Here we go.
"Everlasting Luv"!
Love is eternal, labyrinths are mysterious.
Saturday nights are for mystery!
Today, we'll solve the murder trick of the closed green room...
And reveal the noise from within the band!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is Detective Conan!
Watanabe Yukiko (24)
Vocals
Nishimoto Makato (25)
Guitar
Aoki Shouta (27)
Bass
Tanaka Risako (22)
Keyboard
Nakamura Yuusuke (30)
Drums
Sakamoto Yuuki (38)
Music Producer
Hey, don't hold back!
Eat whatever you like!
Consider yourself lucky since it's all my treat!
As for "whatever" I like...
There's nothing to eat aside from edamame and sausages.
Isn't that nice?
Dinner with edamame and sausages!
So awesome!
One more beer!
Dad, you shouldn't drink that much.
What do you mean!?
I had to spend my day out with you because you wanted to buy clothes!
Don't you go and get stingy with my beer!
But...
These are all songs I've never heard...
Now, let's change pace...
And play a song everyone may be familiar with.
Play Okino Youko-chan's "Moon Lady"!
Don't tell me you punks don't know how to play it!
Stop it, Dad!
Going to the bathroom.
All right, please welcome S&G's most famous song.
They aren't gonna play Youko-chan's?
8th Floor
Drawings...
Reminds me of having to draw pictures at school.
To think I have to pretend to draw like a kid...
Uhm...
Please forgive me if I'm wrong...
But aren't you that famous detective, Mouri Kogorou-san?
Indeed, this is yours truly, Famous Detective Mouri Kogorou-san.
As I thought!
You requested for us to play one of Okino
Youko-chan's songs, so I thought it might be you.
I've seen you on TV with her.
My name is Nakamura Yuusuke.
Oh, so you saw me on TV?
Hey, two more beers!
No thanks.
I only wanted your autograph on this guitar if that's all right.
My, no need to hold back!
Hey, Conan!
Go order more snacks!
Fine.
My autograph, huh?
Sure thing!
I'm getting tired of these...
Huh?
Where's Ran-neechan?
That guy said he had a CD that Ran wanted pretty bad...
So they went to the green room to grab it.
A green room is an area in entertainment venues
designated as a resting lounge for performers.
I see.
Basement 1st Floor
Is the green room still open?
No, the key's been returned.
Here.
Green Room
Authorized Personnel Only
Sorry, but please wait here for a moment.
All right.
So this is how they store their instruments, huh?
Huh?
What's this?
Somebody help!
What's wrong?
That...
When I lifted the blanket...
Yukiko was...
She looked dead!
Hurry, get Mouri-san!
Right!
Someone's dead?
Mouri-san...
Yukiko was...
She was strangled.
Ran, call the police!
Yes!
This...
What is this?
So, the members of the band range
from the victim, Watanabe Yukiko-san...
To you and the other three?
Yes.
Inspector...
According to the security guard...
The only ones who borrowed the key to this
room today were members of this band.
Nakamura-san...
Could you contact those three and ask
them to return to this department store?
Yes, sir.
Say, on Yukiko-san's shoulders, there
are greenish smears, aren't there?
Yeah.
Inspector, we've got something on her shoulders!
Please confirm the identity of the substance immediately!
Yes, sir.
Something wrong?
Somehow, I think something's different around here.
What do you mean?
That's just it—I can't pinpoint it...
The performance at the rooftop beer garden ended at 8:30.
Yukiko-san's body was discovered around 9:15.
Would you please detail your actions during that timeframe?
Also, please include when you last saw Yukiko-san alive.
As for me, once the performance had ended, I helped
the department store staff put away the instruments.
Twenty minutes later, I visited Mouri-san's table...
Where we talked for about fifteen minutes, and
then I came to this green room with Ran-san.
I last saw Yukiko when she left the stage.
And the rest of you?
I went down to the green room by elevator with Shouta and Makato...
I stayed for about five minutes, and then left with Shouta.
According to the security office's record, that was at 8:40.
The last time I saw Yukiko was in front of the elevator...
You guys go ahead.
That's what she said.
It's the same for me.
Me too.
After you left the department store, what did you do?
Shouta said he had some other things to take care of...
So we parted ways from there.
And you, Nishimoto-san?
Five minutes after those two headed home...
I returned the key to the security office and went home myself.
The record shows that the time he returned the key was at 8:45.
Aoki-san, you?
I was...
Sitting in the car inside the parking garage, waiting on Yukiko.
What were you doing waiting for Yukiko?
Weren't you supposed to be dating Risako?
With Yukiko...
I wasn't seeing her.
Then, why were you with her yesterday!?
You told me you were busy!
Shouta!
You and Yukiko actually were...
Stop it.
Not here, not now.
Before Nakamura-san and Ran-kun borrowed the key...
There was someone else who borrowed the key at 8:55.
Aoki Shouta-san...
It was you, no?
Yes...
Shouta...
You...
It's not like that!
When Yukiko didn't show, I went to the green room to look for her.
But Yukiko wasn't there.
I waited for a while, but when she still didn't show...
I had no choice but to give up, return the key, and go home.
That was when the department store staff
hauled the instruments down here.
According to the security guard, the key
was definitely returned after five minutes.
By the way...
Why was it you were waiting for the victim, Watanbe Yukiko-san?
By your own account, you weren't seeing one another.
Yukiko and I...
Were asked to join a new band.
What was that!?
"Why don't you guys join that band and have a major debut?"
That came from the Thomas Records company.
So, that's why...
What's with that mark?
Inspector...
I checked the security footage from the elevator, but...
I didn't see Yukiko-san taking the elevator
from the rooftop to B1F on the tape.
What now?
That means, from the roof to B1F...
Yukiko-san took the stairs all way down.
I think that must be it.
Why do you think so?
Tonight, at the beer garden...
Sakamoto-san from Thomas Records was there.
Just when we were about to take the elevator down...
Sakamoto-san headed down the stairs.
At any rate...
Can you do us a favor and contact this Sakamoto-san?
Right away.
It's true that, after the show...
I met Yukiko on the stairway landing leading down to the 8th floor.
So you killed Yukiko!
I didn't!
I just...
Talked to her about the performance and left her alone.
She said she didn't want her fellow
band members to see us together.
You're lying!
That person is not the culprit.
Neither that person nor Yukiko-san...
Had the key to the green room.
He couldn't have entered the room.
Why are you so worked up?
Makoto...
Maybe it was you that did this?
How dare you!
I knew it already.
You were dumped by Yukiko.
I guess Yukiko came back as you were returning the key, huh?
And then, Yukiko...
Didn't Shouta say that, when he came back...
There was no one in the green room?
And what about you?
You were holding the key from noon on!
Maybe you went off and secretly copied the key?
That's nonsense!
You thought Shouta took Yukiko away from you, didn't you?
Knock it off!
It's pathetic to fight among the group!
Let's go ahead and recap all of this information.
Yukiko-san...
After parting ways with Sakamoto-san, then
proceeded to the green room at B1F via the stairs.
However, since she didn't have the key with her...
The one who opened the door had to be the culprit.
Which means...
It could've been Nishimoto-san prior to him returning the key...
As well as Aoki-san, who came back one last time...
Or even the one who had time to make
a duplicate of the key, Risako-san.
The culprit would have to be among you.
The landing between the roof and eighth floor...
This was the place where Yukiko-san spoke to Sakamoto-san.
Afterwards, Yukiko-san climbed down the stairs to B1F.
Why didn't she take the elevator?
Oops.
I was thinking so hard that I don't remember why I came here.
This drawing...
Could it be?
Is this it?
Am I wrong?
Boy, what're you doing there?
Nothing, really!
That's right...
The security office is just nearby...
But, why did Ran...
Ran-neechan!
Conan-kun...
When you saw Yukiko-san's body...
Instead of reporting it to the security office,
why did you come up the rooftop to call us?
That's because Nakamura-san told me to "get Mouri-san."
Oh yeah, Conan-kun...
I finally figured it out—what seemed off.
There was a big drum there.
When I was first here, there was a drum on top of that case.
But now, it's nowhere to be seen...
I see...
Tome-san...
About the greenish thing on Yukiko-san's shoulders, was it...
That's right, I'm surprised you figured that out.
All right...
Now it all makes sense!
The culprit is that person!
All right, everyone.
We'll need you to come to the station for further inquiries.
For real?
Me too?
I didn't kill her!
Oh, Mouri-kun!
Could it be...
That pose...
Yeah.
It's getting really late, so what do you say we wrap this up quickly?
This case, that is.
Inspector...
Conan told me he heard from the forensics investigator...
That the smear on the victim's shoulder was crayon.
Crayon?
But where would she get such a smear?
There weren't any crayons in the green room.
Then, where?
It was on the 8th floor.
The 8th floor?
On the 8th floor, there's a display
showcasing drawings created by children.
According to Conan...
One of the drawings there...
Had been partially rubbed off for some reason.
Most likely, Yukiko-san was attacked on the 8th floor.
And, at that time, she was pressed against
the wall, causing the crayon to get on her.
What now?
In other words...
The crime scene was not in the green room, but on the 8th floor.
But the body was found in the green room.
It was transported.
Detective Takagi!
Near the shin on the body...
There was a rectangular pressure mark, wasn't there?
Yes.
There was one.
Dad, I've brought it.
What is that?
That's the case for the bass drum.
Ran, lift the lid.
All right.
Inspector...
Do you see the metal fitting inside the case that supports the handle?
The mark on her shin...
Was made by that metal fitting as it pressed against her.
What'd you say!?
Yukiko-san's body was placed inside the
bass drum case and carried around.
Isn't that right...
Nakamura-san?
Why are you asking me?
Because only you could have done it.
Only you, who helped pack away the instruments...
Had the opportunity to put her body into the bass drum case.
But, when I unlocked the door and went into the green room...
Yukiko's body was already there, wasn't it?
Ran-san saw it as well!
From just after I finished putting away the instruments...
I was with either you or Ran-san from then on.
I didn't have the chance to transport her body to the green room.
Unfortunately, what Ran saw...
Wasn't Yukiko-san's body.
What do you mean, Mouri-kun?
Mouri-san...
I've brought what you asked for.
That a mannequin?
Yeah.
This is from the sports shop on the 8th floor.
As you can see, the left hand has been removed.
What Ran saw in the room was actually
the left hand of this mannequin.
I see.
It would be easy to just transport the mannequin's hand.
At that time, no one saw me carrying anything
like a mannequin's hand, did they?
Nakamura-san...
Why don't you play your guitar?
Detective Takagi...
Play the guitar.
All right.
Huh?
It's completely out of tune.
Nakamura-san...
When you entered this green room...
You were carrying that guitar, no?
The mannequin's hand...
Was placed inside that guitar.
After you hid Yukiko-san's body in that drum case...
You took off the left hand of the mannequin...
Put Yukiko-san's glove on it...
And placed it inside your guitar.
It's likely you used some tape to keep it in place.
You even tried to lower my suspicions by asking me to sign it.
Then, after asking Ran to wait in the corridor, you went inside...
Took the mannequin hand from inside the guitar...
And made the shape of a body with cushions and
a blanket before placing the hand underneath.
That ensured Ran would believe
Yukiko-san was lying there all along.
It can't be...
Leader...
After you had Ran come to fetch me...
You took the opportunity to carry the drum
case that contained her body inside the room.
Next...
You put the glove back on her hand...
And placed her under the blanket.
You stuck the mannequin's hand
back into your guitar, didn't you?
But, you didn't have time to re-tune it.
This is the truth of the case.
Leader...
Why'd you do this!?
This band is my life!
And I thought you guys felt the same...
I'll get in touch later.
Yeah.
Leader?
You and Shouta...
Were rumored to have been recruited into that new band.
So, it was true, wasn't it?
Yeah, that's right.
Is that problem?
You...
When you were in your previous band, you tried to sell yourself
to the record company but ended up being kicked out.
Isn't it thanks to us that you could still continue your singing career?
Don't make me laugh.
What?
You should be thanking me for joining...
So that your band could continue at all.
If it weren't for me...
A band this shabby would have already fallen apart!
How dare you...
You've served as my stepping stone to my major debut.
That's reason enough to thank me.
Everyone...
I thought you all felt the same as I did...
I really thought...
Nakamura-san...
We'll continue this conversation after we arrive at the station.
Please excuse him.
It looks like the alcohol suddenly kicked in after he solved the case.
No, it's no problem at all.
Here we are.
Was anything forgotten?
Oh, Ran-neechan...
Where's the stuff you bought?
I forgot to bring them!
The clothes I bought!
Back to the Beika Department Store we go.
Thank you...