This isn't good...
The fog's getting thick out here.
Really...
I can only see the guardrail beside us.
Beyond that, I can't see much of anything.
It can't be helped.
Here on Mount Fuyuna during this season...
The temperature and humidity give rise to thick fogs all the time.
That's what I heard on a TV program.
Again with the TV?
Concentrate on school!
He does!
Conan-kun gets the highest marks on every test!
Right?
Of course I do...
I'm actually in my second year of high school.
Damn, if I knew it was going to be like this...
I wouldn't have gone along with that client's offer for dinner.
Having to stay all night and hurry back is really just...
Dad, was that not due to you getting drunk?
Well, you two have school today, so I'm gonna speed back.
You're going to speed in this fog?
No worries.
No one else is gonna be out in fog like this.
We won't even have to worry about cars in the other lane.
I think it would be best if you didn't.
Look, there.
A roadblock?
License, please.
Has something happened?
No, it's OK.
You can let the male drivers pass—no problem.
After all, the one we're really after is...
A witch.
Yes, sir.
You!
Is that Yamamura from Gunma Prefecture!?
Mouri-san, if it isn't you!
It's been so, so long!
"So, so long," is it?
Has something happened nearby, Detective Yamamura?
You've got it all wrong, Ran-san.
Have you forgotten?
I'm afraid I no longer go by "detective," but instead...
"Inspector."
Inspector Yamamura at your service.
Is Gunma Prefecture really gonna make it?
Well?
There some murder near here or something, "Detective" Yamamura?
Inspector Yamamura!
We're actually taking on an important mission!
Important mission?
Witch-hunting!
Wi-tch hunt-ing.
Witch-hunting?
A witch?
Love is eternal, labyrinths are mysterious.
Saturday nights are for mystery!
What is the true identity of the eerie witch
that appears stop the foggy mountain!?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
"Witch-hunting"—what do you mean by that?
You haven't heard about it, Mouri-san?
Around four years ago, the one who could
be found here on Mount Fuyuna...
That legendary female driver.
That "legendary female driver"?
You've heard this is a favorite spot for local racers, right?
Yeah.
It's been said that she suddenly comes out of the fog...
And passes drivers that have already finished their battles.
That unique noise generated from her exhaust, coupled with
the high-pitched screech of her tires meeting such friction...
It sounds like the shriek of a woman coming right up behind you.
That's why they call her...
The Silver-White Witch
of Mount Fuyuna!
THE SILVER WHITE WITCH
The Silver-White Witch?
Why is it "silver-white"?
It's because her car is an all-white FD model.
But, still...
That alone doesn't prove the driver is a woman, right?
During a battle with that same car, the other racer skidded out.
When his opponent stopped and asked, "Are you all right?"
He only saw a beautiful woman!
And?
Just why are you after this woman?
You see, she seems to have appeared again recently.
All of the racers who went up against her ended up in accidents.
Not long ago, one crashed right into the
railing and was severely wounded...
Hold on!
Why are investigators from the crime unit handling this?
Traffic accidents should be handled by the traffic department.
It's because I've met her!
That witch!
Seriously!?
A senior officer told me to pick up their
car they'd parked and left on a stakeout.
As I was driving it back, I saw the witch's
car suddenly appear from the fog!
How'd you know it was the witch?
The hand, the hand.
The hand that stretched out of the car
was like that of a witch's, or so I heard.
You "heard"?
Weren't you the one who did the driving?
Well, no...
To be specific, it was my grandma.
Since she wanted to get out of her village for a while...
I decided to go by and pick her up.
That's when she said...
"It looks like you're worn out from all that working, so just let
me drive while you get sleep over on the passenger's side."
Then?
Don't tell me your grandmother raced with the witch.
Oh, she definitely did!
Grandma loves F1 and movies about racing.
Ah, but, she gave up in the middle of the race.
She said the opponent was a goddess, and she couldn't win.
A goddess?
Yeah, that's what grandma said.
That car...
It could ride on top of the fog where
there was no road, like an act of god.
On top of the fog!?
Yes.
Since she couldn't believe it either, she had to stop and get out.
Then, grandma saw her opponent step out of the car as well.
When grandma waved to them...
Her opponent waved back.
How could we believe that story?
Right?
That's why I wanted to verify it, and came to help with
the roadblock after finishing up my criminal case work.
But still, she only appears on mornings with thick fogs...
That's why I can only do this while I'm not on duty.
Let's see, my next free day is...
Next Saturday.
Then, let me lend you a hand as well.
Ah, there's no need.
Maybe my Grandma was mistaken.
And even a famous detective wouldn't be able
to catch a witch that rides the fog, right?
If it's someone with a pure heart like me...
I may have a chance to see her again, right?
Oh, is that so?
The Silver-White Witch of Mount Fuyuna?
I know, I know.
I heard that she reappeared recently, but...
What do you wanna know about it, Ran-chan?
Actually...
My dad vowed to catch her and won't let it go.
It's a white FD! FD!
He's been calling all of his friends that are into cars...
But, aside from the driver being female and that
she drives a white FD, we don't know much else.
That's why I thought you, Yumi-san from the
traffic department, might have more details.
We only deal with traffic affairs here in Tokyo.
Miwako, you know about this?
A female racer who drives a white FD.
I'm not too familiar with cars.
The one I'm driving is my dad's old car, so...
Is that so?
Sorry, Ran-chan.
Looks like I'm of no help.
FD?
A foreign car, maybe?
I say, Dad...
Let's go home!
This is already the second round for the day.
Be quiet!
I even rented this Lancer Evolution as bait for that woman!
No turning back now!
But if it's really the witch, it'll be scary!
That's why I told you not to come along!
But Conan-kun said...
I wanna see her...
This witch.
Since today's Saturday, we don't have school.
But we've been driving so long and she still hasn't shown...
Maybe the witch is taking a break?
Fine, it can't be helped.
Let's go.
What're you screaming about back there, Ran?
I'm not speeding at all.
No...
I didn't scream.
The sound of tires?
The sound of friction resembling a woman's scream...
And...
The feedback noise generated from
flooring the gas to the max rev speed...
In addition to the unique, high-pitched engine
rotary noise resembling that of a motor...
Could it be...
Hey, Ran!
Look back now.
Anything coming?
Back?
There's nothing there!
Uncle!
Beside you, beside you!
It appeared!
The White FD!
The battle sign?
Very well...
So you want to take me on?
Wait, Dad!
Please stop!
Shut up!
I never back down from a challenge!
Think you're tough?
Already that far away...
Damn!
Another curve!
I won't let you escape!
Uncle, stop!
Brake! Hurry!
Hey, hey!
Stop!
The hell were you doing!?
Uncle...
Which way did you plan to turn?
Left, it's left!
That car turned left!
But, uncle...
There is no road...
To the left.
What!?
No way...
It can't be!
That car really did turn left...
Just what the hell is going on here!?
The witch of Mount Fuyuna that speeds on the fog...
Isn't this interesting?
Say, was it true?
Could it be you were mistaken, Dad?
Absolutely not.
The white FD really turned to the left and drove on top of the fog.
The red tail light of that car suddenly tilted...
And dashed to the left right in front of my eyes!
I couldn't be mistaken!
I saw it too.
I also heard the tires screech.
That's why, when I felt strange and sensed the guardrail...
I decided to pull the handbrake.
So she really is a witch after all!
She must've used some scary magic and drove on top of
the fog, baiting us to follow and end up in an accident!
Inspector Yamamura's grandma also saw her stand on top of the fog.
And then, there's her eerie, witch-like
hand that was stretched out of the car...
Perhaps that car wasn't meant to be chased by humans...
Two.
Two people should have been in that car.
You mean—you saw it?
The interior of that car!?
I didn't, but it's still obvious.
That FD is a Japanese car with right-side steering.
lt'd be impossible for the driver to reach out
the passenger side window, wouldn't it?
But...
A witch could easily stretch her arm over there like a snake!
Then, how about we go confirm it?
With Det—Inspector Yamamura.
Why did you mention that hack's name now?
Because, didn't he say he'd come here again this Saturday?
If we call him now, he might be able to stop that car!
That's true.
A white FD with two people inside...
That should be easy to sort out.
Don't do it!
If we keep chasing her like this and get
badly cursed, what will we do then?
No need to worry.
Be it driving a car on top of the fog...
Or even standing on the fog...
They're all just tricks that can be explained with logic.
The only place that witches and curses exist...
Is in the world of fantasy.
Conan-kun?
I mean, Shinichi-niichan would say something like that!
I see.
You want me to stop all white FDs
with two or more people inside?
We did stop and check all white FDs, but...
There was nothing suspicious about them, so I let them go.
"Let them go"?
There was more than one white FD?
Yes.
Five of them.
Five!?
Five of them!?
It seems everyone has caught onto the Silver-White Witch fad.
They're hot right now...
White FDs.
But it's all right.
All the drivers so far were male.
We haven't seen a female driving yet.
You idiot!
Stop the men too!
The woman who came out of the witch's car four
years ago may have only been there by chance!
At any rate, be sure to stop all white FDs
that pass by from now on until we get there!
Judging from the position of your roadblock,
the witch shouldn't have passed by you yet!
Right...
So, these three, huh?
These are the white FDs that were stopped after I called you?
Yeah.
All three cars had two people on board.
Then...
The last car must be the witch's.
After all, I didn't pass by any other cars.
But we can't be sure about their proper order of arrival.
What?
Only the first car came to the roadblock without stopping elsewhere.
The two behind them said they were passed
by several cars when they stopped for breaks.
Come to think of it, a few cars did pass by
while you were calling Inspector Yamamura.
Which means, we can't know which FD belongs
to the witch by using only the arrival order?
Well, I questioned them anyway, but...
I don't think the witch is here.
What'd you ask them?
Of course...
"Are you the witch!?"
What kind of idiot...
Regardless, why don't you ask them, Uncle?
We even saw the witch's hand.
Yeah, guess you're right.
So, which was the first to arrive?
The FD with two men inside.
Egashira Raito (25)
How annoying!
I already told you we aren't the witch!
Well, while it may be true we drive a
white FD just to mimic the witch.
Mafune Akira (26)
It's also easier to speed on these mountain roads this way.
Easier to speed?
Other mediocre racers are scared of
white FDs and will clear the road for us.
Say...
Were you guys going fishing?
See, there's fishing gear here in the backseat, right?
Yeah.
It's because we can catch black bass at Fuyuna Lake.
Will you allow us to take at a look at your fishing rod?
Fine, but...
Don't break it.
It's a very good rod.
Here.
It really is a nice rod.
And?
Is it true no one passed by you
before you came to this roadblock?
Yeah, 'cause this guy was doing the driving today.
Don't be fooled by his looks—he's a hell of a safe driver.
Shut up.
Say...
You're wearing a really nice-looking ring.
Yeah, but it caused me to get cut while putting on my seatbelt.
It's still seeping blood now.
Come to think of it, the witch was also wearing a ring like this.
Is that so?
Our reason for driving a white FD?
Kawai Haruka (24)
Handou Rumi (23)
Of course it's because we admire the witch!
She's our spiritual leader.
And?
I heard you were passed by several cars before you arrived here.
Yeah.
I had to take a call while driving and, after I
pulled over to talk, two or three cars went by.
Were any of them white FDs?
Well, how should we know?
The fog was thick after all.
About that call, could it have been from a golf friend?
Yeah...
What's with this kid?
Since you have three golf bags stowed in there...
I though that may be it.
We asked what the hell's with this kid!
Well, see, this kid is...
Ah-le-le...
What happened to that fingernail?
Only the one on your middle finger is missing.
It must have come off while I was changing gears.
You know, the witch had really long fingernails as well.
Take a good look!
Haruka's are pink!
The witch's are black, no?
Anyway, would you object to us checking your golf bags?
Sure...
I guess that's fine.
Taira Yasue (28)
Enda Jinya (31)
The witch that roams this area drives a white FD too?
We didn't know that.
We chose this car because I happen to like
white, and for its streamlined design.
Then, were you passed by any white FDs like yours?
Out of these three cars...
You were the last to arrive at this roadblock, right?
Yeah.
Some cars passed us when I stopped to buy
coffee from a vending machine off the road, but...
I dunno what models.
We were drinking coffee in the car and talking about
the lakeside park we're going to, so we didn't notice.
That's why you brought the ring floats and rubber raft, right?
That's right.
We can go lake-rafting and float on the lake.
But wouldn't it be hard get them out once
you've already inflated them inside the car?
That was what she said also.
She said we should inflate them after we arrived.
Which means you were the one who did the driving, ma'am?
Right.
I was sitting in the passenger seat,
reading the map and giving directions.
What is it?
This hand is too large to be the witch's...
Then, please allow us to inspect
your rubber raft and floats, all right?
Hey, hey, Misao!
Grandma!
Yamamura Misae (85)
Inspector Yamamura's Grandma
Didn't I tell you to stay in the car?
Grandma?
You even brought her here?
Yeah.
She said she would recognize the witch if
she saw her again and wouldn't let it go.
My, it would seem she isn't here.
Why do you think she isn't here?
That's right...
That day, the driver who got out of the car and waved
to me in the fog had holy light shining from her back.
She was much more like a goddess than a witch.
None of them have light shining from their backs, right?
Who is this old hag?
Grandma!
Anyway, that's all for today and you may go as you please.
If we require anything further, the police will give you a call.
The Silver-White Witch...
The legendary female driver who started
roaming Mount Fuyuna four years ago.
She was said to drive on top of fogs...
And stand on them while waving...
What trick did she use?
Are those really possible?
And the three suspicious-looking pairs of drivers...
Egashira Raito-san and Mafune Akira-san.
Handou Rumi-san and Kawai Haruka-san.
Enda Jinya-san and Taira Yasue-san.
Just you wait, Silver-White Witch.
I'll reveal your true identity without a doubt.
Idiot!
The ending song of today's drama was sung by
Okino Youko-chan, titled "Midnight Mirage"!
Mirage?
I already thought of that simple trick too.
But that can't explain what comes next!
The mystery of standing on the fog!
Then, why don't we just ask the person-in-question about it?
The Silver-White Witch.
Next Conan's Hint:
Mirage
Ah, I can see Shinichi over there...
Look forward to the next episode
That has to be a mirage!
('Cause I'm right here...)