Four years ago, roaming the roads of Mount Fuyuna...
Was a legendary female driver who drove a white FD.
THE SILVER WHITE WITCH
"The Silver White Witch."
Recently, that legendary driver reappeared...
And began causing accidents by provoking racing battles.
By chance, the witch was witnessed by Inspector
Yamamura and, according to his grandmother...
The witch's car rode on top of the fog.
In addition, the witch stood atop the fog and waved.
After Uncle Kogoro heard this story...
He vowed to capture this witch himself...
And drove to Mount Fuyuma at dawn.
On the mountain roads enshrouded by fog...
The white FD drove by and the witch appeared.
We tried to chase the witch thanks to Uncle's skilled driving, but...
The white FD emitted a high-pitched screech like a woman's shriek...
And vanished into the fog where no road was present.
How could this be...
This must've been some kind of trick.
In order to verify this, we contacted Inspector
Yamamura who set up a roadblock...
And made him stop all white FDs.
As a result, three FDs with three pairs of drivers were stopped.
Is the witch one of them?
And...
The witch's FD...
How did it drive on the fog?
Love is eternal, labyrinths are mysterious.
Saturday nights are for mystery!
Let's reveal how the car drives atop the fog...
Along with the identity of the witch!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Egashira Raito (25)
How annoying!
I already told you we aren't the witch!
Mafune Akira (26)
Well, it may be true drive a white FD just to mimic the witch.
Were you guys going fishing?
See, there's fishing gear here in the backseat, right?
Yeah.
It's because we can catch black bass at Fuyuna Lake.
And?
Is it true no one passed by you before you came to this roadblock?
Yeah, 'cause this guy was doing the driving today.
Don't be fooled by his looks—he's a hell of a safe driver.
Shut up.
Say...
You're wearing a really nice-looking ring.
Yeah.
But it caused me to get cut while putting on my seatbelt.
It's still seeping blood now.
Our reason for driving a white FD?
Kawai Haruka (24)
Handou Rumi (23)
Of course it's because we admire the witch!
She's our spiritual leader.
And?
I heard you were passed by several cars before you arrived here.
Yeah.
I had to take a call while driving.
And after I pulled over to talk, two or three cars went by.
About that call, could it have been from a golf friend?
Since you have three golf bags stowed in there...
I thought that may be it.
What? What the hell's with this kid?
Well, see, this kid is...
Ah-le-le?
What happened to that fingernail?
Only the one on your middle finger is missing.
It must have come off while I was changing gears.
Taira Yasue (28)
Enda Jinya (31)
The witch that roams this area drives a white FD too?
We didn't know that.
Then, were you passed by any white FDs like yours?
Yeah.
Some cars passed us when I stopped to buy coffee
from a vending machine off the road, but...
I don't know what models.
We were drinking coffee in the car and talking about
the lakeside park we're going to, so we didn't notice.
That's why you brought the ring floats and rubber raft, right?
Then, please allow us to inspect your rubber raft and floats...
Hey, hey, Misao!
Grandma!
Didn't I tell you to stay in the car?
That day, the driver who got out of
the car and waved to me in the fog...
She had holy light shining from her back.
She was much more like a goddess than a witch.
The six of them were let go, just like that?
I think it's likely that the witch is among them.
But...
The arms of the three people who sat in the passenger seats...
They were all very different from the witch's that we saw.
Dad also said that she may really be a witch.
I see...
I just wanted to know how it went, so I called you.
Bye then, Ran-chan!
Mount Fuyuna's Silver-White Witch...
Come to think of it...
Miwako, didn't you wake up early to
drive on those mountain roads before?
Yeah.
Because of an incident...
A girl was hospitalized after losing her parents
and the ability to speak from the trauma.
It was on that mountain.
But then, because I insisted on visiting her often...
She was able to smile at me again.
When she was discharged, she said...
"I wanna grow up and be a police officer, just like you."
Isn't that great?
And did you spot the witch at that time?
Beats me.
All I thought about was visiting that girl.
I never really paid attention to the other cars.
Somebody help!
Stop him!
A convenience store robbery?
Sorry, Yumi.
Karaoke will have to wait!
That car...
It's fast.
Yumi, get ready.
I'm going to start doing "that" again!
Seriously!?
The hell?
There a car chase out there?
What a bunch of happy-goers...
And here I am still worrying about this mysterious witch's identity...
No...
I already have a clue leading to the witch.
It must be the FD driver who said that strange line, but...
I have no clue how they could drive on the fog...
Nor the trick they used to stand on it...
OH NO!
It's already 8:50!?
Nichiuri TV, Nichiuri TV!
Why won't the TV come on!?
I unplugged it earlier so I could use the vacuum cleaner.
What!?
Idiot!
The ending song of today's drama was sung by
Okino Yoko-chan, titled "Midnight Mirage"!
Mirage?
Why did you have to clean the house at a time like this!?
Because you knocked over your ash tray, that's why!
When light passes through two different air densities, it refracts.
That leads people to see illusions that aren't actually
there—the phenomenon known as a mirage.
The driver who waved to me had holy
light shining from behind her back.
Holy light?
This program was brought to you by these sponsors...
Damn, after all that chitchat, the program's already over!
It's actually because you overslept.
In that case...
I think it'd be best if you went back to sleep.
We'll have to wake up early tomorrow...
In order to hunt down the witch.
Hunt down the witch?
So you really knew that, among those that
were stopped at the roadblock last week...
The witch was inside one of the three cars?
But the witch could drive on the fog and even stand on it!
Don't you think she had to cast some magic to achieve that?
It's the arm.
The arm?
When we saw the witch's car last week...
Wasn't there an arm stretched out from the passenger window?
The arm with bracelets and rings that looked like the witch's.
I figured it out after seeing that.
But...
As for the first car, which had two men,
the man sitting in the passenger seat...
He had a hairy arm.
As for the woman in the passenger seat of the next car...
She was very tanned.
And for the last car, the one sitting in the passenger seat...
Was a man with large arms, wasn't it?
I think they're all different from the skinny
and pale arm of the witch we saw.
But of course.
It's because someone lied and said they were
the passenger when they were really driving!
Lied?
I see.
All three people that claimed they
were driving had thin and pale arms.
That person lied so they wouldn't be suspected of being the witch.
Then, they look the most suspicious to me now...
It's that couple, right?
The slightly overweight guy...
Admitted to inflating the raft in the back seat.
All the same, he also claimed to have been
in the passenger seat giving directions.
There's no way to blow up such a big raft in the back seat
with your mouth while sitting on the passenger's side!
There is.
You can just use a bicycle tire pump
or an electric pump instead, right?
That may be true...
Then, does that mean it's the pair with two women?
That one lady had her fake fingernail
on her left middle finger fall off.
She could have been wearing black fingernails like the witch,
and then hurried and changed after making the gesture.
That may be true, but...
It's also possible to lose a left hand nail
while changing gears in a Japanese car.
Then, could it be...
The man with hairy arms lied?
Because that man said his ring cut his right
cheek while putting this seatbelt on, no?
The witch's FD is a Japanese car with right-side steering.
In order to hurt your right cheek...
You'd have to use the seatbelt on
the driver's side, which is on the right.
Then, the witch's arm belongs to...
Yeah.
It's the one sitting next to the hairy-armed guy...
The pale-skinned man who wore jewelry and
fake fingernails to appear to be the witch.
But how would you explain their driving on the fog...
And their ability to stand on it?
Ah, that's because...
Because?
You already knew?
I didn't know a thing!
I only thought it was unbelievable.
Jeez...
I can't keep rattling off like this.
Even worse...
I can't put Uncle to sleep while he's driving, either.
That's it!
Say, the title of Yoko chan's new song,
"Midnight Mirage," is strange, don't you think?
What?
Because you can't see a mirage at midnight.
How would a kid know about an adult's naming sense?
A mirage is magic that lets us see
something that's not really there, right?
It's not magic—it's a natural phenomenon.
Then maybe...
The witch's car that overtook us and drove
on the fog really wasn't there either?
Idiot!
I clearly saw the witch's car turn left where
there was no road and drive on top of the fog.
But, you only saw the red tail light, right?
The fog was very thick back then, just like today.
It wasn't just the tail light.
You also heard it, didn't you?
The high-pitched screech of tires!
That's why I thought the car turned left.
Hey...
What's so funny?
It's just that, if you pay too much attention
to the light, you'll fall into the trap.
It reminds me of the prey that are attracted by an anglerfish's light!
Angler... fish?
I see!
Those two carried a fishing rod!
They could hang a red light at the end of the rod like an anglerfish...
Hang it out the passenger window...
And fling the rod to the left while they're actually turning right.
It'll look as though they turned left!
They could broadcast some pre-recorded tire
screech sounds with just the right timing!
I already thought of that simple trick too.
But that can't explain what comes next!
The mystery of standing on the fog!
Right...
If you keep thinking, "The same trick was used for
both driving on the fog and standing on top of it..."
You'll never come to the realization that
it's merely another simple matter.
Don't tell me they put a puppet at the
end of the rod and moved it around.
Then, why don't we just ask the person-in-question about it?
The person-in-question?
You mean...
Looks like they've come.
Mount Fuyuna's...
Silver-White Witch!
It's the same as last time...
The battle sign...
Bastard!
I won't let you get away today!
Don't be fooled by their tail lights!
Sure thing!
We're not alone today, either!
Bastard...
Tough as always, huh?
But this time...
I won't let you have your way!
Swift as usual...
They turned to the left!?
You think you can fool me...
But it's actually to the right!
As we thought...
They never left the road even once.
They're hastily pulling in their rod.
But there weren't any lights coming on before they turned!
That's easily explained!
They can turn off the tail lights manually...
And if you use the handbrake while drifting...
The brake lights won't come on then either!
Damn!
Why didn't they fall for it?
I'll lose you over these four hairpin turns for sure!
Good, good!
They can't follow now!
Good riddance, just like that!
What!?
Pity, isn't it?
Mr. Hairy Witch!
Such bad luck.
If it hadn't been for this stalled car, well...
Wrong, this was my plan.
Right, Yamamura?
Ah, yep.
I've been waiting for a while.
It was Mouri-san's order for me to block the road.
Well, I'd been driving about 200m in front
of Mouri-san's car at a crawling speed...
So slowly I was about to fall asleep.
We were set up, huh?
Then, will you tell us?
The reason you did this.
What!?
You wanted to get rid of all the racers on this mountain?
Aren't you racers too?
Yeah...
We were, anyway.
But then a friend of ours crashed and died racing up here.
We quit after that.
But even then...
Those punks continued racing like nothing happened.
We couldn't forgive that.
That's why we started trying to
scare them into quitting with this trick.
We pretended to be the witch who beat them four years ago.
Well, you could say we're doing society some good.
In actuality, there aren't a lot of races going on here these days.
Hey!
Don't you know?
People have gotten seriously injured because of you!
I do feel bad about that.
By the way, how did you stand on the fog and wave back?
Well...
That may have been what your granny claimed...
But we never did anything like that.
Maybe she was just confused?
Brocken Specter.
Sunlight shining from someone's back
may be scattered by clouds or fog...
Which causes your shadow to be projected forward,
leading to a rainbow-like halo to appear around it.
This phenomenon is common in
the German Brocken mountains...
That's what led to some deeming the
mysterious bow "The Brocken Monster."
That's what they said on TV, anyway!
You and that TV again?
So, that means my grandma was fooled by it, and what
she really saw was just the shadow of her own waving?
Well, at any rate, my subordinates will
come to take possession of your car.
You two will ride with me to the police station.
Then, at least let me get my wallet before I go.
Yumi-san?
Ah, about the witch...
We actually just captured them.
What's this?
It isn't here.
Hey, help me look on the other side.
Those bastards!
No way!
They're running!?
Hey!
Did you record their license plate number?
No...
I was going to do that at the station...
Damn!
They're experts on these mountain roads.
No use chasing them now.
What was that?
Huh?
That car just now...
Could it be...
Hey, is this all right!?
Running away like this!
Yeah...
That officer looks stupid.
Not to mention, I'm still on parole.
I could get locked up again over this.
A woman's shriek!?
Idiot!
That's just the screech of tires!
Hey, drive faster!
They're almost on us!
I can't...
The one behind us is coming at max speed!
If I try to outrun that...
Shit!
They're tailgating us!
Hold it...
I know this sound.
I tried to replicate it so many times...
But I failed, no matter how hard I tried tuning my tires and silencers.
It's the witch's shriek!
Hey, this is the police!
Pull over to the side now!
Police...
Detective Sato!
What!?
The witch four years ago was Detective Sato!?
Seriously!?
Yeah.
Even though she never realized it herself...
Her car is actually an FD as well.
But Detective Sato's car isn't white, is it?
Back then, after a car tried to outrun her and
skidded out, she decided to paint her car red.
She thought it was her fault because
white is hard to spot in the fog.
But, could Detective Sato's FD make that kind of a sound?
Yeah, yeah!
That shriek-like sound.
That's actually a bad habit of Miwako's.
When I try to drift without pulling the handbrake...
I find that screaming helps make it a bit easier.
It's a little embarrassing, though...
That's it.
So, she really screamed...
That's definitely a shriek...
No doubt.
That's...
The one being ransomed, Kayoko-chan!
If I can't confirm whether he's carrying a gun or not...
It'll be too dangerous for me to act.
Dad!
Conan-kun's in danger!
I think there's one more suspect.
It's you...
Kanayama-san.
Next Conan's Hint:
Gun
Look forward to the next episode
What's our next episode?
Conan-kun's going to hang out with the culprit for two days!
Eh? What now?