So...
You're Kanayama's good-for-nothing gangster, huh?
Onda Kazuyoshi (48)
Game Software Company President
And you've called me out on his behalf, no?
Oomine Ryousuke (24)
Shut up!
Stop talking bullshit and give us the money!
I've already paid his salary.
That Kanayama's.
But that's only chicken feed!
That's labor abuse—you should pay up, or else!
And what you're doing is called blackmail.
I'll take you to the police!
What's wrong, pal?
Aren't you a black-belt in Judo?
A candidate for the Olympics, wasn't it?
Try to throw me to the cops, punk.
Thanks to Kanayama's games...
You've earned a shitload of money, no?
And you, you can't even operate a computer!
Making two billion yen while paying
Kanayama a mere one-hundred thousand?
The hell are you thinking!?
No...
Our company has had to make a number
of investments to make our games...
Shut up!
Dumbass!
Love is magic, attack the mystery.
On Saturday nights, be sure to click on Conan!
Meet the clumsy kidnapper.
What will be the fate of me, the hostage?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
So lucky!
Thanks for coming with us!
That's right!
It's all thanks to Conan-kun.
To think Creamy Heaven's Dragon Mountain Parfait is 20% off!
Kid's Service
Bring An elementary
school student along
and save!!
20% off
We're really lucky!
While I'm the unlucky one...
All I wanted to do was watch soccer on TV.
The toys department is over there.
Don't go too far, all right?
Just come back when we finish our parfait!
Yeah.
That's right.
No doubt it was Oomine.
He's kidnapped a child.
Please save my Kayoko.
I beg of you!
We will save her, without a doubt.
The child that was kidnapped is Yuuki Kayoko-chan, age 5.
Yes.
I'll be careful.
It's possible that he's armed.
Ma'am, please stay with us.
Y-Yes, sir...
A child was kidnapped...
And the culprit may be carrying a gun...
Any culprit keeping a child hostage...
They would definitely aim to escape a shopping mall...
By car.
Ran, I told you that brat would never get lost.
Guess you're right.
Inspector Megure?
This is the mother of the kidnapped
Kayoko-chan, Yuuki Natsumi-san.
When they plan to accost a car,
kidnappers first hide in a discrete place...
Near pillars and shadows...
And...
A place in the area furthest from the entrance.
That's the one being kidnapped, Kayoko-chan!
Hey!
You're gonna lend me your car!
What are you doing!?
Here...
Goes!
I told you to comply!
Kayoko-chan!
He's here!
Oomine's in the parking lot, over!
Run, quick!
You brat!
Conan-kun!?
Shit!
Now, now...
Everything's all right.
Oomine!
Drop your gun and surrender!
You have nowhere to run!
Don't you dare move, you brat!
If I can't confirm whether he's carrying a gun or not...
It'll be too dangerous for me to act.
Oomine's in the parking lot!
Team, seal off all entrances and exits!
What happened?
How careless!
Stop!
This is the police!
Scram!
Idiot!
It's dangerous—get out of here!
Conan-kun?
The hostage's life is our priority!
Copy?
Yes, sir!
Dad!
Conan-kun's in danger!
Stupid!
You're a hostage, so shut the hell up!
Stinky brat!
Look out!
Now, for our next piece of news...
Ah, that's...
Oomine!
Bastard!
Inspector Megure!
Oh, Chiba?
Kayoko-chan's been rescued.
However...
And please don't be shocked by this, but...
This time, Conan-kun has been...
Conan kun has been kidnapped as a substitute!
I've already known that for a million years now!
And all of you, get over here as quickly as you can!
They lost him, huh?
Seems so.
Last night, at a park near Shibuya-ku, company
president Onda Kazuyoshi-san was found shot dead.
The primary suspect believed to be responsible for the slaying,
Oomine Ryousuke, age 25, is wanted for questioning.
Damn idiots!
I'm only 24!
The suspect appears to have kidnapped a young boy
at Haido's shopping mall and is now fleeing by car.
It is highly probable that suspect Oomine is armed, and the police...
Are you a killer?
Mister.
Damn right!
Got a problem?
Of course I do...
Damn, can't be helped.
Conan was taken?
I'm sorry...
I was with him, but...
Where'd that punk's car go?
This time...
It'll be best for you to not be involved.
Inspector?
The man who kidnapped Conan-kun, this Oomine guy...
He's a gangster near the border of Shinjuku.
He's known for blackmail, violent behavior, and was jailed twice.
The victim, Onda-san...
Was the president of a large game software company...
And was rumored to earn over a billion yen annually.
But, it was said he would underpay his employees
and refuse to pay outsource personnel.
Numerous people had monetary issues with him.
Oomine heard from Kanayama-san, a friend
from Tokyo who worked for Onda-san...
About just how tyrannical the president was.
It seems Oomine was furious after hearing
this, and decided to get his money back.
He killed the president as a result.
The whole incident was caught on tape
by the park's security video camera.
It's highly probable Oomine is still carrying a gun.
Let us do our job here.
We've already set up cordons as well.
Conan-kun...
I'll stay here for a while.
Lemme go.
I'm already unneeded, right?
If I did that...
You'd go talk to the police!
I would not...
You definitely would!
Do I really look like somebody who would do that?
You do!
First, to confirm whether he's armed or not...
Then look for my chance...
And decide whether it'll be fight or flight.
So this is where he abandoned the car?
Right.
Either he's hiding somewhere nearby...
Or he escaped from here.
Search the perimeter thoroughly!
Yes, sir!
What are you doing at a time like this?
Say, Dad!
Well...
In the newspaper, two months ago...
I remember there was a special report on Onda-san's company...
Here.
What do you want to know about?
The man acting as President Onda's subordinate...
As well as Oomine's friend, this Kanayama guy.
Wow, this is convenient!
I just upgraded to wireless LAN last month, did you forget?
Wireless "RAN"?
But you're Mouri Ran!
Game Programmer
aaaaaaaaaa
32nd Games Awards winner.
Hired during our company's own
Original Games Convention.
Youngest programmer
in ONDACK Co.
aaaaaaaaaa
Born in:
Iwate Prefecture
Blood Type: B
HOBBY:
None
aaaaaaa
Kanayama Seiichi
Under ONDACK Brand
- Sasuke VS Monster
- Trio the Brothers
- Detective R. Second
- Zekakakaka
- Drift Drift
Looks like he's developed a lot of games...
He's a genius with games, this guy.
Dad...
Conan-kun...
He's going to be OK, right?
Of course he is.
Damn!
Out of range.
All right, I can do this...
I'm scared!
What!?
I saw a mouse!
There can't be one in here!
What mouse!?
He's not armed...
You're making me sick!
If you're not armed...
Come!
It should be...
This room.
Why did you bring so many keys?
Don't ask questions at a time like this!
What's that sound?
Just get in already!
Bingo.
We can get outta here through that window.
Back then...
Is the person with the pistol your acquaintance?
Not a chance...
Then, who are they?
Why did you know someone else in there?
And, why did that person start shooting?
How should I know that?
Come on, reach up here, quick!
Looks like that asshole gave up.
It's peculiar for them to give up so quickly...
And that explosive sound...
What was it?
Why didn't you make some noise?
They're cops, aren't they?
You're a hostage.
Why wouldn't you yell for help when you see the cops?
Oh, yeah.
Isn't that common sense?
But...
Why did you cover for me and get shot?
You could've just run away yourself.
Well, I guess so...
Isn't that common sense?
Oh well.
Mister...
Are you really a killer?
I just confessed!
How can I be wrong!?
You don't look like one, though...
Lend me your cellphone.
Why?
Hurry!
Professor?
Kanayama Seiichi-san...
I believe?
Kanayama Seiichi (24)
Game Creator
The famous detective Mouri Kogorou-san.
You've taken much longer than I expected.
Sorry to have kept you waiting.
Did you go shopping?
Yeah.
Just a little trip to the convenience store.
Well, it won't do to have you stand out here and talk.
Why don't we go inside?
You must have so much to ask me, mustn't you?
Sure.
As you wish.
Kanayama Seiichi
So, the kid Oomine kidnapped was living at Mouri-san's, huh?
And Oomine hasn't been captured yet.
One would assume a detective like the great Mouri
Kogorou would be out searching for him right now.
In that case...
You would first come to my place.
That's all common logic, isn't it?
I've heard you're an old pal of Oomine.
We had been classmates since middle school.
In Morioka, that is.
Even after I moved to Tokyo, we
still ran into each other occasionally.
Oomine tried to get your money back and
committed that crime because of you.
I do feel deeply sorry for that.
After all, I was the one who badmouthed the president.
He earned a fortune yet paid me so very little.
Just because he was good at Judo, he started to get cocky...
And started relying on violence to deal with things.
Very stingy, that president.
He took the back-margin money himself...
And only left me, the game creator,
a mere three million yen salary!
Excuse me.
Received Log / Sent Log
01 Oomine [Missed]
02 Oomine [Missed]
03 Oomine [Missed]
04 Momoko
05 Kanda
06 Oomine [Missed]
I haven't taken his calls.
You know it, right?
That mark.
Pick it up, when he calls.
What's this?
The police haven't arrived at your apartment already?
Stop saying such stupid things.
Wasn't it you who actually persuaded Oomine, Momoko?
Uemiya Momoko (24)
Onda's Secretary
Why would a secretary like me want the president dead?
You did call the president "Papa."
And even mooched big bucks off him, didn't you?
You're acting cranky just because I dumped you, huh?
Well, that's fine.
Stop goofing around chitchatting and get to work already.
I don't need your advice.
It's best for you to suspect Momoko too.
Onda-san's secretary, huh?
There anyone else?
Let's see.
The vice president, Kanda-san.
Kanda Satoshi (32)
Vice President
That's because Kanda-san was abused by the president.
Abuse?
Power harassment, you mean?
If it were me, I'd have already quit.
Well, there you go...
If you're looking for his accomplice.
I think there's one more suspect.
And an important one.
It's you...
Kanayama-san.
Hey, watch your step...
You hear something?
Over there.
All right, you go look that way.
Got it.
I can't let them take him yet.
Hurry and hide!
Quick!
Hey!
That was dangerous!
Is that you, Professor Agasa?
What're you doing here?
Ah, that, well...
Something came up.
I'm in a big hurry now.
Sorry for speeding by.
I really have to go now.
See you!
It's all good now.
Thank you, Professor.
I'm saved...
Right...
Even if he were caught now...
It wouldn't resolve anything.
This case...
Something's still behind it.
Ran!
Even you're being held hostage!?
Dad!
Murderer Oomine Ryousuke...
Has been defeated by the great detective, Mouri Kogorou!
Oomine-san was likely used by someone else.
There's blood on it...
Don't move!
Or I'll shoot this brat!
Next Conan's Hint:
Yes!
Window Wiping
Look forward to the next episode
Five, six, seven, eight, kyu-kyu-kyu.
(Note: "kyu" is both the
number nine and the
sound of window wiping)
What're you doing?
Wiping the windows.