The president of a game company, Onda Kazuyoshi-san...
Was shot and killed.
Oomine Ryousuke (24)
The shooter, Oomine Ryousuke, became wanted.
Oomine then kidnapped a young girl inside a shopping mall...
And attempted to escape.
I happened to be there, and successfully rescued the girl.
But as a result, I was taken hostage as a substitute.
After getting through the police cordon...
Oomine hid himself in a building's basement.
After I confirmed he wasn't armed...
I planned for my escape.
Suddenly...
Someone began shooting at us in the dark.
At that moment...
I was saved by Oomine, who was injured in the process.
Is this man really a killer?
Or perhaps...
In the case of President Onda's murder...
There's something else going on.
When Detective Takagi almost spotted us...
Professor Agasa sped by as per our request.
Because of him, we were saved.
Right...
I can't allow the police to arrest him just yet.
Not until I've uncovered the truth...
Hidden behind this case.
Love is magic, attack the mystery.
On Saturday nights, be sure to click on Conan!
Today is a peculiar kidnapping case...
I, the hostage, will be revealing the culprit!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Conan-kun!
Are you all right?
Ran-neechan!
I'm so glad!
Conan-kun is safe and sound...
You!
Ran-neechan, wait!
That mister...
He might not be the culprit.
Received Call
Oomine
You can answer that call.
That is what you came here for, no?
It's me!
Oomine, I presume?
Who the hell're you?
My name is Mouri Kogorou.
Mouri Kogorou?
Hand the phone over to Kanayama!
Hey, don't move.
Yes, ma'am...
Let me hear Conan's voice!
That comes first!
Don't order me around, dumbass!
Conan-kun is safe!
No need to worry.
Ran!?
Even you are being held hostage!?
I'm not.
Hand the phone to Kanayama already!
What's going on here?
Here.
He wants you.
Very well.
Kanayama Seiichi (24)
Game Creator
Oomine?
Asshole!
I'm in a pinch here!
Take my call already!
My bad, my bad.
I'll give you the address!
Bring your car over here!
Go ask Momoko for help.
Ask where he is.
I was gonna meet her at the shopping mall...
But then the cops showed up!
Momoko?
Anyway...
Get a car over here!
I gotta get out of Tokyo!
The address...
Just tell him you're at Professor Agasa's house.
Professor Agasa's house?
Don't tell me Professor Agasa's being held hostage too!?
Fine, I'll be there.
That Momoko-san...
Is she the one you just talked to using that?
She was Onda's secretary.
I've had drinks with her a number of times.
With Oomine too.
Mouri-san, go right ahead.
I'm of no use, anyway.
Have you owned that pistol for long?
I bought it.
On the internet.
It said it was an air pistol, but...
Air?
There's a gun maniac who converts metallic
model guns and sells 'em on the net.
But, see...
These aren't sure-fire guns.
Homemade Gun Sale
And the site said the ammo it came with were blanks.
That's why I ordered a revolver with three blanks.
I only intended to scare Onda by carrying it.
Even the instructions that were included said they were blanks.
CAUTION
While these cartridges may appear real,
they are in fact blanks. Blanks do contain
gunpowder, however, so please exercise
caution while handling these items.
DO NOT FIRE AT OTHER PEOPLE!
And, you only realized they were live bullets after firing?
Yeah.
And then?
What happened to the pistol?
I tossed it.
I figured I was in big trouble.
There hasn't been any news to the effect of a weapon being found.
Shall we go there?
Don't be a moron!
When the car gets here, I'm getting outta here!
Kanayama!
Dad!
Murderer Oomine Ryousuke...
Has been defeated by the great detective, Mouri Kogorou!
That'd be great, if it were true.
Oomine-san was likely used by someone else.
What're you talking about, brat?
It looks like Oomine was carrying an air pistol.
That means we have to find that pistol, right?
Come to think of it, the gun still hasn't been found.
All right, let's find it!
First, let's visit the building where the pistol was thrown away.
You said that, when you tossed the gun away,
it sounded like it hit something, right?
Yeah.
Which means...
It's highly probable that it hit a wall.
There!
Over here!
The crack does look fresh.
It's safe to assume the pistol hit that wall.
Judging from the impact, the pistol shouldn't have bounced far.
Probably.
It's a little damp here...
And someone was walking around.
Could it be...
If this "real culprit" does exist and did set up Oomine...
It's likely they would've already hid the weapon.
When you tossed that pistol, did you do anything else near this building?
It's such an honor to see the great
detective Mouri Kogorou-sensei here!
I'm so glad I took this job!
Is that so?
Very well, very well.
I actually wanted to be a private detective.
I'll be quitting this job soon, so...
Will you allow me to be your assistant, Sensei?
Is this the machine that wipes the windows?
That's right.
Don't you dare touch it, brat.
What's with your big attitude, man?
How rude of me!
This goes up and down the railings of the building, right?
That is correct, little prince.
Is it automatic?
Absolutely correct!
Last night...
Did you wipe the windows?
Indeed I did.
For the windows on the street side.
If I were to operate it midday...
The odor from the detergent would
cause trouble for the office workers.
That's why I do it at night.
Which means the damp ground was due to the detergent...
There!
Pretty please, Mouri-sensei?
Over here!
When Oomine-san tossed the gun...
The automatic window wiping machine was in operation.
The gun Oomine-san threw...
Then landed on top of the machine.
And then...
When the cleaning was complete...
It traveled up along with the machine...
Up here to the roof...
And landed here.
Although it does look real...
The ammo is fake.
Because of the gunpowder inside...
It will make the sound of a shot when fired.
But the tip of the cartridge will be
smashed into pieces due to the impact.
Then...
Why is President Onda dead?
Doesn't that mean someone else shot him?
What?
By the real culprit who had hid in the park...
And waited for Oomine-san to fire...
So they could fire a live bullet...
And really kill Onda-san.
I see.
In that case, those three are suspicious.
Game creator, Kanayama Seiichi.
The president's secretary, Uemiya Momoko.
And the vice president, Kanda Satoshi.
Kanayama was arguing with President Onda over money...
Uemiya probably had some sort of trouble from their relationship...
While Kanda was said to be the victim of his power harassment.
But, President Onda himself has had trouble
because of his way of doing business, right?
Oh, I see.
Hey, don't be so cocky, you little brat!
How did you find the homepage of that
website where you bought the gun?
Well, that...
Are you hiding something?
Spit it out!
Momoko...
What?
She said Onda was an Olympics candidate and a master of Judo...
So she suggested I get armed with a pistol.
She then gave me to the link to that gun site.
I see now.
Don't get in the way anymore!
Time for kids to go to bed!
Professor...
There's one more place...
That I need to visit.
Why do you have so many spare keys?
When I first came to Tokyo, I found a job as a security guard here.
I copied them back then.
At that time...
What was that sound?
I see!
Hey!
So that's how it was...
Hey, what are you doing, kid?
Mister, who else knew you worked here as security?
Kanayama, Momoko...
And I guess the vice president, Kanda-san.
Who is this Kanda-san?
He looks after Kanayama a lot.
Kanda Satoshi (32)
Vice President
Kanayama and I went drinking with him before, too.
He's a gentle and nice guy.
Mister...
Have you ever acted before?
What's this, all of a sudden...
Wait, now's not a good time to...
Mouri-san?
I need to speak with the Inspector.
I've heard from Kanayama.
You've met Oomine at Agasa's residence?
Yes.
Inspector-dono...
Oomine is not the culprit.
The real culprit is someone else.
What's that?
Can you call in Uemiya Momoko-san?
Uemiya Momoko (24)
Onda's Secretary
Seems like all of the actors are in place.
What is this all about, Mouri-kun?
Let me explain this in order.
First, this case started with the quarrel
between President Onda and Kanayama-san.
The game Kanayama created was a big hit.
But, despite the enormous profits it generated...
President Onda refused to pay Kanayama more...
Which lead to the beginning of all this.
Furiously as ever, Kanayama-san...
Met up with his buddy Oomine and badmouthed the president.
After hearing him out...
Oomine proclaimed he would threaten President Onda.
At just that moment, Uemiya Momoko-san arrived.
Kanayama-san and Uemiya-san had been
co-workers, and had even dated before.
And after seeing that Momoko-san, Oomine fell in love.
Are you saying I persuaded Oomine-kun?
That's it exactly.
Stop saying stupid things.
You told Oomine about the guns being sold
on that website ran by a gun maniac, and...
It came to my email inbox!
An advertisement for that site.
I merely told him about...
What are you...
Oomine!
Conan!
Don't move!
Or I'll shoot this brat!
Don't move, or else I'll get shot!
You bastard...
It was finally my showtime for a second!
Gather at the wall!
The wall!
Lemme go...
Stop!
It's dangerous!
That was really dangerous...
Kanda-san.
I didn't think...
This happened 'cause the brat just had to jump in...
Oomine...
Prepare yourself.
Please wait a moment.
I haven't finished my speech yet.
Mouri-kun?
Now where was I?
You had just said Uemiya-san was the culprit...
That is not the case.
But you just...
What's more important is: who will
benefit from President Onda's death?
Even with the president dead...
I still won't get any money.
It isn't me, either.
That's why I bothered to report to the
police that Oomine-kun had called me.
In that case, only one person remains...
What?
Why are you looking at me?
You were quite brave.
You dared to wrestle with Oomine, a wanted
suspect, who was armed with a gun.
No...
I tried hard to save everyone...
Or is it really because you knew
what Oomine-san had was an air gun?
Which is because...
You were the one who sold Oomine-san
the gun and the blanks in the first place.
The culprit who killed President Onda...
Kanda-san!
It was you!
Nonsense...
Stop saying such nonsense!
You were the victim of President Onda's power harassment.
Isn't that so, Kanayama-san?
Kanda-san was the target of the president's abuse.
After you heard that Kanayama-san had
a grudge against President Onda...
You decided to use that and planned this murder.
Once Onda-san was out of the picture, you would be president.
Since you collect and toy with model guns as a hobby, you
converted some metallic models into homemade firearms...
And created a website to sell them, whose
address you forwarded to Momoko-san.
As you calculated, Momoko-san did
tell Oomine about your website...
And Oomine-san in turn bought the gun and blanks from you.
You created the blanks by removing the bullets from
the cartridges you smuggled from overseas, right?
Then, at the same time Oomine-san fired the air gun...
You fired your gun that was loaded with live ammunition.
After that, in order to conceal the fact that Oomine-san's
gun contained only blanks...
You had to retrieve the gun.
You tried your best to find the gun, but...
It was nowhere to be found.
Where did you think it went?
It traveled along with the automatic window wiping machine...
And went up to the rooftop of the building.
I see.
That was an impressive deduction you came up with.
But, do you have any evidence?
Something to the effect of me converting
model guns, or searching for the pistol?
If you were there searching for the pistol...
The dirt near the building and the detergent from
the machine would have gotten on your shoes.
And one more thing...
The culprit would have injured his right hand.
After taking Conan as a hostage and fleeing, Oomine-san...
Was shot in a building's basement.
But converted guns...
They're still fragile models.
Here, look.
Thank you.
There's blood on it.
Right!
If you check the blood sample...
You should find that it's from Vice President Kanda.
Serve your time and restart your life.
I'm sorry.
It was because of me that this happened.
It's cool.
This is a chance...
For me to do some good.
That's great.
Think so?
What happened?
Case closed, already.
Yep, great work.
Thanks...
It must've been scary, huh, Conan-kun?
I said I was all right.
Because you've been through so much...
I'll go ahead and treat you to something.
Thank you!
There you are, brat!
You're quite useful, really!
"Bring an elementary student and get half price on
Patisserie Matsui's Miracle Mille Crepe" this time!
I have something else to do, so if you'll excuse me!
Hold it right there!
Why don't you take a discount off of some of your crazy ideas!?
I can get points for this, too!
Awesome!
The sushi are revolving!
Don't move!
Should any of you move even a single step...
I'll inform the police!
I always thought Mouri-kun was the God of Death, but actually...
It might be you.
For the poisoned plate to not be
taken by anyone else along the way...
Is there a way to ensure that it reaches the victim?
Next Conan's Hint
Clockwise
What does clockwise" mean?
Look forward to the next episode
Was it left or right?
Just leave it to the clocks.