Sushi, sushi, we're so happy~
Because we beat Professor at a game~
He has to treat us to sushi~
Snapper, flounder, squid and all~
Well, it doesn't matter if it's squid, snapper, or
flounder—they have everything you could want.
This restaurant has a very extensive menu.
The low prices and tasty food have given them a great reputation.
An extensive menu...
And it's cheap and tasty!
It's like the sushi shop of my dreams!
Say Professor...
Could this be the type of sushi that's...
Known to revolve?
Love is magic, attack the mystery.
On Saturday nights, be sure to click on Conan!
At everyone's favorite revolving sushi shop...
An atmosphere-changing case occurs!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
As expected, it was a revolving sushi shop.
Didn't you say that, if we beat your game...
You would take us to a high-class sushi restaurant?
That's not fair, Professor!
I only had two bowls of rice this morning, just to save room for this!
Isn't that already a meal?
Well...
The professor really should have taken into
account everyone's feelings of anticipation.
You should also consider the feelings of my wallet.
Well, don't be so disappointed.
It really is delicious!
Have you guys ever had revolving sushi before?
Not me.
Ayumi neither.
My Dad has always said that, if you're from Tokyo,
you should eat at a real sushi restaurant!
While he may be right about that...
With this being your first time, it may surprise you.
Awesome!
The sushi's revolving!
It really is!
Is it really all right to eat from whichever plate we choose?
Yeah, as much as you'd like.
Just remember not to place plates you've taken back on the belt.
Not only is it bad manners...
You pay for how much you ate and which plates you took.
But wait...
What if the sushi I want never comes around?
You can just order it from the menu if that's the case.
Just tell the Professor what you want, and
he can order it from the touch screen.
Miso soup and chawanmushi are available too.
What sushi would you like to order?
In that case, I want ten orders of eel!
As for me, I'd like to try the silver mackerel.
Ayumi wants salted salmon roe!
Hey now, one at a time.
Isn't that it!?
Such delicious-looking eel!
Itadakima—
No, you can't!
That's someone else's order.
Here, when the sushi you've ordered makes its way to you...
There's a beep to indicate it.
It's here, it's here!
My eel!
Itadakimasu!
Delicious!
It's here!
Salmon roe-san!
This is great!
Delicious, isn't it?
Delicious, delicious!
I guess we made the right choice in coming here, huh?
Yeah.
While it may not be able to compare to a real sushi restaurant...
There's nothing like finding a place
where everyone can enjoy themselves.
Well, I won't hold back either.
I already took a lot down for Conan-kun.
See?
It's all salmon roe...
Ayumi loves salmon roe!
Conan-kun, eat up too!
Even so, this may be too much...
Yummy!
How so?
I'm stuffed, I'm stuffed!
It was really tasty, wasn't it?
They even have pudding for dessert!
Seriously?
Geez, what are you doing?
My bad.
Huh?
There's a weird picture on the bottom of the plate.
That's the mark used for the automatic recycling.
A sensor is used to read the microcode...
So that plates that have circled for a while are automatically recycled.
This is useful because of how difficult it is to
tell when sushi was made by sight alone...
And due to it being even more difficult to
remember what each plate looks like.
Hey now, you brats.
Agatsuma Ryuuzou (43)
Customer
You purposely dropped those plates in order to
cause confusion when it's time to pay, didn't you?
I wouldn't do something like that.
Ah, my apologies.
This is their first time visiting a revolving sushi restaurant.
Their first time?
I bet you always eat at those fancy sushi places, don't you?
You have better taste than this guy's undiscerning tongue.
Right, Flounder Guy?
What?
Oh, isn't this the flounder that your wife liked so much?
Aizono Osamu (32)
Customer
It's flounder.
Aren't you going to take it?
Flouunnder!
I see, I see.
This is actually sea bass, isn't it?
Sir, please stop.
You're becoming a disturbance toward the other customers.
Namiki Danji (39)
Manager
Should you insist on continuing...
I'll...
Shut up!
You're just a small-time shopkeeper that
can only get by with making sushi!
You have no right to criticize me!
That has nothing to do with this...
I could ruin this little restaurant of yours...
I'm a reputable food critic.
If I were to include a little write-up on you in my article...
I could have you closed down within a week!
Just like...
The restaurant of the who's eating so suspicious in the corner...
Takemura Sakiko (51)
Customer
That old lady over there!
And what's with you?
Don't stare at me!
Sir, there will be no charge for your meal today.
Would you please leave?
Free, is it?
Well then, I'll be sure to eat a bit more before I head out.
Sir!
What an annoying geezer.
He ruined the atmosphere.
Let's go.
We may as well.
Please pay the price of 8700 yen.
These kids sure can eat...
Oh, well...
Thank you very much for your patronage!
But you should bring us back again sometime, Professor...
When there aren't any disruptive customers, preferably.
Sir?
Are you all right, sir?
What the...
Don't tell me it's food poisoning!
Hey, stop eating!
Put yours back too!
Yeah!
Let's go to another shop!
Don't move!
If anyone leaves this place, I'll inform the police about it later.
T-The police?
Boy...
There's the scent of bitter almond in his mouth.
This man died from cyanide poisoning.
What?
Poison?
Furthermore...
There are grains of rice stuck to his fingers, which means...
The probability of the poison being in his sushi is high.
In this unique scenario...
There are any number of chances to accomplish it.
In any case, Professor...
Hurry and call the police and an ambulance.
Got it!
And you, Manager...
Stop the conveyor belt immediately!
It's you again...
Conan-kun.
Well...
I used to think it was Mouri-kun who jinxed those cases...
But it might actually be you, I suppose...
No, that's...
We aren't some sort of jinx!
We're the Detective Boys!
It's not our fault that these cases happen!
You could say that these cases call out to us!
What's with this proud act?
And?
Was the poison really in the sushi?
Well, considering we haven't checked
the victim's stomach contents yet...
We can't be sure yet, but...
According to the investigation team...
The plate the victim last held...
Had poison on this part of the plate, so...
Most likely...
I see.
The culprit pretended to take a plate,
but instead smeared poison on it...
And let the plate continue traveling on the belt
so that it would eventually reach the victim.
Yeah.
When the victim took the plate, the poison moved to his fingers...
So later, when he held the sushi between his fingers to eat...
After the incident, did everyone stay where they were?
Yeah.
The people in the kitchen didn't move either, did they?
I instructed them to stay where they were, as you asked.
Then, let us conduct a body search!
If our theory is correct, the culprit should
still have a container with poison inside.
Or, at the very least, a handkerchief
or similar object with poison on it!
Check all the customers that were sitting along the
same conveyor belt as well as the chefs operating it!
Yes, sir!
That's right...
Especially...
Those who have history with the victim...
These three need to be checked thoroughly.
Nothing!?
Not a container with poison?
Or even something like a handkerchief covered in poison?
Yeah, not on anyone or anywhere here...
That can't be...
The culprit shouldn't have had the opportunity to dispose of it.
Why couldn't they locate it?
Moreover...
Is there some way to ensure that only the
victim would handle the poisoned plate?
A method that prevents anyone else from taking
the plate and only targets the victim...
Food critic?
The poisoned Agatsuma-san was a food critic?
Yeah.
He's famous for his biting reviews.
It seems restaurants that he awarded
positive reviews to were actually good.
That made him quite popular with the readers.
On the other hand...
Restaurants that received harsh critique from him...
Always saw a distinct decrease in their customer
base, and some were even forced to close.
It's possible that this was the motive for the murder.
The question is...
How did the culprit get the victim to take the poisoned plate?
That's true.
The poisoned plate could be brought to Agatsuma-san
automatically by the conveyor belt system, but...
To ensure that he was the one who took the plate...
Well, since there were several customers sitting
along the same conveyor belt as the victim...
Adding in the chefs in the kitchen...
We can only investigate one by one, I suppose.
Ah, no.
There should've only been three
people who could poison the plate.
Three people?
Yes.
Before Agatsuma-san ate from the poisoned plate,
he got into a conflict with the restaurant manager.
That old guy was talking real loud!
It was really scary!
He was even shouting at other customers!
Due to that, the customers sitting opposite the victim became upset...
And as they were preparing to leave, the victim collapsed.
About five minutes prior to him collapsing,
none of the customers took any plates.
I see.
Over five minutes, the conveyor belt could rotate numerous times.
That's why it wouldn't be possible to poison a plate
that Agatsuma-san didn't take during the first round.
Which means that, the most suspicious parties
were those working unseen in the kitchen.
No...
Because he was causing such a distraction,
almost no plates were taken from the belt...
The workers say that newly made sushi
couldn't be put on the belt in question.
In other words, the only ones who could put
poison on the plate after the disturbance are...
The one sitting to the left of the victim, that man.
The one sitting six places to the right of the victim, this older woman.
The one who rushed to the victim after he collapsed...
This restaurant manager—it's these three.
Isn't that right, Detective Takagi?
Yeah...
But, why are you including the restaurant manager?
Well, see...
The restaurant manager got into an argument
with the victim before he collapsed, didn't he?
The argument occurred near Agatsuma-san's seat...
So the two of them must have been standing quite close.
Also, those three...
Seem to have a special relationship with the victim.
You had an earlier conflict with Agatsuma-san at this restaurant?
Yes.
I tend to boast when I'm with my wife.
I said that the flounder here was not only cheap, but also very tasty.
And then, he came up and interrupted me, saying...
"That definitely isn't flounder."
"It's sea bass, idiot."
Was it sea bass?
I noticed it after I gave it a proper taste.
I see.
You were humiliated in front of your wife, is that it?
That's not all!
I'm not sure how he did it, but...
He tracked down my food blog and
started saying things in the comments.
"This guy has no taste."
"This blog is simply garbage!"
But it's not like I had any thoughts of revenge.
However, your seat was right next to Agatsuma-san's.
It would have been easy for you to have...
Even though I was next to him, I was on his left!
Since this sushi belt goes from right to left...
It would've been impossible for me to have poisoned his plate!
And it does revolve right to left?
Yes.
It revolves clockwise.
Following this child's instructions, we already stopped it.
If that's the case...
Even if he had put the poison on the plate...
It would've taken an entire round before it came to Agatsuma-san.
Yes.
And the chances are high of Agatsuma-san not taking the
poisoned sushi plate after it'd already gone around once.
That said, it would be different for someone sitting to his right.
Hold it right there!
Even if I poisoned the plate...
I wouldn't know for sure if that good-for-nothing would take it!
Good-for-nothing?
So, you really do have a previous connection to Agatsuma-san.
So what?
I was once the owner of a sushi shop...
But that man's reviews caused it to close down!
Close down?
Due to Agatsuma-san's reviews?
Yeah.
That man...
He was once a frequent customer, but...
Then he suddenly wrote that the taste deteriorated
and wasn't even as tasty as packaged sushi!
Is that true?
Nothing could be done...
Our sushi chef quit because of old age...
And the chef who was supposed to
replace him suddenly passed on the job!
Could it be that the replacement chef was the manager?
Yeah, the chef at the restaurant I previously worked at knew her...
It was a direct request from him.
But, before I was to start work there, I injured my wrist.
I couldn't match the sushi I'd made before...
So I had to decline.
What happened to your wrist?
I was trying to intervene in a fight between two customers.
In the end, some tendons in my wrist were cut.
One of those customers...
Was that Agatsuma-san, which is how we're connected.
Well, it was because of him that I had to give up being a chef.
But I could never forget the smell of rice and
vinegar, which is why I became a manager.
Even with that, I'd never think about poisoning him.
But, you were next to him prior to his collapse, no?
While that's true...
I didn't touch any plates on the belt.
And as the lady here said...
Even if I had gotten poison on the plate...
How could I be sure he'd take it?
That's...
Couldn't it just be something he liked?
If it was something he liked, he would likely take it.
For Genta-kun, it'd be eel!
If some came my way, I'd definitely not let it go!
Did Agatasuma-san have any favorites, or...
No, nothing in particular...
Well, even if he did, it wouldn't be of any consequence.
Even if it were the victim's favorite food...
Whether he took it or not would depend entirely on his mood then.
You could never be 100% sure which sushi he would take.
Of course, it would be a different story...
Should this have been a random murder.
That's true.
But, can it be done?
Is there a way to make only Agatasuma-san take the poisoned plate?
That's right, the menu!
You would definitely take down something you've ordered.
Order?
Yes.
Once you've selected something from the touch-screen...
The order will be placed on a bowl
labeled "reserved " and onto the belt.
When it reaches your seat, a beep sounds as a reminder.
I see.
Then, the one sitting to the right of the victim, Takamura-san...
Impossible!
Even if his order did come around...
I still wouldn't have been able to poison it!
That guy wearing the hat was sitting next to him.
I wouldn't know which of them ordered it!
Besides, I couldn't see their touch-screen from my seat...
So I couldn't know what it was they ordered anyway, now could I?
Then, the one who could see it...
Would be the one sitting next to him, Aizono-san.
Please, just hold on a second.
Didn't I say it earlier?
I was sitting to his left.
The sushi comes around from the right, doesn't it?
Even if I had seen what Agatsuma-san ordered on the touch-screen...
Wouldn't he have taken it before it reached me?
That's true...
Besides...
I'm not the only one who could see the touch-screen.
The manager could too!
From after my argument with Agatsuma-san until he collapsed...
The manager was standing right over our shoulders!
Is that really true?
Yes.
Because he was causing such a disturbance...
I said his meal would come free of
charge and asked him nicely to leave.
He said he'd eat more now that it was free.
To ensure he didn't cause any more
trouble, I stood watch behind him.
Well, while I was watching, he didn't order anything.
You can confirm that with the restaurant computer.
Check it out.
Yes, sir.
Say, Officer...
Aren't you forgetting something?
Despite already being put through a body search...
And with you finding no poison container...
Or even a handkerchief with poison on it...
You still continue to suspect us.
The culprit must have already escaped with the crowd.
That's why you couldn't find any containers housing poison.
In other words...
Unless we locate the culprit...
We won't be able to determine how Agatsuma-san was targeted.
No...
The culprit is most likely among those three.
First, the person to the left of Agatsuma-san: Aizono Osamu-san.
If it had been Aizono-san, he would've known what
Agatsuma-san had ordered from the touch-screen.
However...
The sushi goes from right to left.
Before he could poison the plate,
Agatsuma-san would've already taken it.
If it was the person sitting to the right of
Agatsuma-san and us, Takemura Sakiko-san...
It would be possible for her to poison the
plate before Agatsuma-san took it.
But, she can't see the touch-screen from her seat...
As for the manager standing behind
Agatsuma-san, Namiki Danji-san...
He was able to see the touch-screen.
However, Namiki-san didn't move from behind Agatsuma-san...
He couldn't have come into contact with the sushi plate.
Just which one is the culprit here?
And...
Just how...
Did they target Agatsuma-san, with the poisoned plate?
All that sushi...
Can I eat them all?
I see now.
This is a trick that can only be accomplished with sushi!
Next Conan's Hint
Method of Eating Sushi
Look forward to the next episode
First, you have to catch the fish...
You sure you start there?
We'll be starting at 5:30 PM next time!