Because Professor Agasa was treating, we went out for sushi...
But we ended up at a revolving sushi shop.
At first, Genta and the others were disappointed...
But they soon understood the charm of revolving sushi...
And began enjoying their favorite dishes.
However, a customer next to us named Agatsuma-san...
Agatsuma Ryuuzou (43)
Customer
Started saying mean things to us and the other customers.
Even the manager was harassed in the process.
We felt uncomfortable, and decided to leave, but...
Agatsuma-san suddenly yelled and collapsed to the floor.
There was the scent of bitter almond emanating from his mouth...
Murder by poison.
Three people had history with him and were natural suspects.
The one who'd had a dispute with Agatsuma-san
in this very shop - Aizono Osamu-san.
The woman who had to close her sushi shop due to the review
from food critic Agatsuma-san - Takemura Sakiko-san.
The manager who was caught in Agatsuma-san's fight and
injured his wrist - the former chef, Namiki Danji-san.
However, after the body search, none of those
three were discovered to be carrying poison.
Where did the poison go?
And how did the culprit only target
Agatsuma-san with the poisoned plate?
Love is magic, attack the mystery.
On Saturday nights, be sure to click on Conan!
A case at a revolving sushi restaurant...
It's showtime for the Detective Boys!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
But, can it be done?
Is there a way to make only Agatsuma-san take the poisoned plate?
That's right, the menu!
You would definitely take down something you've ordered.
Order?
Namiki Danji (39)
Manager
Yes.
Once you've selected something from the touch-screen...
The order will be placed on a bowl labeled
"reserved" and then put onto the belt.
When it reaches your seat, a beep sounds as a reminder.
I see!
Then, the one sitting to the right of the victim, Takemura-san...
Takemura Sakiko (51)
Customer
Impossible!
Even if his order did come around...
I still wouldn't have been able to poison it!
That guy wearing the hat was sitting next to him.
I wouldn't know which of them ordered it!
Besides, I couldn't see their touch-screen from my seat...
So I couldn't know what it was they ordered anyway, now could I?
Then, the one who could see it...
Would be the one sitting next to him, Aizono-san.
Aizono Osamu (32)
Customer
Please, just hold on a second.
Didn't I say it earlier?
I was sitting to his left.
The sushi comes around from the right, doesn't is?p
Even if I had seen what Agatsuma-san ordered on the touch-screen...
Wouldn't he have taken it before it reached me?
That's true...
Besides...
I'm not the only one who could see the touch-screen.
The manager could, too!
From after my argument with Agatsuma-san until he collapsed...
The manager was standing right over our shoulders!
Is that really true?
Yes.
Because he was causing such a disturbance...
I said his meal would come free of
charge and asked him nicely to leave.
He said he'd eat more if it was free, so...
To ensure he didn't cause anymore
trouble, I stood watch behind him.
Well, while I was watching, he didn't order anything.
You can confirm that with the restaurant computer.
Check it out.
Yes, sir.
Say, Officer...
Aren't you forgetting something?
Despite already being put through a body search...
And with you finding no poison container...
Or even a handkerchief with poison on it...
You still continue to suspect us.
The culprit must have already escaped with the crowd.
That's why you couldn't find any containers housing poison.
In other words...
Unless we locate the culprit...
We won't be able to determine how Agatsuma-san was targeted.
Inspector!
I've checked out the computer...
And there was no order from Agatsuma-san.
Left?
Left...?
The man that was killed...
I think he was left-handed.
Because on the tips of his left hand's fingers...
There were two or three grains of rice stuck to them.
Come to think of it, I saw him eating with his left hand!
That's right!
He was picking up his sushi with his left hand.
I saw it too!
I see...
If he was left-handed...
And you put poison on the left side of most of the plates...
It would be possible to make him touch it that way, right?
Yeah.
All right.
Check all plates on the belt and see if
there's any poison on them as well.
Yes, sir.
Forensics, if you would...
Roger.
But...
Is that deduction correct?
The culprit probably made sure that only Agatsuma-san was
left handed among us before applying the poison, but...
What if another left-handed customer came in later?
Besides...
Left-handed or not, most kids...
Still pick up plates with both hands.
And then, where did the poison go?
Without a container or cloth-like
material, it would be difficult to poison...
There's something next to Agatsuma-san's cup...
The corner of a plastic packet?
Huh?
Could this be...
What?
Even though there were many plates on the belt
when Agatsuma-san took the poisoned plate...
Were any of the other plates poisoned?
Not a single one.
In that case, it's as if the victim were hypnotized...
To take only the plate laced with poison.
Maybe there was a message card on the plate?
Something like, "This is a present for you!"
I wouldn't take a plate like that.
It sounds eerie.
Well, there wasn't any card.
Oh?
If there had been one, the victim would still have it.
I don't care about any of that.
I'm hungry now...
But we just ate!
All of that sushi...
Can I eat all of it?
Of course not!
But it'll just be thrown away!
Isn't that a waste?
That's it!
That's how it was done!
Ai-kun...
Could you lend me a handkerchief?
I need to wipe my glasses.
Then, use one of the restaurant's hand wipes.
They're by the entrance.
Wait...
That was...
I see, now...
This is a trick that can only be accomplished with sushi!
In that case, the culprit is that person...
To be able to poison only Agatsuma-san, while
using this trick to dispose of the evidence...
A clever trick centered around this revolving sushi's special system.
Say, Officers...
Are you still suspecting us?
It's understandable for you to suspect us due
to our conflicts with Agatsuma-san, but...
If the only plate that was poisoned
was the one Agatsuma-san took...
I think it would've been impossible
for us to have predicted that.
But...
You three did have a chance to poison the plate...
Well then, how about you please try to explain it!
How did we force that man to take
the only plate laced with poison?
Or, what?
Do any of us look like the type of cold-
blooded killer who would kill at random?
No, we don't mean...
And even if we wanted to apply poison, we
don't have any container for that, right?
If one of us were the culprit, something
like that would still be here!
Considering from the time when that man
collapsed to when you got here...
None of us moved!
Like I said earlier...
The culprit must've been one of the customers who already left.
That also explains why no containers housing poison were found.
Which means...
Someone who is long gone left the poisoned plate with
the intention of committing a random murder.
Agatsuma-san just had the unfortunate luck of taking that plate.
That's...
It certainly was bad luck.
Using my voice without warning again...
But I'm not talking about the murdered Agatsuma-san.
I mean the snickering culprit who thought they had succeeded.
Because not only the method by which
Agatsuma-san was murdered...
But also the trick used to get rid of the poison...
Will soon be exposed!
By me, who came here by chance...
And my humble deduction!
Then, it's true? The culprit is among them!
That's right, just as you police suspected.
Someone who had a grudge against Agatsuma-san...
One of those three!
Hey, what's wrong with you?
Saying things like that out of the blue?
Just because you're a little large doesn't mean
you can bluff like you're some great detective!
No...
Size doesn't matter, anyway.
Did you see it?
One of us put poison on that plate?
No, I didn't see it.
Then, what?
However, that's how it was.
Because the one who did it was Agatsuma-san himself.
Professor, please act more like a detective.
But, Agasa-san...
If the one who put poison on the plate was the victim himself...
Wouldn't this be a suicide?
No, what I mean is that the poison wasn't only on the plate...
But also on something he touched before he took the plate.
That was why only Agatsuma-san's plate had poison on it.
But, what's that "something"?
What was it?
Hey, you guys.
When your favorite sushi comes around in a revolving sushi shop...
What do you pick up before taking the plate?
Let's see...
I pick up my chopsticks first.
I pick up my cup to drink.
I pick up the soy sauce bottle and pour some.
No, I don't mean before taking your first plate.
But instead what you pick up each time you finish any plate.
Genta would definitely do this.
Me?
Conan-kun...
All of the things at Agatsuma-san's seat were
tested, and none of them had poison.
So no matter what he picked up before taking the plate...
Then, what's at Mitsuhiko's seat, but not Genta's?
You're not listening...
Ah, chopsticks!
Genta-kun's seat doesn't have chopsticks!
Genta-kun used his hands to eat, so...
My Dad told me before!
If you're from Tokyo, you gotta eat sushi with your hands!
Then, after using your hands, there's
something you'd want to pick up.
Something I'd pick up?
I'd pick up my fingers and lick them.
And after licking your fingers?
Let's see, after that...
I see.
The hand wipe.
Since you're directly touching the sushi
rice and toppings with your fingers...
Before taking the next plate...
You'd want to wipe off the oil, water,
and sticky rice with the hand wipe.
And the poison was placed in the hand wipe, right?
That's the case, right, Professor?
Yeah.
But there wasn't a hand wipe at Agatsuma-san's seat.
But you can see some traces of it, right?
This?
Yes, it's from what you can pick up for
free at the entrance of the shop...
Traces of the plastic packet for a disposable hand wipe.
I see.
The culprit likely put the poison into the
packet of the hand wipe beforehand...
Using something like a syringe.
I see!
Taking a plate after wiping your
hand with the poisoned hand wipe...
And then using those same fingers
to eat sushi would result in death.
That way, only your plate would have poison on it!
Yes, that's correct.
However...
Before Agatsuma-san was poisoned, he ate a lot of sushi.
Why didn't he come across the poisoned hand wipe earlier?
It was switched out at some point.
Possibly when he was arguing with the manager.
Ah, but...
If someone happened to touch your hand wipe...
Wouldn't you notice?
And say, "What are you doing?"
And if we suppose the culprit knew Agatsuma-san
would put the hand wipe down next to him?
But people can vary on where they put something down...
No, Agatsuma-san was left-handed.
Every time he used the hand wipe after eating,
he'd naturally put it down on his left side, right?
That's right, the one sitting to the left of Agatsuma-san...
Aizono-san.
The hand wipe was placed right next to you.
Sitting to the left of Agatsuma-san,
If you pretend the poisoned wipe
is your own and put it next to his...
Switching them would be no trouble at all.
What are you saying?
If that's the case, where did it go?
That poisoned hand wipe!
Was I carrying anything like that, Officer?
No...
We conducted a body search, but didn't find anything.
See?
If you insist on naming me as the culprit...
Then first explain how the poisoned
hand wipe disappeared on its own!
It didn't disappear on its own.
You made it happen!
By using something that automatically removes
plates after a certain amount of time...
This revolving sushi's transport system!
I see!
The revolving sushi here automatically removes
dishes that have been on the belt for too long.
He used this system for his trick.
Yes.
He likely did it when Agatsuma-san was poisoned and collapsed;
while everyone was focusing their attention on him.
If he wrapped Agatsuma-san's hand wipe around the packet
and poisoned wipe, and then put them on a plate...
No one around them would notice because
both the hand wipe and rice are white.
While it's true that the hand wipes could be
disposed of by the belt, would it work?
Putting a plate back on the belt is bad manners, and
someone would've noticed something this outrageous.
Whether they noticed or not, everyone was doing the same thing.
Everyone?
They were saying, "It's food poisoning!"
"Don't eat that!"
"Put your plate back."
Since everyone was doing it, no one cared.
But wasn't the conveyor belt stopped immediately?
Yes...
I stopped it about two or three
minutes after Agatsuma-san collapsed.
Wouldn't it be strange for the machine
to dispose of it in such a short time?
It's true that if it were a plate that had just been
removed, it would take a while to be recycled, but...
If it had been switched with the first plate you had taken...
The machine would scan the microcode and
think it had been on the belt for too long.
Then, it'd be recycled immediately.
Where is the disposed sushi placed?
Well, it's in the kitchen waste bin.
Right, check that waste bin now!
The poisoned hand wipe and packet must be in there!
Yes, sir!
Aizono-san...
If your fingerprints are found on the packet...
That will be conclusive evidence.
If you are our culprit...
Your motive would be the argument you had with
Agatsuma-san in this shop previously, correct?
Yes...
If I recall, that was about you being corrected after
confusing sea bass with flounder in front of your wife.
Yeah, I had a cold at the time, so my taste was off.
But that's not the reason I had gotten it wrong.
The sea bass had been switched onto the more
expensive flounder plate, that was why.
Switched?
It was that Agatsuma!
He saw me showing off in front of my wife and wanted to bully me...
So he switched the flounder and sea bass on purpose!
Afterwards, he visited my food blog and
wrote demeaning comments on it everyday.
Even though my wife told me to pay him no mind...
I just couldn't forgive him!
That bastard with a rotten heart...
He said whatever he wanted about
food just because he's a food critic!
So that's the reason you poisoned him?
Yeah...
Since then, nothing I've eaten has tasted good.
In the end, my wife ended up divorcing me too.
I only loved to eat...
I only wanted to see my wife's happy face while
eating food from restaurants I recommended...
But that man...
But mister, did you know?
The one who stained what you loved...
Was you, yourself.
The stain that can never be wiped away...
The poison known as "murder."
Afterwards, the packet and poisoned hand wipe were
found in the waste bin, and the case was closed.
The sushi that had stopped has likely begun revolving again.
But I don't think I'll have any for now.
Now, revolving sushi only reminds me of this annoying case...
Well, even though I won't be having any revolving sushi...
Yummy!
This restaurant is good, too!
Yeah!
It's addictive.
Two eel plates for me.
Sushi has always been a proud part of
Japanese culinary culture around the world.
It's no wonder we Japanese enjoy eating it so much.
Come to think of it, there's a new one in front of the train station.
A revolving sushi shop.
Really?
Then, let's have the Professor take us there next time!
That's a good idea.
Let's go, let's go!
That will be 12,500 yen, please.
Did you make some sort of mistake, or...
The fruit parfait was tasty.
So was Ayumi's pudding à la mode!
I had all of the desserts, and they were great!
Did we have parfait and pudding, too?
Yes.
They're slightly more expensive than the sushi is.
That's it!
I've got a good idea.
Why don't we make every Saturday Sushi Day?
Good idea!
Ayumi agrees!
All right!
Detective Boys - Saturday is for revolving sushi!
Yeah!
Hey now...
My eyes are revolving, too.
That's because you were stingy in the beginning.
A Nationwide Kojima-san Competition?
Don't tell me, Genta's dad is also...
One of our suspects?
Next Conan's Hint
Kojima-san
Next time, Genta's dad will makes his debut!
Look forward to the next episode
Not the culprit, not the culprit...
OK, cut!