A Nationwide Kojima-san Competition?
You're taking part?
I mean, your dad is?
Yeah.
Seems like he got in through a fish shrine!
Fish shrine?
What's that?
He meant "form screening."
They determine the participants by screening their
application forms with their pictures and profiles.
My dad must've been chosen because he's the greatest man!
I've never met him, but does that really sound like Genta's dad?
So?
What kind of prize does he get if he wins?
The letter that was sent mentioned a cash prize.
The amount was a one with seven zeroes behind it.
Seven zeroes?
That's ten million yen, isn't it?
Awesome!
So, who organized it?
Orphanize?
Organize! I mean, who sent that letter?
It was sent from Nichiuri TV.
But instead of the money, my dad seems
to want the boar scroll bonus prize more.
If it was really sent by Nichiuri TV, it shouldn't be a scam, but...
The bonus prize is huge.
So, there's a boar drawn on the scroll?
Yeah, when I saw the photo in the letter,
it was a black and white painting.
Even though I thought it wasn't a big deal...
My dad is a big fan of boars.
He said he wanted to hang it in the alcove.
He also said the painter's name sounded
like "Thank You," so he loved it.
"Thank You"?
Genta, maybe it's the money that's considered a bonus.
The ten million yen is just a bonus?
Love is magic, attack the mystery.
On Saturday nights, be sure to click on Conan!
Talk about unexpected!
Genta's dad is one of the suspects and is in a huge pinch!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
It's worth fifty million yen?
This scroll is?
Yeah, if it was really made by the legendary
ink-and-wash painter - Sankyuu Shounin.
But this pattern...
I think I've seen it before.
Ayumi too.
My dad said the same thing.
That's called "bush, clover, and boar."
It's one of the patterns on the flower cars.
And?
Why would a replica of the flower card be worth so much?
When people first found out about this painting...
Sankyuu claimed it was only a random doodling, but...
They then found two more scrolls by Sankyuu
with the deer and the butterfly on them...
Causing their value to skyrocket.
Together, you get "boar-deer-butterfly,"
which is considered good luck.
Actually, there was once a young entrepreneur who
bought those with all of his pocket money...
He ended up raking in huge profits and success,
which added to the value of the scrolls.
So it really is a scroll that brings luck!
But since one of the scrolls is the prize, does
that mean he sold it? That entrepreneur.
No, if he had sold it then the media would have covered it...
So I think he still has it.
Now, what was that entrepreneur's name...
Kojima Gonsaku.
He's the president of the Kojima Group, and
the sponsor of this Kojima-san Competition.
"Kojima Group"...
You mean the rich guy who owns all
those railways and department stores?
That's right.
And since he lost two of the three scrolls...
He said the last one is useless to him...
And has decided to give it away as a prize in this competition.
That's what he wrote on his blog.
He wanted it to go to another Kojima-san.
It's lucky you're a Kojima.
So, was that letter sent directly to your house?
No, it was sent to another nearby Kojima's house.
Since the blog said anyone named Kojima could enter...
They asked my dad if he was interested.
So?
What will they have to do in order to win?
Various things.
A strength test...
A singing contest...
And a kanji writing test, it seems.
I see.
They want a Kojima-san who's strong in every aspect.
That sounds tough.
But my dad's singing is fine.
Even better than Conan over here!
Isn't that setting the bar too low?
Will Genta-kun's dad be all right?
If you put it that way...
Hey...
So, whoever gets the highest total points
between the three tests wins, right?
Nope, there's more to it than that.
Those who pass the three tests report to the 5th studio.
They'll determine the winner in front of us spectators.
With a trivia game!
OK, all five machines checked.
So they'll just play a trivia game in the end.
Oh, so those are the Kojima-san's who are participating.
How was the competition?
I don't give a damn anymore.
The test was to do as many push-ups as you could in three minutes.
I gave it my best.
I did over 180 and still got eliminated.
Well, whoever passes this must be a monster.
Genta-kun's dad is going to be all right, isn't he?
He'll easily win.
Oh, looks like more Kojima-san's are coming.
I didn't think I'd get eliminated in the singing round.
Oh well, it just can't be done.
Even this guy who's won consecutive singing awards got eliminated.
Don't be so upset.
Seems like you needed the voice of Presley to pass this round.
By Presley, did he mean the kung fu movie actor?
That's Bruce Lee.
They're referring to the king of Rock 'n' Roll, Elvis Presley.
Will he be all right?
Genta-kun's dad...
Probably...
Why!? Why me!?
Calm down.
There's another group.
Isn't this weird?
I aced the Level 1 Kanji Aptitude Test, so
how is it possible that I got eliminated?
My answers were all perfect!
Maybe they weren't totally perfect...
So, could you write these?
Could you write the kanji for "rose" and "melancholy"!?
Ah, no...
Hey; Genta, your dad...
Probably...
No chance...
Ah, phone.
Ah, it's from dad!
Hello?
Genta speaking.
Seriously?
You're one of the three finalists?
Really?
Awesome!
Everyone's cheering for you, so be sure to nail this one!
But how strange...
There are five seats for the finalists...
Why did they only pick three?
President Kojima...
The TV network producer is complaining.
They said we can't do a show this way.
Kojima Gonsaku (71)
Kojima Group President
Don't mind them.
In any case, did you show it to those three finalist?
I'm asking if you've shown them the piece of paper I prepared.
Ah, yes.
But all three of them responded to it differently.
No matter.
Just tell me how they pronounced it.
They were...
Kojima Bunta (33)
Participant
Number 35, Kojima Bunta-san answered "happyakuichi" - 801.
Kojima Genji (32)
Participant
Number 84, Kojima Genji-san answered "shakuhachi" - bamboo flute.
Kojima Gankichi (34)
Participant
Number 147, Kojima Gankichi-san answered "ippin" - first class.
President?
Looks like he's exposed his tail.
Tail?
Using money to draw him out was a success.
Where's that piece of paper now?
Ah, yes...
In this envelope.
All right.
I'll handle things from here.
You may go.
But, president...
I shall go to his waiting room and extend
my welcome to this man personally.
To the winner of the Kojima-san Competition.
It's almost time.
My dad should be showing up at any moment.
Someone's coming.
It's just a Nichiuri TV staff member.
Looks like it.
I apologize for any inconvenience...
But due to a problem on our side, the Kojima-san Competition...
Is officially cancelled.
That smudge on his sleeve...
A blood stain?
I'm going to check it out!
Conan-kun!
Don't move, you guys!
President!
President Kojima!
Hey...
Did you call an ambulance?
Yes.
It should be here in ten minutes.
What happened?
Looks like he missed a step and fell down the stairs.
Did you see it?
No.
I just heard a scream and a loud sound, so I rushed here...
And I saw the president lying here.
Then...
You should call the police, too.
Police?
Look here, at the president's right hand.
He's holding a torn piece of paper.
Normally, if someone lost their footing
and was about to fall down the stairs...
They wouldn't hold onto a piece of paper, right?
Either the president grabbed the paper out
of someone's hand as he was falling...
Or he was fighting with someone over the paper, causing the fall.
I see.
What about the staff member who went on stage?
I saw blood on his sleeve.
He was with us when we ran here.
He tried to straighten the president up, so
perhaps that's when blood got on him.
In any case, there was someone near the president when he fell.
And by the time you got here, they vanished with the rest of the paper.
Which means that someone is responsible for his fall.
But...
Who are you?
Don't tell me, that someone...
Is among the three people who passed the preliminary rounds.
The president said...
He would extend his welcome to the champion personally.
That's why the staff was waiting in another room for his return.
Hey, hey, don't tell me those three finalists...
Say, what's all this racket about?
Is something wrong?
I don't care about this.
Can't you hurry and start the trivia game?
We've been waiting long enough.
Don't tell me...
Genta's dad is...
One of the suspects?
No, besides that...
Which one of these three is Genta's dad?
Our victim is Kojima Gonsaku-san, age 71.
He's the president of the Kojima Group...
And he's here today as the head judge
of a special program for Nichiuri TV.
Head judge?
Yes.
It's a show called "The Nationwide Kojima-san Competition,"
planned and sponsored by President Kojima himself.
The winner is set to receive expensive prizes.
However, it looks as if he slipped down the
stairs, making this an accidental death.
It doesn't seem to be a case for us criminal investigators.
I agree.
Why did you call us?
It was you who called me directly, wasn't it?
The paper.
Paper?
When we staff members rushed here...
The president was bleeding from his head and
holding a piece of paper while lying on the floor.
Normally, when someone falls down the
stairs, they don't hold onto paper, do they?
No...
So it's possible that someone else was nearby,
and he grabbed the paper as he fell...
Or he was fighting with someone over
the paper and fell as a result, right?
When we found the president lying on
the floor, nobody else was around.
Which would mean someone left the president
here, snatched the rest of the paper and fled.
If that's the case, this could be manslaughter.
But that was amazing.
To observe all of this and contact us in the first division.
Ah, no...
It wasn't us.
It was that boy who wanted us to contact
Detective Takagi from the police department.
You really don't know?
Aren't you the president's secretary?
But I was told by the president not to look.
Conan-kun?
Here we go again.
I really don't know what was written on that piece of paper.
It was kept in an envelope, too.
About that piece of paper...
That's the one the president was holding, right?
Yes, probably.
That paper was only used by the president on
special occasions - a unique type called "washi."
I saw it when the president put it in the envelope...
But he only gave it to me for safekeeping for a short time.
And before leaving, I returned it to him with the envelope intact.
We found an empty envelope on the
victim's body, so that's likely the truth.
But, why did he let you keep it?
He asked me to show it to those three people.
Three people?
The ones who passed the Kojima-san Competition preliminary rounds.
It was...
Those three people.
Kojima-san Competition, huh?
By the way, how did you select the participants?
We called for everyone with the
surname of Kojima on the internet...
And chose 200 people from the
applicants to participate in the contest.
It consists of three-minutes of push ups for our physical test...
Singing a favorite song for our singing contest...
And a kanji writing quiz for our knowledge test.
I see.
So the ones who aced the knowledge, physical,
and singing tests are those three people?
Yes, more or less.
More or less?
So the president showed them the question on the piece of paper.
What was on it?
About that...
He only asked me to listen to how they read it.
But all three responses were all over the place.
All over the place?
Was it written as a code or something?
No, all three answered immediately...
So I don't think it was a complicated word.
Number 35, Kojima Bunta-san answered "happyakuichi" - 801.
Number 81, Kojima Genji-san answered "shakuhachi" - bamboo flute.
And number 147, Kojima Gankichi-san answered "ippin" - first class.
Those three answers really were all over the place.
Did you really show them the same piece of paper?
Yes, no doubt about it.
After I reported their answers to the president, he muttered...
Looks like he exposed his tail.
Tail?
Right after that, he took the envelope from me...
And said he'd go to the waiting room himself to welcome the person.
The winner of the Kojima-san Competition.
So he decided the winner after hearing the three answers?
It seems so.
However, it's odd to say something about a "tail."
And he went to the winner's waiting room?
Well, I was told to leave, so I waited
in the staff room the whole time.
Then I heard the president scream, and a loud noise.
Inspector Megure!
Oh, Chiba?
I asked the other people who participated in this contest.
The waiting rooms for the finalists
are at the top of this flight of stairs.
At the time of the president's fall, only
those three finalists were on that floor.
Were those three in the same room?
No, they were in three separate rooms.
Furthermore, the elevator to this floor is under maintenance.
The stairs have to be used to go up or down.
In other words, when the staff rushed
here under these circumstances...
If there was no one around the president, then...
Someone among them must have pushed him
down the stairs and returned to his room.
That's the likely situation, right?
For now, we should question them one by one.
Yes, sir!
Ah, Detective Takagi!
While you're questioning them, please
ask a few extra questions for me.
That's quite rare.
Usually you would just secretly follow us
and suddenly interrupt with questions.
Ah, actually...
What is it?
Genta-kun's dad is among those three?
Which one is he?
I've never met him before, so I don't know.
He might know me from photos or somewhere, though.
If it's like that, we can just ask and find out quickly.
I'll tell Inspector Megure about it
and remove him from the suspects.
Don't do that.
Holmes once said...
Not to allow your judgment to be biased by personal qualities,
and emotional qualities are antagonistic to clear reasoning.
Just because he's Genta's dad doesn't mean
we're 100% sure he's not the culprit, right?
If we want to conduct a proper investigation, it's best that we don't ask.
So, can you help me ask the questions I'm about to tell you?
Perhaps those three...
Didn't really ace those tests.
Conan-kun still hasn't come back.
Yeah.
Guess something really did happen.
I heard sirens from an ambulance and police cars.
How about we go and check out the situation?
We should!
Let's go, let's go!
Don't.
Didn't Edogawa-kun tell us to stay here and wait?
That's true, but...
But you know...
If this is really a criminal case, Genta-kun's
father might be dragged into it.
That's exactly why.
If this didn't involve him...
He'd have called us and told us not to worry.
Since he still hasn't...
The possibility of him being a suspect is very high.
Kojima-kun's father, that is.
What now?
Dad...
Hyakki Yakou...
That robber group?
I guess I have to go take a look!
Genta-kun!
Next Conan's Hint
Tokyoite
My dad is the greatest man, so he can't be the culprit!
Look forward to the next episode
That reasoning is flawed.
Yep.