The Nationwide Kojima-san Competition.
From all of the people with the Kojima surname in Japan...
The best was to be determined - that's
what the Nichiuri TV special was about.
The winner's prize was ten million yen.
On top of that, they also would receive a scroll as a bonus prize.
Painted by the ink-and-wash prodigy...
It's one of the boar-deer-butterfly trio - the "bush clover and boar."
Genta's dad was also participating in the competition.
The preliminary rounds consisted of a push-up and
a singing test, as well as a kanji writing quiz.
The evaluation was quite a tough one.
There were only three participants who passes
the harsh tests and went to the final round.
Surprisingly, Genta's dad was among them.
However, just as the final round was about to start...
The president of the Kojima Group who
hosted this competition, Kojima Gonsaku...
Kojima Gonsaku (71)
Kojima Group President
Was killed by someone who pushed him down the stairs.
The only people who used the stairs were the three finalists.
That's right, Genta's dad has become one of the suspects.
But, which of them is Genta's dad?
Love is magic, attack the mystery.
On Saturday nights, be sure to click on Conan!
The mystery of the case and the identity of Genta's dad...
Will both be revealed at last!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Waiting Room A
waiting room
While I was waiting in this hikaeshitsu...
I heard a door being knocked on elsewhere.
Then, I heard a scream and a loud noise so I went out to look.
Kojima Bunta (33)
Participant
That's when I was that old man lying
at the bottom of the stairs, that's all.
Did you leave the room immediately after the scream and noise?
No, I waited for a while.
I thought it was just another kind of test.
Also, was happyakuichi - 801 really what was written on the paper?
Yeah, that was it.
By the way, how many push-ups did you complete in three minutes?
About a hundred.
I see.
Waiting Room B
Oh, that means...
You also heard someone knocking on the door of another room...
And after hearing the scream and loud noise...
You rushed out of the room and hurried to the scene, right?
Yeah...
After I heard the ruckus and opened my door...
Kojima Genji (32)
Participant
I saw the other two were coming out too.
So, on that piece of paper was something you claimed was...
One foot, eight inches
Yes, shakuhachi - bamboo flute.
801 and 1'8"...
Only the "8" matches.
By the way, what song did you sing today?
Kuroda Bushi.
Do you want me to sing it?
There's no need...
If you would, please!
Waiting Room C
Yeah; it's the same as those other two.
I heard a loud scream and noise so I rushed out.
Kojima Gankichi (34)
Participant
That's when I saw the old man lying all
by himself on the floor downstairs.
Also, was the word ippin - first-class - really written on that paper?
Yeah.
"Ippin" as in "the world's first-class item."
By the way, can you write the kanji for "rose"?
Rose...
I can't possibly write the kanji for it.
Hey, what was all of that about?
Ah, actually...
What?
Conan-kun asked you to do that?
Yes.
He said if we asked them those questions, we might
find out the real purpose for this competition.
Detective Takagi, how'd it go?
Push-ups... about a hundred.
Singing was about at Inspector Megure's level.
And he couldn't write the kanji for "rose."
My singing is better that his, isn't it?
He also messed up the lyrics of Kuroda Bushi.
I guess.
He messed up?
Yeah.
[Drink and win this best spear in Japan]
"Hi no moto ichi no kono yari wo."
And he mistook it as...
"Shi no moto ichi no."
Like that.
I recorded the song as well as the investigative interview.
Want to hear them?
But, what can we learn from that?
This competition wasn't about being number one.
Right?
What does that mean?
We all thought the contest was to choose the best Kojima-san, but...
When we sent the push-up records to the
evaluation room where the president was...
I've already finished the evaluation.
It's these 58 people.
Is what he said...
Before he saw the records?
Yes.
It was the same situation for the kanji test.
He just went to look at the video tape
recording of the participants for a while.
Then, the singing?
He listened to each of the contestants' recordings himself.
Only the president was evaluating?
Yeah, seems like the president wanted to handle it all by himself.
Even the numbered shirts and shoes for the
participants were prepared by the president.
Then, what standard did he use to evaluate them?
Inspector Megure!
Inside the president's bag in the evaluation room...
Was a gun!
What!?
Along with that, this paper too.
Paper?
Yes.
It's written with messy handwriting.
"Regarding the scrolls - the first-class items of the world..."
"We have indeed obtained them."
"With respect - Hyakki Yakou."
Hyakki Yakou...
The murderous robbery group?
Actually...
The president wrote in his blog that,
among the "boar-deer-butterfly"...
He had misplaced the deer and butterfly scrolls...
But they were actually snatched by that gang six months ago.
Fortunately, the boar scroll was sent for repair, so it was not taken.
Say, was anyone killed at that time?
No.
The president, his wife, and his servants
were merely drugged and knocked out.
But the president's pet dog Gonta...
Its head was cut off by the group leader in the front yard.
And apparently, as the leader was
leaving, he was muttering something...
The barely conscious president overheard him.
"I'll spare your life since we have the same surname."
"We might even be distant relatives."
Did you report that incident to the police?
No, the president ordered me not to say anything.
Say, Detective Takagi...
Perhaps, those three suspects...
Come to think of it, all three were like that.
I see.
I finally get it.
However...
Even if the president asked you to keep silent...
If that robber group broke into your house and took the scrolls...
You should have informed us police.
I'm terribly sorry.
But, he said, "I will avenge Gonta's death, so don't tell anyone."
Then, could it be this Kojima-san
Competition organized by the president was...
Right.
It wasn't to choose the best Kojima-san.
It was to find the one who killed Gonta and avenge its death...
With the gun he had hidden in the evaluation room.
Besides, for the surname Kojima, you could
write it as 小島 or 児島 or something else.
But all the participants here spelled Kojima as 小嶋.
Is that so?
Yes.
All three finalists spelled Kojima as 小 for "ko" and 嶋 for "jima."
Speaking of which, the president spelled his surname the same way.
Does that mean the president knew the gang leader's name?
He didn't know.
He figured it out.
With those words left by the leader...
"I'll spare your life since we have the same surname."
"We might even be distant relatives."
I see!
Only relatives would have the exact same surname and spelling.
If that's the case...
He could've chosen the participants with the same
surnames during the application form screening process.
I think that's it.
We thought it was strange when we saw all of
the contestants wrote Kojima the same way.
However...
While it makes sense up to here, how
did he narrow it down from there?
Say, for the push-up test, the shoes worn by the
participants were prepared by the president, right?
Yeah, that's right.
Then, you checked the shoe sizes of everyone, right?
Yeah.
We were told by the president to do that.
If I recall, wasn't Gonta killed in the front yard?
Yeah...
Hey, hey, what is it you're...
If it was in the yard, don't they have to be at the scene?
The culprit's...
Footprints.
I see, the shoe prints!
The president pretended it was a physical test...
And narrowed down the participants by their shoe size!
Then, the singing test was to hear their voices?
Yeah.
Since the president heard the leader's voice, there's no doubt.
Also, the three finalists all have similar voices.
In that case, the kanji test was to see their handwriting.
To compare with this gang leader's handwriting on this letter.
Not exactly.
Because the leader wouldn't have used his
usual handwriting for the letter, would he?
I think either he attempted a different handwriting style...
Or he asked someone else to write it.
Then what's the purpose for the kanji test?
The handedness.
If the dog was killed with a knife, he could tell from
the wound which hand the leader used, right?
All three had the same handedness, right?
Detective Takagi.
Yeah.
When Kojima Bunta-san lit up his cigarette...
When Kojima Genji-san drank from his cup...
And when Kojima Gankichi-san wiped his sweat with a towel...
All three used their left hands.
I see.
That's why he can narrow them down just by watching
the VTR of the contestants doing the kanji quiz.
But aside from the voice, why not make them report their
shoe sizes and their handedness on their applications?
I think if he did that, the culprit might realize
this was about finding the dog's killer.
I see.
But boy, that's a great deduction!
I messaged a teenage detective I know, and this is what he told me...
So it really was Kudou-kun after all...
The question now is, what was written on the paper
the president asked the finalists to read?
It seems that after making them read it, he knew
who the culprit was and went to see him.
Which resulted in a fight for that paper, leading to his fall and death.
But all three answered differently after reading that piece of paper.
Also, we searched their bodies and their waiting
rooms, but there was no sign of the paper.
As for where the paper is, Shinichi-niichan said he already knows.
Of course, he also knows what was on the paper.
Conan-kun is really late.
So Genta-kun's dad really is involved in some kind of a case?
Well, let's just leave it to Conan-kun.
That's right.
So Kojima-kun, don't make such a face.
Wait for his return.
That's right!
Genta-kun's dad would never do anything bad!
I'm not really worried about that.
I was just thinking it would be bad if a fight started.
A fight?
Yeah...
My dad is combative, honest, and hates dishonorable things...
Combative...
Honest...
Hates dishonorable things...
Sounds like a typical Tokyoite.
I guess I have to go take a look!
Genta-kun!
Excuse me.
Waiting Room
What is this about?
Gathering us in such a room...
Didn't you finish your interrogation?
Don't tell me you know who the culprit is?
Ah, no...
We just wanted to confirm how you read the words on the paper.
It's Happyakuichi - 801!
Shakuhachi - bamboo flute.
Ippin - first class!
What are you talking about?
That was a number that was written!
Yeah, what I said was a number too.
Cut the shit!
Isn't it obvious that it was kanji!?
I think those three saw different pieces of paper...
The paper probably...
Had this on it, right?
Yeah!
That's it!
Look, isn't that 801?
But I saw it upside-down...
So it was 108.
So by "shakuhachi"...
You meant "hyakuhachi"?
Yeah.
108 was what I said.
What nonsense are you guys talking about?
Give me that!
Isn't this "first class" as in "the world's first-class item"?
It sort of looks that way...
But it's hard to read it as the kanji for "item"...
Well, he can't help it.
That kanji "品" was written in circles
instead of the proper tetragons.
And if you aren't used to this kind of
writing, you wouldn't read this as "item."
Isn't that right?
The leader of the robber group.
Come to think of it, the word "item" as in "first-class
items of the world" on the letter was also like this.
Of course they're the same.
Because I asked Detective Chiba to copy the words from the letter.
Which means...
The president also copied the words to that
washi paper and made you read them...
And whoever read it as kanji instead
of numbers would be the culprit.
Apparently, you were the one who fell for it.
The hell're you saying...
If you want to accuse me, then show me!
That washi you're talking about!
Say, mister, do you know?
That washi was specially made from mulberry of the fig family...
And it's extremely toxic.
So even if you accidentally licked it...
Don't tell me, you...
An ambulance!
Call an ambulance, hurry!
I ate it!
That washi!
Then, you're confessing?
You were fighting over the paper with the president...
And made him fall down the stairs...
And then left him alone and fled?
I confess...
I confess!
Hurry and call the ambulance!
And you also confess to being the leader of the robber group?
That's right!
I'm the leader of Hyakki Yakou!
That old man, as soon as he came into my room...
He grinned and said...
Long time no see!
The man who killed my dog...
I knew you would come.
You would want to get that boar scroll you failed to get last time.
Well, don't you worry.
Depending on how you respond, I might even forgive you.
If you want to run away, I won't stop you.
I'll just report it to the police.
Your face has already been captured by the TV cameras.
And, I have this piece of paper as evidence.
I thought I was doomed when he said that...
So I tried to snatch away that evidential paper.
But that old guy fell down the stairs just like that!
So you left the president alone and fled...
And swallowed that paper to destroy evidence?
Yeah!
So go call an ambulance already!
I'm going to die!
It's all right.
It's normal to use mulberry in making washi paper.
And it's not that toxic.
What did you...
But mulberries, unlike you...
Although the skins are black, their insides are white.
For a black-hearted man like you, isn't it a good medicine?
We'll talk about this at the station.
Nah, it was all a joke!
I was fooling around with what the brat said...
What the hell!
Hey!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
'Nuff with playin' innocent already!
Whatcha just said, I've heard everything clearly with mah ears!
Don't 'cha go tryin' to talk shit now!
I said I was joking...
Still tryin' to play dumb, ya poor bastage!?
B-Bastage?
I own a bar, so what kinda drunkard haven't I seen?
I'll tell ya what!
Why don't I reach my fingernails deep into ya throat...
And dig that washi up together with ya lunch!?
Ah, don't...
I surrender.
Dad!
What happened?
Genta!
Don't tell me, Genta-kun's dad is the culprit!?
Dad...
What are you doing in a place like this?
Oh, Genta!
What's with those glasses?
Ah, these...
Mom made you wear them?
Just because of the contest?
That's right!
She said they'd make me look smarter, and
kept naggin' me 'bout wearin' them.
But it looks like they were your granny's glasses.
They're so strong that I could hardly open my eyes with 'em on.
And she kept naggin' me about "using
proper language" and "not to pick fights."
But why did you answer with "bamboo flute"?
That's right, we heard about it from Detective Takagi!
You pronounced 108 as shakuhachi.
Because he's a Tokyoite.
For native Tokyoites, when they try to pronounce "hi" or "hya"...
It usually comes out as "shi" or "sha."
Well, you could call it a dialect.
Incidentally, when you sang the Kuroda Bushi song...
You turned "Hi no moto ichi no kono
yari wo," into "Shi no moto ichi", right?
That's how you hear it?
I see.
So that's how you knew he was Kojima-kun's dad.
Yeah.
waiting room
The other two could pronounce "hikaeshitsu" and "himself" properly.
But, Dad...
If we had come any later, you'd have started fighting, wouldn't you?
Well, don't be mindin' the details!
Fires and fights are the flowers of Edo, they say!
That's a pretty ancient saying, you know...
The prosecution's takeover will commence as planned, 4:00pm.
What?
He faced the window and threw the weapon?
The prosecution's takeover is at 4:00pm...
That's the time limit!
Next Conan's Hint
Left-Handed
What's Detective Takagi?
Look forward to the next episode
I'm a handy guy.
That's not the right hand.