Beika Police Dept. Interrogation Room
Togashi!
Don't stay silent, say something!
Togashi...
Dad...
At 4:00pm today...
Togashi Fumitaka (32)
Ex-con
This man - Togashi Fumitaka...
Will be sent to the prosecutor as a murder suspect.
They call it a prosecutor's takeover.
Everything started yesterday.
Love is magic, attack the mystery.
On Saturday nights, be sure to click on Conan!
Uncle Kogoro is in the interrogation room...
And he's fighting hard for the truth!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Yesterday Afternoon
Musashino Prison
Togashi!
Great work.
You've been keeping at it.
Mouri-san!
Togashi Fumitaka.
He's a murderer who was arrested by
Uncle while he was still a police detective.
Today, he went on parole.
Excuse us!
Hakamada Tsuneo (34)
Ex-con
Throw it back!
Here!
Thank you!
As a small celebration, I've already made a reservation.
Allow me to treat you to...
Sorry, I have to go...
Hey, Togashi!
Wait, Hakamada!
And then, the murder happened...
At 10:00 PM last night...
A parole officer living at 4th Street in Beika City,
55-year-old Sakuraba Takehiko-san, was found murdered.
A former convict released on parole
yesterday from Musashino Prison...
One which Officer Sakuraba
Takehiko-san had supervised...
Togashi Fumitaka, age 32, has been
arrested in connection with the crime.
What?
Impossible!
That's impossible!
Today 10:05 AM
Kasamatsu Norio (52)
Beika Police First Division Detective
Keeping your mouth shut won't save you, Togashi.
Detective Mouri is waiting outside.
What?
I see.
Togashi was the one you arrested all that time ago...
Right.
He accidentally killed his victim in a dispute.
His attorney claimed it was self defense, but...
He behaved violently in court...
And had a long rap sheet...
Which earned him a thirteen year jail sentence.
But, this guy was actually a nice guy at heart and loved his mother.
While serving his time, he changed and become a model inmate.
And now...
He murdered again?
On his first night of parole?
I can't believe it.
I know how you feel, but...
Don't be naive.
It goes to show that people can't change easily.
Then, Inspector...
We will begin the prosecutor's takeover paperwork as planned.
Can't you wait just a...
Mouri-san, isn't it?
I've heard a lot about you.
But forget about the past.
You're only a private detective now.
There's no call for outsiders to intervene.
Kasamatsu-kun, proceed with your paperwork.
Inspector!
But, the prosecutor's takeover will
commence as planned - at 4:00pm.
As such, we'll be on break until then.
Togashi will remain in custody in the interrogation room.
What nonsense is that!
This isn't some sort of joke!
I will pass the word to your supervisor myself.
Thank you, Inspector.
Sleeping Kogoro...
I've always appreciated your help.
But I repeat:
Our break ends at 4:00.
Understood.
As such...
Uncle got special permission to continue interrogating Togashi, but...
Togashi!
Don't stay silent, say something!
Dad...
The victim's wounds are mostly on the right side of the body...
Stop that, Conan-kun.
You can't just snoop around!
Doesn't that mean the culprit held the weapon in their left hand?
Yeah.
It matches the witness testimony.
But that person...
He's not left-handed, is he?
Yeah.
But, there are wounds that aren't on the left side as well.
He must've been wrestling with the
victim and switched to another hand.
That's certainly a possibility.
To confirm that...
Say, where's the restroom?
It'd be bad if you got lost, so I'll wait here.
Thank you.
Hello?
Mouri-san? Huh?
What about the interrogation?
We're taking a lunch break.
Actually, Takagi...
I have a favor to ask of you.
Yes?
Go to the crime scene now?
Yes. Yes. Understood.
Also, about Ran...
Dad's telling me to go home?
Yeah, he said there's no need to worry.
Conan-kun went home already too.
Then, if you'll excuse me.
Ah, wait...
Jeez, everybody's in such a hurry.
Conan-kun?
Uncle forgot to tell you something so he wants me to tag along.
Mouri-san did?
Hurry.
There's not much time left until the takeover, right?
Do you remember, Togashi?
After six months of time served, you sent me a letter.
You said you had been spending your days
feeling remorse and bettering yourself.
That you'd walk away clean and take care of your mother.
That's right.
You regained your footing...
And I had never thought being a
police detective could be so rewarding.
Well, the happiest one must've been your mother.
Is she doing all right?
What's wrong, Togashi?
Guess it can't be helped.
Don't touch anything on your own, Conan-kun.
All right!
"Reconstruct the crime scene according to witness testimony."
He even requested that...
Say.
The culprit was seen through this window, right?
Yeah.
The witness is that lady over there.
Why are the pools of blood so far apart?
You're right.
Why is that?
These shiny shards are from that mirror, right?
It's the mirror from that cabinet.
It seems like it was smashed during the
struggle between the culprit and the victim.
Was the weapon dropped here?
Yeah.
Fingerprints?
On the weapon?
There weren't any.
It was wiped clean.
Not only the weapon...
The sliding screens and places the
culprit most likely touched were all...
Let me see.
The victim's prints aren't there either.
That's right.
Kitchen, bathroom, bedroom...
Even the victim's everyday fingerprints were wiped off.
Why did they have to...
Say, when and where was Togashi-san arrested?
Let's see...
At 10:30 last night, in Beika Park.
And the time when the murder was witnessed?
Ten minutes before that, around 10:20.
Beika Park: from here to there would take
7 or 8 minutes, even if you were running.
Which means...
After the crime, they only had a few
minutes to tamper with the scene...
Impossible.
Could they have wiped them before the crime?
Nah, it can't be.
Then, they did it while the crime was ongoing...
Could it be, another person was here?
Yeah, that is quite likely.
But...
At the time of arrest, Togashi was alone.
Which means, they split up and escaped.
It's only been one night.
If we can find more witnesses...
Will do!
Togashi.
When I arrested you at that time...
It was because your friend was beaten up
by gangsters, but you tried to fight back...
And you went too far.
Could it be, you're helping someone out again this time?
Don't tell me, another person was involved?
Togashi...
Tell the truth!
Tell me right now, Togashi!
Pause it there.
What?
This man...
What about him?
I think he was...
So that's how it was.
This is?
Say, about the thing Uncle Kogoro forgot to tell you...
Ah, I totally forgot about that.
Well, it's about the witness testimony reconstruction.
He wanted you to do it for both sides - for
the crime scene and where the witness was.
So you witnessed the crime through these windows
and into that house's window, right Miss?
Yoshizawa Kane (75)
Witness
That's right, it was scary.
Thunder and lightning, and then there was a blackout.
Without thinking, I looked out the window...
Though I couldn't see his face, our eyes met.
And all of a sudden...
What?
He faced the window and threw the weapon?
Wait, but...
The weapon...
Right.
The weapon was not near the window,
but was instead in front of the cabinet.
Maybe you saw it wrong...
But my eyes are good.
My eyesight hasn't changed since I was 30 years old.
And what happened next?
I couldn't see anything after that.
Although, there were several more lightning strikes afterwards.
So it was actually like that...
But if that's the case, we may have come to a surprising truth.
Uncle...
Don't tell me, Inspector...
I'm sorry, Mouri-kun.
Time is running out.
Hold it.
There's still time.
Answer me, Togashi!
You really...
You're so persistent!
Mouri-kun, this is it.
Togashi...
Whaaaat thhheee...
It's all right, Uncle.
Here, just sit down.
And Detective Takagi wanted to tell you this.
Excuse me.
What's with him?
To suddenly make a funny sound...
Well, after that he usually...
Just wait, please.
There's something more to this case.
Right, right!
He usually does this.
Don't tell me, this is that famous Sleeping Kogoro...
Before the prosecutor's takeover at 4:00...
Allow me to reveal every bit of truth to you.
Understood.
I'll let you have at it.
But wait...
It's still as planned.
No problem.
Then?
What is this "something more" about the case?
At that murder crime scene...
There was actually someone else present...
Which adds something more to the case.
What now?
That's nonsense...
Detective Takagi is currently investigating this man's identity.
Are you telling us that this man is our real culprit?
How stupid.
We have a witness who testified that she saw him!
She didn't see his face.
That's true...
Then, how would you explain all of the blood?
According to the forensics, the blood on him matches the victim's.
What a pity, but we have a motive.
Motive?
Looks like the victim was a so-called malicious parole officer.
He made a lot of empty promises, such as
assuring there would be no prosecution...
And he took advantage of suspects' families
to squeeze out large sums of money.
A year and a half ago, your mother suffered
from his pressure and died of illness.
Isn't that right?
So it's just as we thought...
No.
About that motive, one more man fits in as well.
Under the same pressure, his wife and son committed suicide...
He is the man caught on tape by a convenience store camera...
Hakamada Tsuneo, 34 years old.
Yesterday, he went on parole along with Togashi.
Moreover, Hakamada is left-handed.
That would also explain the concentrated
amount of wounds on the right side of the body.
I recall the witness reporting the culprit
holding the weapon in his left hand.
The guy from Musashino Prison who went on parole yesterday...
Hakamada Tsuneo, check his whereabouts now!
Yes, sir!
You're wrong!
That guy... Hakamada had nothing to do with this!
It's me!
I did it!
What?
Hakamada turned himself in?
What's that?
Hakamada...
Why?
It's all right, Togashi.
I went to my wife and son's grave.
I planned to turn myself in after that.
So, it's true you committed the crime?
Yeah.
We became pals while in the slammer...
That's when he discovered my plan to murder Sakuraba.
I proceeded ahead, despite Togashi's warning...
And finally did the deed.
But Togashi arrived at the scene, completely stunned...
And he told me, "I'll take care of the fingerprints, so flee at once!"
Without thinking, I fled the scene just like that.
And he was caught as a result...
I couldn't believe that...
In other words, after letting Hakamada go,
he didn't know what had been touched...
As a result, he wiped off even
the victim's everyday fingerprints.
Am I right?
There's no doubt.
I have to hand it to you, Mouri-kun.
Thanks to you, an innocent person wasn't used as a scapegoat.
Well, I don't know about that.
Detective Takagi...
What time was Hakamada caught on tape?
Well, it was last night...
At 10:20.
What now?
That means...
Yes.
That is the exact time Yoshizawa Kane-san witnessed the crime.
What does that mean?
That would mean Hakamada was at two
different places at the same time...
No, that's not possible.
Hakamada had blood on him.
Which put him on the scene, no doubt.
However...
At the time the witness saw the crime scene...
He was already gone.
Detective Takagi.
What did the witness say?
About the weapon.
About the weapon?
Though I couldn't see his face, our eyes met.
And all of a sudden...
He faced the witness and threw the weapon?
Yeah, but it's weird.
The weapon was not near the window, but was near
the cabinet, among the shattered mirror shards.
Meaning, the culprit didn't face the witness...
But instead faced the mirror and threw the weapon.
Don't tell me, what the witness saw was a reflection of the culprit?
That's correct.
As such, what we thought was the left
hand of the culprit holding a weapon...
Was actually his right hand.
What now...
And in return...
The culprit was shocked by the reflection of the witness.
So he immediately threw his weapon into the mirror, breaking it.
In other words, the culprit who was seen was right-handed...
And the culprit who fled previously was left-handed.
Hold on.
Are you saying the victim was murdered twice?
There is only one imaginable scenario.
The victim who was thought to be dead came to...
And he was finished off by another culprit.
What now?
And that culprit is...
Togashi... it was you.
I couldn't forgive him.
Because of that guy...
Hakamada and my families had to suffer...
I couldn't forgive him!
The long day in the interrogation room finally came to an end.
The Next Day 9:00 AM
Togashi Fumitaka Being Sent to the Prosecutor
While I was sitting in that interrogation room yesterday...
I wish you had been the one to tell me the truth, Togashi.
Well, I guess you couldn't tell an old detective like
me who wasn't even aware your mother had died.
I was scared, and...
I couldn't bring myself to tell the truth.
But, because of you, I didn't have to make Hakamada my scapegoat.
Thank you very much!
Did I do that again?
Seems like I lost my memory...
Well, that must be it!
Ran, give Eri a call.
Mom?
Are you...
Hey, I don't mean for that!
You want her to represent Togashi, don't you?
I already know that.
But let's get together for lunch while we're at it!
If that woman really insists...
I guess wasting some time on that wouldn't be too bad.
Hey, hey.
"Wasting some time" and "wouldn't be too bad"?
If you keep that up...
What just popped out!?
Regardless, why did you sprain your ankle, brat?
Think I would tell you such a thing?
Haruna-chan!
Let go of that girl now!
Next Conan's Hint
Letter
Next time, it's the Kinosaki hot spring!
Look forward to the next episode
Then, to the hot spring I go!
Inspector, you're staying home.
What!?