Said to deliver newborns...
And to bring happiness should they roost on
someone's home - they're known as storks.
And the baby storks we encountered...
Were no exception.
Love is magic, attack the mystery.
On Saturday nights, be sure to dick on Conan!
Today's story is in Hyogo Prefecture.
Heiji's here too, for the mystery of the Kinosaki Spring?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Kinosaki Hot Spring
1400 years ago, it was discovered that this
hot spring could heal injured storks.
And Douchi, a high-ranking monk,
then founded this Kinosaki Hot Spring.
Located in the north of Hyogo Prefecture...
It's surrounded by Amanohashidate - one of Japan's
"three scenic views" - and many other historic places.
Amanohashidate
Be it visiting one of the seven outdoor spas...
Or splurging on the famous Matsuba crab and Tajima beef...
The number of tourists never wanes throughout the year.
Satono Spa
It's so warm!
Hurry up, you two.
This feels great!
A foot spa!
How soothing!
And the weather's so nice too!
Outdoor spas are fun!
I thought they were just hot springs, but...
These are actually quite enjoyable.
Excuse me, could I squeeze in?
Sorry for the inconvenience.
Bear with me.
It's because you're too fat.
You're one to talk.
As I thought, it's no good...
Let's visit all of the outdoor spas!
I wonder where Genta-kun and the others went to visit?
Feels so good.
Mandara Spa
How luxurious for us to enjoy hot spring early in the morning.
I'd say.
Got the Mandara Spa!
A crab-cream cone after a hot spring - awesome!
Next, to Ichino Spa...
Genta-kun, your ice cream is dripping on your badge.
What a waste!
Kouno Spa
As for why we're here visiting the Kinosaki Hot Spring...
Actually...
This is why.
In the past, the storks were said to heal
their legs in this spa - the Kouno Spa.
Isn't this a perfect fit for you?
Thank you, Uncle.
You think I'm a stork now?
Don't sweat it.
A client from a previous case I solved introduced me to this spa.
Actually, I solved that.
At any rate, how'd you sprain your ankle anyway, brat?
Well...
Isn't that right?
Right, right!
What is?
Ran and... Araide-sensei?
Why are they...
Conan-kun!
Think I would tell you such a thing?
Bet you weren't paying attention to where you were going.
Geez, be careful next time.
The hell are you doing!?
You're...
Thought I was a goner...
Say...
Yumoto Kouchi (28)
Freelance Writer
Could you be...
That famous detective, Mouri Kogorou-san?
I am indeed the famous detective Mouri.
Me - sorry, I am Yumoto Kouichi, a freelance writer.
Allow me to do a close-up interview on you!
But, this isn't about a case...
"A Famous Detective's Vacation."
This is something the readers would want to read and know about.
Please accept!
Well, uhm...
If you say so, all right then!
Thank you!
This might be my lucky break!
So much for my therapy...
Let's go to Yanagi Spa next!
Hey!
Wait up, you two...
Ayumi-chan's...
Ayumi-chan?
Geez, guess I'll hold onto it.
Let's see, Yanagi Spa is...
This way.
Are you all right?
Are you hurt?
Don't touch me!
I'm sorry.
Haruna?
Haruna-chan, is it?
Aren't you with your mom and dad?
I'm not!
Wait up...
Haruna-chan!
A beer right after a bath is unmatchable!
Goshono Spa
But are you sure this can make into publication?
Of course! I'll follow you throughout the day!
Geez, have it your way then!
Beer is fine, but shochu mixed in hot spring water is dandy too!
Perfect, keep this up, please!
The famous detective's vacation can't be anything else but this!
Got the Ichino Spa!
Three down already!
Mitsuhiko!
Tadaa! I got Crab dogs!
This seems to come up every time, but when
are you going to stop eating, Genta-kun?
After I try that horse beef steak!
"Horse beef"?
Isn't that horse meat mixed with beef?
It's famous here!
[The "ma" in Tajima literally means horse, but Tajima is a proper noun.]
Don't tell me... you mean Tajima beef?
Just because you can't read it doesn't mean you can shorten it!
What the... it's not horse meat mixed with beef?
And I thought that was a steal.
Genta-kun, you already had a big breakfast.
Huh?
Where's Ran-neechan?
About that...
We lost her a while ago.
Where could she be?
If it's about Ran-neechan, we just saw her.
Really?
Yeah, it was near the Yanagi Spa.
Look.
This is Ran-san in the photo, right?
Who's that girl in the photo with her?
Mitsuhiko, show me the left side.
Here?
Yes.
Who's he?
This man...
That guy! He's an annoying punk!
He knocked Genta-kun over and didn't apologize!
Genta-kun!
What's with him...
How dare he ruin my crab-cream!
It was only my second one!
Could that man be stalking Ran and that girl?
Regardless, let me give Ran-neechan a call.
The number you have dialed is either outside
of the service area, or is switched off...
What's up, what's up?
You guys talking about where to eat lunch?
Ran-oneesan disappeared.
What?
She's not answering her phone.
What now?
Things are getting interesting!
Hey! The close-up's over as of now.
No way!
The editor-in-chief already gave me the OK for this!
My daughter is missing.
Excuse me, but we're done.
Can't you do something...
Don't be pushy!
There goes my lucky break...
Damn it!
And? Do we have anything?
Any clue that leads to Ran's whereabouts?
We don't...
If only I knew something about that girl with Ran...
What happened? With you and that crutch.
Did you fall and sprain your ankle?
Hattori!
I mean, Heiji-niichan!
Such a coincidence to see you here.
Huh?
Where's Ran-chan?
Ran-san... she disappeared.
Disappeared?
Yes, although it looks like she was with this girl.
Girl?
Wait a sec, this girl...
You know her?
Not only that, but the reason I came here was to find her.
Tabuse Haruna (8)
Daughter of Catering Chain Company President
Tabuse Haruna-chan, age 8.
She's the daughter of a large catering chain company's president.
She's been missing since yesterday.
What?
Missing!?
Ah, Tabuse-san.
Sorry to have you wait.
Oh, Hattori-kun.
Tabuse Shuuhei (42)
President of the "Tabuse" Catering Chain Company
How's Haruna? Have you found my daughter Haruna?
I haven't found her yet, but I came across a powerful clue.
Is that so?
By the way, who is this?
He's a private detective from Tokyo...
The name's Mouri Kogorou.
Mouri? You mean...
The famous detective?
What's that smudge?
And this puny little kid...
I'm Edogawa Conan.
The "puny" bit is uncalled for.
Geez, why'd you have to come?
Stay away from this, brat!
But I'm worried about Ran-neechan!
Ran-neechan?
Actually, your daughter somehow ended up with my daughter...
Your daughter kidnapped my Haruna!?
What the hell's going on!?
Hey, hey...
Kinosaki Hot Spring Original
Meat bun made with Tajima Beef!
Yum!
As yummy as expected of a Tajima beef bun!
The crab bun here looks delicious, too.
Hey, don't get too greedy!
I'm not your personal wallet, you know?
Don't be stingy, it was just a little treat for me!
By "a little" you mean...
TEN hot spring eggs, FIVE pork buns, and FOUR beef buns!?
This isn't fair; they only took Conan with them.
I guess something did happen - to Ran-san, that is.
At least it seems like Edogawa-kun thought so.
Then, lets go find out where Ran-oneesan is before Conan does!
I agree!
That should be how the Detective Boys roll!
If that could be done, we wouldn't have to worry.
Since the only clue we have is that photo.
You're right...
Her backpack!
It's the same one I wanted so bad!
The same?
Look, it's in this pamphlet.
This backpack, right?
Please forgive me - I lost my cool back there.
Please, don't mention it.
Tabuse-san...
If it's possible, could you tell us what happened from the beginning?
Yes...
It all started yesterday.
There was an exhibition piece stolen
from the Tabuse Museum in Kobe.
It happened during the rearrangement of the exhibitions.
And, around the same time, my daughter
Haruna who came to visit the museum...
She went missing as well.
I was working in Kinosaki at the time and
received work from Director Kamachi.
Kamachi Takeshi (45)
Tabuse Museum Director
After that, with the help of a friend...
I enlisted Hattori-kun to search for her.
And, what was that stolen exhibition about?
It's called "The Rainbow's Child," made
by a sculptor named Handa Kaho.
Let's see...
So this is the Rainbow's Child sculpture?
When the sculpture was stolen, Haruna-chan happened
to be there, so she was kidnapped, I assume?
Where on earth is Haruna?
By the way, what did you mean by "a powerful clue"?
Actually, it seems like Haruna-chan is somehow in Kinosaki as well.
In Kinosaki?
This is...
It's Haruna, no doubt about it.
And this man in the corner...
Though we don't have proof, we suspect he's the kidnapper.
In other words, your daughter ran away from the
kidnapper, met up with Ran, and escaped together.
Ran, why didn't you call us?
Don't tell me...
That guy already got you...
Toyooka Caban Street
Speaking of Toyooka, it's got to be caban!
[Note: A caban is a Japanese handbag of backpack]
Look, a caban vending machine!
What a rare sight!
Let's buy one, let's buy one!
I think the stork design looks great!
Why don't you buy one as well?
Please, let me go!
Excuse me.
Awesome!
So many caban here!
We're looking for a girl.
Did you see a girl carrying a backpack just like that one over there?
Can you wait for a moment?
Please go ahead and listen to them.
I'll be fine.
I apologize.
By "backpack," you mean this?
Yeah.
If that's the case, I recently saw Tabuse-san and Haruna-chan here.
Her caban was pink.
Then, I think it was probably her.
Uhm...
Iruga Yui (23)
Dolphin Trainer
Are you guys friends of Haruna-chan?
Has something happened to her?
Kinosaki Marine World?
Yeah.
A dolphin trainer who knows Haruna-chan
called her colleagues on a hunch...
And they told her they saw two people who fit the descriptions.
For real?
If I find out anything else, I'll call you.
Hey!
I should go, too.
Hold your horses.
There are still things that warrant our investigations in this city.
Let me be your legs.
All you have to do is give me instructions.
Hattori...
I appreciate it.
By the way, what happened to your ankle?
Were you paying too much attention
to that girl and ended up tripping?
No, it's not what you think!
Kinosaki Marine World
Awesome!
Yui-san is so cool!
This is our sea lion, Genta-kun!
Look, his name is Genta-kun!
He's huge!
Just like you.
Are you brothers?
How is that possible!?
Geez, we didn't come here for fun.
That lady... she showed that in the caban shop too.
Have you seen this girl?
I'm looking for this girl.
Ah, I've seen this girl before.
Look, over there...
She prayed at that Kishibojin Shrine.
She was searching for something?
Yeah.
She searched around the outdoor
spas and the usual sightseeing spots.
Regardless, have you heard of the Legend of Kishibojin?
The Legend of Kishibojin...
I think it was...
There was once a demon with a thousand children in ancient India.
She would eat other people's children and was shunned by others.
As such, Shakyamuni Buddha hid her
youngest son to teach her a lesson.
Saddened by her missing son, she listened to Shakyamuni's lecture
on how other parents were suffering because of her cannibalism.
Enlightened and reformed, the demon became the goddess
of easy delivery and the protector of children - Kishibojin.
Even at the Kishibojin Shrine, she
was searching around for something.
Regardless, was she really being chased by someone?
Looks to me she merely wanted Ran to go sightseeing with her.
Yeah, I know her.
She probably belongs to the family in that photo.
This is from three years ago.
Tabuse Haruna-chan and her father Shuuhei-san, mother Kaho-san...
Kaho?
Kaho... I remember that name.
The sculptor of the Rainbow's Child, Handa Kaho-san...
Tabuse-san...
She was your ex-wife and Haruna-chan's mother, wasn't she?
Why didn't you tell us before?
I never heard of this either.
Tabuse-san?
I didn't mean to hide it...
Where is Kaho-san now?
That woman...
She chose art over her own daughter; she's a demon!
I don't know where she is, and I don't care!
Tabuse-san...
But if you hate her that much, why did
you showcase her work in the museum?
About that...
I see, it's her!
That woman stole the Rainbow's Child!
Or she ordered Haruna to steal it...
I see, that's how it is!
In that case, that shady person would be Kaho-san in disguise.
I doubt it.
It's still too early to jump to conclusions.
In that case, show them, Kamochi.
Yes.
This is a letter addressed to his daughter from Kaho-san.
The president saw this and kept it in his possession.
Let's see.
May I read this?
Yes.
What do we have here...
"Kinosaki Hot Spring and Marine World... we had so much fun."
"Of course you were still little, you probably don't remember anything."
It's the same - visiting the outdoor
spas, arcades, and Kiyamachi Street...
Haruna-chan was spotted at all the places written in this letter.
Which means Haruna-chan was revisiting the
places you went during your family trip.
That woman could be waiting at any of those places
- for Haruna and the Rainbow's child to appear.
No, she could have just specified one place.
She didn't have to beat around the bush.
This is weird.
What is?
Haruna-chan and Ran visited Kinosaki Straw Works
Museum too, but it wasn't mentioned in the letter.
Kinosaki Straw Works Museum
Kinosaki Cultural Museum
Furthermore, they didn't go to the Kinosaki Cultural
Museum that actually was mentioned here.
Let me see.
"At the Kinosaki Cultural Museum, we unexpectedly
came across our friend Michiko's straw works..."
Who's this Michiko-san?
Kaho's high school classmate, a straw works craftswoman.
But why did Haruna-chan go to a place she's never been before?
Three years ago, she was only five years old.
She couldn't remember that well.
Is that so?
Something's not right.
This is...
"I'll keep that along with the memories of our trip."
Say, what's the "that" mentioned in this letter?
Well, beats me.
Regardless, what's more important
is where your daughter will go next.
I'm guessing it would be the Kinosaki Hot
Spring Station mentioned in the letter.
(The Goddess of Mercy)
Jibo Kannon Statue
Great! This is probably it!
Say, Haruna-chan...
What have you been looking for all this time?
Hey!
Where? Where?
Let me go!
Haruna-chan!
Let go of that girl now!
Don't move!
Haruna-chan!
Where is it!?
I dunno!
Hold it right there!
Haruna-chan, go call the police!
Miss!
Sorry, Ran...
If only I could move freely...
Bingo.
Haruna-chan's on the move!
Finally, this is more like the Detective Boys!
The sound of drums are coming from the badge?
Looks like our deduction is same as mine, Kudou.
Somebody help!
Ran, wait for me!
Next Conan's Hint
D-Boys Badge
Look forward to the next episode
Let's use the badge to badger the culprit into surrender!
Your pun can freeze even a crab!