For my sprained ankle's therapy, we came to the Kinosaki Hot Spring...
But then Ran suddenly disappeared.
Yumoto Kouichi (28)
Freelance Writer
From a photo taken by Mitsuhiko...
We learned that Ran had been running with a young girl...
But, also in that photo was a suspicious
person who appeared to be stalking them.
After coming across Hattori Heiji...
He told us that the young girl, Tabuse Haruna...
Was the missing person he was trying to find.
Tabuse Haruna (8)
Daughter of Catering Chain Company President
The day before, in museum owned by Haruna-chan's father...
Tabuse Shuuhei (42)
"Tabuse" Catering Chain Company President
A sculpture known as "The Rainbow's Child" was stolen.
Haruna-chan went missing at the same time.
From information obtained from an acquaintance of Haruna-chan...
Iruga Yui (23)
Dolphin Trainer
A dolphin trainer named Yui-san...
We learned that the sculptor who made the Rainbow's
Child was Haruna-chan's divorced mother.
As such, we tried to trace them from the
clues written in her mother's letter.
But, meanwhile...
Miss!
Love is magic, attack the mystery.
On Saturday nights, be sure to click on Conan!
Ran's whereabouts and the truth behind this case...
Heiji and I are about to team up to solve them!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Near the Mountaintop Station up the ropeway...
Hattori and Uncle found Haruna-chan lying unconscious.
But Ran wasn't there...
And the suspicious man from before was nowhere to be found.
Sorry, Ran...
If only I could move freely...
I've already reported it to the police.
Tabuse-san and the others are headed to the hospital.
I see.
Sorry to let you down.
No, I'm the one who should have noticed this earlier.
The reason why Haruna-chan didn't visit the Kinosaki
Cultural Museum like she did three years ago...
Probably lies in her mother's letter:
"...Kinosaki Cultural Museum, we unexpectedly..."
She couldn't read the kanji for "Kinosaki Cultural Museum."
However, she could read the word "Straw," which...
Kinosaki Straw Works Museum
Caused her to visit the Kinosaki Straw Works Museum instead.
Why she went to the Mountaintop Station
up the ropeway can also be explained.
For the "Kinosaki Hot Spring Station" in
the letter, she could only read "Station."
And next to it is the kanji for "mountain," so
she mistook it as "Mountaintop Station."
Kinosaki Hot Spring Station
Since we staked out the Kinosaki Hot Spring Station...
We couldn't make it to the Mountaintop Station in time.
Geez, kids can be really confusing sometimes.
Hattori, there wasn't anything inside Haruna's backpack, was there?
No.
But we can't say that the culprit already took the Rainbow's Child.
Yeah, he wouldn't have to attack Ran if that were the case.
The Rainbow's Child must've been hidden by Haruna-chan.
I think it's safe to assume that the one who took the
Rainbow's Child from the museum was Haruna-chan.
Handa Kaho (35)
Sculptor - Haruna's Mother
Why... are you here?
I'm friends with the hospital director.
He notified me.
How's Haruna?
Me? Take the Rainbow's Child?
Stop talking nonsense, how could I do such a thing?
Be quiet.
You're in a hospital.
Where have you been all this time?
At Michiko's.
Mama?
At any rate, give me back the Rainbow's Child.
That is my museum's property.
I told you, I did not take that thing!
Knock it off, already.
Shut up!
This has nothing to do with you!
It does.
My daughter was dragged into this as well.
What do you mean?
Mind if I ask you something?
Could it be!?
Damn it!
Please...
Wait up, Haruna-chan.
Geez, why are you still following me?
As you requested, l've turned off my cell phone
I won't tell anyone, either.
I'll help you find your mom and dad, so let's go home.
I don't have anyone at home.
Mama divorced us and left Haruna alone.
Papa only thinks about work, work, work.
I bet he doesn't care about Haruna...
I see.
Me too.
When I was young, my mom and dad decided to live separately.
Haruna-chan's feelings...
I think I can relate a little bit.
So...
So, if you don't do as I say, something terrible will happen to that girl.
Miss...
Bingo!
Haruna-chan's on the move.
OK.
Do not lose sight of them, Hattori.
If the culprit kidnapped Ran because he couldn't
get his hands on the Rainbow's Child...
He'll next order Haruna to do things for him.
Just as we deduced.
Looks like she spotted us.
Driver.
Finally, this is more like the Detective Boys!
We will save Ran-san ourselves!
Huh?
I've lost my badge!
It's gone!
Did you drop it at the spa?
No way!
Somebody...
Somebody help!
This is...
What Ayumi-chan dropped...
Her Detective Boys Badge!
The badge...
Someone's calling us?
Conan-kun, maybe?
Could it be my...?
Wait.
I can hear something.
The sound of drums is coming from the badge?
Could it be, Ran is...
That's it!
I think...
1:00 PM.
This!
Shinkorou!
Shinkorou (Clock Tower)
They'll sound the drum in Shinkorou at 1:00PM!
Which means Ran's...
Izushi City
Most likely in Izushi!
Mother-child Jizou?
Haruna-chan prayed there?
Yeah.
I don't know its formal name, but...
It's an old Jizou statue covered in moss.
She's holding a baby in her hand.
Haruna-chan also prayed at Kijinboshi's.
And at the Mountaintop Station up the ropeway...
Is Jibo Kannon.
This time it's a Mother-child Jizou...
Could it be?
Looks like your deduction is the same as mine, Kudou.
Yeah.
In that case, Haruna-chan's goal would be...
What are those two talking about?
Sukyou Temple
Izushi Meiji Museum
Izushi Karou House
Eirakukan (Playhouse)
Damn it!
You go that way.
You lost her?
What now!?
What're you guys talking about!?
Uncle, calm down.
Walking down those stone steps is tiring!
Really!
My calves are all swollen!
I wonder how many steps that was?
Hey, check it out.
The place we just visited...
It's called Gonbee-san.
Gonbee-san?
Interesting.
What?
Did you hear something?
My guests, are you going to visit Gonbee-san?
Driver, you know where Gonbee-san is?
Yes.
Go there!
Will do.
Ran, wait for me!
I see, this is it!
I finally got it...
The truth behind this case!
Izushi Castle
I'm wiped.
I'm too hungry to take another step.
You two are too wimpy!
Kannouden (Shrine)
We're here...
Kannouden.
Why is this Gonbee-san?
Well, it's because...
This Kannouden is dedicated to an ancient Izushi feudal lord...
And his name was Gonbee Hidehisa.
So that's why it's Gonbee-san...
I bet that girl from the detective agency is around here.
Damn it!
It's that group of women again!
What was that for?
Hey, let us pass!
Get in!
How's that Miss?
Hurry!
We lost her!
Chase that car!
Move!
I said move!
I have no choice...
Hey!
I definitely won't let you escape!
That brat...
Where'd they go!?
Sagara Michiko (35)
Straw Works Craftswoman
Auntie!
Haruna-chan?
Auntie, Mom asked you to keep something for her, didn't she?
Kaho did?
You mean this, right?
Finally found it!
You were searching for this?
What's that!?
I told you to lead me to where the Rainbow's Child is!
What's with you?
I can't let you separate them!
If you want to take it, take this too!
What's that supposed to mean?
Exactly how it sounds.
You...
Haruna-chan, you were searching for that, right?
Is that paired with the Rainbow's Child?
Who... are you?
Edogawa Conan...
A detective.
Detective?
Cut the shit!
Miss, I'm taking a break...
Yui!
Hold it!
Finally found you!
Sorry to make you wait.
Ran-chan, are you all right!?
Shit!
Let go!
Shut up!
Conan-kun!
Oh no!
Hold it right there!
You all right, Conan-kun?
And Ran-neechan?
I'm totally fine!
Seems so.
Ran!
Dad!
Ran, you all right?
You're not hurt?
That's great, that's great!
Dad...
Please, don't cry.
What's this about...
Kou-chan!
Kou-chan, what were you doing?
Geez, I was looking for you!
Hey, say something!
Kou-chan! Kou-chan!
I am terribly sorry!
Sorry to have caused you trouble.
What an idiot.
You did this just because you wanted to pay off your loans?
Sorry, Yui.
He's an idiot, but he's not a bad person.
So please, forgive him just this time.
I beg of you.
Why did you do such a thing?
Actually, someone asked me to.
It was after you refused my close-up interview and I was in a pickle.
That someone, could it be Kamachi-san?
How did you...
Kamachi-san... the museum director?
Isn't it about time you came out now?
Kamachi-san!
I don't know what you're talking about.
Kamachi Takeshi (45)
Tabuse Museum Director
A while ago, Yumoto-kun did publish an interview about or museum.
But I merely happened to be here this time.
Kamachi-san...
The man in this photo was not Yumoto-san.
At that time, Yumoto-san was doing a close-up interview on Uncle.
This is you, isn't it?
That's stupid.
Stop talking nonsense.
Kamachi-san, could it be that you knew all along?
From the museum documents or something like that...
You learned that the Rainbow's Child is
actually paired with its mother's sculpture.
And, you also knew that Haruna-chan wanted to combine
the Rainbow's Child with the mother's sculpture.
Which is why you purposely created a chance
when you were rearranging the exhibitions...
In order to let Haruna-chan take the Rainbow's Child away.
Then, you followed Haruna-chan...
And planned to return with both of them once
she led you to the mother's sculpture, right?
However, not only Heiji-niichan but also Uncle
came, so you panicked, didn't you?
That's why you used Yumoto-san, to try
to at least recover the Rainbow's Child.
That's right.
However, Haruna-chan didn't have the Rainbow's Child...
And then I tasered that girl...
Enough of this nonsense!
Do you have any evidence to support that?
Say, what's with the smudge on your pants?
What about it?
Genta, you were knocked over by a man with sunglasses, right?
He's an enemy of my crab-cream cone!
But what about him?
Kojima-kun, your badge is pretty dirty.
Yeah, I dripped ice cream on it.
Could that smudge be...
What's this?
No doubt, it's the smell from my crab-cream!
It's a match!
Which means the man with sunglasses
who knocked him over was you.
Give it up.
I've used up everything... the museum's budget.
That's when I thought to sell the Rainbow's
Child and its mother's sculpture as a set...
In order to fill in the gap...
As for the Rainbow's Child...
The first thing Haruna-chan did after arriving in Kinosaki was
to hide it in a locker at the Kinosaki Hot Spring station.
Beautiful!
How wonderful.
They are!
They're beautiful.
This happened because you wrote unnecessary things to her!
You're one to talk, if only you took good care of her...
What was that?
You left us in the first place!
It's because you never listened to what I said!
Knock it off already!
Haven't you realized it yet?
Think of Haruna-chan's feelings when she took the Rainbow's Child.
Haruna-chan was lonely.
Her mom left her for a long time...
And her dad worked nonstop everyday.
That's when she thought of combining the two sculptures into one...
Thinking this would bring back her family.
This was how she felt when she carried the Rainbow's Child.
Just like...
Just like the bird that is said to bring happiness...
The stork.
Mama, Papa...
Haruna...
Haruna!
I'm sorry, Haruna!
Mama...
Haruna... I'm sorry, really.
Papa...
Papa, Papa...
Haruna-chan...
Homeland for the Oriental White Stork
Look at that, Papa, Mama!
So many!
I wish my family could be like that eventually...
Look at it fly!
No good!
We can't save him like this!
The two cars we saw at the convenience store are all smashed up.
This car... it has a grill guard installed.
Geez.
If you wander around again, Dad's going to get angry at you!
Looks like the case is closed!
I'm counting on you then, Ran.
Next Conan's Hint
Rainbow
Look forward to the Next Episode
Huh? Isn't the broadcast at 6:00 PM?
[Note: "Niji" can mean
"rainbow" or "2:00"]
By "niji," we mean "rainbow."
Wow!