Look, a rainbow!
See, it's beautiful!
A rainbow?
Geez, you played mahjong all night!
But I had to!
It was the game of a lifetime.
We gambled with Youko-chan's precious photos!
And that was something that required you to go to the hot springs?
Look at that!
Love is magic, attack the mystery.
On Saturday nights, be sure to click on Conan!
It has a clear view but it's prone to accidents.
At the diabolical intersection, a tiny suspicion surfaces!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
An accident!
Ran, go check on that car!
Got it!
No good!
We can't save him like this!
Ran, how is it over there?
I can't get the door open!
Please hang in there!
Say, both of these cars stopped at the
convenience store a while ago, right?
I don't care about that!
Are you all right?
I... gu... ess...
What happened?
It looks like you were in an accident.
What about the other car?
I wanted to help him...
But the car was on fire and I can't go near it.
Are you all right?
Ran, call an ambulance and the police!
Yes!
Why did this happen...
What a huge accident I've caused...
What should I do?
I've caused something irreversible...
Well, well, calm down.
Want a cigarette?
Thanks... but I don't smoke.
I see.
You were driving the green car, weren't you?
Yes.
I have some questions to ask, will that be all right?
First, your name and occupation.
Kurumatani Seiji (28)
Auto Mechanic
I'm Kurumatani Seiji, an auto mechanic.
And you're the primary witness?
Your name?
Wow, so you're the famous detective Mouri Kogorou-san?
I've heard a lot about you.
Nah, it's no big deal.
He's that Mouri Kogorou?
Michida Junko (38)
Okuho Police Dept, Traffic Division Patrol Officer
I'm so honored to have such a
famous detective here to help us out.
So, Mouri-san, you were the first to discover
the two cars involved in the accident, right?
Yes, the red car was already on fire.
The driver, Hayami Shun-san, was confirmed dead.
Kurumatani-san...
Could you tell me what happened during the accident?
Yes.
When I was entering the intersection...
For some reason, I didn't notice the other car approaching at all.
And I kept driving straight ahead...
Then, red car suddenly entered my line of sight...
I slammed my brakes and turned my steering wheel...
But still couldn't avoid it.
Before you entered the intersection, did you not stop for a moment?
I'm sorry, I neglected to do that.
That's why the accident happened.
The iron bars are severely bent...
This car...
It has a front grill guard installed.
Regardless...
What you said about the other car suddenly
coming into sight is unbelievable.
Perhaps you actually dozed off or looked elsewhere?
I didn't.
I looked in front of me and drove as usual.
I just didn't notice the other car.
That's impossible!
This intersection is in the middle of an
open field and you had a clear view!
Maybe it's because of that.
That?
This place is notorious for being accident-prone.
Locals have even nicknamed it the "Intersection of Fear."
"Intersection of Fear," you say?
According to one theory, the "collision course
phenomenon" may play a role in this type of accident.
What's that?
That "college course phenomenon"?
It's "collision course phenomenon."
Even during the daytime and with a clear view
of the intersection, accidents may still occur.
If two cars approach the same intersection at the same speed...
They will constantly stay at a 45 degree angle relative to each other.
In other words, the other car will always be in
the same spot of the driver's outer visual field.
Although humans have both central and peripheral vision...
It's hard to detect tiny movements with only our peripheral vision.
It might take too much time to finally notice the other car.
As such, it's already too late when the cars come
up on the intersection, and a collision is inevitable.
Then, Kurumatani-san's accident was caused by this...
"Collie-show course phenomenon"?
It's "collision course", you know.
I think that was why the accident happened.
I can't believe there's such a phenomenon...
If I had paid more attention, this wouldn't have happened...
But still...
There aren't any brake marks coming from the red car at all.
The other driver in the red car didn't
notice the incoming traffic either.
In that case...
The "collision course phenomenon"
explanation becomes all the more plausible.
But, in a wide field such as this...
Both drivers still couldn't notice each other?
I can't accept that so easily!
Since you're a private detective, it's second
nature for you to doubt everything, I guess.
The two cars we saw at the convenience store are all smashed up.
Right, Uncle?
Were both cars at the convenience store?
Yeah.
When I stopped to buy canned coffee...
I saw the two cars leave the parking lot around the same time.
Hold on.
If you think about it, this is too coincidental.
What is it?
The two cars departed at the same time, but drove on different roads...
A few minutes later, they crashed into each other here.
Was that merely a coincidence?
I think it was a coincidence...
To be safe, shall we go check with the convenience store?
Yes, this person.
He came around 2:00PM.
He had quite an attitude so it bothered me.
Sir, did you come yesterday?
Out there, I think I remember seeing that green car of yours.
That belongs to that bastard, Kurumatani!
Don't mix things up!
He snapped at me like that.
Don't tell me...
He really mentioned "Kurumatani," you're sure?
Yeah.
That makes Hayami-san an acquaintance of Kurumatani-san.
I knew something was fishy.
In that case...
How about this person?
This person...
He was the one who was quarrelling with the young man earlier.
I see.
By the time we saw the two cars leave, it was
after those two had finished their fight.
The crash happened shortly after that.
If I recall, at that time...
Let's go, Conan-kun.
Yes.
Kurumatani-san.
You were actually acquaintanced with
Hayami-san, who drove that foreign red car, no?
No...
I've seen his face before, but I don't know if I'd call us acquaintances.
Then, what were you arguing about with
Hayami-san at the convenience store?
The store manager witnessed what happened between you two.
Actually, about that red foreign car...
It was sold by a friend at a used car company three months ago.
I heard that the customer who bought it wasn't
paying his loans, so I tried to talk to him.
But he snapped at me, and it turned into a fight.
I see.
By the way, why did you drive this way?
Your residence should be in the opposite direction.
I just... I had extra time to spare, so I drove around to chill.
The rainbow was beautiful, too!
Rainbow?
Was there a rainbow?
But why all these questions?
They have nothing to do with the accident.
I get it!
Kurumatani-san, you're an auto mechanic, aren't you?
Yes, and?
Also, you already knew that this place is prone to car accidents!
No.
After you argued with him at the store...
You rigged his brakes while Hayami-san
went shopping for a few minutes!
It'd be a piece of cake for a mechanic like you!
That was why there were no brake marks from that red foreign car!
However, we didn't find any abnormalities
from the red car's braking system.
Is that so?
Then, you must've jammed something under his brake pedal.
It's done often to disguise accidents!
You did that because you wanted to teach Hayami-san a lesson.
But, to your surprise, this caused a
serious accident and Hayami-san died.
That's why you had to pretend
you knew nothing, didn't you?
But we didn't discover anything suspicious inside that red car either.
Detective, please don't come up with strange stories!
Dad, don't smoke in the open!
There's an ashtray inside the car, you know?
The car ashtray?
I see...
So that's how it was.
What were you doing, Conan-kun?
Nothing much.
We've prepared the footage from the surveillance camera.
You have a surveillance camera at this place?
It's because there are so many accidents around here.
I see.
No kids allowed!
The red car entered the intersection without hitting the brakes.
And the green car smashed into it soon after.
Then, the green car crashed into the billboard...
And the red car fell into the ditch.
I don't see anything out of the ordinary.
It looks that way.
There's no doubt that this was merely an accident.
Damn...
I really want a look at that footage...
Geez.
If you wander around again, Dad's gonna get get angry at you!
Huh?
Ran-neechan, excuse me.
Conan-kun!
Geez...
This is...
Ran-neechan...
Dad said so?
Excuse me...
How was it?
It seems like it was a normal accident, just as you testified.
However, I'm holding you responsible for not stopping before entering.
I am terribly sorry.
Looks like the case is closed!
I'm counting on you then, Ran.
I'm going to take your statement regarding the accident at the station.
Please come with me.
Understood.
Hold on a moment.
This is no ordinary accident.
It's a premeditated...
Murder case.
What do you mean by that?
Kurumatani-san said he coincidentally met
Hayami-san at the convenience store.
That was a lie.
What are you talking about?
The boy from my agency just checked out your car ashtray.
There were many cigarette butts inside.
How strange.
You said you don't smoke.
That's...
The brand of the cigarettes is Paradise.
And there are bite marks on the cigarette filters.
It was the same...
The same as the one at the convenience store's parking lot.
The smoked cigarette tossed by Hayami-san.
In other words, on the way to the convenience store,
Hayami-san was actually driving the green car.
Perhaps while you serviced Hayami-san's red foreign car at
your repair shop, you lent him the green car as a loaner.
After you serviced it, you called him to that convenience store
to exchange his car with your green loaner, didn't you?
And you murdered Hayami-san, disguising it as a car accident!
What do you mean, Mouri-san?
In other words, Kurumatani-san planned to
crash his own car into Hayami-san's all along.
That's stupid!
I'm injured, too!
Without some luck, I could've died as well!
You had no reason to worry.
Because your car...
Was protected by a sturdy front grill guard.
You planned to injure yourself a little, so the
accident would look all the more convincing.
You're just bluffing!
It was an accident caused by the collision course phenomenon!
The other car didn't hit its brakes at all.
That's the best evidence, isn't it?
I agree.
Mouri-san, I think it's hard for people to manipulate this phenomenon.
The reason why Hayami-san didn't hit the brakes
wasn't due to the collision course phenomenon.
Kurumatani-san deployed a trick to disable
Hayami-san from hitting the brakes.
They just said nothing was suspicious in the car!
Not in the car.
The trick was placed at a different place.
Ran!
Yes!
That is a billboard covered with a light-reflective
sheet, like they do with traffic signs.
It's usually facing the direction Hayami-san had approached from.
If you shine light on the billboard, there will be a resulting glare.
The glare does strain the eye.
I'm afraid that Kurumatani-san adjusted the
position that the billboard faced beforehand.
That way, Hayami-san would be blinded by the
billboard reflecting sunlight directly into his eyes.
Why didn't we notice that when we
were watching the camera footage?
It was outside the camera's range, so it wasn't caught on tape.
After leaving the convenience store, Hayami-san's car was
moving alongside the ditch, approaching this intersection.
Because he had the right-of-way over other traffic...
He didn't slow down, and drove straight ahead.
By then, the billboard had been adjusted so that the reflected
sunlight would shine right before the intersection.
Without knowing this, Hayami-san drove straight into the intersection...
What's this!?
Hayami-san was blinded by the glare,
and couldn't hit the brakes in time.
And because of the afterimage caused by the light
interfering with his eyes, he couldn't see your car.
You chose to meet at the convenience store at 2:00PM...
Because you calculated beforehand
where the glare would shine, right?
Don't tell me, the reason he crashed into the billboard...
Was to hide the fact he adjusted the board's direction?
And perhaps the reason you crashed into
Hayami-san's driver seat was also...
Actually, I planned to run straight into him, crushing him to pieces!
Hayami was the culprit who ran over my
little sister with his car one year ago.
What?
Half a year ago, I recognized the foreign red
car that came to my shop for maintenance.
After that, all I could think about was revenge.
Then Hayami brought his car in for maintenance again.
That was when I planned this whole thing.
When I returned his car, I asked him to turn himself over to the police.
But he acted like he didn't care.
That's when I proceeded with my plan!
If he had turned himself in, I would've spared his life!
That coward!
Yet you kept quiet about killing Hayami-san
and disguising it as an accident.
You're the same kind of coward.
It's now your turn to turn yourself in.
Detective, when did you realize that I planned this?
When you said you didn't remember seeing a rainbow.
The collision course phenomenon requires
the driver to face straight ahead.
The reason you didn't notice a rainbow...
Wasn't it because all you thought about was crashing into
Hayami-san's car, meaning you only looked to the side?
If you let anger and revenge consume you...
You'll find yourself unable to behold the
beautiful sights right before your eyes.
Dad, speeding while you're sleepy is dangerous!
Don't worry.
I feel refreshed somehow!
You should, since I put you to sleep earlier.
If we don't return this car tonight, they're
gonna charge us an extra rental fee!
It would cost much more if you get into an accident!
We're fine, we're fine!
Speaking of which, we're gambling for Youko-chan's
premiere DVD in our mahjong tournament tonight!
Wait for me, Youko-chan!
That's the "Kogorou-never-learns phenomenon" for you.
That evil-eyed yawny girl.
Well, excuse me...
For being an evil-eyed yawny girl.
You hitchhiked and got in a car with bad guys!?
These two people... who the hell are they?
If they're from the Black Organization...
What do I do?
Half-kill and... overkill!?
Next Conan's Hint
Dialect
Look forward to the Next Episode