All right, Conan-kun.
Can I count on you to watch the house?
Bye, then.
Bye!
Ran's heading for her club...
Uncle's investigating an infidelity case...
And Genta and the others haven't called me.
Looks like I can finally have some time to myself today.
Love is magic, attack the mystery.
On Saturday nights, be sure to click on Conan!
The professor and Haibara are hitchhiking?
Inside the car awaits a suspicious couple!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Hey, hey, hey...
Your Beetle broke down again, Professor?
That's right...
There's a presentation for new inventions in Yamanashi.
Oh, that one you attend every year.
Yeah, I was on my way back after the presentation...
And it suddenly stopped running.
I called the towing company to tow away my car.
And they gave us a ride to the nearest bus stop, but...
Hasn't the bus come yet?
Ah, no...
Excuse me, I'm not getting on.
Hey, did you lose your wallet?
Yeah...
Seems like I dropped it somewhere.
There wasn't a lot of money in it anyway, so it's all right.
I see.
You called me to ask Uncle Kogorou to pick you up, but...
Uncle is out on an infidelity investigation.
Oh no!
It's not a problem, is it?
Just have her come pick you up in a taxi.
Her?
It's her, her!
She's taking care of your house, isn't she?
That evil-eyed yawny girl.
Well, excuse me...
For being an evil-eyed yawny girl.
Why the hell're you there!?
Aren't you always calling the Professor's inventions stupid?
Yeah.
I didn't want to come, but...
l also had no desire to stay alone in that house.
With that eerie, unknown person living next door...
I prefer not to stay.
You mean Okiya Subaru-san?
Don't worry about him.
He seems to be a good person.
That's right!
Why don't you ask Subaru-san to pick you up in his car?
Listen...
I don't know how you feel about him, but...
I suspect he's a member of what you refer to as the Black Organization.
Subaru-san?
Impossible.
I felt it!
During that Ikkaku Rock case...
I felt that pressure coming from him.
That was...
Undoubtedly like the organization.
It's not like that.
If that were true, you and I would already be...
Perhaps you're...
Keeping him in your house so you can monitor him?
Using me as bait, you want to see whether he makes a move or not!
Idiot!
You think I would do that?
At any rate...
Can't you think of an excuse and get him out of your house?
They probably used information they obtained from him...
Maybe the fact that I'm the Sherry who betrayed the organization...
And the fact that you're alive when you're thought to be dead...
Have both been exposed!
So, to ensure we're killed discreetly,
they may already be on the move...
And their assassins could already be closing in on us.
If you guys are in trouble, I could give you a ride.
You don't have any money, right?
Thank you very much.
We're headed to Tokyo, though.
Is that all right?
Yeah, we only need to get back to Tokyo as well.
Have a seat in the back, then.
Thank you.
Looks like we've found a way to get home.
By the time we make it back, come up
with a reason to kick that person out!
Hey, Haibara!
My, you've sure saved us.
This guy didn't get much sleep last night.
Yes...
It's a little packed, but bare with it.
"Packed"?
I mean our luggage back there.
It's made it a bit cramped, isn't it?
Say, by the way...
Can you explain it to us?
How you knew...
That we had no money?
I guess she must've heard me talking on the phone a while ago.
I said that I dropped my wallet.
Do you think you can hear exactly what someone's
saying on the side of the road while you're driving?
If she had stopped the car right after passing
us, that would have made more sense.
But instead, you stopped before you even passed us, didn't you?
Ah, I stopped the car because...
I saw you standing at the bus stop, but
didn't get on the bus when it came.
Are you trying to say you overheard our
conversation after you stopped the car?
No.
When I stopped, I saw something on the old man...
That stain on his chest.
I spilled some cola there.
About that, you spilled cola while wearing your seatbelt, right?
Since there aren't any stains in the middle.
Also, it must've happened recently.
Otherwise, you would've changed while at home, no?
In other words, you were driving until just a while ago.
But I didn't see your car at all.
And, as I was buying coffee from the
roadside vending machine a while ago...
I saw a tow truck towing a car away.
I figured you had a problem with your car,
and called the towing company to move it.
Then, you had them drop you off at the bus stop.
You wanted to get on the bus, but realized that
you lost your wallet - that's what I think.
That's exactly what happened.
As I thought.
Then, what do you say we get going now?
Sweetie.
Fine.
Quite a bit of traffic.
Seems like there's an accident ahead.
You can take a nap until we get there, if you'd like.
Ah, thank you.
Say, where in Tokyo is your house?
Beika City, 2nd District.
Beika City?
What a coincidence.
Coincidence?
We happen to be heading there as well.
Beika City, 5th District...
The Mouri Detective Agency.
Oh, so that's how it is!
Actually, we're friends of his and...
I suddenly feel sleepy.
Grandpa, won't you take a nap with me?
Please wake us when we arrive!
Sure.
What's wrong, Ai-kun?
They're very suspicious, these people.
You saw it, right?
The face of the man sitting in the passenger's seat.
He had a large scar and an eerie look.
But we can't just assume they're suspicious...
Didn't you notice?
On the back of the driver's seat.
There's a hole...
And there are two on the left side back seat's door.
I'm afraid these are bullet holes.
And I see signs of them trying to clean this up, but...
In the seam of the seat cover, there still stains from the blood.
What'd you say!?
Something wrong?
Oh, nope!
Grandpa was talking in his sleep!
I see.
Anyway, we should pretend to be
asleep and gather some information.
About their identities, and the reason why...
They want to visit Mouri's Detective Agency.
Hey.
Who're they?
The load increased while I was asleep?
I picked them up along the way.
They seem to be friends of Detective Mouri.
What great news for us.
Now we won't have to blindly search for his place.
Speaking of which, what do you think about that brat?
"Brat"?
He's always with Mouri Kogorou; the
brat that goes by Edogawa Conan.
Well, while I do think he has a sharp mind for a kid, why do you ask?
I have a feeling he's the one who's really in control of everything.
He's a fierce monster, that brat.
Well, we are bringing him a surprise.
If we treat him well, he may happily blurt out everything.
But, do you really think that'll be enough?
Yeah.
Half-kill is enough for now.
Half-kill!?
It's a bit too early, isn't it?
They need to wait some...
For my overkill.
I can't wait to meet them.
Yeah.
They'll cry for joy after I show them my half-kill.
Mine isn't your average half-kill, you know.
I can't wait to meet them.
Yeah.
They'll cry for joy after I show them my half-kill.
Mine isn't your average half-kill, you know.
Oh, you're awake?
Could it be, you overheard our conversation?
Conversation?
I just woke up because of grandpa's snoring.
Did you say something you didn't want us to hear?
No, if you didn't hear anything, forget about it.
But what a traffic jam we have here.
Even though we're already in Tokyo.
Shall we have some tea at a drive-in diner?
Maybe after a rest, the traffic jam will have cleared up.
We'd also like to ask about your relationship to Detective Mouri.
Of course, that's only if you're not in a hurry to get home.
If you want to get home as quickly as possible...
Get out of our car and fly back yourself.
Fly back?
How could we fly?
Understood.
Let's rest at the drive-in diner.
Then, mind helping me read the map?
It's in the glove compartment.
A gun!?
What!?
You hitchhiked and got in a car with bad guys!?
Yeah, a man and a woman.
Seems like they wanted you and
Detective Mouri to tell them something.
Are they with the Black Organization?
Who knows.
They didn't emit that scent like the others, but...
They do have a gun.
Are you still with them?
Yeah.
The Professor is talking with them and I pretended
to go to the restroom so I could give you a call.
Is the Professor all right?
No need to worry.
In regards to our relationship, we decided to tell
them that you helped us looked for our missing cat.
That's not what I mean!
If they're dangerous people, you should escape now!
Idiot!
Those people said they want to half-kill you.
They're heading to your place!
We can't just leave them like that!
Half-kill?
The man said it.
"Half-kill is enough. It's still too early for overkill."
Overkill!?
In other words, they'll first keep you barely
alive so they can probe you for information.
After that, they'll proceed to slaughter you.
Hey, are you sure they really aren't from the Black Organization!?
Well, I can't say for sure now.
If their goal was to find my whereabouts, as
the one who betrayed the organization...
It would make sense.
In any case...
I'm rushing to that drive-in diner on my skateboard.
I'll be there in 30 minutes.
Until I arrive, try to stall them as long as you can!
Stall them?
How?
Just say you happened to meet a friend
who's going back to Tokyo from Chiba...
And you decided to go home in their car instead!
Chiba!?
We're at the drive-in diner between Yamanashi and Tokyo!
A lie like that would be uncovered in no time!
After they realize it's a lie, they'll surely
be on guard and try to find you, right?
I see.
So, before that, we're supposed to hide somewhere in the diner?
But if they don't see through our lie...
If they aren't that smart, then there's no need to worry.
I'll call Detective Takagi to set up an ambush at the detective agency.
I'll tell him that they're dangerous people with a gun!
With my tranquilizer gun and soccer ball,
I should be able to beat those two, but...
What then?
If they're from the Black Organization...
What do I do?
You'll ride with a friend who's going back to Tokyo from Chiba?
That's nice, isn't it?
Yes.
Thank you for giving us a ride up until now.
Bye.
A friend? That's a lie.
Yeah.
But why?
As I thought...
Our conversation about half-kill...
Seems like they overheard it.
As you thought...
Those two realized it was a lie and started searching for us.
And?
Where are you?
We're hiding in the restroom for now.
But them finding us is just a matter of time...
Perhaps they have a grudge against Uncle
Kogorou because of some case he solved before.
Tell me what those two look like!
The woman is wearing a knit cap and sunglasses.
Her hair is parted on both sides in the front.
The man is dark skinned and has an unshaven face.
I also saw a large scar on his left eye...
A large scar on his left eye?
Yeah, they're definitely not harmless people.
In the glove compartment of their car...
They had a gun.
And there are three bullet holes in the car.
I even saw where traces of blood had been wiped away.
Notice anything else?
Anything else...
Oh, that's right.
They're saying weird things.
Weird things?
"It's a little packed, but bare with it."
"If you want to get home as quickly as possible,
get out of our car and fly back yourself."
Packed...
Fly?
Are they talking in code?
Anyway, I'll be there in five minutes.
So just hang in the-
Hey! Old man, you in there!?
If you are, answer me!
It's occupied...
Seems like we're out of time.
He's knocking on each of the stall doors.
I'll be done soon...
What should we do?
Wait, I think "packed" and "fly" are...
Kudou-kun?
Half-kill and overkill...
A large scar on his left eye...
Hey, what's wrong!?
Here he comes!
Answer me, will ya!?
Kudou-kun!?
It's all right.
Just use an adult-like voice and shout that
you're using the toilet. I think he'll leave soon.
If that guy realizes there's a woman inside, he'll be embarrassed.
I see.
Looks like the person inside must be that old man.
HOW RUDE!
CAN'T YOU TELL I'M USING THIS?
YOU FREAKING PERVERT!
Ah, excuse me.
My bad.
Wait, this is the men's room, you know!
I figured.
The Professor couldn't possibly go in the ladies' room.
You figured!?
Wouldn't he realize it was us by my voice!?
Is there a window you can use to get out of the restroom?
There is...
Then you and the Professor should get out from there.
We're out.
Now what?
Let's see.
If you look around, I think...
That lady will be waiting.
And soon...
The man should also appear.
Just give up and surrender!
Give up!?
Don't worry!
These two...
Are police officers!
P-
Police!?
But why are you wearing sunglasses?
Actually, not that long ago...
Uehara Yui (29)
Nagano Prefecture Police Detective
I got clocked by a suspect we arrested and ended up with a black eye.
Getting away with just a black eye isn't so bad.
As for me...
Yamato Kansuke (35)
Nagano Prefecture Police Detective
My forehead got nicked by a bullet from him, and ended up like this.
Well, with your scars and those sunglasses...
No wonder they thought you were bad guys!
Not long ago, we had just chased down a guy, but...
When we tried to get him in the car...
He pulled out a concealed gun and started firing at us.
As we tried to subdue him...
I got a black eye and Kan-chan injured his forehead.
So the bullet holes and blood inside their car were due to that.
But, you figured out it was us pretty quickly.
"Packed" means a tight fit.
"Fly" means to drive in Nagano dialect.
Someone from Nagano who knows so much about us...
And has a scar on his left eye - that has to be Inspector Yamato.
But you shouldn't joke like that...
With the half kill and overkill talk.
We figured you mistook us as dangerous people because of that.
You tried to escape even though you
had no money, so we looked for you!
A misunderstanding?
By half-kill, I meant...
These botamochi!
Wow, they look delicious!
Yeah.
Kan-chan learned to make his botamochi from
his granny, so they're the best in the world!
And?
What does botamochi have to do with half-kill?
Botamochi is made from half-ground sweet
rice, so they're nicknamed half-kill.
And if we fully grind or "overkill" sweet rice, we get regular mochi.
So, by saying, "It's still too early for overkill"...
He meant it's too early to eat regular
mochi, which is for New Year's Day.
Correct.
Nagano people use terminology like that?
No, they're old-fashioned terms Kan-chan heard
from his granny, so he goes ahead and uses them.
Kan-chan likes shocking words like those.
And?
What happened in Nagano?
Surely you didn't come all this way just to give us botamochi.
Actually...
There's a case we can't solve.
So we came to borrow your wisdom.
The bloody...
Mystery of the "Red Wall."
What's that!?
The Bloody Red Wall...
Mystery?
Instead of "Hope"...
It's now the "Mansion of Death."
Kan-chan wasn't trying to get help from Detective Mouri.
Seems like it was actually from you.
This is the Red Wall.
Hey!
Don't tell me this is...
Human Blood?
Why the hell are you here!?
Koumei!
Next Conan's Hint
Red Spray
Look forward to the Next Episode