Professor Agasa and Haibara went to attend an invention conference.
On their way back, the Professor's car broke down...
And he also dropped his wallet, leaving them unable to board the bus.
Fortunately, they were able to get a ride in a passing car...
But there were bullet holes inside...
And traces of where blood had been wiped away.
In the glove compartment was also a gun.
Who are these two people who said they
intend to visit the Mouri Detective Agency?
Could they be members of the Black Organization?
After getting Haibara's call...
I headed toward the drive-in diner where the four of them were.
But the suspicious couple who were waiting outside...
Were from the Nagano police - Inspector Yamato Kansuke...
Yamato Kansuke (35)
Nagano Prefecture Police Inspector
And Detective Uehara Yui.
Uehara Yui (29)
Nagano Prefecture Police Inspector
Geez, talk about a huge false alarm.
But these two...
Just what is it they're doing here?
Love is magic, attack the mystery.
On Saturday nights, be sure to click on Conan!
A new character from Nagano — Inspector Koumei.
Together well unravel the mystery of the Red Wall!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
And?
What happened in Nagano?
Surely you didn't come all this way just to give us botamochi.
Actually...
There's a case we can't solve.
So we came to borrow your wisdom.
The bloody...
Mystery of the "Red Wall."
Hey, hey!
Are there really no roads smoother than this?
To think I, the famous detective Mouri
Korogou, had to hear you guys out...
And come all the way to Nagano to assist
you on this murder investigation of yours...
Not to mention that this kept me from eating any of that botamochi.
My apologies.
This is the shortcut, though.
And?
Isn't it about time you told us?
What this bloody Red Wall mystery is about.
Could it be that the wall was dyed deep red with
human blood, and is somewhere in the forest?
No, it's not.
"Bloody" was only Kan-chan's talk.
But actually...
Hey, stop it right there.
Kan-chan...
Preconceptions will interfere with your deductions.
We wanted you to look at the scene yourself;
that's why we bothered to escort you from Tokyo.
Also, Uehara...
I'm technically your superior.
Stop calling me "Kan-chan."
Fine, fine...
Inspector Yamato Kansuke!
Still, it'd be nice if you at least told
us where we're headed, you know...
To an old mansion built in this forest.
One called the "Mansion of Hope."
"Mansion of Hope," you say?
What a charming name.
It was only known by that name until three years ago.
Right, three years ago there was a woman...
Whose miserable body was found
in the storage room of that mansion.
After that, the locals gave it a new name.
Instead of "Hope"...
It's now the "Mansion of Death."
The Mansion of Death...
It's become quite old, but it's still a splendid house.
That's because it was a villa owned by someone rich.
Say.
To think that Inspector Yamato is seeking help from Uncle Kogorou...
It's not like him, is it?
Ah, that's because...
Someone he vowed not to lose to is also
participating in this investigation.
You mean...
That "someone" is also a police officer?
Yeah.
But unlike us detectives with the Nagano
prefecture police headquarters...
He's a detective with this area's
local police station, the Arano police.
But if he's the local detective...
Why would a headquarters detective compete with him?
To be honest, that man...
He was a classmate of Kan-chan's since elementary school.
It seems like they competed with each other in whatever they did.
Although he graduated with honors from the
law department of Touto University...
He didn't take the career test and went into the
prefectural police headquarters as a non-career, but...
Because of a case, this oddball
transferred to the local station in Arano.
Which means, they were actually colleagues
at the same Nagano police headquarters?
That's right.
He also bears a tactician-like name, just like Kan-chan's.
Hey, Uehara!
We're going inside.
Yes, sir!
Come to think of it, the name "Yamato Kansuke"...
It sounds really close to Takeda Shingen's
famous tactician, Yamamoto Kansuke.
Regardless...
Kan-chan has always been enraged by that rival of his.
He's never beaten this rival, so please give him a hand.
Kan-chan wasn't trying to get help from Detective Mouri...
Seems like it was actually from you.
Allow me to explain why they once called it the "Mansion of Hope."
When this mansion grew old, the
rich man who built it stopped using it.
He decided to handpick talented,
prospective young people without money...
And let them live here technically for free...
Until they had fulfilled their dreams.
Well, as for that generous rich man
who occasionally visited this place...
Soon after he settled to give this mansion
to those people, he died of illness.
And most of those people, after two or three years,
moved out of this house to live on their own.
Since five or six years ago, the only ones still
living in this house were a married couple.
Hey, Uehara.
Show them the photos of the people who were living here.
Yes!
It was these six people.
The first photo you're looking at...
Is an illustrator, Akashi Shuusaku-san.
Next, an actor, Midorikawa Naoki-san.
The next one is a novelist, Kobashi Aoi-san.
Fashion designer, Yamabuki Shouji-san.
Computer graphic creator, Momose Takuto-san.
And the last is a musician, Naoki Shirou-san.
I may have heard those names somewhere...
Or maybe not, I guess.
Come to think of it...
I noticed something a while ago.
What is this?
There are traces of a torn paper that
had once been glued to this door.
You're right - this door has a similar outline.
I think those...
Were colors they used for identification, right?
Colors?
I bet they stuck colored paper on
the doors to distinguish their rooms.
Since all six people have colors in their names.
Idiot!
Their names are on the photos...
But no one has a name with the kanji of a color...
It's not the kanji, it's the pronunciation!
**********
I see.
Akashi Shuusaku-san is...
Red!
Midorikawa Naoki-san is...
Green!
That's correct.
Kobashi Aoi-san is blue.
And Yamabuki Shouji-san is golden yellow.
Momose Takuto-san is pink.
While Naoki Shirou-san is... white?
See?
All six people have colors in their names.
Good find, Conan-kun!
Not only the rooms.
The six people also...
Used colors to distinguish their own names as well.
Look!
This is an old cooking duty list we found in the storage room.
What's written on it isn't their names, but their colors in kanji.
I'm assuming...
They even called one another by color instead of by name.
And?
Where's the room where the body was found?
Here.
What's with those cardboard boxes stacked on that cart?
They're only books.
But there's a lot of them, which makes them heavy.
This door swings outwards, and was blocked by the cart at that time.
The one who was inside...
Couldn't get out and ended up dying.
Then, that room is the rumored...
Yeah.
When we arrived...
He had already starved to death and lost a lot of weight.
In this disgusting...
Room with the Red Wall.
Hey...
Don't tell me this is...
Human blood?
It's paint.
Look.
The nozzle of the spray can lying on the floor.
It has the same red color as what's on the wall.
But... what are these?
These black and white chairs.
Looks like they've been purposely painted and nailed to the floor.
The body was upright on the white chair.
Could it be...
A message left by the culprit?
No, it's not that.
Because in this room...
A bug had been installed and was still here.
A bug?
I see.
The culprit eavesdropped on this room and
checked on the victim's vitals through the sounds.
Should the sounds stop, the culprit would've
come to this room to confirm the victim's death.
It was then that they'd retrieve the bug.
But since the bug was still here...
Yeah.
The victim was locked in here and the culprit never returned.
In other words...
The red wall, as well as the black and white chairs, are in fact...
Left by the victim...
A dying message!
Well?
The meaning of this red wall...
Figured it out yet?
Figured or not...
The message is "red."
Which means...
The person whose name contains "red"...
This Akashi guy is the culprit, isn't he?
Unfortunately...
The shriveled-up victim in this room...
Was that Akashi Shuusaku!
By the way...
About Akashi Shuusaku's wife, Kobashi Aoi...
Her surname was changed to Akashi, but...
Three years ago, she died in the storage room of this mansion.
Don't tell me, she was murdered too?
No, her heart had always been weak.
She was looking for something in the storage room
when she had a heart attack, and died like that.
Her husband Shuusaku-san...
He was completing his work in this room.
When he finally discovered his wife lying on the floor...
Half a day already passed.
No way...
In that case...
The "aka" doesn't mean the name.
Aka...
Aka no...
I see! The culprit was a stranger!
Hey, hey!
I didn't bring you here from Tokyo to listen
to you pulling answers out of your -
Attempting to meet a worthy man...
Without taking the proper course...
Is as if inviting him to come...
Yet barring the gate against him.
I see.
You didn't merely summon the famous detective here...
But instead personally escorted him here, which is good.
However...
Your demeanor toward Detective Mouri just then...
Was insolently rude.
As an old acquaintance of yours, I can only feel embarrassment...
Kansuke-kun.
Why the hell're you here!?
Local cops should stay out!
No, no.
This territory falls under the jurisdiction of the Arano police.
I'm afraid I cannot merely stand down.
Stop talking nonsense!
It's the truth.
What was that just now?
"Attempting to eat a woolly man"?
It's not "attempting to eat a woolly man"!
Liu Bei was from the Three Kingdoms era.
In order to recruit a famous sage as his tactician...
He decided to meet him personally by saying the following:
"Attempting to meat a worthy man without taking the proper course...
"Is as if inviting him to come yet barring the gate against him."
In other words...
"I'm trying to recruit a famous man, but if I summoned
him instead of properly paying him a visit...
"It will appear as if I don't really wish for him
to come and have closed the gate on him."
After saying that, Liu Bei even took
the effort and paid him three visits.
Hey, you didn't know a thing about Fuurinkazan.
Why are you so familiar with the Three Kingdoms?
Who cares?
I don't.
At any rate...
In regards to the mystery bequeathed to this room...
It isn't limited to this red wall nor the white and black chairs.
That sealed window was broken from the inside.
Through that opening, items such as tubes of paint, sprays...
And art supplies with colors were all thrown out.
The only one that remained in this room...
Was this red can of spray paint.
The victim bit into his own finger...
And used the blood to sign his name upon the edge of the wall.
To properly evaluate these clues...
It's logical to seek the assessment of a prominent detective.
Liu Bei...
Tactician...
Three visits?
Naturally, that would be done in my presence.
Given that, when the body was initially found...
Drawing utensils were scattered outside the mansion...
And it was those that caught my eye as I happened to pass by.
Hey, don't tell me that tactician is the famous...
Yes, he always held a feather fan.
While you may be from the headquarters...
That degree of disrespect toward me is unacceptable.
I think his name was...
I get it, I get it!
Stay as long as you'd like, even until you drop dead...
Shokatsuryou...
Koumei!
Ko-
Koumei!?
I have yet to introduce myself.
Morofushi Takaaki (35)
Nagano Prefecture Arano Station Inspector
My surname is Morosuhi...
And my name is Takaaki.
People refer to me by the Chinese pronounciation...
"Koumei."
In the future, please remember me.
I see...
Instead of Shokatsuryou Koumei...
shokatsu
He's "Local Detective Koumei," huh?
And?
What do you think?
Sleeping Kogorou-san!
This wall sprayed with red paint...
The victim's bloody signature at the bottom...
The sealed window being broken from the inside...
While painting materials were thrown outside through the opening...
And...
These two chairs which were painted white
and black and nailed down to the floor.
The man who was locked up in this room and starved to death...
What was it he wanted to tell us?
You know?
You're asking me if I know?
So, this can't be solved with ease even with
the wits of a reputable detective...
Red, white, and black!
He wanted to use those three colors to tell us something, right?
Because all the other colors were thrown out the window.
And this young boy is?
He's staying at Sleeping Kogorou's detective agency.
A brat named Edogawa Conan.
Edogawa Conan...
One more thing...
About these boxes stacked on that cart that was blocking the door.
You said there were books inside, but...
Whose are they?
They were Aoi-san's books.
Remember, we mentioned her earlier.
She's the wife of the man who starved to
death in this room - Akashi Shuusaku-san.
Three years ago, she died of illness in the storage
room - her maiden name was Kobashi Aoi-san.
The books from the shelves in her room were removed...
And put in those cardboard boxes.
She had a lot of books.
She was a novelist, too.
Then, maybe Aoi-san's siblings did this to
hold the victim responsible for her death.
Since, when Aoi-san had a heart attack in the storage room...
Shuusaku-san was busy drawing and
didn't find her until half a day later.
But, she had no siblings...
Aoi-san was an only child.
And both of her parents died early...
Then, those who used to live with these two people...
Those four men are suspicious, aren't they?
How come?
Because, the fact that there were many books in Aoi-san's room...
And that the door opens outward requires prior knowledge.
Otherwise, the culprit wouldn't think of placing a
cart filled with boxes of books to block the door.
In other words, the culprit...
Might be the actor, Midorikawa Naoki-san...
The fashion designer, Yamabuki Shouji-san...
The CG creator, Momose Takuto-san...
Or the musician, Naoki Shirou-san.
It's very likely to be one of them.
Isn't that right, Uncle Kogorou?
Yeah...
I see.
Up to this point, your deduction has been the same as ours.
The reason you didn't speak it out loud...
Is because you believe a deduction of this level need not be said, no?
What!?
Is that true!?
Yeah, I got it!
I'll confirm that myself!
What's wrong, Kan-chan...
No...
Inspector Yamato.
I'll tell you what's wrong.
The fingerprints on the doorknob inside the room...
And the fingerprints on the red spray paint can...
I thought that they had belonged to the victim, Akashi Shuusaku.
Listen up, Koumei!
They're from your subordinate who was with
you when you found the body, or so I heard!
Right now, we're calling that detective back
to the station to begin questioning.
Well, I beg your people not to be too hard on him.
Given that he only recently made detective...
He may have panicked upon seeing a body for the first time.
That could have led to him aimlessly feeling around the scene.
Then, the people who found the body
were you and that novice detective?
Yeah.
We were in the car after having just finished investigating a case...
When I asked him to drive me to this mansion.
I wanted to place some flowers in front of the storage room.
Flowers?
We forgot to mention it, but...
Inspector Morofushi and Inspector Yamato...
They were classmates of that Aoi-san who
died in the storage room three years ago.
Classmates?
Inspector Morofushi is...
The classmate of Kobashi Aoi-san who died in
this mansion's storage room three years ago?
That inspector being the primary discoverer
of Akashi Shuusaku-san's body...
Was it a mere coincidence?
Also...
Akashi-san left us a dying message.
The wall that was covered in red spray paint.
The two chairs that were painted white
and black, and nailed to the floor.
What was it Akashi-san was trying to tell us with these?
The Red Wall's Mystery...
And the culprit who let Akashi-san starve to death...
I'll be sure to reveal the culprit's identity in due course!
That's as improbable as...
Finding bamboo shoots in the snow.
There was indeed someone strange!
Say, about Aoi-san, what kind of person was she?
It's a Red Wall again.
"Be as swift as the wind," is it?
Just as we found the key person to solving this case...
We've had him murdered under our own watch!
Next Conan's Hint
Chess
Look forward to the Next Episode