The Mansion of Hope...
Once upon a time, it housed six talented young people.
However, three years ago...
One woman among the six died of a heart attack inside.
Instead of "Hope," people now call it the "Mansion of Death."
The man who lived alone in the mansion - Akashi Shuusaku-san...
Was the husband of the woman who passed away - Aoi-san.
That Akashi-san was confined in one of the rooms of
the mansion by someone, and died of starvation.
In his final hours, Akashi-san left us a strange message.
One of the walls was completely painted red.
Also, the chair painted white was facing the red wall...
While the other chair, painted black, was
facing the white wall on the opposite side.
Both chairs were nailed to the floor.
Akashi-san was sitting on the white chair when he drew his last breath.
The rival of Inspector Yamato from the
Nagano Police is Morofushi Takaaki.
Morofushi Takaaki (35)
Nagano Prefecture Arano Station Inspector
Nicknamed "Local Detective Koumei,"
he tackled this mystery along with us.
But what on earth was the red wall supposed to mean?
Love is magic, attack the mystery.
On Saturday nights, be sure to click on Conan!
Our suspects are full of colors.
As the second murder occurs, things are turning out unexpectedly!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Bring flowers?
Yeah, we forgot to mention it, but...
Inspector Morofushi and Inspector Yamato...
They were classmates of that Aoi-san who
died in the storage room three years ago.
Classmates?
Inspector Morofushi is...
The classmate of Kobashi Aoi-san who died in
this mansion's storage room three years ago?
This inspector being the primary discoverer
of Akashi Shuusaku-san's body...
Was it a mere coincidence?
My motivation for approaching this place...
It was due to it being the anniversary of her passing.
After placing the flowers and departing, I took
notice of something under the broken window.
An abundance of painting materials had been
strewn about, which did feel suspicious.
There was no reply after I rang the doorbell.
Finding the door unlocked, my subordinate
and I decided to enter the premises.
It was at that time that we discovered
the body confined inside this room.
However, is it not true that the victim's fingerprints
were found on the scattered painting materials?
Yeah, all of them.
But, on the doorknob and spray can...
Your subordinate's fingerprints were found.
That's akin to bamboo shoots in the snow.
Most intriguing.
Bamboo shoots in the know?
Not "in the know," but "in the snow."
It's finding bamboo shoots in the winter.
Why the bamboo shoots all of a sudden?
Bamboo shoots appear only in spring, don't they?
So in China, people use that metaphor to describe
something impossible or highly unachievable.
Bamboo Shoots in the Snow
But, how is it impossible?
Don't you understand?
The victim was locked inside this room.
Normally, you would try to turn the doorknob
in an attempt to escape, wouldn't you?
Painting a wall red with a spray can
should also leave the victim's fingerprints.
It also doesn't look like the culprit
had returned to this room yet.
That's true...
And, given that the victim's fingerprints aren't there...
There must be a reason why they had to be eradicated.
Or perhaps...
Regardless, it would be best if we visited those
four who resided in this mansion one more time.
This time, we'll prepare a leading question.
If you want to go, then go alone.
In my place, why don't you take that nosy
brat and the girl in your car for a while?
Now that I finally have Sleeping Kogorou-san all to myself...
I'd like to make good use of his intellect to solve this case.
There might be topics not suitable for kids.
Well, after you've visited those four and reported
back, bring that brat and girl to my house.
Although I do doubt you'll find anything.
And?
Let's get to the discussion of the case...
He's asleep!?
So that's why Kan-chan left Conan-kun...
Oh, the police officer from before.
Midorikawa Naoki (38)
Actor
If it's about Shuusaku's death, I've already told you everything.
Actually, on the doorknob of the room
in which Akashi-san was confined...
We found your fingerprints on it.
It's been six years since I last lived there...
Can fingerprints really stay that long?
So, after leaving the mansion six years ago, you never went back?
You can't, Conan-kun.
Who are those kids?
No...
They're accompanying me temporarily
due to extenuating circumstances.
Didn't I tell you to wait in the car?
Well, I have to report to Uncle Kogorou what kind of people they are!
Uhm, excuse me, but haven't you been on TV often?
"Sone Naoki" - that name ring a bell to you?
I recognize that name!
He often acts as a corrupt official in those historical dramas.
"Sone" is my mother's maiden name.
I use it as my stage name.
Because everyone in the mansion called
me "Midori" this, "Midori" that...
If I hadn't changed it, I may have felt I couldn't
stand on my own feet after leaving the mansion.
Then, those people in the mansion did call one another by colors?
Yeah.
But Shuusaku was my childhood friend, so
the two of us greeted each other by name.
Really now, my fingerprints were on the doorknob of Aka-kun's room?
Yamabuki Shouji (39)
Fashion Designer
Oh, but of course they were!
After all, I used to live there.
You just called Akashi-san "Aka," so does
that mean you were called "Yamabuki"?
Yeah, that's my surname after all.
But only Ao-chan called me "Yama-chan"!
Say, about Aoi-san, what kind of person was she?
Simply speaking, she was our Madonna.
Of the six of us she was the only female, and was a beauty too.
That's why when we heard she was
dating Aka-kun, we were all surprised.
That's also why everyone moved out of that mansion.
Well, I was one of them, too.
Momose Takuto (37)
CG Creator
My fingerprints were on the doorknob of Aka's room?
Hey, hey, don't tell me you're suspecting me
simply because I lived there at one point?
I don't even know when I left those!
No, we just wished to confirm.
Say, you were called "Momo" by everyone, right?
Yeah, how annoying.
To think some idiot even called me "Pink"!
Pink...
And, after moving out of the mansion, you never returned?
Oh yeah, I forgot to mention, but I went back once four years ago.
It was to deliver a game I helped create.
Game, you say?
Yeah, just an ordinary chess game.
Both Aka and Ao-chan loved chess a lot.
What!?
Naoki Shirou (36)
Musician
On the doorknob of Aka's room...
You found my fingerprints!?
Yeah.
That's why I wanted to check with you.
But, that's just... impossible!
Besides, I used to live there, you know!
Wait, I think I went back there to visit half a year ago!
I might've also touched Aka's painting tools back then!
Ah, and by "Aka" I meant Akashi's nickname!
Then, were you called "Shiro" by the others?
They never greeted me by my surname.
Ah, shoot!
I've got an appointment with my band members!
May I be excused?
I've gotta bolt right now!
In that case, we'll visit another time.
It's me...
Oh, I see.
You lead them to believe their fingerprints
were on the doorknob of Akashi's room...
And observed their reactions, didn't you?
So, any results?
Yeah, well...
There was indeed someone strange!
He was very antsy...
And said he might've touched some painting tools
during his last visit, even though we never asked!
And who was he?
It's Naoki Shirou-san.
Naoki Shirou?
Come to think of it, when we asked him
questions before, he was also acting strangely.
Yeah, although we have our eyes on him...
We have no proof against him.
Well, it's already late.
Let's rest tonight, and tomorrow morning we'll ask
Naoki Shirou to voluntarily come to the station with us.
What?
You figured out who starved Akashi Shuusaku to death?
Really?
Yeah!
After thinking it over for the night, it just dawned on me!
And?
Who could our culprit be?
It's the one you said was weird last night - Naoki Shirou!
The victim Akashi-san was sitting on the white
chair, and in front of him was the red wall.
Which means, the red color was meant to indicate himself!
And what about the black chair?
Black represents the culprit, of course!
And what will you see if you sit on the black chair?
A white wall.
I see, he wanted to tell us the culprit is someone
who's called "White" - Naoki Shirou-san!
Bingo!
Sorry if I sound rude, but that deduction...
Ignore him, Uehara.
How annoying.
But...
What's that in front of the apartment?
Has something happened?
Kan-chan, look!
Koumei?
Inspector Morofushi...
Hey, don't tell me...
Yeah, I had this bizarre premonition so I came to
have an early look, but it was already like this.
A Red Wall?
The killer must have seen our movements
last night and decided to take action first.
"Be as swift as the wind," is it?
Yeah.
"The item in hand might not be within one's grasp."
We were careless.
Huh?
"The item in brandy might not be within one's glass?"
He meant...
"The item in hand might not be within one's grasp."
It means even if something was placed
in our hand, we might still lose it.
Which means, just as we placed the key person
to solving this case under our watch...
We've carelessly allowed him to be
murdered and the culprit to break free!
The victim was a musician, Naoki Shirou, 36 years old.
The estimated time of death was
between 10:00 and 11:00 last night.
The cause of death is suffocation due to
constriction on the neck - strangulation.
The victim was apparently seated.
And facing the chair, the closet doors have been
sprayed by the can next to the victim's feet.
Seeing as it was painted bloody red...
It's highly probable that the culprit is the same guy who
starved the imprisoned Akashi Shuusaku a few days ago.
It's a Red Wall again...
So that means, this red wall is also the victim's dying message?
No.
For Naoki Shirou-san to paint the wall red...
He had to do it before being strangled.
However, it's equally unlikely that he would have
painted the wall before he met with the culprit.
Then, about this red wall...
Could it be...
Yeah, I think the culprit painted the wall red on purpose.
Hey, hey, isn't this weird?
Why would a culprit leave a declarative dying message like that?
They're trying to challenge us police!
Right.
Regarding the red wall Akashi-san left, they
decided to reproduce it at this scene.
I believe they are attempting to taunt us.
"Come solve this mystery, and catch me if you can."
At any rate, we know one thing.
The suspects are those who lived in
the mansion with Akashi Shuusaku.
The actor Midorikawa Naoki...
The fashion designer Yamabuki Shouji...
And CG creator Momose Takuto, these three people.
Why's that?
Because those three and the victim,
Naoki-san, were the only ones we told...
About the wall painted bloody red...
And that Akashi-san was seated on a chair.
But, we didn't tell them that Akashi-san died on a chair
painted white, with a chair painted black behind him...
Nor the fact that both chairs were nailed to the floor.
Therefore, even if they wanted to recreate Akashi-san's death
scene, the culprit could only put the victim on a chair.
But isn't the culprit gonna worry?
Without fully acknowledging the last death scene,
they still tried to imitate the dying message?
That's true.
Well, it's best that we asked those three what they
were doing between 10:00 and 11:00 last night, but...
I still want to discuss some things with
Sleeping Kogorou-san about this case.
Sorry Koumei, but I'll need to have you
take the brat and girl in your car again...
"Give advice and good guidance, then halt after such is of no avail...
"Do not disgrace yourself for it."
Kansuke-kun, it seems your desire is to
have that fine young man accompany me...
But allow me to decline this time.
Please permit me to investigate this alone.
Of course, once I discover the truth, I promise I'll contact you.
So long.
Hey, what was that again?
Something about giving advice or whatever...
Well, I think they're words by Confucius.
When people make a mistake, it is nice to give them advice, but...
If they don't listen, just leave them alone.
Otherwise you'll do yourself a disservice by wasting
your time and effort; that's what it means.
But, what mistake?
Well, during a past investigation,
Kan-chan got caught under an avalanche.
You heard about him injuring his left eye,
left leg, and going missing, right?
During that time, we lost contact with Kan-chan for days.
But Inspector Morofushi, despite his superior's
orders, dashed to another prefecture alone...
Conducted an unauthorized investigation,
arrested the suspect Kan-chan was after...
Obtained information about the avalanche,
and found Kan-chan in a hospital.
Because of that, he was punished and
moved to the local police department.
Since Kan-chan owed him one...
And to prevent Inspector Morofushi from starting another rash
investigation alone, I think that's why you let this kid tag along with him.
I agree Conan-kun is smart, no?
But c'mon, his rash investigation was because
he wanted to find you as soon as possible.
Unlike this case...
He's likely to recklessly go off alone again!
Have you heard of a book called
"Koumei-kun from Second Grade Class A!"?
Ah, I've read it before.
It's about a famous young student detective
solving a mystery that occurred in school, right?
The author of that book is the one who died three years
ago in that mansion's storage room - Kobashi Aoi.
She was Akashi Shuusaku's wife!
And the main character of the book...
That student detective is actually derived from...
That Morofushi Takaaki over there.
Come to think of it, there's also a rival detective
from another class who uses rough language...
Could that be...?
Probably derived from Kan-chan!
In any case!
If we suppose this serial murder case is done by someone
who's holding a grudge over the death of Kobashi Aoi...
Koumei would probably tackle this case without thinking.
After all, he still cherishes that book and
even keeps it in his glove compartment.
Uehara, call a taxi and go after Koumei's car!
I'll check out those three guys with Kogorou-san.
Yes!
I'm sure you already know, but don't let
your eyes off Koumei even for a second!
Yes!
Regardless, if you don't want him to investigate
rashly alone, why don't you just go with him?
I bet you wanted to monitor him, right?
Even yesterday when we went with Inspector Morofushi to
question those suspects, a strange car was following us.
That was an officer's car, no?
Yeah.
But, why monitor him?
We just told you that those three knew about
the red wall at the crime scene, right?
But of course that information was also known to us police.
As such, since we know someone who was friends with Kobashi
Aoi is in the police force, shouldn't we take a closer look?
Don't tell me...
Yeah, that Morofushi Takaaki...
He's also one of the suspects!
What!?
You lost sight of Koumei!?
Koumei should be headed to the mansion!
Go there now!
What?
What was written in it?
The late... Koumei.
It's on fire!
That Mansion of Death!
Koumei, can it be...
They've struck first again...
Next Conan's Hint
Surgical Gown
Look forward to the Next Episode