The Mansion of Hope...
Once upon a time, it housed six talented young people.
However, three years ago...
One woman among the six died of a heart attack inside.
Instead of "Hope," people now call it the "Mansion of Death."
In that mansion, a new tragedy took place.
The deceased woman's husband, Akashi Shuusaku-san...
Had been confined to one of the mansion's
rooms, causing him to die of starvation.
In his final hours, Akashi-san painted one
of the walls in the room bloody red.
What was he trying to say?
We deduced that our suspect is among the
remaining four who also resided in the mansion.
The rival of Inspector Yamato from Nagano Police,
Morofushi Takaaki, took us with him on his investigation.
Morofushi Takaaki (35)
Nagano Prefecture Arano Station Inspector
We felt suspicious towards one Naoki Shirou-san's reactions.
And so we revisited his apartment the next
day, only to find Naoki-san murdered.
Similar to Akashi-san, he was seated
on a chair, facing a wall painted red.
The differences are that Naoki-san's body
was not seated on a chair painted white...
And there was no black chair in the room...
Then, the fact that instead of the victim, the
wall was seemingly painted by the culprit.
Was the culprit challenging the police?
Or...
Love is magic, attack the mystery.
On Saturday nights, be sure to click on Conan!
The culprit has assaulted Inspector Koumei!
Can we finally solve the mystery of the Red Wall?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Regardless, if you don't want him to investigate
rashly alone, why don't you just go with him?
I bet you wanted to monitor him, right?
Even yesterday when we went with Inspector Morofushi to
question those suspects, a strange car was following us.
That was an officer's car, no?
Yeah.
But, why monitor him?
We just told you that those three knew about
the red wall at the crime scene, right?
But of course that information was also known to us police.
As such, since we know someone who was friends with Kobashi
Aoi is in the police force, shouldn't we take a closer look?
Don't tell me...
Yeah, that Morofushi Takaaki...
He's also one of the suspects!
Midorikawa Naoki (38)
Actor
Shiro-kun is...
Is that true!?
That's why we wanted to ask, last night between
10:00 and 11:00, what were you doing?
During that time, I was in my room
reading my script for a TV drama.
When I was done and went to sleep, it
was about 2:00 in the morning I guess.
Hey, don't tell me you're suspecting me?
We're asking just in case, and is there anyone who can support that?
My wife went to sleep at 9:00, so...
Well, if it's your spouse, their testimony won't count.
Say, did you notice anything about Shirou-san?
Like his being afraid of something.
Well, I haven't seen him for a longtime, but
it seems Shuusaku met with him often.
Shiro-kun's band wasn't doing very well.
Shuusaku said he always came to visit and borrow money.
You're asking me what I was doing
between 10:00 and 11:00 last night?
Oh please, don't tell me you, too, are
suspecting me of Shiro-kun's death?
By "you too," you mean...
Yamabuki Shouji (39)
Fashion Designer
The officer from last night with slanted eyes and a small
mustache asked me the same thing, so I told him:
"I was in here alone working on my design. Is that problem?"
So that bastard Koumei has been here already, huh?
"Koumei"?
Was that officer's name Koumei?
His nickname is Koumei, and he was a
classmate of the Kobashi Aoi you know.
Then, he's the famous detective from Ao-chan's book?
Well, about that Naoki Shirou-san, had
anything happened to him recently?
Beats me—I'd heard he had some financial trouble, but...
Ah, he did tell me he wanted to travel overseas!
I even asked him, "No problem with your traveling expenses?" too.
Geez, the police again?
I've said this before, during 10:00 and 1:00 last night
I was sleeping on the sofa in the next room.
So Koumei's been here, too.
And, do you have someone to verify that?
Momose Takuto (37)
CG Creator
Go ask my partner who tried to wake me
up every hour starting from 11:00!
Oh, but I covered myself with a blanket to sleep, so
they likely couldn't tell if it was really me or not.
Then, about the murdered Naoki Shirou-san,
had anything suspicious happened to him?
Who knows... a while back he came
to me specifically asking for money.
After I shooed him off angrily, he never came back.
Well, it seems like he got some money.
Looks like he was planning to go to Lecce in Italy.
He even e-mailed me saying, "If I'm gone, try searching there."
Lecce in Italy?
By the way, that officer with slanted eyes and a small mustache...
Was he really the model for the famous detective in Ao-chan's book?
Yeah, but why do you ask?
A while ago, Yamabuki phoned me about it,
and said that Midori was surprised, too.
Well, we've finished hearing the three suspects talk.
But those three apparently had no alibis.
Yeah, looks like we have to solve
the Red Wall mystery no matter what.
The Red Wall...
If that truly was a dying message by Akashi
Shuusaku-san, why did he paint the wall red?
It's understandable why he didn't
just write out the culprit's name, but...
Right, he didn't write the culprit's name because...
He feared that, after he had passed on from starving, the culprit
would return, discover it before anyone else, and remove it.
Remove...
Red...
Wall...
I see.
In this murder adaptation, Koumei is of no use.
It's time for your early retirement.
What!?
Koumei disappeared!?
What were you doing, Uehara?
Sorry!
When we reached Gojou Forest, his car accelerated suddenly...
Gojou Forest?
That's the forest where the mansion is!
Koumei should be headed there!
Go there now!
Yes, sir!
Koumei sent me a message?
Maybe he figured out who the culprit is?
What?
What was written in it?
The late... Koumei...
Hey, hey, don't jinx him.
Hey, Uehara, have you found Koumei yet?
Well...
I've arrived at the mansion, but...
It's on fire!
That Mansion of Death!
What!?
The mansion's on fire!?
And Koumei?
Where's Koumei!?
I don't know!
His car is in front of the mansion, but...
By the time I got here, the mansion was already burning!
Koumei, can it be...
They've struck first again...
Inspector Morofushi!
Koumei!
If he's still inside, it's too late...
No way...
Once I discover the truth, I promise I'll contact you.
Koumei, I haven't... gotten your report yet!
Shit!
Wait, you!
Stop it, Inspector Yamato!
There's no use entering now!
Shut up!
We won't know if we don't find out!
Like—I—said!
It's meaningless to enter the mansion, see?
Koumei!
Hey, what happened!?
I entered the back door where the fire hadn't spread...
And found him lying in that room!
Looks like someone assaulted him.
Who was it, Koumei?
Who did this to you?
No use, he's completely unconscious.
Moreover, the trauma is on the back of his head.
If he was hit from behind, it's unlikely he saw the culprit.
But, the culprit can be anyone among the people over there.
Hey, why are you guys here?
Ah, no...
We were called over...
With this text message...
Text message?
Who sent it!?
It's from you, Inspector.
What?
It says, "Come to the mansion where Shuusaku
was trapped, I have things to check with you."
Right?
Yeah, it was at 14:00.
Then we came here and saw it burning.
Don't you think it's odd that I would send you text messages?
I felt strange for a bit, but...
When I called these two, they said they received the same message.
The contents and the address were the
same, so we didn't suspect anything.
So did you three come here together?
No, we were told to come alone.
In the text.
Naoki Shirou-san's cell phone?
The text message was sent to those three from that phone?
Yeah.
After killing Naoki Shirou, the culprit probably
swiped the phone and changed the mailing address.
He then sent the same message to
the three suspects, himself included.
I see.
The suspicious individuals are...
Midorikawa Naoki-san, Yamabuki Shouji-san,
and Momose Takuto-san, these three.
If the culprit manages to drag the other two over...
The culprit wouldn't be the only one without
an alibi when the mansion is burned down.
But why did they have to light it on fire?
The culprit figured it out, didn't he?
That the dying message of the red wall left by Akashi-san...
Actually pointed out who the culprit was!
So the culprit went there intending to burn down the mansion, but...
Unfortunately Koumei was there, so they had no choice but to
knock him out, and try to burn him to ashes with the mansion.
And?
What's the meaning behind the red wall?
You already know, right?
It'd be nice if I figured that out...
Killing move...
DRILL PUNCH!
Conan-kun!
You don't even know the truth, so just shut your trap!
Well, even though our first crime scene went
into flames, we did receive a new clue.
That Koumei sent me a text message.
"The late Koumei."
But, didn't the culprit send that to Kan-chan on purpose?
I don't think that's it.
The message was interrupted half way, and he did say that
he'd contact Inspector Yamato after he solved the mystery.
So, apparently Inspector Morofushi realized something...
And while he was in the process of texting it to
Inspector Yamato, he was struck down by the culprit.
I bet he pressed the send button just before he passed out.
But why during it?
The famous tactician Shokatsu Koumei and Inspector Morofushi
Takaaki's having a nickname that sounds like "Koumei"...
Wasn't the culprit just utilizing that reference?
Just to tell us, "Koumei is dead."
"The late Koumei scares away the living Zhonda."
Huh?
What's that?
The army led by Shokatsuryou Koumei in the Shu
Kingdom appeared to be retreating from battle.
Seeing that and assuming Koumei had died of illness, the
Wei Kingdom's tactician Sima Yi Zhonda ordered a pursuit.
But the Shu army, following Koumei's final words,
pretended to be ready for a counterattack.
That made Zhonda scream "Koumei isn't dead; we're
falling into their trap!" and immediately retreated.
Basically, the moral is: "People can have a great
influence and intimidate the living, even after death."
But in that case, the "late Koumei" would
refer to the starved Akashi Shuusaku-san...
And the "living Zhonda" would mean the culprit.
That means Akashi-san was trying to scare the culprit with the
red wall and black and white chairs nailed to the floor, but...
We don't know what the message means.
There's one thing I don't get.
Why did the culprit also leave the message of the red
wall in the room of the next victim - Naoki Shirou?
If they really left the message to challenge
the police, were they that certain?
Were they that confident that the red wall
itself would never reveal their identity?
But, is the culprit's motive really because of Aoi-san?
Maybe the culprit painted the wall because
of something pertinent to the color red.
No, the motive was the anger caused by Aoi's death.
Like I said, three years ago she collapsed in the
mansion's storage room due to a heart attack.
But her husband Akashi Shuusaku just left her there to die alone.
Sound familiar?
It's the same situation as the confined,
abandoned, and starved Akashi Shuusaku.
But, that's not enough to say...
On the day of Aoi-san's death...
Our three suspects and yesterday's victim, Naoki
Shirou-san, all spoke with Aoi-san on the phone.
She asked, "About the portrait of me that my husband
Shuusaku made, do you guys remember where it was put?"
So the thing Aoi-san tried to find in the
storage room before she died was...
Yeah, she was looking for her portrait.
She also asked Shuusaku-san about its whereabouts, but he
didn't answer because he was busy finishing up his work.
Aoi-san wanted to decorate her room
with that portrait for her birthday.
Since she died on the day before her birthday, I'm not
surprised that someone would hold a grudge over this.
Well, regardless, once Koumei regains consciousness we
can ask him whether he sent this "late Koumei" or not.
If he did, we could deduce its meaning.
The doctor said that if he doesn't regain consciousness
by tomorrow, he'll require another examination.
I see.
Sorry about this.
Calling you all the way out here and not letting you do much.
No, no, I'm the one who hasn't contributed enough.
But let's face it.
The one you really wanted to invite is
this brat with glasses, isn't that right?
Yeah, I thought this brat was a
good choice for monitoring Koumei.
Because once that guy puts on his thinking
cap, he ignores everything around him.
After he makes up his mind, he'd
even go so far as to jump off a cliff.
So I thought even if he doesn't listen to us,
he may take on candid advice from a child.
But he still went off by himself and ended up in trouble.
Excuse me for not being useful enough...
Well, once I solve the mystery of the red
wall, I'll make sure to tell you first.
Doctor, how's my wife?
Don't worry, the operation was a success.
What's wrong, Ran?
I was just wondering to myself why
surgical gowns have to be light green?
See, all those doctors and nurses wear white coats, right?
That may be true, but why are you asking this now?
Because the case this time has something to do with colors, right?
I've been thinking of colors all this time.
Ah, I know why they're like that.
The reason why surgical gowns are light green is because
surgeons constantly see blood during operations.
If they keep looking at it...
The afterimage will...
Interrupt their focus...
I see...
This dying message can't be acknowledged
just by looking at the red wall alone!
The message has to be interpreted by pairing
it with the white wall on the opposite side.
What happened to you two?
The mysterious death that occurred in the Mansion of Hope...
That illustrator who called that mansion home, Akashi
Shuusaku-san, was confined to his room and starved to death.
What's intriguing is one of the walls was
painted completely red by Akashi-san.
Also inside the room, two chairs painted
white and black were nailed to the floor...
And we have Akashi-san sitting on the white chair,
facing the red wall, when he drew his last breath.
It looks like this was a dying message left by Akashi-san.
The murder concerns the one who died of a heart attack in this
mansion's storage room three years ago - Akashi-san's wife.
Maiden name Kobashi Aoi-san, the culprit
may hold a grudge over her death.
The case didn't end there.
Just as we started looking into the case.
One of those who lived in the mansion, Naoki
Shirou-san, was found murdered in his apartment.
Furthermore, his body was seated on a
chair, facing the closet doors painted red.
Right - the culprit reproduced the scene
where Akashi-san's body was found.
Was it a challenge to the police?
The suspects are among the six people who
resided in the mansion, three of whom still live.
The actor, Midorikawa Naoki-san.
The fashion designer, Yamabuki Shouji-san.
And CG creator, Momose Takuto-san.
Akashi Shuusaku-san's dying message is...
Without a doubt, it's referring to that person!
Naoki Shirou-san said it, right?
That he would be going to Lecce in Italy soon.
In that case, I have a great idea.
As do I.
Why not type your strategy in one word on your
cell phone and then show it to each other?
As I expected...
It's the Empty Fort Strategy, isn't it?
Next Conan's Hint
Italy
Look forward to the Next Episode