A new tragedy occurred in the Mansion of Death.
Thee years ago, Aoi-san died there...
And her husband, Akashi Shuusaku-san, was confined in
one of the rooms of the mansion and died of starvation.
In his final hours, Akashi-san painted
one of the walls in the room blood red.
What was he trying to say?
After we started questioning the former residents of the mansion...
One of them, the musician Naoki Shirou-san, was murdered.
Similar to Akashi-san, he was seated
on a chair, facing a wall painted red.
A former classmate of Aoi-san, Inspector Morofushi...
Went off to investigate alone despite advice
from another classmate, Inspector Yamato.
And coming from that Inspector Morofushi was a
text message, with only one sentence written on it.
"The late Koumei."
Moreover, the Mansion of Death was consumed by flames.
Inspector Morofushi was saved by Detective Uehara in a pinch, but...
He had been struck in the head, and lost consciousness.
As such, we couldn't determine what "the late Koumei" meant...
And the mystery of the case seemed unfathomable.
But Ran's unassuming question shed a ray of light on this case.
Which is...
Love is magic, attack the mystery.
On Saturday nights, be sure to click on Conan!
We're finally nearing the climax...
It's time to unravel the mystery of the Red Wall and the true culprit!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
I see...
This dying message can't be acknowledged
just by looking at the red wall alone!
I see.
So that's why the chairs at the first crime scene...
Were painted white and black!
The victim, Akashi Shuusaku-san...
Was really fond of chess.
If so, why did the culprit leave a red wall at the second crime scene?
If they did it out of confidence that we'd never find out its meaning...
I've got it!
After all, the dying message...
Isn't about the red wall!
The only person besides the culprit who had to paint it red...
Had to be Naoki Shirou!
At last...
At last, you've deduced to this point.
Koumei?
You've regained consciousness!
But is it all right for you to be walking around?
Yes, I'm fine.
In that case, let's go catch the culprit!
Mochi drawn on the ground...
Cannot be consumed.
It's a pity that our deductions are
still like mochi drawn on the ground.
We can't pick it up and have it.
In other words, we lack evidence...
However...
Naoki Shirou-san said it, right?
That he would be going to Lecce in Italy soon.
And that, if he were gone, that's where we'd need to search.
That's most interesting.
In that case, I have a great idea.
As do I.
Hey now, you should let headquarters handle this!
No, I cannot allow that.
Then, how about this?
Why not type your strategy in one word on your
cell phone and then show it to each other?
Just like Koumei and Zhou Yu before the Battle of Red Cliffs.
Very well.
Geez, such a hassle.
Then...
One, two, and go!
As I expected...
It's the Empty Fort strategy, isn't it?
Please be more considerate, Inspector!
If you keep calling us out like this...
We can't do our jobs!
Midorikawa Naoki (38)
Actor
Though it's true we all lived in that mansion before...
The fact that we don't have alibis for
last night must've been coincidental.
Yamabuki Shouji (39)
Fashion Designer
Momose Takuto (37)
CG Creator
The reason why we were at the burning mansion...
Was because we saw that text message, didn't I tell you?
First of all, have you figured out what that red wall's about?
We haven't worked it out yet...
But it looks like the second victim,
Naoki Shirou, did figure out something.
Do you have any ideas?
Nothing.
I only knew he needed money.
But he'd said he'd be traveling soon.
Yeah, yeah.
To a place called Lecce in Italy.
In that case, maybe he was about to walk to Lecce,
and hide something really important there!
Because Shirou-san said that, if he were
gone, that's where we'd need to search.
But why "walk" there?
Because Italy is shaped like a boot, right?
Whatever!
If you want to keep suspecting us...
Why don't you find some concrete evidence first?
We're busy people, you know.
Later.
Excuse us.
We've worked hard on this, so why don't you guys wait and see?
"A journey of a hundred kilometers is only half over after ninety."
We cannot lower our guards.
We can't throw this race away.
PC60, PC60, a taxi robbery occurred in the industry area...
Shit, just as I thought, there are even cops
waiting behind Shirou's apartment...
Did I really fall into a trap?
What? A taxi robber?
Around here?
Yeah, we have to hurry!
What? They're leaving?
Then, that means the apartment's unguarded...
No, wait...
There's a drunkard sitting in front of the apartment, and
a masked man has been wandering around for a while.
One of them could be a cop.
Mister...
If you sleep here, you'll catch a cold.
SHUDDAP!
GO AWAY, BRAT!
Damn, who does the boss think he is!?
Maybe I was wrong...
Honey, are you all right?
You're so drunk.
Two or three more'll be fine!
Honey!
Sowwy...
Ow, ow, owww!
My leg's broken!
Honey, you all right?
Hey, bastard!
Gimme a million yen for medical fees!
A million?
I don't have that much money...
Then hand over your wallet!
Noooo...
Extortion?
If the masked man were a cop, he wouldn't turn a blind eye like that.
Now we can drink some more!
Are you sure?
Damn it...
What am I gonna tell mom...
What!?
Don't tell me this guy's...
A panty thief?
Hey, hey, he's heading for Shiro's room...
Idiot, if he goes in...
The cops at the front door will...
They're gone?
I see, the cops all went after the taxi robber.
That guy just came out of Shiro's room.
Extortion, panty theft, and burglary...
There's no doubt, no cops are around here.
Now's my chance to find that...
Which one?
Which shoe did he hide it in?
Perhaps...
This is it?
The shoe you're after.
What a unique shoe!
The heel of the shoe is loose, and there's
a cell phone memory card inside.
Right...
Just like Lecce, the heel of Italy's boot!
What a pity, you couldn't find it first...
Midorikawa Naoki-san.
Who are you!?
Come on, we've met several times already.
Can't you remember me?
Edogawa Conan...
A detective.
You are!?
But I believe...
You haven't...
Forgotten about us...
Right?
Then, that extortion and burglary were...
Yeah.
The Empty Fort strategy.
The Empty Fort strategy?
If we merely called away the patrol cars, you'd
suspect it was possible a trap had been set.
If that were your mindset, should we present
you with others around the apartment...
Acting in a manner the police would not...
And have them committing a number of crimes...
Lowering your guard is a simple task.
Empty Fort Strategy
The original Empty Fort strategy was to purposely show vulnerability.
All in order to make the opposition assume there was
a hidden trap, causing them to halt their approach.
But ours has the opposite effect.
Then, the reason you police mentioned the boot...
Was to see whether the culprit would
come and fall into your trap, right?
No, we believed from the beginning that you'd come.
We were intrigued.
At the first crime scene, it was the
victim who left the dying message.
Yet why did the culprit leave the same
message at the second crime scene?
But then, if we consider that the red wall wasn't left by the victim...
Right.
If we suppose a third person other than the
victim or the culprit painted the wall red...
We can more easily conclude that the culprit duplicated
the scene in order to lead the investigation astray.
Then, you're saying this third person was Naoki Shirou-san?
Yeah.
If someone other than the culprit
had to paint over Akashi's message...
Then the message had to have
been written in katakana as...
"I was killed by Naoki."
That means you, Midorikawa Naoki...
Were his murderer.
I see.
That message must've been spotted by Naoki
Shirou-san who came to borrow money.
He thought that it meant him, so he painted over it.
But instead of katakana, why not use kanji to avoid confusion?
That's because...
He used a spray can to write it, didn't he?
The amount of strokes in kanji would make it blurry.
And then, as Shirou-san painted over it with
that same red spray, he came to a realization.
It was that the "Naoki" did not refer to his last name, but rather...
To the only person on a first-name basis with
Akashi-san - Midorikawa Naoki san, that was you.
Midorikawa Naoki
Then, he took a picture of the partially obscured word
with his cell phone in order to attempt to blackmail you.
Isn't that so?
Yeah, that's why...
I killed Shiro in this very room he called me to.
Damn...
If only Shiro hadn't gone to the room Shuusaku was starved in...
If only I were the one who painted it red...
Could it be, Mister...
That you still don't get the meaning of the red wall?
The victim had to get the culprit to paint the
wall red to complete his dying message.
What do you mean?
Ever heard of "complementary color afterimage"?
Complementary color afterimage?
Complementary Color Afterimage?
If you look elsewhere after staring at one color long enough...
Its complementary color will appear in your visual field.
See, surgeons always wear light green surgical gowns, right?
That's because after they keep staring
at blood during a long operation...
Their eyes would form afterimages of green that interfere with
their focus, so they wear the same color to lessen this effect.
In other words, the red wall sets up the afterimage
effect to show us the real dying message.
Inside that room...
The fact that the white chair faces the red wall and the black
chair faces the white wall while being nailed to the floor...
Serves as a hint for us to decipher the message.
Akashi Shuusaku-san was fond of chess.
In chess, white goes first and then black.
In other words, it tells us to first sit on the
white chair and stare at the red wall...
Then sit on the black chair
and stare at the white wall.
That way, red's complementary color, green,
will vividly appear at the white wall.
Green...
Meaning you, Midorikawa-san.
That's also why Akashi-san...
Threw all the painting materials out
the window except the red spray.
Just to prevent anyone from painting over it with other colors.
In other words, he suspected that the first
to check on his body might be you...
And whatever he wrote might be removed.
So he took advantage of that and tried to make you paint over it...
Effectively completing his message that you were the culprit.
So it really is like, "The late Koumei scares away the living Zhonda."
Precisely.
He tried to make me paint over it, huh...
What a jerk...
To think he painted over that important portrait, and
caused the death of such an important person...
By "portrait," you don't mean...
Yeah...
It's the one Ao-chan had been looking for
before succumbing to a heart attack.
A portrait of Ao-chan that had been
created by Shuusaku some time ago.
I found the portrait later on!
It was hidden under another portrait I bought last year!
Hidden under?
I bought it because it looked like Ao-chan.
But out of curiosity...
I sent it to be inspected by X-ray.
And it revealed Ao-chan's portrait was actually under the layers!
That bastard Shuusaku painted over Ao-chan's portrait
with white, and repainted it with something else!
No way...
It may be true that Shuusaku's art wasn't
famous until two or three years ago.
He may have done that out of desperation, after running
low on money for new supplies like blank canvases...
But why didn't he tell Ao-chan about it!?
Had he told her about it, Ao-chan
wouldn't have died trying to find it!
Instead, he kept quiet and locked himself
in his room to continue painting!
That's why I trapped him in his room to let him
taste the pain that Ao-chan had suffered...
On the day after Aoi-san's death...
I came to the mansion, and found a painting burning in the yard.
The paint on it had not yet dried.
It was a painting of Aoi-san.
So, the painting that Akashi-san had
been working on in his room was...
It was most likely that new portrait.
The reason why he didn't tell Aoi-san
and worked on the painting alone...
Was because he wanted to complete it
before Aoi-san's birthday as a surprise.
No, it can't be...
What have I done...
Ao-chan...
Shuusaku...
"Make no intrusion into other's affairs."
When it comes to the relationships between close
people, perhaps outsiders should never interfere.
All right, Koumei.
You take care of the rest.
After all, you did figure out the Red Wall mystery first.
I may not like it, but I'll let you write up the case report.
I knew you would do that.
You said you had that kid follow me around in order to spy on me...
But let's say that I really was a suspect; it'd still
be too dangerous for him to stay with me.
Meaning, you never suspected me even from the beginning...
And instead merely wished for that
intelligent child to accompany me, right?
As an ally to assist in uncovering the truth.
Hey, hey, he's only a brat.
After seeing the red wall at the second crime scene...
We all thought that was a challenge to the police from the culprit.
But only that young man said this:
But isn't the culprit gonna worry?
Without fully acknowledging the last death scene,
they still tried to imitate the dying message?
If it weren't for those words, I doubt we would
have arrived at the truth behind the red wall.
The same goes for the evidence's location.
Because the young man mentioned information
regarding Lecce, we became enlightened.
So you planned to let me solve the case...
And take credit for this case so I could return
to the Nagano Police Headquarters, but...
How unnecessary.
If our roles were reversed, you'd do the same for me, no?
If it were me, I would've done it more discreetly.
Not letting you suspect any traces of my plan.
Oh, is that so? I get it!
I'll take credit for this case!
Stay at that local station forever!
But, Kansuke-kun...
I am really grateful to you for letting me meet this boy.
Thanks to you, I recalled once again...
From my most favorite book, my most favorite phrase.
"That child carried with him a calm
glare that saw through everything...
"And then proceeded to reveal the
truth in a quiet but steady manner.
"Indeed, just like the famous tactician, Shokatsuryou Koumei."