ANY TIME, ANY WHERE!
Whenever and wherever you go, bring along a Nijimura bag.
Spilled water on it?
No problem!
Bumped into something?
No worries!
ANY TIME, ANY WHERE!
Whenever and wherever you need a bag, get Nijimura.
ANYTIME, ANYWHERE!
Whenever and wherever you go, bring along a Nijimura bag.
Are Nijimura bags really selling hot?
It's their rainbow color trademark that makes them so popular!
This does?
Also, Nijimura bags are very sturdy, and they're highly waterproof.
Look at the fastener - it's said to be the
same kind they use for scuba diving suits.
Which means the contents won't get wet
even when the bag's dropped in water.
However, no doubt this is a celebrity
brand - there's one too many zeroes...
No, two more than our budget!
I'd hoped to find a pouch inside our budget
range, but I guess I'll have to give up.
Cheer up!
We've taken on President Nijimura's personal request.
If we accomplish this, be it a pouch or
a poncho, I'll buy anything for you!
They don't carry ponchos you know.
Sorry for your wait.
President Nijimura should be available in a moment.
Someone help!
What was that?
Conan-kun!
The hell are you doing!?
Let me go!
Help me!
President Nijimura!
A kidnapping!
Love is magic, attack the mystery.
On Saturday nights, bu sure to click on Conan!
Hidden in the rainbow colors after the rain is a handbag's secret.
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
We had roadblocks set up five minutes after the incident
occurred, but have failed to locate any suspicious vehicles.
Perhaps you misread the plate number?
That's impossible.
By the way, you are
I'm Inspector Katsuragi from SID, Detective Mouri Kogorou-san.
Katsuragi Kenzou (45)
Police HQ First Division Special Investigation Dept. Inspector
SID?
First division of the police headquarters,
the Special Investigation Department.
It's a section for handling hostage situations
such as kidnappings or hijackings.
You know a lot, boy.
But then, why is a kid like you in a place like this?
I also witnessed the crime scene, so...
Excuse us if we are interfering with your work.
Detective, may I ask you to stay away from this?
Investigating kidnappings for ransom is our job.
But we can't be sure that this case's kidnapping is for ransom...
No, it's been confirmed.
Nijimura Saki (35)
Nijimura Vice President
This was inside our mailbox.
Excuse me, but you are?
I'm Nijimura's wife, my name is Saki.
I am the vice president of the company.
Allow me.
"We have President Nijimura.
"If you want him released, put ¥ 100,000,000
in a Nijimura handbag and have Saki carry it.
"At precisely 14:00, go to Touto-Ikebukuro
Station and board the Blue Sky express train.
"Have her get off at the last stop - Okuho Station.
"However, ANYTIME ANYWHERE, we will be watching closely.
"If we see any authorities, the hostage will die."
From Black Rainbow?
Damn those bastards!
A hundred million yen ransom?
Any idea who they might be?
To tell the truth, we've always had problems
with counterfeit products copying our brand.
We have just begun filing a lawsuit.
It's possible that those types of companies
would hold a grudge because of this...
It's plausible, since that "ANYTIME AYNWHERE"
in the ransom note is Nijimura's catch phrase.
Also, adding "black" in front of your rainbow trademark...
It's something a counterfeit company would do.
Stop right there.
We will take over the investigation, so leave immediately.
Hold it.
Mouri-san was actually contacted by my husband
to collect evidence pertaining to the lawsuit.
I'm also afraid to carry that much money all by
myself, so I'd like him to be my bodyguard.
Just count on me!
Allow me to carry it outside.
No thanks, I'll be fine.
Touto Ikebukuro Station Inbound
Express Train Blue Sky
Hey now, why do you guys have to come?
As camouflage, didn't you say so yourself, Dad?
Yeah! Hiking, hiking!
Anytime, anywhere...
We don't know when or where the culprit may appear.
Understood.
Next stop is the final stop, Okuho Station. Okuho Station.
You may transfer to the Koushuu Express Line or the Touto Okuho Line.
Okuho Station
Hey, let's hurry up!
Hurry up!
Right.
Ma'am, what did the culprit say?
"Transfer now."
Transfer?
We'll be late for the train!
We barely made it!
Thank goodness.
It would've taken forever to wait for the next train.
You're right.
I'll go this time.
Wow, so fast!
Let me see that paper.
TRANSFER TO THE
TOUTO - OKUHO LINE,
AND WHEN YOU REACH
THE MIDDLE OF THE
NAKATORO BRIDGE,
TOSS THE RANSOM
MONEY BAG!
"Transfer to the Touto-Okuho Line, and when you reach the
middle of the Nakatoro Bridge, toss the ransom money bag."
What!?
Nakatoro Bridge
This is...
What siren is that?
This is bad, the dam's discharging!
Oh no!
The culprit's plan is...
To flush away the bag!
I see, so that's why they demanded the money be
put in a sturdy and waterproof Nijimura bag!
Damn, what a cunning criminal!
Contact the other squads!
Downstream! Have them go downstream!
Are you all right?
I'm sure your husband is fine.
Thank you.
What's this —
what's eating at me?
I have this terrible feeling...
You still can't locate the bag?
I see. Continue the search.
Our transmitter bug planted on the name tag
seems to have been damaged by the water.
Unfortunately, my terrible feeling soon ended up true.
The handbag, swept away by the dam discharge, was
recovered at the riverbank 5 kilometers downstream.
But the hundred million yen inside the
bag was apparently taken by the culprit.
We were supposed to wait for the release of the hostage, but...
The next morning, along with the stolen
vehicle that was used during the kidnapping...
President Nijimura's murdered body was also found.
Darling, why...
I'm sorry.
We will do everything we can to apprehend the culprit.
You're sorry?
Like hell you are!
It's because they spotted you police that they killed my husband!
No, we didn't expose ourselves...
Ma'am, please calm down.
Then it was you! You were discovered by the culprit!
What kind of "great detective" are you!?
No...
Inspector!
Regarding your husband's murder,
we've come across new information.
The time of Nijimura's murder was determined
to be between 11:00 AM and noon yesterday.
What?
He was kidnapped around 10:30 AM, so...
Those bastards!
They think hostages only hinder them, so they
killed him shortly after the kidnapping...
And still worked up the nerve to demand a ransom!
How horrible...
This...
You can't, Conan-kun!
Geez, why's that kid here?
The name tag with the bug is missing...
Brats need to go away!
Here.
Sorry about that.
Let's go, Conan-kun.
At any rate, our culprit is a ruthless murderer and sly as a fox!
This is a murder case now.
Katsuragi-kun, we will be joining the investigation from here on out.
Understood.
Although at a time like this, no, because of a time like this...
Madam Saki Takes
President's Place!
I have to respond to the love and support shown to our Nijimura bags.
I hereby vow to work hard to live up the reputation of the company.
And, regarding the counterfeit products that have
been causing problems to my beloved customers...
I will request that law enforcement authorities enhance
their effort in fighting copyright infringement...
Until total annihilation has been achieved.
Where are you going, Dad?
Where else?
"Recheck crime scenes thoroughly," it's the
motto of the police, no, for detectives too!
In that case I'll go too!
Don't be stupid!
How can I work when a kid's with me?
However, I was at the scene from the beginning this time.
If Uncle forgets or misses something, I might be able to pick it up.
Don't you dare talk back to me.
See, two heads are better than one!
Three heads are better than two.
I was at the scene from the beginning too,
so I can't allow you to leave me by myself.
Yes, ma'am.
Nimura Office Backdoor
The incident started here.
How scary, to think the kidnapping happened right in front of us.
The police set up roadblocks immediately,
yet still failed to spot the criminal...
Carrying the ransom money, Saki-san
boarded the Blue Sky express train.
Okuho Station
She then got off here - at Okuho Station.
Most likely, this was the culprit's attempt to distract the police.
Then, as the train she transfered to
was just about to pass the bridge...
She tossed the bag into the river from the train.
That was when the dam was scheduled to discharge water.
Thus, the bag was swept away by the rising water level.
When it was finally found at the riverbank 5 kilometers downstream...
The ransom money had already been taken by the culprit.
By the way, the name tag that was fitted with the
transmitter bug wasn't found with the bag, right?
The bag tumbled downstream due to the force of the current.
The tag must've fallen off.
Speaking of which, the discharge was surprisingly strong.
To think it could have pushed a bag weighing
10 kilograms over a distance of five kilometers.
Saki-san must've been carrying a lot of weight.
Come to think of it, at that time...
Allow me to carry it outside.
No thanks, I'll be fine.
Don't tell me...
The rain stopped.
You're right.
Hey, look at that!
Wow, a rainbow!
Beautiful!
Red, orange, yellow, green, blue, indigo, violet!
I see, so that's how it is!
Hello, Nijimura speaking.
It's me, Mouri Kogorou.
I've figured out who killed your husband.
Are you sure?
That press conference of yours served as a hint.
Tomorrow morning, I will reveal the truth at the
riverbank under the bridge where the bag was tossed.
Bye.
What did you say?
You know who the culprit is?
Really, Inspector?
What do you mean, Mouri-kun?
Under that bridge, you say?
Roger that.
Now, for the finale.
The wife!?
That's... the ransom money!
But wasn't the bag swept away...?
Explain this to us, Mouri-kun!
I'm the one who wants to ask that, Inspector!
What exactly do you...
The bag we found downstream was a dummy.
If you toss the bag into a dam discharge, people
would think it'd get washed away downstream.
That was your diversionary tactic.
Detective Takagi, try emptying the bag.
Right away.
This bag... why is it so heavy even when it's empty?
This is...
An iron plate?
Don't tell me...
Correct.
Because of the metal weight planted inside,
the bag stayed under the bridge until now.
We have been fooled by the culprit into believing the
dummy bag at the downstream riverbank was real.
You must've panicked when you heard that
I'd reveal the truth here tomorrow morning.
As such, you came to quickly collect the money...
No, the bag - that would've otherwise been unnecessary.
Because you didn't want us to find out that the bag downstream,
unlike the bag with ransom money in it, was a counterfeit!
A counterfeit?
That bag was?
Although they look alike...
The fake bag has a slightly different
color arrangement than the real one.
Isn't that right?
In this kidnapping case, there was an
unnatural situation I'd like to address.
Which is, the culprit didn't restrain the hostage,
but merely seated him in the passenger seat.
In other words, the kidnapping was
actually staged by Saki-san and Nijimura.
They wanted none other than me,
Mouri Kogorou, to become a witness.
As for the reason why the kidnapper's car
wasn't caught in your timely roadblock...
It was because they hid themselves
in a parking garage near the scene.
But immediately after that, you killed Nijimura in the garage.
The rest would be simply your solo play.
You mailed yourself the ransom note.
Then, you prepared the kidnapper's instructions
yourself while among the crowd of passengers.
You made it look like the culprit was really there.
But, Saki-san, why did you use a counterfeit bag as your dummy?
Had you used a real bag, perhaps your
plan would've never been seen through.
There's no way I could do that, now could I?
Nijimura's products are like my adorable children.
To think I'd damage my own bag like that one?
It's something I could never do!
That's why you used a counterfeit.
After all, it was all the counterfeit company's
fault that our household income was suffering!
Despite this, that man cut a deal with the counterfeit
company, getting dirty money from them...
He then put everything into gambling and went deeply in debt!
I can't believe he came up with this staged
kidnapping idea to pay off his debt!
That's why I pretended to agree and took him down!
This brand is the result of my design and all my hard work, you know?
I only wanted to take it back!
ANYTIME, ANYWHERE...
Since it was her handmade bag, be it submerged into
the water or withstanding the dam discharge...
It would definitely protect the 100 million yen.
Betting on her confidence and pride, she committed the crime...
And lost her gamble.
How beautiful!
A rainbow across the sky!
Conan-kun!
Dad!
There's a leg across my head...
It's an organization I must crush,
even if it requires sacrificing you.
If only Akai-san were here, we wouldn't have to fear that Bourbon guy.
We don't fear him!
In any case, Akai Shuuichi is dead!
Shuu!
A gunshot?
Don't tell me...
Bank robbers...
Next Conan's Hint
Eye covering
Look forward to the Next Episode