Friday the 13th...
On this day, a man met his fate.
FBI investigator, Akai Shuuichi.
A while ago, the FBI stopped the assassination of Domon
Yasutera that had been plotted by the Black Organization.
They also captured one of the organization's
members, anchorwoman Mizunashi Rena.
In actually, she was a spy from the CIA
that had infiltrated the organization.
We tricked the organization into seizing Mizunashi Rena back...
And successfully placed her back within the organization.
However, in order to prove her loyalty to the organization,
Mizunashi Rena was ordered to gun down Akai Shuuichi.
And, after he was called out to Raiha Pass...
To think you'd go this far...
I'm surprised myself.
That it's worked out... this well.
As such, the FBI has driven into the organization...
A wedge of steel so deep that it can never be removed.
All at the price of leaving a traumatic wound in their hearts...
Love is magic, attack the mystery.
On Saturday nights, be sure to click on Conan!
The Detective Boys versus a robber group.
The FBI's also involved in a bank panic!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Please give me a break, boss.
I'm already past the age of celebrating birthdays.
Don't be a killjoy.
Everyone's going to have one light drink, that's all.
But...
There's nothing to worry about, Camel.
With the investigation into the organization dragging along...
He's just using this as an excuse to relax.
Of course, James is treating, right?
Yeah.
In that case, we need to choose a good alcohol!
Hey, hey, nothing too expensive, now.
The Organization has activated a new member.
An agent who is frighteningly skilled at intelligence
gathering as well as observation and discernment.
Their codename is...
Bourbon.
It's been a while since we got information on him from that
Mizunashi Rena who managed to re-infiltrate the organization.
But he hasn't shown himself at all, that detective-like fellow.
Bourbon's target is likely that little girl known as "Sherry."
Based on everything that's transpired so far...
It wouldn't be surprising for the organization to think
that little girl is connected to us FBI members.
Because of that, we thought they would
make a move and approach us, but...
That's true...
A while ago, the same type of listening bug used by that girl was
deployed to lure the organization to Detective Mouri's agency...
And we FBI ending up sniping them.
Although, the one who planted the bug
was actually Edogawa Conan-kun.
That reminds me, that person liked that alcohol too, right?
I mean Akai-san!
The one who shot those guys that'd been
lured to a building 700 yards away...
That was Akai-san too, wasn't it?
Huh?
Was I wrong?
No, it was as you said, but...
If only Akai-san were here, we wouldn't have to fear that Bourbon guy.
We don't fear him!
We're just waiting for the organization to
become impatient and make a move!
Moreover, Akai Shuuichi is dead!
Do not bring his name up again!
I'm going back to the car.
All right...
Do be more considerate.
To her, Akai-kun wasn't merely an FBI colleague, you know.
You two started going out?
And she's the one you mentioned before, the
member of that syndicate, Miyano Akemi-san?
Yeah.
That's why we have to break this off.
Hold on a second, Shuu!
You're only going out with her because of the investigation, right?
I don't see the need for us to separate.
It's an organization I must crush,
even if it requires sacrificing you.
Being able to love two women at once...
That just isn't who I am.
I'm still glad...
To have had the chance to work with you...
Shuu... why?
Why did you, all of a sudden...
Shuu!
Wait for me...
Shuu, wait...
Shuu!
SHUU!
No doubt about it, that was Shuu.
But he should be dead!
Could it be a doppelganger?
I need to make sure.
I need to meet him and make sure!
Did something happen?
I don't remember parking my car around here.
No...
Don't tell me you saw someone from the organization?
Nothing like that!
I just lost my way, that's all.
That aside, did you get some good alcohol?
No, I couldn't use my card at that store.
And I didn't bring that much yen with me...
Sorry, Jodie-kun, but could you pay for us first?
I planned to make a withdrawal later, so my wallet's empty now!
Is that so...
Well, I'll make a trip to a nearby bank.
Please wait for me at the store.
Much appreciated.
No...
No, it has to be someone else!
That was just an illusion...
It wasn't Shuu.
Mitsuhiko-kun, you saved all of your New Year's money.
Yeah, I opened my very own account a while ago.
You got quite a lot and you're saving it all, isn't that a waste?
Please call it being thrifty!
Genta, what did you do with your New Year's money then?
I gave it to Mom for safekeeping!
She said she'll use it to buy expensive stuff for me!
And?
Did she buy anything for you?
Come to think of it, never.
She'd say, "Don't be extravagant."
She's pretty clever, Genta's mom.
Well, she could be saving up just in case Genta becomes terribly sick.
But that's the same as saving with a bank.
Well then, I'm gonna get back everything I've received so far!
Hey, hey.
After all, I won't get sick!
Oww! My stomach hurts!
Are you all right, Genta-kun?
Did you eat something weird?
I only had two helpings of curry rice for lunch.
But when I went to pick you up, I saw
soy flour on your mouth, didn't I?
That's because, after eating curry,
I felt like eating something sweet...
So I roasted some mochi from the fridge, made
some kinako mochi and ate four of them.
After that, I felt like eating something spicy again.
So I put soy sauce on them, wrapped them
with dried seaweed, and ate three more.
You just ate too much.
Geez, Genta-kun...
Well, we'll buy some stomach medicine from a nearby pharmacy.
Do whatever you need to in the restroom.
His New Year's money will end up as his food.
That sums it up.
That was...
Jodie-sensei?
She didn't notice us.
Maybe she had something on her mind?
Ah, ma'am, please avoid using your cellphone while using the ATM.
We're doing our best to prevent cases of remittance fraud.
Cellphone...
Just as you said...
Both your and Conan-kun's prints are there on the cellphone.
As are the prints of the man whose burnt
corpse was found just a while ago.
Right...
He's dead... haven't I told myself that numerous times?
Even so...
To have seen such an illusion...
I hope it doesn't happen again... I don't want to experience that.
Yeah, it's as though a bullet just penetrated my heart...
Lock the entrances and close the shutters!
Everyone gather in one place now!
What was that?
That sound just now...
That was loud...
A gunshot...
Don't tell me...
Hey, did something happen?
Genta, stay there.
Mitsuhiko and Ayumi-chan, you too.
I'll check out the situation.
Conan-kun!
Hey, hurry up and have a seat over here!
You see how it is now?
If you don't wanna get hurt, get a move on!
Listen up!
If there's someone you know or brought along, stay close to them!
Stay close to someone you know or brought along?
Did something happen?
It looks like it's been locked.
And it doesn't look so normal inside.
The shutters are closing!
What happened?
Hey, what's wrong?
Don't tell me, it's a...
Bank robbery, huh?
All right!
For the time being, put your cellphones in this bag!
This sort of thing happened before...
Yeah, during that bus-jacking.
But at that time...
At that time, Shuu...
You were there...
Hey, foreign lady!
You don't understand Japanese?
No, I understand a little bit!
Then hand over your cellphone and sit down!
OK, OK!
Sorry.
Shu...
Shuu?
Shuu...
Are you Shuu?
You're Shuu, right?
Say that you're Shuu!
You don't know me?
You can't talk?
Burn marks...
Don't tell me, he managed to escape from the burning Chevrolet...
And the shocking experience robbed him of his voice and memory?
Hey, you!
Stop making a fuss, you foreign woman!
Hurry and put your cellphone in this bag!
OK, OK.
Hey, you too, hurry!
Bastard, you wanna die?
No, no!
He no talk because a shock from accident!
The burn marks, they proof!
I think he no talk even if had phone!
Fine, I got it!
Just sit down and hush!
Hey, you're next!
Yes...
At any rate, I have to take him back to the FBI and restore his memory.
We need to know how he survived...
And whose burnt body was in the Chevrolet.
But first, I have to take care of these robbers.
Hey, is the branch chief here?
Good, come over here!
Hurry over here!
Yes...
Don't be scared, just pack all your money into these cases.
Easy, ain't it?
Only me?
Yeah, seems like you'd know about where the money is!
Now, the ones who have no companions here, stand up!
Come here and take a roll of tape each!
Use it to tape the eyes and mouths of everyone with
a companion, and tie their arms behind their backs!
Since you aren't acquainted with any of them,
I don't have to worry about you going soft on them.
Here.
Of course, we'll tape you up all the same afterwards!
Uhm...
I'm sorry, I'm putting it on...
Oh, before that!
Please let me go potty!
I no hold it more!
Damn, it's that foreign woman again...
Pwetty pwease!
Fine, but your eyes, mouth and arms need to be taped up!
OK, thank you.
Walk faster now!
Stop.
Well, won't make a difference to just take her to the men's room.
Not like there's anyone here to see us.
Go in.
Call me when you finish!
Oh, right, with your arms bound,
you can't get your underwear off.
Guess I'll do the honors!
As expected of an FBI agent.
You did it.
Why are you here?
We originally came with Mitsuhiko to make a deposit, but...
Ended up bringing Genta to the restroom due to his stomachache.
Then, we heard a loud bang!
We've been hiding in here ever since.
My stomach has already calmed down.
And?
How many robbers?
Five, and all of them are armed.
So they're after the money?
Yeah, they ordered the money to be packed inside their cases.
But it's strange, they sorted out the ones with companions...
And allowed only the branch chief to pack the money.
For some reason, all of them were concerned with the time.
Time?
I doubt I can do this, but if I can defeat them alone, no problem!
Go for it, Jodie, the game starts now!
Enough.
You don't need to go for it.
I was just thinking something may have gone
wrong here, and it turns out I was right.
No use, he's completely out cold.
It's gonna be a drag carrying him!
We don't have much time.
Just take off his mask and jacket, and seat him on the toilet.
He'll appear to be a customer who was hiding in the restroom
and got beaten by the robbers when they found him.
Hey, carry that end!
But, who was that woman?
Who knows.
Well, no need to know who she is or where she's from.
She'll just blast off anyway.
Got that right!
What now?
Jodie-sensei was taken!
We'll have to beat those punks up!
But, there are five of them!
No, there are four.
Really bad, something really bad happened.
We've completely surrounded the bank.
And?
Have the robbers listed their demands?
Not yet, sir.
I see...
How odd.
In this situation, it would be normal for robbers
to use hostages as a shield to flee the scene.
That may be true, but I think they'll just
give up and surrender soon enough.
They have no way to escape.
Do you really think so?
I saw the inside before the shutters went down.
I saw several men with guns and masks.
In order to pull it off wearing those...
They'd have to arm up in a large vehicle,
park it in front of the bank, and charge in.
They planned their robbery, but they
didn't escape after stealing the money...
Instead they closed everyone inside without
making a demand, isn't that strange?
They probably have something up their sleeves.
A plan to take the money and get out of there.
What a sly fox she was.
Something as unworthy as a bank robbery...
Will only end up ruining your life.
He said there wasn't much time left.
First of all, why didn't he keep his mask?
Don't tell me...
Inside of those cases...
There may be bombs.
Bombs!?
Next Conan's Hint
Hostages
Look forward to the Next Episode