While accompanying Mitsuhiko as he deposited
his New Year's money, we arrived at Teito Bank.
However, Genta ate too much mochi, and had a stomachache.
While waiting for Professor and Haibara to buy
medicine, we took Genta to the restroom, but...
Men donning ski masks suddenly appeared,
and took control of the entire bank.
Among the customers — now hostages — was
FBI agent Jodie who happened to be present.
She managed to knock out one of the
robbers she had lured into the restroom...
But some of the others spotted her,
and incapacitated her with a taser.
As such, it's up to us to defeat the robber group.
Although it looks like they have something up their sleeves...
We're still going to take them down!
Love is magic, attack the mystery.
On Saturday nights, be sure to click on Conan!
An epic battle with the robber group.
What is their true intention?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
What a sly fox she was, this foreign woman.
We could bust a cap in her...
But it'd be bad if we alerted the cops
with a gunshot, so we better not.
Yeah.
Uh, um...
The money is ready...
Can you open the cases for me?
Hey, hey! That's a small wad!
Isn't there anything else in the vault!?
Do you want to be blown to pieces?
Just shut up and do what this piece of paper says.
If I hear a peep from you...
I'll split your head open.
Listen up!
Those of you without a companion, get over here
and put duct tape over your eyes and mouths!
We're going to tie your hands behind your backs!
Hey, it's me.
How are things on your end?
What, you're awake?
Yeah...
But my head is spinning and I can't get around by myself...
Can you come for a sec and help me up?
Got it.
Wait for me.
What is it?
That guy woke up.
I'm gonna help him up, you take care of things here.
Be quick, we don't have much time.
Hey, hey!
You're still out cold!
Then who just called?
Must've been a message from Dreamland, huh?
Something as unworthy as a bank robbery...
Will only end up ruining your life.
Brat, where'd you-!?
Hey, wait!
I said wait!
Wait, or else...
I'll kill ya!
How is it, Conan?
Ah, he got a concussion and fainted.
Let's tie him up with the bathroom hose for now!
We did it!
The toilet paper strategy was a big success!
Our effort of spreading them out was rewarded!
The stun dart is my last resort, so I'll save it for later.
Conan-kun, what do we do next?
How about this?
Let's use his cell phone to call his other partners.
If I check his call log, I'll probably find his
partner's number before the call I just made.
Hey, it's me.
How are things on your end?
Huh? Things on my end?
Didn't I say I was going to the beauty salon when we talked earlier?
I'm getting ready for our date tonight~
I see, later then.
This bastard actually called his girl before the crime...
Other, other...
But most of the other calls were to the guy
who was knocked out in the restroom.
Hey, Conan, what are you doing?
Hurry up and call them!
He said there wasn't much time left.
Time...
We don't have much time.
Just take off his mask and jacket, and seat him on the toilet.
What kind of time?
Are they expecting another accomplice to pick them up?
Also...
They sorted out the ones with companions...
And allowed only the branch chief to pack the money.
Why did they sort out the customers?
And what's the purpose of allowing only the chief to pack the money?
First of all, why didn't he keep his mask?
If the police came charging in, his face would...
Don't tell me...
Uhm...
This one's done.
I see.
Good work.
But he sure is slow.
The guy who went to get our unconscious colleague in the restroom.
It's been five minutes.
Forget about them.
We don't have any time left.
It's time for the finale!
Everything is prepared, sir.
We're ready to charge in.
We can go at any time!
Good!
Technical backup team and control team,
get ready to move when the time's right!
Roger!
Have the robbers made any demands?
Not yet.
We've been calling the phone inside
the bank, but the line was still busy.
The line's busy?
Those cops out there must be wondering what we're up to...
Since we aren't saying anything.
But why don't we pull out the phone line?
It's better for us this way.
By letting them think we're on the phone making
demands with someone else out there...
They'll hesitate on forcing their way inside!
But the guy who went to help in the restroom still isn't back.
Maybe the guy can't haul him back alone?
The one in the toilet was a fatso, y'know.
Not a problem.
To prepare for a rare instance such as this, I had
given you instructions beforehand, right?
Also...
About this pesky foreign woman who managed
to knock out the guy in the restroom...
She's headed for the other world anyway.
You figured it out?
You figured out the robbers' plan?
Yeah.
Those robbers probably...
Intend to disguise themselves as hostages
in order to escape from the bank.
Disguise, you say?
But how?
Did you notice that all the robbers had a similar appearance?
Yes.
The guy Jodie-sensei beat up in the restroom...
And the guys who made Jodie-sensei faint with the stun gun...
They all wore ski masks and the same jumpers.
The guy left in the restroom by his partners
had his mask and jumper removed, right?
And this man who came to pick him up removed his as well.
In other words, they planned to choose five people among
the hostages, knock them out with the stun gun...
Cover them with the ski masks, put the jumpers on them,
and have the hostages pose as the robbers themselves.
But, won't they be found out immediately?
They won't.
Judging from Jodie-sensei having her
eyes, mouth, and hands taped up...
The other hostages should be in the same condition as well.
I get it, because they can't see anything, they
have no idea what the bad guys are doing!
Yeah.
Further proof is that the robbers sorted out the hostages by
those who came with companions and those who were alone.
By selecting five from those who came
alone and dressing them as robbers...
After the incident plays out and those five
people disappear, no one can say anything.
After the incident plays out, they'll disappear?
But why?
The robbers demanded the money to be
collected and packed up inside their cases...
But only allowed the branch chief to do it, why's that?
Isn't it because he knows the most about the bank?
First of all, in a small branch like this, you can
only collect 100 million yen at the counter.
Adding another 200 million from the ATM,
you'll end up with 300 million in cash.
It will take quite a while for only one person to
collect and pack all that cash into the cases.
Then, why only one person?
Because the cases aren't planned for storing the money after all.
Inside of those cases...
There may be bombs.
Bombs!?
Bombs...
What do you mean?
The cases with bombs will be put behind the counter.
And after the robbers put the five hostages,
branch chief, and Jodie-sensei to sleep...
They'll scatter the money that the branch
chief had taken out and set off the bombs.
After the explosion, seven bodies will remain,
along with the money flying around.
To the eyes of the police who charge in later...
It will appear that the bombs were used to open
the vaults, but exploded at the wrong time.
It would seem to have killed the robbers
along with the branch chief and Jodie-sensei.
This crime will then be considered a failure.
So you mean, the robbers weren't here for the money?
No.
They may have forced the branch chief to transfer a
large amount of money to a bank account online...
Which would then be forwarded to their own account.
Probably to some foreign bank outside of Japan's jurisdiction.
They're intelligent criminals.
No, they're a bunch of amateurs.
Even if they are able to transfer 300
million yen from here to a foreign bank...
Any remittance over five million yen,
without proper cause as required by law...
Will be stopped by the headquarters
of the foreign exchange bill center.
That regulation didn't exist in the past.
But these days, fraud and money laundering are rampant.
Perhaps the plan to rob this bank was formed long ago...
But it took a substantial amount of time to
arrange for the personnel and weapons.
So their plan is bound to fail, right?
What idiots they are.
But their guns are real.
The bombs may be, too.
If we're careless, we won't be able to jump right in to capture them.
Jump right in?
How?
Are you going to fire that gun?
No, I'm just holding onto it.
I won't shoot.
When we jump in, we'll take them head on.
But there are still three robbers left!
We'll get shot!
Don't worry.
When that moment comes, they won't be able to see us.
That moment?
I bet they'll shout something like this at the hostages.
SCREW IT, WE'LL JUST GO AHEAD AND BLOW THE BANK UP!
GIVE ME A HAND, GUYS!
They've made a move.
By "shout" you mean...
What they just said?
Yeah.
Ayumi-chan, keep the elevator door open and wait there.
Genta, move the cart in front of the elevator to
the counter where the hostages are gathering.
Mitsuhiko and I will head there first.
Got it.
Leave it to me!
Listen, act calmly and don't make any noise.
Be swift, swift.
Say, Conan-kun...
Is it really safe...
There are a lot hostages here, but no sign of the robbers.
I see...
In order to disguise themselves as hostages, they've
taped their eyes and mouths, so they can't see us.
As I expected.
Only about two minutes left until the explosion.
This is more than enough.
Hey, Conan.
The cart is here.
Get these on the cart.
Ayumi-chan, get out quick!
A loud noise just...
Go verify it!
Roger!
Looks like something happened!
That sure was close.
We're lucky it didn't explode immediately!
It wasn't luck.
To disguise as hostages, they have to
tape their eyes and mouths as well.
After the guy let out a loud shout just now...
The robbers used their mouths to bind their own hands
together, and walked into the midst of the hostages.
After taping their eyes and mouths, they passed both legs through
their bound hands, and brought their hands behind their backs.
If they hadn't left plenty of time to do that, they wouldn't be at ease.
They figured that three minutes was enough.
But why did they use time bombs?
Had they used a remote control, they could've
set the bombs off at their own pace.
If they used a remote, they could press the button, but they
couldn't throw the remote far away with their hands bound.
I see.
But, how do we find the robbers among these people?
It's simple, if I use the robber's voice and shout this...
Listen up! Everyone stand up and slowly
walk towards the direction of my voice!
I repeat, slowly!
Don't trip on the person in front of you!
Hey, this...
How do we find the culprits like this...
This wasn't part of the plan!
Did the plan change?
Something's not right...
It's you three, isn't it?
Not obeying orders outside of the plan,
you can only be the robbers themselves.
All right!
Let's get the tape off the bank employees
and ask them to open the doors.
Yes!
When the police charge in, they'll take these three men, the guy
bound in the corridor, and the guy lying in the restroom...
Who's lying in the restroom?
Conan-kun!
Whether it's that foreign woman or this brat...
What are they up to!?
Damn, did the explosion wake him up!?
Hey, you brats over there!
If you don't want to see his neck broken,
hand me that gun on the counter!
With things this way, we'll go down together.
Just accompany me to hell!
What's this?
You already got one.
You just get ready to...
DIE!
Who was it?
Who fired that shot?
Was it Jodie-sensei?
Due to the gunshot, the police swarmed the bank...
And the group of robbers were apprehended in a flash.
It seems everyone's all right!
Well, it's an obvious result.
Edogawa-kun and an FBI agent were there.
No, this time...
It's thanks to these kids, the Detective Boys.
Well...
It's not like...
We're awesome!
But, we still wanted to ask you something.
Jodie-sensei, you're an English teacher, right?
When did you start working with the FBI?
Well...
Don't tell me, you're roleplaying?
Genta-kun always like to roleplay Kamen Yaiba!
Yeah, I was roleplaying!
I knew it!
What's wrong? You and your serious face.
I was wondering who shot the culprit with a gun in the end.
Jodie-sensei was unconscious...
With the situation like that, who else could fire that shot?
Shuu!
Hey, did you see him?
Wasn't he with the hostages?
You must've gone through a lot, Jodie-kun.
We were in the liquor store this whole time and didn't realize...
And?
Who were you looking for?
T-That...
Akai Shuuichi is dead!
Do not bring his name up again!
Is something wrong?
No, it's nothing...
Please forget what I said.
While getting his hair cut, Uncle encountered a murder case.
Find out who the culprit is through the witness testimonies!
One, Two...
Next Conan's Hint
Wig
Look forward to the Next Episode