Dad was invited to a party on short notice.
So that's why Uncle took out his special occasion outfit, right?
Right.
And this is done.
What's wrong?
I was thinking maybe I should get a nicer tie for Shin'ichi.
Why did you turn all red, Conan-kun?
Ah, no, it's nothing!
And where's Uncle?
At the barber's.
He's pretty late.
Then I-I'll go get him!
Flowers dance to the piano's rhythm.
Two people face-to-face is a mystery!
Not seeing anything despite being at the scene...
Who is this perplexed eye-witness?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Why do those shops have to be full, especially today?
Wait for me!
I said wait!
We're already closed.
Sorry, but I'm in a hurry.
So another customer is ahead of me?
Please, do mine first and I'll come to your shop from now on.
Understood.
Looks like he's deeply relaxing, so I'll do yours first.
Thank you!
Hot, hot!
Please wait.
What're they gonna serve at the party tonight?
Would be nice if it were French cuisine!
Chinese food is good too —
shark fin and Peking duck!
Sounds like the shuttle bus of the newly opened swimming school.
Noisy as always, geez!
So noisy!
You want me to sue you for noise violation!?
Cut it out already!
Just hurry and go somewhere else, dammit!
Noisy, noisy!
Finally...
What was that!?
What is it?
He's dead!
Ebihara!
Uncle!
You weren't at your usual shop so it took a while to find you!
Hey! Did you see anyone suspicious?
Well, I didn't, but is something wrong?
Call the police now.
Yes!
Uncle!
Hey, don't come inside!
This is...
Hey!
All right, let's fly it one more time...
Hey, Genta!
Conan-kun!
Did anyone come out from here?
No one came out.
Did something happen?
I wonder what's wrong.
Damn...
A murder right behind my back?
How dare they!
Excuse me, you are —
?
I'm the famous detective, Mouri Kogoro.
You're the famous...
You got it!
Conan, is it a case again?
Hey, no kids allowed here!
That includes you.
I guess it does...
And, as I turned my head after getting startled by the noise,
I saw the shop owner Ebihara-san lying on the floor.
He had already stopped breathing.
I see, so you heard everything as the crime was taking place, right?
Yes.
What you heard was the sound of these dropping on the floor?
That's right.
They were on the cashier counter, so I suspect Ebihara-san
knocked those over with his elbow as he was falling.
I see.
That single dart... why is it lying way over there?
Noda-san, was it?
So you were in a deep sleep at the time Mouri-kun entered this shop?
Yes.
Noda Masao (43)
Clock Shop Owner
That's why I didn't notice Mouri-san come inside.
What time did you come here?
About that...
I had been looking for barber shops that were
vacant, so I didn't take note of the time.
But, the incident happened only a few minutes after I got here.
The 1-1-0 call was placed at 6:36 PM, so...
Mouri-san's arrival would be approximately 6:30 PM.
And what time did you arrive here?
Around 6:20 PM.
Maybe I was just overly tired, but as soon as
I got on the chair, I fell into a deep sleep.
By the way, during the incident, no one else was
entering or exiting the shop, is that right?
Right.
At that time, the shuttle bus from the
swimming school was in front of the shop.
I don't think it was possible to enter or exit without being seen.
I didn't see anyone coming out of the shop, either.
And no one left through the back door either?
Nope, not a single person.
We were playing in the vacant lot behind the shop the whole time.
The culprit may have thrown a dart from
the outside and killed Ebihara-san.
From the outside?
The swimming school shuttle bus was
incidentally playing loud music at the time.
I bet he opened the window in order to complain.
You're saying the culprit anticipated that,
and threw a dart at him from the outside?
Exactly.
The culprit was probably hiding in the
alley on the opposite side of the shop.
Culprit
Ebihara
It's about 4 meters from the alley to this shop —
not a far-fetched distance for a dart to travel.
The tip of the dart was dabbed with poison.
Say, why did Ebihara-san wear a wig?
True, it doesn't seem like he needed one.
Do you know why, Noda-san?
No, I don't...
His reason for wearing a wig...
Ebihara-san is wearing an uncommon sweatshirt.
That's the sweatshirt from the Darts Hearts Club,
formed by the regulars at a nearby dart bar.
Darts Hearts...?
You too?
Yes.
A regular at a darts bar was killed by a dart.
This could mean that the culprit is a regular at that darts bar, too.
These two frequent that darts bar.
Shimazaki Nozomu (28)
Linen Services Employee
An employee from a linen service company,
Shimazaki Nozomu-san, and...
A pharmacist who works at a nearby
drugstore, Koike Tatsutarou-san.
Koike Tatsutarou (45)
Pharmacist
I'm told that you two were arguing with
Ebihara-san at the darts bar last night, correct?
Well, uhm...
It's because that old man Ebihara was blabbering
things that were neither here nor there!
Neither here nor there?
About that...
"Shima-chan has been embezzling from
the company," was what Ebi-chan said...
And then, Shima-chan flew into a rage and grabbed
him by his chest, so I went to stop them was all.
Cut the crap!
You, too!
When he said you've been selling drugs on the black market in an
attempt to overcome your debt, your face turned blue, didn't it?
That wasn't...
What, Noda-chan?
You haven't recovered from your cold?
Where's your mask?
I seem to have dropped it somewhere.
And you, Noda-san!
You may stand there pretending everything's cool, but
you've been borrowing from old man Ebihara, no?
That's right, Ebi-chan said that he's been footing
the bill for your store's operating costs.
Is that true?
I did borrow from him, but it wasn't a large amount.
I wonder.
When the incident took place, Noda-san, weren't you at the shop?
Isn't that most suspicious?
No, during Ebihara-san's murder, Noda-san
was sitting on the chair next to me.
It would be impossible for him to commit the crime.
Who are you supposed to be, with such a big attitude?
I'm the famous detective Mouri Kogoro.
Sleeping Kogoro!?
By the way, at approximately 6:30 PM...
Where were you two?
You first, Koike-san.
I was in my drugstore.
Can someone else confirm your statement?
About that...
No customers came, and my wife was in the kitchen preparing dinner...
So no one else?
But I didn't do it!
Please believe me.
Shimazaki-san, you?
Around 6:30 PM, I think I was still in the middle of a delivery.
Oh, right, I did stop by a gasoline station.
Gasoline station?
Then, if I were to contact the manager, would
they be able to confirm your whereabouts?
No, I used a self-serve pump, so I
didn't come across the manager...
But I have the receipt here!
6:24 PM...
From that gas station to this shop, it would
take at least thirty minutes even by car.
Ayumi did see that person earlier!
Where did you see him?
In front of this shop.
He was coming out the front door.
About what time did that happen?
Sometime in the evening.
Let's see, I could see the clock inside this shop through the windows.
It was 5:50!
That clock...
4:15!?
Huh?
7:45?
That clock has its left and right reversed.
It's for customers to see in the mirror.
Oh, I see.
So you finally got one of those?
It was a regular clock before.
Noda-chan, when did you get one in stock?
Oh, last night.
In that case, the time Ayumi-chan saw
Shimazaki-san wasn't at 5:50, but 6:10.
If you came out of here at 6:10, it would be impossible
for you to have arrived at the gas station at 6:24.
No, I did come here to pick up the towels!
Although we had a fight about things that happened last
night, I left quickly because I had other deliveries to do.
It was as she said —
before six o'clock!
But we told you, that clock has its display
flipped horizontally, so it was 6:10.
Wrong, it was before six o'clock!
Shimazaki-san...
Your embezzling was discovered by Ebihara-san, so you killed him.
Nonsense...
After you left the shop, you hid in the alley,
waiting for Ebihara-san to open the windows...
I couldn't make that with my skills...
I'm the worst rookie in Darts Hearts.
That's right, Koike-san!
You could've done it!
What are you saying?
You're the most skilled among our group!
The tip of the dart used in the murder was laced with poison!
As a pharmacist, Koike-san could've easily concocted a poison, right?
What nonsense!
Koike-san... The culprit is you!
You're wrong!
So who is the culprit?
As a famous detective, he should really be more specific on that.
He seems unreliable.
YOU BRATS, SCRAM!
Tsk, stingy!
We even gave them important witness statements!
Right, right!
If a poisoned dart was prepared, then this was a premeditated crime.
If that's so, would they really throw it from this far away?
I can't see the clock through the windows!
Ayumi-chan, you said you saw the clock, but from where?
Let's see...
It was around here.
Huh?
How weird, I can't see the clock now...
But I really saw it earlier!
The clock was moved?
But why...
I see!
It was like that!
I've got it.
The culprit is that person!
Shimazaki-san and Koike-san, please come
to the station for further questioning.
How come...
Hold it right there.
I will reveal the truth at this very moment.
What's that?
Are you saying you figured out who did it?
Actually the culprit was already in the shop before I arrived...
And he's still among us.
What did you say!?
Right, the culprit is...
Noda-san.
It's you!
Noda-san, you...
Now, now, Mouri-san...
During that entire time, I was sitting right next to you, wasn't I?
When you heard something fall on the floor and looked back...
You said Noda-san also got up from the chair next to you, no?
Ebihara-san wasn't killed at the time the smashing occurred.
In fact, he had already been killed before I arrived here.
What's that!?
That's crazy...
You met with Ebihara-san when you got here, didn't you?
To be exact, a man with an afro who wore a mask,
and a blue sweatshirt saying "Darts Hearts" on it.
And that was Ebihara!
Wrong, that was you in disguise.
Disguise?
Because of my sudden visit, you quickly put on
a wig and a mask to hide your face from me.
Noda-san, you actually still have your mask, don't you?
In that case, where was Ebihara-san's body?
It was in the chair next to me.
Covered with an apron and a hot towel.
Noda-san...
After you killed Ebihara-san at this shop, you were
planning to leave by pretending nothing happened.
But I came in instead.
In a rush, you put on a disguise and introduced yourself as the owner.
After that, you put a hot towel on me to cover my
eyes, and tried to escape through the back door.
However, there were kids in the backyard, and you couldn't escape.
There were people in front of the shop too,
so you were cornered inside like a mouse.
At that very moment, the swimming school's shuttle bus came.
Shuttle bus?
While the bus was playing that noisy and
loud music, you came up with an idea.
Using that music to your advantage, you would
switch yourself with the body on the chair.
And managed to become the primary discoverer along with me.
Under that loud volume, small sounds would go unnoticed.
You quickly laid the body in front of the
counter, and got in the chair yourself.
In that case, how did he make everything fall from the counter?
He threw a dart at those —
the single dart
lying on the floor near the windows.
I see.
As such, he pretended to be awakened by the smashing noise...
So that's how it was...
But tell me, Mouri-kun...
Why did Noda-san have to put the body in the chair?
He didn't think you'd come, did he?
Ebihara-san was killed while he was sitting on the chair.
Why would a barber shop owner sit in his own chair?
He was checking the position of the clock.
The position of the clock?
That clock was brought here before the murder.
I looked from the outside just a while ago, but...
Conan-kun, where did you...
I couldn't see the clock through the windows.
You couldn't see it?
What do you mean?
The clock was hanging right over there, wasn't it?
Hey, that's true!
It was over there before!
If it's over there, we could see it from the outside, huh?
When Ayumi-chan witnessed Shimazaki-san's presence,
the clock was still hanging in the old position.
After that, Noda-san came and
replaced the clock with a flipped one.
And, in order to check the angle, Ebihara-san sat on the chair.
You then restrained him from behind and stabbed him with the dart.
Afterwards, you put a towel over his
face and covered him with an apron.
That way, even if people peeked in from the outside...
They would think a customer was waiting for a shave.
However, you arrived before he could escape.
But wait, where's the original clock?
It's in the shoecase near the back door.
Nonsense!
What Mouri-san said about meeting me
in disguise earlier, do you have proof?
Noda-san...
Under your T-shirt is the sweatshirt from the Darts Hearts club, right?
Why don't you take it off?
Would you mind?
Understood.
No logo or anything!
What a pity.
You didn't seriously think I'd be fooled
by such a childish trick, did you?
Detective Takagi, relieve Noda-san of his shirt.
Hurry!
Roger!
What are you doing?
Please, allow me to do my job...
Stop it!
Please excuse me.
Let go of me!
So you wore it backwards.
He hastily changed it while switching himself with the body.
No one other than the culprit has any reason to wear it backwards.
Noda-chan, why?
The IOU Ebihara forced me to write
when I borrowed money from him...
It was transfered to the loan sharks without me knowing.
I've been receiving threats everyday,
and my wife developed neurosis...
Why did Ebihara-san do that?
He was the one who borrowed money from the loan sharks.
In order to write off his debt, he sold me out!
How could he...
I couldn't forgive...
That terrible guy...
Dammit!
I was supposed to be treated tonight!
After he solved the case, he kept sleeping all the way through?
Yeah, soundly.
That's why he didn't make it to the party.
Ran, another cup!
Sorry that you couldn't enjoy fancy cuisine, Uncle...