Here you go.
It's delicious.
Geez, you think crying can solve everything, huh?
It's hot, so you need to blow on it before you eat it.
Fuu, fuu, like this.
Here, have a bite.
Where?
Where'd you go?
Santa?
The kid's two years old, name's Santa.
About this tall.
Blue clothes and green pants...
Santa-san, where are you!?
Santa-san!
Shh... desu.
Santa!
Watch out!
There! There! There!
This isn't good, Santa!
You can't just do whatever you want.
There! There!
What? You want to look at the cars?
No, no!
Flowers dance to the piano's rhythm.
Two people face-to-face is a mystery!
A little companion with a cute name.
Conan's troublesome partner!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
One, two, one, two...
Dad told you to?
Yeah, he told me to watch this kid.
Go on ahead.
What's your name?
Santa-san!
Santa-san?
You add the "-san" honorific to your own name?
How old are you?
Two years old?
How cute!
Ran!
Dad!
So you're here, too.
Mama, mama!
Conan, you watched the kid like I told you, right?
Yeah.
Let me introduce her.
This is Ishikawa Shigeko-san.
Ishikawa Shigeko (30)
Santa's Mother
Nice to meet you.
You were pushed over? At the pedestrian bridge?
Yeah.
A person wearing a full face helmet pushed me over from behind.
I deliver clothes from a laundry shop as a part time job.
In the middle of a delivery...
And that's when I happened to walk by.
It's a good thing she wasn't hurt, but...
She said something suspicious has been
going on over the past four or five days.
I've been getting this feeling of...
Being constantly watched.
If they were only watching from afar, it wouldn't be a problem, but...
Since she was pushed over...
This might well be a serious case!
Noticing this, I ordered Conan to watch out for the kid...
And proceeded with my investigation!
You're too much.
Do you have any other family?
No, my husband died last year.
It's just me and my child.
Mouri-san, I know you're busy, so I'm sorry to bother you.
Don't say such a thing.
I am a single father with a kid, too.
I'm living a life similar to yours.
Should anything bad happen to you,
this kid would be left all alone!
Something as troublesome as that will
never be tolerated by my conscience!
Never!
I know how you feel, but...
Even if she's a beauty you should put your money where your mouth is.
Say, do you have any idea who the
person with the full face helmet was?
No, not a clue...
Well, let's get going.
I'll find that bastard and grab them by their neck!
Hey...
Relax your shoulders and act as calmly as you can.
Do not alert them to my presence.
Yes.
Good, everything looks perfect for now.
Damn, you're bringing me trouble after trouble...
Do you have a grudge against me or what?
Splash!
On to our next story.
An adorable panda has been born in our local zoo.
According to Suzuki-san, the zookeeper...
Good afternoon. I'm from Sun Sun Cleaning.
Please come in.
Excuse me.
Geez, why'd you do that?
What's wrong, Santa?
P-Potty!?
Wait, hold it for a while.
Not yet, not yet!
For me?
Melted candy?
Potty, tankies!
No problem, don't mention it.
But I guess that was a surprise.
What a turn of events.
Conan!
That kid all right!?
Santa!
Conan!
What is it, Uncle?
You all right?
Shigeko-san was taken by a man!
Taken?
Yeah, that bastard hid himself in her customer's house and jumped her!
What the hell are they thinking, attacking a housewife like that?
Boy, Uncle's here for you.
I'm reporting it to the police, so don't you worry!
Well?
You found Ishikawa Shigeko-san yet?
No.
We found traces of blood in the backseat of the car.
She might have struggled and hurt herself.
The car was stolen from Haido City five days ago.
We've received a report.
That full face helmet guy again.
Judging from the untouched cash, we can
assume that the culprit's aim wasn't money.
Shigeko-san is quite a beauty.
The culprit may have taken a fancy to her, but then...
He couldn't bottle up his desires anymore and took action!
It's a case involving twisted love!
Unforgivable!
But would you push over someone you love?
Conan, how many times have I told you now!?
Don't talk back to me!
Take a hike now!
Fine.
Her bag was open and her things fell out.
No, they were scattered.
Was that guy after something in the bag?
Thank you, Santa.
As I thought.
The culprit was looking for something.
It happened around 1:30.
Did he obtain the keys after kidnapping Shigeko-san?
And what was the culprit looking for?
A bird feather?
Why is it there?
Santa-san, good afternoon.
I've brought a present for you.
What happened? It's a mess here.
We were just playing pro wrestling.
Are you friends with this kid, mister?
Yes, I live upstairs. The name's Moriwaki Minoru.
Moriwaki Minoru (22)
Beika University School Of Veterinary Medicine Student
I'm a vet med student at Beika University, nice to meet you.
Say, do they keep birds in this place?
I found this in the room, but...
This place was locked, so I wonder where it could've come from?
Perhaps it got stuck on someone's body and got here that way.
For example, maybe on you or Santa-san.
Transfer from someone's body?
Could it be from the culprit's?
This is... a Japanese white-eye's feather.
Let's take a look at Santa-san's bird book, shall we?
Book, look!
See, it's white around their eyes, thus the name white-eye.
They're in the Passer family.
There's a bird called black-eye, too?
And they're an endangered species?
Say, I gave you a white-eye figurine the other day, didn't I?
My friend, present!
You gave it away as a present?
A white-eye's feather and a white-eye figurine...
Both involve the white-eye...
Do these coinciding facts have anything
to do with Shigeko-san's kidnapping?
Santa-san, which friend did you give
the white-eye figurine to as a present?
There, there, and over there!
You gave them everywhere?
Santa-san, where is it?
The place where your friend is waiting for your present.
Here!
Owwch!
At this rate I'm gonna get bunny ears.
Look!
No, they don't look like culprits.
I said don't pull my ears!
Wow!
Ow, ow, ow!
So you'd like me to go straight, huh!?
How cute!
Santa-san, which way are we going?
What's wrong?
Santa-san, please wake up.
We're not quite finished here, Santa-san.
I know you're tired, but please try to stay awake.
I'm the one who wants to cry.
Uncle Candy!
Uncle Candy?
You mean the man who gave you this?
I see.
This is...
Today at 5:00 PM, shop?
4:30.
I don't have much time.
Santa-san, you all right?
About your neighbor Yamanaka-san, does he own a pet shop?
Yes, I've heard that he was selling birds and goldfish a while ago.
Could you please tell me the location and the name of the shop?
Pwease!
Was it Beika City's 3rd District?
But his shop already went bankrupt.
He's going to his bankrupted shop at 5:00 today?
Could it be that Santa's mom is there?
Enjoying this, aren't you?
Well, beats crying at me.
So that's why.
I actually prevented the kid from chasing that Uncle Candy.
No wonder this little one was upset.
Hey, mister.
What is it, you guys?
We're trying to find someone.
The mother of this Santa... is here, isn't she?
I don't think so.
Except for me, no one else is here.
I'm sorry but I'm very busy.
Can you just leave?
Say, about that bird in the cage, isn't it a black-eye?
Black-eye?
No, it's a white-eye.
Is that so?
It's written right here.
The black-eye species is protected by our country.
It gets its name from the black patch around its eyes.
The yellow feathers from its neck to its chest are its characteristics.
Its favorite food is papaya.
Wrong, wrong!
If that bird is actually a black-eye, the endangered species...
It could sell for a fortune.
I said go home!
Mister, you were in this kid's home, no?
This feather had fallen in the room.
My guess is it got stuck on your clothes and transfered there.
I don't recall.
Mister, I think you'll get a lighter punishment
if you turn yourself in to the police.
The police?
Why do I have to go to the police?
I don't have time for kids.
If you don't leave, you'll regret it.
Listen to me for a little bit more.
I think you misunderstood.
About what?
This figurine was near the door, right?
The one who put it there... was this Santa.
Santa!
This kid?
Mister, you gave Santa a piece of candy before, right?
This was a gift for you.
A gift?
The reason for the name "Santa-san" is...
Because this kid loves Santa Claus.
That's why this kid wants to give others presents too.
Santa Claus...?
Presents...?
The one who placed it there... was this kid?
As a present...
I see...
That's how it was.
Mister, this Santa kid loves you very much.
I think you are highly trusted.
You can't let Santa cry, now can you?
Santa-san, I'm sorry.
Mama!
My shop hasn't been doing well, and my debt grew larger and larger.
That's why I didn't want others to find out,
and fled to the mountains in Ogasawara.
I found a black-eye there.
A bird that was said to be extinct from that island!
So Kurata, the man I borrowed money from...
Said he'd sell it for me to a collegue of his who loves animals.
But, soon afterward...
Someone placed a black-eye figurine at my door.
And then I saw that woman's suggestive smile.
As if she knew everything.
That woman must've noticed the black-eye!
I thought the figurine and her smile were a silent threat.
I was only taking my child back...
But, you hired that media-buzzing detective.
I didn't want my deal to be broken off, so I thought
that, if you had any evidence against me...
I'd take it away, so I searched your home.
This Santa-san...
Smiling so cutely while looking into the capsule machines...
I couldn't help but to hand out a candy.
And yet I misunderstood the figurine gift, and the child's gratitude...
Little boy, I vow to become a man who's suitable
for getting presents from Santa-san.
Please take care of that black-eye.
Unckie.
Here.
A black-eye figurine?
Mister, look closely. That bird's a white-eye.
White-eye?
No, the color around its eyes is black, it's a black-eye.
Incorrect.
It's just that the white paint fell off, exposing the black plastic inside.
It's true!
The paint merely fell off.
I saw this with impure eyes, that's why I failed to notice it.
Santa-san, I'll cherish it.
Cherish!
I've heard your entire stupid conversation.
You're going to the police? Then I'll take this black-eye.
You can't!
I'm returning this bird back to its island!
Shut up!
Stop it!
Back off, brat!
I'm calling the police!
Call them... if you can!
Hang up the phone!
Understood, so please release my child!
Until I'm somewhere safe, this brat
is going to keep me company.
Santa!
Kurata!
Did it malfunction because of the struggle?
Kurata, let go!
Don't move —
don't you move a bit!
Now.
Take this!
Well, the police said they would
consider Yamanaka's circumstances.
I see.
You're very considerate, Santa-chan!
What's going on, Santa-chan?
Wearing a ribbon like that.
It's a gift from Ran-san.
That fits you perfectly, Haruka-chan.
Ha-Haruka!?
Could it be that Santa-chan is a girl?
Yes.
But... I can't believe you figured that out.
It was when she first hugged me.
I heard that baby girls hug with their whole bodies.
Conan, so you knew that too?
No, I didn't.
Actually, I noticed that while we were in the bathroom.
You didn't notice even when you were with her all this time?
Is that so, is that so?
Is this funny?
All right, come and have fun some other time!
And bring your mom too!
"Bring your mom"!
I knew you'd say that.
Foot spa, waterfall spa, and iron tub.
A case in the hot springs park.
Let's blow away the steam enshrouding the truth!
Next Conan's Hint
Towel
Look Forward to the Next Episode