I'm tired...
Hot Springs Park?
Looks like fun to me!
Let's give it a try!
Flowers dance to the piano's rhythm.
Two people face-to-face is a mystery!
Find out the alibi trick based on
the outdoor spa's blind spot!
Perceiving to the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
There's no use in stalling!
Umezu Hideaki (70)
Mortgage Company President
Why won't you just hurry up and sign this contract!?
Maekawa Koichi (50)
Hot Spring Park Manager
I told you many times that I have no desire to sell this place!
What an incapable successor.
You seriously think you can gather customers by selling octopuses here?
It's because of a certain gargoyle perching over my
place that the customers are being driven away!
Welcome.
Be prepared to be disappointed by these lousy hot springs.
What was that!?
What?
Now, now...
It's all right, just ignore him.
Ehara Mari (35)
Umezu Hideaki's First Daughter
This happens all the time, so don't mind him.
That's right. Dad only comes here to pick fights.
Umeze Yasuko (28)
Umezu Hideaki's Second Daughter
Enough of that!
You're all grown up, yet all you can do is mooch off of me.
I'll have you know that you're to be quiet and respect my decisions!
Oww!
Yagihashi Shousuke (27)
Umezu Hideaki's Secretary
The reason our president comes to this place is for business.
You got that right.
Let's head inside.
You say we'll be disappointed?
Yet you go in anyway...
Two adults and one child.
I sincerely apologize for embarrassing you with our fight earlier.
Who was that man with such a big attitude?
He's the president from a mortgage company.
Over the past month, he's been frequenting out private outdoor spa.
Business harassment.
I'm going to prepare some freshly caught octopuses...
So please come to our restaurant after your baths.
Looks tasty!
All right! Spa first and octopus later!
Looks like we're starting to run low on octopuses...
So I'll go to the coast and catch some.
Take care of the place.
Huh? But low tide is at 8:02 today.
One hour earlier won't make a difference.
Amazing!
Such a variety of baths!
I can't decide!
Let's check out the iron tub first!
Such a nice bath...
Ran-neechan, the heat's starting to get to me.
Already?
Hey, is it all right for you to get in the spa even when you're injured?
No, that's why I'll only take a light dip in the jacuzzi.
I can't wring a towel while I'm like this, after all.
Conan-kun!
This spa is fabulous!
My body's floating on the water!
I'm heading out now!
Weird child.
Huh?
Wasn't she...
Delicious!
Drinking beer again...
Aren't you going to be driving later?
No need to worry!
I've decided that we'll stay at a nearby hotel tonight!
That was actually your plan all along, wasn't it?
The octoputh'th thucktion cup'th getting on me...
The arm will still move even after it's cut off.
Isn't it fresh?
I used a harpoon to capture these during low tide.
But other times, I use octopus pots or longlines to trap them.
How do you figure out where to place the pots and longlines?
I float a buoy to mark the spot.
Do other people around here fish for octopuses too?
Just me, since I'm specially trained as a fisherman.
But I only do when I feel like it...
And my dad suddenly died a year ago, so I've
become this place's manager on short notice.
What was that sound?
It was probably from the private outdoor spa.
Go check out the private outdoor spa.
Sure.
President...
Dad!
No way...
It's no use, he's already stopped breathing.
Please call the police and an ambulance!
Ah, right!
The deceased is mortgage company president, Umezu Hideaki-san...
He frequented this private outdoor spa every night, correct?
That's right.
You found him bleeding from his head and sitting in the spa...
It was at exactly 8:00.
A loud tumbling and splashing sound came from this outdoor spa.
A rock on the cliff was close to tumbling off...
And I was about to schedule a maintenance appointment.
Safety management is a grave responsibility, you know!?
I'm truly sorry.
So this was an accident.
The rock fell from that cliff and hit Umezu-san's head.
Hey, retrieve that rock immediately.
Yes, sir!
Ah, let me help too.
We don't require your help.
...I see.
This rock is covered in quite a bit of moss.
Bloodstains and hair are attached on it.
Looks like the rock broke off and fell from here.
Hey, there are friction marks on the nearby rocks around that hole.
What?
This is...
Don't tell me someone tried to force the rock out...
And caused the scratch marks by wiggling the rock around!
In other words, the rock didn't naturally
fall off the cliff and hit Umezu-san...
Rather, someone stood on top of the cliff
and threw the rock directly at Umezu-san!
This is not an accident, but a murder!
But, we did hear sounds resembling a rock rolling down the cliff.
Since the rock was heavy, they rolled it over the edge.
I see!
At this height, it was impossible for
anyone to enter from the outside.
In that case, the only passage to get here is from that glass door.
A crime committed by someone from this
hot springs park at 8:00, so it seems.
All right, everyone gather in the lobby!
Ah, I'll bring some tea here.
Watch out!
Hey, you! Where were you looking?
I'm terribly sorry.
My apologies.
I can't believe you.
Maekawa-san, there's no need for tea, so please come here!
All right.
What do you want to talk to us about?
Umezu-san was apparently murdered by someone!
During the estimated time of death around 8:00 PM, the relevant
parties in the spas of this hot springs park were you three people!
I would like to ask what you were doing
and your whereabouts during that time.
Nonsense!
Don't tell me that you're suspecting us?
First, I'll question the person who met with Umezu-san
last - his secretary Yagihashi-san, if you please!
Around 7:00, I was helping the president get changed in the locker room.
After I sent the president off, I received a call from work.
By the time I went in the spa, Mouri-san had
already been in there for five minutes.
Where were you at around 8:00?
I was taking a shower.
After that I heard the commotion...
It's only a short distance from the showers to the crime scene.
No way!
And the eldest daughter, Mari-san?
I entered the spa some time after the detective's daughter did.
And once there, I was in the jacuzzi the whole time.
Here, you can smell the jasmine from my hair, can't you?
Jasmine?
In order to enhance the healing effects of
our jacuzzi, we supplement it with herbs.
Ran-san, is that correct?
Yes.
I went in the spa earlier than both Mari-san and Yasuko-san.
The jacuzzi is right next to the private outdoor spa, too.
Looks like Mari-san had an opportunity to commit the crime as well.
Stop blurting out nonsense!
And the younger daughter, Yasuko-san?
I was talking to a friend on the phone...
So I got in the spa about five minutes later than my sister did.
I was at the reclining spa in the far back.
But sometime before 8:00...
I saw Yasuko-san headed for the mist sauna.
Yagihashi-san was there too.
Oh my, what were you two doing in the mist?
We... happened to bump into each other at the sauna, that's all.
And, Officer, you forgot about the most suspicious party.
Our president was about to buyout this hot springs park.
Couldn't the manager, Maekawa, have held a grudge over this?
The female staff member was confirmed to be
at the front desk by the security camera...
But Maekawa-san, you were not present at all times!
Well, since we were running low on octopuses,
I went out to catch some at sea around 7:00.
From 7:30 to 8:00 I was in the restaurant,
and Mouri-san can attest to that.
Is that true?
Yeah, Maekawa-san was with me in the restaurant the whole time.
I see.
To recap, of the four people relating to Umezu-san, all of
you except Maekawa-san were in the hot springs park...
And had the opportunity to murder him.
The elder daughter, Mari-san, was at the jacuzzi.
The younger daughter, Yasuko-san, was at the reclining spa.
And the secretary, Yagihashi-san, was in the showers.
Those two have motives, as well.
Father was fiercely opposed to the two of them getting married.
If you're trying to incriminate us, you'd also be one to benefit from this!
How dare you!
After all, your business did poorly and you're in debt now.
In order to pay them off, you would want to sink
your claws into dad's assets, wouldn't you?
Don't just go saying whatever you please!
Regardless, is it true that you merely "happened"
to bump into Yasuko-san at the sauna?
That is...
I called him there.
Miss!
I figured since dad opposed our marriage,
we could run away or something...
We had planned to do just that after the buyout of this park was done.
You're just spitting a bunch of rubbish out of your mouth.
Officer, don't be fooled by this man's words!
Because of his attempt to marry Yasuko,
father angrily told him to learn his place!
That's why he held a grudge...
You ungrateful goon!
This is...
I see.
Mouri-san, did you figure out who did it?
Yeah, I got it.
I bet that the culprit didn't want to leave their fingerprints behind...
So they used a towel to wrap around the
rock before throwing it at Umezu-san!
In that case, the towel should have moss on it that came off of the rock.
You can see green smudges here, can't you?
Could it be that this towel...
I don't know anything about that.
Why was something like that inside my bag?
Mari-san, it won't do you any good to
try and talk your way out of this.
We'll find out for ourselves after having this towel examined.
Now, everyone.
I'll explain everything in detail.
Please, come to the private outdoor spa!
As expected of Mouri-san.
Not good, at this rate...
Ran-neechan, what's up?
I was just wondering why I was able to stay
on top of the water in that float spa.
That's easy.
Like the Dead Sea, it contains a high
concentration of salt which makes you float.
Float...?
Don't tell me...
Wait, Conan-kun...
Found it.
This is it.
Now I've figured out the trick that the culprit used.
Geez, Conan-kun...
You're always running off at the drop of a hat.
Ah, sorry.
Actually, Uncle Kogorou asked me to do something...
Got it.
All right, let's get things started!
The reason I named Mari-san as the culprit was...
Just for laughs.
Mouri-san!
Now is not the time for laughs...
Well, quiet down and listen.
Mari-san, your right hand is injured, isn't it?
Yeah...
With a wound like that, it would be difficult to tightly wring a towel.
Wring a towel...
But that towel was tightly wrung!
That's right.
In other words, that towel did not belong to Mari-san.
However, the towel did come out of her bag.
The culprit put it there.
In order to place the blame on Mari-san.
What was that?
However, that ended up exposing them.
They didn't think deep enough about Mari-san's wound.
So, how did the culprit do it?
Mari-san's been carrying her bag all along,
so the only chance to put it there...
I'm terribly sorry.
Maekawa-san, it was you.
But Mouri-san...
At the time of the crime, Maekawa-san has an alibi of being with you.
Umezu-san's fingernails were ragged and dirty.
It's plausible that Umezu-san didn't die after being hit by the rock...
But from having his head forced under the water and being drowned!
The reason why Umezu-san's fingernails were ragged and dirty was...
Because he was struggling and scratching at the bottom of the spa.
Verify this with forensics.
Yes, sir!
However, we rushed here soon after we
heard the noise made by the rock.
It's impossible to drown a person in such a short time.
Then, when was Umezu-san drowned?
Look at the disposable shampoo and soap.
None of them were used.
The seats weren't used either.
You're right! They weren't used at all.
In other words, Umezu-san was killed as soon as he entered the spa!
Around 7:00?
Meanwhile, Yagihashi-san, Yasuko-san, and
Mari-san were still in the locker room.
The only person capable of committing the crime...
Was Maekawa-san!
At that time, you went to catch octopuses despite
the fact that it was an hour too early for low tide.
You actually didn't go to catch octopuses, did you?
You quickly hid yourself near the private spa...
And without him suspecting anything,
you brained Umezu-san with the rock.
Then, you forced his head under the water and drowned him.
What are you talking about?
You heard the noise at 8:00 as well, didn't you?
If the time of the crime was 7:00,
then who rolled the rock at 8:00?
After all, Maekawa-san was in the restaurant at that time.
He used a trick.
Conan, do what I just taught you.
Right!
Huh?
Inspector Yokomizo, carry that rock and climb up this cliff.
Sure...
This rock sure is heavy.
You can see a small harbor down there, right?
Ran-neechan!
Here!
This rope was tied to the buoy near the harbor
— it's a type of rope called a longline.
Longline?
Grab the longline and pull it straight.
Next, tilt the rock you just brought up forward at the edge of the cliff...
Then use the wooden rod to support the rock.
With this, we're all set.
Ran-neechan!
All right!
What's this?
The sea entered low tide at 8:00 and had the lowest water level.
As such, the buoy floating in the sea went down as well.
The buoy pulled the line down, which removed
the rod and caused the rock to fall.
In other words, he used low tide as his time difference trick.
Low tide...
The would-be evidences of the rope and the rod then
flew off the ledge, headed straight to the sea.
It's true.
You're able to see that part of the ledge has been chipped away, right?
Yes.
Those friction marks were made by the hooks attached to the longline.
That was pretty telltale.
I see, using this method...
He could cause the rock to roll down at 8:00,
even if he were in a different place.
It's an interesting deduction, but that's
all circumstantial evidence, isn't it?
Do you have any concrete evidence?
Maekawa-san, why have you kept your pants rolled up all this time?
Why don't you roll them down?
What was that?
You can't, right?
When you brained Umezu-san with the rock,
his blood splattered on your pants.
You only noticed that...
After you saw forensics roll up his pants to retrieve the rock from the spa.
You then unconsciously glanced at your pants...
And hurriedly rolled them up.
The police had already started their investigation, so
you couldn't change them without raising suspicion.
We now have the decisive evidence.
As I thought, you held a grudge against our president
because he tried to buyout your hot springs park!
It wasn't just that.
A year ago, my father was driven to despair by his debts to Umezu-san...
So he got drunk, and ended up drowning in the spa.
I followed my father's will and used his life
insurance to reconstruct this hot springs park...
Tried to make it big, too.
But after all, I'm a man of the sea.
I can't support myself on the land.
In the end, I couldn't fight against Umezu-san's buyout...
I figured if he were going to rob me of this place, then
I'd just bury him with the entire hot springs park.
So, I carried out my plan.
His snoring is so loud I can't sleep!
Now I can't sleep at all!
Next Conan's Hint
Monster Movie
Look Forward to the Next Episode