Well done!
This case was solved surprisingly quickly.
Yeah, it's all thanks to Takagi-kun's stubborn stakeout.
Please, use "determined" to describe me.
Here.
Hot!
A reward!
Ah, thanks...
How warm...
Here.
Shiratori-kun, thanks for your hard work too.
Hm? You don't like canned coffee?
That's... not it.
Here.
Thank you.
So, how about the three of us go out and eat later?
Good idea!
Sorry...
I think I'll pass.
Huh? Why?
Tomorrow's my day off.
I have many plans to attend to.
I see...
Ah, speaking of which, I've found a delicious ramen place!
Oh? Well done, Sergeant!
Their potstickers are the best!
Flowers dance to the piano's rhythm.
Two people face-to-face is a mystery!
Fusing with the cherry blossoms, what could
Inspector Shiratori's memories of first love be?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
White Cliff
Well, by plans, I mean...
To just watch a movie by myself.
Huh? Inspector Shiratori?
What a coincidence to meet you here!
I'm quite surprised...
Inspector Shiratori likes it too!
Like what?
Gomera, of course?
Gomera?
No, the one I'm going to watch is "White Cliff"...
But the ticket coming out is...
Did I mess up my selection when I bought the ticket online?
Before we head inside, let's go to the kiosk and buy snacks!
Yeah!
Let's go, let's go!
Oh well, today's a rare day off.
"Might as well get in the same mood as the kids," huh?
It's written all over your face.
I guess it's the usual Detective Satou
love triangle that gave you a shock.
Maybe you're better off giving it up?
Since, in the hospital room, Detective
Satou and Detective Takagi already...
I won't give up so easily.
Because she changed my life, and she's my girl of destiny.
Girl of destiny?
Yes.
It was back when I was in elementary school...
It happened once when I was selecting a textbook in a bookstore.
Hold it right there!
I saw you guys!
You two secretly stuffed manga in your jackets!
Who the hell are you, brat?
Hey...
Huh?
Just ignore her.
Let's go.
Right.
I said stop!
Thieves!
Shut up!
Damn brat.
I witnessed it too.
The crime scene of you shoplifting.
What are you talking about?!
Criminal Law, Article #235.
A person who steals the property of
another commits the crime of theft...
And shall be punished by imprisonment for up to ten years.
Imprisonment?
Hey...
Gentlemen, is something wrong?
Ah, no, we were just arguing with this kid over these books.
Because this comic book is quite popular.
Young master...
Is something wrong?
Ah...
Not really.
Nothing at all.
Are you looking for someone?
No...
If you needed a textbook, you could
have just asked me to buy it for you.
I can't.
One needs to personally choose, and train
oneself to pick up distinguished books.
This is important for my practicing law in future.
I agree with that.
Here you go.
My way of saying thanks for your help.
I bought this cola from that fast food restaurant, and
made the flowers out of straw wrappers in a hurry.
It's probably not that pretty...
Sakura petals?
Yeah, it's the symbol of courage!
But I didn't think that's what this flower meant.
But you know, the sakura is the symbol of police officers in Japan!
Determined, kind, and dignified.
It's a flower of justice!
I see...
So that's why you joined the police force.
Yeah.
That's why, when I met her again in First Division...
I thought for sure that it was destiny.
Until that Takagi-kun appeared.
But are you sure that girl was actually Detective Satou?
Well, that face of hers was a perfect match.
But Detective Satou is tougher than most
men—would she do something that girlish?
I have considered that before.
Hey, it's almost time to go in!
If you guys want drinks then get them quickly.
We already bought the popcorn.
Thank you for waiting.
Here.
Thanks.
Well, make sure to confirm it with Detective Satou.
Maybe you'll be able to get your big turnabout.
May I help the next customer?
What would you like?
Let's see...
Well...
Cola, please.
Thank you for waiting.
A big turnabout?
Say, can you give me your straw wrappers?
Huh? Sure, but...
What for?
Se-cr-et!
Found them!
These are our seats.
Awesome!
They're facing the center of the screen!
We've gotta thank the Professor for buying these tickets online!
I heard that every seat is gonna be full by the time the movie starts!
If only the Professor could have joined us...
Something came up, so he couldn't help it.
Here, huh.
My seat is directly in front of the children.
I'm sorry!
I was only paying attention to finding my seat...
Was that cola?
Yeah...
Then, I'll get you a new one right away!
I guess my memory is demolished just like that...
I'm terribly sorry about before.
Here.
Are these... flowers?
Yeah, it's been a habit of mine since I was a child.
Kasakura Nami (27)
Whenever I have some straw wrappers, I make those.
It's part of my apology, but...
If you don't like it, feel free to remove it.
Ah, no...
It's the lady from before.
We're over here!
I forgot my wallet on the ticket machine
earlier, and those kids let me know.
Is that so?
But I never thought my seat would be next to yours...
Yeah...
It feels like destiny or something like that.
Destiny?
I guess I kind of overdid that.
Ah, no, I was just a little surprised.
Look, those two...
Seem to be getting along!
This popcorn and I get along!
A sign of a new relationship...
Think so?
Gomera
Final
Big Monster
Battle
Gomera...
Please, Gomera.
Help us with the last bit your strength!
Last this, last that—this movie series really drags on.
Yeah, the last movie was "Farewell, Gomera"...
And the one before that was "Gomera Forever."
Well, if the kids are enjoying them, I guess that's all right, huh?
Cellphone...?
Ah, my god!
Gomera's guts...
Not too shabby on those CG effects, huh...
Hey, Haibara, it's just CG...
That "Gomera Final" was awesome!
Yeah, very emotional!
Are you all right?
Yeah.
I didn't sleep much last night is all.
He can't help it.
Police officers have lots of work to do, and don't get much sleep!
You're a police officer?
Yeah, but today's my day off.
Is something wrong?
Well...
There is something I wished to consult with the police.
Do you mind hearing me out?
Stalker trouble...
Yes, I started to get this feeling several days ago.
Did you not discuss this with any friends or family?
Well, I did talk to my boyfriend...
And asked him to stay in my apartment for a few days.
Boyfriend, huh...
Now that's too bad.
Hey, move over a bit!
There's no way!
Genta-kun, you take up too much space.
The car's too small!
Kids, if you get too loud, I'll have to kick you out.
I see.
Someone's been following you, going through your garbage...
And silent calls?
Well, there's a chance that it's all my imagination...
I'm home!
Right now, a police officer is with me...
At the theater...
So, Shiratori-kun...
You and this Kasakura-san happened to
sit next to each other at the theater?
Yes.
Then, after she found out that I was a police officer,
she consulted with me over a stalker problem.
So I came to her apartment, and...
We discovered that murdered man's body in the room.
The victim's name is Somei Yoshirou-san, 30 years old.
He was working as a bondsman at a nearby bond agency.
And Kasakura-san, he was dating you, is that correct?
Yes.
I also told him about the stalker issue, and had
him stay at my place two or three days ago.
According to the medical examiner, the time
of death was around 2:00 PM today.
It appears that he was bludgeoned to death.
The murder weapon should be something hard and cylindrical.
When you arrived home, how was the lock on the door?
It was locked, but the duplicate key he had
around his waist was gone, so perhaps...
The culprit may have used the duplicate
key to lock the door and leave.
In order to delay the discovery time of the body.
In that case, the suspicious party would be that stalker.
We still don't know how he got into the room.
But, if that stalker has extreme affections towards you...
It wouldn't be strange that he'd want to kill your
boyfriend, who was staying at your place.
No way...
Or...
Making it to look that way, you killed him.
Wait a second, Inspector Megure.
At about 2:00 PM, she was sitting next to me, watching the movie.
She didn't have the chance to do it.
However, it doesn't even take five minutes
to go from here to the theater by car.
If she pretended to go to the restroom and left the theater,
she could have done it by making a round trip in a taxi.
Well, if you can testify that she was sitting next to
you the entire time, there will be no problem.
Actually, I can't...
I fell asleep halfway through the movie...
Inspector Megure.
It looks like the victim was talking with someone on the
phone at about 2:00 PM, the time of the murder.
What?
Ah, that could've been me.
The call came while I was watching the movie, so I hurried and ended it.
I forgot to turn off my phone before the movie started.
About that, do you remember?
No, I think I was fast asleep at that time...
About that, Ayumi saw it.
What do you mean?
During the movie, something suddenly lit up.
We could also see that lady's hat.
I guess the backlight came out when she opened
the phone while turning the power off.
If that call was really from the boyfriend,
then it's a sound alibi for her, isn't it?
That's correct, but...
Why are you guys here anyway?
Because this lady said she would treat us to lunch.
Lunch?
On the movie ticket machine, we saw a wallet left by that lady...
We found it and told her, so she wanted to thank us.
But what was really scary was some time after that cellphone lit up!
Yeah, that was scary!
What happened?
Ah, perhaps that was...
The scene where Gomera's internal organs could be seen.
That image was pretty realistic and grotesque.
By Gomera, you mean the monster?
Yes.
You were watching that kind of movie?
I love special effects... is that bad?
Ah, that scene was also shocking, but...
What really scared me was...
What happened after that scene.
Ah, you mean the scene where Gomera chomped his enemy's head!
There was a lot of blood scattering around.
Shiratori-kun, you also like that kind of movie?
Well, uhm...
And?
The time you watched the movie was
between 1:00 PM and 3:00 PM, correct?
Yeah, to be exact...
It started at 1:05 PM...
This was...
On the cola cup that Kasakura-san bought for Inspector Shiratori.
It started at 1:05 PM and ended at 2:50 PM,
totaling one hour and 45 minutes.
Well, to be safe, I'd like to ask Takagi-kun
to head to the theater to confirm it.
Whether she actually left during the movie or not.
There's something else that's been on my mind as well.
Then, Takagi-kun, if you would.
Yes, sir.
Now, while he's away, we would like to search your room.
Is that all right?
Yeah...
If there really is a stalker harassing you, there may be
listening devices or tiny cameras hidden somewhere here.
I guess you're right...
Please go ahead.
Conan-kun...
You don't have to search for us.
Go to the corner of the room and wait quietly, all right?
Ah, sorry.
Shiratori-kun, did you find anything?
No, nothing.
Have you seen anything out of the ordinary in this room before?
No, nothing strange...
Hey, Ayumi.
What have you been doing all this time?
Making flowers!
Flowers?
Yeah.
First, carefully tear along the dotted line on the straw wrapper.
Flatten it out to make it a long strip of paper.
Then, fold it into small squares.
Like this.
Then you take the whole folded paper, and tear out pieces like this...
Like this?
Look, amazing!
A flower band is ready to go!
Awesome!
Very pretty!
Is this really how to act at the scene of a murder, guys?
Well?
What do you think?
Is the culprit really that Kasakura-san?
You glared at her with that look of yours, no?
Yeah...
Claiming to be a fan of special effects movies, I find it strange that
she doesn't have any monster figurines or books of that sort.
It isn't only about that, right?
Since you are doubting her alibi.
Not to mention that we're the witnesses.
The seats in the theater.
Seats?
Didn't you find it weird?
By seats, you mean...
That the five of us were sitting in the middle-front row seats...
And Inspector Shiratori and the woman were
seated directly in front of us across the aisle.
What's so weird about that?
The showing we watched was on a Sunday afternoon.
At such a time, it's packed with kids and their parents.
But, somehow, the two seats adjacent to
hers and Inspector Shiratori's were empty.
Couldn't it be a coincidence?
Also, it bothers me that she only met us by chance
today, yet we became her alibi witnesses.
But didn't you see it too?
She was in the theater at the time of the crime.
True, I saw it.
Her hat, that is.
Wait, does that mean...
Well, I guess it's fine.
I believe that Inspector Shiratori also noticed it...
And had Detective Takagi go to the theater.
All the while hiding the evidence in his chest.
Next Conan's Hint
Hat
Look Forward to the Next Episode
Next time, Inspector Shiratori and that person are getting really close!
What a surprise!
Sure is!