We happened to bump into Inspector Shiratori at the theater.
We then heard from the inspector about his fateful encounter
with a young girl that resembled Detective Satou in the past.
At the theater we also met a woman named Kasakura Nami-san.
Kasakura Nami (27)
And, like the girl from the past...
She decorated the cola cup with a flower
band made out of a straw wrapper.
Perhaps the girl from his past is actually Nami-san?
After hearing that Nami-san was being troubled by a stalker...
We accompanied Inspector Shiratori to visit her apartment.
To our dismay, we found the murdered body of
Nami-san's boyfriend, Somei Yoshirou-san.
Was it a crime by the stalker?
Or, in an effort to make it appear that
way, did Nami-san do it herself?
However, the ones who could confirm her alibi were
none other than Inspector Shiratori and us.
If she were the culprit, what kind of trick did she use?
Flowers dance to the piano's rhythm.
Two people face-to-face is a mystery!
In the cherry blossom season with
many meeting and partings...
Love is coming Inspector Shiratori's way!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
We confirmed Kasakura-san's alibi...
And we couldn't uncover any hidden bugs or spy cameras.
We still didn't find any traces of the stalker in the apartment, either.
This is Takagi.
Oh, did you find anything?
Well, about that...
It looks like many people left their seats
to use the restrooms during the movie.
So nobody remembers who left or returned.
Since today is a Sunday, it's very crowded and it can't be helped.
I see.
Ah, Takagi-kun.
Hey!
There's a trash can on that floor, right?
Yes.
They're about replace the trash bag with a new one.
Then, can you tell them you're a
police officer and retrieve the bag?
There should be a cup with a flower band
made from a straw wrapper inside.
A flower band made from a straw wrapper?
There is!
Can you take it to forensics?
To be safe, also take the other cups from that bag.
I'd like them to test the fingerprints on
the cup and the contents in it.
Yes, sir.
And...
And?
No...
That's all.
Let me know when the results are in.
I apologize for using your phone without asking.
Ah, well...
Hey...
Why didn't you ask about the straw wrapper?
It could have become your critical evidence.
What are you saying...
Don't tell me it's because she's beautiful, and
you're finally about to know her better.
You're not going to say something this silly, are you?
Isn't that right?
Inspector Shiratori.
Seriously...
This is how it should be.
You want me to buy a drink at the kiosk?
But I'm not thirsty at all.
Don't ask why, just go ahead and buy it.
Do what I say for now.
Hey...
I understand now...
The real reason behind Inspector Shiratori's hesitation.
I've finished measuring it like you asked.
Well, what's the length?
Has it become a little bit shorter?
No, it's exactly the same.
I see...
Exactly the same...
Looks like he got his results.
Yeah.
The sad, final results.
But you know, the sakura is the symbol of police officers!
Determined, kind, and dignified.
It's a flower of justice!
According to Kasakura-san's testimony...
This afternoon, while she was watching the movie...
That stalker entered this apartment...
And killed Somei Yoshirou-san, who was waiting for her return.
It's safe to conclude that they fled the scene after that.
We won't be able to draw new conclusions
without questioning others in the area.
What should we do about the children?
Ah.
I've already asked their teacher from their
elementary school to pick them up.
Since Agasa-san and Mouri-kun are both out.
Do you have anything else you want to confirm with the kids?
Ah, no...
Inspector Shiratori.
Well then, Kasakura-san, would you mind
going to the station to give your testimony?
Well... may I have some time to myself?
I just lost him... and I'm still quite shocked.
I see.
Well, after you've calmed yourself I'll have my men escort you...
No, we need her to come immediately.
Not as a witness...
But as a suspect of this murder case.
The one who murdered Somei Yoshirou-san in this apartment...
Kasakura Nami-san, it was you, no?
Hey now, what are you saying?
Judging from the victim's time of death...
The crime was committed at about 2:00 PM today.
At that time, didn't you say that Kasakura-san was
sitting next to you watching the movie in the theater?
Not to mention that the victim called Kasakura-san's
cellphone immediately before his death.
The call she received was also witnessed by
these kids sitting behind you, wasn't it?
Yeah, we saw it.
In the dark, the seat in front of us suddenly lit up!
We could see that lady wearing her hat.
That light was because the phone was getting a call.
Right?
Conan-kun and Ai-chan, you both saw it, right?
Yeah...
We saw it.
The lady's wool hat.
Right.
We didn't actually see her.
What we saw was someone wearing her hat, being lit up
by the cellphone backlight, and glowing in the dark.
It was the silhouette of Inspector
Shiratori, whose seat was next to hers.
Isn't that right, Inspector Shiratori?
Yeah...
But even if the phone did light up...
No one would be able to see it if it wasn't near your face, right?
It was placed on the cola cup.
If you opened a cellphone, and placed it on a cup...
When the phone receives a call, it will light
up as if it was being held in your hand.
Of course, she had to turn off the sound and vibration beforehand.
But even if that were the case, wouldn't
the people around you notice?
It's true that people would notice if they were sitting right next to me.
But behind us was an aisle, and the two seats next to ours were empty.
It's likely that Kasakura-san had already purchased
the two adjacent seats over the internet.
If you distance yourself with an empty seat, people aren't
likely to pay attention to your activities in the dark.
So, you happened to buy the ticket for the seat
right between the ones she purchased?
Yes.
Even if I didn't buy it, someone else would fill in because
it was a popular movie on a Sunday afternoon.
She could also check which seats were still
available from the movie ticket website.
After confirming that the five seats behind hers were filled in...
Kasakura-san stayed near the ticket dispenser to check
and confirm that the kids bought those seats.
She left her wallet in front of the kids to ensure they
would notice it, so they would become acquainted.
After the movie, she would bring the kids to her
apartment and make them her alibi witnesses.
No way...
And, since she also learned of my being a police officer...
She thought it would be even better to bring me as well.
Hold it, what are you saying?
However, if you didn't happen to fall asleep...
This murder plan you insinuated wouldn't have...
It wasn't a coincidence.
It's likely that inside my cola cup...
There were sleeping pills that she slipped inside.
Sleeping pills?
In other words, when she saw me looking at
my ticket stub while trying to find my seat...
She confirmed that I was the neighbor whom
she would drug to sleep and place her hat on.
She then bumped into me on purpose and knocked down my cola...
Then bought me a new one, slipped the
pills in the cola, and handed it to me.
Of course, whether the sleeping pills will work in
such a short time depends on the target's body.
If she rehearsed her plan several times beforehand...
She was bound to find an effective target such as myself.
Well, all we have to do is check her ticket purchase record.
We'll find out whether she was the one who bought three
nearby seats for showings on crowded weekends.
If it weren't for that, she wouldn't have been able to know
the plot of the movie that she didn't watch today.
Today is the first time I watched that movie!
The tickets I bought before were for my friends!
I tried to invite them, but they happened to decline is all...
That's right!
Why don't you check whether I slipped you pills or not?
Your cola cup was clearly marked, after all.
You're talking about this flower, aren't you?
This is from the straw wrapper flower band you put around my cup.
Actually, I took off one of the flowers and
placed it in my notebook as a souvenir.
Therefore, if we investigate the cup I threw
away in the cinema's trash can...
I brought it here.
Then, repeat what you found about the length of the flower band.
Yes, sir.
The flower band on the cup and the empty straw
wrapper both have the same lengths.
The same?
That's odd... since Shiratori-kun said he took a
segment, the length should be a little shorter.
That is...
When you secretly left the theater,
you took the cup with sleeping pills...
Then returned with a new cup and a new flower band on it, right?
She was preparing for the police investigations?
Yes.
In other words, the plan of her crime was...
To first acquaint herself with the viewers who would
eventually become her alibi witnesses...
And then slip sleeping pills into the drink of her neighbor.
During the movie, she confirmed that her neighbor
had fallen asleep and placed her hat on them.
She then switched the drugged cup with her
own and placed her cellphone on top of it.
Taking the drugged cup with her, she secretly left the theater.
She then returned to her apartment via taxi, and
brained Somei-san who was waiting for her inside.
Immediately after that, she used his cellphone to call
her own phone that had remained in the theater.
After the viewers behind her witnessed it, she would have a solid alibi.
After that, she threw away the drugged cup and the murder weapon.
She returned to the theater in a taxi,
retrieved her hat from her neighbor...
And, finally, replaced the cup and cellphone on
top of it with a new cup and a new flower band.
The reason why she wrapped a new flower band was...
Because I removed a piece off from the
middle instead of from the two ends.
You mistakenly thought that you broke the old
strip when you tried to wrap it back on the cup.
You thought that, if you left it broken, your cup
switch trick might be discovered by the police.
That's why you replaced it with a new band.
What's so important about this flower band thing?
If you are accusing me, why don't you bring the taxi
driver here whom you claim drove me around?
I think the taxi driver will be located in no time.
After all, it was a fact that you were in a taxi during the movie.
Because, Miss, you didn't know there
was an earthquake during the movie!
Earthquake?
There was, right?
Yeah, that was a big one!
Right after the scene with Gomera's guts.
I was so scared that I grabbed Conan-kun's hand!
Well, if you were sitting in a cab, of course you
wouldn't be able to feel the earthquake.
I only forgot to mention it!
I just lost my boyfriend and was pretty shaken up.
What... What's going on here?
All of you suddenly attacking me.
You were trying to clear me a while ago, weren't you?!
A while ago, Inspector Megure asked me about your alibi.
No, I think I was fast asleep at that time...
While I was scratching my hair, I found it.
A string from your hat.
Therefore, it's highly possible that it's still stuck to your hat.
Inside your hat...
Traces of my hair.
Fine...
Take it.
Allow me.
If you want to search, knock yourselves out.
You'll find it anyway.
The hair from that arrogant cop with curly hair!
So, you are confessing your crime?
Yeah, it was I who killed him!
That son of a bitch, a dirty liar!
Liar?
We started going out seven years ago.
I was about 20 then.
That guy always said that he was short on money...
I can't even recall how much I had given him.
When I finally told him that I didn't have any more money...
He said he wanted to pawn my accessories.
So I handed it over, but it was my mother's memento,
so I went to the pawn shop to buy it back.
But the pawn shop said they never received it.
It felt very suspicious, so I followed him... and that's when I saw it.
Another woman was wearing my mother's ring.
Later, I found out she had been going out with
that man since two years before I met him...
And they were even engaged!
Why didn't you report this to the police?
This is a fraud case!
Even if I did report it, he would've only been arrested.
My seven years wouldn't come back!
That's why I ended it!
That man's life!
As punishment for wasting seven years of my beautiful youth!
Anyway, I've never thought highly of you nasty police officers.
So I felt I had to do it myself.
Here, let's go.
What a pity.
You weren't like this in the past.
Oh, so you used to know me?
Yeah...
Though you may have already forgotten.
Then, let me tell you something...
Believing women will never change is just men's ego at work!
They do change!
Given the circumstances, they can change from angels to demons!
A woman's heart is like the autumn weather!
That lady's so mean...
That was too much.
What's an "ego"?
It's the part of your mind that thinks selfish things.
Are you all right?
Ah, Inspector Shiratori has gone through a lot...
Hey, how about we call Detective Satou over?
I know her phone number.
No, anything but that.
I'll be fine, just leave me alone.
Here!
A reward for catching the culprit.
I made it out of straw wrappers a while ago!
This is...
Sakura...
Because the sakura is the symbol of police officers!
Determined, kind, and dignified.
It's a flower of justice!
Who taught you that?
Kobayashi-sensei did.
She taught me how to make those a long time ago.
Uhm...
And Kobayashi-sensei is!?
I heard students from my class were staying with you...
It's Kobayashi-sensei!
Then, if you would please take these children with you.
Yes, I'll take them home in a taxi.
No.
If you would allow, please accompany me in my car.
Sure...
I apologize for letting these kids cause trouble
and having to make you drive them back...
No, it's an easy task.
What a surprisingly happy ending.
Yeah...
Blooming cherry blossoms, huh?
Next Conan's Hint
Nail Art
Look Forward to the Next Episode