That lady...
She's been sitting in that seat since we got here.
Takahata Kyouko (35)
What a beauty!
She sure has.
It's been two hours already.
Hello?
Speaking...
What did you say?
Are you all right?
Pardon me...
Did something happen?
Please, confide in me if you would like.
My name is Mouri Kogoro.
You're that great detective?
Yes!
Actually, I just got a call from the police.
Someone has died at my home.
What was that?
Flowers dance to the piano's rhythm.
Two people face-to-face is a mystery!
Today's case is pretty troublesome.
What's this crime that cannot be proven?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
The deceased was Soejima Itsurou-san, 27 years old.
He was the husband of Shiori-san, whose sister,
Takahata Kyouko, is the owner of this house.
These are... a fallen chandelier and a shotgun.
Looks like the gun accidentally went off.
Is something wrong?
No, it's nothing.
And to our surprise...
Sorry I'm late.
What were you doing, Chiba!?
I apologize.
Soejima!?
This can't be!
The victim was actually Detective Chiba's friend back in college.
What happened here?
His shotgun suddenly discharged, causing the
chandelier to fall and crash on his head.
What's the estimated time of death?
Approximately an hour ago.
In other words...
He entered her house by himself while she was out...
Consumed alcohol to the point of getting drunk...
Grabbed the shotgun from the cabinet...
Loaded up his gun...
And played with it until it went off.
No way...
So Itsurou-san really...
I was worried...
That something like this would happen.
What do you mean?
I don't want to say this...
But the business which Itsurou-san started turned
out to be a blunder, and he was deep in debt.
And he caused my little sister Shiori to suffer.
However, he continued drinking and
caused more trouble for those around him.
When my sister died of illness half a year
ago, his drinking problem worsened.
He even went to the fitness club and
shooting range I showed him, drunk.
Please stop it!
Lemme go! I said let go! Let go!
In the end, the club expelled him, and his gun license was revoked.
And, it looks like he wanted to get his hands on my guns...
So that's why he snuck into your house when
you were out, and ended up like this.
No way...
It's true that he was a drunkard... and he even consulted me about it.
But, he said he was going to quit... drinking alcohol.
He wanted to quit, but he just couldn't.
No way.
I had heard about the incident at the shooting range.
Then he vowed to me, and said he wouldn't touch a gun ever again.
He was blinded by alcohol and simply forgot about his vow.
That can't be it!
If he saw these delicious dishes lying around
here, I bet he'd start to crave a drink.
It's true that these dishes all go well with alcohol...
Hey, a brat like you shouldn't talk like you know about this!
He apparently raided my fridge for dishes...
Looks like I'm responsible for this too.
No, that's not what we meant.
Ran!
Conan-kun, we're interfering with them.
But where are the keys?
Keys?
Yeah.
Since she was out, how did this man get in?
I don't see any traces of the windows or doors being forced open.
He carried a spare key, perhaps?
That must be it!
But I don't see any spare key.
And not only that.
I don't see this man's wallet or cellphone.
Hey!
Stop messing around!
The spare key is outside the entrance.
I had let him know where I hide it.
What about for your cabinet with shotgun and shells?
I'm pretty sure I locked the doors...
How's it look?
Yes, well, it's rusted and the locks are not working so well.
If it's like this, anyone can easily open the doors.
In any case, an insecure cabinet such as that doesn't meet
the requisites for the metropolitan firearm storage law.
Be prepared for a revocation of your license and any applicable fines.
I'm sorry...
Well, I guess it can't be helped.
But thinking backwards, this may be what she had hoped for.
Instead of being held responsible for a person's death.
As for this case, we'll deem it an accident and let the precinct handle it.
Please wait!
I still can't believe this.
But look...
Let's investigate this a little further!
Chiba, calm yourself down.
It's an accident no matter how you look at it.
But!
Knock it off already!
Go outside and cool down!
It's understandable to react like that when your friend dies, but...
Say, what were you doing at the cafe terrace?
For over two hours...
Were you waiting for something?
I wasn't waiting for anything.
Really?
Knock it off now!
You go cool yourself down too!
What's this?
Hmm?
That... is from Soejima's cellphone strap.
Really?
Yeah, it's the same strap Shiori-chan had before her death.
But there weren't any cellphones at the scene...
Say, can you tell me something?
Soejima's personality?
When it came to sports, I was only good at judo, but...
That guy was good at all of them.
But, at the same time, he couldn't really handle pressure.
He'd been relieving his stress from work by drinking.
Perhaps the trouble he caused wasn't just
at the shooting range and the pool?
Maybe we should go check out those incidents, don't you think?
I see!
With some luck, maybe we can uncover some new facts!
All right!
During our investigation, we uncovered
more of his troublesome incidents.
Driving under the influence...
If it weren't for the guard rail, his car
would have gone over the edge.
He would've been dead.
That was a month ago.
And, two months ago...
He was drunk and collapsed on the street in the cold winter weather.
He would've frozen to death if he had been found any later.
Adding up these similar accidents and incidents...
We get nine of them in the span of half a year.
After Shiori-chan's death, Soejima became very depressed.
It's true that, for a while his consumption increased, but...
But he would always say "I'm going to quit for real this time."
Then, just as he was getting better, he would relapse once again.
This happened over and over again for half a year.
Maybe Mouri-san's right.
He wanted to quit, but he just couldn't.
Still, he was a fortunate guy.
Even though he was just her sister's husband...
All the fines and compensation for the accidents he caused...
As well as the condolence money and the role of a guarantor...
They were all taken care of by Kyouko-san.
Also...
The one who introduced him to the shooting range
and fitness club where he caused that trouble...
As well as the owner of the house with shotguns kept in an
insecure cabinet, a house he could access using a spare key...
Say...
Do you know what "indirect intent" means?
Indirect intent?
INDIRECT INTENT
Indirect intent refers to...
A person foreseeing that an action will
likely result in a harmful outcome...
But disregards whether it's ensured or not...
And follows through with the action regardless.
Of course I know that...
But...
Conan-kun, I'm surprised that you know something like that.
I heard about it from Uncle Kogoro a while ago.
To foresee that a drunkard like Soejima-san
might get himself killed under the influence...
Yet still allow him to drive a car...
Inviting him to a shooting range and the swimming pool...
And leaving the house and allowed him to come, drink, and carry a gun.
He may die, or he may not die.
The possibility wasn't 100% but it wasn't zero, either.
If the culprit bet on that...
Don't tell me...
Conan-kun.
I've borrowed the keys.
But I think...
We ought to tell Mouri-san and the Inspector first...
It's all right, just hurry up.
Conan-kun!
This room...
It's dark.
Where's the switch?
Wait!
I see...
It was the cellphone recharging indicator light.
Recharging?
Say, whose cellphone is this?
That is...
Shiori-chan's cellphone.
That Soejima...
He didn't want Shiori-chan's cellphone data to vanish...
So he constantly recharged it.
Hold on...
This room should've been vacant for at least half a day...
Don't tell me...
Someone entered this room recently and used the cellphone?
What did you say?
Who would do that.
Looks like someone really was here.
It looks like they searched the room.
Could it be a cat burglar?
If that's the case, they wouldn't have re-locked the door, right?
That's true, but...
Not long ago, I received a report from my transceiver...
Saying that a cat burglar frequenting this
neighborhood was arrested at Beika Station.
Wait, don't tell me...
What's this?
There's something that looks like glitter.
Huh, what?
This is...
So that's how it was.
What's this about, Mouri-san?
Are you suspecting me of something?
Ah, no...
It's not like that.
Hey, Chiba!
What's this about?
Calling us here all of a sudden.
Explain yourself.
That is to say...
The culprit of this incident is...
Takahata Kyouko-san.
You committed the crime.
What did you say!?
Further explanations...
Will be offered by Mouri-san, according to Conan-kun.
Huh!?
Something like that...
I never—
All right, let me explain.
Disregard what I said earlier.
I do suspect you.
I think it was you who killed Soejima-san.
I killed Itsurou-san?
This had been planned for over half a year...
No, as long as the plan succeeds,
it doesn't matter how long it would take.
It was a long-range murder plan.
A complete murder based on indirect intent.
Knowing that Soejima-san was an alcoholic...
You created numerous situations where
he might get himself accidentally killed.
Then, all you had to do is wait.
Right.
Like sitting in a cafe terrace, drinking tea.
That's interesting.
Sounds like the plot for a movie or novel.
But do you have evidence?
Evidence, you ask?
It's about time for the first piece of
evidence, no... witness, to arrive.
Witness?
Chiba!
I forced Beika Station to cooperate and brought him here.
Thank you.
Eh? I heard nothing about this!
Ah, sorry...
Mouri-san told me to assist Chiba with this.
This man is Nishitani Naoya.
Nishinani Naoya (37)
Recurring Cat Burglar
A recurring cat burglar who the Beika police arrested yesterday.
Cat burglar?
Yes.
He snuck into this house yesterday...
And witnessed the incident taking place.
What was that?
Now, tell us again about the testimony you gave.
Like I said...
When I was rummaging around on the second floor...
Someone came in.
That man.
It's Itsurou.
Sis?
What's she up to, calling me all the way here...
I can't...
I can't drink!
This can't be...
Soon, he drank himself into a stupor...
And he took the gun out of the cabinet.
Just as I thought it was bad...
Every bit of it was being set up.
Having her license revoked due to improper
storage isn't even at our level of concern.
This was actually a crime of murder!
Please hold it!
About that, it's merely that man's story!
Who do you trust, me or that burglar?
About where Soejima-san's cellphone went...
Aren't you intrigued by it?
Back then...
You were trying to find something.
That something was Soejima-san's cellphone.
You wanted to delete it.
What's she up to... calling me all the way here.
What you used to call Soejima-san here...
The data of your text message!
Last night, you went into Soejima-san's room
and tried to find the cellphone, right?
What're you saying?
That's some impressive nail art.
But, is every piece of them there?
The rhinestones.
Chiba.
Yes, sir.
This was dropped near Shiori-chan's cellphone.
It was the same, no?
As your nail decoration.
And the cellphone?
Well, about that...
After pulling out the money from the wallet,
he threw the whole pouch into the river.
The data was damaged, impossible to recover.
No way...
What a shame —
you couldn't get your evidence.
But regardless, there wasn't such a message in the first place.
What I was trying to find was not the message you sent.
Shiori-san's cellphone, which you touched...
Even after her death, he still recharged the phone and cherished it.
That Soejima-san...
To him, that was a symbol that Shiori-san was still alive.
Stop talking nonsense!
That man caused Shiori indescribable pain!
He deserved to die for all I care!
Now we finally know...
About your true feelings.
So what?
Are you arresting me?
I'm a private detective.
I can neither arrest nor sentence you.
A private detective's job merely is to find the truth.
This time I did find something...
Your sister's feelings.
Shiori's feelings?
That's a message.
Just go ahead and pick it up.
Excuse me.
No way...
It's probably a message from heaven.
Why don't you read on?
I'm sorry, Itsurou...
I know we should hang onto each other...
But I allowed illness to defeat me.
When I get well, promise me that you'll stand
on your own feet and apologize to my sister.
Don't worry, I know she'll understand.
Because she's the nicest in the world... my only big sister
Shiori...
Could this be...
Before she died...
Shiori-san sent this message to Soejima-san.
All I did was send you the saved message
stored inside Shiori-san's cellphone.
Conan!
Here!
I'm sorry if I surprised you.
Since this was Shiori-san's cellphone,
you didn't think to check, right?
Yesterday.
However...
In the end, Shiori-san died of illness.
Without knowing Shiori-san's true feelings...
You began your plan to murder Soejima-san.
It's a lie!
Shiori couldn't be...
She was supposed to hate that guy!
Soejima truly wanted to stand on his own feet.
If you hadn't let anger control you, you could've seen it as well!
His feelings...
And Shiori-chan's wish.
What's going to happen is up to you.
After you've learned of Shiori-san's feelings, will
you still turn a blind eye to what you did...
And lie to her constantly for the remainder of your life?
Or...
Shiori...
Takahata Kyouko admitted to everything.
However, about what the law will decide regarding
her crime of "indirect intent"...
Won't be revealed in the near future.
Wait, what are you doing, Dad?
You see...
I've come to realize that splurging on alcohol is unhealthy.
So, by putting beer in front of me, I'm
training myself to resist the temptation...
I can't do it!
Resisting too much will only stress your body!
Learn your lesson sometime, Uncle.
Next Conan's Hint
Magatama
Look Forward to the Next Episode