Hey!
Come out already!
I said it's enough!
I'm about to go home!
Geez...
Where'd you go...
Awesome!
Flowers dance to the piano's rhythm.
Two people face-to-face is a mystery!
The Detective Boys are a little different this time.
A treasure battle at the haunted warehouse!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Now, let's review our recent achievements as the Detective Boys!
First, there was that "red, white, and yellow" case!
That was the case where Sugiura Kaito-kun's apartment was set on fire!
He told us!
There was a guy who was doing suspicious things at night.
Shall I be Kuroshiro-kun...
And make plain what's black and white right here?
I'll tell you which one among them is...
The yellow arsonist!
In Kaito-kun's diary, he wrote something about a red and a white guy.
And the yellow guy was the culprit, right?
Conan-kun was the black-and-white guy!
Conan-kun solved the mystery of the red, white,
and yellow guy, and sniffed out the culprit!
Conan's achievements are our Detective Boys' achievements!
Of course!
Conan-kun is one of the Detective Boys after all.
After that was the Ikkaku Rock case!
The female victim left us the message of "mackerel,
carp, sea bream, and flounder."
That rock behind you...
Something's written on it.
Mackerel, carp, sea bream, flounder?
Conan-kun!
He solved the message and caught the culprit!
Conan-kun is...
Our Detective Boys' glory!
That's right!
After that, the TV station case where my dad was involved!
I'm going to check it out!
Conan-kun!
Don't move, you guys!
Hey!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
'Nuff with playin' innocent already!
Whatcha just said, I've heard everything clearly with mah ears!
I'll tell ya what!
Why don't I reach my fingernails deep into ya throat...
And dig that washi paper up together with ya lunch!?
Don't...
I surrender.
During that case, my dad was pretty heroic too!
But, we didn't get to do anything in that case.
Conan-kun left us alone.
It's all right!
It was my dad and the Detective Boys' achievement!
If you put it that way.
And don't forget about that Kinosaki Hot Spring case!
That's right!
In order to find the missing Ran-san...
We Detective Boys teamed up with the famous high
school Detective from the West, Hattori Heiji-san!
And Conan-kun, even though he was using a crutch...
Managed to hop on a skateboard and chased down the culprit!
Crab buns, crab-cream, and crab sticks...
Those were delicious!
And that bank robbery case!
Don't forget the case when we went to watch Gomera!
We have achieved so much!
It's all thanks to Conan-kun!
You mean the Detective Boys!
I've reported to Kobayashi-sensei that
we've finished our cleaning chores.
Good, now let's go home!
Huh, a robbery case?
Could that be what today's news was talking about?
Yes.
Please make sure to lock your doors and windows properly.
This robber targeted the nearby jewelry stores and antique shops...
And has committed five crimes already this month.
But, this is an elementary school, and there's nothing here to steal...
No no no!
You can't let your guard down.
If anything happens, call me immediately.
I'll come running over!
Yes!
Inspector Shiratori's here again.
He was also here yesterday, right?
Yeah, he's working hard!
Well, to be safe, may I have your number?
Yeah, because the police are always protecting citizens!
Huh? Do I have to...
No, Inspector Shiratori is in the 1st division of the police department.
They mainly deal with homicide cases.
Robbery and theft are dealt with by the 3rd division.
Well, in cases like when Kaitou Kid sends
his manifestos and stirs everyone up...
Those types of grand theft cases are given to the 2nd division.
Then, why is he here?
Even if he's not in charge?
No, that's...
It can't be helped, right?
For Inspector Shiratori, Kobayashi-sensei is...
Here you go.
My way of saying thanks for your help.
Sakura petals?
But you know, the sakura is the symbol of police officers in Japan!
Determined, kind, and dignified.
It's a flower of justice!
His person of destiny.
PERSON OF DESTINY!?
Hey, he said he would say it himself once the moment
is right and told us to keep quiet, remember?
Huh, is that so?
It's irritating though.
To fail to express his own feelings straightforwardly, leaving
his girl in the dark —
a typical love drama moron.
Hey, you aren't talking about me are you?
Well, I think they make a good couple.
You ignored me...
Uh... to chance the subject, do you believe in destiny?
Kobayashi-sensei is an Edogawa Ranpo fan and loves mysteries.
And Inspector Shiratori might be able to feed her some case stories.
Why do you ask...?
I believe in it...
Speaking of cases, Mitsuhiko mentioned something earlier, right?
Yeah.
That's right, something about... a hearty warehouse?
No, it's not "hearty."
It's a "haunted warehouse."
A haunted warehouse?
Takuma-kun from our class said...
While he was playing hide-and-seek with his friend
at a relative's house in Beika City's 5th District...
He couldn't find his friend...
And he had looked everywhere except the warehouse...
So he climbed a tree and peeked in through a window.
The inside of the warehouse was filled with expensive treasures.
And behind the treasures, a shadow was looking back at him.
Wasn't that...
His friend who was playing hide-and-seek?
Takuma-kun thought that too, so he tried to go inside...
But the door was locked and wouldn't open.
He called out his friend's name but got no answer...
So he asked someone in the house to open the door.
Then, the house owner said that the warehouse
hadn't been opened in years...
So there was no way anyone could get in.
So, did he give up the search?
No.
Takuma-kun insisted that someone was
inside, and had the door opened.
Once inside, he saw that the person and
the treasures were no longer there...
Then, the owner told a puzzled Takuma-kun
a rumor about the warehouse.
"Do not place valuables in this warehouse."
"If you do, they will soon vanish..."
"...Swallowed by the hungry, haunted warehouse," he said!
D-Don't tell me his friend was eaten by the warehouse!?
No, I heard that his friend soon popped up from somewhere else.
But it seems like Takuma-kun's been having
nightmares after learning that rumor.
He didn't come to school today, either.
I see...
A warehouse with a large appetite.
Something bizarre like this could come from Edogawa Ranpo's world!
Kobayashi-sensei...
Where's Inspector Shiratori?
He left a while ago, whistling happily.
Anyway, about that warehouse problem...
We, as the Detective Boys, need to hurry
and solve the mystery behind it...
And make Takuma-kun feel better...
Huh?
Let's hurry up!
W-Wait!
I'm the manager of you Detective Boys, so don't leave your teacher out!
Geez...
If Kobayashi-sensei tags along, things will be more troublesome!
She'll nag us about not going in there,
or that it's time to go home.
A burden to us!
In that case, since the warehouse in question is in the 5th District...
...We'll meet at the Mouri Detective Agency
that's also in the 5th District, huh?
Well, you guys wait for me in the office.
I'll leave a note for Ran-neechan saying I'll be home a little late.
How exciting, visiting a haunted warehouse!
But, what if the warehouse really is a monster?
It's fine!
Conan-kun will definitely say that there's no monster and find the truth!
Yep, you're right.
I agree.
Come on...
You guys really rely on Edogawa-kun every single time.
Even if it's just once, don't you wish to make him speechless?
Something like that's impossible...
Because Conan-kun is too smart...
And he knows so many weird facts...
I'm talking about your attitude!
Without any ambition you'll never grow up.
Um, where're you going?
Restroom.
I've been growing up, though.
Today, Mom said that I grew taller.
However...
I'd really like to see it.
Conan-kun's speechless face!
I'm speechless...
Like that!
Yeah, even if it's just once...
I'd like to see his expression of admitting his loss to us!
No, we were just...
Joking around...
Not serious at all...
My bad, my bad, to let you wait.
What's wrong, gathering around the desk.
Huh?
Oh, no...
If you're looking for Uncle Kogorou
he's gone and headed to the racetrack.
Huh? Where's Haibara?
You called?
Well, let's hurry to the warehouse!
Rush there swiftly and solve the case quickly!
There's no mystery that we Detective Boys cannot solve!
You guys seem ambitious all of a sudden...
Oh, we look like that?
Well, you could say that today...
We certainly aren't the same as usual!
Whatever, just don't get too excited and overdo things.
Roger!
Let's go, let's go.
Oh, you're Takuma-kun's friends?
So you're here to check out that warehouse?
Yes.
We're the Detective Boys after all!
Well, there's nothing wrong with curiosity...
But don't delve too deep and let yourselves get eaten by the warehouse!
Hear that?
Don't worry.
All ghost stories are caused by illusions created by fear in the mind.
Something like an unsolvable mystery...
Does not exist in this world!
Though it looks quite old, it's still a pretty ordinary warehouse.
It's said to have been built during the Bakumatsu era.
What're you doing?
We're taking photos.
Because we're solving this case starting now.
There's nothing wrong with documenting the surroundings!
T-That's true...
Here, it's open.
Well, there shouldn't be anything in here.
It's pretty big in here!
But it's so dark that you almost can't see anything.
You can barely see that near the ceiling...
A window with a bit of light slipping in.
Good, let's take lots of pictures of the inside as well!
Be careful, watch your step since it's dark...
Conan-kun!?
Ow ow ow...
Telling others to watch out while falling down yourself, pitiful.
It's not that, it's the stairs...
Footsteps from someone else being in here before...
And they're only in the center of the warehouse.
They aren't a child's footprints.
That's...
An abacus?
The footprints...
Lead to this abacus encased in the wall.
For an abacus, the number of beads is unusual.
Hey...
There's nothing in there, right?
I'm about to lock the door, so time to come out!
All right.
Hey, let's go you guys.
Fine...
Satisfied now, little detectives?
Yeah...
Well...
See you.
But, can we check this place again after it gets dark?
We will wait patiently until then!
Please!
Well, that'd be fine...
But I don't think you'd find anything.
Say, that's the window right?
The one Takuma-kun peeked through.
Yeah, since that's the only window here.
Well then, instead of waiting until it's dark...
Let's check it out now.
The treasures that Takuma-kun saw.
Conan-kun, are you all right?
Please don't fall down!
You're not going to find anything.
Didn't we see the inside before?
Just checking to be sure!
After I take a quick look, I'll come down.
Bring that old man back here!
Hurry!
There shouldn't be anything in here...
Well, see?
This is...
Impossible.
So, what did you see?
There really was something back then...
The floor was completely covered...
By a mountain of treasure!
But, there's nothing here it seems.
Yeah...
But, when I peeked through that window, they were here.
On the floor of this warehouse, artwork and
antiques were piled up like a mountain!
But I don't see anything.
That's why there should be something.
The mechanism that caused the treasure to disappear.
Maybe it's on the floor?
Or in the ceiling?
No, I don't think there's anything in the ceiling.
The evidence is this photo.
A photo of Conan-kun climbing the tree beside the
warehouse and looking in the window a while ago.
It's about two meters from the rooftop to the window, right?
And looking at the window from within the warehouse, it's the same.
It's about two meters away from the ceiling.
In other words, there's no room for any mechanism in the ceiling!
T-That's true...
In that case, the only place left is the floor.
Yeah, probably a mechanism that would open up the
floor and bring the real floor and the treasure up.
Wrong.
There isn't.
It's not possible.
Come and look at this.
Here, look.
A Detective Badge...
And pencil lines have been drawn around the badge...
I drew them!
As proof of putting my badge here.
Ayumi's badge is here!
See, mine hasn't been moved either, right?
Yeah, not to mention yours and Genta's are so far apart.
I see.
In other words, in such a huge area of this floor, no traces
of it being slid around or angled can be found.
Edogawa-kun's hypothesis that the real floor rose after the
floorboards opened up is thus completely off the mark.
You guys are quite good, aren't you?
Is that so?
Wait a minute!
What's wrong, Mitsuhiko?
This warehouse is indeed weird!
What's weird?
It's missing...
My badge that I put right here.
Did you really put it here?
Yeah, I let it lean against the wall, no doubt about it.
Maybe it rolled off to somewhere else?
No, I searched around, but couldn't find it anywhere.
In that case, the wall or the floor in that area moved...
And it fell into the crack of the mechanism...
Or...
It was picked up by someone lurking in this warehouse.
S-Someone!?
C-Could it be...
A demon!?
That's not possible.
Didn't you say that ghosts are caused by illusions created by fear?
That's true...
Well, at any rate, something was definitely inside this warehouse.
To make the treasure appear and disappear in a short time...
A magic-like mechanism!
Next Conan's Hint
Ceiling
Look Forward to the Next Episode