The Haunted Warehouse.
Rumored that things stored inside it will vanish on the
spot, we Detective Boys came to investigate the matter.
But why are Genta and the others so fired up all of a sudden?
After we looked inside the warehouse, we
found a number of scattered footprints.
As well as a large abacus encased in the wall.
But other than that, the warehouse was empty.
However, when I peeked in through the window...
I saw a mountain of treasures piling up on the floor.
That's impossible, seeing as how it was empty a moment earlier.
But, when we reopened the door...
The treasures that were supposed to be there were gone...
Returning to its empty state.
I thought that the ceiling or floor must have been
moved, making the treasures appear and disappear.
But the photos Mitsuhiko and the others took
and the markings they made on the floor...
Proved my hypothesis wrong.
However, it must be somewhere here.
Enabling the treasures to appear and
disappear—that magic-like mechanism.
Flowers dance to the piano's rhythm.
Two people face-to-face is a mystery!
The Detective Boys have become suspiciously clever.
They're going to solve the tricky warehouse mystery!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
First, what stands out the most is...
That strange shrine installed right above the entrance.
Setting that thing up above doors that
open inward is dangerous, right?
If someone were to open the door while
you were placing the offerings...
That's true.
And then, what catches more attention than the shrine is...
The abacus inlaid in the wall directly opposite it.
What's that for, I wonder?
Probably used to keep track of the number
of treasures in this warehouse?
In that case, it should be lying flat.
If it's like this, no matter how you move the beads up
for counting, they will keep falling to the bottom.
No...
Behind some beads are bars, and they
stick into the beads to hold them.
Genta, lend me your back.
It's likely that if we move one of the beads up...
Something made a sound.
Conan-kun, move another one!
Then, I'll move the bead below the one I just moved...
They fell.
Looks like the abacus acts like a switch of some sort,
and moving the wrong bead will reset the mechanism.
Judging by the dust collected on the beads...
There's no sign of movement on the top level
other than the column furthest to the right...
On the bottom level, excluding the third
and sixth columns from the right...
And the fourth column with no beads...
As well as the eighth column which is completely
full, all other beads have been moved.
Let's see, that's the third column from the right and...
What else?
The fourth, sixth, and eighth columns.
You're texting?
This is a memo.
So that we don't forget.
Then, I'll go take a look from that window again.
You guys wait in here.
Hey!
Still not finished investigating the warehouse?
There's a strange slit on the door.
And these stairs...
Hey!
Hurry up and go look!
Investigate in a timely manner, that's a standard!
Damn, is it Kobayashi-sensei?
The one who's helping that bunch...
Huh?
Me, phoning the children?
I don't have time for that, I'm in a staff meeting.
By the way, you're at that warehouse, right?
Tell me where it is!
I'll go there after th-
It wasn't her...
So the only one left is...
Yeah, there was a call.
From Ai-kun.
Hey, don't play dumb!
You called Mitsuhiko and the others, didn't you?
I did no such thing!
Ai-kun told me she'd be home late today...
So I'm making some beef stew that's gonna take a long while.
Beef stew?
Professor, surely you couldn't make that...
The onions are almost done!
Oh, is that so?
Hey, is Subaru-san there too?
Yeah, since Ai-kun isn't here, I asked him to help me cook.
His cooking skills are really something!
Subaru-san... didn't call or text while frying the onions, did he?
Of course he didn't!
If he doesn't pay attention, the onions'll burn!
Then, who is it?
Who's helping those guys?
That call—was it from Edogawa Conan-kun?
Yeah, seems like he was investigating some
haunted warehouse with the other children.
A haunted warehouse?
According to Ai-kun who called earlier...
She said that things placed inside would
vanish in no time — truly a bizarre place.
That sounds terribly interesting.
Conan-kun!
How is it?
How's the warehouse now compared to earlier?
Nothing seems to have changed...
Other than the treasure not being here.
The floor seems a little deeper than before.
A little deeper?
That's not possible, is it?
It's not like a warehouse can grow.
Could it be...
The warehouse ate the treasure Conan-kun saw, so it grew bigger?
That's impossible.
But...
Something fell!
Yeah, sounded like it was near the wall.
A Detective Badge!
This is Mitsuhiko-kun's!
Where did it fall from?
I knew it...
I knew something really is here!
A monster in the ceiling!
That thing took Mitsuhiko's badge, and dropped it just now!
No way!
A monster in the ceiling?
How stupid...
Could it be...
Hey, let's leave... this warehouse...
Yeah, I have a bad feeling...
But...
The phone!
Could it be...
I figured it out!!
Hey, it's about time to go—it's getting dark!
Say...
You said this warehouse was built during the Bakumatsu era, right?
Yeah.
Could it be, the one who built it was the
Master of Traps, Samizu Kichiemon?
Yeah, it was.
If so, I think it'd be best to make a call.
To the police department's third division.
What, so it was you guys that called us police here?
It's been a while since the festival doll case, Inspector Momose.
And?
Is it true that you may have found a criminal who was on the run?
Yeah, in fact...
It's a thief!
It's the culprit behind the recent nearby
jewelry and antique store robberies.
That guy's here, inside the warehouse!
There's a lot of treasure in there!
Inside this warehouse...
There's nobody here, let alone treasure, is there?
There's a mechanism.
A mechanism that can hide treasures.
Mechanism?
First of all, take a look at the entrance stairs.
There's four steps, right?
But look...
On the inside, there are five steps.
You're right.
Also, compared to the steps outside, the depth
of the steps inside are deeper, don't you think?
Now that you mention it...
I see.
That's why when you first entered this warehouse...
Be careful, watch your step since it's dark...
You fell.
I thought there were also four steps like the entrance stairs.
But, what does this mean?
Don't you get it?
Compared to the steps out front, there are
more of them and the steps go further down.
Meaning, the interior is significantly deeper than the ground outside.
It seems deeper, but there isn't any place
to hide people or treasure, is there?
It couldn't be that there's a hole in the floor...
What's that?
It's a badge we left as a marker when we first came in here.
At that time, the warehouse was empty, but...
We went outside after that, and when Conan-kun
peeked through the window, it was full of treasure!
But that window is about two meters from the ceiling.
The window I saw from outside just now was
also about two meters from the roof.
It doesn't look like there's anything in the ceiling...
And since your badges don't seem to have moved...
There's nothing in the floor either.
It's the warehouse's trick that makes you think that!
Trick?
Genta-kun, are you ready?
Yeah, opening it now!
What!?
A window above the window?
Hey, did you really open the window from the outside?
Yeah, I climbed the tree and opened it.
But, isn't it strange?
There was light coming through the lower window earlier...
Huh?
There's no light coming through now.
Perhaps there are cuts in the boards
underneath the window outside.
So the light can leak into the warehouse.
Aligning with the cuts, window panels were
mounted so that it looks like a real window.
The reason there's no light coming in now is that...
There's a mechanism so that when you open the window...
Something like a board will slide up and cover up the cuts.
However...
If you open the window while shining a light
on it like so, the trick would be revealed...
Yeah, if this warehouse had been built
recently, it would just be a cheap trick, but...
This was built during the Bakumatsu.
In an era when they didn't have flashlights that
could conveniently illuminate things from afar...
Wouldn't this be a great trick?
In addition, just above the entrance that's already
nearing the ceiling is something that acts as a mask.
A mask?
It's that shrine.
It was placed right above the entrance so as to
distract people from looking up at the ceiling.
If people compare the height of the roof
before entering with the ceiling afterwards...
They'd easily notice that the ceiling is
lower, and it would spoil the illusion.
So, the reason the floor is deeper than the ground is a trick
to prevent you from noticing that the ceiling is lower?
That's right.
In other words, it seems like there was nothing in the warehouse...
But in actuality there is extra space in the ceiling.
It sure looks that way...
But how do we climb up to the ceiling?
You don't climb!
We told you earlier, right?
Shortly after we entered, we left our
badges on the floor as markers.
When we came back again, Ayumi-chan and
Genta-kun's badges hadn't moved...
But my badge, which had been leaning
against the wall, had disappeared.
It disappeared?
A little bit later, it fell from above.
Most likely, the badge leaning against the wall got
stuck in the ceiling board directly above it...
After it dangled up there for a while, it naturally fell down.
The badge got stuck in the ceiling board...
Could it be...
Yeah, judging from the fact that when Conan-kun peeked
through that window the floor was covered in treasure...
The ceiling must've gone up and down, no doubt about it.
I see.
To activate a mechanism that was built in an era with no
remote controls, someone must've been here to do it.
But, if we can't see them, and there's no
evidence of anyone having left the warehouse...
Then that someone must still be hiding in the ceiling's trick space.
Yeah, and if they have to hide in the ceiling like this...
And if they're surrounded by treasure...
That person is likely to be that robber who
caused the public to be in an uproar.
So?
Do you agree, Conan-kun?
Yeah, that's correct.
Not bad, you guys!
Awesome!
So, do you also know how to move the ceiling?
Well, we probably have to move those abacus beads...
Move the beads... how?
Well, that...
If I dun' look at it myself, I wun' know.
I see, I see...
If you dun' look at it yourself, you wun' know, huh?
Oh, no...
Hey, Inspector, did you bring someone else with you?
Yeah...
Then, tell them to wait outside the warehouse.
Genta, move your neck away from the window!
Sure!
Ayumi-chan, Mitsuhiko, and Haibara, you go outside and
wait behind the Inspector's accompanying officers.
For the time being, I've called two officers over.
Then, all that's left is to lower the ceiling.
By moving the beads on this abacus.
But, which ones to move?
The first thing to notice is the centermost
column completely filled with beads.
If it's not letting you move even if you want to...
Shouldn't it mean it's a center divider, and you need
to form something on the left and right side?
Form something?
They could be hiragana or katakana...
Or kanji.
Kanji?
The character on the left side is easy to see, right?
If you move the bottommost beads on the first
seven columns from the left one space upward...
That's right.
Then for the third, fourth, and fifth columns from the left, move
each bead located third from the bottom up one space...
The empty spaces form the kanji "san"!
Now the right side.
The column in the middle has no beads.
Meaning this kanji will have a vertical stroke down the middle.
Keeping that in mind...
Let's move the following beads up one space.
The second bead from the bottom of the rightmost column...
The third bead from the bottom of the second column from the right...
The bottom bead of the fifth column from the right...
And the second bead from the bottom
of the seventh column from the right.
This...
The character on the right side...
Is "mizu"!
San and mizu...
It's Samizu Kichiemon!
Samizu Kichiemon
Samizu Kichiemon?
The famous Master of Traps from the Bakumatsu era!
But, nothing's moving!
We haven't completed the "mizu" character yet!
Try raising the bead on the rightmost column's top level.
That's the only bead on the top level that shows signs of movement.
Oh!
Now the "mizu" character is complete!
The ceiling!
It's getting closer!
What just happened?
Conan-kun!
Don't worry.
The angle of the ceiling creates adequate space.
So, shall we take a look?
At the mountain of treasure!
It's...
It's full of the items from the robbery reports!
I'd expect no less from Kichiemon...
Such an amazing contraption.
There are also some items I've never seen before.
They may have been put here when the warehouse was built.
I think those treasure belonged to the person who
hired Samizu Kichiemon to build this warehouse.
Furthermore, the one who's been using this warehouse's trick...
And secretly placing stolen goods here...
Is this robber, you see.
I see.
After the children left the warehouse, he
lowered the ceiling and tried to leave here...
But he saw you peeking through the window...
So he hurriedly engaged the mechanism
and brought the ceiling up again.
Goodness, what an amazing contraption.
Hey boy, be careful.
His pals might still be around.
They aren't!
There was only one set of footprints.
But, how do we get out of here?
With the ceiling lowered, half of the door is blocked, isn't it?
Look, where the floor and the door meet, there's a long slit, right?
So if we poke around the door...
Conan-kun!
You're the gardener I hired a while ago!
Is that how you learned about the secret of the warehouse!?
I'm sorry!
So?
How was it?
Our deduction!
Feel defeated?
That was well done.
That's directed at Hattori.
Sorry, sorry.
I had business at the detective agency, but...
Those kids were talking about how
they wanted to see you speechless...
So I lent them a bit of wisdom.
That won't do, Conan-kun.
You can't say your master's name so impolitely!
Master?
That's right!
Hattori-san is Conan-kun's master, isn't he?
What's this about?
I showed them this photo.
And said I'm your detective master!
Hey!
This is the one you took when you were fooling around before...
Hey, Kudo!
Something's on the ground.
Hattori, you...
But, we didn't get to see Conan-kun's defeated face...
That's right.
Too bad.
You can't ask someone else for help!
True, true!
If you want your wishes to be granted,
you have to work hard yourselves!
Hattori, you're one to talk.
Are you looking for someone?
Kunisue Teruaki, sophomore of the University of Teitan.
Wait, is that the talisman that you cherish so much?
Something happened?
A man with a bandage on his arm was attacked in a restroom.
Then it turns out the criminal is still inside?
If we are lucky, we can find out at once which of them is a criminal!
Next Conan's Hint
Cracker
Look Forward to the Next Episode