Rumored that items placed inside
will vanish immediately...
The haunted warehouse
mystery was solved.
We Detective Boys then discovered
the robber hiding in the attic.
As for the suspiciously clever deductions
made by Mitsuhiko and the others...
Those were actually supplied by Hattori Heiji,
who'd just visited the detective agency.
What the hell is Hattori even doing here?
Flowers dance to the piano's rhythm.
Two people face-to-face is a mystery!
With a secret inside that she doesn't want Heiji to know...
Kazuha's charm has disappeared?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Looking for someone?
You came all the way to Tokyo just to look for somebody?
That's right.
The one we're looking for is...
Kunisue Teruaki, a second-year at Teitan University.
It seems his primary residence was right next door to Kazuha.
Is that so?
Why are you looking for this person?
The truth is, he's a tennis player, but...
When Kunisue-san went back to Osaka during his last holiday...
A charm?
Yeah.
Can you make me one to help me
win the next tennis tournament?
Can't you just ask your mom to make you one?
Kunisue Teruaki (20)
Teitan University Second Student
I want Kazuha-chan's handmade charm.
They say your charms are very effective, right?
Besides, I don't want to lose this tournament!
Well?
Please?
I'm begging you.
And?
You didn't end up giving him a charm?
Ah, no...
He did get a charm, but...
It was the wrong one.
From this idiot!
What?
The wrong one?
Actually...
He was outside the Aikido dojo where Kazuha was, staring inside.
Just when I thought, "You pervert! I'll teach you a lesson!"—
Oh?
You came to Kazuha for a charm?
Yeah—she said she'd have one to give me today, but...
That's not possible right now.
Kazuha said her Aikido exams are
coming up, so she'll be practicing late.
All the same, Kazuha's mom asked
me to bring this water bottle to her.
It's because that idiot once overworked
herself and collapsed due to dehydration.
But that's a problem.
I'm about to leave on the bullet train, so I don't have much time...
In that case, I'll get it for you.
If she said she'd give it to you, it must be in her bag, right?
Dressing
Room
Found it, found it.
Here it is.
Wait, that charm...
Don't tell me it was your important charm?
That's right!
It's the same as the charm I made for Heiji
with the piece of handcuff inside!
And this idiot gave it away by mistake!
I couldn't help it!
You didn't tell me which charm you planned to give him!
You should know even if I didn't tell you!
Why would I attach the charm to my bag
if I had planned on giving it away?
Don't be so bitchy!
You made that charm too!
And it's not like it works or...
What the hell did you say!?
Nothing's happened to me because I always have it with me!
And that time you lent yours to Conan-kun, you
ended up getting really wounded from a gunshot!
Well, thanks to that charm, I ended up
surviving being stabbed with a knife.
And that time you fell in the sea!
Wasn't it the charm's blessing that saved you?
Couldn't it have also been the charm's fault
that I fell into the sea in the first place?
In any case, if something happens to
me because I don't have my charm...
Heiji—I'd never forgive you!
That's why I said I'd go find this guy and bring it back myself.
And why'd you have to come along, anyway?
Because... that's... it's...
Now, now.
We can all go and look for that guy together tomorrow.
But why do you need to look for him?
You know which university he goes to and where he lives, no?
That's because...
We haven't been able to reach him in the last few days.
He's been absent from his classes, and...
He hasn't been to his apartment in a while, either.
So you think he's missing?
I hope he isn't gotten into any trouble...
Well, you guys should check out his university tomorrow.
Teitan University
Tennis Club
Ah, Kunisue huh?
Well, I haven't seen him recently.
Do you happen to know of a reason for that?
He was injured, injured.
He got a bone fracture in his left wrist
while practicing for the tournament.
A bone fracture?
Was it because he was too hard on himself?
Just the opposite!
It's because he wasn't paying attention at all.
To think he was so concentrated before the break...
Then, is Kunisue-san in the hospital?
No, it wasn't that severe.
He said he'd be relying on his friend and is staying at his place.
Yeah, Kunisue is staying with me.
Although I told him to move out soon
since my room's getting too crowded.
By any chance, is Kunisue-san in your room right now?
No, after I told him to take a walk instead
of cooping himself up inside all day...
He went somewhere else and has been there all afternoon.
Where?
Not sure, but he really likes sports.
Maybe he went to watch some games?
He was very excited when he called earlier.
Called?
This is awesome!
Looks like my luck has changed!
I'll show you my evidence later!
And he asked me to come to this sports cafe in Shibuya.
If you're looking for him, why don't we go together?
Oh, really?
Please take us!
By the way...
Did Kunisue-san mention anything about a charm?
Yeah, he said he got a charm made
by some girl in his hometown...
And he's been keeping it in his wallet ever since.
Really?
Then, we should be able to get it back soon.
Well, wait here and I'll go get ready.
Yes.
That was too easy.
But it's kind of disappointing, finding it so fast.
You came because you wanted to be with Hattori-kun, right?
Wrong, wrong!
I'm wrong?
No...
That's part of it, but...
The real reason is...
Inside the charm is...
There's a picture inside!?
What about a picture?
This photo of Kunisue-san...
I think he looks good in it!
If I let Heiji go and retrieve the charm
alone, he'd check the contents, right?
To be sure that it was really mine.
He'd discover it then!
The hidden photo of Heiji that I keep inside the charm!
That's why I came along, to prevent that from happening.
If I checked the contents first, Heiji wouldn't have to do it.
Understood.
If Kunisue-san tries to return the charm to
Hattori-kun, I'll do my best to intervene!
Thanks!
But...
I might accidentally give it to Hattori-kun!
Just kidding!
Geez!
Really, Ran-chan, don't tell mean jokes like that!
What are they so exited about?
Promise me!
Absolutely!
Maybe they're just happy that the charm'll be returned soon?
On your life!
For real!
You won't show it to him!
I said I will.
Kazuha-chan you're so funny...
What's so good... about this charm?
Speaking of charms...
About Hattori-kun's charm, did Shinichi ever touch it?
Remember, in the Shiragami-sama case...
Didn't Hattori-kun say that he compared something
to prove that the culprit wasn't Shinichi?
He had Shinichi's fingerprints from the handcuff link in the charm
compared against those of the culprit who dressed like Shinichi.
But the one who touched the handcuff piece...
Was Conan-kun, right?
He must've lent it to Kudo-kun at some point, right?
Otherwise it'd be strange.
I guess so.
Let's see, I remember it being around here...
There it is.
It's that sports cafe.
What happened?
There are patrol cars here...
Make sure no one intrudes on the scene.
Detective Takagi!
Conan-kun!
And Hattori-kun too!
Did something happen?
An assault case.
A man with his arm in a sling was struck in the restroom.
A man in a sling?
Was it this guy?
Yeah, yeah—this was his face.
Why do—!?
This means we're related to the case.
Let us see the crime scene.
Kunisue-san was found on this toilet, right?
Yeah.
Apparently he was unconscious with blood flowing from his head.
But then, is Kunisue-san all right?
He was transported to the hospital,
unconscious and in critical condition.
No way...
Why Kunisue...
We don't know who attacked him or why, but...
It happened between 7:55 and 8:05 PM, a span of ten minutes.
That's really precise.
Today is this store's first anniversary.
All customers were given a party cracker for
a celebration to begin at precisely 8:00.
An employee began passing the crackers out 5 minutes before eight.
The victim also received one as he drank at the
counter, and then was told of the anniversary, but...
He left the cracker on the counter and went to the restroom.
Then, after the cracker noises had passed and he still
hadn't returned, the employee went to check on him...
And found Kunisue-san blundgeoned,
so he reported it to the police?
Yeah.
It seems the employee heard some strange sounds and moaning
coming from the restroom mixed in with the cracker noises.
Then, why didn't the employee immediately check the restroom?
He was busy collecting all the crackers after use...
Then, did any customers leave the store in those ten minutes?
I don't think so.
The register broke before 8:00, and the
customers were piling up in the line.
In that case, the culprit is still inside?
Yeah.
Of course, we'll be questioning them one by one...
That won't be necessary.
If we're lucky, we might find out who the culprit is in one shot!
How's that?
For starters...
Let's first tell the customers this:
This is Takagi from the police department.
You may be aware that an assault occurred in the
restroom of this establishment a little while ago.
Before the investigation, I have a simple question:
Please stand with your eyes closed, and listen carefully.
Tonight at 8:00, this establishment had a small celebration.
Please bring me proof that this celebration
occurred after I finish counting to three.
All right?
One...
Two...
Three!
Three people?
Seems like we narrowed it down, huh?
Now then, we'd like to have a talk with
the three of you who are still standing.
Please step forward.
A talk?
Why only the three of us?
Could you tell us why?
Kunisue-san went to the restroom at five minutes before 8:00.
After that, the employee heard strange noises
and moaning coming from the restroom.
When the employee went to check on him ten minutes later,
he found Kunisue-san with blood coming from his head.
Therefore the crime occurred at 8:00.
What does that have to do with us?
Didn't Detective Takagi say it earlier?
At exactly 8:00, this place had a small
celebration, and he asked everyone for proof.
Proof of everyone celebrating its first anniversary!
First anniversary?
Oh, they set off party crackers, right?
That employee passed them out.
That's why I tried to show my cracker,
but it wasn't on the counter.
How could it be there?
After they were set off, the employee
immediately collected them.
The customers who set one off knew they
had already been collected, right?
That's why they were trying to collect and show us the
ribbon tape and confetti that was left on the ground, right?
Yeah.
The three of you who are still standing didn't set
off your crackers at 8:00 like everyone else...
But for some reason you're here now,
meaning you're our prime suspects!
These three men are the suspects.
You can have the other customers go home
after you collect their names and addresses.
Go record the names and addresses
of the customers on the floor.
Yes, sir.
The three of you will wait at the table over there.
Say, have you found the weapon
used to attack Kunisue-san?
Yeah.
It was a mop we found in the restroom utility closet.
That's why we think this wasn't
premeditated, but an impulsive attack.
Say...
May I ask you something?
Did Kunisue-san have a charm with him?
I think it should have been in his wallet, but...
Oh, yeah, there was.
A charm was inside...
Really!?
That's Kazuha-chan's charm.
Could you return it to her?
Not quite...
It's currently considered evidence and
has to be thoroughly examined first.
If they examine it, the photo of Heiji inside will—!
Don't!
You can't examine it!
Hey, knock it off.
Kunisue-san was assaulted, and is currently
in the hospital in critical condition.
Your charm isn't important right now!
I guess not...
Speaking of the charm, it's strange...
About the wallet the charm was in...
It was in the back right pocket of the victim's pants, but...
The victim also had his cellphone and cigarettes in the
same pocket, and it was completely bulging out.
I wonder why he would put so many things in the same pocket...
Could it be because his left arm was in a sling?
Since Kunisue-san fractured his left wrist,
he'd only be able to use his right hand.
I see, that's why he'd only be able to
use the pockets on the right side.
But see...
His right jacket pocket was empty.
Say...
You're sure Kunisue-san went to watch a game this afternoon?
Yeah.
Last night he was browsing the internet
and said, "I've decided on this game."
In that case...
If we question those three, we might be able to find out soon.
If the crime wasn't premeditated, the culprit probably
didn't hold a grudge against Kunisue-san until today.
It's very possible that something happened
at the game Kunisue-san watched.
Furthermore...
After the game was over, Kunisue-san
called you all excited, didn't he?
Yeah.
He said, "This is awesome, looks like my luck
has changed. I'll show you my evidence later."
And then you agreed to meet him at this sports cafe?
Yeah, Kunisue said to meet him here at 8:00.
In other words...
Kunisue-san's assailant may have also
been at the same thrilling game.
All right, first of all, tell me your names
and why you left your seat around 8:00.
We'll start with...
You in the glasses.
Yes.
My name is Satsuma Kazuo.
Satsuma Kazuo (51)
I came to this place a little after eight, and didn't
know anything about the anniversary thing.
Is that so?
I'm not lying!
When I came in, the customers were clapping and getting
roused up, so I thought something might have happened.
Mister, you came to this shop because you like sports?
Yeah.
I like sumo wrestling, so I came to watch it.
Overhand throw!
Look, it's that match.
Kokuhou wins!
Well, it was a good match, but...
I'm a fan of Akashouryuu, who lost the
match, so I'm a little down about it.
And?
Did you hold a grudge against Kunisue-san who
was probably happy about the match's outcome?
No, it's not like that...
Does Kunisue-san like sumo wrestling?
Dunno...
He watched sumo broadcasts before, but...
The name's Harufuji Kengo.
Harufuji Kengo (44)
Someone called me just before eight.
I thought it'd be too noisy when they set off
their crackers, so I left the cafe for a bit.
About that call, who was it?
I dunno!
Some kinda solicitor with a damn long
speech, so I yelled at him and hung up.
And, when I returned, people were
freaking out about an assault.
The damn cash register was broken too, so I
returned to my seat, but then you police came.
Do you still have your call log?
Yeah, but the number was restricted.
By the way, did you go watch a game today?
Yeah, I did.
What was it?
It was beach volleyball!
Watching them tossing back and forth was exciting!
I was hoping for some boob slippin', though.
So Kunisue-san caught your perverted looks
towards the players and quarreled with you?
There wasn't a quarrel!
Does Kunisue-san watch beach volleyball?
Well, he seemed to like it.
Well then, it's your turn...
My name's Kyuuma Takuya.
Kyuuma Takuya (26)
The reason I wasn't here at 8:00 was
Because I ran out of cigarettes...
And the cafe's vending machine didn't carry my
favorite brand, so I went out to buy some.
And when you returned with your cigarettes, there
was an uproar and the police had arrived?
Yes.
And?
Did you go watch a game?
Yeah, I did.
The one at Touto Stadium with the Tokyo Spirits versus Big Osaka.
So you watched soccer?
Yeah, it was a thrilling game, right up to the final score of 1-2.
Well, because I'm a fan of Big Osaka, the visiting team...
Seeing them hugging each other on the soccer ground in
victory, I clapped discreetly to avoid enraging my neighbors.
It this soccer game was the one Kunisue-san was excited
about, it's likely he'd have been a Big Osaka fan as well.
If that's so, it's unlikely they would've
formed a grudge with one another.
Say, how did Kunisue-san feel about soccer?
He often watched it on TV, but...
He didn't have a favorite team in particular.
I see.
What's up?
Looks like you're on to something too.
Yeah.
An assault case occurred in this sports cafe.
During the cafe's anniversary celebration, someone
knocked Kunisue-san unconscious in the restroom.
The suspects are these three who were in the
shop and did not set off their crackers.
The answer pointing to the real culprit lies in their testimonies.
What was that all about?
Charm this, charm that...
It only works for me, so it's obvious that it didn't work.
You can't just keep us here without any proof!
If you really want to go home, be my guest.
Of course...
That only goes for the two who aren't the culprit.
Because the culprit said something odd
that even a kid like me would know.
Next Conan's Hint
Pocket
Look Forward to the Next Episode