The reason Hattori and Kazuha came to Tokyo...
Was because they wanted to retrieve Kazuha's
charm that Hattori mistakenly gave away.
The person it was given away to was Kunisue Teruaki-san...
Who had fractured his wrist while practicing
tennis and began staying at a friend's apartment.
That Kunisue-san was later assaulted and badly
injured by someone in a sports cafe restroom.
Kunisue Teruaki (20)
Teitan University Second Student
Accompanied by Detective Takagi, Hattori and I began
investigating, and narrowed down the suspects to three.
Furthermore, we learned that the sports game Kunisue-san
attended in the afternoon was somehow related to the case...
But it wasn't known to us which he had gone to.
All three of the suspects watched a sports game in the afternoon.
The key to finding the culprit should
lie within the suspects' testimonies.
Flowers dance to the piano's rhythm.
Two people face-to-face is a mystery!
It's finally revealed!
What's the solution to the case and
the contents of Kazuha's charm?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
For now, we have three men who watched
games that appeared to be interesting, but...
If we can't figure out which game Kunisue-san watched...
Yeah...
Was there anything in his wallet?
Like a ticket stub from a game?
No, other than money and credit cards, there was only the charm.
Coming up next, pro-baseball news!
First up, we'll be reporting on the day game,
which took place in Shinjuku Stadium...
Could it have been baseball?
See, even if someone were at a baseball game,
they might have lied and say they weren't.
I see.
If the culprit formed a grudge against Kunisue-san at the stadium...
They wouldn't say they watched baseball, right?
But hold on...
This was the only baseball day game
today, and it was dull and full of errors.
The only good part was in the bottom of the ninth...
Hey!
Hold it right there!
Ah, well...
The guests are gone, so I thought I'd clean up the table is all...
Don't touch it without asking!
Kyuuma Takuya (26)
I still have some popcorn left...
Harufuji Kengo (44)
Yeah, go microwave my half-eaten hot
dog and bring it here while you're at it!
And bring my beer too.
Satsuma Kazuo (51)
Yes, sir.
Let's see, where was I?
The day game, the day game!
If it's baseball, why does it have to be day games?
Nearby areas like Yokohama have night games too!
Idiot!
The time Kunisue-san called and said, "This is awesome! Looks like my
luck has changed, I'll show you my evidence later," was in the evening.
That had to be the completed daytime game!
I guess so.
Beyond that, I checked my cell phone and
the final score of the day game was 1-10.
The losing team that made a lot of errors finally
scored a home run in the bottom of the ninth inning.
Watching a mundane game like that, do you
think he would say, "This is awesome"?
Anyway...
What was played during the day were sumo wrestling,
beach volleyball, soccer, and that baseball game...
After that there was only golf.
Then maybe it was golf?
It's true that in that match, the final turnabout
on the last hole seemed pretty exciting, but...
That golf course is quite far from here.
Trying to get to this sports cafe by 8:00
after the game would be cutting it close.
And according to the employee, Kunisue-san
arrived here about an hour before the incident.
So we don't have any clues, do we?
Yeah...
Without those, we won't be able to know who assaulted Kunisue-san.
No.
We already know who the culprit is!
No way!
Really?
If you already know, why don't you hurry up and
tell everyone so the case can be solved!?
Detective Takagi, if we find out the charm has nothing
to do with the case, you'll return it soon, won't you?
Yeah...
What was that all about?
Charm this, charm that...
Kunisue-san had it and yet he was assaulted!
It only works for me, so it's obvious that it didn't work.
Well then?
Who's the culprit?
Right, you know, don't you?
Well...
We still need evidence...
You don't have any?
Right...?
Yeah...
Speaking of evidence, what do you think the
"evidence" was that Kunisue intended to show me?
Let's see...
As evidence of an "awesome game,"
what comes to mind first is...
A picture he took of one of the
players making a great play, but...
There wasn't such a picture in the victim's cell phone.
In that case, could it be he got an autograph
from a famous player at that game?
But...
While Kunisue likes sports, tennis players are the only
ones he's interested in getting autographs from.
Migikawa Shou, on the 18th and
final hole, chips it in for an eagle...
And has achieved a terrific turnabout victory!
I see...
So that's what happened.
That's why Kunisue-san asked his friend to come to this sports cafe...
So he could show of that conclusive evidence.
But unbeknownst to him...
It would soon be stolen by his attacker.
Uhm...
Is there anything else?
I'd like to head home now...
It's already after 10:00.
We've already told you what we know.
And you searched us before, but didn't end up finding anything.
Well, see, you three are the only customers without an alibi...
Hey, hey!
You can't just keep us here without any proof!
If you really want to go home, be my guest.
Of course...
That only goes for the two who aren't the culprit.
Does that means you found the evidence?
Yeah, both the culprit and the evidence are here.
Really, Conan-kun?
It seems that way...
But, why are you asking me?
Shouldn't you ask Heiji-niichan?
Well, you said earlier that you also knew who the culprit was...
So I thought you also...
Knew about the evidence...
I guess...
But why did I think that?
Of course I know!
Because the culprit said something odd
that even a kid like me would know.
Even a kid would know...
Something odd?
The statements given by those three
about the games they watched today.
One of them said something strange, right?
Well, let's see...
Satsuma Kazuo-san watched sumo wrestling...
Well, it was a good match, but...
I'm a fan of Akashouryuu, who lost the
match, so I'm a little down about it.
Harufuji Kengo-san watched beach volleyball...
Watching them tossing back and forth was exciting!
I was hoping for some boob slippin', though.
And finally, Kyuuma Takuya-san watched soccer.
Well, because I'm a fan of Big Osaka, the visiting team...
Seeing them hugging each other on the soccer ground in
victory, I clapped discreetly to avoid enraging my neighbors.
I don't see anything out of the ordinary...
Maybe it's the "slipping" he said about beach volleyball?
It's strange that you'd go to a game
and wait for a bathing suit to fall off!
That's practically sexual harassment!
That was just a joke!
Yeah, he's just a middle-aged man being a pervert...
But he didn't say anything odd.
Besides, unlike the sumo loincloth, having your
bathing suit fall off won't result in a loss.
In that case, the man who watched sumo... is the culprit?
No, I didn't say anything about a sumo loincloth...
GOAL!
Higo from Big Osaka!
Despite the pressure of being away,
he's come through with a terrific shot!
Away?
Hold on...
The team who travels to the opponent's stadium is
called the "away" team in soccer, not "visiting"...
That's right.
Fans are called "supporters," and the soccer
ground should be called a "pitch," right?
That means...
Right.
Someone didn't use a single term like a
true soccer supporter would use, but...
He had to lie and tell the police, "Soccer is
my favorite game, so I went to watch it."
That Kyuuma-san...
Happens to be the culprit we're after.
Wait!
It's only recently that I became a soccer
fan, so I'm not used to the terms yet.
If you really saw the match, tell me what's the
number of the game-winning player, Higo?
Well...
Of course you don't know.
You may have found out the game reports with
your cell phone about who scored and when, but...
The reports wouldn't show you the player's number.
Well, Higo's already become a symbol of Big Osaka.
Many supporters wear Higo's jersey with his number.
If you really went to the game, you should
remember even if you didn't want to.
I told you, this was the first soccer game I went to watch...
You're a baseball fan, right?
Visitor, fan, and ground...
Those are all baseball terms.
You actually went to a baseball game, didn't you?
Why baseball?
Didn't we talk about it before?
Because Kunisue-san called his friend excitingly,
he must have gone to a very interesting game.
If it was not a premeditated crime, but one out of anger from
meeting and conflicting with Kunisue-san somewhere today...
Then it most likely would've taken place in the same stadium.
In other words, the culprit should
have also been at that game.
But that baseball game Kunisue-san might've
gone to had a final score of 1-10...
And the error prone team didn't score anything
until the end with a home run, right?
Something like that wouldn't be
called an "awesome game"!
Certainly...
No matter what sport, no one would feel good if the match
is filled with mistakes, regardless of who won or lost.
Not to mention it had an uneven score of 1-10.
We wouldn't call that a great match even if we'd tried.
However, what if he were the only one
in the stadium to receive a souvenir?
Souvenir?
Furthermore, if that souvenir were something used in the game, and
proof of a certain outstanding performance, wouldn't he be thrilled?
Even if he's not particularly a fan.
Could that be...
A home run ball?
If it was, the audience could keep it as souvenir!
Then, Kunisue-san got the home run ball from that game?
That's right.
He got that and was planning to show it off to his friend...
But Kyuuma-san followed him from the
game, and took it away from him.
But, how did you know that Kunisue-san got the home run ball?
Oh, that...
Because of Kunisue-san's pocket.
The reason that the back right pocket of his pants was
bulging out with his wallet, cell phone, and cigarettes...
Is that the culprit purposely stuffed them in there.
He did it so the loose, puffy jeans
pocket wouldn't seem suspicious.
I get it!
Kunisue-san originally forced his home run ball into that pocket.
Even if the ball was removed, if the empty pocket was still
puffy, anyone would think that something was there, right?
The culprit must've been worried that people would
guess a baseball was inside by the way it bulged.
But, why did Kunisue-san ask his friend to come here?
Yeah...
If he had the home run ball, he could
just take it home and show it off.
Kunisue-san's staying at his friend's place after all.
In that case...
If I had a baseball and told you, "This is the winning ball
from when Japan won the WBC," would you believe me?
Who would believe that?
You see?
However, what if there was footage to prove it?
Footage?
Come to think of it, a home run ball landing in the
audience stands would be shown on TV, right?
Right.
In other sports, a spectator being shown by the
TV cameras may be just a coincidence...
But they would definitely show
a home run ball being caught.
If a guy with a sling caught it,
they would probably zoom in!
That's why Kunisue-san asked
his friend to come here.
And now, today's home run!
He wanted his friend and the other
customers to see this sports news footage...
And show off his home run ball to get everyone excited!
It's true, Kunisue-san caught the ball!
And behind Kunisue-san, isn't that Kyuuma-san?
That's right!
I see.
That's why when the pro-baseball game was showing
on the news earlier, he let out a shout, right?
To draw our eyes away from the footage.
That's not all, is it?
It's also because the employee was
about to throw this away, right?
Buried in the popcorn is something
you stole from Kunisue-san...
The home run ball!
But, why did you steal it?
Are you a fan of the player who hit it?
Yeah...
She's definitely an avid fan...
My girlfriend, that is...
Who died of illness last night.
She had always wanted to get a home run ball from that player.
She was saying it with her last breath too...
So I thought the least I could do was try to get
one, and place it in her cremation casket...
I went to the stadium, in the outfield
bleachers with my glove ready...
I was actually able to make a flying catch!
A catch...
But wasn't it Kunisue-san?
I really did catch it!
But immediately afterwards, I was shoved
by the spectators around me...
The next thing I know, it was in the hand of the sling guy...
But, I think that can't be helped!
You can't just get angry at Kunisue-san and
attack him so you can steal the ball!
No, I did explain everything and begged him for the ball.
Over and over...
But, he...
What, you again?
You're so stubborn.
I'm begging you!
Please, let me have the home run ball...
Who cares if you want to give it to your girlfriend or whatever!
Who'd just hand it over to someone like you, idiot!?
I snapped after hearing that...
And thought the only way was to resort to force...
I'm so sorry.
About your apology, please tell him that yourself.
I just received word from the hospital.
Kunisue-san has regained consciousness!
Really?
That's great!
It was for his girlfriend who passed away?
That's why that guy was trying so hard to beg me for the ball?
You didn't know?
He said he explained everything to you.
Well, I was upset when he said it was for his girlfriend.
I stopped listening before he said she had died.
Why's that?
Because I was recently rejected!
By the girl I love!
By the way, about the charm we mistakenly gave you...
That came back from being tested, so I handed it over to Hattori-kun.
When!?
Where!?
Just now, in the hospital hallway...
YOU IDIOT!
Say, could it be...
The girl you said rejected you...
Was Kazuha-neechan, right?
There's no way.
See, despite going back to Osaka just to ask Kazuha-neechan
for a charm in order to win the tennis tournament...
Once he returned to Tokyo, he lost motivation so
quickly that he injured himself during practice.
Because you saw it, right?
Inside the charm.
Yeah!
That dark-skinned boy's photo!
Conan-kun, you knew about the photo?
Yeah, I could hear some of your conversation.
I thought for a newly made charm,
the cloth was pretty worn out...
So I opened it to have a look.
That boy did say that it was attached to Kazuha-chan's bag.
So I realized that this was Kazuha-chan's
own charm, and I felt like crying.
I had wanted to say that I love her
after I won the tennis tournament.
When I caught the home run ball,
I thought my luck had changed, but...
Seems I was wrong.
Where's that ball now?
It's currently in the investigators' possession.
In that case, could you give it to the guy who hit me later?
And tell him I'm sorry for being mean.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
Please also pass the word to Kazuha-chan.
What would you like to say?
"I'm sorry for being mean," right?
Being mean?
Please, don't look inside it!
Ah, Heiji!
Hey!
What are you doing!?
Not good!
The charm's opened!
Kazuha...
The reason you were trying so
hard to retrieve your charm...
I finally understand...
What you think of me...
Of me...
You think I'm as ridiculous as this, do you!?
What is this!?
Well, I'm an adult.
So I won't get angry at this!
I see...
He was being mean by pranking the photo...
What's that?
That eerie looking witch outfit.
It's goth loli, goth loli!
I think it's great!
What happened!?
Next Conan's Hint
Cup