I'm sorry, Yuika, about Kadowaki-kun...
Kuze Mihiro (26)
If I had done a better job, it wouldn't have
turned out like that between you two...
That's enough, Mihiro.
I don't want to talk about a guy who'd hit on a friend.
I'm glad to be rid of a guy like him.
Shoudou Yuika (26)
By the way, did you buy it?
That outfit for tomorrow.
Yeah, I bought it!
The cute goth clothes.
I'm wearing it right now!
Please look forward to tomorrow.
Yeah.
Then let's meet at the usual place.
Yeah!
Yuika...
We're... best friends, aren't we?
What a stupid thing to say.
We're best friends until death.
Yuika...
Then I'll look forward to tomorrow!
Yeah.
Until death, huh...
Flowers dance to the piano's rhythm.
Two people face-to-face is a mystery!
What the dark plot hidden behind the goth loli fashion?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Geez, what a bummer...
How sad to think that I, the great detective Mouri Kogorou...
Had to accompany a girls' shopping day on a precious off-day like this!
Come on, it's only once in a while.
There are young ladies filling the
streets for you to feast your eyes on!
Besides...
There aren't any cases, so you're totally free.
Idiot!
I need to organize the dramas I recorded on DVD.
I also need to check out the payoff rate of
the newly remodeled pachinko parlor.
And also, also...
Today's the G1 horse race!
People all over the world would describe
you as goofing off and doing nothing.
What!?
Dad, don't waste money on pachinko and horse racing.
You too!
I won't have it if you dare buy some stupid expensive clothes!
Don't worry!
I'll only buy cheap and cute clothes!
Well, whatever, but you'll have to show me first before you buy!
No, that's a bit...
What, what!?
Are you going to buy indecent clothes
that you can't show your parents!?
Like a crop top that shows your belly button?
Or a Chinese dress that shows too much leg?
Well!?
Those are your interests...
You don't need to see them!
They aren't the sexy type.
Well, if you saw them it'd be awkward for everyone.
Welcome!
What's with that eerie-looking witch outfit?
Super cute!
It's goth loli, goth loli!
I think it's great!
Goth... loli?
Short for "gothic lolita"...
It's the black clothing fashion often seen in Gothic novels
like Dracula or horror movies derived from them.
In addition, it's a fashion designed to fit young girls.
That's what they said on TV!
This brat... what kind of TV show has he been watching?
Well...
That fashion would fit Haibara perfectly.
Don't tell me, you're planning to buy
some demonic outfits like that?
We're buying something adorable!
Something like a doll's outfit.
You're kidding me... a lolita look?
I don't care about goth lolis or gross lolis!
But there's no way I'm allowing you to dress
like you're going to some masquerade!
Thank you for waiting.
Uhm... about that customer...
Don't tell me she got upset and left
because I criticized her clothes?
Oh, no.
She was waiting for a friend who hasn't arrived yet...
And she left to go to the restroom.
The restroom is outside of our restaurant.
I see.
That goth loli lady from earlier hasn't come back yet.
If she's waiting for someone, it'd be best to wait inside, but...
Women just take a long time in the restroom.
Welcome!
Is it a party of one?
Oh, no...
Has a goth loli lady come in here?
She's a friend of mine.
Yes, she was here.
She's in the restroom at the moment.
Oh, I'm ten minutes late...
What did Mihiro order?
Well, she looked at the menu, but...
She said she'd wait for her friend before ordering.
Then, I too will wait until Mihiro comes back...
I'm sorry!
Oh, don't worry, I can take care of it...
I'm terribly sorry.
Not at all.
Well, since we're done with our drinks, let's hit the streets!
We've looked up the places we're going, after all.
Hey—let's go, boy.
Hey!
Hey, hey, hey...
What the...
Everyone's dressed all weird and crazy.
That's Harajuku for you.
Don't tell me you two want to dress like these...
They're gone!
Ran-neechan said that since they're here
to shop, we can just wander around.
Geez!
What are they thinking?
There was no reason for me to come!
No, they probably...
Want you to...
As I thought.
Carry their bags...
Well, let's try this store then!
This is so cute!
What's so cute...?
Wait, don't look without asking!
Then, why don't you carry them!?
Aww, no!
This is ice cream, isn't it?
What language is that?
I don't know, he's talking so fast.
These people are ice cream robbers!
Robbers?
It's a trick often used on Japanese tourists overseas.
If you got ice cream on your clothes, you'd drop
your bags and try to wipe it clean, right?
Then, they'd distract you by quickly
speaking a foreign language...
And an accomplice would escape with the tourist's bags.
Hey, hold it!
I saw it on TV!
Conan-kun, just what program were you watching?
But this is a problem...
We can't go shopping like this.
Why don't you change into the clothes you just bought?
You did buy them, no?
All right?
Promise me you two won't laugh!
Well, I bet it'll disappoint...
Wow, the restroom's full.
Looks like they had the same idea.
Hey, you!
Would you please hurry up!
Geez...
What's wrong?
This lady's been in there for over 30 minutes!
Could it be...
She had a heart attack and collapsed?
In that case...
Sonoko!
Let's see from above...
Hey, what happened!?
In the... toilet...
G... Goth loli...
What are you saying?
Rope marks on her neck...
And the Yoshikawa lines caused by her
resisting and scratching her neck.
strangulation...
My, what an extraordinary appearance.
This female victim, that is.
Has this come into fashion recently?
Oh, no...
It's called goth loli, and it's been in fashion for quite a while...
Excuse me for being an unfashionable old man.
Oh, no, I didn't mean...
And, the victim's identity?
According to the driver's license we found on her...
She lives in Haido District, and her name is Kuze Mihiro-san.
There are strangulation marks and Yoshikawa lines on her neck.
We can assume that she was strangled to death.
Yoshikawa lines?
What's that?
It's terminology used by the police...
When someone's being strangled, they'd be in pain and
try to remove the rope or cord around their neck.
At that time, the one being strangled
would usually leave fingernail marks.
They'd struggle hard in order to breathe, so
sometimes they'd leave deep scratch marks.
Therefore, those scratches are proof that
someone else strangled the person.
This was first realized in the Taisho period by the head of
the police forensics department, Yoshikawa Chouichi-san.
That's why those scratches came to
be known as "Yoshikawa lines."
And, that was on TV too, was it?
What program?
The evening news...
And, is it true that you saw this woman today?
Yes.
I was accompanying the girls while they were shopping today.
Before shopping, we stopped by the Shinjuku bookstore...
And then went to the teahouse where the girls checked
out stores in the fashion magazines they bought.
That's when the victim came in.
The teahouse in Shinjuku?
Yes.
And when the girls came to this restroom to change into the
clothes they bought in Harajuku, they came across her again.
In this tragic state, that is.
When the victim arrived at the teahouse, was she with anyone?
It seemed like she was meeting a friend.
An office lady with glasses.
What time did those two arrive at the teahouse?
The goth loli arrived just before 1:00...
The office lady came ten to fifteen minutes later.
The time of death is estimated to be between
12:30 and 1:30—a span of one hour, right?
In that case...
The office lady could've met with the victim at the teahouse...
Then brought her to this park's restroom in Harajuku, and killed her.
But, how was the door locked after the body was put inside?
After closing the door, they could've
stood on the bucket in this closet...
And locked it from above using the tip of a cleaning brush.
Since the door just has a simple sliding lock.
Is this restroom always so crowded?
No, it's just crowded during this time of day...
When these women arrived, the stall was already
locked and the cell phone would ring at times.
Cell phone?
Yes.
I checked the incoming call log on the victim's cell phone.
It seems someone has been trying to call her
every ten minutes for the last two hours.
Oh, again?
It's the same number from the call log.
Hey, Mihiro, what are you doing?
I'm still waiting at the teahouse.
Mihiro!
Oh, no—I'm with the police.
Police?
Has something happened to Mihiro?
Actually...
No way!
Mihiro, why!?
Am I correct that you had a meeting
with this Kuze Mihiro-san today?
Yes...
1:00 PM at the Shinjuku teahouse...
Then, you met with Mihiro-san there and came
to this Harajuku park restroom together?
I hadn't met with Mihiro yet today.
But you were both at the teahouse...
They missed each other.
The goth loli left to use the restroom
about ten minutes before she arrived.
Then, Mihiro-san left for the restroom and didn't come back?
Yes...
Because she was so slow, I asked the employee
to check on her, but no one was in there.
That's why I began calling Mihiro's cell phone
every ten minutes, but never got through.
When I finally did get through...
I was the one who answered, huh?
Yes.
But, why didn't you check the restroom yourself?
The restroom is outside of the teahouse.
After you've ordered something, it'd be wrong
to leave the store before paying the bill.
Then, you were in the teahouse all this time?
Yes.
You can confirm that if you ask the teahouse employee.
I guess the first thing we should do is to check out the teahouse?
That's true, while they still remember.
Well, we're headed to the store.
Takagi-kun, wait here.
If you discover anything, let me know.
Yes, sir.
What's wrong, Sonoko?
Something about this person feels off...
What is it?
Normally if you dress up as a goth loli, you'd
put on either black or white fingernails, but...
I don't see any fake nails on her.
Come to think of it, she didn't have
any on back in the teahouse, either.
Say, were there any fake nails dropped in the stall?
No, nothing was dropped inside.
Hey, what are you doing?
Let's go.
You guys are witnesses too.
Yes, she was here.
A little before 1:00 PM, in this seat.
So there's no mistake that it was this woman?
Yes, I think so.
She had a very soft voice.
A soft voice?
Soon after she was seated, she asked what time it was.
I told her it was 12:56.
Although the clock was right next to her.
And ten minutes after she left for the bathroom...
This woman came in, correct?
Yes.
She said she was meeting with the goth loli customer.
Oh, I'm ten minutes late...
I think it was about 1:12.
And she stayed in this seat the entire time?
Yes.
She appeared to call the customer who
went to the restroom many times.
If she were the culprit, she'd need to call the victim
to the park soon after she left for the restroom...
And then come straight back to this store after the murder.
Park Restroom
Teahouse
But going from this teahouse to the park and back
would take at least thirty minutes, even by car or train.
That means it'd have been impossible for her to do it.
Then she must've been killed by an evil witch's curse!
A witch, Conan-kun?
But that goth loli lady...
She had a normal photo on her driver's license...
But when we saw her she had a cursed, witch-like face!
Idiot.
When you dress as a goth loli...
It's customary to use foundation to make your skin
look white, and mascara to highlight your eyes!
That's right.
If Sonoko and I dressed up like that, we'd also wear that makeup.
So, if your clothes were the same, no one could tell you two apart!
Inspector, could it be that she...
Yeah...
Looks like we need to look into whether it was
really Mihiro-san who entered this store.
A body with a goth loli costume was
discovered in the park's restroom.
We saw the victim at a teahouse in Shinjuku prior to her death.
After she was seated, she went straight
to the restroom outside the store...
And ten minutes later, a woman who was meeting her showed up.
But the goth loli never returned to the store.
The victim was Kuze Mihiro-san, who lived in Haido City.
The woman who was meeting with her
claimed to be her friend, Shoudou Yuika-san.
Shoudou-san had been waiting for the
unreturned Mihiro-san in the teahouse.
From the Harajuku park's restroom where the
body was found to the teahouse in Shinjuku...
It would take 30 minutes back and forth even by car or train.
Park Restroom
Teahouse
It'd be impossible for Shoudou-san, who
stayed the entire time, to commit the crime.
But, is that the truth?
Looks like this case can't be closed so easily...
I guess... it's weird?
I don't think it's weird...
But that was lucky, wasn't it?
That the glass broke.
Lucky?
I won't allow this case to continue sleeping.
Next Conan's Hint
Twins
Look Forward to the Next Episode