Uncle Kogorou and I accompanied Ran
and Sonoko as they went shopping.
But later, we discovered the body of a strangled woman in a park restroom.
The victim, who had dressed in goth
loli fashion, was Kuze Mihiro-san...
Who we'd seen at a teahouse in Shinjuku prior to her death.
Soon after Mihiro-san was seated...
She went to the restroom outside the store before ordering.
Afterward, Shoudou Yuika-san, a friend who
was meeting with Mihiro-san, arrived there.
But Mihiro-san never returned to her seat.
Shoudou-san was counted as one of the suspects, but...
Her alibi was perfect.
Park Restroom
Teahouse
But...
Flowers dance to the piano's rhythm.
Two people face-to-face is a mystery!
The goth loli case is about to be solved.
Pay attention to Ran and Sonoko's cosplay too!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Did this woman who came here first order anything?
No, she didn't.
Although, before she left for the restroom, she did look at the menu.
Then, would you mind lending us the menu?
Sure.
I don't think you'll find them.
Mihiro's fingerprints.
Shoudou Yuika (26)
I accidentally knocked over a glass of water.
When I went to pick it up...
I carelessly put the menu down on the
soaked table, so I wiped it off later.
Of course, I also wiped the table and the sofa that got wet...
So there should be no trace left showing Mihiro had been here.
Does that mean I will be made out to be the culprit?
Inspector.
No...
But it's a problem.
Since Mihiro's glass already fell to the floor and shattered...
Shattered?
If it shattered, does that mean you still have it?
That glass!
Yes.
It's in the non-flammable waste bag.
So, these are the fragments?
Yes.
This is the only glass that was broken today.
I'll call the investigators to examine it.
If you'd like...
Shall we also go to the store where Mihiro bought the outfit?
I know the store she was likely to visit.
Yes, it's this person.
She came to buy it last night.
By herself?
Yeah.
Then, was she the only one to buy this outfit?
No...
These outfits came out yesterday as our store original.
They're very popular, and were completely gone by the end of the day.
Was this person one of the customers who bought one of the outfits?
Well...
It was impossible for me to buy it.
Last night, I was taking a taxi in Fukuoka for business...
And talked to her on the phone about the clothes she'd bought.
In Fukuoka?
Yeah.
I arrived at Haneda today, and went
straight to that Shinjuku teahouse.
Is that true?
Go ahead and investigate if you'd like!
Because I was on that plane with my co-workers.
If that's true, she wouldn't have had a chance to buy the outfit.
But, as the most likely culprit, how did she do it?
Hey, Conan-kun.
Come here for a sec.
I borrowed this store's dressing room to change, but...
Hey, hey, there's a murder case going on and
you still took time to change into loli clothes?
Well?
I guess... it's weird?
I don't think it's weird...
Damn, it's really cute!
Geez, it's a waste showing it to a brat like him!
Huh?
Why are you two wearing the same outfit?
You really are clueless about these things!
This is one of the current fashion trends...
I see.
You found Mihiro-san's fingerprints on the broken glass?
Well then, she has a perfect alibi.
In that case, are you finally going to let me go?
Look at the time...
It's getting pretty late.
I see...
So that's how it was.
An unusually clean place?
Well, I don't think there was anything like
that in the stall where the body was.
Have you checked the other stalls?
No, I haven't done that yet...
In the neighboring stall...
Only the toilet paper cover is unusually clean.
That's it.
Well, I'd like to go home then.
I have to let my friends know about Mihiro's death, after all.
Oh, no, we can't let you yet.
It's been bothering me.
Today, Mihiro-san had an appointment
to meet you at the Shinjuku teahouse.
Yet she didn't wait for you, left for the restroom and never returned...
Then, for some reason, she was killed in the Harajuku park restroom.
I wouldn't know about that even if you asked me!
All I can say is...
I entered the teahouse about ten minutes
after Mihiro went to the restroom.
When Mihiro didn't return for a while,
I kept calling her cell phone, but...
It never went through.
And when it finally did go through...
The one who answered was you, Inspector—that's all I can say.
Or what?
Are you still suspecting me of murder?
No, I don't mean...
Inspector, Shoudou-san is innocent.
Didn't we go over this?
If Shoudou-san were the culprit...
She'd have to call Mihiro-san to the park after she left for the restroom.
Then she'd have to go back to the teahouse after the murder.
From the teahouse in Shinjuku to the park in Harajuku...
The roundtrip requires at least thirty minutes.
It's impossible for Shoudou-san to have arrived at
the teahouse ten minutes after Mihiro-san left.
And weren't Mihiro-san's fingerprints found on that glass?
From that, it's obvious that Mihiro-san
was the one who came to the teahouse.
But, why did Mihiro-san touch that glass?
When you're given water at a teahouse, it's normal to drink it!
But wait, on the glass that this lady dropped and shattered...
There wasn't any lipstick, was there?
See, Mihiro-san cosplayed goth loli...
And wore dark colored lipstick, right?
But...
Although that's true...
Boy, I don't think you know this...
But if you get lipstick on the rim of a glass, it's
ladylike to use your finger to casually wipe it off.
But I don't think there was any trace of lipstick being wiped away.
Then, maybe when Mihiro was opening
her menu, the glass was in the way...
So she simply grabbed it and moved it away?
And then she left for the restroom without ever drinking it.
In fact, I was also trying to put the menu down
when I knocked over and broke the glass.
But that was lucky, wasn't it?
That the glass broke.
"Lucky"?
I mean, if it hadn't broken...
After you were asked by the inspector to go to the
murder scene, and you had to leave the teahouse...
Don't you think the waitress would've picked it up and
washed it, completely removing the fingerprints?
Plus, I was wondering why you...
Sat on the side where the goth loli lady left the glass?
Normally, when two people are meeting up,
they sit across from each other, right?
That's...
If you hadn't sat on that side, you wouldn't have broken the glass...
Idiot!
People can sit wherever they like!
Besides, even if the shattered glass weren't
washed, it would've been thrown away!
Then, when it's finally taken away by a garbage
truck and dumped on Dream Island...
To dig it up from a mountain of trash...
How bothersome.
Just how many officers do you thin—
Hey, Mouri-kun!
It's happening again?
By "Mouri"...
Do you mean Sleeping Kogorou?
Indeed.
But, I won't allow this case to continue sleeping.
I'll proceed to explain things in a logical manner.
The person who strangled Kuze Mihiro-san
in the Harajuku park restroom...
And traveled by foot to the Shinjuku
teahouse and artfully devised an alibi...
Shoudou Yuika-san...
It was you!
Hey, hey, hold on, Mouri-kun.
Didn't you just say it?
That it would take thirty minutes to get to and come
back from the park's restroom to the teahouse.
How could Shoudou-san get to the teahouse ten
minutes after Mihiro-san left for the restroom?
Certainly, that would be impossible if the murder
took place after Mihiro-san left for the restroom.
But suppose the murder took place before
Mihiro-san came to the teahouse...
And it is then possible!
Before she came to the teahouse?
Then, the one who appeared there was actually...
Yeah.
Inspector, I believe you felt the same
when you saw Mihiro-san's body.
The goth loli fashion is rather loud and gaudy.
It left a strong first impression on the teahouse
employee and on those of us who were there...
So strong that we couldn't recognize her face clearly.
Who would've thought that the office lady who
entered the teahouse ten minutes later...
Was in fact the same as the goth loli herself!
What kind of nonsense is that?
Didn't you say the fingerprints on the
glass from the teahouse were Mihiro's?
That's right, I did.
Because that glass was one you had stolen from that store earlier.
Right...
Perhaps you invited Mihiro-san to your home...
And gave her a drink from that glass, so that
Mihiro-san's fingerprints would be on the glass.
Then, you arrived by dressing up as
a goth loli, and were given a glass.
All you had to do was switch the glass with the one in
your purse that was covered in Mihiro-san's fingerprints.
Ten minutes later, you returned with your
makeup removed and clothes changed.
And the reason why you sat on the same
side of the table as you did earlier...
Was to purposely knock over the glass you had switched...
In order to have it shatter on the floor and spill water everywhere.
You wiped off the seat that you sat in ten minutes prior.
Because of that, we didn't find it odd that there
were no traces of Mihiro-san sitting in that seat.
You made the broken glass the only
evidence that Mihiro-san had been here.
After you shattered the glass, you picked the shards up.
Even if you left your fingerprints on the glass while
you made the switch, you now had an excuse.
But you just said that they might be thrown away!
That'd only be the case if Mihiro-san's body
were discovered after two or three days.
I see!
That's why you called Mihiro-san so many times.
If she stayed in the stall without coming out even as her
phone kept ringing, someone would no doubt check inside.
All the more if it happened to be when
the park restroom was crowded.
Once the body was discovered, the police would
suspect your calling Mihiro-san so many times...
And would then check the teahouse where you had been.
The police would then find the shattered glass
before it was sent away as non-flammable waste!
Wait a minute!
Aren't you forgetting something?
The goth outfit Mihiro wore was bought
by herself from this shop last night.
Furthermore, it was only being sold yesterday.
I was on a business trip in Fukuoka and
didn't return here until noon today.
I couldn't have bought it!
The question isn't who bought it...
But instead: How many were bought?
Miss, did Mihiro-san buy only one outfit?
No, she bought two.
She said that she could only come in the evening, and
asked me to reserve two outfits of the same size for her.
The outfits were going fast as interest has been
high since they were announced a few days ago.
Yet right after the inspector confirmed with the clerk that
Mihiro-san came by herself to buy the outfit, you...
Then, was she the only one to buy this outfit?
You interrupted, right?
Was it not so you could ask your question before the clerk
could mention Mihiro-san had purchased two of the outfits?
You did that in order to change the topic to who
bought the outfit, and not how many she bought.
Am I wrong?
But, Mouri-kun...
I get that Mihiro-san and Shoudou-san wear the same size...
And she asked Mihiro-san to buy an outfit for
her and to bring it to their date today. but...
After the crime, it would take an awful long time to fix her
clothes, makeup, and hair to be exactly like Mihiro-san...
Wouldn't that interfere with her alibi setup?
It isn't like the two of them decided to
come dressed the same prior to the crime...
Oh, actually...
That's right!
And perhaps she bought two outfits all for herself?
Maybe she really liked it, and kept a spare in case one got dirty!
Right?
Aren't there people who do that?
Well, yes...
About that mystery...
Let's have the girls come and explain it to us.
Ran-neechan, Sonoko-neechan!
Why did you sneak off and hide?
Hey...
That idiot...
Uncle told you to hurry out and show us those cute clothes!
Guess it can't be helped!
Ta-daaa!
What's with those looks?
And you're wearing the same outfit!
That's called the twin fashion.
Twin fashion?
Close friends choose to dress in the same clothes...
And also keep the same hairstyle, makeup, and handbags.
It's a fashion in which the two look like twins!
That's why I thought for sure that Mihiro-san was
also trying out the twin fashion with her friend.
I see.
You made the suggestion to dress like that to Mihiro-san...
And then, right after going to that park restroom to change clothes...
You proceeded to strangle and kill Mihiro-san.
Well, I wonder?
If you're naming me as a suspect, why don't you show me?
The proof that I did it...
We do have evidence.
It's on your left arm.
You were going to look at your watch a while ago.
Look at the time...
But you gave up and checked your cell phone clock instead, right?
The reason you hesitated is that...
While you were strangling Mihiro-san, she
most likely left scratch marks on your left arm.
I do see wounds.
You're wrong!
I did this myself...
True.
You may talk your way out of those wounds.
Since it appears that no bits of skin were
discovered on Mihiro-san's fingertips.
Perhaps it was her fake nails that created the scratches.
It would be impossible to prove if the nails were disposed of.
But, instead of setting up your alibi and
leaving the scene as soon as possible...
You used remover to completely strip
the fake nails from both of her hands.
Why is that?
Because you wanted to hide the fact that you were scratched!
As well as your blood while you were strangling her...
That came from your wounds and
dropped onto a certain place in the stall!
Well, what certain place?
As for that, Detective Takagi should contact you shortly.
Megure speaking.
What!?
In the next stall, you found traces of blood?
Since the toilet paper cover was the only place not covered in dust...
Forensics investigated it and got a luminol reaction.
And?
What about the results of the blood tests?
It's not a match to our victim's blood,
so it may actually be the culprit's.
Perhaps the crime actually happened in this stall...
But the culprit's blood dripped onto the cover,
causing them to move the body to the next stall.
You heard it.
In that case, I'd like to take a sample of your blood.
Take whatever you want if you must.
Mihiro has already taken everything from me.
You can't even get my nose to bleed.
Taken... you mean like your boyfriend?
Yeah, that too.
The first man she took was when I was 20 years old.
I was in a slump...
It was one thing after another, I had lost my job...
Been driven away from my apartment, and had
all my friends leave me for some reason.
In the end, all that was left was my childhood friend, Mihiro.
Through Mihiro, I got a job at her parent's company...
And she suggested that I live with her in her apartment.
Rather than taking from you, it sounds like she
was a great friend that helped you tremendously!
Yeah...
That's what I thought until recently.
Until I found out that losing my job, being kicked out
of my apartment, and my friends disappearing...
Everything!
It was all secretly Mihiro's doing!
Why would she...
Who knows?
Maybe she wanted to make sure that I stuck with her forever?
I was also her only friend.
But...
I was betrayed.
I trusted her!
That's why...
This time I was the one doing the taking.
You two should also cherish those fairytale-like feelings of yours.
There's nothing as unreliable and fragile as friendship.
Well, let's talk at the station.
Are you an idiot!?
So what if friendship is unreliable and fragile!
That way, when you communicate with
your heart, you can feel warmth inside.
If it were as hard as some chattering iron plate...
You wouldn't feel that warmth, y'know!?
I see...
If I had spoken to her the way you did...
We may have rekindled that warmth...
From so long ago...
Sonoko, how cool!
Respect!
Don't act so wild in those pretty clothes!
Where is everybody?
Huh?
Awesome!
The scent of almond...
What?
Was is cyanide poisoning?
We are the Detective Boys!
We wanted to help with the investigation!
So Mayu was my look-like who died in the landslide?
Genta, what's with that flashlight?
If I recall, at that time...
Next Conan's Hint
Drink bottle
Look Forward to the Next Episode