I'm really looking forward to the fireflies!
They should hurry up and come sooner!
Yeah!
Owada Michitake (47)
Chief Priest
Hello, Owada speaking.
It's Nakamine!
Oh, Nakamine-kun!
Where are you right now?
The Firefly Song...
Because we're driving carefully, we might arrive later than planned...
But we've passed the Akazawa Bridge,
and will be there in about 15 minutes.
Oh, is that so!
Nakamine-kun, make sure you guys drive carefully.
Nakamine Tokurou (28)
Village Head's Son
I got it.
Later.
Flowers dance to the piano's rhythm.
Two people face-to-face is a mystery!
The young are clashing about
amidst the  village revitalization.
The flicker of the fireflies will shine the truth to us!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
He said he'll be here in 15 minutes.
I want to see the fireflies now!
It's about time.
The fireflies serve as the trump card of this village's sightseeing spot.
All of the villagers are excited.
It was the shrine that gathered tourist interest before, though.
People were pretty crazy about a shrine that's inside a cave...
But they aren't anymore.
That's why Priest Owada-san here came
up with the idea of breeding fireflies...
But it was difficult to raise funds.
But, you did manage that, right?
Yeah, it's all thanks to the village head's son, Nakamine-kun.
What about the matter regarding Aoi-san?
Well...
He said that in exchange for his fundraising
service, he wants to marry my daughter Aoi.
Owada Aoi (22)
Michitake's Daughter
And how did Aoi reply?
She gave him the cold shoulder.
Nakamine-kun abuses the fact
that he's the village head's son...
Kashiwa Tatsuma (26)
Eldest Son of an Old Family in the Village
He beats people up and fools around with women.
But since he's the youth group's leader,
he still helps us at times like this.
Alright, let's go!
Yeah!
Hey, turn off the streetlights!
Tarumi-kun, thanks for the good work.
Tarumi Shuuichirou (26)
Nakamine's Friend
It's nothing.
Nakamine-kun, I thank you too...
Tarumi, you can open them now.
Right.
Awesome!
Pretty!
Unlike the city, it's dark here so we can see clearly.
Yeah.
Alright, I'll catch ya!
Wait up!
Right here!
Huh?
Where'd it go?
Where are you, firefly?
Did you know?
A firefly's mouth is undeveloped, so it can only ingest water.
Once the nutrient it stored during its larval form is used up, it dies.
Narutaki Souichi (59)
Police Detective
Narutaki-san, so you're here.
Priest Owada-san, huh?
How pretty these are.
I couldn't help but to think how nice
it'd be if I could show Mayu these.
Is something wrong?
No, it's nothing.
How unfortunate...
A landslide struck his house last year.
He lost his family because of that.
You mentioned that in the letter you sent.
About a man who lost his cute granddaughter because of it...
Yes, that was Narutaki-san.
He's a local police detective, right?
It really gave me the creeps; the road was narrow...
Where's Nakamine-kun?
I want to thank him.
Huh?
Where could he be?
Let me call him.
Hello?
Is this Nakamine-san?
Where are you?
What now?
Hey, who's over there?
What did Nakamine-kun say?
I don't know.
All he said was "I'm at Eboshi Rock, help me!" in a painful voice.
Where's this Eboshi Rock?
It's a rock upstream.
Let's take the truck.
Yes!
What's wrong?
No, it's just...
The keys... the keys are missing!
Perhaps Nakamine-san took them.
Nakamine-san!
Nakamine-san, you there?
How is he?
The scent of almond...
What?
Was it cyanide poisoning?
Poison?
A drink bottle...
Was it poisoned?
A firefly.
While we wait for the local backup to come...
Let's summarize the chain of events in this case.
After carrying the fireflies here, Nakamine-san
went missing for some reason.
When Tarumi-san called him, he merely said
that he was at Eboshi Rock and in agony.
It sounded like someone else was present.
Yes.
After you guys rushed there, you saw Nakamine-san
in his car, his breathing already ceased.
But, Nakamine-san couldn't have driven alone.
His right leg seemed to be broken.
In that case, after he released the fireflies,
someone else drove him to Eboshi Rock...
And he was given the poisoned drink and murdered.
Did that firefly get in while they were boarding the car?
What are you guys doing?
We are the Detective Boys!
We wanted to help with the investigation!
The Detective Boys?
Children are not allowed here.
Hurry up and go to bed!
I told you guys to stop.
Mayu...
Grandpa!
I think Narutaki-san was reminded of his granddaughter.
I was surprised when I saw you too.
So Mayu was my look-alike who died in the landslide?
The mountain collapses easily nowadays.
Too many trees have been cut.
Whenever the rain gets heavy, my heart jumps in fright.
Dad...
Aoi, come here.
Where did you go off to after the fireflies were released?
Where...?
I don't want to believe it, but did you meet with Nakamine-kun?
You're wrong!
When it comes to that man, I can't stop worrying about what he'd do.
Are you listening?
Kashiwa-kun...
I said you're wrong!
And what is wrong?
What happened to Kashiwa-san?
According to Tarumi-kun, he was being picked on.
Say, Tatsuma...
As the village's oldest noble family, your donation was too stingy!
Your late father would definitely frown upon it.
Don't talk so loud, people will hear you.
This is my normal voice!
If the Kashiwa family could help out more, it'd
be easier for me to gather funds from people!
Right, Tarumi?
That's right.
Like I said, the village revitalization all depends on you!
My, my, my...
It's the village head's son.
It's been a while.
Miss, it's been quite a while.
Oh, don't be so formal.
What can I do for you?
Tatsuma, hurry up and invite him in.
He was scolded severely by his mother later on:
"Why didn't you help with the village revitalization?"
His mother didn't know...
That her late husband almost bankrupted the family with his debt.
Let me remind you.
Even though you and Kashiwa-kun are childhood
friends, I disallow you marrying each other.
In a family headed toward turmoil, and with a
mother like that, I can only foresee you suffering.
Be careful, it's very slippery.
Yes!
A shrine inside a cave, how incredible!
Could there be fireflies around here?
♪ Come, come, come, fireflies... ♪
♪The water there is bitter...♪
Come to think of it, I could hear the firefly song back then...
Hello, Owada speaking.
It's Nakamine!
Oh, Nakamine-kun!
Where are you right now?
Detective Boys, let's do our best!
You'll be scolded by the detective again!
He's not here, so we should be fine.
He's right inside the shrine office!
Their local backup has arrived, and they're
about to start a thorough investigation.
Did they find out something new?
Yeah, about the drink bottle...
The drink was Nakamine-san's favorite.
And the bottle left at the scene had its contents washed clean.
It was washed?
Aoi, you're there, right?
The shrine office uses that to communicate.
Aoi, the police wanted to see you.
Sorry to make you wait.
To be frank...
According to our interview taken since last night,
we found out something unfortunate.
What's this?
The priest forgot to turn off the mike.
For an entire 30 minutes after the fireflies' release,
no one witnessed Aoi-san's presence.
In other words, it was in the time span before
the victim's body was discovered.
But Narutaki-san, in the darkness like that, it wouldn't
be a surprise if no one had seen my daughter, right?
But, after some investigation, everyone
else confirmed each other's presence.
It's because people often huddle together during firefly-watching.
Within a confined space, I may add.
Despite this, no one else saw Owada Aoi-san and another person.
They said it was me.
Because Nakamine-san took a fancy in Aoi-san...
He would without a doubt follow her to Eboshi Rock if invited.
And if she gave him the poisoned drink...
But in that case, that could also apply to me.
Then again, if you were the inviter, I don't
think that Nakamine-san would take the bait.
In any case, it looks like I'm safe.
What a relief.
Hold it, it's too early to relax.
You have something you're hiding too, don't you?
Nakamine-san was angry with you.
He said that you embezzled funds from gathering fireflies.
That's not true at all.
It was a misunderstanding.
I explained everything and Nakamine-san understood!
Genta, what's with that flashlight?
You've had that since last night, right?
I forgot to return it.
It was in that truck that brought the fireflies.
Let me take a look at that.
What's wrong?
If I recall, at that time...
Nakamine-kun, I thank you too...
Tarumi, you can open them now.
I see, so that's how it was.
Aoi-san, do you have anything to say?
I do have something to say.
Agasa-kun...
Do not worry, Owada-kun.
Your daughter is not the culprit.
As a layperson, please refrain from interfering.
I'll make it quick, but only after...
I've exposed the crime that Tarumi-san committed!
What do you mean, "my crime"?
It was you, wasn't it?
The one who killed Nakamine-san with poisoned drink.
Stop joking around!
When Nakamine-san died, I was right beside you, wasn't I?
The phone call, in which you claimed Nakamine-san
was dying, was merely your acting.
Nakamine-san was already dead before that.
What?
Wait a sec.
After I released the fireflies, I was with my friends the whole time.
When did I go near Eboshi Rock if you're accusing me?
It was before you released the fireflies.
Last night, we received a call from Nakamine-san
as he was transporting the fireflies.
We could hear the Firefly Song's melody from the phone.
That's true.
That was coming from the grocery store halfway
through the path to Eboshi Rock.
In other words, Nakamine-san was headed toward Eboshi
Rock with Tarumi-san who was driving the truck.
Then he dropped Nakamine-san off at Eboshi
Rock, and returned to the riverbank alone.
Sasa Bridge
Grocery Store
Eboshi Rock
That's impossible.
When the fireflies were about to be released,
we heard Nakamine-kun's voice.
That was a simple trick.
Using this.
What, isn't that a flashlight?
Actually, this is...
Hey, turn off the streetlights!
This is...
Tarumi, you can open them now.
This is a voice recorder shaped like a flashlight.
You used this and pretended to have a
conversation with Nakamine-san, right?
I see, that's why he didn't respond to me when I talked to him.
Exactly.
Tarumi-san, just as you were about
to take the truck to Eboshi Rock...
You panicked a little when you looked inside.
Because this thing that was supposed to be in there was gone.
In fact, one of the kids accidentally kept it.
You probably lured Nakamine-san by saying this:
Aoi-san wanted to meet you, but she didn't
want her father to know about this.
So she wanted you to create an alibi
and meet her secretly at Eboshi Rock.
Nakamine-san easily took the bait.
He had you take him to Eboshi Rock, and recorded
his voice himself as alibi fabrication...
And he got into his own car that was parked
beforehand, waiting for Aoi-san.
Just then, you handed him the poisoned drink.
So, as he was waiting for Aoi-san, he drank that and died...
Nonsense!
If I went to Eboshi Rock before releasing the fireflies...
Why did a firefly fly out of the car!?
You released one into the car, just so you could say that.
When? How?
It was pretty bold of you.
You arrived at the victim's car a few steps sooner than us.
That's when you made the switch.
You switched the poisoned bottle for one with a firefly in it.
The reason the bottle was washed was
so that you could insert a firefly.
Come to the station to explain yourself.
Aoi!
Tatsuma-san!
Haibara!
Mayu!
Ai-chan!
What's that noise?
Landslide!
Everyone all right?
Yeah.
We're fine.
Where's Ai-chan?
Here.
Damn it.
Tarumi!
Stop this nonsense!
There's nowhere for you to run!
Shut up!
Mayu!
Ai-chan!
What?
A firefly, firefly!
Who cares about a firefly!
You should.
The fact that the firefly came here means
that there's a path to the outside, no?
I see...
Good, it's over here.
Mayu!
Hey!
If you move a bit, this brat loses her life!
Huh?
Now there are two fireflies.
That's not it.
That's a reflection from a puddle.
I bet Haibara notices.
You brat!
Mayu!
Damn you!
We did it!
Are you all right, Mayu?
Mayu!?
I'm not Mayu-chan.
But thank you.
Thank goodness...
Truly, thank goddess...
Thank goodness.
The motive for Tarumi's wasn't just about
the embezzling of the firefly fund...
But he also stole money from Nakamine's father's
company, and feared that would be exposed.
I was afraid about what would happen back there...
But it was a happy ending, happy ending.
You're right.
Looks like a happy ending over there, too.
That's right.
A Robber!
I said wait!
As I recall, his right cheek was burnt.
Was there such a man during that bus jacking?
I think he was wearing a knitted cap and a mask.
What the...
Next Conan's Hint
Reading Glasses
Look Forward to the Next Episode