It's finally going to happen, tomorrow at 16:00!
Yeah!
That's right!
The deciding match between the Tokyo Spirits and Big Osaka.
Big beat the Spirits last time, so they need to step it up.
But...
Hide from the Spirits...
He's injured and can't play in tomorrow's game, so
don't you think they'll get stomped by Big again?
Yeah...
I bet Higo-san from Big will score a hat trick...
And go on to become the top scorer and
easily lead Big to the championship, no?
What'd you say!?
Well, that Higo-san can't participate in tomorrow's
game either, due to too many yellow cards.
Really?
It was in the morning newspaper.
It read, "Two Great Rivals Absent From Final Match."
Now that you mention it...
Higo-san did get a yellow card in that last match.
The commentator did sound really
disappointed, so I had a bad feeling...
Can't believe he feel for such a sly scheme.
Sly scheme, huh...
This girl knows what a hat trick is, but doesn't know
what happens to those who accumulate yellow cards?
But, it's painful to know that the point-getters
for both teams won't be showing up, huh?
Speaking of pain...
I have to get my cavity pulled at the dentist's tomorrow.
Oh no, it sounds painful!
Damn it!
Hide won't be showing up, and I have to go to the dentist!
I hope tomorrow never comes!
Hey, hey!
Don't say things like that.
Tomorrow is full of hope, right?
Especially for you kids!
What's with you, mister?
Daita Kyouzou (62)
Passerby
Well...
I'm just a retired old man who happens to be passing by.
Then, what's going to be so much fun for you tomorrow?
Oh, it'll be so much fun I won't be able to handle it.
Tomorrow I'll be going to Osaka for a soccer match.
Soccer?
And then...
I'll come back to drink with a friend I haven't seen in ten years.
And the final episode of a series I've been watching is tomorrow.
Not to mention the Summer Big Lottery!
They'll be announcing the winner tomorrow!
I bought a lot of tickets this time, so I'm pretty excited...
A robber!
Flowers dance to the piano's rhythm.
Two people face-to-face is a mystery!
A commotion caused by a lottery ticket.
The FBI and Akai's ghost are moving about!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
Thief!
You guys, stay where you are!
Conan-kun!
Wait!
I said wait!
He got away...
Conan-kun!
Where's the snatcher?
Did you lose him?
Yeah.
I did retrieve this man's bag, at least.
The zipper isn't open, so I don't think anything was stolen.
You should check just in case, though.
Thank you!
Let's see...
My wallet, my house key, my notebook, and my soccer ticket...
And my glasses case!
Seems nothing was stolen!
Huh?
There's a photo booth sticker on your glasses case!
This photo is of my granddaughter
who will be turning seven this year.
These glasses were a birthday present that she chose for me...
They're my most precious treasure.
Seven years old...
She's the same age as us!
Does she go to Teitan Elementary?
No...
What was the name of her school...
Here.
Your lottery tickets.
We picked up all of the ones we could find, but...
You picked them up for me?
I also picked some up!
I got three of them!
I got five!
Thank you for all of your help.
Not only did you get my bag back, but also my tickets...
But of course!
We're the Detective Boys!
We help those in trouble!
Detective Boys?
Yeah!
We've assisted in several real-life cases!
We're friends with some police officers too!
That's incredible.
Then I'd like to treat you Detective Boys
to some dessert, do you have time?
We do, we do!
Plenty of time!
In that case, let's head to the nearest cake shop!
Awesome!
The match you're going to see tomorrow is the Big versus Spirits game?
Yeah.
Here's the ticket.
I've got a good seat too.
How nice!
I love both Hide and Higo, so I'm looking forward to their battle.
But...
Those two...
Omi-kun!
We'll drink until dusk tomorrow like before...
Something came up and you'll have to go home at 10:00 PM?
Hey, hey—that only leaves an hour for drinking!
Well, how about we start drinking at 7:00?
We're both retired and have free time.
Anyway, I'll give the bar a call beforehand.
Then, I'm looking forward to seeing you tomorrow.
Don't be surprised to see how old my face looks!
See you!
Yeah...
Changing the drinking time to 7:00 PM...
You're right!
You have a lot to do tomorrow.
Told you!
But you wrote "washing machine" on today's plan.
Yeah, I'm going to Akihabara to buy one.
Mine is broken.
That's why I've had to go to the coin laundry lately.
Well, I'd take some coins and put on a
shirt and jersey, go to the coin laundry...
And enjoy myself by waiting leisurely for the
machine to finish while I read a newspaper.
Speaking of coin laundry...
I'm looking forward to Detective Samonji's "Coin Laundry Murder Case"!
Tomorrow is the solution part!
Yes, yes!
I'm also watching that drama.
Well, I look forward to finding out who the culprit is!
My deduction says that the culprit
should be that seemingly nice...
I know who it is.
The culprit in that drama.
Because I already read the original novel.
Seriously?
Don't say it!
We're looking forward to it!
No, I won't say it.
Can you privately tell me who the culprit is?
You sure?
It'll air tomorrow.
See, I'll be drinking with my friend, so I won't see it live.
But you'll be taping it or something, right?
I think it'd be best if you took your time watching it.
You're right...
Well, thank you for everything today.
My fellow Detective Boys!
My name is Daita Kyouzou.
Don't hesitate to say hi if you see me somewhere!
Yes!
What a great old guy.
Yeah.
He's full of hope for tomorrow.
Definitely!
The train for Line 2 is approaching.
Please wait behind the white line.
Yoshimi...
Wait for me.
I'm going to save you now...
It'll hurt.
If you're run over by a train.
Beika, Beika Station.
Thank you for riding with us today.
Please do not forget your belongings.
Mister, you're planning to jump and kill yourself, right?
In order to get money for your granddaughter's operation.
Would you happen to have a life
insurance policy with a high premium?
How did you know?
Because...
Even though you said you were looking forward to tomorrow...
You don't really care what happens tomorrow.
Don't care?
Despite your going to Osaka to see the Big versus Spirits game...
You didn't know that Hide and Higo-san won't be there!
The match starts at 4:00 PM, but after a mere three hours...
You'd return here to drink with your friend—that's really strange.
The game will last two hours.
You can't possibly return here from Osaka in just an hour!
Besides...
You simply put the lottery tickets we picked
up in your bag without counting them.
It's also weird that you'd want to hear
the spoiler about tomorrow's drama.
It's as though you knew you wouldn't be seeing tomorrow.
That's why we knew...
That you were planning to die today!
Well, we heard everything from Conan-kun.
You drank to make it seem like you were
drunk and accidentally fell off the platform.
After the accident, the police would find the
soccer ticket and lottery tickets on you...
And they'd gather testimonies from people like us
corroborating that you were anticipating tomorrow...
All so that they would never suspect it was
a suicide to get the insurance money.
In other words...
Your life insurance policy becomes void upon suicide.
But...
How'd you know my granddaughter is ill?
If you treasure the glasses case she gave you so much...
You should at least know the name of the school she goes to.
But since you didn't know...
That indicated she was in no condition to attend school.
Due to that, I figured she was likely hospitalized somewhere.
Yeah...
She's been hospitalized for six months.
Because she has a heart disease...
We finally found a good doctor overseas,
and scheduled for a surgery soon.
But, the surgery costs are outrageous, there's no other way...
But even if she were cured, she'd be sad if you were gone!
Besides, didn't you buy a lot of lottery tickets?
There's still a chance that you could win!
There's no way, is there!?
That the same person can win 100 million yen again!
By "again"...
Do you mean you won before?
Yeah...
At the end of last month.
I thanked God over and over!
But then I lost the winning ticket...
And I couldn't find it anywhere!
Could it be...
You were checking the winning number while
reading a newspaper at the coin laundry?
Yeah...
I couldn't find it when I got home.
I might have lost it on the way home...
What about the other tickets?
I threw them away on the spot because they were of no use.
Then you must've put the winning ticket somewhere.
But it'd be unsafe for you to put it in your jersey pocket.
About your wallet...
You said you'd take a few coins to the laundry...
So you didn't bring it.
That means the only other place you could've put it inside is...
The glasses case you've been carrying, right?
I see!
It's here!
But, how did you know he was
carrying his glasses case back then?
When he was correcting the schedule
in his notebook, he squinted his eyes.
That's why I assumed they must be his reading glasses.
Since he checked the numbers in the
newspaper, he must've had them with him.
The reason he hadn't opened the
glasses case since he lost his ticket...
Is that he felt too guilty about
his granddaughter to wear them.
Besides, you don't need reading glasses
if you're only looking for something.
Wow, I was even thinking of robbing a bank at one point...
But I'm glad I didn't!
Hey, hey...
No, no, it's not good to do bad things!
Thank you very much!
My fellow Detective Boys!
I shall repay my gratitude another time!
Well then!
What an easygoing guy.
To think we just encountered a bank robbery not long ago!
Yeah...
I couldn't help but to shudder at that.
Oh, yeah...
We saw someone familiar among the bank customers.
Someone familiar?
Wasn't it Jodie-sensei?
No, it was the man who was also there during that bus-jacking.
You mean the guy with mean-looking eyes?
I saw him too!
As I recall, his right cheek was burnt.
Was there such a man during that bus-jacking?
He didn't have any burns at the time of the bus-jacking.
But I think he was wearing a knitted cap and a mask.
What the...
Akai!?
Yeah.
akai
They mentioned red shirts with long sleeves on the phone.
Someone wanted us to solve the mystery behind
these red T-shirts that have been coming every week.
The client will arrive tomorrow afternoon,
and wanted Dad to take their case.
Oh, she meant the color red...
Well?
You get the name and address of the person who called?
No...
They only stated their problem and hung up...
Well, I bet it's some college girl having a problem with some stalker.
The voice sounded altered by a machine...
I couldn't tell if it was a man or woman.
It's kind of scary!
We can just refuse the case directly if it really is that dubious.
Because even if we let it be, the client
introduced by the weird-voiced caller...
Will still come here tomorrow with the red T-shirt mystery.
They won't be coming to our office.
They'll be at the sports equipment counter
in the 3rd District Beika Department Store.
Why should I bother going all the way
there for someone I don't know?
But...
We already ate it.
Already "ate it"?
When I came home from school today...
I saw an envelope in the mailbox with "retainer fee" written on it...
And 100,000 yen in it.
Then, don't tell me this sushi...
Yeah, and I also used it to pay off the tab at Poirot...
I thought it was the fee from the
client you finished a job for last week.
By the time the caller told me they'd put the money in the mailbox...
I'd already ordered the sushi.
Geez!
Beika Department Store...
That's next to Teito Bank—the site of that robbery case from before...
Red T-shirt mystery?
Someone who wants you to solve it will be coming here?
Yeah, this afternoon...
Have they come yet?
No...
But why would they come here?
Well... I don't know myself.
Maybe they're at another counter?
Hey, hey...
Do we have to wander around the entire floor?
Come to think of it, someone was here asking about a cap.
A cap?
Look, it's that foreigner...
Hey, don't make me repeat myself!
The one-point mark on the back of this cap
is this department store's original design!
That means it's your exclusive merchandise, right?
Do you not remember the customer who came to buy this?
No...
I don't remember anyone like you've described coming here.
Uhm...
Please tell me about it now.
What's this about a customer who bought that cap?
It's all right, just stay quiet!
Jodie-sensei!
And Agent Camel too?
Why are you here?
Just to check on something...
Hey, were you speaking fluent Japanese just now?
That's because...
Of Camel here...
Yeah!
I've become fluent in Japanese!
Because I like Japan!
Got a problem?
No...
She managed to escape...
Jodie-sensei...
If I recall, you're the FBI agent who taught English at the high school...
Didn't you go back to America?
No, I still have a few things to do here...
This is my partner, Agent Camel.
We'll stay in Japan for a while.
Be sure to say hello whenever you see us.
Well, they don't seem to have anything to do...
With the red shirt mystery...
Well then, let's head to the golf equipment section!
Say...
Did the foreign lady just now talk about anything besides the cap?
Yeah.
She kept on asking me...
If a man with a burn on his right cheek came to buy anything.
A burn on his right cheek?
Then, Jodie-sensei saw him too...
That man among the hostages at the bank robbery.
Shuu...
Hey, Conan-kun, let's go.
Thank you!
Uhm...
Excuse me.
May I ask you a few questions?
Geez!
It's already past 1:00!
The client isn't coming...
I give up!
Won't have it!
We're going home!
What's with this paper bag?
Someone lost it?
It'd be best if you didn't touch that.
Because it probably...
Has a bomb inside.
Bomb!?
A bomb?
Why do you know something like that?
Because...
I'm also...
Strapped up...
Like this!
Bombs!?
"Run! This place is dangerous!"
You... why do you have that?
He said that the sender of the 13 red T-shirts...
Must be located at any cost.
Red T-shirts...
Just what is his aim!?
Next Conan's Hint
Receipt
Look Forward to the Next Episode