What?
You saw Akai Shuuichi?
Remember, not too long ago...
There was a robbery at Teito Bank in Beika City.
They said on the news that the trial for the case started yesterday.
And in the video of the incident that they played back...
One of the customers that was freed looked just like him.
But, I suppose it was just a look-alike.
After all, we witnessed it with our own eyes, didn't we?
When that Akai came to Raiha Pass unsuspectingly...
And got a bullet in the head, courtesy of Kir's gun.
Call Kir.
First it was the Haido City Hotel where
that escapee Sherry showed up.
And the place where Akai lured us to in order to snipe us...
Was at the Mouri Detective Agency in Beika City.
The FBI also kept Kir in custody at Haido Central Hospital.
And now, a man resembling Akai
has appeared at a bank in Beika City.
Haido and Beika are but a stone's throw from one another.
Think that's a coincidence?
Flowers dance to the piano's rhythm.
Two people face-to-face is a mystery!
Bomb threats at the department store.
What is the aim of the men in black?
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
After school, we came across an old man named Daita Kyouzou-san.
We then detected his intention of committing suicide...
And succeeded in talking some sense into him.
Then, at that point, Genta and the others
shared with me a surprising revelation.
Among the customers who had become hostages
in the bank robbery we'd encountered...
Was a man who had also found himself
involved in the bus-jacking from before.
Don't tell me he's...
Meanwhile, a strange request arrived at the Mouri Detective Agency.
"Someone wishes for you to solve the mystery of
the red T-shirts that have been sent every week...
"So please offer your expertise," it went.
The next day, we arrived at Beika
Department Store to meet said person.
Also there was Agent Jodie from the FBI.
The person she was looking for was indeed...
Geez!
It's already past 1:00!
The client isn't coming...
I give up!
Not having it!
We're going home!
What's with this paper bag?
Somebody lose it?
It'd be best if you didn't touch that.
Because it probably...
Has a bomb inside.
Bomb!?
A bomb?
Why do you know something like that?
Because...
I'm also...
Strapped up...
Like this!
Bombs!?
I'm sorry, James.
We haven't finished our lunch yet.
Hey, hey, Jodie-kun...
How much longer is this lunch going to take?
A few things came up...
And we're still at the department store cafe downstairs.
"Things"?
Did you encounter problems?
No...
It's not like that.
Well, once Camel's finished in the restroom...
We'll meet you there, after I finish my iced tea.
What's with her?
It seems as if Jodie-san has changed...
Especially since that bank robbery.
She told me not to tell James-san, but...
What on earth is with the black cap?
Wait...
Wait a minute!
Was that really...
Was it!?
Strange...
If a man with a burnt face who couldn't talk came to buy something...
One of the clerks should be able to remember him.
Could it be he wasn't there in the first place?
If that's so, who was the man I saw?
Shuu!?
Sorry.
Shuu...
Are you Shuu?
You're Shuu, right?
Say that you're Shuu!
Who on earth was he?
Huh?
The edge of the coaster is folded.
Was it like that before?
"Run! This place is dangerous!"
Shuu!
You... why do you have that?
I don't know!
I was knocked unconscious from behind in the restroom...
And when I came to, a masked man had put this on me.
The man told me...
That he'd also put the paper bags in
front of the escalators and stairs.
He threated to blow everything up if I didn't do as he said.
At any rate, the police!
I'm calling the police!
Don't!
He said that he'd press the detonator the moment
any police approach this department store!
He also said if anyone escaped from this floor, it'd be the end.
No way...
Can't be...
Well, what does that man want?
Inside this bag...
He said that the sender of these 13 red T-shirts...
Must be located at any cost.
Red T-shirts?
What!?
Yeah...
About the sender...
He said that they're definitely on this floor!
They're definitely on this floor?
Hey, hey...
Are you serious?
If we don't locate the sender of the red T-shirts in that bag...
He'll detonate the bombs?
Yes...
The masked man that strapped this bomb to me said so.
And he mentioned that the sender is on this floor?
He said if that person owned up, he wouldn't press the switch.
Hey, you hear that!?
I don't care why you did it, but whoever sent all these red T-shirts...
If you're here, come out!
No one's coming out.
He demanded that the escalators be stopped...
And to not let the elevators stop on this floor.
I see.
Until the sender is identified...
He's locking up all the customers on this floor, huh?
No way!
No...
NOOO!
Hey, wait!
Hold on!
Hey, hey!
Calm down, hey!
Everyone, calm down!
Hey!
Please...
Stay on this floor!
CALM DOWN!
You just heard, didn't you?
The bomber is searching for whoever
keeps sending him those red T-shirts...
And he believes that the sender is on this floor.
Until we locate the sender...
If anyone tries to escape this floor, he'll engage the switch.
Of course, it'd be over if we informed the police.
Any arbitrary step by one of us will result in casualties.
That's what he said, right?
Excuse me, but can you call and relay
the situation to the store manager...
And have them stop the escalator and not
allow the elevator to stop on this floor?
Yes!
Of course, any use of the stairs will also be disallowed.
Please make absolutely sure that
the police are not informed of this.
The bomber could be on this floor...
Watching our every move at this very moment.
Understood.
Now, what should we do next?
How about we have a look at those?
The red T-shirts he keeps receiving
every week from the mysterious sender.
Huh?
Did I say that he had been receiving those weekly?
We were asked to come here by someone
seemingly related to the bomber.
They claimed someone related to the mystery of
the red T-shirts that had been sent weekly...
Would come to the sports equipment counter
in Beika Department Store this afternoon.
And they wanted me, Mouri Kogorou, to take on the case.
Mouri Kogorou?
You're that great detective?
That's why I'm here to expose the identities of the
red T-shirts' sender and the bomber in no time.
Anyway, just watch me from a distance!
Yes...
A man with a burn mark on his right cheek left this shop a bit ago?
Is that true?
Yes.
It was soon after you left your seat in
order to answer your phone outside.
Was he...
Wearing a cap like this?
Yeah, he was.
Was that Akai-san?
We crossed paths in the restroom just now.
The man with a burn that looked just like Akai-san.
No way!
He came?
Right here?
Yeah...
But I lost sight of him.
But, why is he here?
Then, could it be...
The person you said you saw during that bank robbery incident was...
Yeah, that's right.
He disappeared in the confusion following
that incident, so I started to look for him.
And the mark on the back of the cap he was wearing at that time...
I found out it was an original design of this department store.
That's why I came to search for clues.
I apologize.
I was half in doubt so I didn't tell anyone.
And since it looked like he lost his memory and the ability to speak...
I couldn't confirm anything from him.
Say...
Don't you think this could be a trap set by them?
Didn't you say it yourself?
That Akai Shuuichi is dead.
You also confirmed the fingerprints on his body.
He can't still be alive.
But...
Both your and Conan-kun's prints are there, just as you told me.
We also found the fingerprints of the man
whose burnt corpse was found a while ago.
I know Shuu could've managed...
Besides!
What is this trap for anyway!?
Well...
They may try to confuse us and pull something off...
The SWAT team?
But why?
Come to think of it, something happened on the next floor.
People were shouting that the elevator wouldn't stop on it.
Then, the man with the burn must be Shuu.
Look!
This is a message left to me by that man with a burn.
Then...
Akai-san sensed that something would
happen at this department store?
Yeah.
No doubt he must've regained his memory.
But, what is it?
What's going on right now?
Shuu...
According to the torn delivery slips
inside the bags containing the T-shirts...
Seven, six, and five weeks ago,
two T-shirts were sent per week.
But on the fourth week, for some reason...
Only one was sent.
Then, three, two, and one week ago...
Two T-shirts were sent each time again.
Does this mean something?
Well...
I can only say that it totals 13, an unlucky number...
Hey, you!
Don't come near me!
You've got bombs on you!
Oh, I'm sorry.
Huh?
On the shoulder of your coat...
There's something red on it.
Hey, hey!
If it's red, could that be related to this case?
Oh, this is probably just someone's lipstick.
I was on a very crowded bullet train before I came here.
Is that so...
In any case, stay away from me for a bit.
Yes!
Huh?
Inside the bag that had the T-shirts...
There's still something.
Isn't this a receipt from when they bought the T-shirt?
The amount matches too.
A receipt?
In the bag that had one T-shirt...
There was a receipt for one T-shirt as well.
The other bags have them too.
What?
Look.
It's true...
The dates on the receipts match those on the delivery slips.
They sent those the same day they bought them.
But the receipts are also torn...
We can't tell where these were bought.
But still...
Something can be seen only on last week's receipt.
See, they didn't tear it off...
We can see a mark.
That's...
Isn't that Beika Department Store's mark?
And also...
Look at the time of purchase.
It's interesting that all of them were at 12:28.
I see.
That's why the bomber knew that the sender would be on this floor.
He realized the sender always bought them in the afternoon.
Wait...
Why does it have to be in the sports department?
Maybe it's because the T-shirts are classified as underwear?
It says "underwear" on the receipts too.
See, you'd wear them when you go jogging.
They're made out of polyester that absorb sweat and dry easily.
I see!
Do you know where these would be sold?
I think...
In the fitness supplies section.
Please take me there.
Yes!
This way.
Strange...
Up until two weeks ago, the receipts were torn
so that no one could tell the place of purchase.
Why did they miss only this week's?
Besides...
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
Did you notice something else?
Yeah...
I think this receipt is strange.
Strange?
Just think.
If you're trying to hide where it was bought...
You only have to tear the upper left side...
But they tore the upper right side too.
Maybe they're just careless?
The way they folded the clothes were careless too.
The way they folded?
See, take this single shirt that was sent as example.
There are strange creases on it.
If we fold along the creases...
It ends up like this.
This is...
Don't tell me...
What do we do?
Should we charge in?
No, wait.
The bomber claimed that if we police
close in, he'll send the place up in flames.
But...
According to the informant, the bombs are...
We can't rely on that information.
They may have said that just because they want to be saved.
We'll have to wait here for a while...
And see what the bomber's next move is.
Hey...
How long I gotta wait?
For a ghost that may not even exist.
Be patient, Chianti.
We're certain the man that looks like
Akai entered that department store.
I'll decide whether he's a ghost or not with my own eyes.
If it turns out that he isn't a ghost...
In that exact moment...
I'll turn you into a ghost myself.
Kir.
TRANS... FORM!
I'm so overjoyed I can't contain it...
Because then, I could kill him all over again.
I won't allow the bombs to explode.
In the name of the great detective, Mouri Kogorou!
Next Conan's Hint
T-Shirt
Look Forward to the Next Episode