It's a ghost.
He can't be alive.
I shot Akai Shuuichi with my own hands.
Gin, it happened right in front of your eyes.
Not in front of my eyes.
It was through a monitor.
You could have employed any number of tricks to fake it.
Am I wrong, Kir?
Tricks?
What kind of tricks could I use?
Remember, the one who ordered me to call
Akai to Raiha Pass in the first place...
Was you.
No.
Now.
You'll call him now, right here.
Actually...
It's become difficult to stay in the Organization.
I want your help to leave and fly out of here.
Of course, I'll offer any information that the FBI wants.
Can we meet now, just the two of us?
Yeah.
It won't be a problem...
So long as you're alone.
Was that good?
It was also you who ordered me to blow his head off.
The head.
Drive a bullet right into his head.
That way we can be sure that his life...
Has come to a final end.
Meanwhile, you saw his blood pouring
out of his head while he collapsed...
Via the camera you installed on me.
After you rescued me from the FBI...
The organization constantly monitored me closely.
It'd have been impossible for me to contact him.
There's no means of utilizing any sort of trick.
That is, unless you're implying he or I had superhuman
brainpower that allowed us to calculate that far ahead...
Maybe then we could have tricked you.
Yes, like that of Sherlock Holmes.
How about you put a stop to your baseless doubts
and just be happy that your nemesis is gone?
I'm so overjoyed I can't contain it.
Because if he were really alive...
I could kill him all over again.
Flowers dance to the piano's rhythm.
Two people face-to-face is a mystery!
The time limit's drawing near.
Time for me to unearth the bomber's true intent!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
A strange request arrived at the Mouri Detective Agency:
"Someone wishes for you to solve the mystery of the
red T-shirts that have been sent every week...
"So please offer your expertise," it went.
We went to Beika Department Store to meet said person, but...
We encountered a man with bombs strapped around his body.
Apparently, he was threatened by a masked man who
claimed bombs had been planted all over the floor.
It appeared we had become trapped on that same floor.
The masked man ordered that the sender
of the weekly red T-shirts be found.
He also said that the sender is on the very same floor.
We checked the 13 red T-shirts that were
carried by the man with bombs on his body.
And from the enclosed receipts...
We learned that these were bought at the
fitness section every Sunday at 12:28 PM.
Who was the sender of the T-shirts?
What is their intent?
And, what is the identity of the bomber who
demanded that the sender be found?
Vodka, move the car opposite the department store.
Get us in a position where we can see this
man who looks like Akai as he leaves.
What's wrong?
Get moving.
Oh, no...
It's just...
According to Korn, who's watching the basement exit...
There's apparently something going on inside the store.
Hey, Korn!
Got any details?
Dunno, but I did see...
A SWAT and bomb disposal team head in earlier.
A SWAT and bomb disposal team?
What?
What's going on?
Please, hold on a minute.
I'm here to find the person among the customers on
this floor that's been sending red shirts every week.
You do understand that this is per the bomber's request?
Yes.
The receipts that were also sent were from this department store.
And the only place the shirts are sold is here, in the fitness section.
Even beyond that...
They were always purchased on Sundays at 12:28.
And the salesperson in charge at this time on Sunday...
Is you and you only, right?
Then, why is it you can't remember that customer?
Normally you would remember!
Since they've been coming to buy the
same thing at the same time every week!
But...
I really don't remember that.
No way...
And I haven't sold any of that red underwear today.
Then, did any other clerks happen to cover for you around that time?
No one has covered for me in the past half year.
Well, could this receipt be from a few years back?
No...
We just started using that type of receipt earlier this year.
Anyway, I always take the money and items from the customers...
And hand them over to the office of the cashier, Seta-san...
Then, I bring the change and receipt along with
the bagged items back to the waiting customer.
If there had been such a strange customer...
I doubt I'd forget someone like that.
But, you know...
We have the receipts proving they were here.
Excuse me...
The bomb man!
Don't come any closer!
Please, stop calling me the bomb man!
I'm not the bomber!
Just someone who has been strapped with bombs!
I'm an innocent, ordinary citizen!
Did you hot hear me?
I told you to stay away until I've solved the case!
Yes...
But the boy with glasses...
He's playing around with those red T-shirts.
Playing around?
What is this?
Just like you did earlier...
I merely folded along the creases in the shirts.
But they look creepy when you line them up, don't they?
Yeah, just like in that Holmes story...
"The Dancing Men"?
Right, right—they look like that code.
Then, maybe this is a code too.
If we read them from right to left in the order they were sent...
Maybe a phrase will be formed.
I take my eyes off of you for a bit and this is what happens!
Geez!
Dad!
Didn't I tell you to behave?
But, Conan-kun said that by folding along the creases in the shirts...
It might form a code.
A code?
It can't possibly be.
There's no way to tell when those creases were made!
What?
The sender of the red underwear?
Yes, sir.
It seems the bomber's aim is to find that person.
And, do we know how many bombs?
According to the surveillance cameras...
There's one at each of the two elevators and each of the two stairs.
Adding the upward and downward escalators...
We're looking at six places at least.
Six places, huh?
What a hassle.
How odd.
For a bomber to hijack an entire floor...
They let too much information leak in such a short time.
That's true.
Besides...
No way!
You're on the floor with the bombs?
Hey, hey, is it all right for you to be calling?
Isn't the bomber there?
It seems they haven't even taken the hostages' cell phones.
Think this is an amateur job?
Let's hope so.
Idiot, quit joking around already!
I'm not joking!
Here, take a look.
A video phone...
See him?
The guy with the bombs on him.
It's real!?
Shuu...
Shuu!
TRANS... FORM!
What are you doing?
Nah...
I was just mimicking the moves of these shirts.
But nothing makes sense.
Rather than doing things like that,
please focus on finding the sender!
Right...
But still...
Your movements just then reminded me of something...
What was it?
That's it!
I bet Conan-kun knows something.
He's gone off somewhere again!
I see.
After you get the items from the customers...
You take them to the cashier's office back there, right?
Yep, that's right.
And I'll say, "Please wait a moment."
Thank you for sharing that with me.
Bye then!
Pardon me!
Wow!
Hey!
Boy...
So this is what the cashier's room is like!
Uhm...
Let me use your PC for a bit.
For what?
Uncle Kogoro asked me to check something out...
About a snowy mountain disaster case from December 28th.
I see...
Found it!
This must be it.
The case is from over ten years ago.
Looks like an experienced mountain climber...
Got caught in an avalanche and died.
All right.
You're done?
I'm going to tell Uncle Kogoro it was just as he thought!
Oh...
Thank you, Maruoka-san!
I've pinpointed the sender's intention.
Now I just need to figure out the bomber's aim...
Why did he have to cause all this commotion?
Now all I can do is to wait for the bomber to make his next move.
In any case, there's no mistaking that the bomber is very confident.
Confident that his crime from the past...
Will never be found out.
Geez, where have you been?
Just the bathroom.
Man!
Right, no one will find out.
My crime is perfect.
There's no evidence and not a single witness.
The one threatening me is a fool.
I'll make sure they'll never be able to do this again.
Well, did he figure something out?
Not a thing.
It's because of that brat fooling around...
I can't get my thinking straight!
Huh, so you're putting the blame on Conan-kun?
And you had to go order sushi with that money...
You're putting the blame on Ran-neechan this time!
Shut up!
Fine, I'll think, I'll think!
Uhm, excuse me.
So, it was indeed snowy mountains...
Why can't we go in?
We are not at liberty to say.
Someone took control of the floor with bombs?
Yeah, seems some fool's in there screwing around.
His demands were to find somebody.
And the guy that looks like Akai hasn't shown any signs of leaving.
I bet he's stuck on that floor.
This is a hell of a problem.
Whether the bomber's caught or the bombs explode...
People are gonna immediately rush out either way.
I doubt we'll be able to finish him off.
No, this is even better.
The crowd will drown out the scent of our sniper.
And even should he wish to flee, he'll
no longer be able to move about freely.
For Chianti sniping from above and Korn
looking on from the basement exit...
He'll be easy prey.
Say, does he know about this?
"He"?
Who?
Bourbon, I mean.
I heard he started searching for the scientist,
Sherry, who betrayed the organization.
Who knows, he's a secretive one like Vermouth.
I have no knowledge of his actions or whereabouts.
Speaking of which, Bourbon hates Akai too.
Even more than Gin.
Well, even if I knew where he was, I have
no intention of sharing any intel with him.
Why?
He didn't believe Akai was dead from the beginning.
He can't help but think he's the only one who could finish Akai.
And if that man turns out to be Akai...
He'd let out his I-told-you-so snicker.
I'd rather not see him with that face.
Hey, hurry up already!
Yeah, that's right!
How long is this gonna take?
Aren't you that famous detective, Mouri Kogoro?
Hurry up and find the sender of those red
T-shirts that the bomber's looking for...
So that we may be released!
See...
The identities of the sender and the
bomber are still a mystery to me...
I don't recognize the address...
No way!
Hey, Dad!
There's a bomb next to...
That's fine.
I won't allow the bombs to explode.
In the name of the great detective, Mouri Kogoro!
Then, you figured it out?
The sender of the red underwear?
But, you just said that it was a mystery to you...
Right, a mysterious sender and a mysterious bomber.
The key to solving this case is right there.
What?
Something's happening on that hijacked floor?
Yes, looks like the great detective Mouri happens to be on that floor.
What?
Sleeping Korogou is?
I do hope that he can prevent the explosion...
This is stressful, but do your best, Detective Mouri!
Don't you find it strange?
Look at the receipts that were sent with the red underwear.
You'll see that they were all sold on a Sunday at
12:28 in the fitness section of this department store.
If he wanted to find the sender...
He would only need to wait secretly near
that section at that time for them to come.
But I bet the sender didn't come.
That's why the bomber knocked out that man
in the restroom and strapped on the bombs...
And demanded the sender be found.
That's exactly what's strange.
To strap bombs onto someone, you need
to go somewhere to avoid people.
But to do that, you'd have to take
your eyes off the fitness section.
If he was so desperate to find the
sender that he'd resort to bombs...
Do you think he'd do something this careless?
That's true, but...
What if the bomber had an accomplice
to watch the fitness section for him?
That's impossible.
Take a look around you.
You see how people are talking on their cell phones, no?
If our floor-hijacker had an accomplice...
He wouldn't allow the customers to call.
Then, he probably strapped the bombs to
that man long before 12:28 for preparation?
No, the bombs were his last resort.
The bombs he had left by the exits to this floor,
he could easily retrieve them before explosion.
But if he doesn't know whether the sender would really come...
It'd be too risky for him to strap the bombs to someone prematurely.
But, you're saying the bomber is alone, right?
How could he not take his eyes off that section...
And still manage to strap bombs around that man?
The bombs weren't strapped to him here.
Those were already strapped before he came.
Already strapped?
You aren't trying to say...
Isn't that right?
Mr. Bomber...
The "ordinary citizen"?
Why are you in such a hurry?
Could it be that you're looking for the same person I am?
Don't, Shuu!
They're targeting you!
Please, stop!
Akai Shuuichi...
Next Conan's Hint
Lipstick