Uhm, sir?
Oh, pardon me.
I'll be going now.
I just wanted to see what was going on outside.
Besides, this floor is occupied by bombs.
I hardly feel like drinking anything.
However...
For those holding their breath, waiting
impatiently for their prey in this heat...
I'd like to treat them to some hot, bitter coffee.
Flowers dance to the piano's rhythm.
Two people face-to-face is a mystery!
It's revealed!
The truth of the bombing case and the fate of Akai's ghost!
Perceiving the one and only truth...
The appearance of a child and the intellect of an adult...
His name is: Detective Conan!
In order to solve the mystery
of the weekly red T-shirts...
We went to Beika Department Store,
only to end up encountering a man...
Whose body was strapped with bombs.
He claimed that a masked man put the bombs on him...
And demanded that the sender of the T-shirts,
supposedly still on the floor, to be found.
We learned that the thirteen red T-shirts
were bought every Sunday at 12:28...
But the clerk claimed she couldn't remember who bought them.
What on earth does this mean?
From the strange creases in the red T-shirts...
I discovered that a disaster which claimed
the life of an alpinist over ten years ago...
Has everything to do with this case.
Hey, Dad!
There's a bomb next to...
That's fine.
I won't allow the bombs to explode.
Isn't that right?
Mr. Bomber...
The "ordinary citizen"?
I'm not...
When 12:28 came around...
Nobody had come to buy the shirt, so you thought...
"This must be a trap set by the sender in order to lure me here."
That's why you thought of a way to smoke that pestering sender out.
How would he smoke them out?
Since the sender knows his address...
The sender likely knows his face too.
If he strapped himself with bombs...
And claimed, "If we don't find the sender, they'll explode"...
He thought the sender would appear and say it was a lie.
Well, I don't have to employ such a tiresome
method to uncover the identity of the sender.
Really?
It's the receipts.
No matter how customers try...
There's no way they are guaranteed to get receipts at precisely 12:28.
They could request the receipt to be rung up on that time...
And they might get what they wanted.
But then the sales personnel would
remember such an eccentric customer.
Regardless, no one remembers any customers like that.
That means our sender is the one who made the receipts.
In other words, it's the cashier of the fitness
section who handles these red underwear...
Seta-san...
It was you, was it not?
Since the cash register for that section is in a small back room...
No customers or other employees could see you.
As a result, you could make 12:28 receipts without arousing suspicion.
Beyond that...
It's likely that the sender and recipient are acquaintances.
Regardless, the recipient still couldn't locate you.
That's further proof that the sender was you, who
had been hiding in that small room all this time.
Mai-chan?
Are you Mai-chan?
You're Maruoka-san's daughter?
Yeah, that's right, Fukunishi-san!
My father, who you killed on those
snowy mountains thirteen years ago...
I'm the daughter of Maruoka Daisaku!
So will you stop calling me "chan" so casually!?
No, he died in that avalanche...
Yeah, right!
That sudden avalanche was in your favor...
So the police didn't investigate further.
They wrote it off as a simple disaster case.
But, thirteen years ago, on Sunday, December 28th...
The morning before my father went with you to climb that mountain...
He wrote about it in his journal!
He said that, should you see the magnificent
scenery of a summit even once...
You might clean up your ways!
The charges of corruption against my father surfaced after his death!
And the company's embezzlement...
I knew it was you who placed all the blame on your boss - my dad!
What are you saying, Mai-chan?
I see, this woman is the one who set me up...
Well, are you satisfied now?
Release my son already!
Son?
What do you mean?
Wasn't it you who ordered me to do all of this in this letter?
Letter?
Let me see.
"I have your son."
"If you want him back, strap the enclosed bombs to yourself..."
"Then take the remaining bombs to Beika Department
Store and occupy the floor of the fitness section..."
"And shriek that the sender must be found or you will be killed."
"When I am satisfied laughing at the scene, I shall return your son."
This letter...
I know nothing about it!
Don't play dumb!
My son's been missing since last week!
Now, return my son!
I see, so that was your intention.
Dad...
Seta-san is at a disadvantage because she really
had been sending those red shirts every week.
All the same, it'd be in your favor to claim that, should it not have
been for the letter, you wouldn't have caused this bomb frenzy.
That's why you faked that threatening letter...
In order to deepen the guilt of the sender and punish them!
Unbeknownst to you, Seta-san holds the decisive evidence...
Which proves you were her father's killer.
Decisive?
What evidence?
Impossible... such a thing doesn't exist.
It's the thirteen red underwear Seta-san sent you.
Actually, by folding along the creases in those shirts...
You get something resembling flag signals.
Flag signals...
You mean the method of waving red and white
flags with both hands to communicate?
Yes, and by reading them in the order they were sent you get...
"I saw you burying it..."
Is it about the dead body's burial place?
So it was a bluff!
A bluff?
Isn't that right?
At that time, the snowstorm was so strong
that you couldn't even open your eyes.
So, even if someone other than me was there...
"It'd still be impossible for them to see the
place where I buried the body," you say?
No, that's...
According to Maruoka-san's journal, it was
the first time you climbed a mountain.
A novice like you wouldn't be able to travel far from
the mountain cabin in a snowstorm to bury a body.
In that case, if we dig near the cabin on that mountain...
We might find it.
The one you killed and buried thirteen years ago...
The body of an alpinist.
It seems you were confident that no one saw you...
But there really was a witness.
It was you, the murderer.
By the way, did your son really disappear?
I think he just ran away like usual...
How foolish...
I wanted my son to enter a famous elementary
school so bad that I embezzled from the company...
And I even killed my boss who reprimanded me.
But, in the end, my son ran away from home...
Well, someone call the police to take
Seta-san and this man to the station.
Yes.
Also let the customers know that the bombs in the bags are fakes...
And are only capable of producing smoke.
Understood.
Although it looks like the SWAT team
Seta-san called for is already nearby.
I called them and said that the bombs are
probably fake, so go ahead and arrest him, but...
They didn't budge.
But, Dad, how did you know that the bombs were fake?
There were traces of lipstick on his shoulder.
If the bombs he strapped to himself were real...
It'd be unlikely for him to have boarded a crowded train.
With that, my investigation on your behalf has come to an end.
Are you satisfied?
Seta-san.
Yes.
So you already figured it out...
That I was the client who changed her voice and called you.
Actually, I only wanted you to reveal the meaning
of those flag signals that I learned from my dad...
And to see what expression that man would make.
I never expected him to confess...
That was really impressive!
With just that little hint...
You realized it was about the snowy
mountain disaster on December 28th.
And to think you had that boy check on it...
Oh, that's...
Flag signaling is used where verbal communication
isn't possible, such as on the sea or in the mountains.
Since the meaning of the message was "I saw you burying it"...
It'd be the mountains rather than the sea.
Moreover, the receipts torn unnaturally on the right side...
Suggested snowy mountains.
And the color red on the underwear suggests murder.
One would disguise a murder on snowy
mountains as a disastrous accident.
Since disasters aren't registered with the unit of minutes...
The "12:28" on the receipts was
likely referring to December 28th.
That's what was written.
In a mail I received a while ago from someone I don't know, that is.
Let me see it!
So, what happened to the bomb case?
Huh?
A mail from someone unknown...
Who was it?
Who on earth sent this mail?
The only thing I can say for sure is that the sender of this mail...
Was definitely on this floor a few moments ago.
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
I was just thinking that the one who sent
this mail was a really great detective.
A-mail?
Here.
Well, I'll leave the rest to you.
You must feel hot, but keep up the good work!
It's true!
Don't tell me Dad was talking while reading this mail?
But, the fact that I, the sender, am the daughter of the alpinist
who was killed thirteen years ago in those snowy mountains...
That was unmentioned.
You heard about that from Detective Mouri, right, boy?
Since you didn't call me "Seta" as it is on my nameplate...
But by my maiden name, "Maruoka".
Yeah, when I went into your office...
I said I'd borrow your PC to look up a snowy
mountain disaster case from December 28th.
Yet, you didn't seem surprised by that, right?
That's why I figured you were the client who requested the
investigation and were somehow associated with that incident.
Since the deceased Maruoka-san had a picture with his daughter in it...
And you were wearing a wedding ring...
I figured you got married and changed your surname.
That's amazing, Conan-kun.
Of course...
All of that was stuff Uncle Kogoro told me!
Well, it was exactly as I deduced.
There is only one truth, after all!
As expected from Sleeping Kogoro-san!
But the one who sent this message was also a good detective.
Everything except that one thing was very accurate.
I wonder who?
Could they still be on this floor?
Then, maybe they'll show up if I send a "thank you" reply!
They won't.
Judging from the wording, they don't
seem to want to get involved in this.
Is it that guy?
Excuse me, but did you get a
"thank you" mail just now?
Yes, I got one.
Then, did you make these deductions?
No, I have no idea about that.
But, this mail came from your cell phone, didn't it?
It was probably sent by that guy who picked up my phone.
He was wearing a black cap...
And his right cheek had a burn mark.
What!?
Where is that man!?
He took the escalator when it started moving.
I think he probably went downstairs.
Conan-kun!
Why are you in such a hurry?
Jodie-sensei...
Could it be that you're looking for the same person I am?
No...
Seems like this place really is dangerous, just like that message warned.
"That message"?
The message Shuu left for me.
You met him?
Akai-san?
No, while I was away from my seat at the basement cafe...
He discreetly wrote it on the back of my coaster.
So, why is it dangerous here?
The bombing case is already solved.
Because I saw it.
Near the window of the hotel across the street...
There's someone resembling a sniper...
And there's a black Porsche 356A parked below.
Gin!
Could they have discovered Shuu's still alive and plan to finish him?
Shuu...
Where are you, Shuu?
There!
It's Shuu!
Don't, Shuu!
Don't go out!
They're targeting you!
Shuu!
I'm sorry, are you all right?
But we share a fifty-fifty responsibility.
You're also at fault for not paying attention to your surroundings.
It seems as if you're searching for someone.
Shuu...
Where are you, Shuu!?
It's him!
It's him all right!
I found the ghost!
At the left side of the front entrance.
He's right next to your car!
If you want confirmation, make it fast, Gin!
My finger on the trigger is itching in excitement so badly...
It could go off at any moment!
Akai Shuuichi...
Vermouth...
Did you get authorization from that person?
Yeah.
Our boss is cautious as hell.
Knocking on and even breaking a
stone bridge just to test its sturdiness.
What's the hold up!?
Kill him?
Don't kill him?
What's the verdict?
He looked...
That bastard!
He looked my way!
He fucking looked at me and laughed!
Do I kill him or do I not!?
What do I do!?
Partner, this is odd.
The customers are rushing back into the department store.
Where is he?
Where the hell did he go!?
The customers are speeding up, and my aim...
Hey, isn't she dangerous?
She's carrying a rifle!
Are they filming a movie or something?
We're pulling out.
Inform Korn as well.
Wait, what do you mean!?
Gin!
Gi—
Always doing as he pleases.
That bastard irritates me as usual.
Who do you mean?
Like you said...
One who you would wish only existed in novels.
A private eye like Sherlock Holmes.
Hey, hurry and hand over that gift certificate!
It'll give us 10,000 yen worth, right!?
What are you talking about?
You're issuing gift certificates to all customers
as an apology for the bomb commotion!
The kid with glasses raced around and said so!
I never heard anything about that...
Hey, hey, don't give us that!
We took all the trouble coming back here!
I see, a gift certificate...
I can't say it was a smart method...
But in order to remove the customers from
harm's way, you had no choice, right?
Subaru-san!
I had some business at Teito, Bank next to this department store.
After I was done there and left...
I saw you guys and tried to catch up to greet you.
But then I got caught up in this case.
Who is this guy?
For starters, he lost his apartment in a fire...
And now he's temporarily staying at Shin'ichi's house.
He's Okiya Subaru-san, a grad student.
But what did you mean?
About Conan-kun removing the customers from harm's way?
It's nothing worth asking.
Just a trivial story about a pack of
stupid wolves who lost their easy prey.
But, isn't Teito Bank rather far away from where you're living?
Why do you have an account in such a far place?
No, I went to that bank for some other business.
Other business?
Well, there was a robbery case in that bank before, right?
Someone I once knew happened to appear in the
video they showed in the follow-up news report.
That's why I went there, hoping that he might use that bank.
If he uses it, I thought he might also live around here.
Maybe I would've gotten lucky and met him.
Then, does that mean you couldn't find him?
Actually, I happened to see him on the floor from earlier.
Unfortunately, it seems he wasn't who I
thought he was, so I didn't talk to him.
I've known his face for a very long time.
There's no way I could be mistaken.
A stalker, you say?
Unforgivable!
Zombie...
This is self defense, no matter how you look at it.
So it is...
As I thought.
Next Conan's Hint
Strawberry